( phone ringing )
PHONE:
No one is available.
Please leave a message
( beep )
MAN:
Jane, you there?
Pick up.
Okay... I'll call back later.
( sniffling and trembling )
( phone ringing )
( sobbing gasp )
PHONE:
No one is available.
Please leave a message.
( beep )
MAN:
Slut. You can't hide
from me, bitch.
Jane, you there?
Now, didn't I tell you...
not to bite your nails?!
( door opening softly )
( scratching softly )
( gasping )
( whimpering softly )
Shoo, Peanut.
Go away. Go away.
( whimpering )
( screaming )
( screaming and crying )
Posed?
Reading my mind.
What do you make
of the smears?
It's definitely
not blood.
Wrong color, texture.
It's hair dye.
Her hair's still wet.
You think
the assailant
surprised her
while she was dyeing her hair?
Who called it in?
Neighbor lady--
doing the dishes
with her window open.
Heard the dog
yelping, evidently.
Called the cops.
There's no sign
of forced entry.
The bathroom window's
nailed shut.
So, has anyone
seen this dog?
Dog bed, dog bowl, dog food;
no dog.
Triple locks
on all the doors.
Every shade drawn.
State-of-the-art
alarm system.
As far as we know
her place was perfectly
hermetically sealed
until the cops
batter-rammed
their way in.
Prisoner in
her own home?
So, how did he get in?
A better question--
how'd he get out?
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
Aluminum foil.
Keeps the
sunlight out.
Keeps the eyeballs out, too.
( gasping )
Sorry, Nick.
You've been staring at this girl
for ten minutes.
Do you know her?
No.
Why don't you
go do the bedroom?
I'll get the coroner
in here
and finish up
in the bathroom.
Sure.
Hey, Catherine,
I'll get that.
No. I got it.
Tweeze me.
Thank you.
So, what do you think?
A little thick
for a human hair.
No, I've seen
them this thick.
Really?
Yeah.
I'll get it to the lab.
Oh, and don't forget
what's under the bed.
Why, what's
under the bed?
Something that you would
have caught eventually...
Crime Stopper.
( chuckles )
No one's going to
let me live that
one down, are they?
No.
You know, now that
you're a celebrity
you may want to think
about getting a new shirt.
Yeah? Well...
I'm short on options.
Besides, the dry cleaners
keeps losing my stuff.
What'd you get?
Grocery bag
with a red smudge.
GRISSOM:
Good. Fume it.
Tell Sara and Warrick
to grab a couple shovels
and dig in, too.
( sighing )
( laughter )
MAN:
Who wrote this?
You're kidding me, right?
"Nick Stokes,
Crime Stopper."
( both chuckling )
You went Hollywood
on me, man.
And I quote,
"In his off time
he enjoys creating
and inventing toys."
That's fascinating.
What kind of toys
do you make, Nick?
I thought I got my hands on all
those departmental newsletters.
Where'd you get those?
Greg.
Yeah, that figures.
All right, listen,
Griss wants us
to divide and conquer.
Blond hair
for you, Warrick.
I do love a blond.
Sara
you're on phone records.
Yay.
Hey, I wasn't done
reading that.
Yes, you are.
( chuckling )
We know two things for certain.
Jane Galloway died
from a lack of O2
and she is
a natural blond.
What are you looking at me for?
Sorry.
So, what--
suffocation?
It certainly looks that way.
Uh, petechial
hemorrhaging in the eyes,
deoxygenation
led to cyanosis,
hence the blue lips...
blue fingertips
and blue face.
GRISSOM:
No ligature marks
on her neck.
If she had struggled
with her assailant
that effort alone could have
limited her oxygen intake
causing further O2 depletion
of the brain.
Easy kill.
Sexual assault?
No physical findings.
You'll have
to check the kit.
So, he murders her, poses her
yet he doesn't rob her
or rape her.
So, what's his agenda?
How's that platinum blond
coming?
Wrong question.
Come on, Greg
I'm not getting
anything out of Trace.
I was hoping you
could help me out here.
I took a snip, ran a crossed
immuno-electrophoresis.
Didn't pass.
Not hair?
Not human?
What are you reading?
This is Pink.
Pink, this is Warrick.
Do you know how hot you are?
Ssss!
Bet I know someone
who's hotter
and I'm not talking
about looks.
Yeah?
Yeah.
How mad is he?
Watch your back.
Heard you were
looking for me?
Greg. Come here.
I want to talk to you
for a sec.
Come on.
What's up?
Stop invading my privacy, man,
I don't like it.
I'm just trying
to do my job around here.
I don't need
the extra attention.
Okay. But, I mean,
you are the one
who's doing the
"Forensic Spotlight"
in the department
newsletter.
I didn't
do anything, man.
Someone from the community
wrote a letter of commendation.
Public Affairs
ran it. Cool?
Cool.
( pats Greg on the back )
( sighing )
So, uh, what
are you fuming?
Plastic bag
from the crime scene.
I'm trying to get lucky--
see if I can get
some prints off it.
Did she die of suffocation?
( muffled screams )
Did some digging
on Jane Galloway.
Her boyfriend had
a TRO against him.
And according
to the phone records
the guy called Jane 13 times
the day of the murder.
And that's 13 times
too many
according to
the restraining order.
We're going
to check out his house.
I'll be on my cell.
Grissom,
you got a second?
I got a mystery.
GRISSOM:
No Becke Line.
Yeah.
Hair refracts light
under cross polarization
but glass doesn't.
Well, it's not a hair.
It's a synthetic fiber.
Glass-- what do you
think, fiberglass?
Maybe.
This could be
a lot of things.
You'll figure it out.
( pounding on door )
Looks like the boyfriend
skipped out on us.
( sighing )
Hey, Brass?
Isn't that his car?
Control,
this is P-9241
requesting backup
and medical assistance.
The 1800 block
of Newhaven Road.
Possible 419.
DISPATCHER:
P-9241, copy.
( gasping )
BRASS:
All right,
all right.
Get out of the car,
get out of the car.
Sit down
on the ground.
Sit down,
sit down.
Sit down;
just sit.
Sir, are you okay?
You all right?
You seem injured.
No, I'm all right.
Are you Adam Piorio?
Yes.
Any idea how you got this blood?
I don't remember.
We're going
to take you to a place
and help you
remember.
Let's start again.
What happened last night?
I'm telling you,
I don't know.
Adam, we're analyzing the blood
that we found on your shirt
with the blood
of your girlfriend.
It's going to tell us everything
that we want to know.
Look, we broke up
a few weeks ago.
She...
She started acting weird
for no reason.
She had a TRO against you.
Something must have happened
to spook her.
She changed overnight.
She... she wouldn't return any
of my phone calls.
She started calling in sick
at work.
Barricading herself
in her own house.
So, you went to Jane's
house. What next?
We started arguing.
Open this door.
What do you mean
I can't come within
1000 feet of you?
Open the door.
Stay away from me!
I was afraid she was going
to call the cops, so I-I left.
SIDLE:
Well, that's interesting
because according to her phone
records, she never did...
call the cops.
BRASS:
But you called
her 13 times.
Once, you're in love.
Twice, you're obsessed.
More than three,
you're a stalker.
We just broke up.
All right, I was...
I was rolling on E last night.
Give me a break.
Adam?
That's not all
you were taking last night.
I was on a lot of stuff
last night. I was a space cadet.
I'm not a murderer.
Blood doesn't match our victim.
The girlfriend
of a Ricco
Manzo filed the police report
last night.
It seems that Adam here
put Ricco in the hospital
with a broken nose
from a fight
at Bar 9-1-1.
BRASS:
Well, that's
a lucky alibi.
Roll him out of here.
You've got mail.
Horndog?
That's a blast from the past.
What did your prom date say
when you called her?
She said that she
was cleaning out
the attic one day
stumbled upon them
thought she'd
send them to me
for a laugh.
You think she's a suspect?
No. She lives
in Bosnia, man.
Maine or something.
She's got three kids.
What's she going to do,
fly in for murder?
( chuckles )
Stranger things have happened.
I don't know.
Something in
my gut tells me
it isn't right.
Hey, what if somebody from
work tapped into my e-mail?
No.
Yeah. Maybe I forgot
to log off one day.
No. You're tripping.
No. I'm serious.
Somebody had to
have read my e-mail.
Change your password.
I already did.
How does this relate
to the case?
Well, he was an eyewitness,
sort of.
I mean, he says he had a vision
of Jane Galloway's murder
hours before it happened.
He's a psychic?
Well, he has details.
He has details
that weren't on the news
or the press release.
Mr. Pearson.
Sit down.
Captain Brass
tells me that, uh
you had some
sort of "vision"
regarding Jane
Galloway's murder.
Yes, I did.
What kind of vision?
Screaming face
in a plastic womb.
Blood shower.
Anything else?
Three hearts beating very fast.
Two large, one small.
( screaming )
( dog barking )
GRISSOM:
Okay.
Thank you.
This is your
eyewitness?
The dog didn't make it,
did it?
What about Jane's
work history?
Secretary
at a brokerage firm.
About three weeks
from the day of her death
she took a leave of absence.
Medical records?
She saw Dr. Slater.
Had a prescription
for Valium and Librium.
Severe anxiety due
to personal reasons.
One day back from leave,
Jane quits her job.
No notice.
Hotel receipts show
she checked into the Monaco
for two nights.
A week before that
she goes on a frightened woman
shopping spree.
Hardware shop receipts
for locks.
Locksmiths.
Alarm installations.
Phone screeners.
The voice on her
answering machine-- electronic.
She changes
her telephone number.
She cancels all
but one of her credit cards.
It's as if she's trying
to make herself disappear.
Make no mistake.
Jane Galloway was being stalked.
Emotional terrorism
at its finest.
And her boyfriend had an alibi?
Here's the, uh, worst part.
Uh, I ran a phone check
on all her incoming calls.
Guess where
they were coming from.
Inside her house.
BRASS:
So I ran
Merlin's, uh, credit card
with his
permission.
Do you know where he was
the night of the murder?
Monaco Hotel.
Room 834.
Guess who was in
the adjoining room?
Jane Galloway.
Why didn't you tell us
you were staying here?
I didn't know
she was your victim.
According
to the front desk
you placed a call
to Jane Galloway's room at, uh
9:12 p.m.?
Lasting 21 seconds?
May I ask what you two
were talking about?
Energy.
( phone rings )
( gasps )
Hello?
I'm calling from the next room.
I don't mean to alarm you
but I'm feeling some negative
energy coming from your room.
S-she wouldn't talk to me.
I-I get that a lot.
But evidently, you
called her back.
Yes, she picked up,
and hung up.
Phone records say that
she received three calls.
Twice, I believe.
The front desk
records also show
that she checked
out that night.
And you checked out
shortly thereafter.
Why?
Well, she was suffering,
and I shared her fear.
Seems my
intuition was accurate,
as it turns out.
( sighs )
You don't believe me, do you?
Mr. Pearson, I'm
a scientist.
And I am a clairvoyant.
You see science
without abstractions.
I see visions with abstractions.
Am I less credible than you
Mr. Grissom?
These visions that you've had
in the past...
nothing specific triggered them?
Sometimes a touch or an object.
Fear?
Sure.
And you were
hoping to heal Jane Galloway?
I was only hoping
to comfort her.
I'm bound by that obligation.
So, these visions you
told us about earlier?
These are the only ones
you've experienced?
I have more.
( inhaling )
Locks.
Three locks.
Hanging... ghosts,
hanging ghosts.
Chest to back, back to chest.
A frames, wooden beams
church dark.
( sighs )
That's it.
Are these the three locks
you saw?
Yeah... they-they seem
different, though.
Perhaps it's
the angle.
What do you mean?
It seemed...
I was looking down on them.
Is this what
you saw?
Yes...
only it was...
From above.
( cell phone ringing )
Hello?
GRISSOM:
Pick a number
between two and five
and indicate it
with your fingers.
Why?
Please, humor me.
Four. Thank you.
Where are you?
Look up.
Jane's bedroom closet
has a door to the attic.
( phone rings )
Warrick.
Warrick, Grissom.
You know that blond fiber
we were looking at?
Fiberglass insulation--
comes in pink and yellow.
But you already knew that.
Is that why you're calling?
Not really.
I was checking a phone line.
But good work.
Yeah.
( grunts )
GRISSOM:
He tapped into
her second line.
He's got a peep hole
into every room.
They're labeled.
Uh, Gil, there's a, uh...
Yeah.
He's our psychic-- Mr. Pearson.
Right.
You know, I don't
think this thing
was about sex at all.
I think it was about control,
voyeurism.
Jane was like his,
uh, little goldfish.
Then why kill her?
And why...
leave all this stuff behind?
Interesting collection of toys.
Digital camera...
with a fiber-optic lens.
Night vision goggles.
Digital recorder.
I'm guessing he's got
microphones all over the house.
Probably.
( sighs )
Same question--
how did he get in?
Well, this only opens
from the inside.
So at some point
it's possible that Jane
let him in.
Thank you.
So.
Who do we let into
our homes every day?
Well,
pretty much
if you got
a uniform on
you can walk right in
the front door.
So, we go through
her bills
and we see
which utility companies
worked on her house.
Luna Cable.
Good company,
same as mine.
150 channels.
I'm telling you,
you got to get it, man.
The last three weeks
have been heaven.
( knocking )
Mr. Crane?
Nick Stokes,
Criminalistics.
( cell phone rings )
Hello.
Hello? I-I can't
hear you.
H-hold on.
Mr. Crane, your door's open.
Just want to...
ask you a couple questions.
WARRICK:
I can hardly
hear you.
We're at the, uh,
satellite guy's house
that installed Jane's cable.
( rustling )
( screams )
Nick!
Patrol.
Request immediate backup.
Immediate backup.
Officer down.
I need emergency
medical assistance right now!
Emergency medical assistance.
Nick!
Oh, God. Nick. Nick.
Concussion
two cracked ribs
sprained wrist,
five stitches to the forehead.
It could have been a lot worse.
But he's going
to be all right?
He needs rest.
But I don't see
why he can't go home
relatively soon.
Thank you, Doctor.
Damn it.
Grissom, this guy
was right there.
I could have had him.
You helped out Nick.
That was the right thing to do.
Doesn't feel
like the right thing.
WILLOWS:
You know,
Nick was alone.
The stalker could have
killed him and didn't.
Yeah, I wonder why.
Let's go back
over there.
I'm going
with you.
No, no.
You need to calm down a little.
Talk to Nick when he wakes up.
GRISSOM:
Nigel Crane, age 37.
No criminal record.
Working for Luna Cable
for 11 years.
No immediate family,
lives alone.
Last seen by coworkers
two days ago.
No priors.
Not a stick of furniture...
except for a computer
and a chair.
( grunting )
( gasping )
What the hell?!
He lives up there.
Not down here.
Works, sleeps
changes his clothes...
everything in the attic.
He looks down
on the world
separating himself
from others.
Fascinating, really.
Well...
you're going to love this.
Red dye.
Yup.
Now what?
Dinner and a movie?
CRANE:
Walking pukes.
Soulless, lost, useless,
sick puppets.
Little sheep
looking for direction.
Gullible.
From an airplane
they used to look like ants.
And now...
they're all ants
all the time.
You squash one.
WILLOWS:
Well.
Just think,
this is only tape one.
They all start running
around in a panic.
DOCTOR:
Now, these painkillers
are the real deal, okay?
Don't overdo it.
Plenty of rest.
No work for
at least a week.
SIDLE:
Will do,
thank you, Doctor.
NICK:
The gloves,
you find them?
Catherine thinks
he might have
got away with them.
But, uh, Grissom
did find
some wacky video
collection.
Of what?
Now, did you not
just hear the doctor?
You're supposed to rest.
We're on it, okay?
Yeah, relax, Ironside.
CRANE:
I see you, Jane.
Do you feel me?
( tape squeaks forward )
You...
you will never get me.
No.
Not the way he does.
And we all get what we deserve.
And I...
I got a friend.
How's it going?
How's Nick doing?
Well, groggy.
How's the epic?
Epic.
Gotten any clues as to where
this guy might be?
Not really,
not yet.
Archie, freeze it.
Do you see that
behind him?
To the left hand
of the screen?
Can you focus the pixels?
( typing )
Okay, we're now
at 26 times magnification.
Rendering
at 1086 lines.
That's the
Crime Stopper article.
GRISSOM:
Isn't our newsletter
for in-house only?
Do you think he knows Nick?
He may know him well enough
to read his e-mail.
Found that photo
of Nick and his prom date.
Used Jane Galloway
to emulate the photo?
GRISSOM:
Why would he do that?
Why Nick?
Nick has satellite cable, right?
Lunar Cable-- 150 channels.
Wait a minute
we've been doing this
the wrong way.
We need to see the last tape.
( shuffling tapes )
Archie, play this.
It's like he, he's...
he's the kind of guy
I always wanted to, um...
to be.
And that's why it's
so great, because...
we're friends now.
I feel like I can count on him,
you know?
And you know what?
I think if it came
right down to it
he would lay his life down
for me.
Ask him.
A-A-Ask Nick.
Nick
would you let me
stop your heart?
( knocking at door )
Who is it?
My name is Pearson.
Morris Pearson.
We haven't met.
I worked with
Mr. Grissom
on the Jane
Galloway case.
It's almost 1:00 in the morning.
What do you want?
I've had more visions.
Please let me in.
Yeah, maybe
but look...
Please, please
let me in.
I can't just
let you in my...
Please, please, please...
Hey, hold up.
I saw this house.
I saw this house,
I saw the number
I saw the street name.
Something
is wrong here.
Something terrible
is going to happen here
Sir...
I can feel it.
You're going
to have to leave.
Please, please,
listen to me.
Get out of here.
Listen to me!
I saw the address.
I saw this
address.
You saw my address?
Yeah, but that's not it,
that's not it.
I saw, I saw...
I saw crashing.
I saw...
falling and
crashing-- I saw
somebody seeing
through the back of his head.
I don't know, I don't know...
Green tea.
Does that mean anything to you?
Green tea?
I don't know.
( phone rings )
Just...
Hello?
GRISSOM:
Nick, listen, he's
been in your house.
Who?
Nigel Crane, the stalker.
Brass is one his way
with two uniforms
to put at your door.
Yeah, well, I'm not alone.
What?
Your psychic's here.
Good, keep him there.
Mr. Pearson.
( gun cocking )
Mr. Pearson...
you back here?
( wood creaking )
( thumping )
( footsteps )
( coughing )
Oh, man.
You got to...
you got to watch who
you let in here.
Guy was snooping around
all over the place.
You know, smart move.
Spare gun.
Ah.
Keep it right
by the phone
right?
Right next to your address book
and, and take out menus.
Cops are on their way.
Yeah.
I heard that.
You wearing my clothes?
Oh, yeah.
I'm...
( deep exhale )
You know, I-I-I picked
these up at the dry cleaners
and I...
I hope you
don't mind.
It's just that...
I'm sorry
I, I just get a little confused
about what's yours
and what's mine.
You know what?
I'm a little confused
here myself.
Uh, why don't you
refresh my memory.
When did we meet?
Sports package.
150 channels.
I-I-I even threw in
a few movie channels.
Free.
We talked, like, forever.
I mean, it's like
I knew you my entire life.
You installed my cable.
Yeah.
The... the minute
I met you
I knew we connected.
Because you told me
what you did
and I knew exactly
what you were talking
about, because...
that's what I do.
I do it, too.
You know, I observe people.
I-I-I notice everything
about them.
I watch them.
All the time.
Like you watched
Jane Galloway?
Jane was cool.
But, um, it would have never
worked out between us, you know.
Never.
I mean, she had
a boyfriend
and she was
kind of stuck up.
And you know what,
she would have
totally, totally
gotten between us.
So, you know,
consider that a gift.
A gift?
Yeah.
Prom night.
Your date.
Melissa.
Bent over the toilet
puking her guts out.
Is that ringing any bells, huh?
Yeah.
You know, I mean,
Jane's hair
was the wrong color but,
you know
obviously, I fixed that.
Because I know how much
you love redheads.
You know, you...
You mentioned her name
in your sleep.
You watch me sleep?
You, um...
You want to open him up?
Hmm?
No, no,
it's, uh...
it's not my job.
You should know that.
It's the coroner's gig.
Are you humoring me, Nick?
No.
You know...
We made friends that day
and every time since
you just blew me off.
Do you know that?
You just
completely blanked me.
You are so self-absorbed.
I was right in front
of your face.
Manners, Nick!
Manners!
Hey, now, Nigel, now
we got a DB here, huh?
You're going to help me with
the crime scene, right?
No, no, I'm going to...
I'm going to give you
a brand-new one.
I'm going to do
better than that.
I'm going to give you
the best you ever had.
Stand up, Nick.
Stand up.
Nick, you know what
a nine-millimeter slug
does to a skull at close range?
You know?
Blow it right
apart, right?
Brains like strawberry swirled.
Whipped cream, everywhere.
And you.
You'd have to scoop
that stuff up, right?
Yeah, little pieces of
skull and bone and brains.
All in individual baggies with
the victim's name on the label.
You know I don't want
to disappoint you, Nigel
but this isn't the first time
I've had a gun in my face.
How do you want this
to end, Nigel?
How do I want this to end?
I want you to be able
to remember my name.
( grunting )
Gun!
Get down! Get down!
Put him down.
Cuff him.
Get him secured.
Hey.
( breathing heavy )
It's, it's done.
All right, yeah.
I am one, and who am I?
I am one,
and who am I?
I am one, and who am I?
I am one,
and who am I?
I am one, and who am I?
I am one,
and who am I?
Why me?
I don't think it was
about you, Nick.
Or Jane Galloway,
for that matter.
I think it was
more about
Maslow's Hierarchy
of Needs.
His premise is that social
beings strive to belong.
In Nigel's mind
Jane Galloway was someone
he could control
which was okay
for a while
but you...
you were someone he
could actually become.
See, Maslow's
fifth tier
of the Hierarchy
is Self-Actualization.
I am one, and who am I?
The problem for Nigel
is that you would
have to die in order
for that to happen.
Or else he would.
25 years to life, Nick.
It's over.
It's not over for me.
It's over for Jane Galloway.
Well, we should
get back to the lab.
GRISSOM:
Yeah.
I am one, and who am I?
I am one,
and who am I?
I am one, and who am I?
I am one,
and who am I?
I am one, and who am I?
And who am I?