You'll like this apartment.
My wife says
it's the best of the lot.
Now, the tenants
moved out kind of quick
so I don't normally
show apartments
before I've had
a chance to look, so...
use your imagination.
WOMAN:
Oh, my God.
Call 911.
I worked in a slaughterhouse
one summer.
Looked a lot like this.
The lease is in the name
of Clifford Renteria.
He lived here
with his girlfriend
till they snuck out
in the middle of the night.
Gee, I wonder why.
For all we know,
this is animal blood.
BRASS:
Yeah, sure.
Deer, sheep, llama.
A deer hunter comes home
from the mountains drunk
decides to play butcher
clean his kill.
Chops his game up
into oven-sized pieces for the winter.
I mean, what does he care?
He's renting.
BRASS:
Victim's human.
And a human has only
eight pints of blood.
So, whoever the victim is...
is now dead.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
SIDLE:
Any uniformity in the spray?
GRISSOM:
Well, by and large,
the average diameter
is about one millimeter.
SIDLE:
Blood drops this size
are characteristic of
high-velocity impact
like gunshot trauma
but there's no bullet
strikes on the walls...
ruling out murder by gun.
Just acquaint yourself, Sara.
Don't interpret just yet, okay?
All right.
Show time.
This looks
like a multiple.
More than one vic.
Acquainting myself.
Check out these "voids."
That's the real evidence.
Couch?
We've only got 30 seconds
till this luminol disappears.
Television, maybe?
A magazine?
Triangle...
coat rack?
Guys...
What do you think
that is?
Looks like it could be
an electric saw.
High-velocity,
small spray.
( radio static )
( garbled radio dispatch )
RADIO DISPATCHER:
Pine Ridge Command,
go to white fire three.
Dozer tender 1441.
Air attack 140.
O.V. tens on order.
Report to Willow Springs.
Zero humidity,
record highs.
'Tis the season.
You left out the hot firemen.
Hi.
Hey.
I don't even know where
to start with this one.
Take a look at that.
A scuba diver...
up a tree.
Wow.
WILLOWS:
I wonder how he got up there.
STOKES:
He couldn't have
climbed up there
with all that crap on.
He got up there somehow.
Well, you know...
Lake Mead is just
over the hill
and the copters
are dropping water.
( helicopter whirring )
You're serious?
That's a total urban legend.
We're scientists, Nickie.
No way that happened.
Okay.
And I suppose
you believe in Santa?
After today...
oh, yeah.
When I said Cliff Renteria
and his girlfriend
skipped out in the middle
of the night
I didn't have the whole story.
I haven't seen Alison
in over a month.
Any idea where
she might be?
Renteria said
she left town.
So you noticed
that she was gone?
I manage the complex.
I notice everything.
Did you notice
if Mr. Renteria
left a forwarding
address?
No. He just wrote
the letter saying
he was moving on.
Listen, if you find him
you tell him he is not getting
his deposit back, okay?
The blood'll never come out.
Hopefully not.
That's all the evidence we have.
( helicopter whirring )
What do you make of that void?
Green vegetation.
There's a consistent burn
over this whole area.
Except for that one spot.
Well, the chief says the
original fire was a class "C."
Downed power line.
Winds keep shifting
hot spots breaking
out all over.
STOKES:
Well, well...
Downed power line, huh?
Good eye.
STOKES:
Matchbook time-delay device.
Don't touch it.
It'll disintegrate.
That's the only reason
I carry this stuff.
WILLOWS:
Hair spray.
Extra hold?
The difference between
walking and running.
Guy lights a cigarette,
sticks it in a matchbook
takes a stroll.
It buys an arsonist
a five-minute head start.
Mm-hmm.
Monaco Receiving.
Clifford Renteria,
Platform Manager.
Gee, Brass,
all in one shift.
I'm impressed.
BRASS:
Are you
Clifford Renteria?
Cliff.
Who are you?
Las Vegas Police.
With the Crime Lab.
Do you have
any knowledge
of the whereabouts
of Alison Scott?
She's in Canada
visiting her parents. Why?
We just came
from your old apartment.
We found some disturbing
evidence there.
Would you care
to explain that?
Hey, he had it coming.
I'll tell you that
right now.
Apartment stank, there were
flies everywhere, no water.
So I trashed the place.
Who had it coming?
The apartment manager.
The lazy bastard.
Serves him right.
GRISSOM:
Mr. Renteria
your apartment walls
are covered in human blood.
Are you aware
of that?
Yeah.
Do you have
an explanation?
It's my blood.
Your blood?
You got a stigmata?
No. I get nosebleeds.
Nosebleeds?
From hepatitis C.
I got blood to spare.
My nose is like Old Faithful.
Finally came in handy.
You expirated blood
from your nose
all over your apartment walls
to get back at your manager?
Yeah.
I hope I made
his cleanup job hell.
That's not supposed
to go anywhere.
This guy blows
ten quarts of blood
from his nose onto his wall?
You want to ask
for a demonstration?
He's lying.
Expirating from your nose
would leave oval-shaped
blood patterns.
The ones we found
in his apartment
were V-shaped.
Mr. Renteria.
We're going to need
a sample of your blood--
from your arm,
not your nose--
and a visit
to your new apartment.
That's home to me now.
Been staying there
about a week.
Well, may we see your furniture?
Sure.
GRISSOM:
Electric saw.
Used to do some landscaping.
GRISSOM:
Interesting lamp.
Mr. Renteria, with
your permission
I'd like to move
some of your property
to my lab for
a closer inspection.
Hey, save me 250 a week
truck rental.
Keep it as long as you want.
I'll sleep in the break room.
That's after
you come down
and give us
that blood sample.
You check nosebleed's
tools yet?
No observable blood.
Not even with Pheno.
That's because
he probably ditched them
after using them
on the victim.
Now we've just got to
figure out which one.
How long did Firearms
give us these for?
24 hours, then we've got
to get them back. Clean.
Let's do it.
GRISSOM:
So?
DNA results, um...
16 samples from
the apartment walls
and the one we just took
from the guy's arm.
This cannot be right.
Hey, I always
double-check your stuff.
But all the results
are pointing one way.
What about the blood
on the lamp?
That is my next run.
Just a little backlogged.
Well, get through it.
I thought you said the blood
on those walls couldn't be his.
I also thought
the metric system
would catch on.
Look, everything
that starts
with a faulty premise
is bound to fail.
I saw "V" patterns
and I foolishly
ruled out the nose.
I told you I had
a condition, hepatitis C.
I was diagnosed
when I was 18.
And this relates
to your magic nose, how?
Hepatitis C
destroys the liver
and a whole host of
clotting functions.
Cliff, indeed,
has blood to spare.
Thanks for coming around
to my side.
Which way is out?
Nobody released you.
Mr. Renteria,
I can't sign
off on a case
until I fully
understand it.
So, let me get
this straight.
You had a beef
with your landlord
and you decided to pay him back
by blowing blood out
of your nose
all over the apartment walls.
Is that about right?
Yeah.
A day? A week?
A couple of months?
How long did this take?
I don't know.
About a month.
So, you get up
in the morning,
make coffee and go
"I think I'll blow some blood
on the kitchen wall today."
Get out of
the shower
grab your towel, go
"Hey, this looks like
a nice spot to expirate
a couple of pints."
It wasn't like that.
Something would set me off.
The disposal was backed up,
no hot water
the toilet was broken...
I knew the landlord
wasn't going to fix it.
So, you made your statement
through your nose?
I wasn't getting anywhere
with words.
Look, if it'll get me
out of here any quicker,
I'll show you.
Um...
It's really not that big a deal.
You might want to back up.
SIDLE:
Same high-velocity spray.
Same short "V" pattern, too.
Didn't you say expirating
through the nose
made oval patterns?
Yeah, well, as it turns out
our guy stands very close
to the wall
and blows almost sideways.
This is on the real.
You actually saw him do this?
Right through his Jimmy Durante.
Ambidextrous, both nostrils.
Great.
Our big murder's a nosebleed.
Oh, not necessarily.
Sample from the
nosebleed's lamp.
It's not his blood.
And I don't know
whose blood it is
but the Amelogenin
came back with something
pretty interesting: "XX."
Female blood.
Our guy's girlfriend
is still missing.
Two things which may have
nothing to do with each other.
Or everything.
So you got an ID
on the scuba guy?
Jacques Cousteau.
Kidding.
Coroner humor.
But I'll tell you
what I do know.
He didn't die in that fire.
No carboxyhemoglobin
in his blood.
Means he didn't inhale
any carbon monoxide.
Tells us he stopped breathing
before the fire started.
Guy was probably killed
someplace else and dumped.
Oh, he was dumped all right...
out of a chopper.
Right, Doc?
Victim's injuries are inconsistent
with a fall of that magnitude.
No fracture
of the pelvis
no compression of
the lumbar vertebrae
no shortening
of the body.
There goes your theory, Nick.
Good try though.
So what was the cause of death?
His heart stopped beating.
Heart attack... consistent with
being scooped out of Lake Mead.
The human heart beats
in a four-beat rhythm
like a fox-trot.
The two atria contract,
then the two ventricles.
Ba-boom, ba-boom.
So, what happened to this guy?
Commotio cordis.
Cardiac concussion.
The guy short-circuited.
It's rare, but I've seen it.
Couple of years ago
a Minor Leaguer
took a line drive to the chest.
Interrupted the impulse
to the heart
turning it into a bag of worms.
Fibrillation.
So, our scuba diver
took one to the chest.
Definitely.
He could've been clipped
by the chopper's bambi bucket.
Did you find anything
between his toes?
Like sand from...
Lake Mead.
Sorry, Nick.
But I did find something
between him and his wetsuit.
Soap residue.
Like he started to shower.
Soaped up
never soaped off.
Something on
your mind, Greg?
No. I heard
about your case.
Sounds interesting.
Yeah.
You want to make
yourself useful
drop this off at Trace.
Must be some kind of soap.
Robbins got me halfway there.
Bet it's liquid
dishwashing soap.
Yeah, state your source.
Well, you know
I used to do a little
diving myself actually.
Belize, Maui
Great Barrier Reef.
Okay, maybe I took that
one a little too far.
But the point is,
that these rubber suits
aren't very easy to put on.
Neoprene and skin
need a little romance
to get together.
And a capful of liquid
soap works like a charm.
So, you want to check
this safety valve?
Sealed closed.
And what about
the pressure gauge?
Hose melted.
Catherine found it at
the base of the tree.
It's 3,000 psi;
that tank was full.
Guess it's like
anything pressurized.
These things blow for
one of two reasons:
Too much air
or too much heat.
You just made yourself
useful, my friend.
Yeah?
Oh, yeah.
How?
What are we
looking for exactly?
Same thing we're
always looking for
evidence of a crime.
Failing that, we'll
have to release
this apartment.
What about Nose Bleed's
missing girlfriend?
You heard Brass.
He got ahold of Alison
Scott's parents in Canada.
They said
she never arrived.
They had no idea she was
even going to see them.
What if Nose Man blew blood
all over these walls
to cover up Alison
Scott's blood?
I don't see
any evidence of that.
You're not finding another layer
of blood under there?
No.
You don't think maybe
he offed his girlfriend?
( fly buzzing )
How many flies do you
count in this room?
15, give or take.
I counted four on my
first walk-through.
Fly spots.
Regurgitations.
Fresh.
Problem is
flies don't feast
on dry blood.
Place is sealed, and they don't
spontaneously generate.
So they're feeding
on fresh blood.
Could be a rodent, though,
or bad garbage.
Or it could be something
higher up the food chain
like Alison Scott.
The preponderance of
flies is in this room.
They can egress a space
less than .001 centimeters.
Behind you.
Vent.
Hey, coffee boy.
Where's my DNA?
Cigarette butt?
Match book time-delay device?
Hair spray?
Any of this sound familiar?
Bags under the eyes,
coffee cups, stress face.
Any of this look familiar?
I'm working on it.
Did Grissom put his stuff
in front of mine?
No.
I'm working on your case--
with Nick.
I just talked
with your partner.
Working this case
without me, huh?
Hmm?
Greg Sanders?
Let go my Grego.
He's a CSI wannabe.
Please.
Check out the bottom
of this tank.
Fissure.
We had a little
explosion here.
That explains a lot.
Acid etching.
Not bad.
Figure if I can get
the serial number
off the tank
get on the horn
with some surf shops
track the renter
through a credit card.
Pretty smart thinking
there, partner.
Well, we still haven't
ID'd the vic, but...
it's worth a shot.
Okay, N-4-0-0-2, let's see
what kind of lead you are.
Hi. Uh, whatever you're selling,
I have no interest, okay.
Maybe you should find out
what we're selling first.
I'm Catherine Willows,
Las Vegas Crime Lab.
Detective O'Riley.
Is there a Jerry Walden
lives here?
You're looking at him.
What?
Are you missing a scuba tank?
So, let me get this straight,
Mr. Walden.
You lent Bruce Skeller
a spare tank.
( sighs )
Yeah.
I just, I can't believe
what you're telling me here.
I mean, Bruce was
an experienced diver.
Well, he didn't exactly
die in the water.
Bruce and I were about
to break ground
on this project.
Really meant a lot to him.
You guys were
in business together?
We've been best friends
since we were kids.
We used to
build these forts together
like our imaginary casino,
you know?
Now we were going
to build the real thing.
We partnered up with this big
development company Adventures.
Excuse me.
You said that Mr. Skeller
was an experienced diver.
Why would he
be borrowing a tank?
Well, just because
somebody's experienced
doesn't make them any less
of a freeloader.
He was just down
on his luck.
But, as I say,
we were like brothers.
I mean, we shared everything.
What was mine was his,
what was his was mine.
But you just said
he didn't have anything.
Yeah, but he
would've, you know.
And I kept
telling him that.
I mean, that's
what kept him going.
And then this happened.
There used to be something here.
Oh, yeah, it's my coffee table.
Interesting furniture.
What is that, ash wood?
Yeah.
Is that what
the coffee table
was made out of?
Made them out of
the same piece of wood.
Where is the coffee table?
Oh, I sent it out
to get it refinished.
The guy said it would
be back in a week.
I, uh...
...think it needed
a little more than that.
Fly egg casings.
I thought I heard
some banging around.
You, uh, you
find my tenant?
You can contact Captain Brass
for that information, sir.
What do you got?
Either Paul or John.
A very important beetle.
The most important.
The Silphid Beetle
typically feeds
on decomposing human flesh.
There's a dead body
in here somewhere.
Mr. Evans...
...could you get permission
from the owner
to let us break
into these walls?
Our original warrant
didn't cover that.
Depends, how many walls
and what for?
We can't divulge that
but it may be...
all the walls.
In every room?
Yeah.
You CSI's going to pay
for the replastering?
We don't do that.
But you can submit a form
to the city for reimbursement.
Yeah, I'm still waiting
for my tax rebate.
I don't even have to bother
the owner with this.
He's not going to let you
bust out these walls.
Now what?
DNA lab.
I don't want to hear any
rumors that Paul is dead.
He may be the only
chance we have
of getting in these walls.
We already know this beetle
feeds only off
of human blood, so why
are we extracting
its stomach contents?
Not so.
According to Grissom--
Mr. Bug Guy
the Silphid beetle will actually feed on
any decomposing mammal.
So we need to show
human DNA
or we are not
going to get a warrant
to break down those walls.
Well, I hope he got
his grub before you
grabbed him up.
Where's Greg?
We need to get
this processed.
You know, I swear that guy
has a second job somewhere.
I'm, uh, all for
being alone, but...
Did you bring
the file?
Well, there goes
the foreplay.
It's in the car.
I hope you appreciate
that even as
District Engineer
it wasn't easy getting you
the original land deed.
Well, I know how
you love a challenge.
So, what'd
the property sell for?
Half a million bucks
an acre.
Is there anything
else that you need
to use me for?
Excuse me?
It's obvious that
you're not here for me.
You're here for yourself.
So let's not waste
each other's time, all right?
The property was owned
jointly by two men--
Jerry Walden
and Bruce Skeller.
At the time that
they bought it
it was a steal--
50 grand an acre.
Two years later,
Adventures Development
comes in, they start
buying up the surrounding parcels.
Your guys hold out,
until last week
and let me tell you,
they got top dollar.
Capitalist's wet dream--
buy low, sell high.
So they played it smart.
Well, one of them did.
From all I can tell
Jerry Walden was selling to
Adventures from the get-go
but his partner was a different
deal altogether.
He was a diehard
environmentalist.
A real tree-hugger.
You can say that again.
He saw the writing on the wall.
The urbanization of Lake Mead
and he spent every cent he had
trying to fight it.
When it comes down
to money versus the
environment
it's no big surprise
who's going to win.
So is there anything else
that I can do for you?
I'll see you.
This really frosts
my lizard.
I go out to the lake
to get away from
the casinos.
Well, there goes
jet-skiing.
What about the land deed,
Ronnie?
Oh, what I can
tell you about that is...
I'm impressed.
If it is a forgery,
it's a great forgery.
Van Gogh.
Nothing I can testify to.
What can you testify to?
Have you seen my VSC-4 machine?
No.
The original copy
of the land sale
agreement, okay?
Inks luminesce
at different
wavelengths.
At one wavelength
the signature
on the left
disappears.
At another wavelength
the one on the right
disappears.
Where'd it go?
I can bring it back.
What does it mean?
Whatever you make of it.
You've got
a legal document.
Two signatures--
notarized, the whole
nine yards.
The only thing
I can tell you
is your two guys
used separate pens.
Excuse me.
Yeah.
Silphid beetle--
test for presence of human DNA.
Is this definitive?
Yes, sir.
Did we get our warrant?
The beetle was full
of human DNA.
Brass got us a judge.
Let's go knock down some walls.
( coughing )
One wall down...
15 to go.
Sorry to interrupt your fun
but I have someone here
you might like to meet.
Jimmy Durante's
girlfriend.
You're Alison Scott?
I see Cliff's been
showing off again.
It's one of
the reasons I left him.
You left him?
I went back to my old
boyfriend in Chicago.
Miss Scott, we found
some blood on one of Cliff's lamps.
Stubbed my toe on that lamp
like once a week.
I begged Cliff
not to buy that thing
but he never listens.
GRISSOM:
Would you be amenable
to providing us with
a sample of your blood
for comparison purposes?
Sure.
But I'm telling you,
that's my blood.
Look, Cliff's...
well, he's a lot of things
but he's not a murderer.
Yeah, I still want a sample.
Warrick, would you?
Yeah.
You never get
a second chance
to make a first
impression.
A square of nine dots on paper
and you can only draw four lines
to connect them
without the pen
ever leaving the paper.
Right.
Think outside the box.
( doorbell ringing )
Yeah. What do
you want now?
We need to
take a look at your wall.
Hey, yo, Cat...
I'm going to forget
that you called me that.
Sorry.
Um, I've got a full profile on our--
a full profile
on our--
"your" torch.
I pulled his DNA off
of a cigarette butt.
Lucky for us, he's
a wet-lipped smoker.
So, you've done your job.
I got to go do mine.
Just give me something
we can compare it to.
These ash wood splinters
are from scuba guy's back?
Mm-hmm.
Embedded in his aconeus muscle.
After you paged me
I had Robbins comb his body.
They only get
us something
if they match Walden's
Ninja coffee table.
It's your theory.
WILLOWS:
Radial chains align.
Pores match.
Two pieces of ash wood,
one source.
So, Walden and Skeller
get into an argument
probably over their land.
Buy yourself a hundred acres
of rain forest, man!
Cash in your end!
I'm not going to sell!
Walden pushes Skeller
he falls back
onto the ash wood table.
But that's not
what killed Skeller.
Robbins said he took
a line drive to the chest.
Which escalates to a punch.
I'll call O'Reilly.
Scented candles, huh?
EVANS:
Food went rotten
wanted to cover the smell.
You've re-plastered
this wall recently?
I had rain damage.
Funneled down,
wrecked a five-foot area.
You wouldn't mind if I, uh...
examined your vent, would you?
( door opens )
BRASS:
You don't have to ask
his permission.
I got a new warrant
that covers his apartment.
Your wife being
missing put it over.
Funny you didn't
mention that before.
Did you know that your apartment
shares heating ducts
with the apartment next door?
Yeah, me and Cliff were always
fighting about the temperature.
So what?
Sara?
Yeah.
Hold up. Hold up.
Hold up.
Alklyd.
Blood on
the blanket.
And Dermestidae Masculatus.
SARA:
That's Latin
for you're hiding
a dead body.
BRASS:
What's the matter?
Didn't realize
how bad a corpse can smell
so you just decided to move it
around the place?
GRISSOM:
You can tell us where the body is
or we can, uh...
tear your place apart
piece by piece.
Whichever.
Look, you got squat.
Jerry and Bruce signed
with different pens.
You found a cigarette butt
at Lake Mead
and wood chips
on a tree-hugger.
Bottom line, you got
a dead guy up a tree
and you don't know
how he got there.
Hey, I'm just here
to make the arrest.
For what? What have you got?
Plenty.
Why don't we
just start from the beginning.
Bruce Skeller
didn't die in any fire.
He was killed
at your house.
He didn't pick up any ash
splinters from that forest.
It's all telarosa and oak
out there.
STOKES:
You had a dead body.
So, you decided to get creative.
Fire season, wet suit
liquid soap.
You drove out to the lake,
dumped the body...
...and lit up.
Not 'cause
you wanted a cigarette.
You lit up with a purpose.
This gave you a head start.
My guess is around, what,
five-minute mark.
You figured the fire department
would label it a hot spot--
relate it to the original fire
and the body would just burn up.
Still doesn't explain
how Bruce's body
wound up in that tree.
I didn't put him there.
Actually...
you did.
See, the thing you forgot
about a scuba tank is
it contains compressed air.
Too much heat... and
kaboom.
( sighs )
Rocket man.
Yeah.
Got to love this job.
I got a hollow section.
Let's open it up.
Damn.
Are we in the wrong
apartment again?
I don't know.
I don't mind being wrong.
I just don't think
I am this time.
Okay... start on
the floorboards.
I'll be outside.
You okay?
95.
Excuse me?
Normally my pulse is 70.
When it gets to 95
I realize how mad I am.
I have ten people working
around the clock on this thing.
You're too hard
on yourself.
No, no,
I'm not mad at me.
There's a body in there
and that guy knows where it is!
What's your pulse at now?
( sighs )
You want to take a walk
around the block?
Get some air?
No.
Clear your head.
I'm fine.
Okay.
Chalk, from plaster.
Oh.
Better go wash up.
Hey, Brass.
When did the shnoz say
he lost his hot water?
He wasn't exact.
You, uh, have no pressure
for your hot water.
I got a plumber coming
on Saturday.
Well, you know, my Uncle Herb
was a plumber.
I might be able to help.
Where's your installation?
In the basement.
But, really,
I got a plumber coming.
You got an electrician coming,
too?
A filtration system.
It softens the water.
Yeah.
Listen, you know, I
got a guy on retainer.
You don't have
to do this.
Yeah, well, I'm non-union.
There's no disruption
to the cold water line.
Hot water line...
water runs through
the filtration tanks first
and the water heater second,
right?
Yeah.
Why is it bypassed?
You've cut off the water
to the filtration tanks.
Something's wrong with that.
I had no choice.
( knocks )
Brine tanks are usually hollow.
Only got about eight inches of water at the bottom
for the salt mixture.
( knocks on tank again )
Does that sound hollow to you?
Oh...
Not enough candles in the world.
She nagged me.
She nagged you?
Hey, you want to grab
some breakfast?
No, thanks.
STOKES:
Come on...
we always get better service
when you're there.
I'm having breakfast
with a friend of mine.
STOKES:
You're keeping him alive?
Sara said you guys
already solved the case.
He did.
All right.