( phone ringing )
( phone continues ringing )
Grissom.
I'll be right there.
Please tell the doctor
that I have to reschedule
my appointment. Thanks.
She should be
right with... you.
Any I.D. yet?
BRASS:
Nothing but a blanket.
She live here?
We don't know.
Patrol called it in.
Well, whoever she is
she's not talking.
I think she just
ratted herself out.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
( background police radio
transmissions )
GRISSOM:
Drug use?
No visible track marks.
Tox screen
came up empty
except for botulin.
Food poisoning?
I'll know more when I
cut open her stomach.
Heard about the rat.
Hope he didn't have
any children.
Take a look at these tiny
puncture wounds in her forehead.
Indicates repeated injections.
You sure she's homeless?
Sometimes I'm not sure
of anything.
Educated guess: beautification.
She was injected
with pig botulism.
Botox...
the ultimate wrinkle cream.
How did it get into
her bloodstream?
Bad doctor.
Missed the muscle.
Shot directly into her
supratrochlear vein.
Amazing the advances
we make in science
and the primitive uses
we find for them.
People are still animals.
Signs of possible torture.
A lot of scaring.
Some old, some new.
What about the crater
in her check?
The dove-tail abrasion
of the margins
was caused by the scraping
of the handle of some weapon.
Tells me the blade was
completely inserted--
more than once.
There's no ligature
marks anywhere.
I'd think she would
need to be restrained
for something like
that, wouldn't you?
Give me a few hours;
I'll know more.
BROWN:
Show and tell.
Who?
Showing but not telling.
I found a day planner
in the shopping cart.
Mm-hmm.
It's written in code.
"T to the third power.
C 1023, minus ten
OK equals zero."
Looks like ginkwork.
It's the kind of thing
speed freaks do
when they've been up
for ten days straight
and they've already
taken apart the radio.
Yeah. I write everything down
in shorthand.
You couldn't read it.
Shorthand?
Keeps things in order.
You're not a control freak
or anything?
No.
Sara...
what's a homeless woman
doing with a day planner
and a $300 handbag?
That handbag costs $300?
Yeah.
How'd you know that?
I bought one for
an ex-girlfriend once.
Oh.
WILLOWS:
Dusty, we got no hits
on the fingerprints
and no one fitting
her description
has been reported missing.
Oh, she's not missing?
She's in my world.
I'm just mirroring some good
cheek on top of some bad cheek.
Okay.
I'll fix her forehead.
Her chin...
What a mess.
Mm-hmm.
I'm going to do
a little cloning here.
She actually had
a really nice complexion.
Perfect porcelain face.
What can you do about the hair?
It's a macro.
Whose hair do you
want her to have?
Blonde? Courtney Love?
Sounds good to me.
Let's give her some eyes...
blue.
I know her from somewhere.
You do?
Yeah.
Why are you showing me this?
The cover girl,
Ashleigh James--
she's your girl in
the shopping cart.
P.D.'s tracking down
her agency now.
Somebody wanted her dead.
They also wanted her ugly.
BRASS:
It's called
gentrification.
It's not doing anything
to gentrify them.
Tell that to the mayor.
The landlord's on vacation.
It's a good thing because
he's got a swimming pool
in his basement.
Ashleigh James apartment,
tub overflowed.
Who turned
the water off?
The first officer on the scene
found the door open.
After that,
he didn't touch a thing.
Yeah, what have you got?
Well, narcissus would be proud.
Very much a woman,
yet still a little girl.
I thought Doc Robbins
said the victim's tox screen
came back negative.
No, she wasn't a user.
But maybe the boyfriend was.
Let's hope he nicked himself.
Smells like mint.
Hey.
Find anything?
No. Nothing.
Anything out front?
Just a couple of homeless guys.
You, uh, you sure
this is the vic's?
You are what you eat.
( scraping )
Blood in the sink.
None on the floor.
Enema.
The secret life of women.
Don't generalize.
It's not very scientific of you.
You're right. I'm sorry.
Catherine...
Hey.
Ooh, pretty girl.
Yeah. Dangerous being
a pretty girl in this town.
Listen to this:
"Babe, he's not
good enough for you.
"He doesn't have
the history we do.
"You mean the world to me.
I know you'll live
to regret this decision."
Mm.
( camera clicks )
Not exactly the victim's style.
What? You don't
like cupcakes
and candy bars?
Hey, Gris!
Grissom!
Hey!
Where's he going?
I don't know.
( whistles )
BROWN:
Somewhere.
Come on.
♪ With eyes afire ♪
♪ I am drawn ♪
♪ I am drawn to her ♪
♪ Like a moth to flame ♪
♪ She leaves me now ♪
♪ Unbound. ♪
What are you doing here?
Contextualizing.
Shopping cart in the lab
is like a lion in a zoo.
I needed to see it
in its natural habitat.
Question:
How did Ashleigh James
get from her loft
to this underpass?
She didn't walk.
I'm pretty sure
she was pushed.
Grissom...
Is that Ashleigh James?
She was under her
own billboard.
Coincidence?
Somebody was making a point.
Hey.
You like crossword puzzles.
How are you
at deciphering codes?
Aren't you putting
the shopping cart
before the horse?
In order
to decipher a code
you need to know the alphabet
for the code.
In order to know the alphabet,
you need to know the author.
So, what's the cart telling us?
About the victim?
Well, the victim had
no relationship to the cart
except for the fact
that we found her in it.
I'm more interested
in the person
who used
to call this cart home.
Well, aside from the
leather day runner
and the Kate Swan bag--
which appear to be from
Ashleigh James's world--
you got mostly
collectibles.
Newspapers, review
journals, The Sun...
Various editions
going back several months.
A couple of tennis
rackets, a broom
an umbrella, a pot
I guess some kind of
glove or something.
I stand corrected.
I have a feeling
whoever owned this cart...
was an Ashleigh James fan.
Or a fanatic.
Well, it looks like
lover boy isn't home.
Maybe he wrote her a
letter and left town.
It's trash day.
I don't know, man.
We don't even have a warrant.
It's on the street.
It's fair game.
What did you find?
Photographic paper.
That's Ashleigh James.
( camera shutters clicking )
The cow says moo.
I can hold my
breath, I swear.
Lola, if you exhale,
you'll burst the bloody seams.
Rod, I'm sorry. I...
The fitting was two days ago.
Are you telling me
you couldn't keep your face
out of the trough
for 48 hours?
You want me to be your agent
you better start doing
your part, all right?
Rod Darling?
Las Vegas Police.
You're here
about Ashleigh, right?
Yeah.
Sorry about
what happened
but she wasn't
a client anymore.
I dropped her a
couple of months ago.
Did you forget to pack?
We found men's clothing
and personal items at her place.
She was a screwed up kid
looking for a father figure.
One minute
booking a photo shoot.
The next minute,
she's screaming for Daddy.
( grunts )
You son of a bitch!
All right, that's enough.
He killed her.
He killed her!
You're a psycho!
Rod did everything he could
to make her dependent on him
and only him.
She shut me out.
Is that why you
tore up her photograph
and tossed it in the trash?
You just don't get it, do you?
No, I don't.
I mean, I don't know.
I care about a woman,
I put her picture in a frame.
Maybe put it on my desk
but to tear it
up and throw it
in the garbage
with old cole slaw
that just doesn't say "love"
to me.
If you were in love
with an amazing woman
and you knew
she was throwing away everything
that was amazing about her
on some scum...
would you still want her picture
on your desk?
What did you use
to cut up the picture?
Same knife you
were waving
around at Rod?
The same knife you used
to cut up Ashleigh's face?
If you're suggesting
I was sleeping with her,
I wasn't.
You run out of drawer space
in your place?
I was protecting my asset.
I don't know what that means.
( sighs )
You can't drive a mile
in this town
without seeing her face
on a billboard
on the side of a bus.
Up in lights.
The mantra in
this business
is you protect what's bankable
in this business.
( clears throat )
So you didn't sleep with her.
You just "stayed over."
You brought a change of clothes
razor blade, toothbrush,
blah, blah, blah.
Yeah.
She needed constant attention,
supervision.
Leave her alone for a minute,
fill in the blank.
I got crabs.
Excuse me?
Take a look.
Pthirus pubis.
Feeds on human blood.
They prefer the pubic
and perianal regions
because their
legs are adapted
to grasp hairs which
are widely spaced.
They don't usually
nest in clothing.
But when the clothing
is being worn
by someone with substandard
personal hygiene...
Like one
of the victim's neighbors.
We have a high-end handbag
found
in a street person's
shopping cart
a jacket covered in crabs
in a closet full
of designer clothes.
What does that tell us?
Tells me the victim not only
had a visitor
but that visitor was
most likely homeless.
Tells me that whoever is missing
a shopping cart
is also missing his jacket.
Good stuff in here.
Hey, you got a smoke?
No. Sorry.
So, what good
are you?
It depends.
Ooh, hey.
Don't even think
that you can play me, my man.
I'm not playing.
I've got a gal named Sara,
and she would love that scarf.
What do you say?
Trade me.
Yeah. What the hell.
Hey.
Hey, hey, Mister.
Hey, Mister, that
is Tookie's scarf.
That is his scarf.
I gave it to him.
That is Tookie's.
Are you a taker, or are
you a giver, Mister?
I'm a trader.
I traded Tookie my jacket
for this scarf.
Yeah, and fleas can tell time.
I think fleas can tell time.
( muttering )
That's a nice ring.
I'll trade you.
I'll trade you for kit, too.
Now I can see
what the dark looks like.
I've been trying
to do that for years.
Greg ran the blood
on this scarf.
It matches the victim's.
How about the blood
on the knife?
Yeah, we got a
match, too, but
it's not the vic's.
BROWN:
Yeah, Mcbride
clipped Rod Darling's right hand
during his little hissy fit.
Blood's his.
And Mcbride's knife does not
match these wounds.
( sighs )
The tools were trade.
The weapons of beauty.
Yeah. If other people inflicted
as much torture
as women inflict upon themselves
there would be lawsuits.
Someone forgot to clean these,
too, for a long time.
Positive for blood
all over the place.
SANDERS:
Grissom...
I, uh, ran the DNA
on the epithelials
from the homeless lady's ring.
It's like Prince
and the Pauper.
No. Princess and the Pauper.
The princess is
a dead supermodel.
Yeah.
And her pauper sister could
be the killer.
Hot dog?
Relish?
Mm... with all those
preservatives, no, no, no.
I-I don't want to be preserved,
thank you very much. No.
I mean, I mean
do you know
what-what relish
can do to your
insides, huh?
I'd have to investigate.
Yeah, well, you know,
you should.
I mean, you know
because our insides--
they can kill us.
So, you're pretty careful
about what you eat?
Yeah, you know,
you-you have to be
careful, you know
'cause what goes
down, you know
it's got to come out.
It's got to come up.
Out.
( chuckles )
Newton's theory twisted again.
Everybody's twisted.
How about your sister?
My-my sister didn't
have a sister.
Protein's good,
you know?
C-carbs are bad.
This is bad.
That's bad.
Hey, Cassie, you know that scarf
you gave Tookie?
Yeah, I know it.
Did your sister give that
to you, or...
did you steal it from her?
I should have stole it.
Because sh-sh-she stole from me.
What did she steal from you?
My life.
DARLING:
I admit I gave up on Cassie.
Washed my hands.
Ashleigh was the only one
who still gave a damn.
Get together with her
every couple of weeks.
Make sure she had a decent meal,
shower, clothes on her back.
And what did
you do for her?
Let me tell you something.
For every piece of meat,
there has to be a butcher.
( scoffs )
So, you led her
to the slaughter?
Free will.
Recognize this one?
That's Cassie.
It's the homeless sister.
How long ago
was this taken?
Three years.
See, Cassie got deep
into freebase.
No shortage of sleazebags around
to keep her supplied.
I knew she had the sister
in Wichita Falls.
All right, Cassie,
let's go.
Come on, chin up.
Colin, will you get in
there and get her hair
out of her face?
Don't touch me!
I hate this!
I hate this place!
I hate it!
I hate my life!
Get away from me!
( muttering )
One look... that was it.
Camera ate her up.
So, in Cassie's mind,
she was a victim here.
Makes sense that she'd be angry.
Angry was five flights up.
Cassie was an obsessed basehead.
Cocaine already
had her paranoid.
Once Ashleigh
started modeling
everything became
this big conspiracy.
Naturally,
yours truly was Satan.
Cassie threw her life away
and her sister Ashleigh
recycled it.
GRISSOM:
It's like a crossword
puzzle, isn't it?
Once you pick it up,
you can't put it down.
And go home? No way.
You know, this Day Runner
belonged to Ashleigh.
"BFJ3".
BF: Bellagio fountain.
J3? Date?
January 3rd?
June 3rd? July 3rd?
Uh, third "J" month, July?
That's what I
thought at first.
Parking space
in a parking garage?
Nope. Once you pick it up,
you can't put it down.
J3... J3...
City or state grid map?
You're cold.
What's one thing
a model always knows?
Who's shooting her.
Three Js. Jay Jay Jarrett.
Who?
Famous photographer.
Compliments of P.D.:
Ashleigh James's
employment contracts
for the last year.
And, as an aside
she stopped working
two months ago.
Why?
Good question.
( sighs )
Maybe the answer is in
one of these pages.
BRASS:
Nobody could blame you
for being mad, Cassie.
I mean, your sister took
your career
and you wanted to get back
at her.
If you couldn't have success,
she couldn't either.
Isn't that right?
The v-victims have victims, too.
So, which one of you
is the victim?
I-I know... you know,
I know, I tried to warn her.
About the in-in
and-and outing
and the...
and the pick-pick.
And the-and the
and the counting
the counting and the counting.
I mean, I did, I tried.
That's why I tried to really,
really save her.
I mean, I tried to save her.
You tried to save her?
Your sister?
Right. She could
never be, you know...
she could never be...
pretty enough.
And she could never
b-be... skinny enough.
And sh-she could never be...
perfect enough.
And sh-she could never be
any-anything enough.
Hey, fat girl.
I got what you need.
I got it.
( snorting )
( whimpers )
( murmuring )
One more.
Good girl.
Mm.
I mean, that's why I did, I did.
I tried to stop her.
( choked up ):
I tried to stop.
( whimpering )
BRASS:
She's a needle freak.
She doesn't know
what she's talking about.
Yes, she does.
( moans )
You tried to stop yourself,
didn't you?
But you couldn't.
( yelling incoherently )
It's you!
You! You!
All right,
read her her rights.
I found blisters in
the back of her throat.
What? Forced oral?
That's what I thought
until I noticed worn
enamel on the tooth.
In conjunction
with this red mark
on the knuckle
of her middle finger.
Which made me realize
it wasn't sexual abuse.
Eating disorder.
( gagging sound )
She was bulimic and anorexic.
Which explains
the down on her skin.
Lanugo.
Characteristic of premature
babies and anorexics.
She doesn't seem that skinny.
Not this week.
Last week, or the week before,
who knows?
Binge-and-purge.
Till her entire system
is in a state of shock.
You know what's next.
Body starts feeding
on its own muscle.
Is that what killed her?
Uh, starvation and purging
weaken the immune system.
But cause of death: failed
kidney, fueled by septicemia.
Blood infection.
Caused by the injuries
to her face?
Probably, but she's been septic
for at least a month.
She has anemia
borne of chronic disease.
Her red cell count's low,
iron's low.
ESR is extremely high.
So she didn't just die.
She's been dying
for a long time.
( knocking on door )
What do you know that's good?
Cassie James's psych profile.
WILLOWS:
Classic paranoid
schizophrenic.
Which explains why
the interrogation room
was too hard on her.
For schizophrenics,
you know, the tighter the space
the more unbearable
the feelings tend to be.
Well, if you ask me
that's not the only
psych evaluation we need.
Ashleigh James?
( sighs ):
That poor girl.
Definitely lacking
in the self-image department.
She suffered from septicemia,
indicative of chronic abuse.
But...
what if Cassie
wasn't the one who inflicted
Ashleigh's facial wounds?
Well, we know it's not
the ex-boyfriend--
no evidence.
Not the agent--
wouldn't jeopardize an asset.
And if it's not Cassie,
who's left?
I don't know.
( sighs )
T 3. 1834 BC.
48 BF.
T 3...
1834 BC...
48 BF.
2 evo'd... 8G...
1 TU.
You must have been so desperate.
Cassie James's prints
from Booking on the left.
Prints from the loft
faucet on the right.
Do we have a prom date?
( computer key clacking )
All right, well...
Cassie James was
definitely in her
sister's apartment.
STOKES:
Hey, man.
What you eatin'?
Little college cuisine.
That stuff will
kill you, you know.
Hasn't killed me yet.
Grego, find any time
between meals
to check out
Grissom's scrapings?
You mean Ashleigh's
fingernail scrapings?
Yeah.
And?
Got a match.
To Cassie, her sister.
No. To the vic.
Ashleigh?
Yeah. The DNA under her
fingernails was her own.
Excuse me.
So what I realized was
bulimia is a zero sum disease.
That's why she has a plus sign
over here
and a minus sign over there.
Whatever went in had to be
exactly canceled
by what went out.
You're talking about BDD:
Body Dysmorphic Disorder.
Yes. One theory suggests
it's neurobiological.
Another psychological--
that people with extreme sexual
or emotional anxiety
unconsciously displace
their feelings
into the arena of appearance,
because it's more manageable.
You feel like crap,
blame your face.
Or your skin,
or your hair
or that zit
on your forehead.
I knew this dancer.
Every night she'd stare
at herself in the mirror
for three hours.
Meticulous grooming,
when a person suffers from BDD
becomes
a destructive compulsion.
There's one line
in her daybook
that keeps repeating
over and over
and over again: "I'm not even."
So you're saying she knew
she was slipping.
No. She literally means even.
A large number of BDD sufferers
are convinced that
they're not symmetric.
That one side of their body
or their face
doesn't match the other.
All animals prefer symmetry
in their mates.
The male Japanese scorpion flies
with the most symmetrical wings
gets the most mates.
BROWN:
So, really
we're not talking about
being beautiful at all.
In terms of entomology
being beautiful
is about being even.
It signals the fitness
to procreate.
STOKES:
So, we're not really
talking about looks.
We're talking about
survival of the species?
The bottom line
is the same:
control and perfectionism.
That's what her
code was all about.
Let's take "HBWC/3, 1590 BC,
90 BF, 3930 S, 114 TC."
Three hamburgers with cheese.
Content 530.
530 times three
is where she gets 1590 BC.
That's BC for "bad calories."
And at 30 grams a pop
90 grams of BF.
Bad fat?
Yeah.
The rest of her formula
involves sodium,
total carbohydrates
and the actual weight
of everything she ate.
And so,
she was, uh...
operating like a scientist
seeking a perfect formula
to take her pain away.
Or disappear altogether.
Which brings me to
the minus side of her equation.
She would write down
the number of times
she t'u'd, threw up,
in this case twice-- or evo'd.
"Evo'd"?
Moving her bowels.
The directions
on her disposable enema box
use the term "evacuate".
So, after
her burger binge
she "3 evo'd, 14 G,
2 t'u'd, 9 G, 3 #1."
She evo'd three times
but her calculations
didn't stop there.
"G" stands for grams.
14 gram... wait a minute.
You're telling me
that she weighed her bowel?
WILLOWS:
Yeah.
We bagged it.
SIDLE:
Input and output
down to the last quarter gram.
Well, that makes sense
why the blood and skin
under Ashleigh James's
fingernails is a perfect match
to Ashleigh James.
She attacked herself.
I mean, Ashleigh was convinced
that everything about her
needed to be fixed.
The real problem
was inside her head.
She couldn't deal with that
so she tried to fix the outside.
Hence, the digging and picking
and purging and bleeding.
To us, it would be torture.
To her... some sort of release.
Which is why Rod cut her loose.
She was no longer bankable.
Also why Frank was so angry
at Rod.
Yeah, he destroyed
Frank's vision of her.
So the victim and the killer
became one and the same.
The very nature
of addiction--
whether it be self-medicating
herself or self-mutilating--
is that the very behavior
we use to survive it
becomes a behavior
that ends up killing us.
STOKES:
But wait, that
still doesn't answer
how Ashleigh ended up in
a shopping cart by the freeway.
Well, the fingerprints
explain that.
( crying )
I think Cassie was trying
to take care of her sister.
She pushed her
to a place
where she thought
she'd be safe.
Where she thought
she could see herself
for how beautiful
she really was.
What happened to these girls?
I'm sorry about your sister,
Cassie.
The dead don't bleed.
True. Death does have
some advantages.
Would you like me to help you
get into a shelter?
No, I would need a shelter
from a shelter.
No, no, no. Out here,
I can hunt and I can range
and I can find the things
that I need
out here.
I mean, you never know
what you need until you find it.
Or until you lose it.
I mean, all we are
is what we try
to get rid of.
Fat and newspapers
and loneliness
and cat food cans.
And there are going-away people
and there are left-behind people
but, you know,
everybody's secrets...
everybody's secrets
are the same.
Were you and your sister's
secrets the same?
My sister didn't
have secrets.
Her secrets had her.
That... I told you I didn't...
I don't know.
I mean, you know, y-y-you-you
can pick through a million lives
and never have one of your own.
Looking for things,
analyzing them...
trying to figure out the world--
that's a life.
You never know what you
need until you find it.
And the next thing I find
it might be the thing
that changes everything.
What will you do
when you find it?
Sleep...
the most perfect sleep.
( muttering )
( muted tires screeching )
( muted horn honking )
GRISSOM:
Obviously most of crime scene
investigation is about seeing.
But much of it
is about hearing as well.
Listening.
Knowing how to listen.
Not just to what people
are saying
but how they say it.
How their tone of voice matches
their facial expressions
or body posture.
So, even if I read lips
and know what they're
saying...
it's not enough.
We're both scientists,
Mr. Grissom
so let me tell you
the science.
You've got otosclerosis.
Basically, this means
a bony growth
has begun to form around
the base of the stapes.
What this does
is prevent the stapes
from moving
and passing vibrations
to the inner ear
effectively neutralizing
sound waves.
It's hereditary--
my mother.
Most doctors think so.
But there's no way to know
when it's going to show up
and there's no way to reverse it
once it does.
Right.
How long do you think?
I don't have that answer.