So what do you think?
I mean come on.
I earned this vacation.
You ever been married?
When it's good,
it's great.
When it's over,
it's even better, hmm?
I'm telling you, the seven
comes up every six rolls.
I've got
a system.
You know what
the casinos say
about guys
with systems?
What?
Welcome.
He doesn't know
what he's talking about.
Everything you need
to know about craps
is right in this book.
I was talking
to Shirley--
she said the only
way to make money
in that town is slots.
( rock music playing )
I'm up 1,500.
That's nice, dear.
Oh, I found it's pictures.
Now look at this.
( gasps )
Oh, look at him.
He's just learning
how to walk.
Here's another one
with his sister.
Oh, there it is.
You have
a beautiful family.
We've been blessed.
Yes, we sure
have been blessed.
Well, folks, we just
hit Mountain Pass.
Means we're about 40 miles
outside of Vegas.
Some of you
are going to be
driving back
with me.
Some of you are going
to be flying back
with all the money
you're going to win.
In any case
you just sit back, relax
we'll see if we can't
get you there
ahead of schedule.
Hey.
Want a nip?
No, I know my limits.
( tires squealing )
( screaming )
( screaming continues )
( garbled radio transmission)
Everybody stand by.
We do not touch
this car
until every victim
is off the bus.
I feel so useless.
It's still
a rescue operation.
We're not running
the show.
Not yet.
They do their job
and then we do ours.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
( indistinct voices over radio)
Mine are lined up
right over there.
WOMAN:
Walt?
Where's my husband?
Walter?
Walter...
All right, I want everybody
thinking worst case scenario.
The highway's finally ours.
Cones and pictures,
skid marks
ice patches,
loose asphalt
anything and everything.
BROWN:
All right.
It's a pretty wide
area up there.
Are we clear to
call in for help?
Every Las Vegas CSI
is on their way here.
Cadets?
Call them.
( sobbing )
( indistinct voices over radio)
WOMAN ( over radio ):
...1-25 Roger...
( beeping )
STOKES:
You the only
trauma doc?
That's right.
Lucky me.
I personally
black-tagged six.
Excuse me.
My line of work,
that's a bad night.
Yeah, mine, too.
That the bus driver
over there?
Big surprise.
Only person
on the bus
wearing a seat-belt.
Only one on a tour bus
required to wear one.
Thank you.
Hey. Got here
as soon as I could.
Whoa, what are you
doing here, Greg?
All hands on deck.
That was the call, right?
Crims on the scene.
Crims with field training.
Come on.
I'm capable.
He does no collection.
( beeping )
You're taking
my notes.
You didn't bring
a warmer jacket?
No.
( indistinct voices over radio)
MAN:
Listen, I'll, uh...
I'll do anything
that I can.
I just want to help.
Please.
No, sir, just, uh,
uh, stick around.
I'll be right here.
Thank you.
( engine revving )
( siren blares )
( constant whirring )
Hey. Uh, Larry Maddox.
Owns the bus company.
Got here quick.
That should tell you something.
Yeah, he coughed up
the passenger manifest
including the driver,
Martin Draper.
24 passengers, one PAL.
Parolee-at-large.
Calvin McBride.
Seat One-C.
California State Pen,
two years, aggravated assault.
He was paroled last week.
And already over state lines.
It was news
to his parole officer.
I'm sure it was.
You know, my guys
are matching names to faces
both here and at the hospital.
McBride tops the list.
I'm going to talk to Maddox.
Let's roll.
Fire Department says
the driver of the
Camaro's dead.
Yeah, I heard,
but I think I know
why the bus pulled
to the right.
Now that
is a serious blowout.
And the front
left tire's
still intact.
Newton's Third Law:
"For every action
there is an equal
and opposite reaction."
Tire to rim.
Rim to axle.
Axle to suspension.
Suspension to frame.
And the lower radius rod arm...
which connects
the axle to the frame.
Not anymore.
So, if the rod arm broke
while he was driving...
Driver tried
to maintain control.
Veered to the left.
But turning the wheel
was probably
going to make things worse.
Putting pressure
on the right front tire
causing it to blow.
The... the bus then
veers to the right.
Goes off the road.
And we're back to Newton.
The theory's correct
if the rod arm
was the first action.
I'm gonna see what's going on with that Camaro.
WOMAN ( over radio ):
...1-41 north...
Rescue!
Can you tell me your name?
MAN:
Miss, you need
to let him go.
Let's go on three.
One, two, three, in.
( clanging )
( doors shut )
This never happened to me
before.
The wheel just sh-shook
right out of my hands.
How long after
your scheduled
stop in Barstow?
We, uh, we-we always stop
in Barstow.
Uh, McDonald's
the, uh, the train
station one.
I understand that, Mr. Draper,
but how long after that
did the wheel start
to shake on you?
Uh...
I don't, uh...
I don't...
Sir, are you okay?
No.
We're behind schedule.
I got to get back
to the bus.
Hold on, hold on.
Wait a second.
Mr. Draper...
Mr. Draper, have you had
anything to drink at all?
I'm going to do
a preliminary field breath test.
Keep an eye
on Mr. Draper,
will you, Greg?
Sure, right.
I, uh, I got to go.
Won't take a minute.
I understand.
Hang tight.
See, uh, there's people...
I understand.
I want you to take
a deep breath, and I want you
to blow into the end of this
for me, okay?
( coughing )
I need a doctor
over here.
Greg, get some help.
Greg!
Get some help!
STOKES:
It's all right, man.
Stop apologizing.
SANDERS:
Oh, I feel bad.
I just
froze up.
That's why we have
fielding training, Greg.
No disrespect, but you're
not qualified to be out here.
I guess I just wasn't
expecting blood
to look like that.
Pre-collection,
so different.
Yup.
I remember my first
time in the field.
CSI One.
Green as could be.
Initial call was a robbery.
I get there,
triple homicide.
Blood all over the place,
mother and two kids.
How do you deal?
You just do.
Okay, what's next?
Well, we're missing
a passenger.
The only one unaccounted for is
an ex-con named Calvin McBride.
According to Brass, he wasn't
admitted to the hospital
and he's not in any
of the body bags.
What about the rest
stop in Barstow?
CHP and the Barstow PD
are looking.
Anybody check the bus?
I'll find out.
Firefighters only look
in the obvious spots.
Just out of curiosity, what
are the unobvious spots?
For bodies?
Walls, hot water heaters
stuffed in the box spring
of a hotel room bed.
I found a head
in a bucket of paint once.
I get the picture.
What do you see?
Well...
McBride's not on the bus.
Grissom.
Cheap whiskey
broken bottle, brown paper bag.
You know, I never gave
the bus driver a breath test.
Greg
bag this, take it
to the lab
swab the rim for DNA.
You should be wearing gloves.
Sorry.
This guy was in 1C.
Seat 1C was the only seat
with an unobstructed path
through the windshield.
Where's the other half
of this windshield?
STOKES:
Laminated safety glass,
pops in, pops out.
Hello,
Mr. McBride.
I'm afraid our ex-con
just got the death penalty.
WILLOWS:
He's one of the victims
in the bus crash.
He was in the Camaro.
He was driving the Camaro.
Excuse me.
Ma'am,
not now.
Catherine Willows
with the Las Vegas Crime Lab.
This will just take a second.
Can you tell me
your name?
Eric.
Eric?
I just wanted to surprise her.
That's all.
If I don't make it
please tell her
I'm sorry.
Ma'am, this is
the operating room.
You need to leave.
GRISSOM:
I need the two front wheels,
axle, suspension, all of it.
The whole front undercarriage.
Excuse me, Miss.
This is
a crime scene.
It's off limits.
I know.
I was, uh,
I was on the bus.
Why are you here?
I don't...
I don't know.
I'm sorry.
( sighs )
Shreds of rubber everywhere.
Between the crash, and all
the other interstate traffic
it might as well be
the Indy 500.
This stuff could be
from any vehicle.
There's no doubt that this bus
body-checked this K-Rail.
( tires squealing )
You've got that "Sara" look.
You mean that "Grissom" look?
Second set
of skid marks.
Camaro.
I got a theory.
Grissom said the suspension
gave on the bus, right?
Broken rod arm.
Well,
I'm thinking
when that rod arm
hit the pavement
it made this great
first impression here.
If this is the bus...
the bus begins
to slide right.
Driver overcorrects.
Crosses the highway
slams into the K-Rail.
Meanwhile
the Camaro's holding
steady in the right lane
heading straight
for us.
Bus bounces off
this K-Rail...
heads back towards us.
Taking out anything
in its path.
Bus crosses four
lanes of traffic
and only takes out
the car behind it?
Someone upstairs was
looking out big-time.
Hey, boss.
I had a feeling
you were coming.
I ran the DNA
on that whiskey bottle.
You'll never guess.
It's not the bus driver
but I do have an answer
behind door number two.
Seat number 1C.
Calvin McBride.
He's an ex-con.
Found his DNA in CODIS.
Good, Greg.
Did you enjoy
being in the field?
You heard about it, too?
What?
That I...
messed up.
No.
Well, then I enjoyed it fine.
You're telling me
this guy wasn't intoxicated.
Not a drop of ethanol
in his system
not even
from cough syrup.
He could barely
put a sentence together.
If he wasn't drunk,
then what was he?
My guess, hungry.
Driver's medical eval
taken just
last month.
Martin Draper, 40.
Overweight.
One of 15 million
people
in this country suffering
from Type II diabetes.
On any medication?
Primary course of treatment
would have been exercise
and weight loss
to lower blood sugar.
Doesn't look like
he was hitting the gym.
But he was
dieting.
Crash dieting.
Didn't find
any food in
his stomach.
Means he
hadn't eaten
anything in at least six hours.
An empty stomach
invites hypoglycemia.
Symptoms of which can
mirror intoxication.
And in extreme cases?
Loss of consciousness
and seizure.
Do I pass?
Cum laude.
Cause of death?
Just what you'd expect.
Massive injuries,
internal bleeding.
So, if we're not looking
at the driver...
We're looking at the bus.
Check this out.
A bolt?
Nice.
I got 20 of them.
Well, this one's sheared.
It is, isn't it?
Bus company just faxed over
a maintenance report.
Bus was in
perfect working order.
Serviced last week.
Does this look like it's
in perfect working order?
Uh... no.
What'd you get?
Three-quarter
inch bolt.
It matches the bolt
on the specs for this
suspension system.
The hex head says
it's a grade eight.
Snapped in half?
Bolts are graded according
to their hardness.
The higher the grade,
the stronger the steel.
STOKES:
A grade eight bolt shouldn't
snap like a toothpick.
Did you do a Rockwell
Hardness test?
Yeah,
I hit it with the Tru-Blue.
It's not a grade eight.
It's a grade five.
Often when there's one...
there's another one.
Bus company
was using bogus bolts.
Inferior bolts would cause
the suspension to give
the bus veers off the road.
If the sheared bolts
were the first
action.
No, the bolts snapped
midway through the skid
after the bus hit the K-Rail.
Proof?
The gouge in the road.
Broken rod arm,
maybe?
Okay.
Driver hits the brakes,
initiates the skid.
Why'd he hit the brakes?
Another vehicle.
Nope, only two sets
of fresh skid marks
on that stretch
of highway.
And the Camaro's skid marks
place it behind the bus.
So I ask again--
why'd he hit the brakes?
( chuckles )
Man, there could be
a million reasons.
Well, fortunately,
we're just looking for one.
The kid in the Camaro
didn't make it.
Eric Kevlin, 32.
He was a resident
at the UCLA Med Center.
He was on his way to Vegas
to surprise his girlfriend.
Only to end up
pinned under a bus.
But he's rescued.
Given a second chance on life.
And, uh... he signs this.
It's a pre-op DNR.
BRASS:
"Do not resuscitate"?
It doesn't make sense
for a young person.
Why refuse CPR?
MADDOX:
Our company has
an excellent safety record.
BROWN:
Until last night.
Look, you own an airline
or a bus company--
any transport business--
accidents are inevitable.
Criminal acts, however,
are another matter.
Wait a minute.
I've got a family.
Sometimes they ride my buses.
I don't take a chance with
their lives or anybody else's.
I screen all
my drivers.
Zero tolerance for
drugs or alcohol.
I keep strict
maintenance records.
Vehicle inspection every 45 days
as required by law.
You're not going to find
anything criminal here.
I believe this belongs to you.
Bolt, grade eight.
Sheared.
It doesn't happen.
The front suspension
was riddled with these.
We have more questions
about the accident
but one thing we know.
The suspension didn't hold.
I buy all my spare parts
from reputable companies.
We only care about the bolts.
Brillway Bolt Company.
I just switched;
they were low bid.
The consequences
of saving a buck.
I think maybe it's time
for another inspection.
I'll ground
the fleet.
I get it.
It's busy here
in Barstow.
But you do remember the bus?
Yeah, I knew the driver.
Marty.
Always fill him up
on the return trip.
I remember this one guy
kept checking me out.
Bought a lot
of turkey jerky.
Oh, and this one couple
was having a fight.
Did, uh, did they
come off the bus?
I don't know.
But you do remember
the bus?
Of course.
Mojave Express.
Always on time.
Ten-minute rest stop,
right back on the road.
Did you see a couple arguing?
No. But it was really busy.
Hey, Nick.
We making
any progress?
Just this jacket so far.
Passenger seat. And you?
We checked Kevlin's property
at the hospital.
There's no wallet.
Guy drives from L.A.
four and a half hours--
I got an idea.
( grunts )
Hand me that, uh, crowbar
there, please.
Thank you.
Ha.
Bingo.
I always take mine out.
Pain in the ass.
Literally.
Yeah, that's him.
Yeah.
Nice-looking girl.
Wait.
I've seen her.
Yeah. Yeah, I've seen her.
She was in
the accident.
He said he wanted
to surprise you.
He did.
In Barstow at the rest stop.
It was supposed to be
a girls' weekend.
No! This is my weekend.
If this is
going to work,
I need my space.
I don't want
to lose you.
Then go back home.
I saw him pull out.
Drive off.
Well, he didn't
drive back to L.A.
I wish I hadn't yelled at him.
Is there any reason why Eric,
in a medical crisis
would refuse resuscitation?
What are you talking about?
He consented
to lifesaving surgery, but...
signed a DNR.
Oh, God.
It's because he was a doctor.
He saw it every day.
People hooked up to machines
waiting to die.
He swore he wouldn't let
anyone he loved
go through that.
And if his life was at stake
he wanted to make
the hard decision
so no one else would have to.
I thought I told you
I'd page you with the results.
I know. I want to wait.
Greg?
You're really good
at what you do.
Sabotage.
Grissom.
I finally know
the first action.
What initiated the skid.
The right front tire
started to come apart.
When it blew, it left
an indentation in the pavement.
I didn't see it.
You and me both.
Treads from the right rear tire
obscured it.
So, the driver overcorrects
but since
there's no more tire
all that force is displaced
on the suspension system.
The bolt snaps,
the rod arm breaks
and the bus
broadsides the Camaro.
But why did the tire come apart
in the first place?
I don't know.
I do.
Chloroform. Inside the tire.
Newton's Third... with a twist.
Yeah, the front right tire
was compromised.
I found
chloroform
in the interior
fragments of
the rubber.
Oh, that's original.
What happened to
slashing tires?
It wasn't vandalism.
It was an act
of premeditation.
Why chloroform?
Chloroform destroys the
elasticity of the rubber.
Sooner or later,
the air pressure
inside the tire
causes it to explode.
How much later?
Well, that's what
we're going to find out.
We need a treadmill--
a big one.
All right,
to do what?
Exercise a bus.
Warrick, tell Larry Maddox
it's in his best interest
to lend us one of his.
Set it up in the empty police
warehouse next door. Sara?
Yeah, I'll be at Trace.
They're going to love this.
Chloroform
in the tire?
Yeah. Weird, huh?
So, where are we?
Body count jumped to nine dead.
Sabrina Wright
law student, 7-B.
Pronounced an hour ago.
23 passengers,
plus the driver.
WILLOWS:
Whoever tampered with that tire
was playing Russian roulette
with people's lives.
GRISSOM:
Or maybe one of them
was a target.
Hmm.... Gwen Murray, 1-B...
was unemployed,
but was clearing a bundle
in alimony.
Also got the Porsche
and the vacation home.
Michael Goodman,
10-C
was picked up a couple times
by vice for making fake IDs.
Ryan Hyde, a
money manager
in 4-C, filed
bankruptcy last year
but carried a hefty
life insurance policy.
I mean, I could go on.
Right.
You look hard enough
everybody's got
a skeleton.
What was her skeleton?
Tracey Logan?
Seat 8-B?
Her boyfriend
was Eric Kevlin
the Camaro driver.
He was a doctor.
He followed her
from L.A.
They had an argument
in Barstow.
He didn't want her
in Vegas.
First step to stopping her
is stopping the bus.
And he has access to chloroform.
Chloroform can be picked up
at any chemical supply store.
Wait a minute.
Eric Kevlin was a
nervous boyfriend.
He wasn't a criminal.
Still possible.
Motive, access, opportunity.
His car should be towed in
by now.
I'll check for residue.
So, who do you like?
The bus company.
Larry Maddox--
he talks a good game
but, uh, he cheaped out
on his supplies
and he's been way too helpful.
You busy?
I got three minutes
and, uh, five seconds.
Then I have
a question for you.
Bus case?
Uh-huh.
I heard Sanders
broke out of here, fared poorly
and disgraced us all.
No, he didn't.
( monitor beeps )
Listen, I-I found chloroform
on the inside
of a steel-belted radial
and I need to know
how it got there.
You ever hear the expression
"pissing up a rope"?
Not in a scientific context, no.
Well, I don't know
if you can urinate
up a rope
but you can urinate
against a rope
and the urine will dribble down.
Answer your
question?
Yes.
You know we need
to document this
for The Journal
of Forensic Science, right?
Is this the twin?
Yeah, this is the rear trailing
tire of the crash bus.
It has the same
maintenance record
as the tire
that blew.
Chloroform, glass rod
valve core remover....
According to Vincent and Trace
it's like pissing
down a rope.
Gravity, huh?
Reattach the valve...
reinflate the tire...
( air hissing )
...and you're done.
Minute, minute and a half
tops.
Did you see that?
Yeah.
You used your left hand
to prop yourself up.
The perp may have
done the same.
Yeah, I'm going to go dust
that right rim.
I'll see you guys.
Okay. "Drive," he said.
Just the speed limit.
( motor whirring )
( computer beeping )
( cell phone ringing )
Warrick.
Okay.
Yeah, okay.
I'll be there.
Sara. She's at the print lab.
She needs me.
Checkmate.
Print off the rim
matched a work card
on file-- a Sean Nolan.
So, why are you
paging me?
I pulled up his DMV
records looking
for an address.
I found one, not recent, but...
he's got a Class B license
with passenger endorsement.
WARRICK:
Oh... so he can drive
a vehicle
with over ten passengers.
I cross-checked his name
with the employee roster
from Mojave Express.
Mm-hmm?
He's a driver.
Well, I guess
I'll grab a uniform
and pay Mr. Maddox
another visit.
Bus logged into Barstow
at 8:03 p.m.
target would be
two hours later.
No, if the tire was
tampered with in Barstow
it should blow
any minute.
If not, it was
sabotaged in L.A.
and we've got another
two hours and 13 minutes.
Hello.
( sighs )
( explosion )
( motor stops )
Cool.
Well, I guess
it's Barstow.
Listen
I scanned Eric
Kevlin's car
and clothing
with an ion detector.
There was no chloroform.
He was clean.
And I got a hit
off that print--
a Sean Nolan,
employed by Mojave Express.
Any chance
he was
in Barstow yesterday?
Uh, his route is...
Vegas/Grand Canyon
but I'll call Warrick.
He's on his way
to the bus company right now.
You know, if this guy Nolan
worked for the bus company
his print on the wheel
could be legit.
Well, I wish we had a "who"
but at least we have a "where."
I have a zero
tolerance policy.
I found marijuana
in Mr. Nolan's locker.
He was out of here
that afternoon.
Well, we're still going
to need
those maintenance records.
( phone ringing )
( machinery whirring )
Everything from fill-ups
to tune-ups the last six months.
Thank you.
There were security cameras
behind the counter
but none of them were
pointed out here.
Five buses have pulled in
in the last ten minutes.
Not to mention all
the private vehicles
truckers-- nothing's changed
since I was here yesterday.
Forget about getting
a usable print
off that airhose.
BRASS:
Yeah, a guy putting air
in a tire at a rest stop
does not draw
attention.
( cell phone rings)
Grissom.
Sean Nolan was fired
two months ago.
Maddox says he's working
in Barstow
and since then three
of Maddox's buses had blowouts.
They all went through Barstow.
Did you check
their maintenance records?
Yeah, only last night's bus
had been serviced
since Maddox changed suppliers.
Way to go, Warrick. I owe you.
Yeah, you do.
See you.
We got a suspect.
Sean Nolan.
BRASS:
Sean Nolan?
Can I help you?
Yeah, there was a bus crash
up the road.
About nine people died.
Yeah, it's all
over the news.
I already talked to him.
I forgot what you told me.
Wasn't much to tell.
Your prints were
on the bus.
Not following.
Front right wheel hub.
I work here.
Julius Caesar,
murdered in 44 B.C.
Legend has it
that the molecules
from his last breath
spread all over
the world.
Probably like
your fingerprints, right?
They're everywhere.
WILLOWS:
Uh...
Mr. Nolan, have you handled
any chloroform lately?
No.
You mind?
( slow beeping )
What are you doing?
Would you turn
around, please?
( rapid beeping )
( steady beeping )
GRISSOM:
Whoa.
Is that a pickle
in your pocket
or are you just
happy to see us?
( steady beep )
Just wanted to stick it to him.
Give him a few problems.
Maddox?
Yeah.
I smoke one joint
on the weekend... my time.
Now I got a jacket as a junkie.
Can't get a job driving a bus
to save my life.
So, you figured, "I'll just
blow a couple of his tires."
Even if a tire blows
the suspension system
should keep the bus on the road.
I been driving buses
for ten years.
I've never seen a flat
take out a bus.
There's always a first time.
You're under arrest.
I didn't mean to hurt anyone,
okay?
Well, I'd hate to be a juror
on a case like this.
Second-degree murder.
Reckless disregard
for safety and human life
mitigated by bad bolts.
Yeah, which was mitigated
by greed.
MAN:
Folks, we're going to take
a quick 15-minute pit stop.
We're about 45 minutes
outside of Las Vegas.
We'll be back on the bus
in a jiffy