( gasping )
No! No!
( police siren blaring )
( garbled radio transmissions
in background )
Call said one dead body.
O'RILEY:
Caught him red-handed.
Ben Jennings.
Nick Stokes, Gil Grissom,
Las Vegas Crime Lab.
You want to tell us
what's going on?
What happened here?
You have anything
to say?
You don't have to talk to us.
He'll talk to us.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
( background
radio transmissions )
See that lividity?
Blood settled
at the time of death.
Body's been moved
from the murder scene.
Impound his car.
Sorry, guys. I lost
you at the fork.
My bad, Sara.
Let's process this guy
shall we?
Officer, would you
uncuff him, please?!
Okay, make like a scarecrow
for me, partner.
Arms out, away from your body.
That's it.
Stay just like that.
Give me your right foot.
Other right.
Put it down.
Lift it up.
GRISSOM:
Hold still.
Possible secondary transfer.
Got some red fibers.
Other foot.
Lift it up.
Put it down.
GRISSOM:
No defensive wounds.
No hematomas.
Victim didn't fight back.
Probably didn't see it coming.
Matthew...
tag that body for special
processing, VIP room.
Don't wash it till I get there,
and don't touch his fingernails.
"D.B., Mediterranean Casino,
Women's Spa."
Body is Shelley Danvers.
DOB: 10/10/81.
Employee walked in
to get towels...
found her here.
A young woman, healthy,
just reading a magazine
and all of a sudden she DFOs?
Done fell out.
That's what the
night manager says.
BROWN:
Miss?
We're from the Crime Lab.
You found the deceased?
Yes, I was, um...
just getting some towels
and I walked in
and she was there.
WILLOWS:
Hey, Brass...
you touch this body?
Yeah, I was born yesterday.
Well, it looks as if the sash
may have been tied
by somebody else.
Miss...
you know anything
about redressing the body?
Well, she was naked.
I-I-I thought
she should be covered.
Did you move the body here, too?
Guests were looking in.
I put a robe on her.
It's not like
it's a crime or anything.
Actually, it is.
Makes us doubt the circumstances
surrounding the victim's death.
Flour, maybe?
But what kind?
All-purpose?
Self-rising?
Pastry?
Trace will probably
have a better idea.
I'll get DNA
to see if
there's bits
of Ben under
the fingernails.
What about the neck?
Any fibers in the wound?
You told me to wait for you.
Well, that hasn't
stopped you yet.
I did observe
some fibers in the wound.
I didn't collect them, though.
Be my guest.
Yellow.
Not cotton; satin, maybe.
Dress shirt...
but no tie.
Strangled with his own tie?
Find me on the flour.
BROWN:
"Shelley Danvers"--
appointment 8:00.
Ms. Marita,
did the deceased
use the Jacuzzi facilities
this evening?
Not that I remember, no.
( gurney clanging )
What? You don't believe me?
Well, you lied
to us before.
It's, uh,
not uncommon to drown
in a Jacuzzi.
Hair gets caught
in the whirl
a person
gets dragged under.
The hotel wouldn't be
considered unsafe.
Well, that didn't happen here.
She did not drown
on these premises.
Well, if she did, the coroner
would find water in her lungs
but it'd be worse
hearing it from him
than from you.
Oliver Dunne;
corporate lawyer, father of two.
You get all that
from his dentals?
His wife-- widow.
She came down
to I.D. his property.
.380s?
Last one I recovered
entered through his abdominals
pierced the liver,
lodged in the oblique.
That's not what
killed him, is it?
We pulled a yellow fiber
out of the neck wound.
I think it's from his tie.
You might be right.
He died of asphyxiation.
Tie probably
closed the windpipe.
Without oxygen, the alveoli
capillaries wither and dry up.
Whole pulmonary system
shut down.
What you may have here
is the smallest sliver
of the murder weapon.
Why would a guy shoot
a man three times
and then strangle him
with his own tie?
SIDLE:
I cannot
tell you why
but I might be able
to tell you where.
A pizza shop.
The flour on Oliver Dunne
has a low gluten content--
seven percent protein--
it's typical
of flour used to make cakes,
pizzas, that kind of thing.
So, why did you rule out
bakeries?
Well, the subtype of flour is
another subtype; double zero.
It's a very fine flour
used only in pizza-baking ovens.
Oh, and Trace picked up
some oregano in the sample.
When are you set
to interview Ben?
You're the registered owner
of a Lorcin .380.
Takes the same
caliber bullet
as the slugs
we took out of the victim.
So, I'm going to ask you
one more time
where's your gun?
I lost it.
Do you think
we believe that?
Do you think...
Are you employed, Ben?
Yeah... yeah, um...
it's a place called
Dante's Pizzeria.
It's behind the Strato'.
You make pizzas?
Well, I deliver the pizzas.
It's too hot back there
with all the ovens
and stuff.
Do you, uh...
ever come into contact with
the baking flour at Dante's?
Mostly pizza boxes.
Why?
Well, 'cause we found
flour on the victim
and it's the
kind that's used
to make pizza.
Can you explain that?
No.
Ben, why don't you earn
yourself some points
by telling me what the science
is going to tell me anyway?
Well, I don't have to talk.
No... but we're going
to figure it out.
Look, if you know so much
about these murders
what do you need me for?
Murders?
There are more bodies?
( background
radio transmissions )
I feel like I'm mowing a lawn.
What is that?
A beer can?
Soda can?
Zilch.
Don't tell me,
more zilch?
SIDLE:
Whoa... Whoa.
Point of disturbance.
Hold up.
STOKES:
Isolate it.
Any more bodies
you want to tell me about?
No.
We're going to radar
this whole hillside.
Sometimes... when I leave
a crime scene
where I've been particularly
involved with a dead body
I sit in my car
and it hits me--
how close I was...
how heavy the body is...
the texture of the body...
how it feels... you know?
Mr. Grissom...
I'm not a bad person.
You're not a bad person?
Then, what are you?
Oh, I hope that's
Shelley Danvers
the woman
from the hotel spa.
Yep, she's next.
Well, it's about time.
You guys finished
with day-shift runover, huh?
I hate it when
you CSI guys
get territorial.
Yeah, well,
the victims' families
hate it
when we don't.
I'll take it
from here, David.
Good morning.
Catherine.
No serosanguineous
fluid
expunged from the mouth
or nose.
She didn't drown?
Rules out your Jacuzzi theory.
Anything probative?
Bright red lividity
extending down
the body.
From?
Well, heatstroke possibly.
Stroke could cause
multiple organ failure
and if I'm right...
Cover-up.
Hey, I still have
to do the post. Catherine?
Brass, I need you
to get records
from that hotel spa--
a warrant, if we need it.
Yep, that's right.
Bye.
Oh, it's on.
Yeah. Was our girl
staying with anyone
at that hotel?
Uh, yeah.
Tina... Tina Kolas.
Best friends from
Terre Haute, Indiana.
Flew here in
a package. Why?
We need someone
to give us the truth
about last night.
Gil Grissom?
Father?
Benjamin's a member
of my parish.
The officer won't let me
talk to him.
He said you were
in charge.
Of this crime scene.
He needs
spiritual guidance.
Yeah, I imagine
he does.
Ah... then you'd have
no problem
with my talking to him.
It's the 11th hour.
I wouldn't expect
anything less.
11th hour?
When the reality
of their actions set in
they usually turn
to religion.
Can you think
of a better time?
Okay, hold it.
That's enough.
Let's dust him.
No ligature marks.
SIDLE:
Different from
the first guy.
See if this laceration
on this guy's forehead
is consistent with
the kid's shovel.
Hey...
I feel a wallet
here.
Ramirez
Kenny.
A 25-year-old Latino
and a 42-year-old white guy?
SIDLE:
Strangers.
Doesn't make sense.
There's no connection.
Well, it obviously
wasn't a robbery.
STOKES:
Hey, O'Riley.
What's the matter, man--
A.C. not working?
I was on with Dispatch.
Oliver Dunne's car was
just found by the Highway Patrol
abandoned at an AvCon station
off 215.
They didn't happen
to find another car
there, did they?
Yeah.
Registered to a "Ramirez."
Yeah...
gas station.
WILLOWS:
And you can verify
that when Shelley went
to the hotel spa last night
she was going to use
the dry sauna?
We'd been drinking
apple martinis
for three days straight.
Shelley said the sauna
would detox her
you know, clean her out.
Cath.
Whose shirt is this?
Mine. Shelley and I got
in a fight over it.
When?
Yesterday.
I caught her trying it on
and I said
"Give it back,"
and then we started
fighting over it,
you know, tug of war
and the whole thing
ripped right in two.
We fell back laughing.
( laughing and squealing )
I'd give anything to have
her back.
We're going to take
this shirt,
if you don't mind.
No, go ahead,
if it'll help.
You said you have proof
that Shelley used
the dry sauna.
She called down from this phone.
Do they tape phone calls here?
WILLOWS:
Hotel surveillance
would love that.
You're sure she used
that phone to make
the appointment?
Yeah.
We're going to take this
as well.
Okay... but it doesn't have
anything on it.
Well, that's okay.
We do magic.
Two men were shot
and killed
and you didn't
see anything?
Sorry.
You don't just miss
something like that.
What was going on?
A friend of mine came
with his new car.
We took it
for a drive.
I'm afraid my boss
will find out.
I was only gone
five minutes.
Okay, all right.
Just walk us through it.
When did you know
there'd been a crime committed?
Well, my buddy
dropped me back here
and I noticed
these two cars.
I went to check
them out.
Oh, my God.
I don't see any blood.
Yeah, I hosed
it down.
You what?
It was freakin' me out.
H-Hello?
Mr. Grissom?
Uh...
They told me out front
I'd find you here.
I don't see your,
uh... visitor's badge.
Priest's collar.
People trust it.
Most people.
Even lapsed Catholics.
What makes you think, uh...
I was ever a Catholic?
First time we met,
you called me "Father."
Only Romans do that.
Everybody else,
it's "Reverend"
or "Minister."
I wanted to know
how your investigation
against Ben is going.
This is his car.
You know,
you really shouldn't be here.
I didn't come here to tamper
with your evidence.
He was a good kid,
all through school.
Still comes
to Mass
every Sunday.
If he has a problem...
it's trying to please people.
Is that a problem?
It can be.
This Luminol reveals
any dried
blood spots.
He wouldn't do this.
I believe the car.
"To whom much is given,
much will be expected."
I leave you to your work.
I told you we have
no record Shelley Danvers
specifically used
the dry sauna.
WILLOWS:
That's okay, 'cause we do.
ESDA can read
this blank paper
see what's
written on it.
Up to 14 layers.
BROWN:
Sometimes a simple
flashlight
will do the trick.
That's Miss Danvers'
handwriting.
We confirm that.
So she took a dry sauna.
What does that prove?
She died of a heat stroke.
The Coroner
just called in
with the results
of his final post.
Your sauna's kept
in the optimal condition
for heat stroke--
182 °F.
That could kill a person
if you left them
longer than
two straight hours.
Especially if no one
checks up on them.
A hotel employee
is supposed to check
on the various saunas
every 15 minutes.
Hotel regulations,
right?
We, uh,
we got a copy of
the check-up sheet.
No hotel employee
checked in on the sauna after 7:30 p.m.
So, Shelley was in here
from 8:00 until...
what time did
you call 9-1-1?
I, um...
I came in at closing.
10:00.
Miss?
Oh, my God.
You moved her
into the locker room?
Put the robe on her?
I was just trying to protect
the hotel.
From negligent homicide.
They drill into us that
the reputation of this hotel
is everything.
Murder scene
was compromised.
Pump jockey wasn't
very helpful
but bullets pulled
from Victim One
and Victim Two.
Identical striations.
Bullets in both
victims were fired
by the exact same weapon.
A Lorcin .380.
The same pistol
registered to
a Benjamin Jennings.
SIDLE:
P.D. can prove through
credit cards
that Ben frequents
the AvCon gas stations
where both vics
were killed.
STOKES:
And we can prove
he transported those bodies
in his vehicle
based on the blood
you found.
And fibers.
I recovered a burgundy fiber
from the sock of Victim One.
Found the same fiber
on the sock of Victim Two.
We ID'd the fibers
using the FTIR.
It's a polymer commonly used
in vehicle carpeting.
So we went back
to Ben's car.
STOKES:
They're identical.
We got the Master
Standards
from the car
manufacturer.
The assigned name
for the material
is "12-ounce Merlot Trialon."
Bottom line...
he killed them.
Good work, you guys.
Very good.
But you haven't proved murder.
You've proved burial.
Excuse me?
Victim blood on his clothes...
under his nails.
From burying them.
Victim blood in his car?
He transported them.
Show me the gun
with Ben's prints
on it.
Gun shot residue,
the ligature, the...
The holes in Christ's hands,
Doubting Thomas?
Yes. Empirical evidence.
St. Thomas was ahead
of us all.
Does this have anything to do
with the priest that's been
coming around here?
No.
It has to do with the evidence.
It's our job to present the D.A.
with the best evidence possible.
Let a jury decide.
Anything else,
we're playing judge.
The evidence doesn't get
any better than this.
Okay. Ship it.
Show it to the D.A.
Right.
Anyone up
for breakfast?
I'm up for a shower
and tucking my daughter in.
Football-- wide-screen.
Well, I guess I'll go
see Tina alone.
Hotel tells me she's down
playing quarter slots.
I thought we
solved this case.
What'd you get?
Well, my guy in the hotel lounge
tells me that Tina and Shelley
were having a catfight
over some dude named Jeremy
the day she died.
That's probably how the shirt
really got ripped.
Don't ring her bell
till we re-examine our case.
Misunderstood the priest?
How?
I looked deeper
into the evidence.
I should have looked deeper
into Ben's character.
STOKES:
"Benjamin Corey Jennings."
Nonviolent crimes.
"Roger Jennings...
armed robbery.
"Past convictions,
breaking and entering
"assault with
great bodily harm.
Paroled 9/27/2000."
This guy is hard-core.
He's looking
at his third strike here.
What's going on?
You know how we pushed him
to file on Ben?
Yeah.
We might have been wrong.
Tell me
about your brother.
We know that you only
buried the bodies.
So, what happened?
Did he threaten you?
Ben?
Did you learn to throw
pizzas in prison, Roger?
Who the hell are you guys?
Get out of my kitchen.
"Roger Jennings--
armed robbery,
breaking and entering."
You sound like the kind
of guy it wouldn't be
a big jump to murder.
What is this?
Your first stop
the AvCon gas station.
See these two guys?
Nope.
Don't know what
you're talking about.
My little brother
got me this job.
I'm staying clean.
Suppose I told you
your brother said
you did these guys.
He wouldn't do that.
You did it directly after work
using a .380 pistol
and then you strangled
one of the victims
with his own tie.
Ben did it.
Did you witness this?
He told me about it.
Look what I did--
I just lost my head.
What am I supposed to do now?
I'm on a short line, all right?
You're on your own, Ben.
Roger, you've
got to help me.
You know
I can't.
What am I going to do?
Huh?
It's your mess.
You got to deal with it.
What started the beef
with the victims?
I don't know.
Tempers, I guess.
Hey!
Hey, man! I was here first.
You want to
wait your turn?
What are you
going to do, huh?
Bystander gets
a little too nosy...
and he gets it, too.
The perpetrator's
hands left flour
on the victim's face.
This was not
from a gunshot.
This was something a
little more intimate.
When a person changes
his mode of murder
from pistol to ligature
it's for one of
two reasons--
entertainment...
or necessity.
Which was it for you?
Neither.
I told you,
Ben strangled that guy.
The flour said you did.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Anything on the list
besides the tie?
Nope.
Hey, guys.
You can go ahead
and take off.
I think we got it.
Thanks.
Whoa.
Hey.
Dry cleaning.
The trailer's
low-rent.
Dry cleaning's expensive.
Sara?
This man's not
as smart as he thinks.
Dry cleaning
bakes in blood stains.
Could be red sauce.
Oh, now
you're cautious.
I'm just
trying to put
our mistake to good use.
Okay. You wanna...
check the perimeter and I'll see
if we have blood stains or red sauce.
Okay.
Hemoglobin.
Take a look at this.
Nick?
Hey, Nick.
( gunshot )
( gunshots )
jammed, huh?
Get anything instructive?
Possibly.
Blood from Jennings's
denim shirt.
Is the printer out of ink?
"ND, ND, ND."
It means "None Detected."
The dry cleaning
baked in the blood
and it also degraded it
to a degree that I
can't get a result.
Try again. This could be
victim blood. Try again.
I have tried.
It's chemically
impossible, Sara.
Nothing from nothing
is nothing.
The striations
are different. See?
There's no way I can say
that the bullets
taken from the victims
were fired by Jennings's gun.
So, he altered
the barrel somehow.
Yeah. Changed how the bullet
relates to the barrel
so when the bullet emerges,
its fine stria are altered.
Any idea what he used?
Whatever it was...
did the job.
My evidence
is no better.
Total wash.
We present this
to the D.A.
Unfortunately, we've had
this discussion before.
The guilty brother's
going to walk.
He's never been in
any real trouble before.
They'll go easy on him.
The bullet jammed
in the feed, didn't it?
So, it was necessity.
Wait, are you saying Shelley
didn't die in the sauna?
She died of
heat stroke.
But the stroke covered up an
underlying medical catastrophe.
Like what?
Shell was always healthy.
She went into
anaphylactic shock.
Coroner says some
of the indicators
are the same
as a stroke:
renal failure, cerebral edema.
We missed it until Captain Brass
brought your room service
records to our attention.
I don't understand.
Well, maybe this will help--
the travel agency contract
you and Shelley signed.
Under "allergic reactions
to foods" for Shelley Danvers--
shellfish.
As her best friend,
you would know that.
BRASS:
And then we have this
from the hotel computer
for your room
7:01 p.m., on the day:
"A Taste from the Sea
"a lovely tureen
of mild bisque
with pureed bits
of Maine lobster."
Pureed, two bowls.
She didn't know
what she was eating
when it arrived, did she?
Because she didn't
order it; you did.
We've got a machine
known as the ESDA machine
which can read pen imprints.
Well, the machine isolated this.
"Jeremy, drinks, 10:00."
Shelley made that date.
That's her handwriting.
Were you in the room
when Jeremy called?
I answered the phone.
He asked for her.
You killed her over a guy
you two met at a bar?
I didn't mean to kill her.
I thought that she
would just have an
allergic reaction
and she wouldn't be able
to make her date that night
like, get hives or something.
Well, her allergy kicked in
in the sauna
under the worst
possible conditions--
trachea... larynx...
tongue swelled.
Her pressure got so low
her blood quit running
through her organs.
They shut down.
I didn't even like the guy.
I just...
I didn't want to be left out.
BRASS:
Miss Kolas, you're
under arrest.
Hey.
D.A.'s looking for you.
About?
What, you think I
read your messages?
"Top secret and urgent"?
It's a gift,
reading upside down.
The Las Vegas District Attorney
is reportedly...
preparing to file
homicide charges...
against Benjamin Corey Jennings
in the so-called
Burial Murders case.
Jennings has been in police
custody for the last...
Guess we know what
she was calling about.
...since he was caught burying
the first victim, Oliver Dunne
in the National Forest.
Don't you have enough cases
over at CSI
now you're going
to start telling me
which ones I should
take to court?
There isn't one piece
of evidence that says
that kid was even present
at the murders.
As a matter of fact
this is why
I was hunting you.
Jennings brought it in
about an hour ago.
Chain of custody;
I can't touch it.
The first victim was
ligatured, right?
Jennings says his little brother
asked him to hide the tie.
Well, how convenient.
The older brother brings it in
explaining why his epithelials
are all over the murder weapon.
A jury doesn't understand
epi-whatevers, okay?
They understand a twisty tie and
blood all over Ben's car seat.
He set up his brother.
Oh, come on, Grissom,
they're both part of it
and if I can get
one of them, I will.
He's a good kid, Robin.
He hero-worships his brother,
but he's a good kid.
Yeah?
Then his epithelials
shouldn't be on that tie.
Explain how bits
of your skin
got on the ligature
used to strangle
that victim.
I don't know.
Your brother brought this in
to the District Attorney.
What?
He's framing you.
GRISSOM:
Unless you can tell us
how your epithelials
got on that tie.
I don't know.
I swear I don't know.
I... he... I just picked up
the bodies at his place.
Grab that guy's tie, little bro.
I like that thing.
Bury them deep, all right?
You get into any trouble
you don't have to say
anything, all right?
I'm counting on you.
Yeah, yeah, man,
I'm there all the way.
Go, get out of here.
Go on.
I got to ask...
how does somebody bury
two bodies as a favor?
'Cause he's my brother.
He told...
He told me that if I didn't talk...
to you guys and if he didn't talk,
then this would all just blow over;
it'd all just go away.
You're looking at
two counts of Murder
Special Circumstances.
The best you can hope for
is life
without parole.
I don't... I don't think
I can do that kind of time.
Do you have
any physical evidence
linking your brother
to the murders?
Anything?
I know that we've arrested
the wrong brother.
He came to see you as soon
as Ben was in custody.
I tried to help without
breaking my vows.
We both have jobs
that begin after the crime.
After the sin.
Some people would call that
a career in futility.
Some call it a vocation.
100 years ago
we didn't have the technology
for fingerprints.
15 years ago,
we didn't have DNA.
Hopefully one day,
we'll have foolproof means
by which to put the right man
in jail in this case.
Someday, we won't need jails.
I celebrate mass
every Thursday night, 7:00.
Thank you...
but...
no.
You don't believe?
In religion?
I believe in God, in science...
in Sunday supper.
I don't believe in rules
that tell me how I should live.
Even if they're
handed down by God?
How many crusades were fought
in the name of God?
How many people died
because of someone's religion?
Fanaticism; not religion.
Semantics.
They're still dead.
I'm sorry about Ben, Father.
You still suffer
like a Catholic.
Light bulb goes out
other people fix it,
get a new one.
Light bulb goes out
for the Catholic
he stands in the dark
says, "What
did I do wrong?"
That guilt's not in me anymore.
Hey.
Oh.
You're going
to be getting a call
from the local papers
about spa safety.
Spa safety?
We had a victim die
of an allergic reaction
at the Mediterranean.
Some foul play;
some negligence.
So what am I
supposed to say?
That it was an
isolated incident...
that in no way
should it be a mark
against the Strip's other
fine hotel-casinos.
CSI supports Las Vegas.
Bottom line.
Need some help in here!
Hold his head!
I can't stop
the bleeding.
Oh, no, no, no.
How did this happen?!
Incisor.
He used his teeth.
Clamp down.
Keep him with us.
Get out of the way!
Out of the way!
Sir, step back.
Sir.
He's bleeding out.
He's bleeding out here.
We need to stop this.
Compression.
Keep him with us.
Get the head up.
We're losing him,
we're losing him.
I'm going to pronounce.
22:04.