( people chanting )
( chanting continues )
( gunshots )
"Wherever you live
is your temple
if you treat it
like one."
State your source.
Buddha.
Paramedics just pronounced.
Four dead, no witnesses.
Coroner's on his way.
Guy in the robe flagged down
an officer.
"Guy in the robe"
is a monk, Nick.
Yeah? Well...
he's a quiet monk.
Nonnative, from Thailand.
SIDLE:
Rug's low pile, smooth.
I'll try to dust lift.
Okay.
Let's hug the walls.
( Grissom sighs )
Gunshot to the head.
Times four.
SIDLE:
Gold statues...
money trees...
That's a lot of loot
to leave behind.
This wasn't a robbery.
This was a hit.
Five years ago, West Vegas...
German tourist took
a wrong turn, ended up dead.
This "placa" was sprayed
across the windshield
of their rental car.
It's the Snakebacks.
Gangbangers?
At a Buddhist temple?
Stippling around entry.
Close range.
Looks like they were shot
one at a time.
How do you
get one vic--
let alone four-- to sit still
while you put a bullet
between their eyes?
They were praying.
Yeah, for mercy.
For whoever was shooting them.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
( siren blares in distance )
What can you tell me
about the victims?
We came from Thailand
to share Buddhism
here in Nevada.
But you didn't share
the last couple hours together.
Where were you?
I was at the bank.
We're raising money
to build a school.
I was making
a deposit.
Where are
the other monks?
On a retreat.
They come
back tomorrow.
May I ask a question?
This is
a high-crime area.
Have you had
any problems here before?
Like break-ins or burglaries?
The past...
is in the past.
True.
But sometimes, it leaves
its fingerprints on the future.
Aren't you on duty?
MAN:
Hey.
How you doing,
kiddo?
Okay. How are you?
Fine. Sit.
Whew.
Attitude adjustment?
For the wife.
Says she can't face me
without it.
Ah. How is Mrs. Tadero?
Counting the days
till I retire.
Nice job on the Logan case.
Oh.
Hoo-hoo!
Wild ride!
Mm-hmm.
You did good.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Well...
I had a good teacher.
( sighing ):
So, did you see it?
The confession?
On TV, yeah.
And what do you think?
I always regretted the jury
didn't give him the chair.
But I'll take cancer,
long as he's gone.
I've made a lot of mistakes.
I killed that guy in Reno.
But I did not kill
Stephanie Watson.
( panting )
God is my witness,
I did not kill her.
Deathbed denial.
Negotiate with God
for a better seat in hell.
What if Kelso
didn't kill Stephanie?
I looked him in the eyes
15 years ago. He did it.
( screaming )
( sighs )
What if he didn't?
I mean...
( people laughing )
Witnesses saw him bothering her
in the club that night.
Uniform picks him up
a block from the alley.
Knife cut on his hand.
Come on, Cath!
Well... maybe I'm just afraid
ifI accept that he killed her
that it's over,
and Stephanie's really dead.
( muttering ):
I... I don't know.
What never lies?
( sighs )
The evidence.
The statute says that
once the convicted party
is executed or dies,
the evidence can be destroyed.
I-It's not here.
Relax. They said
it'd be here.
Yeah, well,
people make mistakes.
Well, that's why we
have computer tracking.
Fourteen...
It was 15, right?
Yeah.
Fifteen...
Stephanie Watson, right?
Yeah.
Yeah, that's it.
This was my old life.
Yeah?
We all have a past, huh?
Stephanie was my best friend.
Hey, we still on for tonight?
I got a gig.
I promised him I'd be there.
Forgive me?
Just this once.
I never saw her again.
What exactly are we looking for?
( sighs )
Peace of mind
that they got the killer.
Well, I'd start with this.
( man speaking
foreign language )
Forgive me.
English is my second language.
I understand you fine.
So, you're
the part-time cook here?
How many days a week
do you work at the temple?
Three.
You have a key?
No need.
The door is always open.
I told the monks.
Too trusting.
In this neighborhood, yeah.
They ever have
any problems with gangs?
Couple months ago
I saw spray paints
on the back wall.
Gang signs.
I wanted to file
a police report, but Ananda...
told me not to.
Why not?
I told you.
"Monks are too trusting."
Interesting reading
for a man of the cloth.
That monk had it in the
bottom of his desk drawer.
And he was the guy
handling the money.
You hide one thing
from your brothers
then maybe he
was hiding more.
Yeah, but just 'cause
you're stashing trash
doesn't make you a killer.
Yeah, I'm just...
talking it out, Sara.
What'd you find?
I found some boot prints
on the prayer room rug.
Monks don't wear boots,
right, Nick?
No, no, or read porn
or commit murder.
I also found a smudge
with some trace material
on a small statue.
It was a partial, some ridge
detail, but not makable
and a wad of gum that was stuck
to the big Buddha.
All of which is definitely
pointing to an outside job.
Hey, whatever.
Outside, inside.
Why shoot four people, then
leave the murder weapon
behind the temple where even
a blind man could find it?
And I hate taking off my shoes.
MAN:
All were shot
in the third eye
the sixth chakra,
vortex of consciousness.
I was a Gray's Anatomy man,
until I lost my legs.
I started getting
phantom pains
no drug or exercise
could control.
I began studying
the chakras.
Well, I do know that
the seven chakras
correspond to the body's
seven energy centers.
Each has a color
and a vibration.
Muladhara, the root chakra,
keeps us in the physical world.
Svadisthana, seat
of sexual energy.
Manipura, melting pot of
spiritual and earthly desires.
Anahata, the loving heart.
Visuddha, where feelings
are given expression.
Ajna, the third eye.
Saharsrara, the
crown connecting
the mortal human to
the timeless universe.
Let's go back to
the third eye.
Ajna, the hub
of higher consciousness.
If someone were threatened
by that consciousness
that would be
a logical target, yeah?
Hmm, there's a very good chance
your killer's a Buddhist.
SANDERS:
Now, this is
where Ecklie swabbed
the blood sample
from the blade 15 years ago.
It's your friend's
Stephanie Watson.
And we got the second sample
from the handle end.
Perfect match to Dwight Kelso
the guy convicted
for Stephanie's murder.
Thank you, Greg.
Thank you.
Had to be hard on you.
Losing a friend,
someone that you...
I'm taking this to Trace.
Did I miss something?
You see that?
Hmm, it's blood.
That's a weak sample.
That's probably
why Ecklie took
the thicker one.
15 years ago, we figured,
why light up something
you can't analyze
in the first place?
Yeah, except now,
we can replicate
DNA a million times
even from the most minute
sample of blood.
Priority.
Let me know
what you find out.
Yes, ma'am.
Bobby D. shot
the test bullet
through the rifle you
found behind the temple.
It's on the right.
Bullet from vic
number three
on the left.
Lans and grooves
align perfectly.
GRISSOM:
Well, we've got ourselves
a murder weapon.
Well, we've got
more than that.
Sara and I found prints
off the rifle.
And?
Well, I'll give you
a hint.
He's bald, he wears a robe
and he likes his coeds
bodacious.
( sighs )
One survivor,
one suspect.
And a whole lot
of bad karma.
I entered through the back.
The rifle was on my desk.
I walked into the prayer room
to ask my brothers
about the gun.
I returned to my office,
placed the weapon outside
and went for help.
Tampering with evidence is
against the law.
The temple is a holy place.
Maybe, but a crime had been
committed there.
Please understand,
I was obeying my teachings.
Do your teachings allow you
to keep pornography?
Someone left the magazine
at the temple.
I kept it
in case this
person came back.
Yeah, right.
If you are no longer attached
to seeking pleasure
pictures of naked women
mean no more than pictures
of waterfalls.
I abstain from
erotic behavior not
because we believe
sex is sinful
but because preoccupation
with worldly pleasure
diverts us from the path.
Got to be a lot easier
to be a monk
in a monastery on a mountaintop
than one on Las Vegas Boulevard.
I ran that faint blood
sample from the knife.
Wow.
Yeah, I know.
ECKLIE:
Willows.
Just the person
I wanted to see.
I just signed off
on the Authorization
to Destroy Evidence
in the Stephanie Watson
homicides
since I was the primary,
and then I learned tonight
that the evidence
has been checked out
by you and Warrick.
You care to explain that?
Found a third donor
on the knife.
Blood's from a male.
Unknown.
But Kelso didn't have
an accomplice.
Then you know why
we're looking at the file.
Hey.
Here's the good news.
Look at his hands.
The cut on his
left index finger--
it's just like
the evidence log says.
Kelso's glove
is not in any
of the crime scene photos,
any of the sketches, anywhere.
ECKLIE:
Pictures get lost, Warrick.
I do remember that glove,
though.
Kelso's blood was all over it.
It is in the evidence log.
You see
who logged it in?
Jimmy Tadero.
Booked two days
after the murder.
So why no photos?
Want me to tag along?
He's my mentor.
If he screwed up
I don't think
he's going to want an audience.
( computer beeps )
( keyboard clacks )
You know those prints
that Nick and I
got off the rifle?
GRISSOM:
D.A. says it's enough
for a warrant.
Ananda's already
in custody.
Well, I better talk fast, then.
The prints are
only telling half the story.
Even when a shooter holds a gun,
he grips the barrel
and he wraps his index finger
around the trigger.
Ananda never fingered
the trigger.
What about the prints?
On the weapon, but definitely
not where they should be.
( computer beeps )
He held the rifle
by the stock
barrel pointing down.
He never fired it.
No. Anticipating
your next question
the rifle's not registered.
Well, Nevada doesn't require
rifle registration.
What's my next question?
That chewing gum--
is with DNA.
( whirring )
"Placa" was carved
into the panel
with a straight-edged blade.
Nondescript.
Not much to work with.
What's unusual is
the "placa" itself.
Bangers tag homicides
all the time.
Yeah, but after those
German tourists were killed
the Snakebacks were
pretty much wiped out.
The cops really came down hard
on those guys.
27 members were put away
for... for murder
and weapons possession,
drugs, you name it.
According to the Gang Unit
they've been out of business
about a year.
So we're looking at a Warhol.
Hmm?
Well, it's not a real soup can.
It's a painting of a soup can.
Not a gang member, uh...
wannabe?
Except, if you want to be
in a gang, you can be.
False clue.
Excuse me, sir?
I'm sorry to interrupt.
David, stop
calling me "sir."
What's up
with the Air Force?
You're all clear for tonight.
Air Force?
My dad's a colonel
out at Nellis.
Grissom's requested
a meeting.
Why?
I'm enlisting.
( chuckles )
Since 9-11, geosynchronous
government satellites
have maintained
a constant watch
over U.S. military
installations.
And the surrounding areas
as well, right?
This temple is less
than two miles from your base.
What's the chances your
satellite's picked something up?
We can see a postage stamp
on the sidewalk
outside Lenin's tomb.
Cool.
Hey. Glad to see
you're not in uniform.
Only one vehicle passed
through the temple gates
around the time
of the murders.
Parked next
to the monk's car.
"PROUD U.S."
Registered to a Peter Hutchins.
Did you get his picture
from outer space?
All photographs were
intermittent.
None included the driver.
The coffee shop?
Yep.
Would you like to, uh,
process the truck?
Sure.
Thank you.
Hi there.
Can I help you guys?
Yeah, I'm Nick Stokes.
This is Gil Grissom.
We're with the Vegas Crime Lab.
Pete Hutchins.
Uh, cops are always welcome.
Any sandwich,
on the house, guys.
No, thanks.
We're here about the murders
at the Buddhist temple
off Crystal Peak Drive.
Yeah, I heard about it.
I heard that, uh, some
of the local business owners
weren't very happy
with the members of the temple.
The monks?
Well, they don't speak English
and that bothered
the other customers.
And it's kind of hard to sell
beer, sandwiches or videos
when the monks don't partake
in any of those things.
MAN:
Those monks changed
the whole feel
of this neighborhood.
I'm not surprised
at any of these murders.
Your name is?
Peter Hutchins, Sr.
You know what?
I've owned this
shop for 20 years.
Suddenly,
these holy robers move in here
and business takes
a nose-dive.
And I don't care
what they say
it doesn't have
a damn thing to do
with the economy.
Good night, Las Vegas;
good morning, Vietnam.
Uh, Grissom, I found these
on the front seat.
Uh, which one
of you two guys
drives the
truck outside?
I do.
Well, these wouldn't be
your prayer beads, would they?
No. Isn't there
a law against her
sniffing around
inside my truck?
She has a warrant.
STOKES:
Sir, your vehicle was found
in the driveway of the temple
around the time of the murders.
Now, why would I go
to a Buddhist temple?
Probably not looking
for salvation.
( rock music playing )
Jimmy's running late.
Nothing changes, huh?
Oh, uh...
( laughing ):
Some things do.
Aw, you kidding, Catherine?
Any day of the week, honey
you can still have them
three deep, lined up at the bar.
You were always
nice to me, Ted.
Nice has nothing
to do with it, kid.
Let's face it,
you and this CSI stuff...
that's where you light up--
you're a natural.
Jimmy changed my life.
And no funny stuff,
just mentor and pupil.
Guy delivered me
into a whole new life.
Hey! Jimmy!
What's the case of the week?
Guy's up a tree, dead.
Mm-hmm?
Ex-wife in the bedroom,
with the pool man
both very alive, if
you know what I mean.
Guy's spying on his ex.
Has a heart attack
when he sees her
doing the nasty
with the pool man.
You must have read
the coroner's report.
Just my woman's intuition.
I wish he could have done
the same for Stephanie.
Yeah.
TADERO:
Hey, Cath.
What's the case of the week?
( sighs )
Wish I didn't know.
You up for this?
Ted.
I'll see you, kid.
This is where Stephanie
was found.
Worst day of my life.
Over there is where the
beat cop grabbed Kelso
as he was running out
into the alley.
That's right.
Now, do you remember where
you found Kelso's glove?
Up there, around the corner
of that dumpster.
I figure he'd dropped it,
trying to get away.
And then you logged
it into evidence?
No sketches, no photos.
Just brought it in two
days after the murder.
Yeah.
Arresting officer never saw
a glove, according to the file.
He was busy trying
to coral Kelso. It was dark.
I came back in the daylight.
What's going on?
You always used to say
if something doesn't feel right,
it probably isn't.
What do you want?
We got the guy.
Jimmy, you're not hiding
anything, are you?
You didn't try
to make things fit...?
I'm going to forget
you ever asked that.
I thought so.
( sighs )
Lot of activity
in this neighborhood.
Guy going the wrong way
on a one-way.
Fender bender on the corner.
Some guy running down
the middle of the street...
Good, we should go
after him, then
'cause the sandwich man's
going to walk.
His alibi checks out--
he was in Laughlin
with his wife
at a farmers market.
What about the truck?
Took the van.
Left the truck
in the driveway.
Junior?
Yeah.
Teenage kid, no parents,
keys to a ride.
I'm all over him.
SANDERS:
Results from
the colored material
found at the crime scene.
I'm trying to be humble,
but once again
I have the case breaker.
You may be right.
Paintball paint.
( rapid gunfire )
Whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa!
Knock it off!
Come on over here, Rambo.
Wow! One pop
to the chest
and you're out.
You got off easy.
What are you guys
doing here?
GRISSOM:
Well, we know that
your father's truck
was at the temple at
the time of the murders.
And our lab identified
boot prints
and paint residue
near the altar.
HUTCHINS JR.:
What kind of paint?
Water soluble, with
flecks of plastic coating
like the kind
on your clothes.
Toss them in the
wash, paint's gone.
( shots continue firing )
You were there, weren't you?
( clears throat )
I've never been
to the temple.
Never.
Well...
See...
this says that you were.
Tell him who you lent
your boots to.
Tell him, or they'll accuse
you of something else.
Nobody else
wears my boots.
Son...
( sighs )
We heard that this
place was freaky
that there was a
money tree and drugs.
We wanted to see
for ourselves.
( laughing )
That's got to be
solid gold, man.
( door opening )
Come on, come on...
We heard someone coming,
and we took off.
That's why you found
my boot prints.
No.
You see, our dust lifter
is only effective
on very recent prints.
I think you were there
the day of the murders.
It was a...
( clears throat )
It was a week ago when
I went there with my friends.
But Tommy, he copped a statue.
I went back to return it,
and I was removing my boots
when I looked inside
and I saw them laying there.
I wanted to call the police,
but I knew
if they found me there,
they'd think I did it.
How'd you know
to remove your boots?
You'd been there before?
Maybe.
What are you accusing
my son of now?
They were my friends.
Whoa, whoa.
Those monks were your friends?
I'm taking a walk.
( door closes )
Someone once asked the Buddha
"How do we escape the heat
of a summer's day?"
And the Buddha said
"Why not leap
into a blazing furnace?"
WILLOWS:
I got your beep.
Did you run those tests?
Kelso's glove--
embedded in the
fabric-- dog hair.
I isolated motor oil
on the thumb
and the rest of the stains
were bloodstains.
Kelso's, just like
in the report.
From where he cut himself
stabbing her?
You'd think, but you kind of
put me on a wild snipe hunt
so I tested for all biologicals,
and I ran amylase
and I found saliva.
Kelso's saliva?
Yeah.
Well, blood mixed with saliva
sounds like a mouth injury.
Did you check the blood
that Ecklie collected
from the murder weapon?
Also amylase.
Well, how did blood
from Kelso's mouth
end up on the glove
as well as the knife?
Unless it was planted.
Jimmy.
You set him up.
He killed her.
You don't know that.
Yes, I do.
When I stuck her,
she called out your name.
Where's a cop when you need one?
( Kelso yells )
Guys like Kelso brag
all the time
about things they didn't do,
cat-and-mouse...
He had a history of
roughing up girls.
He had a knife
cut on his hand.
But D.A...
got cold feet,
released him.
You don't have jack on me.
( Kelso grunting )
( Tadero muttering )
( Kelso choking )
I helped the
evidence along.
Good evidence
doesn't need help.
You taught me that one.
I'm going to have to ask you
for a sample of your blood.
What?
New technology.
We isolated male blood
on the murder weapon.
It doesn't belong to Kelso.
You think I killed Stephanie?
You were in love
with her, Jimmy.
That was no secret.
But the ring was.
Three karats
and she turned you down.
Same week she died.
I never thought
anything of it till now.
You're good.
You are.
I'll get a warrant.
Yeah, you do that.
You go get a warrant.
I'm going to have
to warn you
any food I find in the gum
is not going to be unique.
Why don't you
just give me
a suspect
I can match to?
I can't give you
what I don't have, Greg.
All we're going to have is
what we get from this gum.
All right, then I guess it's
slice and dice.
Thank you.
Results on
Jimmy Tadero's sample.
I just got it back from DNA.
( sighs )
Not going to take a look at it?
( laughs )
There was a shooting one night
in the club
and Jimmy pulls out
his revolver
and takes down the bad guy.
The guy's on the floor, dying.
Even though this was 15 years
ago, we still knew about AIDS.
Jimmy then puts his gun away,
he leans down--
he starts giving this guy
mouth-to-mouth
after having just shot him.
Forget his own life, he's going
to bring this guy back.
And he did.
You want me to open it?
( sighs heavily )
( laughter )
You've been excluded
on the murder weapon.
I could have
told you that.
Did you compare the unknown
against the club owner, Ted?
Yeah, I compared it to Ted.
I compared it
to every male in CODIS.
There were no hits, nowhere.
Have a seat, Jimmy.
I screwed up--
you want to hear me say it?
I liked Kelso.
Maybe I was wrong.
Yeah, you were.
So now what?
You know now what.
You're not serious.
You put a man away for life
on planted evidence, Jimmy.
He was a scumbag.
He copped to another murder.
Scumbag or saint,
what you did is a capital crime.
You can't play with evidence,
especially in a murder.
I can get life in prison if you
turn me in, do you know that?
Maybe even the death penalty.
Do you know that?!
What do you want me to do?
What do you
want me to do?
Do you want me to look
the other way?
Do you want me to dummy
my report?
I can't believe
you're doing this to me.
I gave you your career.
I earned my career
and you did this to yourself.
You fabricated evidence, Jimmy.
You were two steps away
from turning tricks.
This is the thanks I get?
I danced, period.
And instead of feeling
sorry for yourself
think about this.
When you were out there
planting evidence
on a case
that you couldn't break
Stephanie's real killer
got away.
And he's still out there
because you sold
the one thing a cop
can't afford to sell:
your integrity.
So you tell me,
between the two of us
who's the whore?
Arrest him.
You can hate me
all you want.
I'm going to see you
through this.
If you see the Buddha
on the side of the road,
kill him.
Because the true Buddha
is inside of us
so that is the false Buddha
or a tired monk
who doesn't drive
because he can't control
his anger.
Climb in, I'll
give you a lift.
We've cleared the father.
The son has
also been cleared.
And you're looking
for my help.
You know my religion better
than I know your science.
There was a gang placa
that was scrawled into
the walls of your temple.
It was put there
to mislead us.
The weapon we found
on your desk
was also put there
to mislead us.
The only other unexplained
evidence we have
is the chewing gum.
We found traces of
curry and saffron.
Somebody ate a meal,
then chewed gum.
Sometimes the best
evidence we get
comes from what people do
when they're not thinking.
Old habits, routines.
I don't think the gum was
put there to mislead us.
I think it was just a mistake.
And you want to know
what I eat for dinner.
Curry and saffron.
It's the real stuff.
The neighborhood kids
thought we imported drugs.
We just imported spices.
And the five of you
ate together that night?
Any guests?
No.
How come you don't leave
your cell phone on?
We're in a temple, O'Riley.
Oh, sorry.
I just left the bank.
Mr. Ananda here,
you're playing fast and loose
with the school
fund money.
He raised just
over $13,000
for the school fund
but you only deposited $12,000.
You planning any more
trips to Disneyland?
According to the bank
you opened the school fund
account on the same day
as the murders.
Where did you have
the money before that?
In a box in my office.
Curry powder.
Your temple employs
a part-time cook.
Mr. Suddahara moved on.
After you caught him
with his hand in the till?
Why didn't you tell us
about Mr. Suddahara before?
Because a man steals
doesn't mean he also kills.
Got any more of that
gum, Mr. Suddahara?
Fresh out.
( door opens )
Yep, his DNA matches
the gum sample.
You thought Ananda was going
to report you to the police
for stealing
the money.
Went home, got his rifle
came back to make sure
he didn't talk.
And he'd gone
to the bank
to protect the rest
of the money
but you didn't know that.
Where is he?
( chanting )
Did he go to the cops
already?
If they ask what I look like
here's your answer.
( gunshot )
I'm curious about
one thing, though.
Why did you shoot them all
in their sixth chakra?
I shot them
between the eyes.