( phones ringing )
Good afternoon.
I need to, uh,
make a withdrawal.
( clears throat )
I'll n-need to see
some identification.
( clears throat )
There's sufficient funds
in my account.
Just have to clear it
with my manager.
Is that going to take long?
I'll be right back.
( indistinct conversation )
Is there a problem here?!
It's a lot of money,
Mr. Logan.
It's going to
take some time.
Mr. Logan, would you like
an escort to your car?
( clears throat )
( indistinct police radio
transmission )
( tires screeching )
( alarm blares )
( car honking )
Everything all right, sir?
( phone ringing )
Do you want to get that?
I think you should step
out of the car.
Keep your hands
where I can see them.
Let's go.
Up.
So how rich is
this guy?
Well, he had
a million dollars
in his checking account.
Who doesn't?
He's a real estate
developer.
On the mayor's committee
to revitalize downtown.
And he hasn't said
a word to anyone?
Nope. That's why we're here.
( door opens )
No... I'm not saying anything
without my lawyer.
You don't have
to say anything.
Mr. Logan...
would you please
put your hands out?
Palms up.
I'm also going to need you
to strip.
What?
Vegas.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
Thank you, Mr. Logan.
You can put
your shirt down.
Left arm out, please.
Right arm.
No visible injuries.
No blood on his clothes.
How long is this
going to take?
Sorry for the inconvenience.
What the hell is
going on here?
Paul, get me out of here, now.
Roy, put your
clothes back on.
Don't say another word
to these people.
I'm taking my complaint directly
to the district attorney.
You had no grounds to detain
Mr. Logan
let alone disrobe him.
His hands were covered
in blood
and he had a million dollars
in his briefcase.
It's not a crime
to be rich.
Where's my car?
It's right up front.
My secretary
drove it here.
You're going to be hearing
from us.
Didn't Shakespeare say
"Let's kill all the lawyers"?
Yeah. Henry VI.
Where is he when we need him?
Yeah. Hey, can you do me a favor
and drop this off at the lab?
I'm due at a nursery rhyme
recital.
Lindsey's going to play
the girl in the moon.
What happen
to the man in the moon?
He got the mumps.
Mr. Logan!
( car alarm chirps )
You forgot your sunglasses.
Service-oriented policing.
You don't understand.
Get away from me.
( phone ringing )
Hello.
It's for you.
What?
Hello?
( high-pitched, altered voice):
Who are you?
CSI Three Willows.
Are you a cop?
Criminalist.
Good. Because if you had been
a cop
she'd already be dead.
Who would be dead?
Do you have a weapon?
Yes.
Then put it on the ground,
along with your pager
cell phone and that case
you're holding.
Who is this?
Do it!
We're watching you,
CSI Three Willows.
Attempt to go back
into the police station
and we'll kill her.
Attempt to contact any coworkers
Any false moves at all,
and Amanda is dead.
Now get back in the car.
You drive, anywhere but here
and await my next call.
What did he say?
Is Amanda all right?
Let's talk in the car.
( phone rings )
What'd you find?
The blood's female.
Definitely not Logan's.
BRASS:
I ran Roy Logan.
No criminal record;
no wants; no warrants.
The blood on his hand
was female.
The guy's married.
He lives in Summerlin.
He bucks up; got a
seven-year-old son.
But I'll check him out.
What about the car?
Code Five:
keep vehicle under
surveillance;
do not make contact
with occupants.
You know, Catherine
had a gun.
She could've used it.
You never answered
my question.
Who's Amanda?
Amanda's my girlfriend.
I know, I know.
My, uh, my wife doesn't know.
Somebody does.
How did they make contact?
I, uh, I probably left
a dozen messages for her
and, um, she, uh,
never called me back
so I went over to the condo...
to the condo
and, uh...
this was waiting for me
on the bed.
( car honking )
Got your attention.
My cell phone rang;
it was the kidnapper.
He said, uh, he wanted
a million dollars in cash
by the end of the day,
or he would...
he would send me
the rest of her.
He said if I...
talked to he cops...
Yeah, I heard that part.
I need a drink.
I can't believe you called.
I actually got you
outside of work.
This is nice.
I don't normally date
women from work
but there was...
something about you.
And it definitely wasn't
your perfume.
( coughs )
I cannot believe
you brought that up.
( laughs )
( car alarm chirps )
Yeah, that-that-that,
uh, day we met
that-that was,
that was very gross.
Um...
I mean, not for me
but for everyone else, for you.
Isn't that
one of your coworkers?
Yeah.
( clears throat )
We don't know how long
it's going to be
before he calls.
Why don't you
order something?
You expect me to eat?
We should be in the car,
waiting by the phone.
I have the phone.
Do us both a favor: relax.
What can I get you?
Um, two glasses:
one with ice;
one without.
Roy?
Uh, coffee. Black.
So, let's get
to know each other.
You first.
You were born; you came home
from the hospital.
Then what?
BROWN:
Maybe he wanted to confess.
Take her to the body.
Catherine wouldn't have
left her stuff behind.
Hey. I sent a patrolman
to Logan's house.
Talked to Mrs. Logan.
She's in perfect health.
She's not our vic.
So what do we do now?
We wait. Right?
Yeah. We don't have a crime yet.
Give me the finger.
What if somebody sees you?
I got to preserve this evidence.
( phone ringing )
Hello.
( high-pitched altered voice):
Take Boulder Highway south
till it intersects 93.
Take the Yucca exit, east,
one mile.
You'll see a sign:
Horseshoe Tavern.
You have one hour.
What'd he say?
Let's go.
Is that a finger?
Open the briefcase.
I've got an idea.
I use this
to paint my
daughter's face.
She was playing the moon
tonight in the school play.
I missed it.
Mark the edges of the money.
Do you got
any kids?
Yeah, I've got a son.
He's a soccer freak.
His life's ambition
is to be Roberto Baggio.
Hey, there's a cop.
There's cop.
Slow down. Come on.
We don't want
to be pulled over.
If we're seen
with a cop
Amanda's dead.
STOKES:
Catherine didn't say anything?
She barely made eye contact.
She dropped the finger
on the table and walked out.
Where is it?
Locked up at the Coroner's Lab,
waiting for Dr. Robbins.
Unless you want me to wake
him up in Kansas City.
Brother's wedding,
back tomorrow...
It was the right
index finger?
Top half severed
just below the right
intercostal joint.
Any hemorrhagic tissue?
Yeah, I couldn't tell.
There was blood, though.
How did
Catherine seem?
Like I told Nick,
she completely
ignored me.
And her behavior
toward Logan?
Was she under duress?
Agitated?
No... no,
looked to me
like Catherine was
running the show.
A severed finger,
a million bucks.
And Catherine's not allowed
to talk to anyone.
Kidnapping?
So, who's worth
one mil?
It's time to speak
to his wife.
I'll call Brass.
It's a bit
of a coincidence,
don't you think?
Catherine just showing
up at the diner.
It's not like she knew
I was going to be there.
I knew.
ROY:
That's it-- Yucca.
One more mile.
( tires screeching )
Are you crazy?
Sorry, it's been
a while
since I've driven
a sports car.
Thanks.
( gate creaking )
( inhaling )
( high-pitched, altered voice):
The briefcase.
First we need
to see Amanda.
Hand over the money
get back in the car,
and drive to a pay phone.
The Gas-and-Go
station
Highway 528,
south of Henderson.
I will call you.
I will tell you where she is.
No. We need something more
than just your word.
Then she's dead.
ROY:
No, wait!
The Gas-and-Go station,
Highway 582, south of Henderson.
( breathing heavily )
Mrs. Logan?
Yes? Uh, one
minute, please.
Oh, come on, honey, last time
you got food all over the place.
Your father
spent a fortune
detailing the car.
Mrs. Logan, I'm Jim Brass,
Las Vegas PD.
This is Nick Stokes, Crime Lab.
Hi.
BRASS:
Have you heard
from your husband?
( clears throat ):
No.
When he didn't come
home last night
did you find that unusual?
Or maybe you're used to it.
Look, our lawyer has advised me
not to speak to the police.
And until I hear from Roy
that's exactly
what I'm going to do.
How about if we just
have a look around?
I don't think so.
I don't see a phone.
( glass breaking )
Where's
the phone?
They set us up. She's dead.
I knew it!
He had a shotgun.
If all he wanted was the money,
we'd both be dead.
Give me the phone.
No, no, no-- no, no!
He said no phone calls.
They may be watch...
We're past that.
Give me the phone!
Listen, please. What if it was
someone you loved?
What if it was your daughter?!
The blood from the finger
was diluted due to the ice.
But I made a positive match.
To the blood
on Logan's hands.
So it was kind of
like Getty's ear?
They cut it off,
sent it to the house?
Wife was way too cool
to have seen a severed finger.
I don't think so.
He's a real estate developer.
Does he own any other
properties?
Townhouse off Flamingo.
Under the company name,
not rented.
But occupied?
I'll get a warrant.
See if anybody's missing
a finger over there.
Hey.
State Troopers just spotted
Logan's car on the 582.
Drove past him earlier
this morning.
Five minutes later,
drove past him again
other direction.
Grab Sara. We're gone.
( camera clicking )
Thank you, Catherine.
She was burning
some serious rubber.
Definitely high-end tires--
there's colored flecks
on the treads
and they're fresh.
It's got be Lexus.
Does this mean anything to you?
Looks like some kind
of glow paint stick.
BROWN:
I think Catherine
dragged her heels
a little bit here.
SIDLE:
Yeah.
Helium canister.
You mean like helium
for balloons?
You can also use it to change
the pitch in your voice.
The Lexus stopped there.
Catherine walked up to here.
So the second set
of fresh tire treads
on the access road
could be the kidnapper's.
Looks like the drop-off
went down.
Then why hasn't Catherine
contacted us yet?
Criminalistics. Anybody home?
Okay... talk to me.
( loud squawk )
( squawking )
( beep )
ROY:
Amanda, hi, it's me, Roy.
Where are you?
Call me on the cell.
( beep )
Amanda, I thought you'd be home
all day.
I wanted to swing by.
Call me.
( beep )
Amanda, it's Mark. At the gym.
You missed your session.
Call to reschedule.
( dial tone )
( loud squawk )
( continuous squawking )
Too bad you can't talk.
Maybe you could tell me
where she is.
Well... according
to the map
she should be somewhere
around here.
Amanda!
Why don't you give me a hand?
Oh, God...
DR. ROBBINS:
The finger was severed
postmortem.
No hemorrhagic tissue
at the point of injury.
And they used
a serrated blade.
Jagged teeth patterns
on the bone.
Not much else I can tell you.
It's just a finger.
( phone rings )
Grissom.
Thank God.
There was a kidnapping.
I know-- Amanda Freeman.
She's dead... and whoever
touched the money
probably has glow-in-the-dark
paint on their hands.
You got my clues?
Yeah, nicely done.
I know just about everything
except...
where are you?
She ate, but she didn't
fall asleep till way late.
We had her helping Greg
go out in the lab.
I bet she loved that.
Yeah.
I owe you.
Thank you.
Oh...
GRISSOM:
So, you couldn't see
what he looked like?
You're assuming
it was a "he."
Rabbit mask.
Full-beam headlights.
Truman Capote voice.
Who can tell gender?
Amanda Freeman.
My guess is, she's been
in the water about 24 hours.
Washerwoman effect.
But no saponification.
Blowfly eggs?
Unhatched ova.
They're waterlogged.
I found some in her nose
and trachea, too.
The decomposing body
would need time
to attract the bugs
before submersion.
Well, she's been dead 48 hours
24 hours above water,
24 hours under.
Bloody nose, ecchymosis.
She took a beating.
Cause of death?
Blunt-force trauma.
Back of the head.
Look at this.
What is it?
You'll have to get it
under the microscope.
My guess is
some form of stone.
Granite maybe.
I'm going to head over
to the townhouse
check out those blood spots
with Nick.
Mr. Logan?
I need to see her.
Please.
I wouldn't advise that.
Look, she...
was my life.
I loved her.
Please?
Ooh... ooh...
It's my fault.
If I'd only...
gotten to her sooner.
If I'd only paid them sooner...
It wouldn't have made
any difference.
She was killed long before
you could have helped her.
When?
Where?
WILLOWS:
You've got to give
us time.
Why don't you go home,
get some sleep?
I-I don't think I can face
my wife right now.
This town is
full of hotels.
All right.
You can find me
at the Tangiers.
Marble.
Good to see you again.
Yeah, somebody hit the table.
There's obvious signs
of a struggle.
Kidnapper probably broke in.
She made a run for it.
Got hit in the face.
Went down.
( screaming )
Blood pool here.
Spatter all the way
to the bird.
Birds have blood feathers
and flight feathers.
Flight feathers
don't bleed.
No capillaries,
just cartilage.
And you know this from...?
Discovery Channel.
So, how did the killer get
the body out of the house?
There's no blood
trail from here
to the door,
so my guess is
he wrapped her
in something.
Bedsheets?
Checked.
Bed's still made.
Linen closet's full.
Not to mention,
a wet sheet leaks.
Plastic, maybe.
If she was murdered here
her finger was severed here
where are the knives?
Clever.
Kidnapper washed all the knives.
Why wash the knives
and leave the wine glasses?
Get those glasses to Greg.
Yeah, looks like someone ripped
the liner out.
He wrapped her in it.
Must've gotten dumped
when she did.
Watch your step.
Thank you.
Here we are.
BRASS:
Ran Amanda Freeman's
phone records.
Creature of habit.
Mother, gym,
Logan, pizza.
But the last call made
from that house was
to a cell phone
we traced to Mrs. Logan.
Greg got saliva off
the wine glasses.
Ran the DNA. One was Amanda,
and the other a woman.
Mrs. Logan, maybe.
They would have had
a lot to talk about.
Or fight about.
Looks like a small tear.
Looks more like a slice.
Could've happened
when he cut through her finger.
Does this look like blood
to you?
If the body was wrapped
with this side
that's on the outside.
It's not blood.
Yeah.
This is a grease stain.
An oily substance.
( machine humming )
( beeping )
SANDERS:
Did you guys clean the table
before putting the curtain
on it?
Yeah.
'Cause I think
your evidence got contaminated.
With what?
Oleic acid.
Goes well with jelly.
Peanut butter.
Great.
Hey, Nick?
Yeah?
Have you been eating
peanut butter
in the layout room?
No, man, I hate the stuff.
Well, we found it
on the back of that
shower curtain.
STOKES:
Mrs. Logan scolded her son
for eating in the car.
Peanut butter and jelly.
Said her husband just had
the car detailed.
I need to take my car
to this detailer.
Not bad.
Come on. You know
that treating the surface
with a carpet cleaner only
pushes the dirt further down?
Warrick, you got
those box cutters?
Did I mention how much
I hate peanut butter?
Mrs. Logan, do you
know Amanda Freeman?
Because she called you
on your cell phone
the day she was murdered.
Could have been
a wrong number.
Then, uh, what did
you talk about
for three minutes
and 55 seconds?
WILLOWS:
We could compel
a DNA sample
which would confirm that you had
a glass of wine
with her that night.
Is it your intention
to charge my client
with Miss Freeman's kidnapping?
I think you went to your
husband's townhouse--
a townhouse you
probably didn't
know he had-- and
a civilized drink
turned into a violent brawl.
( yelling )
You tore down the shower curtain
wrapped the body in it.
Cut off her finger,
stuck it in a mint tin
and left it for your husband.
WILLOWS:
You transported the body
to the reservoir
in the back of your SUV
where some
of your son's PB and J
made it onto the
shower curtain.
Are you finished?
Diane?
I had my drink
with Miss Freeman.
I listened
to her rantings
about how she and Roy
were getting married.
That's enough, Diane.
And I set her straight.
Roy was not going
to leave me for her.
He loved his money
more than both of us.
I told her I was going
to evict her
from that tacky
little townhouse
and then Roy came in.
You should have seen
the look on his face.
And I-I left them there
to work it out.
Okay...
If you don't have
anything else?
One more thing.
Mrs. Logan, can you hold
your hands out
palms up?
Jim, can you
hit the lights?
We don't have time
for these games.
Okay, you satisfied?
Whoa!
Look, I can explain.
Look, I put on a mask
I made some phone calls
I took the money
but I did not
break any laws.
You killed Amanda Freeman.
Oh, no.
I didn't kill anybody.
I didn't even know she was dead.
I'm a lawyer.
I work for my client.
I did what
he asked me to do.
Your client?
Roy Logan.
What are you saying?
That Mr. Logan paid you
to dress up as a bunny rabbit?
That was my idea.
So, Roy Logan set
this whole thing up?
Yes.
It started with a phone call.
I just did what
my client asked.
I just played a part.
So, basically, this was a stage
play written by Mr. Logan.
That's right. Now you got it.
GRISSOM:
During this
elaborate farce
you never thought
to ask him
why he was making you
jump through these hoops?
I don't get paid to ask.
I get paid to do.
What about the money?
A million dollars cash?
Well, Roy was having
marital problems
so I figured he was just
hiding his assets.
Where's the money now?
In a locker.
At his country club.
Where did Logan
say he was staying?
The Tangiers.
I'll drive.
I'll follow the money.
Mr. Logan?
Open the door.
Please.
I'll call down, see if
his car's in the parking lot.
Fat chance.
Son of a bitch.
He had me completely fooled.
I bet that locker's empty, too.
Okay, let's run this.
Amanda was tired of being number
two, so she calls up Mrs. Logan
to discuss her affair
with her husband.
But Mrs. Logan doesn't just
discuss it
she throws down the gauntlet.
He's not going to leave me
for you.
( door opening )
He already has.
Amanda broke the only rule.
Don't call the Missus.
Now he really has a problem.
Two problems.
His wife is going to leave him,
take half his money
and he was going to jail.
You got to admit,
his solution was ingenious.
GRISSOM:
Most killers take their time
planning a murder.
He took his time
covering it up.
48 hours to be precise.
So Logan cleans up
the crime scene
and calls his lawyer.
Asks him to help him
with his little charade.
I mean, what better way
to protect your assets
than to pay a kidnapper
who's already on retainer?
Everything from that point on
was calculated.
Blood on his hands
he's the last customer
of the day at the bank
acting suspiciously
driving recklessly.
He knew he'd get hauled
in to the cops.
WILLOWS:
You bet your ass.
He didn't leave those
sunglasses behind by accident.
His cell phone rang on cue.
The call's for me.
( high-pitched, altered voice
talking on phone )
He practically forced that money
into his lawyer's hands.
Out of one pocket
into the other.
I especially liked
the little show he did for us
in the coroner's lab.
Trying to find out
how much we knew.
When? Where?
Why make the map?
Why lead Catherine
to the body?
Because without the body, Logan
would always be under suspicion.
If not by the police,
by his wife.
So, he left these wine glasses
for you to find.
Sure, we wanted us
to suspect the wife.
That's why he
used her SUV
to transport the body.
And he let me mark the money
because he knew that eventually
his lawyer would touch it.
Why though?
The money was
in a suitcase.
A million dollars.
Tempting.
I saw the locker
and I saw Logan's briefcase.
It was too big to fit inside.
His lawyer had to remove
the cash by hand.
How could he possibly know
that Catherine was
going to mark the money?
He didn't.
He probably thought
the bank marked it.
Besides, there's always
fingerprints.
So I did everything in my power
to help him.
Yeah, and he's probably
long gone by now.
( cell phone ringing )
Willows.
Yeah.
That's a beautiful car,
that SC-430.
Don't get to see a nice car like
that in these parts too often.
So when I see one twice
in two days, I notice.
Especially when the driver's
exceeding the speed limit.
Bravo.
You know, with all that money
on my lap
we could've driven to Mexico.
That's right.
You're short one mistress.
I got to hand it to you
that was a brilliant
performance.
But then again,
any man
who juggles a wife and mistress
and God knows what else
has to be a pro.
I don't know.
You get so used to lying
you figure, what's one more?
Try explaining that to your son.