( birds chirping )
( dog barks )
Hey.
How'd you guys get out?
( barking )
What's the matter,
boys?
Easy.
Hey...
( indistinct radio chatter )
( helicopter whirring )
( camera shutter clicking )
Have you been inside?
What have you got?
There you go,
Detective.
Thanks.
Little tired this morning.
Pulling a double.
Yeah, join the club.
Good morning,
Catherine.
Gil.
So, this is
Tony Braun's house.
Son of Sam Braun.
GRISSOM:
He was Steve Wynn
before Steve Wynn.
Oh, yeah,
you bet your ass.
Sam came to Vegas
when Vegas was dying.
Built three casinos
in a year.
Had ties to
Bugsy Siegel.
Wish I had Tony Braun's gardener
working for me.
Guy sniffed it out
from the jump.
Blinds were drawn shut.
Side gate unlocked.
Dogs let out.
"A" plus "B" plus "C"
equals 9-1-1.
All seems very neat
and peaceful, doesn't it?
Chasing the dragon.
A pinch of "H."
Heat the foil.
Inhale the fumes.
With a Xanax back.
100 pills.
Prescription filled
yesterday.
So the rumors
about ol' Tony boy are true.
Drug overdose.
It sure seems that way.
If only life
were that simple.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
( indistinct radio chatter )
SIDLE:
Eight rolls.
Two copies.
Case is hot.
Put a rush on it.
Lose an earring?
Looks like somebody did.
He's got adhesive residue
on his wrists.
He was restrained.
Some sort of tape.
Well, that would be the obvious.
Braun had company.
Welcome...
or unwelcome?
Where's the purge?
Car blows its engine,
there's an oil leak.
A guy ODs,
where's the body fluid?
Urine, vomit, excrement.
Did somebody clean him up?
SIDLE:
Interesting love bites
on the chest.
Curious, isn't it?
And he's posed.
When did you know
this was a homicide
and not an OD?
Initially?
Yeah.
When I saw the TV on.
( barks )
Well, I'll tell
you one thing--
if those were my dogs
I wouldn't be leaving
this gate open.
Yeah, you're talking
about a dog owner on heroin.
How responsible can he be?
Gardener said it was
the first time in five years
that he'd found
this gate unlocked.
What's so different
about this morning?
Last morning of
Tony Braun's life?
Well, either somebody
inside the house
opened it, or
somebody had a key
because this lock
hasn't been forced.
There's no pry marks.
No metal shavings.
So... why was
the gate open?
BROWN:
A heroin addict's confetti.
Nothing like going
on a binge.
Some black tar heroin.
This is the difference
between a Cadillac and a Pinto.
How would you know?
It's my job.
I count at least
six balloons,
and that's
just in the bedroom.
The dealer must have come
down the chimney.
It's like Christmas
in July here.
Not that Braun
even needed any more drugs.
Yeah, looks like the guy
had a pill for everything.
Can you get a print
off those balloons?
I can get a print
off the air.
Any luck?
I have gone through every
garbage can in the house.
What about
the cans outside?
First thing I
checked. Zip.
( rattling )
( handle rattling )
Hey, Doc.
Leg fell asleep.
( clicks )
I always wondered
which one of us coroners
would get to carve Tony.
His lifestyle was no secret--
sex, drugs
and a big bankroll.
No needle marks
on his arms.
The guy plays golf;
short-sleeved shirts
Checked between
the toes... groin area.
Whatever he did
went up his nose.
His nasal cavity
looks like
raw hamburger.
These abrasions around
his mouth? What?
Hard to shave
when you're stoned?
Or they're pressure marks.
For example, if someone
places a pillow or object
against someone's
nose and mouth
in the climate of struggle.
Petechial hemorrhaging?
Also suggestive
of suffocation.
Not always.
For as much as pathology is
an absolute science, it isn't.
Vessels can rupture
under innocent circumstances
such as a violent cough.
These three, circular,
red marks on his chest?
They're not bug bites.
No neurotoxins present
but that's not to say
some overanxious paramedic
trying to save a legend's life
didn't cause them in the moment.
CPR wasn't performed.
Then I don't know
what they are.
It's hard to OD
just inhaling heroin.
I know he was restrained
which leads me to believe
that someone forced him
to ingest lethal amounts
of heroin and Xanax.
( indistinct radio chatter )
Excuse me.
Boy, are you lucky my lawyer's
on a golf course.
I've been standing out here,
in the heat
for hours, answering
these stupid questions.
Here's your answer, okay.
This is my house.
Okay?
This is half my house anyway.
Who's this?
BRASS:
It's Braun's squeeze.
She's an ex-stripper, too.
Perhaps you two met
in a professional capacity.
These are my things...
And, uh, where has she
been the past 12 hours?
Uh, let's see.
Oh, my God.
"Out."
When Tony's drug dealer
showed up, she split.
She slept at a
friend's house.
She didn't like
the way Tony acted
when he was cruising
on magic carpets.
Look, you two, listen--
if anything is missing
from this house
I'm going to add you
to my lawyer's "to sue" list.
Why don't you
just put the camera away
before you get arrested?
You can't arrest me
in my own house.
Right now,
your house is our crime scene...
and we can do whatever we want
and that includes
fingerprinting you.
Why?
Didn't do anything.
Thumb to pinkie.
I just lost
my boyfriend, okay?
You're a woman.
I'm just looking out
for my end here, you know?
Things start to disappear.
If Tony were here right now,
he'd tell you himself
"Just make sure
Janine's taken care of."
That's a lawyer's call.
Hey, I'm in the will.
Of course you are.
Can I help you?
Yeah. Is Sam Braun in?
He's not seeing anyone today.
Would you let him know
that Catherine Willows
is here to see him?
( keyboard clacking )
Just one second, please.
Mugs?
I remember
the first time I saw you.
You didn't have
any clothes on.
Yeah, well, that
was a long time ago.
I would've taken you home
right then, if you had let me.
I know, but you
were married.
I was a baby.
It would've never worked.
Sam... how are
you holding up?
Hey, Dad, I got the press
clogging up Valet.
Should I call Security
or just handle it, or what?
I'll take care of it.
You go back to the pit.
Make sure nobody's
robbing us blind.
You know, back
in, uh... in '67
I was in my 20s and...
I was drinking in a dive
in downtown Buffalo.
At the end of the bar
was this pro quarterback
drinking double scotches,
two at a time
midnight to 7:00
in the morning.
It's Sunday,
game day, mind you.
So you know
what I did?
Called my bookie,
bet against him.
Guess what?
I'll be damned if he didn't
throw six touchdown passes.
( laughing ):
Yeah...
Sounds like Tony.
You know,
even when Tony was juicing
he could run circles around
these college, Harvard types.
( sniffling )
And I'm not saying that
just because he was my kid.
Tony was the best damn casino
exec this town has ever seen
and just between you and me...
I couldn't hold a candle to him.
Now he's dead.
Overdose.
Sam...
The bigger the pedestal
the bigger the target.
Nobody shoots at that target
without going through me.
Well, that's business.
What about personal?
What do you mean?
Did you ever talk
to Tony
about any
of his girlfriends?
Which one?
I mean, they were all trying
to pick the gold
out of his teeth.
Janine Haywood.
She's the worst...
and he loved her the most.
Can you believe it?
Yeah, I do.
If I know her type,
now that she has the gold
she'll be going
after the silver.
( footsteps passing )
Okay, on the left,
Braun prints we got
from the Coroner
and on the right,
gold digger prints
I got
from Janine Haywood.
Here's where it
gets interesting.
I took six prints
off this bottle.
And?
They all belong
to one person.
Good thing or...
bad thing?
It's good if you're us...
( keyboard clacking )
bad if you're
Janine Haywood.
Have you seen Brass?
Not tonight, no. Why?
Oh, print off air.
Orange balloon.
Cyanoacrylate.
Dead bang, drug dealer.
Ooh, ooh, watch it!
Evidence.
Where did you get it?
Cracker box.
It was all stuck
together, muckety-muck.
I don't want to ruin
any potential prints
but I saw this TV dinner
commercial and it hit me.
I'm going to put it
in the freezer.
Did you try this coffee?
Mm-mm.
The last cup I had
tasted like motor oil.
Oh, don't touch it.
That's my pot!
Your pot?
Yeah, you know, from
my own private stash.
Blue Hawaiian--
$40 a pound.
Only grown a couple times
a year on the Big Island
hand-picked to perfection.
Good.
You're using my water
so I guess that makes it
community coffee.
You want a cup, Nick?
No, thanks.
What's the matter
with your leg?
I don't know, man.
Something back at that house
must have bit me.
Oh, is that alcohol
on a bug bite?
That's like butter
on burns, man.
Wives' tale.
Yeah, this is the guy
who told me
to put hemorrhoid cream
on my acne.
It worked, didn't it?
This is pretty good.
Let me see the bite
before you get gangrene.
Chigger bite.
Yeah?
Probably picked it up
walking through the ferns
in Braun's backyard.
See if Catherine's got
some clear nail polish.
It'll seal it off from the
air, keep it from itching.
What happened with
that doggy door?
Something definitely two-legged
went through it.
Got mostly partials.
Print Lab's working on it now.
Be sure to check it against
Janine Haywood's prints.
Braun's stomach contents.
No food.
Plenty of drugs.
Xanax?
And heroin.
I thought he inhaled it.
Inhaled and ingested.
He ate it?
Got there somehow.
Where are all the
undissolved pills?
Didn't find any.
Most OD's die before
digestion's complete, right?
My guess, someone
mashed up the Xanax
dissolved them in red wine,
which I did find.
Okay, so what do we know
that we can write home about?
Well, Braun was a heroin addict
using heavy just before he died
which means he was probably
meek as a lamb.
Wouldn't have taken much to bind
his hands with duct tape.
And make him drink hemlock.
It's a lot easier
to pour liquid
down a guy's throat
than it is to make him
swallow 100 pills.
It wasn't 100 pills.
How many?
Educated,
unofficial guess:
No more than 50.
Based on your pupes,
I could take you in right now.
Hey, man, I'm in mourning.
It's tears you see.
I lost a customer.
It's like losing
my job, kind of.
You're Braun's grocery store.
But I deliver.
When did you
last deliver?
Night before
he croaked.
About 9:00--
ask his woman.
She's fine, too.
Well, she told us as soon as
you got there, she left.
Oh, she didn't go that fast.
I dropped off some balloons
Braun paid me,
she gave me a tip.
What, shave the soul patch?
( laughs )
No.
30 Xanadus.
Xanax?
I told you I dropped them
down the bathroom sink.
First time I heard that.
Look, I took two
gave Tony two
and I accidentally dropped
15 or 20
down the sink.
It was an accident.
You know,
an accident?
Haven't you ever
spilled a drink?
Not lately.
We found 50 Xanax
in Tony's stomach.
Don't pin that on me.
I'd left.
I'll tell you what you left--
your fingerprints
all over
the prescription bottle.
I went to the pharmacy
waited in line
picked up the prescription
signed for it
brought it back to the house.
Tony did nothing
for himself
except work and get high.
Got you a brand-new Mercedes,
didn't it?
Yes, it did.
And it'll buy me
the dress I wear
at Tony's funeral, too.
Look, when you left
your half a house
where did you go?
A friend's.
Well, let's get her on the line.
She's out of town.
Let me guess--
she's incommunicado.
That means you can't reach her?
Yeah.
Oh, mind the dummy.
It's been 24 minutes, Greg.
When's this thing
going to be done?
Well, with all due respect, sir,
it's not a baked potato.
It's Braun's blood
and with all the impurities
in his system
it might take
a little extra time.
Did I ever tell you
I used to live in New York?
Is this going to be
a short story or a novel?
( machine beeps )
Excuse me.
You know, heroin has
a nine-minute half-life.
After that,
it metabolizes
into morphine.
What's the six-MAM count?
158 nanograms per mil.
Definitely not lethal.
The same with your Xanax.
Quarter-mil tabs,
100 micrograms per liter.
Again, not lethal.
There's addicts
walking around Times Square
with more drugs in their system.
So Braun should still
be walking around.
And the point of your
New York story was...?
Oh, I was just
going to tell you about
another way to take heroin--
a suppository up the coolee.
You just stand on your head,
and then you let gravity...
Forget it.
Braun didn't die
of a drug overdose
accidental or otherwise.
I figured.
So why'd I bring the dummy?
Braun's shirt.
Robbins opened him up.
His lungs
were compressed.
Remember Burke and Hare
the two 19th century
Scottish body snatchers
who made a living
intoxicating innocent victims
and suffocating them?
Sold their cadavers
to teaching hospitals?
Got away with it, too,
until a medical student
discovered his fiancee
on a slab.
Is this part of
the Sherlock Holmes
Fan Club kit?
Janine Haywood said that
she left the house when
the drug dealer arrived.
I think she came back.
So Braun would have been on his
third or fourth balloon by then.
Would have been easy
to tape his wrists
mash up 50 pills...
and force-feed him
a Xanax cocktail.
So everything was going great
until the gardener showed up.
Then I think her plan
turned to panic.
It takes time to OD--
time Janine didn't have.
Burke would kneel on
his victim's chest, right
covering their mouth
and nostrils.
But when you're
doing drugs
you're a slob
and when you're
being manhandled,
you're even sloppier.
Like this.
He was Burked.
( phone ringing )
Hello.
( staticky voice )
Where?
Brass, you're breaking up.
Said he was in Blue Diamond,
digging something up.
( sirens wailing )
Hey... Hey,
what's going on?
Anybody ever tell you
to call before you dig?
I got permission to be here.
From who?
A dead man?
You got a name?
My name's Curt Ritten.
Look, Tony Braun was
a friend of mine, right?
This is his property.
He calls me
about a month ago.
He says "If anything
should happen to me,
you start digging.
You take care of what's
mine at all costs."
That's what I'm doing.
BRASS:
Do me a favor.
Put down the shovel.
Okay.
Stand over there.
Maybe Janine had a helper.
Hey, guys, you might want
to check out the basement.
"A sable cloud turns forth
its silver lining to the night."
That's a lot of motive.
And a lot of silver.
Okay, three rolls of tape
found in the truck
owned by Curt Ritten.
Nice.
Let's see if that's
where my print came from.
No match!
Oh, listen to you.
Would you rather hit
a home run in the fourth
or the bottom
of the ninth?
Let me ask you something.
Braun collected silver--
coins, bullion--
23 tons of it.
Why bury it
in Blue Diamond?
'Cause he was smart.
In the past 20 years
the value of silver's
gone to nothing
and a commodity broker's
going to charge you
a storage fee per troy ounce
and there's only one thing
worse than losing
seven to eight percent
on silver a year
and that's losing
nine to ten percent
because of some
stupid storage fee.
What good's collecting
silver coupons
when you're dead?
Depends on
who's doing the clipping.
Oh, we got a positive
association.
Roll to tape.
Curt to Tony.
You arresting me for digging?
No, burglary, theft
and conspiracy, to start.
Tony asked me
to move his silver collection
up to his ranch in Wyoming.
I'm doing what I was told.
Mr. Ritten...
it appears that
we may have
physical evidence
connecting you
to the murder
of Tony Braun.
Look, I had nothing
to do with the drugs.
I swear to you,
I haven't messed around
with that stuff
in a long time.
I was always telling
Tony, as a friend
to get off of it,
to walk away.
How'd you know
where the silver was buried?
Because I built the vault
for him.
I'm a contractor.
That's what I do.
Ever work on his house?
No.
We did... we did talk
about me building a basement
for him once.
It never got
off the ground.
Oh, so,
you've been to his house?
We were friends.
I've been to his house
plenty of times.
I was there
a couple weeks ago.
We were watching
the Notre Dame game together.
Did you ever leave
anything there?
Did you ever bring anything
over to his house?
Yeah, I brought
a six-pack
and some chips--
sour cream.
Tools of the trade,
Curt.
Construction items--
hammer, duct tape?
No.
Why would I do that?
I got no idea
what you're talking about.
Yeah, well, whatever you
don't tell us, we'll find it.
That's the quickest warrant
I ever got.
Yep. Braun family.
Long arms.
I thought you said
that Ritten's wife lives
in Carson City.
She does.
They both do.
He just stays here
when he's working.
Or digging up silver.
( shower running )
Mrs. Ritten?
Criminalistics.
VEGA:
Police officer.
Geez!
You scared me.
How'd you get in here?
I don't have to ask
you that question.
How can this be, Mandy?
We found the duct tape
in the guy's truck.
SIDLE:
You're telling us
the prints on that tape
aren't his or hers?
Well, if their names are
Curt Ritten and Janine Haywood
the answer's, "No,
it's not their prints."
This is ridiculous.
This thing must have a virus.
Maybe you have
the wrong suspects.
Well, that's easy
for you to say.
All you do is scan prints
all day and hit "enter."
Look, I'm not your
beast of burden.
Sara, this is your thing.
Mandy...
give me something dandy.
I'll give you something dandy.
Your doggie-door prints.
Good-bye, I have to go
on a break now.
See what I mean?
Your prints came back unknown,
too?
No.
Came back Walt Braun.
Who is he?
He's Tony Braun's brother.
He's a pit boss
at the Tangiers
which is why his
prints were on file--
gaming card.
He's family.
Why's he using the doggie door
and not the front door?
( chuckling ):
Go figure.
The more evidence
that shows up
the more this case
doesn't make sense.
We got two suspects
in custody
and neither of their prints
are on the duct tape.
Or on the doggie door...
but the brother's are.
Mm-hmm.
So, call the print lab.
It's been done.
They're not Walt Braun's
prints on the tape.
Came back unknown.
Hey.
I've got Detective Vega
rounding up Walt Braun.
Apparently, this
Janine Haywood
really got around.
When she wasn't
at Braun's house
playing girlfriend,
she's over at "Vault Boy's"
flat
playing mistress...
which gives neither of them
a credible alibi.
Flimsy alibis
don't prove murder.
What else have we got?
Nothing probative.
BRASS:
Then I let the
girlfriend go.
Curt Ritten goes back to
lock-up until he posts bail.
Look, forget Curt.
Forget Janine.
Forget the suspects.
It's simple.
We got to figure out
how a piece of duct tape
from a roll we found
in Curt Ritten's truck
ended up wrapped
around the wrists of our victim.
Without Curt's prints on it.
( speaking indistinctly )
Curt, we're out of here.
Oh, you're going
to take this, too, huh?
CURT:
Bonnie...
I come down here with a check
to bail my husband out
and you say to him,
"We're out of here"?
No, honey,
you're out of here!
CURT:
Bonnie, take it easy.
BONNIE:
Take it easy?!
How many men
do you need, huh?
Hey, at least I can take care
of mine.
I've stuck by you
through the bankruptcies
the flings, the lies,
and I have had it, okay?
So, you choose.
Me or her?
Sorry, Janine.
Yeah...
Heard that before.
JANINE:
Call me.
BRASS:
Bail processing is
this way.
Been there.
MAN:
You came down here
to ask me
about a doggie door?
I could've just told you
over the phone.
It's a quirk.
I always like to discuss
fingerprints in person.
Hmm. Tony and I went
to dinner.
How long ago?
A while back.
Be more specific.
Uh, about a month
and a half ago.
We ate at Piero's
talked a little business--
I dropped him off.
TONY:
Walt...
( no audio )
My key still works here.
How come it doesn't work
on the front door?
I changed the locks.
WALT:
And, so,
I used the doggie door
walked through the house,
opened the door, let Tony in.
Guy with that kind of money
doesn't have a security alarm?
When you're a Braun
there's nothing
you can't replace.
You can't replace
your brother.
What's the matter with your leg?
I don't know.
Something must've bit me.
Mind if I take a look?
What are you,
a dermatologist?
I'm an entomologist,
actually.
I-I know all about bugs.
Sure.
Can you tell me
what to put on it?
It's killing me.
Chigger bites.
You might want to
try some nail polish,
keep it from itching.
Would you mind if I
took a photograph
for my bite collection?
Whatever rubs
your Buddha.
We're almost done.
Mr. Braun, uh,
where do you live?
Shoshone Hi-Rise--
J.W. Brown Road.
VEGA:
And you work here?
Yeah, I'm a glorified pit boss.
In the, uh,
last 48 hours
have you been anywhere else
besides those two places?
WALT:
No.
My life's pretty routine.
It might just get
a little more routine.
GRISSOM:
Nick, I need your leg.
Show me your bite.
Oh, it's no worries.
I got some cream.
Hey.
All right.
It's no big deal,
really.
What time did you log in
at the Braun house?
9:15 that morning.
How long after
that did you start
processing the backyard?
About a half hour.
You're not the only one
with chigger bites.
Who is this?
Walt Braun.
It's now 9:30 at night.
Approximately 36 hours
ago, you were bitten.
Three hours
earlier than that
Tony Braun was murdered.
Chiggers run a
predictable course.
A chigger attaches itself
to a hair follicle
injects a digest enzyme
into the skin
which ruptures
the surrounding cells
allowing the chigger
to suck them up
leaving behind a
red, itchy bump.
So...?
Walt Braun lied.
We now have an
entomological timeline
that places him at
the house on the day
his brother was murdered.
I don't know, Boss.
I mean,
ask yourself the question--
are doggie-door prints
and chigger bites enough
to get a man for murder?
What've we got?
Well, I got motive.
According to the
family lawyer,
the drug addict...
Now, Jim, that's just
a little callous.
I'm calling it what it is.
I know you're friends
with the family
but the guy used heroin.
He was a drug addict
who stood in line
to inherit
the old man's fortune.
What about the brother?
Walt's out of the picture.
Out in the cold.
He is?
Yeah.
Tony promised he'd
take care of him.
Whatever he got,
he'd split 50-50
all in...
silver included...
up until about
a month ago.
But Tony changed his mind,
which changed the will.
WILLOWS:
So, wait a second--
Janine, the stripper
claims that half
of everything is hers
so that's actually more
than just wishful thinking?
Bet Walt wasn't too
happy about that.
It's 50-50 going 75-25
the wrong way.
Curt was digging up the silver
to protect Janine's interest.
So, what's right in front of us
that we're missing?
What evidence do we have
that's still open?
Got the references
off of Walt Braun
gave the samples to Greg.
SIDLE:
Couple of things
on the list that haven't
been processed yet:
Tape lifts, adhesive residue,
I got the earring back.
Where'd you find that?
Living room, near the body.
We have to deal
with that earring.
We got to test it
against Janine.
You want to swab me,
go ahead
but I can save you the Q-Tip.
That's really not my style.
Ms. Haywood...
you have pierced ears.
Yeah.
He doesn't understand.
I don't wear studs.
Haven't worn studs
since, like...
God, seventh grade.
Mm-hmm.
Can I see that picture?
Thanks. See?
This is an earring back.
It goes to a stud earring.
I don't wear studs.
I'm more of, like,
a dangle gal.
I like chandeliers.
They move with you.
They're on wires.
They don't have a back.
Are you finished?
Open your mouth.
Don't bite down.
Wouldn't want you
to swallow it.
GRISSOM:
How about your
girlfriends
or Tony's girlfriends--
any of them wear studs?
Look, rule number one:
no women allowed in the house.
Tony had a wandering eye,
he had a wad of cash
who needed that drama?
What about the maid?
No. Rule number two:
Heavyset, over 50, no makeup,
no jewelry, no English.
Wow.
You got this whole thing down
don't you?
Yeah. This is my house.
I didn't do anything wrong.
And I inherited Josie,
and she cleans real good.
How often does she vacuum?
Every day.
Except on her day off.
Hmm. The day Tony died.
Hmm.
Well, if the maid is
as good as Janine
says she is...
then the earring back
was lost that day.
There. Well, maybe not.
The earring back--
not Janine's.
But it was in the ear
of a female.
So, I guess rule number one
was broken.
There was a woman
in the house.
Are you thinking
what I'm thinking?
Whoever's prints are
on the duct tape is
missing an earring back.
Who's the only other
woman in the story?
She lives in Carson City.
She's here now.
She has access
to Curt's truck.
We saw the fight in
the police department.
"Hell hath no fury..."
It's not mine.
I don't wear earrings.
GRISSOM:
It's funny,
just recently
I had a little
education in earrings
and I noticed that
you have pierced ears.
Yeah. So what?
If you don't wear
earrings for a while
the holes will close up.
BRASS:
Will you volunteer
as a DNA sample?
It will confirm your story
or confirm ours.
I'm not giving you anything.
It's okay, Jim,
we have enough.
You should let your
husband rot in jail.
We lifted your thumbprint
from the check that you posted
for his bail.
GRISSOM:
We compared it to a
set of unknown prints
that we found on
some duct tape
at the crime scene.
WILLOWS:
Just like a pair of
earrings-- identical.
So you were at Tony's house
the morning he died.
Along with Walt Braun
whose prints we confirmed
on the doggy door.
( Tony groaning )
GRISSOM:
You know, sometimes,
doing the job that we do
our biggest break comes from
the most innocent circumstance.
It was the maid's day off,
but not the gardener's.
That's the thing about murder
you never think
to have a backup plan.
The dogs lead him
right to you...
( dogs barking )
so you had to wing it.
The gardener came
to the window...
( dogs barking )
but he didn't see you...
so you removed the tape
from Tony's wrists...
and made it look like
an OD.
WILLOWS:
What I don't get is
you and Walt Braun
didn't move in the same circles.
How'd the two of you hook up?
News flash, sweetheart:
Can't make a deal
if you keep your mouth shut.
That's the thing
about my father:
He could never give advice
but he had a million stories.
"Scorpion and the Frog."
Scorpion needed
to get across
the creek
and asked the frog
for a ride.
Frog says, "I can't trust you,
you're a scorpion."
Scorpion says, "Sure you can."
Hops on the frog's back.
Midway across,
the scorpion stings the frog.
Frog looks at him.
"Why would you do that?
Now we're both gonna die."
Scorpion says...
"I can't help it.
I'm a scorpion."
If Tony hadn't thrown a party...
the two of us would never
have been standing at that bar.
Hey, Janine,
you're lookin' good.
You're looking
at my brother's trophy?
No, my husband's bimbo.
Walt Braun.
Bonnie Ritten.
And an opportunity
presented itself.
Tony had erased you
from the will
and Bonnie wanted the people
that hurt her to pay.
Ain't love grand?
You know, this...
this could've all been his.
His and Tony's.
It's not your fault.
Sure it is.
I committed
the cardinal sin.
I loved one son
more than the other.
It's human nature.
We can't deny
our feelings.
But you can hide it.
And I didn't.
And my sons...
I made them,
I raised them...
and one kills the other.
Hey, Sam...
you still got me.
You know, I should've
married your mother.
Well, considering
I was six months old
when you guys lit the flame...
a lot of time has passed.
You had plenty of chances.
Just wasn't in the cards,
Catherine.
It just wasn't
in the cards.