( crowd cheering )
What are you waiting for?
Call it!
( blows whistle )
Come on, come on.
Coming through.
Let me have a look.
Okay, you're out.
Myles will move in
from the second line.
Forget about Myles,
I'm going back in.
Stitch me.
Terry, will you relax?
It's a weekend league,
it's not the NHL.
It is to me.
You're not 100%.
What are you,
a doctor or a coach?
Do me a favor, stitch.
Come on.
( whistles blow )
Get the doc.
Where's the body?
On the bench--
he was moved there
after he collapsed
in front of the net.
Apparently, uh
the guy was
responsive enough
to be helped
off the ice.
He died a few
minutes later.
This looks fresh.
Well, according
to the on-site doctor,
he took one across the cheek
earlier in the second period.
Well, I guess this must be
from the third period.
Looks like that
other team
worked him over pretty good.
Hockey, rough game.
Yeah, it's murder.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
GRISSOM:
Two minutes
for elbowing.
Four minutes
for high sticking.
Ten minutes,
unsportsmanlike conduct.
Boys will be boys.
Yeah, sounds like these
boys went to a fight
and a hockey game
broke out.
You just don't like sports.
That's not true-- I've been
a baseball fan my whole life.
Baseball.
Well, that figures.
All those stats.
It's a beautiful game.
Since when are you
interested in beauty?
Since I met you.
So, we'll start at
the opposite goal
work our way across
the blue line to center ice.
Sure.
It's not much to go on.
Maybe we should be
looking off the ice.
( engine purring )
So, why did you
move the body?
You ever tried
treating someone
on the ice wearing just
street shoes?
Then Mr. Rivers was still
breathing?
When I brought him back
to the bench, yes.
Then I performed CPR,
and he didn't respond.
Did you also do the stitch work?
I'm the on-site doctor
for this facility.
The stitches held,
and I advised Terry
not to go back on the ice.
So, if he'd listened,
he'd still be alive.
What do these
guys play for?
A little money?
Imitation
Stanley Cup?
We play for
the pride of it.
And the joy of kicking ass.
You are...?
Tommy Sconzo.
Right wing, first line.
Hitting's part
of the game.
Take away the
physical aspect
you've got figure skating.
Guys out there doing
triple lutzes.
Is that how you lost the, uh...?
The sit spin?
Second period,
number nine.
The guy's a real McCracken.
Which means?
He gave me a high
stick to the mouth.
That's why my guys crashed
the goalie.
An eye for an eye, you know?
That why your guy ended up dead?
What can I tell you, lady?
It all happened so fast,
you know?
Usually does.
"There are three
things in life
"that people like
to stare at.
"A rippling stream,
a fire in a fireplace
and a Zamboni going
round and round."
Charlie Brown.
I love Zambonis.
We all do.
The thing I love about Zambonis
is they pick up everything.
Hey.
Yeah?
I'm afraid the other part
of this tooth might be in there.
Time to combine
Foyeer's Law of Conduction
with Newton's Law of Cooling.
Pile of ice measures nine feet
by five feet...
by...
nine feet.
Without the calculus,
I'd estimate...
100 cubic feet.
Current temperature,
one degree Celsius.
The heaters max out
at 90 degrees, but
the variables are
constantly changing.
Let's ballpark it.
I don't know, 50-cubic-foot
melt per hour, if we're lucky?
120 minutes for a tooth...
the whole tooth...
and nothing
but the tooth.
( bells dinging )
Whoo! There's a winner.
Easy come, easy go.
♪ If I should die
this very moment ♪
♪ I wouldn't fear ♪
♪ For I've never known
completeness ♪
♪ Like being here ♪
♪ Wrapped in the warmth of you ♪
♪ Loving every breath of you ♪
♪ Still my heart this moment ♪
♪ Oh, it might burst ♪
♪ Could we stay right here ♪
♪ To the end of time ♪
♪ Till the earth stops
turning? ♪
Lockwood, Homicide.
DFO's in the back.
Lead the way.
♪ ...seas run dry ♪
♪ I've found the one ♪
♪ I have waited for ♪
♪ All this time... ♪
Stan Grevey, 35.
Backup sax player.
One of the waitresses
found him.
Tiny scrubbing bubbles.
BROWN:
Yeah, after somebody
wiped them down.
Paramedics?
Nope.
Just pronounced, that's it.
Just pronounced?
Had an interesting diet.
Cowhide.
He tied himself off.
Yup.
All the signs
of an O.D...
without any
of the paraphernalia.
Your waitress say
anything about a needle
butane torch,
that sort of thing?
No, not a word.
Just said he reminded her
of Coltrane.
Coltrane, huh?
See if I can get this back
to Gregor at the lab.
He could tell us
what we're dealing with.
Two coasters, one glass?
What do you think?
Our guy was having a little
party with the waitress?
She was just coming
on shift.
She came through me.
Already cleared her.
Well, somebody
was here...
grabbed the stuff
took their glass.
Forgot this on the way out.
Safe bet the contact wasn't his.
Hey, how's he doing?
Whoa, whoa...
Miss, you can't come in here.
Why not?
I'm sorry, he's dead.
He's dead?
What are you talking about?
They told me he wasn't
feeling well.
He was backing
me up an hour ago.
What happened to him?
Miss...
Why don't we step outside
for a minute?
What took you so long?
I was watching
ice melt.
Tox screen
came up empty
Except for quinine.
Must have had malaria
in the past six months.
Either that
or he's a big
gin and tonic drinker.
I've ordered up his
medical records.
If I was this guy
I'd have been
popping pain pills.
Hairline fracture
of the ulna
bruised kidney
ten stitches off
the orbital bone
fractured nasal bone,
all recent.
Healed rib fractures.
He should have worn a cage.
I bet he was proud of every
last battle scar.
What is it
about organized sports?
Well, organized sports is
the paradigmatic model
of a just society.
Everyone knows the same language
everyone knows the rules.
And there's a specific
punishment handed out
the moment someone tries
to cheat.
Instant morality.
So, uh, what did this guy do
in real life?
Stockbroker.
Competition junky.
Aren't we all?
Not me, not anymore.
No?
How'd you get to be
chief medical examiner?
Look, we're all carrying
prehistoric genes
in a postmodern world.
We get our meat
from the grocery store
instead of with a club
or a knife.
We have to work off our,
uh, testosterone somehow.
Foibles of youth.
Yeah.
So, cause of death?
Not sure.
This cut
nicked his carotid.
Double-edged, clean blade,
hockey skate, uh...
could have killed him.
Fun continues.
Basilar artery
also suffered
significant trauma.
Evidence of blood
in the intimal space.
Possibly enough
to cause syncope.
Loss of consciousness.
Well, it could explain
why the vic ended up
in the bottom of that pile.
So did his death cause his fall
or did his fall cause his death?
What'd you get from Area 51?
Terry Rivers was
an instigator.
Always stirring
the pot.
Every fire needs a match.
So, I guess this is
their equipment?
Yeah, down to
the last stick.
Here's a copy of
the team roster.
Okay.
See you later.
Ms. Gallagher?
Yeah.
Catherine Willows
Crime Lab.
I understand you play
for Area 51.
Did you see much ice time
during the game?
No, they just
let me take off
my cheerleader uniform
and warm the bench.
You know what?
Been there, done that.
Just asking
a question here.
I played 24 minutes,
12 seconds--
about my season
average.
I also lead the team
in assists.
Oh... you've got
good peripheral vision.
You see the ice
really well.
I didn't see what
happened to Terry.
You're a real teammate.
Down the line,
just one of the guys.
You're looking
in the wrong direction.
Now, we may have
disliked Terry
but his own teammates...
hated him.
Any reason why?
How would I know?
I'm just a girl.
Can I go now?
Nice bike.
( Nick clears throat )
Just getting into the mind
of a potential killer.
Potential killer?
Why don't you just
catch us up there, boss?
In a minute.
First things first--
your contact lens
was worn by
a near-sighted person.
And since I was born
with perfect eyesight
I'm experimenting with what
it would feel like
to be near-sighted.
Don't tell us
you're wearing
our evidence.
STOKES:
Come on, Greg.
Give me some credit.
Borrowing a pair
of lenses from
Archie in A/V.
Giving me a headache, though.
Mannitol-- that's
that baby laxative
used to cut heroin with.
China White?
You sure?
The GCMS does not kid around.
West coast heroin
is Mexican Brown.
20, 30% pure, tops.
What's China White, 75%?
Uh, your sample's 91.
91%? No wonder the guy O.D.'d.
That's a death sentence.
Doesn't make any sense, man.
The money from
dealing heroin comes
from the cutting.
The more you cut,
the more money you make.
There's no profit
margin in selling
stuff that's too pure.
Unless you're looking
to kill someone.
So, this is what being
a stockbroker buys you.
( sighs ):
Hmm, well.
How do men live like this?
What's wrong with it?
Well, it's a cave
with hardwood floors.
It's clean.
Television, couch.
What else does a guy need?
Well, how about
a plant?
Anything to makes it
a little more... human.
I mean, it doesn't seem
like this guy had any...
connection to anybody.
I don't know about that.
( clears throat )
It's never a good sign
when the number of women
a guy sleeps with is greater
than the number
of chairs he owns.
So, what's the ratio here?
Well, uh, ballparking it,
I'd say...
four women to every one piece
of furniture he owns
including the TV.
( sighs ):
So...
I guess our guy is
about three things--
pucks, bucks, and...
chicks.
Well, we still don't know
how or why he died.
Well, we know how he lived.
Any blood?
Take your pick.
Testing for blood
on a hockey jersey
it's like handing out
jaywalking tickets
at a marathon.
Well, speaking
on a meta-level...
Isn't it obvious?
The overbearing
patriarchal structure
of modern organized
sports represents
a socially palatable
sublimation of what
Jung refers to
as the "shadows
of the unconscious."
You sucked
at team sports, huh?
I was captain of
the high school
chess squad.
Chess is not
a sport, Greg.
Then why is there
a world chess champion?
I think sports are
physical by definition.
Well, sex is physical.
Is that a sport?
Not to me.
These blades skated
through the blood pool.
Blood spatter.
Good guess--
this is the one
that did the damage.
You know, I had
a roommate in college
freshman year, from Edmonton,
went on to play
for the Swedish
Elite League.
Anyways, he set his blade
at half an inch, tops.
And I should know, because
he made me get them sharpened.
These blades are probably
set at a quarter of an inch.
GREG:
Well, that's as sharp
as it gets.
It's a tough blade
to skate on.
We're talking
Wayne Gretzky style.
And deadly in a fight.
Yeah, that victim was
out of L.A.
and I don't think
the singer, Lillie
met him before last night,
so she may be in the clear.
Sure you don't want to start
in the dressing room?
( chuckles ):
Right...
like you're going
to take Dumpster duty alone.
Hey, just 'cause I've been
on a personal losing streak
with the ladies doesn't mean
you should be, too.
Man, I don't even know
if I'm going to go there.
The odds haven't gone my way
in a long time.
I'm talking about chicks,
not gambling.
Same difference.
Mind if I go
for her, then?
Warrick.
LILLIE:
It's mine--
but anybody could have
lifted this scarf
from my dressing room.
It's still yours.
You trying to pin this
on me, now?
We're just doing
our jobs here.
Well, did you find
my fingerprints on anything?
We won't know
till we print you.
Oh, I'm not worried.
What you see is what you get.
You're putting words
in my mouth.
You said everybody hated
him-- now we know why.
GRISSOM:
We opened up
Terry's hard drive.
It turns out he had
your entire roster
knee-deep in the stock market.
I don't play for the rat pack.
SIDLE:
Not now...
but you used to.
Okay, so I changed teams.
Big deal. I wanted to win.
BRASS:
The fact that Terry Rivers
churned and burned
your brokerage account
out of ten grand
that didn't enter into it?
Terry was a stockbroker.
He did really well for himself--
Rolex, Beemer.
He said he could
do the same for me.
I gave him some money.
If I wasn't willing
to take a risk
I'd have put it
in a bank.
You weren't the only one,
were you?
No. All the guys
had money with him.
I mean, Terry
was a salesman.
You listened to him
talk for five minutes
and your hair was on fire.
Ms. Gallagher,
your skate
had a certain
blood spatter on it.
It indicates that you're the one
that nicked Terry River's
carotid artery.
Look, it was pileup.
Everything was a blur.
That's ten guys with blades on.
Hey, I was just looking out
for myself.
He was a stationary target.
Terry was on the bottom
of all those bodies.
Like you said
nobody saw anything.
Including
your skate intentionally
coming down on his neck.
Oh, God.
( vomiting )
SIDLE:
You okay?
You all right?
( chuckles ):
I knew I shouldn't have had
that shrimp salad
for dinner last night.
If you'll excuse me
I'll get that
cleaned up.
Wait, you're not going to...
What are you doing?
It's evidence.
Food poisoning
especially anything
with spoiled mayonnaise
can induce vomiting
within 15 minutes.
She said last night--
that was 12 hours ago.
She's a liar, and a mother.
Morning sickness?
Yep.
And you know this how?
Well, first I tested for
the presence of shellfish--
crustacean free.
And then I figured
if she's hiding that
what else is she hiding?
Little lie, big lie.
There was blood in the sample.
Not uncommon
in early pregnancy.
Women get mucosal tears
in their esophagus
because they yak so much.
So, I tested the blood
for the presence of human
choriogonadotropins.
She is definitely with child.
She wasn't showing.
She's skinny as a rail.
But...
still, why lie about it?
Maybe she didn't know
she was pregnant.
If she had, would she
have gone out on the ice?
I wonder if
she would know
who the father
is... or was.
Well, if it was Terry Rivers
he was definitely
deadbeat dad material.
Which speaks to motive.
It's enough to
get us a warrant.
Except you can't
safely test for paternity
before the baby's born.
We could search Jane
Gallagher's apartment.
See if Terry Rivers might
have left anything behind.
Yeah. Say goodbye to Greg.
Bye, Greg.
STOKES:
I've got twins here, Bill--
one set of prints
from your work card;
another set
from the drug paraphernalia
we found in the Dumpster.
Look, what can I say?
He's got a son.
Well, that's fine.
That's not
the issue.
You tampered with the evidence.
He's eight years old.
I didn't want Stan's son to hear
that he died in a lounge.
Foam coming out of his mouth
a needle in his arm.
That's too much for a boy.
Yeah, but you
got him the gig.
You didn't know he was a junkie?
So am I.
Former.
Hell, we met in A.A.
I thought he was clean.
I got my fourth birthday
coming up.
Could have lost your job.
Besides, Lillie's going places.
You know, she's on her way up.
I want to be along
for the ride.
So, you cleaned him up,
threw away his works...
Why Lillie's scarf?
I grabbed the first thing
I could find.
Lillie's scarf was there?
Yeah.
Really?
You mind rolling up
your sleeves for us?
( laughs softly )
I've always had good veins.
Yeah, okay.
Thanks.
Hey, one more thing, Bill.
You wear contacts?
Not anymore.
Lasik surgery.
How's that working out for you?
Great.
One less thing I'm dependent on.
( soft jazz piano playing )
( piano music becomes louder)
( stops playing )
No, no, no, no.
Don't stop.
I don't like playing
in front of an audience.
It's just me.
What, are you uncomfortable in
front of strangers or something?
No, I just came by to
ask you a few questions
and I got a little
carried away.
Oh.
Well, if you keep playing
I'll keep talking.
( starts playing softly )
So, um, how well do you know
these people you play with?
Oh...
well enough.
Who is this?
I thought I was the one
asking questions here.
Warrick Brown.
Lillie Ivers.
So, I guess we're not
strangers anymore.
Maybe you should
come by later...
so we can talk some more.
Well, Jane may play hockey
but her sheets
are distinctly female.
There are semen
stains everywhere.
Not very Victoria Secret.
What is Victoria's Secret,
I wonder?
Beauty, Grissom.
Remember?
Sheets may be female,
but this toenail
belonged to a man.
With all the sex these
people are having
maybe I should
take up hockey.
I told you what I make.
What do you bring in?
50, 60 a year?
So, that's what
you're all about?
No, that's what
the business is all about.
Then run.
Hmm.
I just thought that
with your kind of talent
you know,
I could dial you in.
I've got a manager
with a pipeline to God.
Sounds like you're
pretty dependent on him.
I've been booked solid
for the past two years.
Next stop...
Blue Note, Motown...
anything I want.
Studio time,
recording contracts...
Great.
I'm a musician, Warrick,
and I recognize talent.
And the way you look...
you might as well
be dipped in gold.
I don't know
about all that.
What are you holding back for?
You could be out there
making a difference.
I already do make a difference.
Yeah, riding around
chasing ghosts
with that partner of yours.
Nobody even knows you exist.
You do.
Show time.
We're back.
Okay.
Okay, so...
Knock 'em dead.
I'll try.
Catherine...
you seen any guys
with a broken tooth lately?
Yeah, I saw
ten of them.
Yeah, well, one of them
is your suspect.
I got your page.
What's the big news?
Oh, that tooth that you found at
the bottom of the snow pile...
You got a match.
To what?
To the nasty-ass toenail
that Sara found.
What? I thought it
belonged to the dead guy.
No, it belongs to a live guy.
So, what you're
saying is
whoever was in
Jane Gallagher's bed
was on the ice
the night that
Terry Rivers died.
Goal.
It's a temp.
What about the girl?
Is she a temp, too?
You know, I treated Jane better
than that mutt Rivers ever did.
And it never
cost her a cent.
Is that why you
hated Terry?
He was on my
short list, yeah.
You know, I got a list.
It's got a negative figure
of 12,000 after your name.
Well, money's kind
of like my tooth.
It don't grow back.
Did you ever hear
the story of the 19th century
Chinese goldsmith?
He lost a lot of money
for his goldsmith buddies
due to his shoddy
business practices
so they decided to kill him
by biting him to death.
123 goldsmiths took a bite
out of the victim
insuring that no one individual
could be blamed for the murder.
For who would know
which one administered
the lethal bite.
SIDLE:
You're the captain
of the rat pack.
You make it so everyone
gets a shot in
and no one takes the blame--
it's a win-win situation.
Well, it's a nice little
bedtime story for your kids
but it doesn't have
a lick of truth.
Well, there's
truth in this:
your friend Jane
is pregnant.
I'm going to be a dad?
( pager beeping )
What kind
of coronary anomaly?
W.P.W.: Wolff-Parkinson
-White Syndrome.
Interferes with the heart's
electrical system.
I never heard of it.
Well, it didn't show
during the post
but I looked at
the tissue sections
in histopath.
They showed a small defect
in the atrium of the heart.
So, the game had nothing
to do with it?
It was the heart?
Not necessarily.
You know the quinine
I found in his system?
Lethal for someone
with W.P.W.
Big scars didn't
do him in.
It was the little scar.
Someone still gets an assist.
Hey, Sara.
If you come up here
on your nights off
people are going
to start confusing
the two of you.
You're here.
What's up?
New lead.
The bartender.
Purple.
Marquis Mecke Froede.
Test for opiates.
Purple.
You know
what that means.
The coasters test
positive for heroin.
He sandwiched the drugs
between the coasters.
That's how he hid it.
He was dealing
from behind the bar.
When we found those
two coasters
in Stan Grevey's
dressing room
we assumed that
there was two people--
either a user or supplier.
There weren't.
Just our guy--
the victim.
What's wrong?
He wasn't the only one
with two coasters, man.
What do you mean?
Remember when we talked
to Lillie about the scarf?
Yeah?
STOKES:
She had a drink
with two coasters.
So what?
There could be
a hundred reasons why she...
Did you
not hear me?
She might be involved.
You got to walk away
from this fast.
We got the dealer--
the bartender.
Let's just take him out.
And we will.
What about her?
What about her?
Why don't you...
Why don't you just
let me handle my business.
Then handle it.
We were in the sack.
Right in
the middle of it.
Next thing I know,
he stopped...
How do I say this?
He stopped...
Doing it?
Yes. Thank you.
His face
was flushed.
He was sweating.
It was all good,
and then he just...
He went soft and passed out.
I was scared.
I called the team doctor.
The paramedics came
and rushed him
to the E.R.
You know we got
his medical records.
Let me ask you
a question.
When Terry came to
did he tell you what
had happened to him?
He didn't tell
me anything.
Neither did
the doctors.
I wasn't family.
What did you do?
Took off.
I didn't want
anybody to know
I'd been with him.
Worried that the father
of your child
might find out?
I was sleeping with Terry
but I was dating Tommy.
And what's the difference?
Terry was a bad boy.
The kind of guy you just
can't get out of your system.
Who's on your mind
all the time.
He used to drive
my friends crazy.
Tommy... husband material.
So we just double-checked
the search warrant
returned from Terry
Rivers apartment.
There was no quinine
found in the location.
He never had
a prescription
for quinine.
Well, according
to Doc Robbins
he never had
malaria.
Do you have
his medical file?
Yeah.
Let me see it.
Right here.
GRISSOM:
So Jane Gallagher
is officially
no longer a suspect.
Didn't have access
to quinine
let alone know
it would kill him.
So who did know?
Terry was
a roughneck.
He dished it out
so the other players
dished it out harder.
Which they wouldn't
have done
if they had known
about his heart.
They would have
played tentatively.
Which in hockey
is a sacrilege.
Someone besides Terry
had to know.
Somebody did.
You can withhold
medical information
from your friends all you want
but it's still going
to be in your
hospital record.
Anyone with access
to Terry's medical records
knew how to kill him.
How many patients do you have
with malaria?
I'm an orthopedist. None.
BRASS:
Not according
to the pharmacy
in your medical building.
Last month you wrote
a prescription for quinine--
an anti-malaria
medication.
Malaria in Las Vegas.
No wonder they
were out of stock.
Look, a friend of mine
was going to Africa.
I did him a favor.
That's it.
Now, is there a crime in that?
Well... a man is dead.
It hurts getting stitched.
It hurts even more
when you get home.
I always give the guys
something for the pain.
So you're
the go-to guy?
I am the on-site doctor
for this facility.
Nothing more and nothing less.
GRISSOM:
Is this Umbria or Tuscany?
SIDLE:
Italy.
That's pretty serious.
But Jane's had a couple
of boyfriends
since that trip,
right?
Terry was an injury
waiting to happen, wasn't he?
And when it did
you were there on the bench
with two little pills
in your hand.
So what?
So what if I gave him quinine?
It's like giving
a candy bar to
a diabetic
if you know
he's a diabetic.
SIDLE:
And you knew, Doctor.
Terry Rivers had
a heart condition.
I need you.
Oh, yeah, since when?
Look, we tried it out,
it didn't work.
We're friends.
I don't want the whole
world to know
that I've been
with Terry.
Please?
Okay, okay.
I'll stay with Terry.
You were always
cleaning up her messes
weren't you,
Doctor?
Jane told us she paid
you a visit a couple
of days ago.
She thought
she had the flu...
but she didn't.
She's pregnant.
And with the father
out of the way
you knew who she
would turn to.
But Tommy Sconzo
is the father.
You killed the wrong guy.
BRASS:
Let's take
a little drive.
You're nearsighted?
I bet this is going
to match the contact lens
we found at the crime scene.
Let me ask you
another question.
Why deal 91% pure
China White?
Did you have a beef
with the victim,
or what?
I never met the guy.
You're going to have
to do better than that.
You intentionally
sold him stuff
that was too pure.
We know he's not
the only guy
you dealt it to.
Look, I didn't mean
to harm anybody, all right?
I didn't know
what I was cutting.
Probably got
a bad batch.
Bad batch?
Hey, do yourself
a favor, slick.
If you don't know enough
about something
stay out of it.
It's too late
for that.
You want to talk about it?
No.
Okay.
I'm going to meet Lillie.
I'll see you back
at the lab.
You don't know me.
Obviously.
BROWN:
You hiding from me?
Are you looking
for me?
Yeah.
I wanted to talk to you.
Oh, yeah?
About what?
Come on, tell me.
We're not strangers
anymore, remember?
Yeah, you're right.
Warrick Brown.
What?
I'm sorry, Lillie.
Life's too short.
Good-bye.
What are you
doing here?
I'm playing cards...
with my friend.