You're going down!
( laughter )
I got you, I got you!
I got you!
I got you.
Butchy, what's wrong?
Keep going.
( screams )
( sirens wailing )
You've been walking in circles
for ten minutes.
There's no sign of struggle.
Whatever happened
happened somewhere else.
This is a secondary scene.
Body dump?
Textbook.
David, when
we dig her up
I want you to tag her
special processing.
Yes, sir.
Only person who knows
where the crime scene is
has a mouthful of sand.
A thousand square miles
of desert in Vegas
and this perp
dumps the body in a sandbox.
He didn't put it here
to hide it.
He put it here to be found.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
GRISSOM:
What do you think?
WILLOWS:
I think we got a van
full of tools we can't use.
Sand's a nightmare.
To get to the evidence,
we may destroy the evidence.
You get these haikus
out of a book
or do they just
come to you?
Every time you find a body
you have to choose a path
and when you take
that path, Grasshopper
you risk destroying
the evidence.
We grab a trowel and
some fine mesh screens
and we just pretend like
we're panning for gold...
Master.
Gunshot victim
shipped to Desert Palms.
Santee Cherna, 32.
Runs this
check-cashing joint.
Cash business, huh?
You bet.
Was shot in the leg
making his weekly bank run.
Let me guess--
the guy makes his run
same time every week.
Night deposit.
He's either stupid
or suicidal.
We can't arrest people
for that, unfortunately.
Whole thing
went down here?
Sister heard a gunshot,
saw a car take off.
Okay, I'm going to do
a once-around.
All right,
I'll take the lot.
You run this car already?
Oh, yeah.
The RO's our vic.
That's his spot.
Right here?
Mm-hmm.
Hey, Warrick!
Check this out!
( chuckling )
We're dealing with
some criminal geniuses.
Grab the money bag,
slice it and run.
You forgot the "leave
the evidence on the ground."
Let's see.
We got some checks
no cash...
and a deposit slip
for $22,500.
So, our victim
breaks out of the store
with a bag full of dough...
Same time every week.
Guess somebody
was casing the joint, huh?
Or... it was an inside job.
This morning
everything was fine.
Then some pendejo
attacks my brother
and we're out
God knows how much money
and now I'm stuck
running this place alone.
Um, Ms. Delgado,
I know you're upset...
Upset?
Upset is for white people, lady.
I'm pissed off.
My brother was just shot
in the thigh, okay?
That's awful
close to serious
if you know what I'm saying.
Ms. Delgado,
how long have you been here?
Six years.
You have insurance?
You better have insurance.
You take 15% of
a man's paycheck
just to cash it.
People use us
but they don't like us.
Thank you.
So...
You think the brother
might be behind this?
Well, I might bet my own
paycheck on that one.
But if that's true
then our vic gets to collect
the insurance money
plus he gets to keep the money
he stole for himself.
Nice scam.
Check it out.
What's the first
thing you do
when you see
one of these on
your windshield?
Chuck it.
Exactly.
But the only guy to chuck his
was the victim.
I found one on the ground
next to his car.
That means whoever
put these here
wasn't gone long
when the brother was shot.
Potential eyewitness.
She died two to four hours
before she was discovered.
Jury's still out
on cause of death
but considering
the whip and ligature marks
it's no stretch
to say it was violent.
Some of the scars on her back
are years old.
Some are fresh.
So what are we looking at?
Rape, multiple
sexual assaults?
That's the strange part.
Her body's
a road map of abuse
but there's no sign
it was sexual.
She hasn't had intercourse
in months.
I'm thinking trade-in.
Some lowlife gets tired
of beating on the old model
so he punches her ticket
and starts shopping around
for a version 2.0.
Here's a woman who's been beaten
on a regular basis
but look at the care
she's lavished on herself.
Manicured fingernails,
manicured toenails.
Perfect teeth, hair.
Not to mention some serious
breast augmentation.
That is not a Tijuana boob job.
Those puppies are top-of-the-line.
At least we've got
a pair of saline leads.
Can you grab me one of those?
Left or right?
Dealer's choice.
What up, Einstein?
Ooh, you got anything there?
You think Einstein
had people
hovering over his shoulders
all the time?
If he did, do
you think that
we'd be walking around
with E=MC squared t-shirts?
Would you step back?
Just give me some
breathing room?
Maybe I'll tell you something
about the silver sliver
that Grissom found on
Sandbox Girl's back.
It's all yours.
Let's see what the library
has to say.
Tempered steel
with aluminum coating.
Maybe she was chained up.
If she was, she was wearing
something pretty funky.
She was in the raw.
Yeah, in a manner of speaking.
Remember that sparkly stuff
that Grissom got off her body?
Yeah.
I broke it down--
tree sap, ammonia and water.
Sounds like frat house gravy.
Liquid latex.
Never heard of it.
Really? It's all the craze
right now, man.
Girls paint it
on guys.
Guys paint it on girls.
You can paint it on
yourself if you want
if that's what you're into.
You can't get a date.
I got it.
Like I would know.
Sure, sure. I got it, man.
Hey, is that our guy?
( clears throat )
Detective Vega, LVPD.
Can I see some ID?
I am a legitimate
businessman.
My card.
How often do you distribute
around here?
On this street?
Every Thursday and Friday.
Is that a crime?
Well, that depends.
Did you see anything
unusual last night?
In the parking lot
at Flamingo and Rhodes?
I don't know what city
you live in, missy
but in Las Vegas,
unusual is what happens
when you leave the house.
We can do this at the station
if that works better for you.
Okay, okay.
Um, some jerk told me
if I touched his car
he'd shove a flyer
down my throat.
Does that count?
Maybe. Did you get
a good look at him?
Them. There were two.
A couple of lowlifes
in baseball caps.
What about the car?
Did you notice the make?
Honda, maybe.
All those tin boxes
look alike.
WILLOWS:
Dr. Cornfeld?
Catherine Willows,
Las Vegas Crime Lab.
I believe this
is one of yours.
Oh, yeah.
414 series.
Firm, but plenty of give.
Spare me the sales pitch.
We removed that from
a homicide victim.
I've got a photo.
Judging by the size
she had a pretty decent
pair to start with.
Oh, she was
a pretty girl.
I'm going to need her name.
Let's see.
Oh, yeah, here we go.
Third-party billing, but
I do recognize the address.
They send me
a lot of business.
Mona Taylor.
She must have worked there.
Real shame.
I'll tell you
what's a shame--
that she was so
pretty and perfect
and still thought
she needed implants.
You shouldn't judge Mona
for wanting
to improve herself.
Competition's intense
especially for a young woman
living in Las Vegas.
Why don't you put
yourself in her shoes?
Trust me-- I've
been in her shoes.
I got out of them.
Oh, yeah, why is that?
They were killing me.
Are you sure
the surgeon said
this is where
Mona Taylor worked?
Maybe she was
a domestic.
No domestic
has a $10,000 rack.
Not even in Vegas.
Well, the DMV
records indicate
that she hit town
from South Dakota
three years ago.
I figure the
bright lights faded
and she snagged
a sugar daddy.
How much business
can one sugar daddy
give a plastic surgeon?
( doorbell rings )
The eternal question
to which we're about
to find the answer.
Let me guess--
three police officers
looking for respite
from having to control
and dominate our big, bad city?
Close-- one police officer,
two criminalists.
May we come in?
( whip cracking
and man groaning )
Another happy customer.
Now, would you prefer
individual sessions
or would you like
to enjoy each
other's submission?
( laughing )
You don't have to decide now.
Please, make
yourselves comfortable
and welcome to
Lady Heather's Dominion.
That's her.
I'm for fun.
Right.
She drove herself
to work.
But she didn't drive
herself home.
Still locked.
Looks clean.
Hey, Catherine....
Come check this out.
What's that?
Liquid latex.
Grissom found some
on the victim.
Sanders did a trace analysis.
Stuff peels off
like a glove.
Handy.
Yeah.
What do you think
that is there?
Watch?
Bag it.
We can get a mold and
try and track it down.
Never lost one of my girls.
You don't seem very
upset about it.
What you see and what I feel
are two different things.
Really?
Were there any
disturbances last night?
Did you hear screams?
( man groaning loudly )
It's when I don't hear screams
that I start to worry.
Well, then can you
tell us what time
Mona got off?
Knowing Mona,
every couple of hours.
She enjoyed her work.
There's no sexual contact
or anything illegal
going on here, of course.
Captain Brass, surely you
don't think sexual contact
is the only means
of fulfillment?
Lady Heather
you don't what to know
what I think.
Her last client was at 11:00.
She would have left at midnight.
Do you have any kind
of log book?
Some record of who
was working that night?
What they did with their
clients, that sort of thing?
Would that get you excited?
Not particularly.
But it might help us catch
the creep who murdered Mona.
We need names and addresses.
We also need to know
which rooms she worked last
night so we can examine them.
Mona worked the pool house.
Give me a minute.
I'll have to move
some clients around.
WILLOWS:
Oh, there you are.
Um, Mona's car
is in the driveway.
It looks clean.
Okay, tow it to CSI
and then start processing
the rooms in the pool house
where Mona worked
last night.
And you will be...?
I'll be in with
Lady Heather.
Does all this
fascinate you?
Yes.
I find all deviant behavior
fascinating
in that to understand
our human nature
we have to understand
our aberrations.
And you think
what goes on here is aberrant?
I would say that whip marks
and ligature contusions
on a young woman
are aberrant.
Wouldn't you?
Every job
has its peculiar hazards.
Rock stars
damage their ear drums.
Football players
ruin their knees.
In this business,
it's scars.
But no one who works for me
has ever sustained
a serious injury.
Mona did.
She died.
Not because she worked here.
That's your assumption.
What happens here
isn't about violence.
It's about challenging
preconceived notions
of Victorian normalcy.
Bringing people's fantasies
to life.
Making them real and acceptable.
Like the theater.
It's people who don't
come to places like this
that I worry about.
The ones who don't
have an outlet.
Say... someone
like yourself.
Oh, I have outlets.
I read.
I study bugs.
I sometimes
even ride roller coasters.
And your sex life?
It doesn't involve
going to the theater.
In my experience, Mr. Grissom,
some men go to the theater...
some men are the theater.
Either way, what I offer
is a chance for submission
or control,
whichever's required.
Sometimes a client
doesn't know
what he wants until I show him.
"No man is a complete mystery
except to himself."
Marcel Proust.
I bet
he'd have enjoyed himself here.
Probably.
No crime
is a complete mystery, either.
The whip marks on Mona Taylor
were fresh.
That can't be.
Mona was dominant
with her clients.
I know that sometimes
she saw clients off the books.
I let her because
she brought in so
much business
but I just assumed
she knew what she was doing.
My guess is that one of her
off-the-book clients...
is a regular.
I mean, it is a repeat business,
is it not?
Does that one interest you?
Yes, it does.
May I borrow it?
( whip cracking
and man groaning )
All right, Randolph
you may lick my boots and go.
RANDOLPH:
Is it because
I'm naughty?
Shut up!
( groans )
WILLOWS:
I feel like I'm trapped in
the Marquis de Sade's brain pan.
STOKES:
Yeah, I guess Lady Heather
hasn't quite cleared
this room yet.
Waiting for recess.
Didn't Grissom say he found
some flecks of silver
on the victim's back?
STOKES:
Yeah.
I may have found the source.
Mm-hmm.
Hey, hey.
Liquid latex.
Like the kind we found
in the Dumpster and on the vic.
Hand me a bindle, will you?
You know
what I just realized?
Hmm?
None of this
weirds me out anymore.
People are just as twisted
in their own living rooms.
Props are different
here, that's all.
Well, not everybody's twisted.
Everybody, Nick.
Wake up and smell
the species.
Catherine, do you really think
that those freaks out there
running around with their
little dog collars on
getting spanked
are the same as you and me?
Just because you never did it
doesn't mean you never could.
No way;
never going to happen.
Well, relax, Nick.
All I'm saying is you're human.
Hey, man, my mom
and dad are human, and...
There's one thing you learn
on this job
is that human beings
are capable of anything.
A smudge of dirty tire on
a ratty piece of paper?
I know, I know, it sucks.
You couldn't get anything
off of it, huh?
Just because I'm a newbie,
doesn't mean I'm not good.
Your tire print
from the strip mall.
Wow.
Common to a lot of compacts
and subcompacts.
But one manufacturer who uses it
standard off-the-lot: Honda.
So, that confirms
what Sara's eyewitness said.
What else you got?
I've got incidental marks
from where the tire
ran over something.
Left an impression.
All you have to do
is find the tire
attached to the vehicle
your shooter was driving.
Thanks.
Ok now,
look at the bullet from your vic's thigh.
Five lands and grooves on it.
That would be a Colt.
.38 caliber.
According to Vega
the vic owns a Colt.
And?
And... since he
mysteriously got
shot in the leg
instead of a vital organ
I'm thinking I should
go visit him.
DR. ROBBINS:
Mona Taylor didn't die
from the beatings
but cause of death was
equally as slow: asphyxia.
You look like you expected it.
I considered it.
Well, there's something else.
She had some odd scaring
in the inside
of her nose.
Some small red circle.
She worked in a sex club,
it could be caused by anything.
Like a straw?
Maybe I lack
imagination
but why would you need a straw
at a sex club?
Well, it's not a sex club,
actually.
It's a fetish club.
There's a difference?
Like a straw is not used
for sipping Mint Juleps.
Cocaine?
Air.
Anything from last
night would be in here.
Masks, the usual accouterment.
We don't technically
have a warrant.
Not necessary.
I want to help.
Go ahead, ask.
"How can I do this
for a living?"
Oh, that's not
what I was thinking.
How much does this place
clear a week?
Ten grand.
I'm not with the IRS.
Okay, 20.
I don't make that
in three months.
Sex pays a
lot better
than death.
Plus the outfits are cooler.
Well, I have this
genius tailor.
Worked at the Desert
Inn back in the day.
I let him come in weekends
and play human ashtray.
He designs for
me and my girls.
It's a fair trade.
You got a good thing going here.
And the best part is, these guys
think getting slapped around
and being humiliated
is their fantasy.
It's like I always tell
my daughter...
You got a daughter?
18 this month;
freshman at Harvard.
Really?
Mine's seven.
Oh, that's a great age.
Yeah.
When I thought Zoe
was ready to hear it
I told her, "Honey, there are a
lot of things you can give a man
"your body, your time,
even your heart.
"But the one thing you can
never, ever, ever let go of
is your power."
All my mother ever told me
was "cash up front."
Don't take this the wrong way
but I think you've got
everything it takes
to make a great dominatrix.
I take that as a compliment.
Well, you should.
It's just about knowing
yourself, being strong
and not taking any crap
from powerful jerks
who are used to giving it
all day long.
Well, death is still
a man's business
and I don't have to tell you
about police work.
So, how do you survive?
By knowing myself
and working hard...
and by not taking any crap
from powerful jerks
who are used to giving it
all day long.
( bag snaps shut )
Well, these are
masks and straws
I took out of the sink
at Lady Heather's.
None of which have been washed.
GRISSOM:
Mona was a dominatrix
at the fetish club.
But my guess is
that she was a switch
for her off-the-books clients.
( chuckling )
You know what a switch is?
Someone who's dominant
as well as submissive.
Oh, he's even got
the lingo down.
( mocks whip cracking )
If Mona's DNA
is in one of these masks
then she was the submissive
on the night she died.
You're so dialed into this case
I bet you don't need me to tell
you which mask had her DNA.
Yes, I do, Greg.
I also need to know
which straw she used.
( sniffing )
WILLOWS:
Oh, nice. Mmm.
Yeah, that's the idea, Greg.
Two straws per mask.
You can't get any air
through pens.
And not much more
through straws.
And even less if someone's
finger is on the other end.
I found the victim's DNA
on this mask
and...
these two straws.
Red mark: victim; blue mark:...
Our killer.
Now we just need a suspect.
You got the yin.
I got the yang.
Actually,
I've got the yang
and you've got the yin.
At least as far
our watch molds go.
So that's from her wrist.
No air bubbles.
Good job.
Thank you.
Now we'll see
how yours turns out.
Wow.
Looks like there's a few
carats around that bezel.
And the band.
Major bucks.
Oh, and, uh,
Computer Graphics
keyed up this
Mideo System.
Just hit it.
Yin and yang.
Top and bottom.
It's definitely
not a man's watch.
You know any fine jewelers?
You have my pants?
You know, I wake up,
I look around
I can't find my damn pants.
You can't wear them
out of here.
So what, you want them
as a souvenir?
I want my stuff.
Let's start talking
about your pistol.
I have one gun.
It wouldn't happen to be a Colt.
It's on a shelf
behind the cash register.
Ay, mi hermano.
I was so worried about you.
Me, too, Papi, huh?
Hey, don't worry.
Doctor said everything
is going to be okay.
Burglary?
In this neighborhood?
Well, are you missing
any personal property?
Jewelry? Small valuables?
No.
My wife didn't mention
anything either.
Again?
Look, I'm sorry.
I have to go change Dylan.
Before you do...
in the last year
did you buy a diamond watch
at Maarten's Jewelers
at the Forum Shops?
Yeah, in my spare time between
the grocery store and the park
and Baby Jamboree.
No, no, this...
this is my life. Sorry.
Thanks for you help.
Why do men always make
everything look so tough?
If the dad didn't
buy the watch
then the mom did.
Brass has the
credit card receipt.
A $20,000 watch and
he didn't discuss it?
He's lying.
I thought my husband
answered all your questions.
He tried.
Gustav Stickley.
Very nice furniture.
No pictures of
your family though.
I know what they look like.
Most people keep pictures
of their loved ones
in their office.
Well, I would hope that
I'm not like most people.
Is there a point to this?
Did you order
a $20,000 custom-made watch
from a jeweler
at the Forum shops?
I did. Is there a problem?
No. We'd just like to see it.
Do you have a warrant?
Do we need one?
The truth is,
I lost it on a business trip.
I'm waiting to find out
from the hotel if they found it.
Is that the trip
that you took L.A.
with your boss Ronald?
Let me refresh
your memory.
You shared a suite.
Very cost-effective.
What'd you save there,
$200, $300?
I'm a corporate litigator.
It's going to take a lot more
than that to rattle my cage.
Okay.
How about this?
Are you familiar with the gal
who calls herself Lady Heather?
No.
One of the girls who works
for Lady Heather was found dead
with an imprint of your watch
on her wrist.
That's why we'd like
a sample of your DNA.
That's a big leap.
Lost watch to a DNA request.
I think we're done here.
What do you know
about the money bag?
Clean cut, quick way in.
Can you tell us anything
about the tool
that may have been used?
BFK.
Big knife. Great.
Tell us something we don't know.
I found materials on the cut.
Nice.
Got to be transferred
from the knife.
Red fibers.
All uniform length.
The refractive index
of the fibers is 1.544.
It's a synthetic. Fiberglass.
Like the insulation in my attic.
Close.
But those amber beads
are a catalyst--
resin-- which causes
the fiberglass to harden
once it's poured into a mold.
A mold?
To make what?
( whirring )
There's three fiberglass
manufacturers in Vegas.
This is the largest one
for prefab baths
and showers.
24 employees.
Everybody in the bath business
uses isophthalic resin because
it's got the highest
water resistance.
Downside is, the stuff
gets everywhere.
Hair, clothes, skin...
Small world, huh?
Hey, that's ironic, Hector.
We're investigating
your brother-in-law's shooting
and look where we end up.
We found traces
of fiberglass and resin
in Santee's money bag.
So?
So, how many knives in Vegas
come into contact
with both
those materials?
Dame la navaja.
Thanks.
Hey, could be anybody's knife.
We also have a tire print.
See? You got
the wrong car.
We never said what model
we were looking for.
We're looking
for a Honda, Hector.
Do you have one?
Because we can
check your house.
We can check
your neighborhood.
Why don't we just start
right here in this parking lot?
You know it don't look
good when you run, man.
You want to tell us who
that Honda belongs to?
I don't know.
Okay, okay!
It's a friend of mine.
He told me nobody
would get hurt.
I guess that makes
everything okay.
You again?
I thought you people would've
gotten the message.
Oh, we did.
We also got a warrant.
Is this some kind of joke?
This is limited
to my watch box.
Sometimes that's
all it takes.
( baby crying )
Eilene, honey,
everything okay?
Cameron, go see
what Dylan needs.
I think my watch box is
in my glove compartment.
Is the watch in the box?
Latex.
Like Hansel
and Gretel
we just followed the bread
crumbs all the way home.
Afternoon tea.
How nice.
I like a bit of civility
before dark...
when all the needy
little boys show up.
Well, I'm a little
needy myself today.
My lab pulled skin cells
from Mona Taylor's straws.
A DNA sample?
I have several clients
in law enforcement.
X-X OR X-Y?
They're male.
Have you ever seen
either of these two people?
Not the wife
but I have seen the husband.
I didn't say
they were married.
It's obvious.
Look at the way he's
clenching her hand
with both of his
and leaning
toward her.
And see how she's
twisting away
presenting herself
to the wealthy alpha male?
She's insensitive;
he's insecure.
That's a setup for matrimony,
not passion.
She wants the dominant
male to choose her
so she can stop
being dominant.
You're very good.
You could work for me.
You want to be my boss?
You never know.
We both might learn something.
Oh, I'm sure of that.
I can read anyone who walks
through this door
and know their desires.
Sometimes even
before they do.
Why do you think I selected
china and table linens?
You like fine things.
Or maybe I knew
you'd like them.
Same way I know
you enjoy
most of the superficial
trappings of civilization.
I'm that obvious, huh?
Only because you try
not to be.
You spend your life
uncovering what goes on
beneath the surface of civility
and acceptable behavior.
So it's a release
for you
to indulge in something
like high tea
when it seems,
if only for a moment
the world really
is civilized.
The most telling thing about
anyone is what scares them.
And I know what you fear more
than anything, Mr. Grissom.
Which is?
Being known.
You can't accept
that I might know
what you really desire,
because that would mean
that I know you.
Something, for whatever reason
you spend your entire life
making sure no one else does.
Lady Heather,
you're an anthropologist.
More tea?
But, see, I could
give the money back.
But my wife doesn't
even know it.
If I, like, give the money back
to her brother
I could go home, right?
Right?!
Tell us how
it happened--
then we'll talk
about the future.
When I picked Carla up
from work on Wednesday
I doubled back and
I lifted the piece
that Santee keeps
by the register.
I figured I'd
return it Friday.
Nobody would know.
Pretty smart, Hector.
I couldn't use my car
'cause Santee knew my car
so I hit up on a buddy.
Maricon!
No... Ow!
( blow landing )
( car revving
and tires squealing )
Look, it's not like
they're out of anything.
They're insured.
For the money
and his health.
Nobody loses.
So can I go now?
CARLA:
Hector's my husband
but I hope you keep him
in jail a long time.
He's not going
anywhere, right?
You commit a crime,
you pay the price.
You got that right.
Oh, by the way
we found the $5,000
you skimmed
from this business
in your jeans pocket.
What?
You self-righteous bastard.
You stand there
and bad-mouth my husband
while you're robbing me
behind my back?
I was just borrowing it,
I swear.
You going to
arrest his ass?
Yeah.
CAMERON:
They had a warrant.
I didn't want
to bother you at work.
This qualifies a harassment suit.
Too late.
"Grains of golden sand."
What?
Edgar Allan Poe.
Another man who was
familiar with murder.
Played in any sandboxes
lately, Mr. Nelson?
As my husband's attorney
I'm advising him
not to speak with you.
Eilene...
Shut up, Cameron.
I'll handle this.
No.
No, I will not shut up.
I didn't ask you
to be my attorney.
You're just doing this
to look out for yourself.
I'm looking out
for our family.
I'm the only one
that's qualified.
Really?
And how exactly
is sleeping with Ronald
looking after your family?
EILENE:
Cameron...
CAMERON:
Cameron what? What?
You never gave
a damn about me.
And our child...
Our child is just some yuppie pet
designed to make you look better at the firm.
Which happens to be
the only family
you probably
really care about.
Mr. Nelson, you're very
emotional right now.
Why don't you
just take a moment
collect yourself.
Let me get you
a glass of water.
No! No water, no gum,
no anything.
If you think
you can trick him
into giving you some DNA,
you're mistaken.
Liquid latex.
What is that supposed to mean?
Your husband made
Mona Taylor wear it
every time that he paid
to humiliate her.
Why would he do that?
Psychologically,
she was a surrogate.
In fetish club terms,
she was a slave.
Cameron
would put a mask on her face
and cover her body
in liquid latex.
( industrial rock music
playing )
He made her into nothing
in order to make her into you.
My watch.
I guess that made it more real.
Cameron couldn't
dominate you
so he dominated Mona.
Only his last
appointment
he got carried away.
Corporate bitch!
You still think
you're too good
to touch your
own husband?
How about I make you
beg for air?
Huh?
How about I make you...
beg for it?!
( muffled scream )
Are you begging for it? Huh?
I can't hear you, Eilene.
( muffled scream )
I had to pay some girl
to pretend to be my wife.
If this is all that you have,
I am...
happy to go to trial.
Mrs. Nelson, we're going to
match Cameron's epithelials
to the ones on the end
of the straws.
Wait, wait, wait.
Epithelials--
that's like DNA, right?
That's DNA?
Okay, I got an idea.
Why don't we test
little Dylan's epithelials?
See if his daddy isn't
really your law partner.
'Cause, God knows, you haven't
let me touch you in three years.
I'm out of here.
Where are you going?
Away from you.
Other than that,
I really don't care.
I just realized
that you and I
have a very healthy
relationship.
We do?
Well, when we
have a problem
I don't paint
Greg Sanders in latex
and stick a straw
up his nose.
Good. He'd probably
like it.
Gil... you're
supposed to say
something revealing
back to me.
Okay. I never told anybody
this, Catherine.