( meows )
( cats whimpering )
( meowing )
( growling )
( hissing and growling )
( indistinct radio transmission)
Welcome to the Wild Kingdom.
Vic's Ruth Elliot,
80 years old.
Had at least 20 roommates,
all of them feline.
Animal Control's
rounding them up now.
Who alerted Homicide?
Mail was piling up.
Mailman looked in the window
and called 9-1-1.
Take a deep breath
before you go inside.
( indistinct
radio transmission )
Oh, God! Ugh!
I didn't think anything could
mask the smell
of a decomp.
Male cat urine.
To us, smelly.
To a female cat,
it must be like
aftershave.
Me-ow.
David.
You don't look so good.
Allergic to cats.
Oh, bummer.
Rigor mortis
has passed.
Lividity is fixed.
Extensive marbling
on her limbs.
She's been dead
three or four days
and I need a Benadryl.
Excuse me.
Whoa.
She could have died
of natural causes.
Three or four days,
pets could have
been looking for
their next meal.
Sure. Meat is meat.
( meows, hisses )
Or maybe they
turned on her.
Whoa.
Look at this.
Flowing wound.
That's a deep wound track.
This woman was stabbed.
I guess the cats are
off the hook.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
( indistinct radio
transmission )
Floor was coverd by trash.
Lots of partials.
Mostly from
Animal Control boots.
But... I got
something here.
Distinctive heel and toe.
What, a high heel?
Well...
an old lady wears flats
or slippers.
I can't imagine that
this vic entertained.
You got to be careful
with isolation.
It can escalate.
Before you know it,
you're the crazy cat lady
living in the rundown house.
People stop coming by
to visit.
You go outside, your neighbors
run across the street
to get away from you.
Eventually,
you stop going out altogether.
Whoo, man!
It reeks in here.
Who lives like this?
Cat lover.
You think?
So, what do we know?
Well, there's no signs
of forced entry anywhere.
Well, I can see why
somebody would want
to rob this place.
I'll start in the bedroom.
No reaction.
Knives are clean.
Well, killer could
have brought his own
took it with him
when he left.
We might want to reconsider
"burglary gone bad."
I found a busted safe
in the bedroom. Empty.
I lifted prints.
WILLOWS:
A high-heeled thief
who knew
exactly what to look for
and killed the only obstacle
in their path.
( indistinct radio transmission)
Welcome to a 4-45.
Explosives.
It's been a while.
Fatalities?
Just this $50,000 Beemer.
Marcie Tobin.
Her car.
And Marcus Remmick,
mechanic
an eyewitness.
So, divide and conquer?
Yeah, I'll take the rig.
I'll take the grease monkey.
I guess I got the driver.
MARCIE:
This just does that make
any sense.
I mean, why would somebody
put a bomb in my car?
SIDLE:
Ms. Tobin?
Hi. I'm with the Crime Lab.
Mind if I ask you
a few questions?
Have you reached my husband?
I'll check on it,
ma'am.
Thanks.
Can you tell me what happened?
I was on my way to
my father's office.
On Thursdays we have dinner
and then I help him
with his payroll.
( clanking )
Excuse me?
We're closed.
My car is making
a really strange noise.
Take it to the dealership
in the morning.
Lady's driving a
brand-new Beemer.
First service
is 15,000 miles.
Things don't go wrong.
Yeah.
But you checked it out
anyway, huh?
You know how women get.
Go ahead, pop the hood.
( ticking )
Back away.
Why?
Run, run!
Run!
Ms. Tobin, where did
you last park your car?
In my house, in my garage.
And who would have access?
Just me... and my husband.
But Johnny had nothing
to do with this.
He's been at work all day.
You can ask him as
soon as he gets here.
( indistinct radio transmission)
Anything probative?
Check out this displacement.
Detritus blew backwards.
Uh-huh.
( sighs )
That's intentional.
Bombs are personal.
So...
assuming Mrs. Tobin was
the intended target
the bomber knew
what he was doing.
Yeah, a hired hit
on a housewife.
( indistinct radio transmission)
Glad I'm a
dog person.
You know, house cats have
only been domesticated
for 4,000 years.
They still have
predatory instincts.
Only 4,000?
Yeah.
But a cat
didn't kill her.
You're right.
No vital reactions
around the bite marks.
Predation is
all postmortem.
Cause of death,
cardiac trauma.
She was stabbed lateral
to the sternal border,
just below
the fifth intercostal space
straight into
the right ventricle.
Muscle layers decrease with age.
Fascia and tissue layers
are easy to penetrate.
Can't tell you much
about the weapon
but the wound track
is slick.
I swabbed
the foreign substance
sent it to Greg.
Anything else?
Well, vic's lungs were
full of fluid.
Probably not relevant
to your investigation
but the lab cultured her blood.
She had
a severe staph infection.
( phone rings )
Grissom.
We'll be right there.
Homicide has a witness.
Tell them
what you told me.
Come on, Jessica.
What did you see?
Oh, the lady over there
the one that died,
she was nice.
GIRL:
She had cats.
Lots of them.
Yep.
My name's Catherine.
What is your name again?
Jessica Rachel Trent.
I'm eight and a half.
Oh, eight and a half
so I bet you're
in the third grade?
Yeah. My teacher's
Mrs. Armstrong.
She's really nice.
Except I hate
multiplication
especially the eights.
You know, I have a daughter.
She hates the eights, too.
So, Jessica, can you tell me
what you told your mom?
I can. Jessica and I
were playing handball
against the
garage door.
We saw Mrs. Stein go
into Mrs. Elliot's house
and they were yelling.
When Mrs. Stein
came out
she looked really angry.
Kind of like when Mommy's
boyfriend is late for dinner.
She hates that.
GRISSOM:
And, uh...
who is Mrs. Stein?
Mrs. Elliot's
next-door neighbor.
Ran a background check.
The good neighbor filed
three nuisance complaints
against the victim.
Hey, are you girls
sharing secrets?
Can you share it with me?
All right.
Thank you.
No problem.
I think
that we're done here.
Okay. Thanks
for your help.
Sure.
( sighs )
I'll get a warrant for
Mrs. Stein's shoes.
See if we can
place her at
the crime scene.
Don't you have
a secret
to share
with me now?
Oh, uh,
Mrs. Stein?
She hates cats.
Another spring.
Did you know
there's a dozen moving parts
inside a ticking clock?
I do now.
Hmm...
Hello, sweetheart.
End cap?
Pipe bomb.
End cap at both ends.
Either one could have come
in contact
with the explosive
inside the pipe.
I'll swab it
see if Trace
can identify it.
I will see your end cap
and raise you a grommet.
A grommet?
Inside a pipe bomb?
Not in the bomb, itself,
but embedded in the end cap.
The wires from
the timing device
enter the pipe through
a hole in the grommet.
When the timing device
is activated, it sets off
an electrical charge that
detonates the explosives
inside the pipe.
Yet the grommet's fully intact.
How did it survive the blast?
I don't know, but
they always do.
And just when I thought
you knew everything.
BRASS:
How's the puzzle?
Hey. Pieces are small,
but it's coming together.
Well, I got a
corner piece.
The 4-1-1 on Marcie
Tobin's husband?
Junior foreman
on Tobin C &amp;amp; D,
Incorporated.
The "C" stands for
"construction"
the "D" is
for "demolition."
MAN:
I got to do my job,
you got to do your job.
So, if this stuff
isn't taken down there
then we all lose.
So, you just make sure
that you are in touch
with me...
Jonathan Claddon?
Yeah.
I'm Nick Stokes.
This is Sara Sidle.
We're with
the Vegas Crime Lab.
We're here about
your wife's car.
Yeah, she told me
you might stop by.
Mr. Claddon are you
a demolitions expert?
That's what we do.
You must have seen
our work on TV.
We imploded most
of the old Strip hotels.
Do you personally know
how to make a bomb?
It's not hard.
Anybody here
could show you how.
STOKES:
So, I take that
as a "yes"?
If you're implying
I had anything
to do with all of this...
I love my wife.
Not enough, apparently,
to be there for her last night.
Johnny, Reynolds needs
help loading the truck.
These folks are
from the Crime Lab.
They're here about Marcie.
I'd like to talk to them.
Alone.
Well, let me know
if I can help.
Will do.
MAN:
Oh.
Barclay Tobin.
This is my company.
Any leads on my daughter's case?
At this point, we're
still asking questions.
Can you tell us about
your son-in-law?
Well, I got him
his first and only job
when he married Marcie.
STOKES:
You, uh...
you don't think
too much of him, huh?
Even less these days.
Marcie says
that he's cheating on her
but I don't think
he has the stones.
( sighs )
But after last night...
Does Johnny have access
to explosives?
All my foremen have access
to dynamite.
Mr. Tobin, do
you fingerprint
your employees?
Sure do.
It's standard
for the industry.
Just let me know
what you need.
Before you ask
that swab of yours,
from the end cap...
let's play
"Name That Chemical Compound."
Today's category:
"Explosives."
30 seconds on the clock.
Get...
( clears throat )
C-3...
H-5...
and three molecules of NO-3...
Nitroglycerin.
The explosive
component
of dynamite.
Now, the other component
for dynamite
is either silica or sawdust.
Your sample contains sawdust.
Thanks, Greg.
What'd I win?
Hey.
Well, you look...
Happy?
Smug, actually.
I got a perfect print
off the end cap.
Husband.
Nice.
I got the type
of explosive used
in the pipe bomb.
Dynamite--
nitro and sawdust.
The same kind used
at Tobin C &amp; D.
( chuckles )
Mm-hmm...
You found the end cap?
That's not easy.
Hey, if I were you
I'd worry about
my fingerprint.
How'd it get there?
My father-in-law's
company is
the largest purchaser
of end caps in Nevada.
I log inventory.
BRASS:
Well, speaking
of inventory
I checked the books.
As you know,
per the ATF
every stick of dynamite
is catalogued.
You logged-out
a case of 24.
When the demolition project
was postponed
you returned the case...
one stick short.
It was stolen.
Look, I'm the one who
reported the theft.
I kept the dynamite in my SUV,
inside a storage magazine.
So, you're telling us
someone broke into your vehicle
and stole a single stick
of dynamite?
Yes.
Tell us about
your girlfriend.
Is that what Mr.
Tobin told you?
Marcie's the best thing
that ever happened to me.
Plus, I've got an ulcer.
Do you have any idea
what an affair would do to me?
I work my butt off
for her old man.
I barely have enough
time to sleep
let alone Romeo
some other girl.
And the truth is, nothing
I ever do is good enough.
Tobin wouldn't even
let Marcie take my name.
Cry me a river, Johnny.
You're looking at the wrong guy.
Then point us
in the right direction.
Marcie handles the payroll
and she has a rep
for shortchanging overtime.
Talk about pissing
people off.
Any one of those guys could have
put that bomb in her car.
Why didn't you tell us
this before?
Because it's
not her fault.
She's just doing what
her father tells her.
( knocking )
Debbie Stein?
Yes.
I'm here for your shoes.
Phew.
Eau de cat.
Eau de match.
She was a pig.
Her house stunk.
She didn't belong
in the neighborhood.
So, I guess it's
safe to say you
weren't friends?
Why were you in her house?
I wanted to give her a chance
to find homes for her cats
before I called
the Humane Society.
To report her.
By law, you can
only own three.
Well, a witness heard
you scream at her.
She was irrational.
I was angry.
This is disgusting.
Nobody lives like this.
You've got to
get rid of them.
These cats are my children,
and no one's
going to take them away from me.
Then you clean up after them.
I can smell your house
from my kitchen.
When, exactly, did you
confront Mrs. Elliot?
I don't know.
Maybe...
six days ago.
Before my trip
to L.A.
I went to visit my sister.
Look, if you have
any other questions
I want a lawyer.
You're free to go.
Well, she had an answer
for everything.
You know, according
to Mark Twain
the most
striking difference
between a cat and a lie is that
a cat only has nine lives.
What are you saying?
That she's lying?
Unless her alibi
checks out.
Bomber fastened the cap
to the pipe
leaving behind tool marks.
Check it out.
What kind of tool leaves
evenly-spaced vertical
striations?
A vice grip.
A vice grip?
Yeah.
Let's get a warrant
for Johnny Claddon's home
and for Tobin C &amp;amp; D.
Hey, guys.
WILLOWS:
Hey!
Talked with O'Riley.
The neighbor's alibi
does check out.
She was at her sister's
in L.A.
during the time
of the murder.
Well, there goes
our only suspect.
Not so fast.
I got another one.
We have a match
on that print
that we found
on the wall safe.
Right!
Yeah.
He has a non-gaming work card.
He's 45 years old.
He was an electrician
at the Tangiers
from '97 to '99.
His name is Tyler Elliot.
That's the same last name
as the vic.
Victim's son.
Only child.
MAN:
I wasn't skipping town.
O'RILEY:
That why you had
a duffel bag in
the back seat?
I was going camping
out at Red Rock.
And suddenly, these
cops pull me over.
They take me
into custody.
My car's still up there.
Your mother died,
and you never claimed the body.
How come?
Funerals are expensive.
I'm broke.
O'RILEY:
Records show
he filed
for bankruptcy
last month.
I figured let
the county pick
up the tab.
No one was going
to show up anyway.
It's not like
we were close.
So, how often
did you see her?
Twice a month.
Went over,
made sure her bills got paid.
Brought her medication.
Stocked the fridge.
All the stuff
any good son's supposed to do.
WILLOWS:
Mr. Elliot
we found
your mother's safe.
It was busted open
and your prints
were all over it.
( scoffs )
Something funny?
About a month ago,
she called me up--
middle of the night--
hysterical.
Her precious tabby
was locked inside.
She couldn't remember the combo.
I didn't steal her money.
She didn't have any.
The only thing she
owned was the house.
And she left that
to some damn cat sanctuary.
And so...
that's it?
I'm flat broke
and she gives her house
to complete strangers.
Can, uh...
can somebody drive me back
to my car
if we're done?
MARCIE:
You know, since my car blew up
everybody is
in my business.
All of a sudden,
everybody has something to say.
You know, an opinion,
a theory.
My life is
an open book
and my father wants me to hire
a bodyguard.
For what?
To protect me from who?
You know what I think?
Someone put the bomb
in the wrong car.
I think they confused
our house with
somebody else's
because stranger
things have happened.
Marcie?
Yeah. Sorry.
Maybe we should talk alone.
MARCIE:
Uh, we don't have
any secrets.
Okay.
Listen-- about
your marriage--
your father said...
Oh, my God. My father shouldn't
have said anything.
Your father ran his mouth
about our personal life?
Johnny, you know what?
I, um...
A couple of weeks ago
I thought that maybe Johnny
was fooling around
just because
he was never home...
I was working.
and never
interested...
Marcie, we talked
about this. You
know the pressure
your father
has me under.
I know. I know.
It's not fair.
And you know what?
You shouldn't
put too much
stock in this
because every couple has
their problems.
Marcie and I
have had enough.
That's it. Now,
you have your
warrant, fine.
But please
no more questions.
( Marcie sighs )
Just take what you need.
Hey. You got a head start.
Yeah, didn't even have to wait
for my warrant.
I just rolled over
to Tobin C &amp;amp; D
and before I could say
"vice grip"
the senior foreman gave me
every grip in the house.
Bad news, though.
No matches.
Ah! One more vice grip
compliments of
the Tobin/Claddon household.
Aw...
teeth aren't even
the same size.
No.
And we're out of vice grips.
We're out of luck.
Let's unwrap the Beemer.
You know, when I was 16,
I begged my mom for a car.
Swore she'd
come through.
What happened?
Encyclopedia Britannica.
( chuckling )
All 24 volumes.
Still own them, still use them.
Okay.
Mechanic found the bomb
next to the engine mount
closest point to the driver.
Bomb was on a delay.
Clock with a ticking second hand
and a nail driven into "12."
That means
the bomb was triggered
60 seconds before detonation,
one rotation of the second hand.
Question is, what
started the clock?
Something Marcie Tobin touched
inside the car?
Ignition, door locks
window, radio, A/C...
turning signals
hazard lights...
Yeah, but we're only dealing
with a 60-second time frame.
Okay, she pulls into the lot
she gets out of the car,
and she asks for help.
Mechanic offers to take a look.
So, she pops the hood for him.
Hood release.
Whoa.
The latch has been blown apart.
Which means the hood was down
when the bomb was detonated.
How is that possible?
The mechanic saw the bomb.
X-ray vision?
Okay, maybe he took one look
at it, and he slammed the hood.
Sara, if you found a bomb
in your car
would you close the hood?
No, I would back away fast.
Um... maybe the hood dropped?
No way.
BMW has built-in hood shocks.
Liar, liar, car on fire.
♪ Nothing suffocates you more ♪
♪ Than the passing
of everyday human events ♪
♪ And isolation is
the oxygen mask ♪
♪ You make your children
breathe in to survive ♪
♪ Well, I'm not a slave
to a god ♪
♪ That don't exist! ♪
( music stops )
I could have been
a rock star.
There's still
time, Greg.
Tell us about the
foreign substance
we found in the
vic's wound track.
Uh, well, I like to rub it
all over a lady's body.
Even better...
I, uh...
like it when she rubs it
all over me.
And it's also used
as a stool softener.
It's also the only open lead
in our case.
Spit it out, Greg.
Mineral oil.
GRISSOM:
Possibly used as
a preservative
to prevent rusting
of high-carbon steel.
Like the blades of knives.
Old knives. New ones are
made from stainless steel.
Yeah, I'm like a sponge.
I just absorb information.
I thought that was my line.
Yeah, and I absorbed it.
Okay, so...
( clears throat )
knives, screwdriver
ice pick
letter opener.
We're looking for a weapon
with a splash of mineral oil.
I'll grab the A.L.S.
An A.L.S. for mineral oil?
Mineral oil fluoresces
at 525 nanometers
when filtered through a KV590.
A little more absorbing,
a little less rock and roll.
( dog barking )
( machine humming )
Now what?
( meowing )
I thought Animal Control
rounded up all the cats.
Where are you going?
Following the evidence.
( meows )
Wait. Rascal.
Hi.
( Rascal meows )
How'd you get out?
Hi. Girls.
Say hi, Rascal.
WILLOWS:
Hi, Rascal.
Excuse me, uh...
may I hold your cat?
No. He doesn't like you.
Girls, dinner.
Can't she see
we're playing?
Just ignore her.
MRS. TRENT:
Girls.
I see you've met Rascal.
Mrs. Trent, I noticed this
cat has a sore on its leg.
I'd be happy to
swab it for you.
Might need
medical attention.
No.
I don't think that
that's really necessary.
It's just a cut; it'll heal.
But I mean,
for your daughter's sake
wouldn't you rather be safe
than sorry?
I think it's time
to go inside.
Uh, Jessica...
I-I think he might have a point.
I want her to do it.
Okay.
Rascal.
( Rascal meows )
All righty.
Thank you.
MRS. TRENT:
Okay, girls,
go wash up.
Come on, Jackie,
let's go.
Kids these days,
they just don't listen.
Two against one.
Thank you.
See you later.
One thing about my mother
even though she was deaf,
she was always the boss.
Huh. Well...
single mom...
juggling a job, a boyfriend.
It's just easier
to say yes than no
and then eventually,
they just stop asking
for permission.
You want to tell me why
I swabbed their cat?
That cat has an open sore
and a missing patch of fur--
both indicative
of possible staph infection.
And we know that our victim
had a staph infection.
Staphylococcus bacteria
can jump the species barrier--
be passed from human to animal.
MAN:
Guess I must have
shut it, then.
I wasn't thinking;
I was reacting, you know?
No harm, no foul.
STOKES:
No prints.
Come again?
Well, if you were pawing
all over the hood
then your prints
should be on it.
And they're not.
I wear gloves.
You're not wearing them now.
I wear them most of the time.
Mind if we take a look
around the garage?
Knock yourselves out.
( electric tool whirring )
Are you thinking
what I'm thinking?
Mechanics use vice grips?
You got any clay?
No.
Well... we can't just take
the tool without a warrant.
But...
we can improvise.
Trash is trash.
Cheese. Nice.
I'll compare this
with our case toolmark.
You guys having fun?
A blast.
Hey, man...
These yours?
Don't use vice grips--
pipe wrench has a better feel.
Must belong
to one of my mechanics.
I'll take
the prints on those.
Boy, you just have an answer
for everything, don't you?
Yeah, I guess I do.
Striae are identical.
Auto Body vice grip
was definitely used
to tighten the end cap.
Mechanic's prints on file?
Marcus Remmick.
Arrested for fraud in 1994.
He was selling
used parts as new.
Prints are in AFIS, but they
don't match the vice grip.
And, in fact,
AFIS drew a blank.
Hmm. Then what are you running?
I'm running
a Tobin C&amp;amp;D database.
Oh. Shot in the dark.
( beeps )
( beeping )
Even a shot in the dark hits
sometimes.
MARCIE:
Why would I put a bomb
in my car?
SIDLE:
Not only did
you put a bomb
in your car--
you made it yourself.
Why would I do that?
BRASS:
The business
registration
shows that you own 25%
of your father's company.
So Nevada's a community property
state-- you divorce Johnny
he becomes a part-owner
of Tobin Construction.
That wouldn't sit too well
with Dad, would it?
SIDLE:
But if Johnny
goes down
for attempted murder,
he goes to jail
and you get to keep everything,
because a criminal
can't benefit
from his own malfeasance.
This is absurd.
You know, for your
information, um
your mechanic friend
lawyered up.
Guys with records
roll fast.
He's not my friend.
STOKES:
Really?
Because we found
your prints on a tool
at the body shop.
It was the same tool
we know was used to
make the pipe bomb.
( quietly ):
Sit down.
SIDLE:
You and Marcus
tag-teamed us.
You never popped the hood; he
never shut it-- it was latched.
Fortunately for you,
you only worked
Thursday nights,
because your little plan
took a lot of extra
time and effort?
You snagged a stick of dynamite
out of Johnny's SUV
took an end cap
out of inventory,
knowing we'd trace it back
to Johnny if we found it.
And then at the body shop,
you put it all together.
So what if I made a bomb?
That's not a crime.
Really?
You sure about that?
Ready.
MARCIE:
60 seconds.
BRASS:
You used to own
a '92 Volvo.
I ran your credit card.
You owe $20,000
in auto body repairs.
Your dad kicked
in $30,000.
I ran his credit card, too.
That's 50 g's
for a leaky transmission.
STOKES:
You needed Marcus' help
to wire the bomb
and substantiate
your story.
So the two of you
paid him $50,000 for
services rendered.
Look, I'm fine,
and my husband is fine
and it was my car that exploded
so does this...
really need to go any further?
BRASS:
Ma'am, you and
your father
conspired to frame your husband
for attempted murder.
STOKES:
So, you're both looking
at, what, uh...
20-plus.
Oh, and Johnny's getting
a promotion.
Girl's cat...
positive for staphylococcus.
You know,
I spoke with Janet Trent.
She and her daughters
are all healthy.
Could their cat have been
infected by Mrs. Elliot?
Could Rascal
have been her cat at one time?
What, and she...
gave it to
the girls?
No.
So if it was hers, and she...
didn't give it away...
Maybe someone in the Trent house
adopted it.
( indistinct radio transmission)
We know that Mrs. Elliot
was killed by this pen.
Can one of you tell me
what happened?
Girls, do you understand what
Ms. Willows is asking you?
I'll tell.
No. You promised.
WILLOWS:
Jessica, in this room,
the only promise you make
is to tell the truth.
She didn't mean to do it.
I'm sure she didn't.
Who?
Mommy.
What did your mother do?
Mrs. Elliot should have just
given us the cat.
He's always at our house.
Rascal likes
it there.
I won't give them away.
Look, then I'll
pay you for him.
I'm sorry.
Every child
should have a cat
but these are mine.
Just give me...
Oh!
Girls, take the cat and run.
Go. Go.
ELLIOT ( crying ):
No! Please... no!
So then we ran, and that's when
we heard the old lady scream.
Jackie?
Girls, do you...
know about fingerprints?
When you... touch something--
like this floaty pen,
for instance--
you leave behind
an invisible mark
that's special,
that's yours.
I have a way to...
see these invisible marks.
And we found these fingerprints
on the pen.
And they don't belong
to an adult.
They're not mine.
Tattletales burn in hell.
The old lady should have just
given me the cat.
I lied before.
She wasn't nice.
She was mean.
My mom said we can
keep him. Please?
These are my babies.
I don't give them away.
But you have so many.
We don't have even one.
I'm sorry.
Run, Jackie!
I'll tell your mother!
You won't!
Did you know?
I told the girls
that they could have a cat
if Mrs. Elliot gave them one.
I knew she never would.
That's why I made the promise.
JESSICA:
No, I need Mommy.
( crying ):
Mommy. I want
my mommy!
No! Jessica!
Mommy...
( crying ):