( tires squealing )
( train whistle blowing )
WOMAN:
Come on, come on,
come on, come on.
Come on, come on!
( brakes screeching )
( screaming )
Paramedics pronounced
20 minutes ago.
Megan Treadwell.
I ran her plates.
33 tomorrow.
One-on-one
with a train.
Did she think that
she could beat it?
Hey.
Door handle.
Point of impact:
passenger-side door.
WILLOWS:
Dead center.
Question is: Why did the SUV
cross the tracks?
To get to the other side.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
Sheriff says we're
holding up trains
all over the country.
This entire
railroad division
depends on keeping
the main line open.
Well, it's not like
we can take this back
to the garage.
Well, unfortunately,
his priority
is clearing this train
from the tracks.
You have two hours.
Where are you going?
Suspicious circs
in town.
This one's all yours.
Thanks
but you got to give me
some guys.
Sara's all you get.
All I need.
( alarm ringing )
O'RILEY:
"Burglary in Progress"
call.
Once we made entry,
we found the victim downstairs.
Never knew
this place existed.
The Western States
Historical Society.
It's not on a lot
of tourist maps.
( alarm stops ringing )
I had them
cut the wires.
We need to identify the
source of the alarm, Ray.
Security company said
it was downstairs.
The body's there, too.
Trying to get them to turn
some more lights on in here.
There are no more
lights, O'Riley.
It's a controlled
environment.
Notice how you're
not sweating?
It's probably 66
degrees in here.
35% relative humidity.
Too much light,
too much heat
degrades the books.
What-- nobody's
got a key?
The curator's
across town.
He's on his way.
She looks dead to me.
( power tool buzzing )
You got first touch.
10:48.
Red foam, blue tint.
Foam could be from blood
in her lungs.
Edema.
Skin is cyanotic.
Maybe a blood disease.
Leukemia. Meningitis.
We'll know
after the post.
Don't do that.
Excuse me?
These are very rare books.
Aaron Pratt.
Librarian.
Only other person here
when the alarm sounded.
Did he tell you what
he was doing here?
Oh, yeah.
Watching her.
Set off the alarm,
trying to get
in the cage.
PRATT:
I wasn't watching her.
I always say "good night"
to Veronica
because I have to leave at 8:03
to catch the 8:10 bus.
It's three blocks away.
And sometimes
the bus comes at 8:08,
so I have to rush to catch it.
So you went down
to the basement
to say good night.
"Good night, Veronica."
"Good night, Aaron."
Sometimes she...
walks me to the bus.
Did she walk you
to the bus tonight?
"Are you coming?"
"No. You go ahead without me.
I have more work
to do."
Then...
a uniball pen
rolled across the desk...
fell onto the chair...
hit the floor
and stopped rolling
at the wastebasket.
Then water...
water falls into her eyes.
You mean she was sweating?
From her forehead.
Lots...
And then,
she grabs her stomach...
with both hands.
( groans )
"Aaron...
Aaron..."
Then she put on
her new face.
Shelley's Frankenstein.
Up and down...
flopping around
like a salmon
on my uncle's fishing boat.
She was convulsing.
I... couldn't help her...
because the cage is locked
and I don't have a key.
Hey, there.
Warrick's got three
residential burglaries, so...
Mr. Pratt
will you excuse me
for a moment?
According
to O'Riley
this guy's body language
says he's guilty.
I think he's autistic.
Autistic? You mean
like Rain Man?
Rain Man
was a savant.
Extremely rare.
Aaron Pratt is a
high-functioning
autistic man
with superior
right-brain ability.
Kind of sounds like you.
The crime scene's
in the basement.
Man, I hate rushing
through a crime scene.
Two years from now,
no one is going to care
that the Sheriff
turned this into
a "scoop and run."
Call was made
above our heads.
Just document the time
in your notes.
Yeah, well, I'll let you
testify on this one.
Thanks.
Aw...
Hey, little guy.
Hey.
Hey. Let's see.
His name is Maverick.
He lives on
Martingale Street in Henderson.
That's not that far from here.
Guess I'll go call
Animal Control.
Okay.
I'll be right back.
Hey.
Come on, boy.
Let's get you home.
So let me get
this straight--
all you saw was a car
trying to beat the signal?
I'm putting
55 miles an hour.
It's dark.
I got an oil leak,
can't figure out where.
I looked up
and I saw something.
The SUV.
Like I said, it was dark.
I thought it was stopping.
I turned my head
for one second.
Next thing I know, it's
in the middle of the tracks.
With all due respect
we've got the right
of way out here.
Thanks for your time.
That's not yours, is it?
I am collecting evidence.
Do we have an address
on the vic yet?
855 Martingale.
Vic had a passenger.
Say hello to Maverick.
Have you finished with
our lady of the library?
As finished as
I'm going to be.
You were right. Cyanosis.
Blood was unable
to oxygenate
her tissue.
Explains the blue face.
Underlying cause?
With blood in her lungs,
asphyxiation's out.
I found vomit
in her throat
bloody stool, hemolysis
and some irritation of the
mucous membrane on her tongue.
I won't know more
till I get the blood test back.
Could be blood-borne disease.
I'm thinking about homicide.
Then you know more than I do.
It's fine.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Sir, you can't come in here.
I told the officer upstairs.
I'm Stanley Hunter.
The curator.
Do you have any idea
the damage you're causing?
With your dust, flashbulbs.
You see that?
Right there, behind you.
That is a 17th century text
by Johannes Van Den Avelen.
It's one of two volumes
in the world.
Now, do you go
to the Louvre
and put your hands all over
the Raft of the Medusa?
Officer, Mr. Hunter would like
to give a statement
to Detective O'Riley.
Statement?
Mm-hmm.
I just got here.
I don't even know
what happened.
But what I do know is that
these are masterpieces.
One of a kind.
They're evidence
in an active
criminal investigation--
also one of a kind.
Mr. Hunter, why don't
we go upstairs and talk?
The good news, Nick?
We had a camera in here.
There's no surveillance system.
Yeah, there is-- Aaron Pratt.
We just have
to figure out
how to get the film
out of his head.
Filament.
Train probably
busted out her headlights.
First thing on our list
when we get to the tow yard.
Catherine...
Check this out.
Two sets of skid marks.
One set going forward...
( tires squealing )
These skid marks
are about
seven feet
shy of the gate.
The second set
of skid marks are darker
more rubber residue.
Could be an overlay.
Looks like the tires
were spinning in place.
In reverse.
Burning rubber.
Going nowhere.
So... which set of skid marks
are telling the story?
Maybe they both are.
So, all of your chemicals
in here are alkaline?
We're not dealing
with the far ends
of the pH range.
See, old book pages
are slightly acidic.
The acid eats
away the paper.
We neutralize them
by a solution
that's slightly
basic.
To reach "7," the neutral pH.
Exactly.
Imidazole.
15% ammonia.
That's the sort of thing
we work with here.
It's all about
preserving the books.
No, not that you could
even assign a value
but do you have any idea
how much each of these books is worth?
No.
The first printed book
was a Gutenberg Bible.
It sold at Christie's
for $5.3 million.
Lewis and Clark's
Elk Skin Journal
sold for $500,000.
We have an illustrated
Audubon, the Birds of America
which is worth
an estimated $300,000.
All of that and you never thought about
beefing up your security?
Special collections
are kept in the vault.
Any rare book
removed from the vault
gets scanned
through a coder.
If the book
is to be read
it's delivered to
a secure room upstairs.
And If Veronica was
going to work on it
it stayed down here.
Is this one
of the books
that Veronica
was restoring?
Yes. It...
it was published
in 1797.
The author was
a British botanist.
It's worth
an estimated
$300,000.
It's really not
a dangerous profession.
We got a situation.
You know
that weird guy?
He's not weird, O'Riley,
he's autistic.
Whatever. First on the scene,
and he's got
sticky fingers.
"But I will wear my
heart upon my sleeve
"for daws to peck at.
I am not
what I am."
Othello, Act One,
Scene One.
Line 61 and 62,
Iago to Roderigo.
Very good, Aaron.
Now, you want to tell me
how Othello ended up
in your briefcase?
It's my... favorite
Shakespeare tragedy.
I like
Hamlet myself.
And I bet Mr. Hunter
is into King Lear.
He's very concerned
with property rights.
He tells me the rare books
are kept in the vault
and they're not
allowed off-site.
Mr. Hunter doesn't like me.
I don't think the rule
was made with you in mind.
He breaks the rules
all the time.
He takes the books home?
No. He... eats his lunch
in his office.
Carrots, celery
tuna on whole wheat...
and Veronica.
What do you mean,
"and Veronica"?
She's eating
and he takes her sandwich...
and he puts his hand
on her breasts.
And then he puts
his tongue...
Aaron, I get it.
Did they know
that you were watching them?
Hey, you know that filament
you picked up?
Yeah.
The lamp cover's smashed,
but the filament's intact.
So what, the filament's
from another car?
Well, taillights have
different filaments
so... yeah.
Paint transfer.
Recent?
Hard to say.
You know, this right rear tire's
lost a lot of rubber.
I got a cell phone.
Battery's dead.
Hey, Catherine...
her emergency brake
is still on.
Maybe her brakes failed
or she had to engage it
for some reason.
You know, I'm thinking
that maybe another vehicle
was involved.
Engineer didn't mention anything
about a second driver.
Maybe he didn't see it.
15 minutes before
my next post.
Hey.
Great room.
Great table.
I could use this.
Lay out all
the body parts.
Get a real overview.
Is that a light
under there?
Do you have something for me?
Oh, your vic.
Poisoned.
Substance as yet
unidentified.
Well, there's
no smoking gun
in any of these bottles.
What's on the label
is what's in the bottle.
Isopropyl alcohol...
15% ammonia solution...
imidazole...
bleach.
When you isolate the toxin
you'll have a better idea
where it came from.
Nick.
Hmm?
I love this table.
There's no glass
on the filament.
10:30 at night?
Crim 101.
If a guy's driving along
at night with his lights on...
gets in a wreck, glass breaks
fuses to the filament.
Instant evidence.
But there's no glass
on the filament.
His headlights
weren't on.
Black car... headlights off.
Easy for an engineer to miss.
So he hit
our SUV.
Accidental or intentional?
Hard to tell.
Maybe not.
These books are from
the Historical Society.
That's my mail.
Aaron, what about these books?
Don't... don't
mix those up.
I have two bills
due tomorrow--
gas and electric--
and I have to mail
them on my way to work.
Don't.
You're messing
everything up.
Aaron, may I have
a glass of water, please?
Of course you may.
Thank you.
Is this guy
the real deal?
I think he's incapable
of deception, Nick.
We're just witnessing
displaced anxiety.
I mean, look around.
Everything's
in precise order.
Organized by size.
GRISSOM:
Order provides comfort.
His whole life is based
on routine.
Without it,
he can't function.
I'll check out
the bedroom.
Mountain spring water,
Calistoga, California.
Bottled at the source.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Now, how did these
books get here?
Veronica brought them.
She was here?
Yes, she was here.
We date.
What do you mean you date?
We have dinner--
roast beef, baked potato...
organic broccoli...
Acacia
Pinot Noir.
Shakespeare in Love.
DVD. Miramax.
M-C-M-X-C-V-I-I-I.
You two were involved
with each other?
Why? Don't you think she would
date someone like me?
No. You told me
Veronica was involved
with Mr. Hunter.
I have a Masters
in Library Science
and an English degree from UNLV.
And some people
like Mr. Hunter, treat me
like a freak.
But Veronica
didn't.
She... loved me.
Not him.
STOKES:
Grissom.
You might want to come
back here a sec.
Thank you.
Personal effects.
Like some creepy
little shrine.
Vic's hair.
She was seeing Hunter.
Aaron got jealous.
Incapable of
deception, huh?
How do you feel about murder?
"Yet she must die
else she betray more men.
Put out the light,
and then put out the light."
Last call on her
cell phone was to 911.
Reel to reel's already
interfaced on my computer.
DISPATCHER:
911, what's your emergency?
MEGAN:
Oh, God, you've got to help me,
please, help me.
Ma'am, try to calm down.
Where are you?
I'm in my car.
There's this maniac,
he's following me...
Ma'am, what's your location?
Help me, please!
( dog barking )
( train whistle blowing )
Can you isolate
the individual tracks?
Yes, ma'am.
Good. Lose the dog.
Train, too, please.
DISPATCHER:
Ma'am, what's your location?
MEGAN:
Help me, please!
Oh, my God!
( tires screeching )
She was flooring it.
With the emergency brake on?
It doesn't make any sense.
Okay, lose
the victim's voice
and let's just
hear the car.
( tires screeching )
( engines running )
Two engines.
Separate them out.
SUV -- sounds like
any regular four-cylinder.
( engine running )
Sounds like the same thing.
Hang on.
( whirring )
You hear that?
Turbo. Probably diesel.
She definitely likes you.
You ever see The Attack of
the Killer Tomatoes?
'Cause there's something
in the victim's blood
that looks like one
of those Heirlooms.
Well, it's not
pulling a spectra.
It's not a chemical.
No, it's a large,
ugly, globular mass.
You know, it's
probably a protein
'cause it's the largest mass
of anything in the body--
except organs, of course.
But it's foreign.
How did it get in there?
Cart before the horse, Nick.
First you identify it
then you figure out
where it came from.
I always thought
you kept your porn in there.
I move it around.
Okay, now, this is
a 66-kilodalton globular
protein, composed of
two disulfide-linked subunits,
A and B.
Very impressive.
And I know what you
all think of me--
I'm just another pretty face
who got to where I am
by sleeping with Catherine.
But seriously...
Phi Beta Kappa, Stanford.
Can I help it if I'm hip?
Yeah, yeah, which one of
your relatives got you in?
Full ride.
Hey, eyes forward.
A and B chains link together
to form a large
three-dimensional structure
of these beta sheets
and helices.
Translation...
Wait!
You just drew
the molecular structure
of a foreign protein.
Plant?
Correct.
But, more specifically,
a lectin.
( gasps )
This is nastier
than I thought.
It's ricin, a biotoxin.
Biotoxin?
Yeah.
"B chain binds
to glycoside residues
"which trigger endocytotic
uptake of the protein
"which internalizes the toxin
and begins
the irreversible effects..."
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
stop now.
Biotoxin, as in
anthrax, smallpox?
I was at that crime scene
for eight hours, man.
Relax, man.
It takes, like, two hours
for ricin symptoms to show
and, like, 48 more
to kill you.
What kind of symptoms
are we talking about, here?
Um...
Sweats?
Cramps?
No.
Convulsions?
Mm-mm.
Then you're fine.
And where did you say
this woman worked?
Western State
Historical Society.
Hey.
I just got the word on
our library victim.
How does ricin grab you?
Well, ricin.
I never would
have gone there
but it explains
the irritation
of the mucous membrane
on her tongue.
So you think she ate the poison.
I don't know about ate
but the ricin made contact
with the tongue
which means you're probably
looking for a powder.
Day in the life.
SIDLE:
Megan Treadwell
wakes up at home
on Martingale Street
puts the dog in the car,
heads to work
at her desk by 9:00 a.m.
We know this how?
Brass. Talked to her boss.
Why the dog?
Dog went with her, every day.
So she works till 6:00?
8:00, actually. Hard worker.
She packs up
and leaves the office.
Except she doesn't go home.
She runs an errand.
I found these in the
front seat of her SUV.
There's only one store in
Las Vegas that makes them.
Yeah, it happens
all the time.
Parking spaces are too narrow,
and at a premium
now that the restaurant
moved in.
This guy was out of line,
almost... psycho.
Because of this woman?
Yeah. Maverick's owner.
I think her name was
um, something with an M.
Megan.
Yeah. And this guy
yelled so loud.
I came out here
just to check it out.
He said something like...
"You could have
killed me, bitch!"
I heard it, too.
Did you see it?
Kind of.
I mean, I didn't hear a crash
or anything, just brakes.
It seemed like
she backed out,
didn't see him.
Happened right over there.
( engine starts )
Whoa, whoa, hey, hey!
And that set him off.
The last thing this guy needed
was coffee.
Hey!
What?
Pull your head out of your ass
and use your mirror!
Was he a regular?
Double latte, tall
Monday through Friday
between 8:30 and 9:00.
Does Mr. Double Latte
have a name?
I think it's Croft.
Works right down
the street-- CPA.
He's always telling us how
to streamline our business.
How did Megan react
to Mr. Croft?
She told him to go to hell.
Go to hell!
No, you go to hell!
You're an ass!
And then just drove off.
And what about Mr. Croft?
Everyone was just
staring at him
and then he got in his car
and peeled out.
Ricinus communis.
Castor beans,
like castor oil.
Well, botanically speaking,
it's a spurge, not a bean.
Ricin is made
from the husk.
Castor oil is made from
what's inside.
Hmm, which makes two people
who know that--
you and the guy
who wrote the book.
Three, actually.
Someone knew how to turn
this spurge into a poison.
Hey, guys.
That's Aaron's book, right?
Mm-hmm.
Shouldn't you be looking at that
under a fume hood?
We brought this from his
apartment, not his office.
What makes you think
there's a difference?
He probably cooked up that ricin
in his kitchen.
Our guys didn't find
anything there.
So he cleans up well.
What, you're not feeling sorry
for this guy, now, are you?
Hey, man, he is autistic.
Anybody else would be in a cell
right now.
Yes, I've heard of ricin.
Georgy Markov, 1978.
Bulgarian political
refugee in London
assassinated by injection
with a ricin pellet
shot out of a black umbrella.
Died two days later.
Not that different from
the way Veronica died, is it?
I found this book
in your apartment.
What if I also told you
that I found your fingerprint
on this page?
Page 153.
I don't touch
that book anymore.
But you did touch it.
Why are you mad at me?
Answer the question.
I don't touch this book anymore.
It doesn't feel right.
Ever since you
killed Veronica.
I loved Veronica.
What do you mean,
it doesn't feel right?
Like a new bus pass.
Smooth. Feel the page.
It used to feel like
my bus pass after a month.
Now...
Rough.
Did you tell anyone
that the illustrations
felt different?
Yes.
I told Veronica
and I told Mr. Hunter.
She said that sometimes
the books feel that way
after they've been restored.
What did Mr. Hunter say?
He said, "Get out of my office,
Aaron, I'm having my lunch!"
Was Mr. Hunter having lunch
with Veronica again?
Hard-boiled egg, celery,
fruit salad
iced tea.
Veronica was on a diet.
She had to lose three pounds.
Was this lunch different
from the other lunches
you told me about?
Yes.
How?
They fought.
Aaron, I want you
to be very specific.
Tell me what you saw.
You did what?
All I have is my reputation
and I'm not going to let you
ruin it for me!
Veronica started crying.
Mr. Hunter stopped yelling.
He sat down.
He started eating.
He cut the hard-boiled egg
in half.
He reached in the drawer
and pulled out the salt shaker.
No sex, no food, no salt.
Poison?
What are you talking about?
GRISSOM:
We're talking
about ricin.
The toxin that killed
Veronica Bradley.
You were dating her.
You ate lunch together.
O'RILEY:
Opportunity.
So, you mix up
a batch of ricin
put it in a salt shaker.
Next time you're breaking bread,
she asks for the salt...
It never happened.
We have a witness who says
he saw you try to kill her.
What? Aaron?
Are you sure you trust him?
Normally an eyewitness is the
least reliable evidence we have.
But in this case,
it's the most reliable.
Veronica knew about
the forgeries.
A career-ender, huh, Stanley?
For her, not for me.
She's the forger.
Oh, there, there, there.
( clicks tongue )
I suppose he indicted me
for that, too?
He's the one who came to me.
Told me about the illustrations.
Said they felt like
his bus pass.
Whatever that means.
Go on.
He even knew the page numbers.
So, I checked it out
and he was right.
Veronica was using me
and mea culpa.
Why didn't you tell us
about the forgeries earlier?
When she died, I thought
the problem was solved.
In this business, all you have
is your reputation.
There was a dozen books.
I was going to remove them
from the collection
inform the board, collect
the insurance and cut my losses.
If you don't believe me
go ask your
very reliable witness.
Tell me again,
what did you see?
Uniball pen rolls
across the desk.
Falls on the chair,
hits the floor
and stops rolling
at the wastebasket.
Then water falls
into Veronica's eyes...
Aaron, when you look
at things
you see pictures in your mind.
Tell me the first picture
you see
of Veronica
in this cage.
I already told you.
Tell me something
you haven't told me.
Tell me what Veronica was doing
before you said good night.
She pulled out a canvas bag.
Then she looked around.
Why was she looking around?
She was deciding something.
Tell me what "Veronica
deciding something" looks like.
Thank you, Aaron.
Veronica Bradley
must have loved Uniballs.
She had about a dozen
at her house.
Plus every known piece
of forgery equipment.
Some people bite
their nails; she
bit her pens.
Bad habit.
STOKES:
I also found this
under her refrigerator.
Funny how people don't think
to clean there.
Castor bean.
Ricinus communis.
STOKES:
But if we find ricin
on any of the pens
from her house
we'll know where she cooked up
the castor beans.
And maybe how she died.
Get these to Greg right away.
We need the results of the ricin
ELISA test.
I came home straight from work.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
You want to submit
to a lineup?
A lineup?
What for?
His car, out in the parking lot,
it's a rental.
Rented this morning.
Let's just cut the b.s.
Where's your car?
I sold it.
You got proof of sale?
An accountant
who doesn't keep receipts.
Hey, you don't know
anything about me.
I know you've got a temper.
Hey. Brass did the legwork
and rushed the warrant.
Found it in a body shop
a mile from his house.
Black Excursion.
Turbo diesel.
Gutted.
Gets better.
Vic's SUV was silver.
What do you think?
WILLOWS:
Well, this is a lot more
than a fender bender.
Sustained contact.
Get some scrapings.
Yeah.
I think I may know what...
( sniffs )
set this guy off.
He spilled his coffee.
Not a good color for Croft.
Coffee on the outside,
coffee on the inside.
Lipstick on the lid.
She threw her coffee at him.
WILLOWS:
Croft chases her
from the parking lot
caught up to her at the light.
They said their
"screw you, screw yous."
I think I know
the word
that made her throw the coffee.
I hate that word.
SIDLE:
Those lids never fit.
She nailed him.
Light turns green
and the chase is on.
WILLOWS:
And now she's got a problem.
( tires screeching )
She's got a pursuit
on her hands.
And she's the pursued.
So, she dials 9-1-1.
( voice over phone ):
9-1-1. What's your emergency?
Oh, my God, you've got help me,
please. Help me!
Somehow she loses him.
And she's still spooked.
All she wants now
is to get home.
( tires squealing )
Please... pl-please.
( train whistle blowing )
( brakes screeching )
( crossing-guard bells ringing)
( sighs with relief )
Hey, sweetie...
Oh, God, no!
Help me!
( train whistle blowing )
That's why she had
the emergency brake on.
( train whistle blowing )
She could have jumped out.
Not without her dog.
Help!
( tires squealing )
( train whistle blowing )
No!
( starter grinding )
( screams )
And that's why you always cut
the other driver some slack.
I'll call Brass, tell him
to make the arrest.
Veronica removed the
original illustrations
from the books
and replaced them
with forgeries
which she then
left at your house
so that she could point
the finger at you
if it ever came to that.
She never thought
that you'd find out
but you did.
And you told
Mr. Hunter.
"All you have in this business
is your reputation."
So, Veronica tried
to save hers
but instead of
killing Mr. Hunter
she ended up killing herself.
Oh.
Sorry.
That's okay.
( giggling )
I like order.
Me, too.
That's why I was scared.
Scared?
Of Veronica being in love.
I was stupid.
I thought she loved me.
"Then must you speak of one
that loved not wisely...
But too well."
Othello, Act Five, Scene Two,
lines 343 and 344.
But Othello killed Desdemona.
I didn't kill Veronica.
No, you didn't.