We should have
these parties more
than once a month.
I would, but Mina
tends to get jealous.
I love you, Chief
but if anybody should
be jealous, it's you.
( laughs )
Who's that guy?
Hey, Chief...
I didn't know
you were into guys.
What guy?
( two gunshots )
Daddy?
So two nights ago
he has a party.
High-end guest list,
very private.
That was the last
anyone saw of him.
Housekeeper arrives
20 minutes ago.
This is what she found.
Ex-Chief of Detectives.
Left to make the big bucks.
Consultant with security
at every major casino in town
and couldn't even
protect himself.
There's only one interpretation
for this:
"Kill the pig."
And what about
the rest of his family?
No sign of the wife.
What about the daughter?
Housekeeper assumed
that she spent the weekend
with the grandmother.
Assumed?
She's gone.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
His wife and daughter
are missing.
His silver Cadillac DTS
is also missing.
We're looking for any
signs of forced entry
in the house.
Any signs of ransack
that's not associated
with the party.
Okay.
We need serious damage control.
When the media gets a hold of it
it's going to be bad
for morale all around.
Watch your step.
I'll take the downstairs.
Yeah, I'll be above you.
Looks execution-style.
At least one shot
to the back of the head.
A lot of bruising
around these handcuffs.
So he probably
fought back.
Without a doubt.
Found a shell casing.
Looks like one of ours.
Nine-millimeter.
Standard issue.
So where do you suppose
the Chief keeps his gun safe?
( drilling )
We're in.
Thank you, Scott.
What do you got?
.38.
Nice.
Pearl handle .25.
Clear?
Still looking for that .9.
So you think the
Chief might've kept
his signature piece
someplace else?
"For 25 years of
distinguished service."
An honor like that.
Keep it in the case.
Yeah.
So I'm thinking that
the wife might be in on this.
Why didn't
she plan better?
Pack the kid's clothes.
What?
The nanny told me that
she only took one shirt--
one the kid
wouldn't even wear.
Security guard.
No party list
but he did see
each car that left
the night of the
party and morning.
Chief Rittle left
around 5:00 a.m.
5:14 to be exact.
You saw Chief Rittle leave?
Yeah, he was with
his wife and kid.
And he had his baseball cap
and sunglasses on
like always does.
So you saw a baseball cap
and sunglasses.
( cell phone rings )
Did you actually
see the Chief's face?
Grissom.
Well...
Actually, I didn't.
Brass found the
Chief's Cadillac.
Who found it?
In-house security.
Blue jacket.
First time he saw
the car was Saturday.
Chalked the tires twice.
Saw the bulletin on
the Chief and called us.
Any bodies, Joe?
I already checked
inside the car.
We're waiting on you
to check the trunk.
( cell phone rings )
Whoa.
Excuse me.
Who is this?
"Chief Rittle"?
What is his connection
to the Chief?
I don't know.
But if he has gunpowder
residue on him
could be our shooter.
Okay.
Florida Highway Patrol called.
Several motorists
saw a girl
matching Sasha's exact
physical description
walking along an access road.
In Florida?
Miami-Dade County.
Chief was shot Friday night.
It's a two-day drive
if you don't stop.
It's national news
with national attention.
I'm not surprised
we're getting call-ins.
Well, if it is our little girl
she's got evidence on her
from two Vegas homicides.
One of us should be down there
to process.
Take Warrick.
I don't think he's
ever been to Florida.
( sirens blaring )
She's seven years old!
She's wearing a pink shirt!
She was last seen
by a motorist there!
She can be two kilometers
in either direction.
Think of this area
as a quadrant. Divide up.
You, north.
Got it!
You, south.
All right, this way.
Let's go.
( truck horn blows )
( horn blowing )
Clear out!
Watch your back!
( squeals )
( squealing )
Sasha?
Sasha.
My name is Horatio Caine.
I'm the head of the Crime Unit.
Horatio?
Yeah.
That's a funny name,
isn't it?
My mother named me
after a famous writer
named Horatio Alger.
Ever hear of him?
Is your badge real?
Yeah.
Yeah, that's real.
My daddy's a policeman.
I know that.
I knew that.
They're looking for me,
you know.
Me, too. Me, too.
What do you say we sit here
and get found together?
What a day.
( helicopter whirring )
Burgundy sedan.
Caucasian female.
Age 32. Traveling
with a Caucasian male
indeterminate age.
I got a female in distress.
I want the APB to
extend the whole state.
Panhandle to the Keys, yes, sir.
Good.
Horatio Caine.
Catherine Willows.
Caine.
Brown.
Child Services has
sent a doctor out.
All right,
let's just be clear.
This is a Las Vegas case.
This is our victim
and we do the processing.
Okay, I didn't say
he processed her.
I just said he was here.
I appreciate the respect.
You sure about that?
Does she know about her father?
Not yet.
Well, I'd like to get started
processing.
Can you show me
who you found?
Okay, I found her
right in here. And...
this is the young lady
right over here.
Hi, Sasha.
I'm Catherine Willows.
And...
I need to ask you
a few questions.
Okay?
My kit.
Did the man touch you?
He hit my mommy.
Did he hit you?
Did he hurt you
in any way?
He acted like
I wasn't there.
Well, you know what
always happens to
bad people?
They leave behind
a part of themselves
and that's how you can
help us find your mommy.
Now, I need to look
underneath your fingernails.
You want to show me
what's in your hand?
It's okay.
Where did you get that?
Go! Run, Sasha, run!
I ran out after they drove off.
I picked that up.
I bet it felt cold
when you picked it up.
No.
No... hot.
Hmm.
You're tricking me.
You're too smart for that.
You can spot a Glock cartridge
from a block away:
rectangular
firing pin impression
breach face shear.
This casing's no Glock.
It's isn't your Chief's weapon.
Well, whoever this guy
is, he's a lousy shot.
Five casings, no hits.
Oh, by the way,
I'm Calleigh Duquesne.
Don't ask me how to spell it.
Southern.
Catherine Willows.
Southern... Nevada.
You got a theory on how
the mother and daughter
ended up
all the way in Miami
from Las Vegas?
Well, we don't actually
work theories.
Do we, Warrick?
No, just evidence.
We're much more
fanciful down here.
Aren't we, Horatio?
I think that's a
fair description.
My guess is, this belongs
to Taurus 9, made in Brazil.
It's a cheap
Beretta knockoff
and you may not see
many of them in Vegas
but we get them down here
all the time.
Which makes me think this guy
wasn't fleeing Las Vegas.
He was coming home to Miami.
Well, it's no longer
"Trunk Man."
Identified him
from his dental records.
Jason Doyle. Dead
for three days; no GSR.
So, I guess he
didn't shoot Rittle.
We only recovered one
slug from his cranium.
And I got this fragment
from his lower back.
His lower back?
I thought he was shot
twice in the head.
Vascular embolization.
Bullet got into his
arterial system.
That's rare.
Well, it took a
full-body x-ray
for me to find the thing.
Bullet entered here
fragmenting at the neck
and losing velocity
upon penetration
of the carotid artery.
Tube down the aorta,
continually losing momentum.
As it exited the aorta,
it struck the vertebral column
and then was swept down
to the base of the aorta
where I recovered it
here at the lumbar region.
( huffs )
Pinball.
Looks like nines,
like we found in the Chief.
I'll call Catherine. Thanks.
Yeah.
Hey, Nick...
Mm-hmm?
You ever been
to a swingers' party?
Well, if it's the same
thing as a frat party
yeah, lots of them.
You know, you get
enough booze going
things can get pretty wild.
Frat party, huh?
I wouldn't know
anything about that.
How wild?
Multiple-partner wild.
And it'd be no big deal
to have two, maybe three
girls at once, just...
( beeping )
Hit on the rock glass.
"Work card.
Orpheus Hotel. Tiffany Langer."
Who's she?
Showgirl.
Yes, I went to the party.
No, I didn't go alone.
And no, I'm not telling you
my date's name
or anyone else who was there.
These people are important.
Well, a very important
police officer
was murdered there.
I don't care.
It took me a long time
to get into the circle
and I plan on
staying there.
Was there anybody there
you didn't know?
Anybody who wasn't
in "the circle"?
Well, my date.
Do you know where he is?
I haven't seen him
since that night.
He sent me home
with a judge and his wife.
So... your date
stayed at the party
after you left?
As far as I know.
Where does he live?
I don't know.
I've known him for five days.
GRISSOM:
Well, that's 120 hours.
There must be something
you know about him
that you could share with us.
Right-handed, a Libra,
circumcised, rich...
Back-East rich.
Which kind of surprised me
because he wore
really cheap cologne.
Cheap? How?
Smelled funny... sweet.
Are you sure it was cologne?
Or deodorant.
Mouthwash maybe.
All I know is
it smelled sickly sweet.
To be honest I thought he could
have used a little help
in that department.
Would you happen to have
an article of clothing
of his by any chance?
The only thing he gave me
was a good time.
Hey, guess what?
This isn't about you.
This is about a missing
seven-year-old girl.
Why don't you give us his name.
Adam Van der Welk.
Uh, no, the Chief's little girl
is with Child Services.
We're still
at the drop-off place.
Yeah, right.
Will do, Brass.
I got a pill.
Looks like sedative.
Okay.
Diazapam.
Benzos...
That could explain
why the mother
didn't escape
with her daughter.
She was incapacitated.
Go!
How'd the little girl get away?
We got some tire treads
on the shoulder.
Made an easy stop.
And why did he pick
such a secluded area?
Seems like a great place
to ice someone.
Or take a leak.
Maybe that's why he stopped
the car here... to take a leak.
Run! Run, Sash, run!
Let me ask you another question:
When you're home alone
do you lock the bathroom door?
I don't even know you.
Sure you do.
We all do.
It's human nature to avoid
being vulnerable, isn't it?
So, if that's the case
then he would look for a tree
to shield himself, wouldn't he?
So, then the question becomes
how far along this path
before he loses sight of them?
Not very far.
Look at this.
Bang. Footprints...
and this is urine.
If you're lucky urethral cells
with slough off with urine.
But if we get his DNA
there's a chance we'll get him.
( cell phone rings )
Yeah. Caine.
What do you mean FBI?
WILLOWS:
So you're saying
the guy has B.O.?
GRISSOM:
Body odor, bad breath.
I don't know; there's something
about Adam Van der Welk
that makes him smell.
All this because some showgirl
said he smelled sweet?
Sickly sweet.
Smells can be like fingerprints,
my dear.
Hey, what's going on there?
I thought you were meeting
the Feds?
Uh, yeah, we are.
They picked the place.
The Shore Club.
Later.
What's taking so long?
That is a good question.
Hey, I just ran into
a Fed in the lobby.
He told me that
apparently the Vegas case
fits the profile of a serial
the FBI's been tracking.
Hey, you're from Vegas?
Speedle.
Brown.
Where was the Fed?
He's right there
in the lobby.
He's got his
little headphone on
and his little tie.
And you talked to him?
Yeah.
Do they have an ID yet?
No ID yet,
but their perp
targets wealthy couples
at their playgrounds...
Pebble Beach, Aspen,
the Hamptons.
Evidently the husbands
get murdered first
and the wives later.
After they've enjoyed 48 hours
of fun and games.
48?
Vegas?
Speedle.
Willows.
That's it?
There's also a link to Miami.
Of course there is.
Or, you know, he could
just be some geriatric dude
that just digs the weather.
WILLOWS:
I don't understand.
Why didn't the Feds
put this out on NCIC?
Because they're Feds.
Excuse me.
Dennis... Dennis...
Tick-tock, Dennis.
While you're waiting
to get your ducks in a row
the guy with
the "Miami link"
just slipped
through my hands.
Horatio, I didn't have
Federal approval...
I need answers
for this little girl.
Her father's just been killed,
maybe her mother, too.
And that's your fault.
You understand that.
It sounds like you're
making this personal.
Dennis, you don't give me
this link
I will make this very personal.
All of his victims stayed
here in the last year.
Here? This hotel?
Rittle and his wife, too.
Last winter.
Mm, I wish I would have
known that.
Maybe they'd still be alive.
Yeah?
( speaking Spanish )
Si... Vamos.
I had a bad feeling about this.
What'd she just say to you?
She just said that you need
to learn the language.
I don't see this burgundy car.
Where are you looking?
Check the disturbance
along the bank
and follow it in.
How did you find
the disturbance?
Drive up and down
the canals all day?
No, the thing about Miami
is the entire city's
watched from above.
Coast Guard choppers.
Someone going to cover me?
I got you.
WILLOWS:
Cover you for what?
Alligators.
Only way to
outrun a gator
is to swim faster than
the guy next to you.
Isn't that right, Delko?
Used to have a partner.
CAINE:
Guys...
please?
That her?
Yeah, that's Mina Rittle.
Our guy's still in the wind,
folks.
Still in the wind.
What's her name?
Mina Rittle.
Who wrapped you, Mina?
The plastic wasn't
for transport.
Covering her intimates--
most likely sexual.
Two gunshot wounds
left temple.
One shot was
a through-and-through.
Trace ASAP, along
with the plastic.
My preliminary probe
shows water in the lungs
which indicates
she was still alive
when she was put
in the canal.
Looks like the eyes
are glued shut.
Gold crusty substance
underneath.
What is that, Mina?
The substance is water-soluble.
But somehow it got
preserved in the water.
My guess is
the plastic
was wrapped
around her eyes
at some point.
Wait a minute.
There's a lot more of it.
What do you
want to bet
this is in every orifice?
You guys got a sick one.
Aha!
Delko, you've been down there
for 45 minutes.
Do you know the level
of bacteria in the water?
You can get
all kinds of infections.
What do you got?
Water pistol.
One water-logged
Beretta knock-off.
Suspect's personal gun?
That's it.
Congratulations.
I'll put it
over the wires
that he's not carrying
that Taurus anymore.
Do that, and take a shower.
Nice shoes.
Ma'am, you have
to concentrate
on the face.
In parts, not
just the whole.
Ask me
what he wore.
Ask me if he was
good in bed.
Just don't ask me
how close together
his eyes were.
You said he kind of looked
like Ricky Martin, right?
Yeah, with a touch of Jude Law.
ARTIST:
Try to not
just picture him.
Try to think of an event.
Okay...
Three-way kiss.
His lower lip
was kind of pouty...
and he had this
Michael Douglas thing
working, you know---
a cleft in his chin.
Kind of like that?
Yeah.
You're right.
That is easier.
Adam Van der Welk.
Little girl saw a monster.
Showgirl saw a husband.
So this guy could be anybody.
STOKES:
Yeah, that's the problem
with eyewitnesses.
All the more reason
to rely on evidence.
Tell Warrick hey.
Let me know if anything breaks.
You, too.
Hey.
So, how's your colleague
Grissom doing
on the aroma angle?
I'm sure he's
making progress
but Grissom rarely
says anything
until he's good
and ready.
Smart man.
I just wanted to show
you something.
The sticky substance
we got off the wife
is, in fact, honey.
You say that like
it means something.
Well, honey on its own
is just honey
but when you add plastic wrap,
it's... a different situation.
( techno-pop playing )
( cheering )
( crowd chanting )
Five... four... three...
...two... one...
( cheering )
Yum.
This is where
he got the idea.
Yep. This is Hives.
Wish me luck.
Excuse me.
Hi.
Some guys like to lick it off.
Really? I'm partial
to the swab myself.
Ready, honey?
Coming, dear.
Tuberculosis victims
emit breath that smells
like wet leaves.
Maple, elm, ash, what?
I'm not sure.
Miami is pulling
cars out of canals--
chasing leads,
debriefing the kid--
and you guys are
flipping through textbooks?
This is how I work.
Tuberculosis.
Cyanide Poisoning.
Endocrinology.
I'm following my nosino.
You're closer to this
Van der Welk guy
than you're letting on
aren't you?
Doctor...
Doctor.
How about Darier disease?
Doesn't that
give you a rash
that smells like
human excrement?
We're looking for something
a little sweeter.
There's diabetic
ketoacidosis.
Body has excess glucose
which converts to ketone...
gets expelled
through the pores.
Has a fruity smell.
It would help if we had a piece
of the assailant's clothing.
What?
I think I overlooked
some evidence.
SPEEDLE:
I'm going to isolate it
using high-performance
liquid chromatography.
Once we identify
the pollen
we'll know if it's
floral honey.
So, H, when's
the last time
you were in Hives?
I was there opening night.
I didn't see you there.
I was, uh...
VIP.
What is this?
It's Tupelo honey.
It's the purest
of all honeys.
Stays in liquid form for life.
Doesn't crystallize or harden.
Where'd you get that?
CDC hipped me to it
after that Africanized
bee problem.
Okay, let's swap
this out.
I want you to take
a look at this.
We got this off
the Chief's wife.
It's a match.
WARRICK:
$500 for five dollars
worth of honey?
I don't think
it's worth it.
Those are mostly
for decoration
but once in a while
some bigwig comes
takes one of them out of here.
Wouldn't it have
been easier to put
these in order?
This is going
to take forever.
WOMAN:
Maybe not. I've got a receipt
from just two nights ago.
Let me see that.
Do you recognize
this guy?
Yeah, looks just like
every other Joe
that comes in here.
Look, you work the door.
Anybody come in here
in the last 48 hours
that bought some of that
very expensive Tupelo honey
This is Miami.
Every night's a weekend.
My people tell me
that a customer
came in here two nights ago
to buy some.
Wasn't a customer.
It was a limo driver.
A limo driver?
Yeah, Gordon.
Gave me a C-note
just to double park.
Did this Gordon tell you
who he had in back
of his car?
No.
Just that it was some rich guy--
some high roller.
Let me guess-- from Vegas.
Yeah.
( siren blaring )
How'd you find him?
Figured, limo driver--
airport.
I spotted Gordon
here on Alton--
back way to
Miami International.
Lit him up,
pulled him over here.
Nice work.
You got a
last name, Gordon?
Daimler.
Look, Officer,
the Corwins are coming in
on their own private jet.
They're two of my
best customers.
I really should be there.
Well, the Corwins
are going to have to wait.
WILLOWS:
We understand that
another one of your customers
bought some
very expensive honey
from a club.
Yeah, well, I've had
stranger requests.
This customer of yours
have a name?
Never got it.
He paid cash.
Never saw a credit card.
Well, did you notice
anything unusual
about him?
Did he smell?
Did he...
have an odor?
Uh, his breath maybe.
He'd been drinking a lot.
Remember what
he was drinking?
Was it sweet
like Irish whiskey?
Whatever I have stocked.
Well, we'd like
to take a look.
Sure. Go ahead.
Gin.
( engine starting )
Hmm.
Smell that?
Sickly sweet.
That's exactly how
Grissom
described it.
You want me
to do what?
Smell this.
That's it.
That's Adam's smell.
In the five days
that you two were together
did you happen to notice
what he was drinking?
Champagne.
Did he ever drink
anything sweeter
like whiskey or cognac?
Are you kidding me?
With him it was all Dom
all the time.
You found a medical condition.
GRISSOM:
Diabetic ketoacidosis--
it's an insulin deficiency.
His body's been expelling
excess glucose.
Makes him smell fruity.
Which I guess
could easily
be mistaken
for whiskey breath.
Hey, can you
test for diabetic
ketoacidosis off urine?
Well, blood's the best
but if you had a urine sample,
maybe.
Ask him what medication
you would take for that.
What would
a doctor prescribe?
Novalin insulin.
Lucky for us we found
blood in his urine.
Absence of C-Peptide
in the blood.
Means the insulin
in our guy's system
isn't natural--
it's synthetic.
And prescribed.
We're right over here.
This is our database.
Okay, what we're looking for
is a patient
who's purchased
synthetic insulin
in the last 48 hours.
Here we go.
Gordon Daimler.
That's the limo driver.
That's him.
And the reason that old Gordon
probably didn't smell
when we picked him up
is because he'd just taken
his insulin, hadn't he?
But the scent was still
in the limo's AC system.
Well, now we have
this guy's address.
Yes, take a look
at this address.
A limousine driver
with a house on the water
in Coconut Grove?
I don't think so.
Who's the owner of record?
Let's check it.
Sissy and Dylan Corwin.
That's the couple
he was picking up at the airport
when we pulled him over.
That's right.
So then maybe that's how
he finds his victims--
driving a limo.
And when they're away
at some posh resort
he moves into
their house,
doesn't he?
Hops over to Las Vegas.
Visits the couple
he met in Miami.
Kills the husband...
Mm-hmm.
...brings the wife
back here-- kills her.
And when the Corwins
come home...
not good.
WILLOW:
No one's answering inside.
Miami-Dade Police!
Slowly.
I got a blood trail here.
Leading to the garage.
He dragged the body to here...
Put her in that car.
Nine-mil.
One shot's
a through-and-through.
Scalp hair.
He fired this
one first.
I don't know.
To terrorize her.
This strike here.
That one's all business.
He wrapped her
in plastic by the bed
raped her.
Then dragged her
in here
and cornered her
like an animal.
If Gordon's true to form
he's going
to kill the Corwins.
You guys should take
a look at this.
Well, people don't really
buy these houses
for the view.
It's a place to put
a million-dollar boat.
But what's your point?
The boat's missing
and that's where he's
killing them right now.
Speed, get on that thing
right now.
Put the birds in the air
and call the Coast Guard.
Right now. Do it.
Air and Sea, this
is Tim Speedle.
I need you to be
on the lookout
for a yacht, T-45.
R.O. Dylan and
Sissy Corwin.
Commandeered
by one Gordon Daimler.
Gordon Daimler.
Commandeered by...
Coast Guard found her adrift!
No radio contact!
We hailed her.
No response.
Infrared's up.
Blue means dead,
red means alive.
Pink.
Body heat's fading.
Person's dying.
Identify the
other players.
Speed?
Red. Is that our suspect?
I'm not sure.
I am.
How?
We haven't identified
all the players.
He's going back to finish off
the job. Detweiler.
Getting a bead on him, sir.
The M.O.
on this guy
says husband's already dead.
He's going back to
finish off the wife.
You're good to go.
Body language
does not
look like an attack.
Wait a minute,
wait a minute.
Don't the Corwins
have a jet?
The Corwins have a jet!
That's where
Daimler is.
It's the Corwins
in there.
Abort this, Sackheim!
Abort this!
Interstate case,
not your call! Proceed!
Stand down!
Take him out!
Detweiler,
I know you want
to impress your boss
but there's an innocent
man on that boat.
Now, if you
take this shot
I'm going to be
in your grille
for the rest of
your natural life.
I want you to think
about what that
might be like.
Think about that.
Thank you. Speed,
the Corwins have a jet.
Find the jet.
Call the FAA
and ground the jet
by authority
of Miami-Dade County.
You got it, H.
Give us 30 seconds.
Then send backup!
Mr. Corwin!
I tried to save her.
It's too late.
I'm sorry.
( sobbing )
Get me Fire Rescue.
Few more minutes, sir.
We'll be on the way to Monaco.
Good evening.
Mr. Van der Welk.
Gordon, drive
your limo here?
He's clean.
The Corwins...
are my friends.
They lent me this plane.
Like the lent you their boat?
Speak to the pilot.
Dylan Corwin called
him personally.
Directed him to fly me
to Monaco.
I'd rather call "Dylan"
at the hospital to confirm.
WILLOW:
The husband
didn't die.
He left us a witness
and enough evidence
to convict you
in two states.
Rich men don't go to jail.
You're not rich, Gordon.
I'm going to, uh...
I'm going
to book this guy.
You want to go with?
Nah, you got it.
I'll have my DA
call your DA.
( chuckles )
Sounds good.
Uh... Thank you
for your help on this.
Thanks for yours, actually.
Right.
You take care of yourself.
I always do.
Hey.
My mommy and daddy are dead,
aren't they?
Well, your aunt is flying in
to talk to you.
That's a yes.
I lost someone once.
Who?
Well...
Did you feel sick?
Still do.
Sasha.
People are going to say
a lot of things
about your mom and dad
and some of them
are going to be true
but what I want you to remember
is that they fought
like heroes for you.
Will you remember
that for me?
Good.
Good for you.
Hello.
Hey.
Nice tan.
Nice suit.
Yeah, well,
I knew you were
coming back today,
so I dressed up.
Yeah.
Right.
Really.
What?
Nothing.
It's just... unusual
to see you dressed like that.
I had to go
to the Chief's funeral.
Missed me that much, huh?