Mom! Mom!
The dirt burned my hand!
( siren blipping )
What's HazMat doing here?
Kid's playing tag,
takes a header in the dirt
ends up with first-degree
on his hands.
Wait. We got a call
about a dead body.
Yeah, I'm getting there.
So, HazMat arrives
figuring some sort
of chemical spill.
Starts removing
the toxic soil, and bam
a shovel slams
into a shoulder blade.
SIDLE:
Clothing's been
reduced to shreds.
Epidermal tissue.
is virtually gone.
The body's desiccated.
GRISSOM:
Viscous fluid the consistency
of dishwashing soap.
HazMat guy was right.
Killer doused
the body in lye.
Must have thought
it would destroy the body.
Yeah, ashes to ashes,
dust to dust.
Without the wait.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
( dispatcher speaking
in distance )
Ma'am, I'm sorry, but I need
to neutralize the soil.
If you touch the soil
you're going to contaminate
my crime scene
but I'll let you know
when I'm finished.
Okay.
What'd you get?
Vic's wallet, what's left of it.
It's a Nevada license.
Bob Martin.
31. He lived downtown.
There's 20 bucks in the flap.
Rules out robbery.
Look at this.
Looks like a paint fleck
or metal chip, maybe.
What'd the Ranger say?
Nobody saw anything suspicious.
Park closes up at 10:00 p.m.
No security,
minimal lighting.
Basically, a pretty good place
to dump a body.
You found this guy
in the park?
Actually,
HazMat found him.
Well, that explains the
postmortem scar tissue.
Lye had a field day
on his flesh.
( sizzling )
Time of death?
Approximately 24 hours ago.
Tell me about the car.
Car?
What car?
Comminuted fractures
of the proximal tib-fib.
Both legs.
Bumper hits right
below the knees.
Sure sign he was hit by a car.
Look at all the bruising.
If he was struck and killed,
ecchymosis would be nonexistent.
Which suggests he survived
the impact.
Usual injuries.
Ruptured patellar tendon
laceration
of the saphenous vein
and multiple incised wounds
containing slivers of glass
which I will send over to Trace
and bruises:
legs, arms and chest.
What I didn't find
was arterial lacerations
or underlying vessel damage.
Confirms death wasn't immediate?
Correct.
Victim was like
a leaky water balloon.
Heart slowly pumped blood
right out of his body
and based on the coloration
of the bruises
trauma was sustained
approximately 48 hours
before death.
Three days ago,
this man was injured.
He bled out
until he died yesterday.
We didn't find any blood.
Lockwood?
Hey, Stokes.
Who called it in?
BLM chopper pilot.
They always buzz Diablo Canyon
looking for hikers
in distress. Or worse.
He see anyone else
in the vicinity?
No, just the vic:
Stacy Warner, 26.
Las Vegas resident.
I scanned
for a Missing Persons on her.
Nothing.
No tire treads.
Whose are these?
Paramedics and mine.
Same path.
Walked straight in,
straight out.
Engagement ring,
no wedding band.
Orbital bone
looks fractured.
Could have lost her footing
and hit her head.
Could've.
Hold that for me?
Down feather.
But she's not wearing a jacket.
Shine that right here.
Grissom should enjoy this.
Hey, Lockwood
you got any food
in your vehicle?
Hamburger, anything like that?
Gum, sugar-free.
No, gum'll kill him.
I'll stop at the
first place I see
pick up some jerky.
Will you get me a sample
of the ground
underneath the body?
Soon as the Coroner moves her.
Good.
( sighs )
Bob is dead?
His body was found
at Sunset Park.
His license gave
this address.
Are you his domestic partner?
We're roommates.
I got divorced
last year.
And about six months ago,
Bob's wife kicked him out.
He needed a place
to crash
and I needed help
with the mortgage.
He's two months late
on the rent.
How do I go about collecting
under the circumstances?
Look, we were roommates.
We weren't really friends.
When was the last time
you saw him?
We both work at the Tangiers.
He managed the restaurant,
and I work in maintenance.
Last Monday
we drove in together.
But you didn't drive home
together?
Mondays? No.
After shift, he'd walk over
to the university.
He's an amateur photographer.
Take the bus home.
But he didn't come home
Monday night...
I didn't think much of it.
He's always going
back and forth
with Charlotte.
His wife.
What do I care?
As long as
the rent's paid.
Photo Department
kept a log.
Bob Martin reserved
a darkroom on Mondays
from 10:00 to 11:00 p.m.
He was logged in
Monday night.
Good. We got
a bus to catch.
( tires screech )
He left these photos behind.
They're all of the same woman.
I bet it's his wife.
Silver flecks...
like the one you found
at the body.
I got a piece of plastic.
Looks like a headlight cover,
maybe.
This could be our crime scene.
( tires screech )
Assuming this was a hit-and-run
how does a guy
with two broken legs end up
on the other side of town buried
in a park, covered in lye?
What are you looking for?
No sign of blood.
No evidence of a cleanup.
If this is our crime scene
then somewhere between here
and Sunset Park
Bob Martin lost
eight to ten pints of blood.
Where is it?
So do want to tell me about
the silver flecks I found?
Paint chips?
Aluminum and melamine
in the color coat
indicate that
it's car paint.
Factory job.
Uh, body shop paint
contains styrene,
not melamine.
Mm, what type of car?
Trick question.
Paint won't tell me that.
But I do have an answer.
It's not technically part
of my job description
but as you know,
I'm always eager
to expand my
responsibilities.
Take a look
down the scope.
GRISSOM:
Looks like
some sort of insignia.
Crosshairs.
That's the plastic
you collected
at the accident site.
Now that mark is only found
on the S-class Mercedes.
It's all about
branding.
Now knowing
that the headlight
came from a Mercedes
I was able to compare
the infrared spectra
with the paint spectra
supplied by the manufacturer.
Check this out.
SANDERS:
Your vehicle was painted
Sarasota Silver.
Also, only available on
the S-series '99 models.
I checked with
the Mercedes state rep.
Five were sold in Nevada.
Sara's tracking down
the owners.
You've, uh, already shared
this information with Sara?
Yeah, an hour ago.
And she was way more
fascinated than you are.
Well, I'm somewhat
fascinated by the fact
that I'm your boss,
but you talked to her first.
Well, you were at dinner.
I've been in the lab
all day, Greg.
I've been
looking for you.
Well, it's hard
to see me
if you and Greg
are out ahead of me.
Oh, uh, sorry
about that
but Brass got me a list
of those Mercedes owners.
One moved to Los Angeles,
three are over 50.
My guess, they would have
stopped and rendered aid.
Brass is checking them out
which leaves
a Ben Weston, 25.
Leased the vehicle
last week.
You found my car?
Why? Is your car missing?
Yeah, isn't that why
you guys are here?
I filed a police report
a couple days ago.
God, I love that car.
Hocked my future on it.
Tell me it hasn't been stripped.
You wouldn't
happen to have
a copy of that police
report, would you?
I'm a lawyer.
Here you go.
Thanks.
Sarasota Silver, S-series,
stolen Monday night.
Yeah, I stopped
for take-out after work.
When I came out, it was gone.
Don't most of these luxury
vehicles have security systems?
What's with all the questions?
We're investigating
a possible hit-and-run.
You think the bastard
that stole my car hit someone?
GRISSOM:
Ignacias High,
Nevada State University...
Are you a local?
Yeah. Great town.
I studied my ass off
in law school.
Passed the bar first time.
Good for you.
Let me guess--
criminal defense?
Everyone deserves
representation.
Yes, they do.
Would you happen
to remember
what clothes you were
wearing yesterday?
A blue pinstripe,
a light blue oxford
gray tie--
a gift from my girlfriend.
First week as
an associate--
firm like this
you tend to pay attention
to wardrobe.
SIDLE:
Mr. Weston,
we'd like
to take a look
at those clothes.
Really?
Well, you need a warrant.
But I'm a nice guy.
I picked them up
at lunch.
Downstairs--
one-hour dry cleaning.
Nice suit.
Thank you.
I just bought it.
I hope you didn't
just buy the shirt.
Oh, come on.
I've been meaning
to change dry cleaners.
Well, maybe you shouldn't
have gotten lye on it.
Lye is an alkali
and when it's mixed with water,
it eats right through fabric.
Mr. Weston...
you mind taking off your shirt?
Excuse me?
Lye can burn through fabric.
It can also burn through skin.
I have my limits.
You want me to strip,
you're going to need a warrant.
But since there's no basis
for your request
you can forget about it.
MAN:
She drowned.
This is the girl I found
in the desert.
I am aware
of that.
She drowned.
It's not possible, Dave-o.
She was found
in Diablo Canyon--
miles from the nearest
water source.
Lake Mead's got to be
20 miles away.
Desert, no desert--
I don't care.
She drowned.
Look, if it's
any consolation
she dry-drowned.
Dry-drowned?
Happens in about
ten percent of all cases.
When dry-drowning occurs
the larynx closes
involuntarily
preventing air and water
from entering the lungs
resulting in hypoxia--
a reduced concentration
of oxygen in the blood.
Thus, water's
kept out of the lungs--
dry-drowning.
In wet drowning,
hypoxia also occurs
but the larynx relaxes
and water floods the lungs.
Still, the question remains,
how does a girl drown
in the middle
of the desert?
She doesn't.
She was engaged.
The guy never filed
a missing persons on her.
I didn't file a missing persons
report on Stacy
because she wasn't missing.
As far as I knew,
she was on a solo trek
up in Diablo working
toward her NESTFs.
NESTFs?
Sorry.
National
Extreme Sports Trainer Finals.
I took mine last week.
Did it in three days total.
So, I didn't expect her back
for at least two more days.
Okay.
You mind if I have
a look around?
No, go ahead.
Thanks.
Detective.
You see that?
Mr. Hudson...
you own this house with
Stacy Warner, is that right?
That's right.
Any idea
how this blood got there?
No.
Stacy had a head trauma wound.
You wouldn't know anything
about that either, would you?
I'd never hurt Stacy.
No?
How do you explain
the domestic disturbance call
to this address two weeks ago?
We told the officers then
it was nothing.
I don't know...
the neighbor who
filed the complaint
said you were really yelling
at Stacy.
Said it sounded abusive.
HUDSON:
We're sports trainers.
We say some crazy things
to get each other
to do one more lap in the pool,
one more crunch.
Are you a liar?!
Or are you going
to give me more?!
Are you weak?
Are you worthless?!
Can you account for your
whereabouts this week?
Big Sky Triathlon
in Montana.
You want to see a picture
of me crossing the finish line?
No. No.
We got what we need.
BRASS:
So I sent out
some bulletins.
Got a hit on Weston's
missing Mercedes.
Sullivan called it in.
He's a typical tow guy.
I'll run him.
MAN:
Yeah, I got a call.
"You want a wrecked
S-class?"
( chuckles )
You betcha.
The parts alone are worth
four or five times
the Blue Book value
of the car.
I asked where do
I pick it up.
That's all I asked.
You didn't ask his name?
Someone throws you
300 thou in used parts
the only response
is "thank you very much."
So where is the vehicle now?
Look around.
You work fast.
Hey, I called it in.
What more
do you want?
Aristotle said something
about the whole being more
than the sum of its parts.
Of course, he never
worked in a chop shop.
We want all of the parts.
Affirmative for blood--
passenger side.
Well, that's just
a trace amount.
Where's the rest
of it?
Want to pass me the luminol?
Well, you do know
how to light up a room.
Location of the blood
on the seats and the dash
indicates that
the victim
was inside the vehicle.
Maybe the driver hit Bob Martin
stopped
and put him in the front seat.
Okay.
Where'd they go?
Well, not to the emergency room.
Not to Sunset Park
for 48 hours.
I'll swab
the rest
of the car--
bring the samples
to Greg
and have him run it
against Bob Martin's DNA.
If you find any blood
that isn't his then...
Maybe it belongs
to an injured joyrider
and we have a new suspect.
The one day
I'm due in court
and you pull a drowning
in the desert.
How'd it go?
Oh, it went great.
The judge recessed
right before my testimony.
I'm on call.
Catherine's on call.
You're making progress.
The blood from the poolside
matches the female victim.
Yeah, the problem is
the small amount of blood
found in her own home
isn't enough to prove anything,
you know?
People bump their heads
and scrape their knees
all the time.
Yeah.
That musclehead
boyfriend--
he's a little shady.
He's hiding something.
I can feel it.
Are you able to prove
that he drowned her
in their swimming pool?
Four samples:
one from their swimming pool
one from their bathroom,
one from Lake Mead
and one from Clark County
Reservoir
but none are consistent
with the water
I recovered from her stomach.
What else did you collect
from the scene?
Some rocks from under her body
and a goose feather.
Goose feather?
This looks like basalt rock.
Didn't it say somewhere in here
that she found her
at 1,500 feet?
The desert, yeah.
Well, you can only find
this rock
at high altitudes
like 4,000 feet.
Really?
Mm-hmm.
You sure?
Yeah. I went on this field trip
up at Table Mountain
in my senior year--
"Rocks for Jocks."
Don't ask me why
I remember any of this.
Hey, that helps.
I think I'm going
to head out there.
You want to roll?
You're on call at court,
right.
All that blood belonged
to the victim.
Look at this.
Visible blood drops
under the passenger seat.
That's a strange place
for blood.
Radiated spatter.
What do you think?
Blood pooled
onto the floormat.
As more drops splashed down
the impact projected
the blood drops upward.
Okay.
But where
did it fall from?
Greg said you guys
are processing an S-class.
Yeah, what's left of it.
Now, that's a crime.
Oh, this would have broken
my ex's heart.
Every weekend the guy'd be
test-driving another Mercedes.
I'd get myself all dressed up
make the dealer believe
we could actually afford it.
Damn.
Except if this car was stolen
the ignition lock would be
punched, right?
Huh?
Anyway, I got to go.
Warrick and I are due in court.
Later.
We... we would
have caught that.
We were distracted
by what we were
looking for.
Yeah.
So how did the thief
turn the engine over
without breaking that lock?
Maybe there is no thief.
WESTON:
All right, you got me.
I ran
into the Chinese restaurant.
I wasn't in there
more than two minutes
but I left my keys
in the car.
You left
an $80,000 Mercedes idling.
Yeah.
Stupid, right?
That's why I didn't
say anything.
Besides,
if my insurance finds out
it's contributory negligence.
Let's just
cut to the chase.
I told you everything.
Chinese restaurant
near my house.
I couldn't find a parking spot.
Parked in the handicapped zone,
left the motor running.
I wasn't in there
more than a minute.
Take off your shirt, please.
You're going to need a warrant,
like I said.
But you don't
have basis.
Actually, the issuing judge
disagrees.
I can call Judge Scott,
contest your grounds.
But you won't.
You want to refuse?
One of us will remove it
for you.
Yeah, all right.
Here you go.
Look, no chemical burns.
You satisfied?
The warrant
is for the whole shirt.
Yeah.
You don't have to be
a scientist
to know where that came from.
( tires screeching )
We got enough
for a hit-and-run.
All right, hold on.
It's not what you think.
I called in my order.
I looked down to put away
my phone.
( bang )
I hit something.
I stopped. I looked around.
I couldn't see anything.
I figured it must have been
a dog and it ran off.
So I drove
to the restaurant
and that's when
my car was stolen.
It was a rough night.
Look, my car was stolen.
What happened next,
I don't know.
Save it.
You're under arrest.
All right.
I hate lawyers.
We need a warrant for his house.
We need to find something
we can use
to keep that creep
off the street.
( panting )
I'm all for retracing
the girl's steps
but it wouldn't hurt
to bring in some cadets.
If it was a little kid
or a mass casualty
maybe we'd get
that kind of manpower
but hey, exercise is good
for us, right?
Air feels thin to me.
( grunting )
Check it out.
Let's go.
You said the vic
was wearing
light layers of
clothing, right?
Yeah, several layers,
tempered cotton.
This is a men's extra large.
This is too big for her.
Goose down like
I found on her body.
What's this?
Ah. Property of Mr. Muscles.
You want to run it?
Well, maybe he left
a day later than he said
for his little marathon,
you know?
Followed her out here,
started arguing with her
no neighbors around
to call the cops.
( shrieks )
She manages
to fight her way free
finds higher ground,
he follows her, takes her
down.
So then what?
He drowns her
with canteen water?
I'm going to let you
run that by the DA.
You should try describing
a scuba diver
up in a tree, man.
This is nothing.
No, the evidence tells a story.
So why'd a cagey guy
like our suspect
leave his jacket up here?
Everybody thinks
they have a plan
till things start
to go wrong.
I gave Stacy my jacket
the morning she left for Diablo
for night layering.
Extreme hikers can't carry
bedrolls.
That's what makes it extreme.
And she just left
your jacket wedged
under some rocks.
Maybe.
I don't know.
Look, I gave it to her
to take care of her.
I loved Stacy.
Then help us out here, man.
I've got
prior disturbance calls
her blood in the pool
her body drowned
in the middle of the desert
with your jacket nearby
your map.
That's my trail map.
I'd like it back.
No. No, it's evidence now.
You can put
a request in for it
when we complete
our investigation, okay?
Am I free to go?
You're not under arrest.
I'm getting this to QD.
He doesn't want me
to have this map
and I want to know why.
( sighs )
He made bail.
Yeah, that figures.
Oh, I almost forgot.
Here's a warrant
to search your premises.
We'd like to start
in your garage.
Yeah.
Look, I'm filing a complaint
with your supervisor.
You're harassing me.
If you're a lawyer
you should know
the legal definition
of harassment.
Investigating a crime
doesn't quite fit the criteria.
However, a false accusation
of harassment
within earshot of my colleagues
could be construed as slander.
I know the law, too
and I've actually been
in a courtroom.
This was parked in
the driveway, wasn't it?
Now that's a crime?
Jim, could you get
this car moved for us?
Unless the keys
are in the ignition
hand them over.
It's a rental.
You're not
on my policy.
I'm a safe driver.
It smells like bleach to me.
I'll check for blood.
Why would he leave
his car outside
with the sprinklers on
instead of putting it in here?
Maybe the garage was full.
MAN:
What exactly do you
want me to look for?
STOKES:
Alterations, erasures,
paper content.
The guy was really
nervous about me
having these maps.
Okay, I'll test
the components in the inks
and then bombard the paper
with different wavelengths
of light.
We'll see what's up.
Sounds good, man.
Thanks, man.
You bet.
Hey, Grissom...
Keep me posted.
I will.
Did you take a look
at that maggot from
the desert yet?
Yes.
And?
Well, it belongs
to the family
of sarcophagids.
That's as far
as I got.
You mind taking
another look for me?
Your maggot never
developed, Nick.
It never will.
Why?
It happens to
Sarcophagids
when they're exposed
to freezing temperatures
before they're
allowed to pupate.
So, my maggot
was stunted?
Probably by
frozen air.
Yeah, but we found
the vic in the desert.
Well, maybe it was
a very cold night.
Mucho frio.
Muchas gracias.
Come on in, Greg.
Hey.
So I heard about
your cold maggot.
News travels fast.
I was thinking--
most people figure Las Vegas
means The Strip.
But it really means
"the meadows."
I'm trying to calculate
barometric pressures here, G.
Well, my point is
Nevada is a
basin-and-range state.
Down in the desert basin,
hardly any rain.
But up in the
mountain ranges
it's 40 inches a year.
That's more
than Seattle
more than San Francisco.
more than...
Yeah, yeah, I see
where you're going.
Last week in Vegas--
perfect weather.
Warm, steady barometric
pressure, but...
out in Diablo, two days before
I found Stacy Warner's body...
The mountain
shadow effect.
That's what
meteorologists call it.
Right.
This is Ecklie's
Mercedes?
Well, actually,
I sold it to him--
five years ago.
It was in much better
condition back then.
Hey.
So I checked
with Auto Detail.
Uh, obviously, if you fill
a car up with enough water
or, in our case, blood
it's going to leak
through the bottom.
Dicing wounds with
glass were limited
to the upper torso, right?
Top of the head, face,
top of shoulders
and forearms.
Which would be consistent
with a head-on crash.
The head of the victim
crashed into the passenger side
of the windshield.
Well, this isn't
the same model or year
but it's
close enough.
Okay, I'm thinking
that the car
clipped the victim here
and he was catapulted...
and he was positioned
something like this.
( glass shattering )
So now he's bleeding
and his blood is dripping
onto the mat.
The victim bled out
for two days.
Yeah, but he could
have been conscious, right?
Until he lost
a third of his
circulating blood volume?
Then the hypovolemic shock
would have set in
after approximately 12 hours.
So it's possible
that he was wedged
into the windshield
of Ben Weston's Mercedes
which was parked
in Ben Weston's garage.
We know where Bob Martin was.
Where was Ben Weston?
My guess...
At work,
making a good impression.
Sometimes I'm glad
I only deal with dead people.
You know...
the tow truck driver said
Weston's Mercedes was totaled.
But the only damage
would have been
to the bumper
and the windshield.
He's lying.
Maybe it
wasn't totaled.
I don't remember.
I was only interested
in the parts.
You don't know
who phoned it in?
It was a guy.
What else
can I tell you?
Mr. Sullivan, in '96
you were arrested
for vandalism, right?
I was 18.
It was a prank.
I hoisted the principal's
station wagon
onto the roof of the gym.
St. Ignacias High School, right?
GRISSOM:
It's funny, but
the registered owner
of the Mercedes
also went to St. Ignacious.
You were in
the same class.
Ben Weston.
That might ring a bell.
So what?
He's been arrested
on a hit-and-run.
He's also under suspicion
for murder.
That makes you an accomplice
after the fact.
Twenty to life.
Okay, look, all I did
was take his call,
take his car.
I don't even like the guy.
In high school,
he's the one
who turned me in.
He said he wanted
to make it up to me.
Just remind yourself
that usually I bring
the case home.
If that garage floor stain
started out as blood
the bleach
just degraded it.
There's nothing for me
to work with.
Sorry.
There goes the slam dunk.
Blood in the garage
would have conclusively
linked victim to killer.
So is this his
rental car?
Sunset Park is two miles
from Ben Weston's house.
I was thinking maybe
he used this car
to transport the body
to the dump site.
So we should be able to find
some of the vic's blood
or hair or fibers
from his clothes.
No visible trace
of any kind.
Except for this.
So this mountain
shadow effect--
the barometric
pressure spikes down
the temperature
strikes down...
Right. Humidity
spikes up.
Moisture in the air
condenses.
( thunder crashing )
The mountains get
a flash flood.
I checked with the National
Weather Service.
This area got three inches
of rain in 20 minutes
the night Stacy died.
So, she was up here hiking
when the weather changed.
( thunder rumbling )
( wind whistling )
Takes one to the head...
on to the basalt rock.
She's trying to clear
the cobwebs when the rain hit.
( thunder rumbling )
But it was too late.
She drowns in the floodwater.
Body gets carried
to the base of the canyon.
A couple hours
worth of sun
water dries up.
No evidence
of the storm anywhere
except on the vic
who carried traced amounts
of basalt rock with her
and rainwater
in her throat.
( phone ringing )
Stokes.
The map has definitely
been tampered with.
You sure about that?
Positive.
Chemical tag in the ink
tells the tale.
Then I shot the maps with
300 nanometers just to be sure.
I need you to get
those results to me.
Thought you would.
I have a messenger on call.
Are you telling me Stacy's death
was an accident?
An accident
of nature, yeah.
But you still had
a hand in her death
just the same,
didn't you, Mr. Hudson?
What are you
talking about?
Why don't you
take a break.
Come on over here
for a sec.
You altered the map.
You used the same
color ink as the printer
but the chemical tags
in the ink are different.
This is magic marker.
And when you shine
ultraviolet light on it
like this...
you can see exactly
what you did.
You made this look like
an impenetrable ridge--
no way out,
when it's actually a meadow.
If she had a good map
she might have been able
to find her way
out of the highlands
by nightfall.
I didn't want her to die.
I didn't.
Then why did you alter the map?
We competed.
I'd just run the trail
in three days.
I didn't want her
to beat my time.
Am I being charged with murder?
No.
You altered the map
but you didn't make it rain.
What you did isn't a crime...
but it is criminal, isn't it?
Oh, come on.
Your entire case
is circumstantial.
Your physical evidence
is pathetic.
You've got, what,
a wrecked car--
a white powder
in a rental--
and a bleached-out
stain in my garage.
If that's
all you've got
you won't even get
a filing.
My cell phone.
Yeah.
Mitchell Sullivan
found it in your car
at his chop shop.
I hope he didn't make
any long-distance calls.
Thanks.
It's evidence.
Yeah.
Hey, now it's a party.
And I brought the music.
You'll be happy
to know
that there were no
long-distanced calls
made on your cell phone.
But there was one call made--
to 911 at 2:30 a.m.
on Tuesday morning
while your car was
still in your possession.
( tape recorder clicking )
MAN:
911. What's your emergency?
( man gasping ):
Please help me.
I can't hear you.
You'll have to speak up.
Help...
Sir, our system is
not compatible
with your cellular phone.
Where are you calling from?
I'm in a garage.
Sir, can you see a street sign?
It's dark...
Explain it to me, Ben.
How does a lawyer rationalize
something like this?
SIDLE:
You know the law.
You hit a guy.
It was an accident.
Nothing criminal.
But you let it escalate
to first-degree murder.
I spoke with your
senior partner.
It was your first day
on the job.
Big firm.
Big welcome.
How many drinks
did you have that night?
GRISSOM:
Let me guess.
You wanted the alcohol
to wear off
before you called it in, right?
So you decided
to wait it out.
Have a cup of coffee,
sober up
and then call the cops.
But unfortunately,
Bob Martin woke up.
Help me.
Please, help...
help me...
So what do you do now, hmm?
Can't walk into
the emergency room
and say, "Hey, this guy
was bleeding to death
in my garage while I was eating
mu shu pork."
( door opening )
Sara, there's someone
here to see you.
Not right now.
You'll want to talk to him.
It's relevant.
I sacrificed to get where I am.
My whole life
was leading up
to last Monday.
Yeah. It's tough, huh?
Fifteen years
to build your dream
and a 15-second phone call
destroys it.
Where did
you find this?
Packing up
Bob's stuff.
Found it
on his dresser.
Thought you'd
want to see it.
Thanks.
When a driver hits a pedestrian
the presumption is
the driver is negligent.
When a driver's been drinking
and he hits a pedestrian
it's no longer negligence,
it's reckless homicide.
But when a pedestrian
intentionally throws himself
in front of a moving vehicle
then the driver's
no longer responsible.
Legally, he's
off the hook.
This suicide letter
was written by Bob Martin
to his wife Charlotte.
When you hit him
Monday night
it wasn't an accident.
You were off the hook.
Until you let him die.