( thunder crashes )
( country song playing
on radio )
♪ He sounds to blue to fly ♪
♪ The midnight train is
winding low ♪
♪ I'm so lonesome I could cry ♪
( thunder crashes )
Hey, you need a ride?
So, where
are you headed?
It's not where I'm headed.
( thunder crashes )
( indistinct radio
transmissions )
( indistinct talking )
Welcome to Good Springs.
Long drive.
Well, I know it's
out of your jurisdiction
but your name
is on the tape.
Where is he?
Inside.
We left the recorder
where we found it.
Anything else?
Victim's wallet.
Thank you.
Pete Walker,
California.
Date of birth:
August 17, 1957.
It's got to be
the work
of Paul Millander.
What do you think
brought him back out?
The rain?
Hasn't changed
his M.O.--
kills men
whose birthdays
are on the anniversary
of his father's murder.
In descending order--
first victim
was August 17, 1959
second victim,
August 17, 1958
this guy, 1957.
Ready for this?
I have a pretty good idea
what it's going to say.
WALKER ( anxiously ):
My name is Pete Walker.
I reside at 715 Lady Del Sol
and I'm 44 years of age.
I'm going to kill myself.
I'd like to say "I love you"
to my mother.
I'm so sorry, I never wanted
to put you through this.
I just can't do it anymore.
( gunshot )
MILLANDER'S VOICE:
Happy... birthday, Mr. Grissom.
Isn't your birthday
in August?
August 17, 1956.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
( indistinct radio
transmissions )
Hey.
Is it true?
Millander?
SIDLE:
Yeah, it's true.
Gunshot, suicide script
Leaves the body
in a bathtub.
Paul Millander.
Remember
the first victim?
Royce Harmon?
Stuart Rampler, second...
And now...
Pete Walker.
Grissom, Catherine briefed us
about your birth date.
Yeah, what's up with that?
Coincidence.
Make anything
more of it
gives Millander more power
than he deserves.
We work together; he can't
outsmart all five of us.
Yes, he can.
Plan of attack--
split up.
Nick, take the tape
over to A.V.
Break it down.
Warrick, Sara--
examine the perimeter.
We need to know
how he
got in and got out.
We'll stay with the body.
Thanks.
Big night.
SIDLE:
Rain washed
away everything.
What I got will never
hold up in court.
Well, I got
some mud prints.
Check these out.
SIDLE:
This is the point of origin.
They stop at
the warehouse threshold.
BROWN:
He must've taken off his boots
before he stepped in.
Only one set
of prints...
Check out the depth
of the impression
compared to mine.
He carried the body in.
The extra weight explains
the deeper impression.
Shoot it.
Cath...
come here,
take a look at this.
It's not lividity.
WILLOWS:
He's got stippling
on the side of his face.
From what
I can tell
he was shot once
in the chest.
Unburned gunpowder
wouldn't plume this way.
No entry wounds
near his face.
I'll have Robbins
check for leaks.
Maybe he can find
a hidden bullet.
WILLOWS:
Wait...
wait a minute.
I got something.
Hello, Dolly.
Dark hair,
12 inches.
Female?
So another
victim...
or an accomplice?
( recorded voice ):
My name is Pete Walker.
I reside at 715 Lady Del Sol...
First things first.
This tape was not recorded
in the warehouse.
There's no auditory echo.
Contained quarters.
Yeah, a car,
a small SUV.
The tape was an inch
from his mouth.
Sibilant pops
bear that out.
Helps that the killer uses
hi-fi mini-cassettes.
Picks up everything
ambient.
Let me get rid of the wipers.
( whirring noise )
What is that,
that whir sound?
I don't know yet.
But... recognize this?
( country music plays )
Oh, yeah. Willie Hank's
"Don't Pay the Ransom."
I'll contact the local
country and
western stations
get a time and tape
on when the song aired.
Establish a timeline.
What else?
Now, here's
where it gets funky.
Watch my sensor
levels.
WALKER:
My name is Pete Walker.
I reside at...
See how the color wands
gravitate towards
the bottom right corner?
Mm-hmm.
There's an auditory imbalance.
From what,
a blown speaker?
A blown left speaker.
Sounds like the driver's
side one blew.
Pulling all of the sound
bottom right.
Now if that
were true
the victim may
have been sitting
in the passenger seat.
What does that get you?
Millander was driving.
I believe hitchhiking
is illegal in Clark County.
Yeah, you got me.
Came with the car
along with
the registration.
The R.O.'s our vic
Pete Walker.
Who flagged it?
Nevada State Patrol.
So, this
is Walker's car.
Millander
was hitchhiking.
Guy stops
to do a favor...
ends up dead.
Yeah, but how
would Millander know
that the guy
who'd pick him up
had a birthday
August 17, 1957?
There's the
initial bullet hole.
No other leaks.
Died from a single gunshot wound
to the chest
just like the others.
The others didn't
have stippling
on the side of their faces.
Unburned gunpowder doesn't
change direction and stick.
Unless...
he turned his face away
from the gun.
Not likely
due to the origin
of the facial burn.
( gunshot )
Nobody misses
from this distance.
True.
GRISSOM:
I think this might be
intentional.
I-I-I call it
"Good Versus Evil."
He's telling me he's going
to show me both sides.
BROWN:
I found some G.S.R.
SIDLE:
Nice.
That's why Grissom
didn't find a bullet.
It went out the window.
It went
out the window.
I'm so sorry.
I never wanted
to put you through this.
I just can't do it anymore.
I've lost hope.
I'm going to call Nick,
tell him we found out
what that unidentified
whir sound was--
the window going down.
SANDERS:
Your planted hair is full
of information.
It's got a complete
follicular tag.
Well, the vic had
light brown hair
so we know it's not his.
Could be
Millander's.
Well, that's impossible.
The amelogenin
on the follicle
came back XX-- female.
So, back to that again.
Another victim,
or an accomplice?
Yeah, but what decade?
What do you mean?
Look under 400-X.
The tag cell
is aged.
So Millander planted
an aged hair?
But once exposed,
the tag
would dry up and fall off,
especially in transport.
Not if he nurtured it
kept it in a freezer.
That would work.
WILLOWS:
Okay, so what's he
trying to tell us?
That he used to kill women?
Maybe just one.
Grounds?
I don't know yet.
Is this the car
the guy was killed in?
He was killed in
the warehouse--
and don't sneak up
on a person like that.
Now you know how I feel,
like ten times a day.
So what's this
Millander guy's thing?
He saw his dad killed
when he was a kid
over some money dispute.
Ends up killing
guys himself.
Check that out.
An eight digit number
with a dash.
Pep Boys receipt?
Dry cleaning tags?
Well, whatever
it is
it happened during the summer.
Paper only burns itself
into plastic
in high levels of heat.
So what kind
of paper item
would you shove
into the center console
in the heat of summer?
Something you didn't want.
Or something you had to keep.
( pager ringing )
Powwow.
Later.
Nevada State Patrol
found the victim's
vehicle here.
Found the body
in Good Springs here.
Warrick and I found
stippling
on the passenger side
seat back.
WARRICK:
We were thinking Millander
posed as a hitchhiker
overpowered Walker,
and then faked a
gunshot in the car.
I put a call into three area
country and western stations.
Got the FCC list
for each.
During the time of the victim's
suicide recording
KWV had Willie Hank's
"Don't Pay the Ransom"
playing from 1:47 a.m.
to 1:51 a.m.
And what time was
sunrise this morning?
5:13 a.m.
So that's about
a three hour window.
He was racing
daylight.
WILLOWS:
So in that time he had
to get the recording
and get rid of the body.
Made the recording in the car
killed him in the warehouse.
No, he carried him
into the warehouse.
Yeah?
Mud prints--
one set in, one set out.
Are we sure he didn't
kill him
in the car?
He was shot in the warehouse.
He was incapacitated in the car.
SIDLE:
Okay, how?
Grissom, you want
to add something
to this?
Yeah. None of it matters.
It's one of those
few cases
where physical evidence
isn't helping us much.
I mean, put it in context.
The victim's birthday is always
on the anniversary
of the murder
of Millander's father.
Staged like his father's death.
A planted hair
a planted
fingerprint
It's all biographical.
He's using the evidence
to tell us a story.
Hey...
Peter Walker,
our victim
worked for Cinema Road Services
in Valencia, California.
Drives the newly released
film reels
back and forth to Vegas.
Drops off the new reels
every Tuesday
for Friday's release.
Brings the old one back.
Drives the same route
all the time?
Yeah, according
to his mileage log.
Did Walker have
any kind of record?
BRASS:
Pretty much a boy scout
except for a speeding ticket.
Speeding ticket?
How long ago?
July 2, last year.
Summer.
909987-23...
Pete Walker.
Excessive speed.
July 2, 2001.
Walker's birth date's
on the ticket.
August 17, 1957.
Run the other two vics.
Royce Harmon.
WILLOWS:
Employment--
Dinners Delivered.
Need a car for that.
What about
his driving record, Jim?
He drove himself right out
of a license.
Try Stuart Rampler.
STOKES:
There's a few tickets.
Last violation--
excessive speed, June, 2000.
So what's the commonality?
Besides birth dates.
Besides birth dates...
BRASS:
All the tickets were written
by the same cop.
Excuse me.
Officer Yarnell?
Yeah.
My name's Gil Grissom,
with the Las Vegas Crime Lab.
May I ask you how many
speeding tickets
you issue a day?
Why is it any
business of yours?
You wrote tickets to three
people who ended up dead.
You think I had
something to do with it?
Look, I'm a good cop.
I protect and serve.
I even go to court
on my days off.
You mean court dates
for speeding tickets?
Yeah. Sometimes,
believe it or not
people actually contest them
and I'm there fighting
it tooth and nail.
Court.
Yeah.
In fact, I just responded
to a challenge this morning.
Always the same judge?
No, there's three
traffic court judges.
Session's about to start.
Why don't you go
bother them.
All rise.
Honorable Judge Douglas Mason
presiding...
Municipal Court,
City of Mulberry
State of Nevada.
You may be seated.
Gil.
Excuse me, Officer.
I'm with the Las Vegas
Crime Lab.
I need you to arrest
a murder suspect.
Where's the suspect?
Judge Mason.
His real name
is Paul Millander.
You don't want
to do this.
Sir, please take a seat.
Officer, this man is not
who he's pretending to be.
Take a seat now
or I'll have you
removed from this courtroom
and charged with contempt.
He's wanted in
Clark County
for murder.
You are now in contempt
of court. Bailiff?
Come on.
I apologize
for the disruption.
Let's proceed.
You may be seated, miss.
You can leave
this court
when it has concluded
its business.
Or find yourself in contempt
along with your friend.
Where are you from?
You know where
I'm from...
and I know who you are.
I'm not who you
think I am.
Local police have been
out here twice
this past year
about this man--
Paul Millander, is it?
Every time his story's
in the paper.
I've heard I look
like him.
Identical.
You've heard
of the Doppelganger Syndrome?
That every person is supposed
to have an exact double
somewhere in the world?
Do you believe in it?
Never been proved.
A Swiss neurobiologist
recently published papers
supporting its viability.
Brugger, I think his name is.
Stands to reason
this Millander
is my doppelganger.
The monkey wrench for you
is that we're both here
in the state of Nevada.
Well, you know,
we could always
do a DNA test.
You know, if you
keep that up
people are going
to start calling
you crazy.
Guard.
I trust you won't
go near
my courtroom again.
Before you go back
to Las Vegas
why don't you
come to dinner.
I tell my wife stories
about my day
and this one she may
need to hear in person.
6:00.
That's my address.
We live right here
in Mulberry.
Any chance
he's got a twin?
A doppelganger,
evidently.
Do you have your
mentholatum?
Why, you getting a cold?
No.
The judge just got sloppy.
Thanks.
Ah, fuming.
I'll lift it
and get it to the lab.
Go ahead and take
the Tahoe.
Call me later.
I'm going to dinner.
Greg, did you look
at the female hair
from the crime scene tub?
When you say "jump,"
I say "how high?"
I found testosterone
in female hair.
Post pubescent
female hair.
Well, men and women both
have testosterone
in their systems.
No big deal, right?
Well, this is.
This testosterone's
endogenous.
What? What do you mean?
Like outside the body?
Injections. Supplements.
So our mystery lady was trying
to enhance
her athletic performance?
Or increase her sex drive.
You know women do that.
I read.
None that I've ever met.
Not yet anyway.
Okay, I'm not sure
what this means yet, but thanks.
( rings doorbell )
Mr. Grissom?
I was admiring
these rain boots.
Please come in.
( violin music playing )
You have a lovely home.
We like it.
May I ask how long
you've lived here?
We bought the year
we adopted Craig
so that would be '92.
Craig, what did I tell you
you had to do
when our dinner guest arrived?
Hi, I'm Craig Mason.
Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you, Craig.
Want an I.D. tag
for safety?
Craig's school
is sponsoring
an identification program
for students.
Parents get one, too.
Can't be too safe out there,
can we, Mr. Grissom?
No, we can't.
Hungry?
That reminds me, Doug.
Be sure to tell Mr. Grissom
where you bought your rain
boots.
He was admiring them earlier.
Was he?
My husband's
only hobby
is driving around the state
looking for bargains,
rain or shine.
And I tell him,
"You're a judge now.
We don't need bargains."
To which I reply,
"Old habits die hard."
Truth is I think he just enjoys
his private time.
Dear.
As a judge I don't want
the outside world privy
to my private life
because they'll use
it against me.
You'll be safe now.
( typing )
( beeping )
( phone rings )
Excuse me. I'm sorry.
Grissom.
You're never going to believe
who Judge Mason's fingerprints
match.
Judge Mason.
As printed when he was sworn
before the bar
Nevada State Superior Court.
Okay.
Thank you.
My prints came back sound.
Douglas?
As I told you
earlier, dear
Mr. Grissom has confused me
with a very bad man.
I left him fingerprints
so that he could confirm
that I am
who I say I am.
Uh, I have to get back
to my lab right away.
I'm sorry.
Thank you for a lovely dinner,
Mrs. Mason.
Craig...
Your Honor.
I don't care
what the computer says
that guy is Paul Millander.
Yeah, we know that.
How do we prove it?
We have to disprove
this Judge Mason.
Birth certificate--
was he born in Mulberry?
Well, that's
the first thing
Brass looked into.
Apparently,
the records building
burned down in 1982.
Burned down?
Ruled arson.
No suspects ever found.
So Judge Mason has
no birth certificate.
How convenient.
Man, this guy plays
way out in front.
Here's some good news.
Brass went
to the new records building
looking for anything
on a Millander.
Found current
property-tax accounts.
In the name of Paul
and Isabelle Millander.
Mm-hmm.
Isabelle Millander?
We're with the Las Vegas
crime lab.
Are you here about my husband?
That happened over 30 years ago.
It's our understanding
that your child witnessed
your husband's murder.
Thank you.
My child was only ten years old.
So brave to testify
against those men.
But it didn't matter.
The judge ruled it a suicide
and those men went free.
I hope we're not interrupting.
It looks as if you're expecting
someone for dinner.
I always set
an extra place for Paul.
Your son?
My husband.
My way of
being together.
Those are
from his best years.
He started a company
out in Hollywood
in the 1930s.
GRISSOM:
Halloweird.
Movie makeup.
He used himself
as a model.
He made hand molds
and masks, everything.
Like a one-man
company.
May I use your bathroom?
Last door down the hall.
Would you happen
to have
any of his work still?
I kept only what's
most sentimental.
Might I take
a look at it?
Hmm, it's rudimentary.
Almost childlike.
Our child made it.
It's an ashtray?
My husband used his own hand
to imprint the center.
May I?
I wonder what this
green discoloration is.
I was often curious
about that.
I could take this
back to the lab
and analyze it.
I promise
to bring it back.
What are you doing
in my daughter's room?
Oh...
I have
a daughter myself.
I was admiring
the old clothes.
She's beautiful.
She died.
I'm sorry.
When did she die?
A long time ago.
A lifetime ago.
What about your son Paul?
I think it's time
for you to go now.
Mrs. Millander
we're just trying to clarify...
Please?
So, Paul Millander
killed his sister.
It's plausible.
It's not provable...
yet.
SANDERS:
No, you were right.
The substance isMicrocil-like
but it's really
old-school-- alginate.
The book says
that, uh...
makeup people
used it up to the '70s
to make molds
and impressions.
It's green, hence the "algin"
in "alginate."
We sold 10,000
of those units
last Halloween.
Even used
my own hand
for the mold.
These were his father's prints.
He was planting them
as if they were his own.
SANDERS:
The guy's pretty shrewd.
Every murder
comes back to a dead man.
Greg, if I refer
to Millander
as smart, it's one thing
but I mind if
other people do it, okay?
Got it.
What have you got on the hair
Catherine recovered?
Processing it next, sir.
Find me.
Did I miss something?
It's a kid's
fingerprint
from
the baseball card.
GRISSOM:
Clear...
Concise...
Anonymous.
Brass found no prints
from little Pauline
no birth records,
no death certificate.
I'm going to use the prints
from the only other kid who
lived in the Millander house.
Here come de judge.
Ridge analysis proof.
Judge Mason is...
Paul Millander.
( beeping )
It's...
It's Greg.
Come on.
Okay.
The hair you found
in Pauline
Millander's bedroom
Two X chromosomes-- female.
You didn't beep
me for that.
Well, Sara had
me compare it
to the hair
found in the tub
at the crime scene.
They're a
perfect match.
DNA identical.
So her brother
planted it?
Well... not exactly.
Yeah, he planted it.
He planted his own hair.
Millander.
It's a female hair.
With endogenous testosterone.
Pauline was taking
male hormone injections.
Why?
My theory?
Sex change.
You know, when I
was back at the house
I saw several
photographs of Pauline
and nothing of Paul.
In fact,
the only proof
of Paul is
a hidden baseball card.
There is no birth or
death record for Pauline.
Paul killed Pauline.
But he didn't murder her.
So that's what
you've been hiding?
That your daughter
is now your son?
Pauline went away and came
back a very strange man.
And I wouldn't let
him stay here--
not like that.
Mrs. Millander, we believe
that your son
has murdered three people
and that he's living
under the assumed name
of Judge Douglas Mason.
I need your permission
to collect some hairs
from Pauline's bedroom
for use in court.
We took this hair
from your
childhood bedroom
when you used to be Pauline.
They told my parents
I had
an "endocrinic ambiguity."
My chromosomes said female,
but my body wasn't that sure.
The doctors told my
parents to raise me
as they saw fit.
Unfortunately, they disagreed.
So, uh...
You were a girl
when you were inside the house
and a boy when you
were out in the world?
I managed.
Until...
that night.
( gunshot )
A boy...
could have saved his father.
You did what you could do.
You testified
against them.
Do you see the man who
killed your father
in this courtroom?
Y... Yes.
They went free.
And you started to identify
with the aggressors.
Why are you smiling?
I am...
comfortable
sharing this with you.
My, uh...
My mother wouldn't hear it.
Against her wishes
I cut off my hair.
Started wearing big shirts.
Big boots.
If I got tough enough...
No one would ever hurt me.
I went to the clinic...
and became a man.
Sexual reassignment.
Not just a man,
though-- a judge.
Doesn't get much
more powerful than that
but none of it
solved your
problems, did it?
Or else you wouldn't
have killed three innocent men.
I have a warrant
for your DNA.
Identity is so
fluid, you know.
May I?
See you in court.
Aren't you
wondering
about your birthday?
August 17, 1956.
No.
Why I didn't kill you,
since you were next?
No.
I've already picked
my next victim,
if you're curious.
It doesn't matter, Paul--
you'll be in jail.
Next up, People v. Landry.
Are all
the parties present?
What is going on?
I thought Millander
was supposed to be
arraigned at 8:00.
This is just
ridiculous.
I mean, you'd think
they'd make an exception
in this case--
three murders.
This guy's telling me
that Millander
is representing himself.
Pro pers are always
last on the docket.
BRASS:
A clean-cut guy
in a suit--
no one looks too close.
He must have got
a fake I.D.
He had my I.D.
You going home?
Yeah. They know
where to find me.
I re-read the
backgrounds
of Millander's victims.
I think that
he slipped up.
You know how every victim
read the suicide note
"I'd like to say
'I love you' to my mother"?
Well, Pete Walker
had no mother.
She died in
childbirth.
He never slips up.
Mrs. Millander?
My name is Paul Millander.
I reside
at 13891 Sand Creek Road.
I'm 46 years of age
and I'm going to kill myself.
I'd like to say "I love you"
to my mother, Isabelle.
I'm so sorry.
I never wanted
to put you through this.
I just can't do it anymore.
I've lost hope.