You’re going
to like my room.
You can see
the entire Strip
from my balcony...
and the bed.
I usually
don’t do this.
I-I mean, especially with
somebody that I just met.
Yeah?
Well, I could tell that
just by looking at you.
( elevator bell dings )
Uh...
Come on, don’t worry,
all right?
You can trust me.
Okay?
Promise?
I never lie.
You... are so bad.
( laughing )
Yeah, I am.
( gasps )
Hey.
Dispatch said
suspicious circs.
Yeah.
We got an anonymous call
to 911
at the same time
the couple found him.
A male voice said:
"A man has collapsed
at the Devon. Hurry."
Where’s the man?
Well, he was
unconscious but breathing
so paramedics took him
to Desert Palm Hospital.
There was no bullet wounds,
no knife... nothing.
You got a name?
Bob Fairmont.
Upscale home developer.
"A Fairmont home,
you’ll never roam"?
His billboards are everywhere.
They took these pictures
before they moved him.
Well, this is as phony as
a Chappaquiddick neck brace.
The clothes are all bunched.
SIDLE:
Collar’s off
to the side
leg fabric’s gathered.
It’s impossible to redress
an unconscious person
to make it look like
they dressed themselves.
You notice anything
about the suit coat?
Well, unless he’s going
to court or church
there’s no way he buttons
all three buttons.
Very good, Jim.
Why do they think
they can fool us?
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
I’m going to go to the hospital
to talk to Fairmont’s wife.
( camera shutter clicking )
Call me
if you learn anything.
Hey, guys.
I just pulled the manager
out of a restaurant.
Bob Fairmont was staying
in room 2927.
Catherine’s
parking the car.
Let’s go up.
We’ll meet you there.
Okay.
Mr. Fairmont was staying
in Murder Central.
Mmm.
Murder Central?
You never heard
that phrase?
Well, if I did,
would I have asked the question?
Sara, you’re with me
in here.
You guys get the elevator.
All yours, girl.
Thanks.
Sara doesn’t know
what Murder Central means
any more than I do.
Oh, Nick, give it up.
We got a Death Imminent
to worry about.
My husband’s in surgery.
Can’t this wait?
I’m sorry, no.
He was found under
suspicious circumstances.
Do you have any idea
who may have redressed
him or moved him?
He usually goes with women
who look a lot like me...
only younger.
And I’m embarrassed to say
that I’ve been flattered
by that, at times.
Do you have a name?
I was very much on the outside
of that part of his life.
I see.
I know.
The room’s talking to us.
They had champagne.
They were celebrating
something.
No lipstick on
either glass.
911 did say it was a man’s
voice that placed the call.
Smell the musk?
Hint of bleach?
Sexual intercourse.
They kept
the drapes open.
A married man who’s
not worried about...
photographs, long lenses...
Well, he’s either careless
or arrogant, maybe.
Or he has a death wish.
34 C?
If he was with a woman
who was the guy
on the 911 call?
Hand me that magnifier.
Thank you.
What do you got?
See those white specks?
What do you think,
cocaine?
No, I don’t think so.
How can you tell
just by looking?
Never you mind.
Let’s just get this to Trace.
Okay, we’re done
in the elevator.
You guys need a hand?
Yeah, you want to dust
the champagne bottle?
The average American hotel room
is covered with stains
invisible to the naked eye.
Yeah, but they’re
not all biological.
Some are soda stains,
food stains, whiskey
stains, you know.
No matter how clean
or expensive the room seems
that why I always travel
with Nonoxinol Nine.
You sound like
you’re making a commercial.
Nick, hit the lights,
will you?
Okay, we’re looking
for the freshest stains.
Soda, maybe...
Maybe champagne...
Oh! Someone’s little soldiers...
not fresh, dry.
More champagne.
GRISSOM:
Hmm...
"Starlight, star bright,
First star I see tonight."
Okay, I’ll let you guys
do the collection.
Thanks a lot.
Oh, and Sara?
Hmm.
Last hotel room
nearest the stairwell--
easy entry and egress
for an intruder
and if the victim fights back,
50% less chance of being heard.
Rooms only on one side.
Murder Central.
( door closes )
You are so busted.
I gave this to Trace.
Why do you have it?
SANDERS:
Well, because I deal
in DNA.
The smallest sliver
of epidermal tissue.
This is skin.
Scalp skin.
Itchy.
Can be embarrassing
in social situations
especially if one is wearing
a dark shirt.
Dandruff.
Good chance whoever
moved the guy into
the elevator...
Had a bad case of seborrhea.
Thanks.
Hey, Catherine.
Do you think Sara
would ever go out with me?
Sure.
As long as you don’t tell her
it’s a date.
BROWN:
Hey, Cath...
are you on this
Fairmont case?
House mogul caught
with his pants on?
Yeah, I’m just rolling
to the hospital to get
his clothes. Why?
You know the
Fairmont house
was one of my first
calls three years ago?
You serious?
For what?
Shots fired.
He shot himself while
he was cleaning his gun.
Wow!
Yeah. And after hearing
about tonight
I’m wondering if that’s
what really happened.
I’m going to pull his file
and check it out.
Let me know.
I will.
STOKES:
Nice shot.
Reservoir’s still wet.
Why did he
throw it?
Mmm. I’m only impressed
if he aimed.
I wonder if the woman
has any idea she left
her DNA behind?
Not rocket science.
Man’s inside, woman’s out.
Wife says the guy’s
a player.
She doesn’t know
the women.
You tell her about
the 911 tape?
The male voice?
Oh, I just got back
from Central Dispatch.
The tape’s lost.
New computer system.
Any ear-witnesses?
The dispatcher says
it could’ve been
a woman whispering.
Or a very old person,
gender indeterminate.
That’s about as good
as an eyewitness.
( phone ringing )
Grissom.
What?
I’ll be right there.
No lunch.
GRISSOM:
We got a time?
Well, all indications
are he was brain-dead
from the time he collapsed
at the hotel.
From?
An artery out-pouches
blood floods
the subarachnoid space.
Heart still beats,
but the brain’s dead.
And it doesn’t regenerate.
Aneurysm from trauma...
infection...?
Genetic predisposition.
Both parents went that way.
It increases a person’s
chance of stroke ten-fold.
He looks like an athlete.
Brain dead at 38,
otherwise healthy and strong.
Is this a Frankenstein?
I was wondering
when you’d ask.
Prime donor candidate.
Next of kin signed off.
How many organs
they take?
Eight in under two hours.
Man, those harvest doctors move,
don’t they?
Stat!
Go, go, go!
Here comes the liver.
Ready with a basin, please.
Right now.
And here we go.
( steady tone )
Clamp it.
Get it back,
get it back.
Ready and got it.
Here we go.
All right, I’ll notify
the PD about the organs.
So I was thinking...
maybe we could take our break
at the same time.
Later this shift.
Together.
Sure.
Really.
Semen.
No surprise there.
Well, without the DNA sample
from the hotel guy
this test is pretty useless.
I’m more interested...
in who the woman is.
Well, just like the bra,
I’m going to need a
reference of her DNA
in order to do anything,
and that’s not going
to happen until--
What the heck?
What?
Stripes.
Transverse white bands
that appear
six weeks after the onset
of symptoms of toxicity.
You got a closer view?
Uh...
They look like
Mees lines to me.
Could be livor mortis.
Or white striae, indicative
of heavy metal poisoning.
We can’t count
on a photo
to draw that kind
of conclusion.
We need the body.
Don’t take this wrong,
Dr. Robbins, but...
how do you
release a body
that’s been redressed and
dumped in an elevator?
I deal with cause of death,
which was an aneurysm
and therefore, a Natural,
and based on that
his body is released
to a mortuary.
The whole transplant thing
didn’t raise a flag?
I thought I’d raised a flag
with the good doctor
when I told him I was going
to notify the police department.
But evidently,
I miscommunicated again.
Great.
( typing )
( beeping )
All may not be lost. Here...
Body of Robert Fairmont
released at 0400 hours
to the Desert Haven
Mortuary.
I know that place.
Well, if they haven’t
embalmed him
we can still
get a blood sample,
test for heavy metal
poisoning.
Good. I’ll drive.
You’re not coming?
You found it, you run with it.
You can do it. Take Nick.
Okay.
How long’s he been in here?
92 minutes at
1,600 degrees.
What exactly was it
that you wanted to see?
His fingernails.
I’m very sorry.
Who approved
this cremation?
( sighing )
His wife, Julia Fairmont.
Same person who approved
the organ transplants.
( flames crackling )
BRASS:
You told me
your husband was in surgery.
He was.
Surgery to take
his organs
not to save his life.
He was technically... dead.
He wanted to donate his organs.
I was following his wishes.
Why are you being so hostile?
Someone was poisoning
your husband.
What?
We don’t know the dose
or the duration
but we do know
the type of poison.
We processed your husband’s
remains.
Most poisons would be
completely burned off
by cremation
but heavy metals
are very resistant to heat.
This heavy metal is called
selenium.
Did you notice that
your husband’s breath
might have been garlicky?
Garlicky?
The body will excrete
demethyl selenide--
smells just like garlic.
Uh... no.
The white stripes
on his fingernails--
did you notice those?
Um...
We didn’t see each other a lot.
Bob was busy building
his company.
That bother you,
him never being home?
I think it would bother
any woman.
Did you know that
the most common choice
of premeditated murder
among women is poison?
They cite its passivity.
I did not poison my husband.
You cremated his body.
He wanted to be cremated.
I cremated him.
He wanted to donate his organs.
I did that, too.
Now, if there’s nothing else,
I will be at home
preparing for my husband’s
memorial service.
Excuse me.
Do you want us
to notify you?
Of what?
When we find out
the exact amount of selenium
given to your husband
and over what period of time?
I thought you couldn’t tell.
Your husband’s gone, but
his organs are still out there.
Well, good.
Yes, I would like
to be notified.
Straight up,
am I going to die?
You have only a small
fraction of the poison
that was in your
donor’s body--
one organ.
With nothing
new coming in
it should work
its way out.
I must’ve had 100 tests.
How’d you doctors miss this?
A heavy metal like selenium
presents so rarely
that it’s not part of
our screening protocol.
You don’t look like a doctor.
No, sir, no, I’m not.
I’m Nick Stokes.
I’m with the Las Vegas
Crime Lab.
I’ll be right outside.
Thank you, Doctor.
I was hoping I might
be able to get
a sample of that
new kidney of yours.
A sample?
Biopsy. A sliver.
You mean open me up again?
Maybe an invasive scope.
The only way I can get
an accurate barometer
of the poison
in Mr. Fairmont’s system
is through
one of his organs.
I’m sorry, young man,
but this is my kidney now.
I waited four years.
I can’t have anyone
cut into me for it.
I just can’t.
No, hey, I understand.
Thank you for your time.
I like your watch,
man, that’s cool.
It broke while
I was down in surgery--
stuck on 11:00.
Think the Lord’s
trying to tell me something?
( chuckles )
Yeah, get it to
a watch repair shop.
I hope you get to
feeling better, Mr. Mercer.
Nick struck out on the kidney.
I got four no’s
over the phone.
One yes from a recipient
in Illinois--heart.
Useless--heart has
no memory for poison.
Why can’t we
cut the middle man
and just check
the wife’s house
for selenium?
All right, I know, something
about Constitutional law.
Get probable cause,
then get a search warrant...
Sara! I was just looking
for you.
Still up for break?
Sorry, Greggo. Hot case.
I’m going to go look at
Nick’s champagne bottle.
How you doing
with our DNA?
Uh... inside-outside
we’re still looking for
a reference for comparison
but the epidermals
are looking promising.
Nice.
You want to clue me in?
Sara and I were just
going out for dinner.
On the case, Greggo.
Oh. Right.
Excuse me...
I’m Claudia Gideon,
Bob Fairmont’s secretary.
I came to pick up
his property.
NURSE:
Oh, I’m sorry,
but Ms. Willows
already asked for them.
His property is
part of our investigation.
I’m afraid
I have to take it.
Oh, fine. I was
just doing my job.
Yeah, me, too.
Did you work
for the Fairmonts
three years ago,
when Mr. Fairmont was shot?
I was out sick that day.
Interesting.
You have dandruff.
Is that really
proper etiquette?
It is when I’m on a case.
You mind?
Where did you say you worked?
BRASS:
I’m going to ask you again--
were you in that hotel room
with Bob Fairmont?
I was not, no.
But you did redress him
and place him in the elevator.
You don’t know what
you’re talking about.
Well, that’s dangerous
to say to a scientist.
Dandruff is nothing more than
sloughed-off skin.
It has a nucleus
just like a cell on your arm
or your big toe.
These 13 DNA markers
from this dandruff cell
are a match
to the dandruff
that I recovered
from your sweater.
You were there.
At the hotel.
Okay.
Mr. Fairmont told me
earlier that day
to meet him in his hotel room
at 9:00
to pick up some papers, okay?
When I got there,
he was in bed--
naked, unconscious.
He always told me
reputation before health--
no scandals.
I dragged him to the elevator.
Let me guess--
you snuck out down
the stairwell.
Who was Fairmont partying with
in that room?
I don’t know.
Well, we won’t mind
if we compare your DNA
to the vaginal
contribution
of a condom
that we recovered from
Mr. Fairmont’s room?
Sure, go ahead.
Good.
We’d like to show you
something else--
about that
accidental shooting
three years ago
at your boss’ house.
WARRICK:
In this reenactment
Fairmont shot himself
while cleaning his gun.
The story
just doesn’t add up.
I think I fell for it
because I was new
and I wasn’t too eager
to talk to another guy
about him almost shooting off
his manhood.
This is the room
as it was then
based off of
my crime scene photos.
This is crime scene
reconstruction, new school.
Works backward, reverse time.
The bullet hit here.
The only logical place
for that bullet
to have been shot from
is four meters away,
one meter high.
He didn’t
accidentally shoot himself.
Someone shot him.
We’re thinking it was you.
The admission form
from the ER, 9/6/98.
The person who
brought Fairmont in
on the accidental
shooting...
was you.
I didn’t shoot him.
You didn’t poison him, either.
All these bad things
just happen to you.
I’m on call
24 hours a day, okay?
Mr. Fairmont beeped me.
I drove out to the house,
and I took him in.
Where was his wife?
You’d have to ask her.
Yes, I shot him.
He was supposed to go riding
with me
and he didn’t show up
until 2:00 in the morning.
No calls, nothing.
I was... hurt.
So, you just sat
there in the dark
and aimed south of his belt.
I just wanted to scare him.
It was a business meeting.
I swear.
I-It wasn’t like before.
I was thinking about you
the whole time.
So, why didn’t you
tell the truth then?
I wanted to,
but Bob wouldn’t let me.
He said that
it would ruin his career--
Fairmont Family Estates.
WARRICK:
I’m presenting
this case
to the D.A., even if
it is three years old.
My husband’s dead.
We had our problems
but I loved him.
I don’t... I don’t much care
what you do now.
Well, there’s only two reasons
a woman shoots a man.
She either loves him
or hates him.
Or both.
And that’s the sample
Catherine pulled off
of the secretary’s blouse
and the hotel man’s clothes--
same source.
Secretary moved the body.
We just interviewed her.
She copped
to moving him.
We’re looking hard
at the wife on the poisoning.
The secretary
has dandruff.
We know.
Dermatomycoses seborrhea--
we got it.
Topical eczemas
like that require
prescription medication.
The primary ingredient
of those medications--
selenium sulfide.
JULIA:
I don’t really feel right
about doing this.
Oh, this is
your residence.
Everything in Claudia’s
office is your property.
She could be back
from dinner at any moment.
This shouldn’t
take long.
( door closes )
( door opens )
That’s mine.
BRASS:
Could you tell us
why you keep your shampoo
in your office?
WILLOWS:
Shampoo full of
the same poison
found in Bob Fairmont’s remains?
I don’t know.
Aw, you have to do
better than that.
CLAUDIA:
Maybe I picked it up
at the pharmacy on lunch
and put it there.
I don’t know.
Cream cheese.
( Claudia scoffs )
Garlic cream cheese.
Hides the bitter aftertaste.
It explains away
his bad breath.
( laughing )
I did not poison him.
( cabinet door closes )
We’ll see.
Aren’t you going to arrest her?
( scoffs )
I haven’t done anything.
Other than poison Bob.
Poison?
I’m the one who looked out
for him.
You? I ran his home.
I entertained his clients.
Who made all of his
dental appointments, huh?
His haircuts? Who got
his taxes in on time?
Covered for his mistresses.
Oh...
why did he need mistresses?
BRASS:
Ladies...
don’t go there.
This is yours...
and these are yours.
There’s the door.
We build a case
before we make any arrests.
( monitor beeping rhythmically )
Hey, Mr. Mercer.
I got your message.
You wanted to talk to me?
Did you find out
who poisoned Mr. Fairmont?
No.
No, sir. I have found
selenium in his office
but... without actually
knowing how much was
in his system...
What if I could tell you?
My body’s rejecting the organ.
Doctor says it’s got
nothing to do with poison.
It’s antibodies.
( sniffles )
I’m sorry.
I told you this watch stopped
while I was
down in surgery?
It’s funny...
it’s like it knew all along
the kidney wasn’t going to take.
Anyway... there’s
one last good thing I can do
before I leave this earth.
So... how do we do this?
I can’t even talk Warrick
into splitting a sandwich
with me
and this guy’s willing
to give us his kidney?
You asked for it.
Yeah, that’s my point.
Carl Mercer risks
dying sooner to help
our investigation
but who protects
his rights?
He has free will.
Well, so do I.
I want to retract
our request.
I don’t think
any investigation
for the dead
is worth hurting
the living.
What?
SIDLE:
Guys?
You’re not going
to believe this.
Funny.
Sometimes it is
the simplest things
that seem so difficult.
I’ve been trying
to match the partial
from the champagne bottle
to these known prints.
It was upside down.
( computer beeps )
Must’ve grabbed
the bottle...
upside-down to pour.
( beeps )
( keyboard clacking )
( computer beeps twice )
So...
who was he with?
Mrs. Fairmont.
What?
Player was in the hotel
cheating with his own wife?
I was trying to...
rekindle our marriage.
I... got the room...
brought the champagne.
Oh, yes.
Yes.
He squeezed me
in between
business meetings
at the hotel.
And you didn’t think
to tell me that
when we first talked?
No, because you asked me
about him being redressed
in an elevator...
and, besides, when I left him,
he was... alive
watching the news.
( television news playing )
Oh, so, he had a stroke
alone, after you left.
( groaning )
I’m not a doctor.
I don’t know when he had it.
BRASS:
Well, CSI is testing
that champagne bottle
for selenium.
I didn’t think
poison caused strokes.
You seem to know
a lot about poison
for not being a doctor.
I know a lot of things
about a lot of things
but that doesn’t mean
that I killed my husband.
Yeah... but
what never lies?
Fairmont had
three gold crowns.
They should’ve survived
the cremation.
At least partially.
Heavy metal, after all.
SIDLE:
His wife...
had them removed
at the mortuary.
That adds new meaning
to the phrase "gold digger."
Actually, that’s how
the phrase got started.
People used to dig up the
bodies to extract the gold.
Now they just marry them.
In some countries,
this would be enough
to have her arrested
for murdering her husband.
What’s the most
important component
in a poisoning?
Poison.
Patience.
( moaning softly )
Ms. Fairmont...
Ms. Fairmont,
you feeling okay?
Yeah, I’m, I’m...
( groaning )
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa.
Hey...
Maybe I just need
to sit down... for a minute.
Yeah, yeah, let’s sit down
here in the car for a sec.
There you go.
Relax, relax, relax.
( beeping )
Yeah, I need an ambulance.
Uh, Vegas PD,
west parking lot.
( keyboard clacking )
Hey, what’s going on?
We called the hospital.
She’s been released.
ER doc gave her a shot
of Hydropazeen...
sent her on her way.
Hydropazeen?
That’s an antiemetic
used to counteract
heavy metal poisoning.
Which means... somebody’s
been poisoning our suspect.
I don’t know
how it happened.
Maybe she poisoned herself.
Why would she do that?
Why would she hide my
shampoo in my office?
What, you know she did that?
Well, it wasn’t her husband.
He was already dead.
She’s trying to frame me
for killing him.
I mean,
do you have anything
beyond your suspicions
that she did kill him?
She had
his gold fillings removed.
Doesn’t that tell you something
about her?
I had his watch
and ring removed, too.
Do you want to see them?
They’re in a box at home.
You realize that
doesn’t look good?
It can look
however it wants.
I have nothing to hide.
You mean since
you yourself have
been poisoned?
Yeah, why aren’t you asking
Claudia Richards about that?
First my husband, then me?
Why would she want
to kill either one of you?
I don’t know.
Maybe because he refused...
to leave me for her.
I had to wash his grungy
coffee mug every night.
I had to clean his toenail
clippings off of his desktop.
Why would I ever ask Bob
Fairmont to leave anyone for me?
So, you think it was all
in Mrs. Fairmont’s head?
He always said
she was crazy.
Okay, that’s it. All right...
Look, we’re not leaving here
till we get
to the bottom of this.
Then I hope she talks soon.
( printer whirring )
Greg?
Hey.
I was just printing
something out for you
on your hot case.
From the Internet?
SANDERS:
Yeah, I...
I was... on break,
had some time...
thought, hey...
Sorry, I drew
a blank on the wife.
I could really, really
just kiss you right now.
GRISSOM:
So, this is Claudia.
SIDLE:
Ten years ago, her husband,
John Gideon.
Claudia’s rich husband
also died young-- 35.
She donated his organs
and cremated his body.
We don’t have to chase
down these organs.
Ralph Parks rejected
the organ that he got
from Claudia’s husband.
An organ with a memory,
maybe?
The most. Liver.
He died two months
after receiving it
back in ’93.
Lived one state over
in Arizona.
I have the cemetery address.
Hey, Sara,
got the warrant.
Awesome.
We’ll keep you posted.
Embalming certainly retards
the decomposition process.
Yeah, well, it doesn’t
stop the smell.
The liver’s degraded
but any metal should
still be there.
We’ll find out.
Nick, did you get anything?
Hey, Sara. Yeah.
Sodium selenite--selenium.
280 milligrams
for a 180-pound man...
That’s murder.
Yeah, well, it would have been
murder for a 300-pound man.
This is different
than the shampoo compound.
Yeah, it contains
polysorbate 80
and vitamin E.
That combination’s found
in selenium supplements
injected in animals.
Animals? Like cats, dogs?
Mostly livestock, grazers.
To make up for the lack
of selenium nutrient
in the soil.
How did Claudia get
access to this stuff?
A dairy farm.
"Gideon Dairy and Cheese."
Largest supplier of milk
in Connecticut, in fact.
Brass talked to a local
chamber-of-commerce type
about Claudia’s husband.
You want to know
who his secretary was?
Yeah.
( Sara chuckles )
Our Julia Fairmont.
Ten years ago,
you played secretary
and you played wife
to John Gideon.
We have never represented
we didn’t know
each other previously.
JULIA:
And I wasn’t playing.
I was
a hard-working secretary.
And you loved
your husband
right up to the day he died...
of 240 milligrams
of selenium.
Animal selenium,
the kind used for cattle.
Well, we did live
in grazing country.
Although, I have to say,
Julia knew more
about livestock
than I did.
She rode horses.
I took the job because
Mr. G let me board my horse
at the family stables.
CLAUDIA:
Oh, I hated the stables.
The smell.
Never stepped foot in them.
Implicating you, the secretary.
I don’t believe this.
WILLOWS:
Bravo. ladies.
You have got this down
to a science.
Why did it happen
the first time?
Hubby ignored you
or abused you
or you got sick of him
fooling around
so you started slipping
the cow stuff
into his chocolate milk?
So the two of you struck a deal.
I’m, uh...
I’m coming into a lot of money.
No, we are.
SIDLE:
And then what?
The two of you realized
how quickly you could run
through a couple million?
So you went looking
for another mark
here in Nevada?
But the difference is
that you actually
loved Bob Fairmont.
You shot him because
he was cheating
but that didn’t get in the way
of your long-term
goals, did it?
( tapping on glass )
I just came
from the D.A.
Their attorneys were there
as well.
Based on everything we have
the D.A. is not going
to move forward.
He says it’s a reject.
Brass doesn’t have anything?
Brass is still in the field.
You’re free to go.
Where’s the ladies’ room?
It’s down the hall
to your right.
Thanks.
Pardon me.
WILLOWS:
Well, no big surprise.
We have proof of poison
but no way to prove
which one of them did it.
I like either one of them
for the murder--
so will a jury.
She-said/she-said defense?
It’s never going to fly.
They’ll raise each other
as a viable suspect
just like they did with us.
That’s what the D.A. said
verbatim.
See you back at CSI.
Wait. What?
So, what,
and just let them move on
to another state,
another husband?
It’s not always up to us.
( distant siren wailing )
Sara...
look...
I know this isn’t
news to you
but sometimes
science isn’t enough.
What are we doing?
Digging up graves,
chasing prints--
if it’s no good in court...
if the killers win...
It isn’t a competition.
We don’t win.
The courts are
like dice.
They have no memory.
What works one week
doesn’t work
the next.
I know that. I do.
I know that.
That’s why I’m mad.
But, see, if you get mad,
then they do win.
You just said...
This is one of your riddles,
isn’t it?
One of life’s riddles...
but, hey...
the good news--
there’s no statute of limitation
on murder.