That one's not ours.
You sure?
I authorize all cadavers
and associated research.
He's not ours.
BRASS:
People donate their
body to science
end up submerged in a pond?
Crammed in a car?
Body farm; creepy.
GRISSOM:
A body farm
is not creepy.
It's a controlled study of
situational decomposition.
All in all,
a very healthy place.
Tell that to slim
hanging from the tree.
Whoever placed our victim here
knew that the body farm existed.
What they didn't know
is each body
is tracked by
a bunch of scientists.
Can't just slip a card
into the deck.
Well, he's not in rigor.
TSD is under six hours.
I'll move him
as soon as
your finished.
Any I.D.?
None.
Okay, I'm going
to move him.
Gunshot wound
to the chest.
WILLOWS:
Well, look.
One of your friends.
It's a carpet beetle.
It shouldn't be here.
Vic seem more like a hardwood
floors kind of guy to you?
Carpet beetles are the last
to arrive at a corpse--
when it's almost a skeleton.
I mean, this guy's still fresh.
David, get this body
out of here now!
We got cross contamination!
♪ Who... are you? ♪&lt;
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
Wow, you got to go
to the body farm?
Yeah.
I've always wanted
to go there.
What was it like?
Quiet.
I hear Grissom
goes there all the time.
Like even on his nights off.
Why does that
not surprise me?
( sighs )
Man, something stinks
in here again.
What, bad milk?
Cottage-cheese bad?
Worse. It's all
over my sandwich.
Smell that.
( sniffs )
( groans )
Yeah.
He's got one of his
experiments in there.
You're kidding me?
Bugs or blood?
Not bugs.
Oh, that's so not cool.
That's a community fridge.
Someone has got to talk
to Grissom about this.
Talk to me about what?
You leaving your
experiments in our
refrigerator.
The lab fridge was full.
I put in last night.
Well...
I'm going to test
for horizontal motion
on bloodstains.
Vis-a-vis surface
textures.
Hey, any of you guys got
any linoleum at home?
STOKES:
That blood
is rank, man.
I know. That's why the
Red Cross gives it to us
'cause it's past
its expiration date.
Anything new on the
body farm victim?
I gave the prints
to Identification.
They're running through
the bases now.
Okay.
( pager beeping )
I'll be in autopsy. Let me know.
Way to go, Nick.
You really told him.
I told him, he just...
doesn't hear it.
BROWN:
Yeah.
Well...
the entry wound tells me
the body sustained a projectile.
A bullet.
Uh, but there's no bullet
fragments in the tissue
and no exit wound.
So, how do you explain that?
Bullet wounds usually
leave bullet evidence.
There's no evidence
of a bullet in this wound tract.
So, let's excise it.
Do a more localized search.
That was my next suggestion.
What's your best tool
for excising the tissue
of our Mr. Doe?
Oh, it's not a John Doe anymore.
Database says
that our victim
is Mike Kimble
age 38.
He has a townhouse
in Summerlin.
Brass is going to meet
us there along
with the rest
of the unit.
My bet says that it's
the primary crime scene.
Good.
Aren't you coming?
We're excising
a wound tract.
Sounds fascinating.
It is.
( loud whirring )
( siren blaring )
Is that Mike Kimble's house?
That's it.
Seems like somebody
beat us here.
You think?
Neighbor called it in.
She smelled the smoke.
Thought he was barbecuing
in his living room.
Where's his neighbor now?
Over there talking to Brass.
Um, no, I didn't hear any noise
coming from Mike's place
last night.
But, um...
I was wearing my headphones,
doing my workout.
Did Mr. Kimble have many
visitors to his house?
Other than his clients,
just, um...
just his fiancee, Jane.
Uh, but they usually
stayed at her place.
Do you have the full name
and address
of the victim's fiancee Jane?
Yes, actually I do.
It's in my kitchen.
As soon as they let me back in
I can get for you.
BRASS:
Good. Yes.
Something...
a metal fragment.
It's not like any bullet
I've ever seen.
Titanium...
maybe a pin.
From the ribs?
Oh, here's
the manufacturer's number.
I should've bought stock
when I first started finding
all these medical implants.
Bovine.
Excuse me?
Genus Hypaderma.
These are normally found
in the intestinal tract of cows.
These maggots aren't
found in humans.
Foreign tissue. Cow.
Makes absolutely no sense.
The body farm also studies
animals, not just humans.
This more of your
cross contamination?
Only one way to find out.
What up, doc?
Oh, there you are.
Sorry I'm late.
D.A. wanted an update
on my robbery case.
Oh, it's all good.
I'm just starting
my walk-through.
The desk is crispy.
There's a burn pattern for you.
Fire burns upward.
This is moving downward.
Defies the laws of physics.
Fire's drawn to fire.
Could have started upstairs.
Check out the upstairs?
The guy who started the fire
wanted to make sure the
bedroom got it worse.
How do you know it's a guy?
Why are you jumping the gun?
Well, according to Sara
94% of all arsonists
are male.
Yeah, that sounds
like Sara.
The fire burned longest here.
It's the point of origin.
I don't smell any accelerant.
Could have burned off.
Fabric would have fueled it.
I don't know.
It doesn't make any sense.
A fire burning downward?
STOKES:
Must have found an accelerant.
Furniture polish.
Warrick...
Is that blood?
Oh, man.
Something bad happened here.
This fire is just a cover up.
GIRL ( giggling ):
Are you serious?
Hold on a second. Hi.
I'm Detective Jim Brass.
Is Jane Bradley in?
She's in the kitchen.
GIRL:
Really? No way.
JANE:
This can't be happening.
Mike is dead?
I don't know how
I'm going to tell my kids.
They love Mike.
You and Mike were engaged?
The wedding was supposed to
be in a week at the Tangiers.
( door opens )
No sweets after 10:00.
What's the rule?
Oh, come on, Mom,
I'm starving.
Have an apple.
( groans )
He's growing
like a weed.
What was your
fiance's business?
He was a photographer.
He did weddings, events.
We argued over who'd
do our wedding because
he didn't trust
anyone else's work.
( door opens and closes )
Hi.
How many times
have I said you have to knock?
You can't just
barge in this house.
Maybe as many times
as I've asked you
to have the kids
ready and out front
on my nights?
You must be the ex-husband.
What's going on?
Are the kids
all right?
Is Jake in some kind of trouble?
No.
Mike Kimble was
killed last night.
Are you serious?
Would you mind
showing us your hands?
My hands? Why?
To see if there's any gun powder
or evidence of a burn on them.
Sure.
Look, uh, I don't want
to be rude, but...
I stop paying alimony the day
Mike and Jane get married.
I mean, I'm the last person
who would have killed him.
If we wanted to get in touch
with you
how would we reach you?
You can reach me
at any of my four
grocery stores.
Any time.
We'll be in touch.
I'm going to get the kids
if that's all right.
They're in the den.
( beeping )
( beeping grows more rapid )
Accelerant.
Hey.
Yeah, Warrick said
the fire was orange
so low-temperature fuel.
Something accessible...
gasoline, kerosene...
I thought you
were at the post.
I was.
So, anyway, this is where
the fire started.
Victim's bedroom.
STOKES:
Grissom...
Gris...
Sometimes it's about
where the fire isn't.
Sometimes I hate this job.
BRASS:
We have evidence
that Mike may
have had
an inappropriate
relationship
with your daughter.
What kind of evidence?
Photographic
and definitive.
That the man
I was going to marry
somehow sexually...
No, I don't believe that.
Things like this
happen
sometimes right
under our noses.
We're going
to have to talk
with your daughter.
Jody, we found pictures
in Mike's house
of you posing.
Tell her Mike would
never do anything
to hurt you.
In some of the pictures...
He truly was like
a father to both kids.
I wish you would
just listen once.
In some of the pictures
you're wearing a bathing suit.
Do you remember
Mike taking them?
Jody...
Anything that he did to you
was not your fault.
You can tell me
if Mike took
those pictures.
Jody?
Honey?
I loved Mike
and he loved me.
The daughter clammed up.
Seems to be in the
protect-the-abuser trap.
I'm going to take her
over to the hospital
for a SART exam.
What are the chances
Mom knew what her
boyfriend was up to?
I've seen it happen.
As a mother,
I hope not.
Yeah, right.
I'm going
to look into it.
Well, our photo guys tell me
those pictures were taken
with Mike Kimble's
type of camera.
Yeah?
Yeah.
What are you
doing here?
A thousand points
of light
and I only need one
to clear up this picture.
The blur equals
the length of the light.
If I can compress this light
back into a point
then the rest of the picture
gets clear.
That's how they got
Hinkley's image
when he was shooting the Prez.
What is that?
There at the bottom
right corner?
is that a finger?
Yeah, I think so.
Well, that's unusual, isn't it?
A professional photographer
gets a finger in the shot?
Maybe his good hand
was otherwise engaged.
I'm going to work
on that for a while
and see if I can get
some ridge detail.
Maybe even a fat print.
I'll... I'll see you later.
( buzzing )
So because you found beef in
the wound tracts of the victim
you think the meat might be
from one of the body farm cows?
Did the fly find
the beef in the wound
and lay its eggs
or did it bring
the beef with him.
SIDLE:
I did an experiment
similar to this in San Francisco
except the cross-contamination
was blood.
Wasn't a murder case,
but it was instructional.
None of these
beef particles
are as big as
the tissue
found in Mike Kimble's
wound tract.
And I found out
the ex-husband
is the proud owner
of a registered handgun.
Hmm, what does
that mean?
It means I need
to see that gun.
Uh, Grissom...
Aren't you going
to tell me anything?
About?
The case, the meat,
what you found...?
I'm working it.
I thought I was
working it with you.
Yes.
You're right,
you are.
So, take some photos
of the experiment for the D.A.
and then get rid
of that stuff.
That meat... the raw meat... me?
Yeah.
How many meals
have we shared together?
I don't know.
Take a guess--
over a year working together.
Thirty.
I'm a vegetarian.
Everyone here knows
I haven't eaten meat
since we stayed up that night
with that dead pig.
It pains me to see ground beef;
forget about cleaning it up.
Okay.
Have Nick do it.
You're telling me
this bastard took
pictures of my daughter?
Yes, we found them
at his house.
I never liked the way
he looked at Jody.
I never liked it.
How did he look at her?
Touchy-feely.
It wasn't normal.
I told Jane when
she started seeing him
he's not a good guy.
He's not good
for our family.
But you can't control
who your ex-wife dates.
Russ Bradley,
Gil Grissom, CSI Lab.
Thanks for coming in.
Is this your gun?
Yes.
May I take a look at it?
Please.
It's been cleaned.
Of course.
You never store
a dirty firearm.
May I ask what kind
of ammunition you use?
A .38 special.
It takes .38s.
Whatever's on sale.
There you are.
Got something
for you from Trace.
Sara?
Almost finished.
They isolated
the accelerant
used in the fire.
It's alcohol based.
Acetone, methyl
methacrylate?
Nail polish remover.
Guess that's
the six percent
no one talks about.
Female fire starters.
What's this... a burn?
Yeah.
DOCTOR:
How'd that happen?
On a curling iron.
I'll give you
a prescription
for antibiotics.
Let's do the last portion
of your exam now, okay?
Excuse me.
Okay, lay back.
Scoot back
a little more.
Just a little more.
Very good.
Take a deep breath.
This won't
hurt at all.
It's melting.
I thought Nick
asked you not to
put experiments
in our communal
refrigerator.
I'm putting it
in the freezer.
The doctor finished
the exam on Jody Bradley.
Physical findings:
scarring,
chronic sexual abuse.
( sighs )
Well, have Brass get a warrant
for the mother's house.
Check the evidence we recovered
from the dead boyfriend's house.
They stayed in both places.
Listen, there's a good chance
the daughter's our arsonist.
She had second-degree burns
on our wrist.
One thing at a time.
Right.
You coming with?
I can't.
Take Nick.
Right.
Experiment.
A warrant?
Uh-huh.
We've got some samples
coming in.
They're priority one.
What is that...
what did you find?
Child Services will
be remanding Jody
to a foster home.
Was my fiance involved
in any way?
He's not your fiance.
Not anymore, anyway.
Jim?
I just got back
from the events office
at the Tangiers
where you and Mike
were supposed
to be married.
You canceled
your wedding
five days ago.
I even have your
credit card receipt
for the ten percent
cancellation charge.
You didn't like the way
he looked at your daughter
any more than
your ex did.
No. I just got cold feet.
Convenient timing.
Look, when Russ and I got
married 20 years ago
you couldn't find
two happier people
and now we can barely
stand to be civil.
I didn't want to make
another mistake.
It wasn't that you sensed
what was going on?
Mike would not do
what he's being accused of.
Believe me.
I'll believe the DNA.
Feels like blackjack, you know?
You guys all fanned around
the table, holding your breath
waiting to see
which card I'll reveal next.
Greg, this is
an abuse case
involving a minor.
Right. Sorry.
So, I have DNA samples
from every male
that lives with Jody Bradley
full-time or weekends.
First, I have Mike Kimble,
the fiance.
Dead fiance.
BRASS:
"Match not found."
You got to be kidding me.
Sorry, Captain.
The guy has naked pictures
of her in his townhouse.
The mother called off
their wedding.
DNA takes a pair.
So, whose is it,
the father?
"Match not found."
SANDERS:
Third and last.
Give me that.
How'd we miss that?
No. No, I never did
anything like that
to my sister, no.
BRASS:
How do you explain
your semen on her nightgown?
I can't... I can't.
The county automatically
provides your son
with an advocate.
We can't proceed
until he arrives.
You getting anywhere
with the print?
I'm still trying
to enhance it.
It's kind of
frustrating,
that, uh
this picture puts us
at the very moment
of the crime
but we can't see
what she's seeing.
They say the eyes are
the window to the soul.
Yeah, my grandma used
to say that all the time.
In a way, it's true.
The aqueous fluid and the
vitreous in the human eye
allows for an image
to be reflected in it.
Well, maybe... if I enhanced
the reflection in her eye
with the right combination
of algorithms...
I think my Popsicles
are ready.
Jake, did you take pictures
of your sister
and plant them
in Mike Kimble's house?
No.
You do have keys
to his house, though. Right?
I mean, your mother told us
that both you kids do.
Yes, but I didn't
plant anything.
He didn't take the pictures.
He didn't plant them.
He has no idea how
his DNA got in his
sister's nightgown.
Well, maybe a little hobbit
put it there.
That's it, we're done.
All right, hold on.
You mind if I talk
to Jake alone?
To what end?
I have a hunch.
Everyone does it, Jake.
You just... feel like
you're the only one.
Then when you don't do it
it happens in your
sleep anyway, right?
Yeah. And then you
go to take a leak
dust off the equipment
and just grab the first
thing that's handy, huh?
It was just... on the hamper.
Your sister's nightgown?
( laughing softly )
The next thing I know,
I'm getting, like...
questioned by the police
and my parents are looking at me
like I'm some sort of...
pervert.
Yeah, that's rough. Rough.
Well, listen, in
the future, dude...
even if the situation's
embarrassing
the truth's probably
the best policy there.
Yeah.
Hey, listen, you
ever notice your
mom's boyfriend
acting weird around
your sister?
Like a little, uh...
too friendly,
too forward?
Mmm, no.
No, I mean, my sister is
the one that's kind of weird.
Really?
Yeah.
How?
She's just always just,
you know, "Mike's coming over.
I can't wait
till Mike gets here."
Mm. Mm-hmm.
You like the guy?
When, uh, my parents
were getting divorced
my mom, she cried,
like, every day
and, uh, Mike showed up
and she stopped crying
so, yeah. I guess.
What are you doing here?
Isn't this your day off?
On the day you plan
to expend a meat bullet?
Frozen?
Yeah, I had to freeze it with
a touch of liquid nitrogen.
Well, I'm ready
to watch history.
Bullet-like
entry wound.
The soft tissue. Hm.
You're quite
a marksman, Russ.
And inventive-- you managed
to build a bullet made of meat.
The meat from the projectile
was visually indistinguishable
from the victim's
stomach tissue.
We know that
your gun was clean
but it turns out
that your re-loader wasn't.
Yeah. We got this from
your garage on a warrant.
We figured a gun enthusiast
like yourself
would have one of these.
Packs gunpowder
into used shell casings.
Cheaper than buying
new rounds, right?
The material that
was on your re-loader
is consistent with
the material we found
in the victim's wound tract.
Ground beef.
A father knows.
He was giving her gifts,
you know, cameras.
He gave her a camera?
And the wedding was,
like, a week off
and he was going
to be living
under the same roof as
my children full-time.
When I went over there
you know, I was just going
to set him straight, right?
You know what he says?
Now, I can't help it
if she likes me.
I guess it's like mother,
like daughter.
You touch my little girl
and I will kill you.
Too late.
That's when I lost it.
Then you dumped him
at the body farm.
Your grocery chain makes
regular meat deliveries there
for experimental purposes.
Then what?
You arsoned his place
to cover up the murder?
GRISSOM:
Grabbed the nail polish remover
from the bedside table
poured it all over the place?
I'll tell you the truth.
I...
I feel relieved.
I'd like to make
a formal confession.
He can confess
to the homicide
but we're still examining
evidence on the arson.
The guy wants to take the heat
for his daughter on the arson
well, where's
the harm in that?
The harm would be
to the justice system
unless I misunderstand
our place in it.
Don't you think that little
girl's been through enough?
What I think and what
the evidence proves
are possibly
two different things.
What is this?
It's, uh, just what it says:
it's a request
for a leave of absence--
six months... year, maybe.
Why?
I was thinking
of checking out
the federal government
system-- FBI...
( laughs )
We have the best lab
in the country.
I need a different
work environment.
What does that mean?
One with, um, communication...
respect.
Everybody here respects you.
You don't.
Is this about
that hamburger thing?
No. Grissom...
this is not about
that hamburger thing.
I-I-I don't believe you.
How can you reduce
everything that I've said
to some kind
of single quirk?
Do you think the problem here
is just about me?
If you don't sign my leave,
I'm going to have to quit.
Hey, Sara?
The lab needs you here.
Great.
Did you hear the dad
copped a plea
on the murder
and the D.A.
expedited it?
Voluntary man,
first offense.
Out on bail.
Free in four.
No jury was going
to convict a father
for killing
his daughter's abuser.
What do you have?
Accelerant. Identical
to the type found
at the arson.
Police got it out
of Jody's gym locker.
( sizzling )
Looks as if Jody
was probably telling the truth.
She did burn herself
on a curling iron.
So who started the fire?
NICK:
Hey.
You get anywhere
with those fingerprints?
Back burner.
I've been working
on this reflection in her eye.
You see
what I'm seeing?
No.
Come on.
I've been working on this
enhancement all night.
Look closer.
What is it?
A clock, a mirror?
It's got a latch,
a lock.
A porthole?
It's a porthole?
Yeah.
These pictures were taken
on a boat.
Miss Bradley.
Yes.
Warrick Brown.
Your fiance Mike,
did he own a boat?
A boat? No.
No?
Did he borrow one
or rent one?
He wanted to borrow
my ex-husband's boat
but he was too proud to ask.
Your ex-husband owned a boat?
He bought one after our divorce.
I've never been on it.
Okay. Thank you.
Jody?
We know that Mike gave
you his camera.
We suspect that your
father used it
to take pictures of
you on his boat.
We believe that
he then placed
the camera back
at Mike's
to implicate him
along with the pictures.
He said I was like my mom
when she was young
and they were happy.
He said having me
was like having his
family back.
Did you ever tell your mom?
I tried.
I don't want to go to Dad's.
You know what the judge said:
Two weeks with Dad,
two with me.
Jody, we have strong forensic
evidence against your father.
But cases like this are
very difficult to prove.
A victim testifying
makes all the difference.
He told me if I ever talked
he'd kill me.
Jody, if you don't talk...
I told Mike
and he was going to fix things.
And my dad killed him...
okay?
( door opens )
BROWN:
Catherine.
What is this?
Found it on the boat.
DNA just ran it.
She's under 14, right?
Yeah, 12.
He didn't take pictures
of his daughter.
He never touched her.
He's a loving, devoted father
who works hard
at his chain of grocery stores
to keep her in good schools.
Except when she's on his boat,
right?
This is your sleeping bag
we took off your boat.
Our lab turned it
inside-out.
The discoloration you see
is a mixture of vaginal
and seminal fluid...
your daughter's and yours.
Okay.
Don't say a word, Russ.
He doesn't have to.
The sleeping bag's talking
loud and clear.
Brad, make me a deal.
I can't.
What do you mean you can't?
You got me four years
for murder.
I can't.
You can get me something.
No, he can't.
In the state of Nevada
we're all bound
by a legal statute.
The sexual assault of a minor
age 14 and under
is a mandatory life sentence
with no possibility for parole.
Excuse me.
Could I talk to you
for a moment?
Why don't you wait
over there, sweetie.
Okay.
I owe you an apology.
I have an eight-year-old
daughter.
It's okay.
You were looking out for mine.
GRISSOM:
Tough case, huh?
Just give me
a straight-ahead
murder any day.
Well, you wouldn't be human
if it didn't affect you.
I heard about you and Sara.
Sara, you know,
she gets very emotional.
Are you in denial?
No, that's... no, no.
Way too analytical.
Wow, you got burned bad, huh?
Welcome to the club.
I got third-degree burns
from my marriage.
Happens to everybody.
Everybody just moves on.
Good.
Let's move on.
But you have
to deal with it.
You have to deal
with it first.
You got to deal with it
before it goes away.
You are the supervisor.
You have responsibilities,
and people are making
a family around you
whether you like it not,
whether you give them
permission or not.
We don't have to go
to the Grand Tetons together.
Just... every now and then
you got to lift your head up
out of that microscope.
Yeah.
( sighs )
( dialing phone )
Yeah, hi. I'd like to get
some flowers for a girl.
No, no. Not flowers.
A plant. A living plant.
She likes vegetation.
Yeah, that'd be fine.
To a Sara Sidle.
Deliver it at
the CSI Division,
Las Vegas Police Department
the one out on North Trop
Boulevard.
Yeah, you can bill me
at the same place.
Gil Grissom.
The sentiment?
Oh, on the card.
Um, uh...
have it say...
have it say, uh...
"From Grissom."
Thank you.