( hip-hop playing )
♪ Hey, baby, hey, baby,
yeah, baby, yeah, baby ♪
♪♪
♪ I'm so tired of playing ♪
♪ Playing with this bow
and arrow ♪
♪ Going to keep my hideaway ♪
♪ Leave it to the other girls
to play ♪
♪ For I've been a temptress
too long ♪
( phone ringing )
Yeah?
Hold the meter.
I'll be right down.
( sirens wailing )
BRASS:
Paige Rycoff, freshman.
Couldn't stand the heat,
dropped out of school.
Dropped out of sight.
Booked a one-way ticket
home to Boulder.
Never got there.
Four days M.I.A.
Missing persons,
first 24 hours are gold
after that...
Quicksand.
Hey.
Excuse me but could everyone
in this room
do me a big favor
and leave?
Please?
Thanks, fellas.
Thanks, guys.
You want me to go, too?
If you're very still,
you can stay.
She was definitely on her way
out of here.
Lamp's still on.
Yeah, but she didn't
take her suitcase
her purse...
or the cab she called.
It's like going to the vet
without your dog.
Maybe she had
a change of plan.
Or someone changed it for her.
No sign of struggle.
Everything's intact.
Nothing out of place.
( knocking )
Come in.
Door locks automatically
and there were no keys
in her purse.
Maybe they were in her pocket.
If they were
in her pocket
she could've walked
right back in.
Why didn't she?
One moment
Paige Rycoff is here
the next, vanished.
People don't vanish, Jim.
It's a molecular impossibility.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
WARRICK:
They got this multiplex system--
there's eyes all over the place.
There's eight floors, and
four cameras per floor.
GRISSOM:
They have this system in place
when you went to school here?
With all the stuff me and my
boys got away with
it's probably
why they have them now.
Hey, scent dogs
are on their way.
If you don't live
in the dorm
you can't get in.
What about getting out?
CATHERINE:
400 students
12 uniform officers,
ten minutes per interview.
P.D. should be
done by Tuesday.
Well, I'll take prints
over people any day.
How about taking video?
There's cameras
on every floor;
one of them
must have seen something,
please find it.
Okay.
In this case, more is less--
the more time goes by
the less chance we have
of finding this girl.
Four days?
We'd be looking
for a body already.
WARRICK:
Well, hide and seek.
Let's go.
I talked to her R.A.
Paige had put in a request
to have all her mail forwarded,
including her security deposit.
Minty.
Toothpaste-- poor man's spackle.
It's an old college
trick-- covers up
the holes
when the posters come down.
Ah.
Leave the room the way you found
it, get back your full deposit.
$500.
That's huge money at her age
if you actually get it.
That's a big college racket,
like buying books back?
Why would anyone want
to sell their books?
Two beds. Roommate?
Jennifer Riggs.
Left school
two weeks into the semester
Brass checked
with the registrar.
Dust void.
Something was here.
Area rug.
Could've been used to conceal
a body on the way out.
ANNOUNCER:
The disappearance
of Western Las Vegas University
Coed Paige Rycoff
has police baffled.
They're working
on several leads.
And though investigators
are still...
How's this strap right here,
is this tight enough?
Uh, yeah, fine.
How about this one?
Yeah, it's...
it's good, Warrick.
Well, you know,
you can get cadets
to do this, Cath.
I mean, they're used
to obstacle courses.
Yeah, well, on missing persons,
we can't wait.
Yeah, well, it looks
like a kill-and-dump to me.
I mean, the guy waited
for the coast to clear
Door to door,
it's only 10 meters...
( bang )
Hmm, snappy little sucker.
Somebody ought to fix that.
Yeah?
Well, all right,
after we find Paige.
Right.
( sighs )
MAN:
Okay, here we're looking
at the fourth floor.
It's real time.
NICK:
Mm-hmm... I'm interested
in any camera that covers
Paige Rycoff's room.
Oh, that's camera two.
Here, I'll put it
on the large monitor.
Now, go back four days,
one hour window
8:00 to 9:00 p.m.
Fast forward.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa--
hold on.
How'd you miss that?
We don't catch
every minute.
Go back 15 seconds,
replay in slow-mo.
What is that?
Camera captures
13% more than we're seeing
on this monitor.
Picture condenses to fit
the aspect ratio...
Pixel matrix, yeah.
Mm-hmm.
Show me the under scan.
Stop.
Now go back
five seconds before
the lens was covered.
Freeze and magnify.
Hmm, somebody's hand.
Looks like he
pushed off the wall
tossed something
on the lens.
Prints over people.
Thanks man.
Yeah.
( grunting )
WARRICK:
Find anything
interesting down there?
Yeah, plenty, but not
what we're looking for.
How's the smell, good?
Funky.
Wait, stop.
Stop, stop, stop.
What you got?
Looks like, uh...
( panting ):
something or...
someone smashed up against
this chute pretty hard.
What floor are you on?
Uh...
Between, um...
first and second, I think.
Well, if the body was dumped
it would've been moving
pretty fast by then.
Pizza. Keep going.
Ah.
Touchdown.
( gasping )
Uh, chute's clear.
Looks like trash
is picked up every morning.
We got nothing.
CATHERINE:
Hey, Warrick, it looks like
we're not the only ones
chasing our tails.
♪ Water falling down
a hundred meters ♪
♪ Colored by the sun ♪
♪ In day-glo colors ♪
♪ Always dragging me around ♪
♪ Through beams of light ♪
♪ Blinded by the sun ♪
( music fades )
How did you know
where to print?
Knew where to look.
How about you?
DNA, blood and semen.
We shoot, we score.
WOMAN:
No one is telling us anything.
It's been four days.
MAN:
I mean, the police
aren't talking to us.
We have no information.
It's gotten crazy.
I want to know how
this could happen.
Mr. Grissom.
What are you doing
to find my daughter?
I'm thinking.
How many men are
on this case?
Have any leads?!
Any?
Are you looking
anywhere else?
When we get any new information,
I'll let you know.
What can we do?
Just let me do my job.
This is our
daughter, we can't
just be observers.
No, we won't.
We're part of this.
Look.
What no one's telling you
is that the only tangible
connection you have left
between you and your daughter
is the evidence
that my team is collecting
and how we interpret it.
So, please...
let me think.
You showered.
Thanks for noticing, Gil,
you're very observant.
GRISSOM:
Yeah? Well...
I can't tell what
I'm observing here.
What does that
look like?
A five-foot-eleven workaholic.
Sorry.
It looks like somebody
carrying... something.
Paige Rycoff
was missing a rug from her room.
Hello.
Got an ID off
my print.
I know who covered
the cameras.
Good.
We know what he might've
carried out.
It's a hand.
It's your hand.
( scoffing )
Okay, if you say so.
Hey, your fingerprints say so.
Okay. I'll cop to it.
But I'm not copping to it alone.
Pledge prank.
You boosted a carpet
and a couch?
We borrowed-- we borrowed
some stuff from the lounge
but we were going
to return it.
When?
After you graduate?
What else did you
take, Henry?
Ohhh...
Two lamps, coffee table
couple rolls
of toilet paper.
Look, I'll pay for it.
Why the fourth floor?
Uh...
The fourth, fifth
and seventh floor
have the primo goods.
Okay?
Fourth floor's closer
to the ground
less stairs.
Faster we can get out of the
building and into the van
faster we get
out of there.
Do you know Paige Rycoff?
Yeah.
Yeah, but I had
nothing to do with...
with that or whatever
happened to her.
But you do know her.
Well, yeah.
You know, we live
in the same dorm.
We're in Economics 101
together, so what?
So what?
Paige and I
dated once or twice.
She wasn't my type.
If you haven't
noticed...
I'm in the system now.
The talent pool's
pretty deep.
She dumped you.
Guy like you, it had to be
a blow to your ego.
Maybe you tried
to change her mind.
All right, come on, listen.
It wasn't like that.
It wasn't like that at all.
Come on, Paige was seeing
another guy.
Someone who was
"more mature" than I am.
You got a name
on this other guy?
No. She never said.
You can go.
But the stuff
gets returned.
Yes, sir.
From hot to cold in a minute.
This is the worst place
you can be
on a missing person...
a dead end.
REPORTER:
The parents
of Western Las Vegas University
freshman, Paige Rycoff.
They join us now to discuss
their daughter's disappearance.
Mrs. Rycoff,
did your daughter tell you why
she was leaving school?
We're a close family,
and Paige just felt
she needed to be
home... with us.
But why leave mid semester?
I asked her...
She was going to make
a fresh start back in Boulder.
I need you in the lab.
You know, when a tree
falls in the forest
even if no one's
there to hear it
it does, in fact,
make a sound.
Yes. Somebody must have
seen or heard something.
What have we got?
SANDERS:
Well, this is one way
to get her DNA.
Bring me her
whole life.
It's called zeal, Greg.
Or overkill.
It's called protocol.
Let's get on with it.
Okay, well, I, uh,
got Paige's DNA from her toothbrush.
I compared it to
the blood and semen
that Sara found
on the mattress
in her dorm room.
Blood's not hers.
Not hers?
That's not all.
Check out the tox screen.
Rohypnol?
Date rape drug.
What about the semen?
Well, the vaginal contribution
to the semen stain
is a match to the blood.
Whose blood,
don't know.
We may have two victims--
one missing, one raped.
STOKES:
There's our boys
about to move
their "borrowed" furniture.
Advance it to 8:27 p.m.
Okay, I think
the table's set.
Cab double-parked.
He calls up.
Paige says that
she'll be right down.
And he becomes
the world's most patient cabbie.
And just like he tells Brass...
he waits 15 minutes.
13 minutes.
27 seconds
according to the timecode.
Close enough.
Let's get back out
in the field.
Tech can finish up here.
Hey, where's
the fire, Bud?
We're just
getting started.
These security cameras
are the only witnesses
we've got.
( sighs )
I'll, uh, settle in.
Good idea.
BRASS:
Jennifer Riggs--
missing girl's
roommate.
She dropped out
of school, too
about a month
and a half ago.
That dorm room is cursed.
Is this
her parents' house?
Yeah.
Possible sexual assault
so I thought I'd wait
for the whole team.
You thought you should,
uh, wait for a female.
WOMAN( over TV ):
A video shot during
the first week of school
offers fresh insight
into the 18-year-old's personality.
We can see that Paige was
an average, apparently happy
and healthy freshman,
looking forward to...
How did you guys
even find out about me?
I mean, I-I didn't report it.
I just... ran.
And I left school.
Nobody knew, not even Paige.
Jennifer, we found
forensic evidence
in your old dorm room.
We believe you were
sexually assaulted
under the influence of Rohypnol.
And now you guys think
the guy that attacked me
had something to do
with Paige's disappearance?
Two women.
Same dorm room.
We're looking for a connection.
Will you tell us his name?
( shaky breathing )
Do you want to talk alone?
You don't understand.
I can't remember.
I never could remember.
That's one of the side effects
of Rohypnol.
I'm sure he was counting
on that.
There was this party...
Who was at this party?
It was a floor party.
That's why
I had to leave school.
Somebody that I was living with
attacked me...
and I was never
going to know who.
SIDLE:
Why would a rapist
voluntarily give up his DNA?
Officially, we're looking
for the individual
who abducted Paige Rycoff
not the student
who raped Jennifer Riggs.
Oh, so as long
as the students
participate voluntarily
we can use their DNA
as we see fit.
Ah, the old
bait and switch.
Yo, smart and legal.
Yeah, but what if
someone refuses?
That's what we're hoping for.
De facto suspect.
Open.
Are you refusing?
I haven't brushed my teeth.
Hey, mouth boy,
she's not going to kiss you.
She just wants your DNA, okay?
( beeps )
Friederich Miescher
requests my presence?
Figured out my code, huh?
Well, you know,
my boy Freddy
discovered DNA.
He's been dead a
hundred years, Greg.
What do you got?
Well, I ran the samples
on Cofiler and Profiler Plus.
Then I compared each specimen
against the types
obtained from the dried semen
that you found
on the victim's mattress...
Are we paying you
by the word?
13 markers.
13 matches.
One suspect.
Thank you.
Kevin Watson,
19, room 407
just down the hall
from our girls.
Athletic director says
he plays first base,
bats right-handed.
Any record?
Three Ds and a "C,"
nothing criminal.
Number 25, just
like McGwire.
Yeah? I wonder
how he hits.
Listen, Kevin,
we know that
you assaulted
Jennifer Riggs.
Why don't you just tell us
about Paige Rycoff.
I don't know anything
about Paige... or Jennifer.
Well, I'll tell
you what I know.
Jennifer Riggs was raped.
We found semen
on her mattress.
We matched the seminal DNA
to you.
Q-tip down my throat.
Thought you were here
trying to find out
what happened to Paige.
We are.
So what did happen,
Kevin?
You attack Paige, too?
Hell, you been
in her room before
but unlike her roommate
Paige fought back,
is that it?
I never touched Paige.
I wasn't even in town.
Three ball games in Fresno.
We got back yesterday.
Check the roster.
Ask Coach.
No, I'll do that
but in the meantime,
you're coming with us.
You're under arrest
for the use
of a controlled substance
in the sexual assault
on Jennifer Riggs.
Get him out of here.
Wait for me.
Wait for me in the car.
Another dead end.
Yeah, I know,
I talked to the coach.
Road trip.
We're losing her.
And there it is again.
STOKES:
You know, that car
circled the block six times
between... 8:20
and 8:40 p.m.
All right,
you loop around twice
you're looking
for a parking space.
Six times...
STOKES:
You're up to no good.
Is that something hanging
from the rearview mirror?
Why don't you zoom in on that.
You know, it's easier to
get a master's degree than
a parking spot on campus.
Right. Why don't you meet up
with University Parking
and cross-reference
all silver Volvos.
Right.
Oh, and Nick?
Yeah?
When you find the car...
I know-- check the trunk.
Silver Volvo. University I.D.
A world of possibilities
reduced to a single car?
Registered to Robert
Woodbury, philosophy
professor, tenured.
Detail's almost
got the latch.
Nick, tow it to CSI
and process.
Cath...
Office hours
with the professor.
MAN:
Yes...
I was near the dorm that night.
Professor Woodbury,
you circled the block six times.
Let's start
with an easy question.
Paige Rycoff was
a student of yours.
Introduction to Philosophy, yes.
Amanda...
uh, I'll talk to you tomorrow
after class.
WILLOWS:
Cute.
Let me guess-- "C" student?
Not if I can help it.
and what kind of student was Paige?
She was a very bright young woman.
"Some circumstantial
evidence is very strong
"as when you find a trout in the milk."
Henry David Thoreau.
But that's just broken pottery.
My perception--
sign of struggle.
Okay, look,
it's been six days.
If you have a legitimate reason
for being outside of her dorm,
tell us.
If you have
an illegitimate reason, tell us that.
Tell us something,
so that we can move forward.
Again, my perception--
silence confirms guilt.
We found you. We will
find what you're hiding.
I'm married.
Yep. The ring indicates that.
BRASS:
Your car's on the way
to the crime lab.
We're going to need
to search your home.
She was never in my car;
she was never in my house.
Where has she been?
Here. That's how the vase broke,
because we were...
Physical.
Amorous.
Oh, so you cared
about her?
But obviously not enough
to come forward.
And tell you what?
That I cheat on my wife
with my student
who is missing
and I have absolutely
no information?
If it was important enough
for you to hide
it's important enough
for us to know.
Any idea where she might be?
No. I...
I went to the dorm.
I-I did. I went to, I don't
know, maybe to stop her
maybe to say good-bye
one last time
but at the very least,
I wanted to see her.
But she never came down.
BRASS:
Let's take a ride in the black-and-white.
Can I meet you there?
I-I'm not going anywhere.
I just need a little time
to explain all this to my wife.
BRASS:
No, I understand.
I'll send an officer with you,
just in case.
Thank you.
Medulla, cuticle and cortex
are a visual match
to the hairs I pulled
from Paige Rycoff's brush.
The roots have skin tags.
Means hairs were ripped out.
Ouch!
Too bad this doesn't get us
any closer to finding Paige.
She was in his car.
It gets us closer
to our suspect.
GRISSOM:
Let me remind you,
you have the right to counsel.
I don't need counsel.
The only person I was
hiding from was my wife.
She knows everything now.
So ask your questions.
We found some of Paige's
hair in your car.
Well, that's impossible
because she's never been in my car.
Are you sure it was hers?
You mean, uh, will it
stand up in court?
Yes, it will.
Well, maybe it was
on my sweater or something.
Four strands of hair
pulled out by the root,
on the passenger's headrest.
How about this one?
A phone call made from your
house to Paige's dorm room
the day she disappeared.
I only use my cell phone
when I call her--
not my office, not my home.
12:16 p.m., four minutes long.
Faculty lunch
that day, 12:00 to 2:00,
every department head.
And it will stand up in court.
Professor Woodbury,
does your wife work?
No.
BRASS:
So, are you home
during the day?
Sometimes.
Were you home
around 12:00
on the day that Paige
Rycoff disappeared?
I don't remember.
Sharon, someone called
Paige from the house,
and it wasn't me.
Mrs. Woodbury
do you have the keys
to your husband's car?
We share it. It's our car.
How long have you known?
About this one
or all the others?
I knew that she
was different.
And I wasn't about to let some
kid walk away with my marriage
so I called her up,
took her for a ride
explained the facts of life
to her-- wife, three kids
mortgage.
She said it was over,
she was going home.
Didn't say why; I didn't ask.
Mrs. Woodbury, I think
you're leaving something out.
They found Paige's hair
in the car
and they think...
Did you attack her?
No.
I wanted to.
I almost did.
She went to get out of the car.
You are 18. What the hell
do you know about love?
I don't need to take this.
Ow!
I stopped her.
Apologized. We talked.
And I dropped her off.
( cell phone rings )
Excuse me.
Yeah.
Grissom.
( inaudible radio transmission)
So, is it her?
I don't know. I just
got here myself.
Some homeless guy
searching for hidden
treasure finds a body.
P.D.'s here on the scene.
We got first looks.
( sighs )
Yeah.
I've seen things
like this before.
When I worked in Arlington,
Virginia, every winter
homeless trying to stay warm
take a nap in a Dumpster
wake up in a garbage
compactor. Mulch.
Warrick and I searched the
trash chute at the dorm.
It was clean. There was no
reason to check the Dumpster.
GRISSOM:
So you're saying
she was killed
by the compactor.
Crushed to death.
No, she was crushed postmortem.
And you know this how?
Tissue in the extremities
was yellow and dry.
Means blood wasn't pumping
through her veins
when she went
through that compactor.
So what did kill her?
Massive internal bleeding.
Her spleen ruptured.
From what?
Blunt-force trauma.
Point of impact?
Rib cage.
Ribs weren't crushed.
They sustained a single blow.
Type of weapon?
I have no idea.
I'm still trying
to straighten her out.
Truth? I may never know.
Now what?
Well, you followed the lead,
it went cold.
Now it's hot again.
I found some blood.
WILLOWS:
Yeah.
Not much, but enough
to work with.
GRISSOM:
Okay.
Photograph it, swab it.
Let's get it
back to the lab.
If it's hers,
maybe that's why
the scent dogs lost their trail.
The odor from the
Dumpster would've...
thrown them off.
I think I got something here.
Check this out.
The whole Dumpster's
beat to hell.
This one spot's fresh.
Nick's right--
the vehicle paint chips
metal flecks
in the color coat.
There's some matching
chips on the ground.
Still, there's no reason
to think there's a connection
between the paint transfer
and Paige.
No reason to think there's not.
STOKES:
Possibly a
hit-and-run?
Means the vehicle had a high
ground clearance. Maybe an SUV?
It would explain
the blunt-force trauma.
Point of impact was her abdomen.
( tires screeching )
( thudding )
Driver tossed her in
the Dumpster to hide his crime.
Or her crime.
Mrs. Woodbury.
She's still a viable suspect.
But with a silver car.
SIDLE:
She could have rented
borrowed from a friend.
Still, why was Paige
even down here?
GRISSOM:
Look, let's stick
to the how--
we'll deal with the why later.
The car that impacted
the Dumpster was
originally white
then painted red,
and now it's black.
There's two coats of primer
between each paint job.
Quality work--
probably a dealership.
Every paint has a unique
light absorption rate.
We I.D. the paint,
we get to the car.
Really?
Cherokee, '89 or '90.
Three paint jobs,
all factory stock.
Stone white, flame red
and there's your
midnight black there.
Well, this narrows
our scope.
Call Brass.
Done.
An hour ago.
Where you been?
I can't be everywhere,
Warrick
and they banned human cloning.
I just left Sanders.
The blood from the Dumpster
matches Paige.
Hey. Brass just called.
He's down at P.D.
Paint to car; car to driver.
Suspect's down there--
he's looking for you.
Expectant father.
My wife's pregnant.
Almost nine months.
She beeped me.
I was trying to get home.
Couldn't believe the traffic.
You always drive
through campus?
We live on the other side
of Fraternity Row.
It's a straight shot
from my office
but I get to the freshman dorm,
nothing's moving.
What time is this?
Around 8:30, I guess.
So you took a shortcut?
Yeah, I thought
I was having a baby
so I gunned it down the alley.
Then what happened?
I veered to avoid
the parked van.
It was wet...
and I swiped the Dumpster.
( tires screeching, thudding)
If I had hit a car,
I would've stopped.
It... it was just a Dumpster.
Paint transfer's green,
just like the Dumpster.
Doesn't mean
he didn't also hit a body.
We have sprayed,
U.V.'d--
no hair, no fibers,
no blood anywhere.
It was a clean strike
against the Dumpster.
( sighs )
Your guy didn't hit Paige.
And we've chased another lead
to a dead end.
We still have
Mrs. Woodbury.
Or her husband.
WARRICK:
Oh, we've got
tons of motives.
Not a stitch of evidence.
GRISSOM:
H.L. Mencken
once said
"There's an easy solution
to every human problem--
neat, plausible... and wrong."
So if the solution
to our problem
is not neat
plausible and wrong
then it could be messy,
unlikely and right.
Right?
A butterfly flaps its wings
in Brazil
we get a hurricane
off the coast of Florida.
Chaos theory.
Here we go.
Random events;
the wholesale rejection
of linear thought.
Physics meets philosophy.
If we apply it
to Paige Rycoff
and our case
at this particular moment
in time
then we can say
life is unpredictable.
No one can predict more than
a few seconds into the future.
I predict I'll still be standing
here one minute from now.
Where are we going
with this?
Paige was in her dorm room
and then ended up
in the Dumpster.
Somewhere between her dorm room
and the Dumpster is our answer.
That's where we're going.
Coming, Nick?
WARRICK:
Nice try,
Nostradamus.
Look out the window.
What do you see?
Traffic. My cab
is waiting for me.
So what do you do next?
Grab my suitcases...
get out of town.
Stop.
Suitcases never left the room.
You didn't take them with.
I've been cleaning all day.
Because you want
your security deposit back.
Yeah, I have to leave the room
exactly like I found it.
So what's missing?
Two box springs,
two mattresses
two desks... two
lamps, two chairs
two dressers.
Trash can?
And it's missing.
What's the last thing you do
after you've done the cleaning?
Take out the trash.
Hi. Could I borrow
your trash can?
Paige dumps the trash,
goes back to her room.
How does she end up
in the Dumpster?
You're thinking too linear.
Chaos theory, remember?
Just dump it.
Okay.
Whoa.
Almost took my hand off.
Maybe you're quicker
than Paige was.
Excuse me.
Could you do
me a favor?
We're doing a
little experiment.
Could you count
to a hundred
and then drop this
can all the way
down the chute?
Thanks.
Watch your fingers.
( clanging )
What the hell is going on?
There was a busted spring
in the chute.
Oh, yeah, I had
to prop that open
when Catherine
rappelled down.
Relevance?
The trash can was missing
from Paige's room.
You're thinking she
accidentally dropped
it down the chute.
Then how did she end
up in the Dumpster?
SIDLE:
She wanted her
security deposit back.
And there's no
easy access here.
Right, so... she
had to improvise.
Excuse me.
Oh. Please.
This actually happened to me
once before, with a set of keys.
Eddie and I had
this huge blowout.
He threw my keys in the trash.
All right, so Paige...
leans over
reaches for the trash can.
But just then,
here comes Mark Doyle.
( thudding )
Let me get this straight.
You're-you're saying a
confluence of unrelated,
unfortunate events
conspired... to
kill my daughter.
Yes.
No, no, no.
Somebody is responsible.
Mrs. Rycoff
there is no one
guilty of this.
Because you say so?
Because the evidence says so.
We'll hire an investigator,
as many as necessary.
Someone killed Paige
and my wife and I
won't rest
until every question
is answered.
We told them what happened.
Yeah, but we didn't give them
what they needed--
some closure.
Truth brings closure.
Not always.