( school bell ringing )
...I'm telling you, man.
See ya, bro.
Later, losers.
♪ I see the riders
coming over the hill ♪
♪ And if you show me
this time I will kill... ♪
( gun clicks )
( gunshots )
Barry Schickel.
Wallet still with
him, with cash.
"A" student.
Recently voted Class Clown.
Strange...
People aren't usually scared
of class clowns.
Who said his shooter was scared?
Shot him in the back.
BRASS:
With his zipper down
and hands otherwise engaged.
Yeah.
We're looking for a coward.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
WILLOWS:
Hey, whoa, whoa, whoa...
What're you doing?
Removing graffiti.
There's been a murder here,
nothing gets cleaned.
It's school policy, Miss.
I have to get the
graffiti down as soon...
Everything is evidence.
Policy of the Las Vegas
Crime Lab.
Should we call the Sheriff?
No.
Thank you.
Bet you were like that
in high school.
Worse.
Ooh... You were the girl
I ran away from.
Yeah, till you caught me.
So you say football
practice was over
at 5:45?
That's right.
And it was okay
for a student like the victim
to return to the school property
to use the restroom?
That wasn't out
of the ordinary?
Hand me a bindle.
The place isn't locked up
till the janitor leaves
end of his shift
8:00-8:30. Until then
the kids at after-school events
use the facilities.
Brass.
Excuse me,
one of my students is dead
are we interrupting you?
Yeah, a little.
That's okay, I'll
drop by your office.
We'll finish this up.
You found the slug.
So the treasure hunt
paid off, huh?
Yeah, it better.
We have a point
of reference.
Well, the nerd squad
is off and running.
I'm going to burn a little shoe leather;
see if the vic had a beef with anyone.
MAN ( over radio ):
Rescue One,
approaching drop site.
We have a visual, Baker One.
Stand by for eastern approach.
CSI, ready for descent.
You're good to go!
Okay, there he is!
Let's get down there.
Ready?
I'll race you.
MAN ( on radio ):
They're sliding through the air.
CSI is on the ground.
Stokes, Sidle
Crime Lab.
Did you open the bag?
Long enough to see
one gnarly looking hand.
Well, skeleton of a hand.
Anyone touch the bag since?
With that smell?
I thought you Emergency Service
guys were tougher than that.
Hey, I'm plenty tough.
Down, boy
it was a joke.
Nothing like
flirting over a D.B.
You want to airlift the body to
the Coroner's?
We'll radio ahead?
Sure.
Wait.
Are you supposed
to do that already?
Body's Coroner's,
property's ours.
MAN ( on radio ):
We have the basket.
Copy that.
Rescue One returning to base.
Hi.
BROWN:
Construction
on Flamingo. Sorry.
GRISSOM:
Give me a hand,
will you?
Yeah.
A .38?
.44.
Here, take this.
WILLOWS:
Brass said the victim had
a can of spray paint, right?
Orange, by my kit.
It was in his backpack.
( sighs )
Did you get something?
Paint from another source.
I'm going
to find out
who belongs to that locker.
Kind of weird
being in a high school, huh?
They do have a timeless quality.
What were you?
A jock or a brain?
I was a ghost.
There.
Shooter was standing
right there.
( gunshot )
( glass breaking )
( gunfire )
And...?
Reconstruction guys
can give us a more precise
angle measurement,
but I'm thinking...
Five-four...
maybe three.
We got ourselves a shorty.
STOKES:
Let's see what metal shows up.
Well, there's no gun
on our dead body.
Wouldn't it be easier
to just unzip the bag
and see what kind of shape
our vic is in?
I like to put that off
till the last possible moment
with decomps.
I see a coin.
Looks like a half dollar.
PHILLIPS:
Silver, whole.
I've done a few of these.
STOKES:
What's that?
There. About
four inches long.
What is that?
PHILLIPS:
It looks like a pin.
It's a medical implant.
Oh, and that's a
plate in the skull.
The head's
been rolled.
I'd say we're dealing
with a male.
Yeah, and by the sound of things
he's been dead about two months.
Sound?
You weren't here when
ESD brought this in.
Well, it wasn't from
lack of trying.
PHILLIPS:
Let's go to
the VIP room.
I'll show you what I mean.
That's Dennis Fram's locker.
And was this a first
or has the deceased
spray-painted his locker before?
Look, I'm the school counselor
I don't know every move
these kids make.
Well, that's obvious
or a young man wouldn't be dead.
Tell me what "stick" means.
Is that a polymer
sensor proboscis?
Cyranose 320.
Company sent it to me,
gratis for a week.
They figure if it helps
CSI will buy one.
Electronic noses
run like ten grand.
Yeah, well,
what if the shooter
chews a certain kind
of tobacco
or has a unique halitosis
and the e-nose picks up on it?
If that thing ran out of here
and bit the shooter in the ass
the county would not approve
a $10,000
purchase order.
I thought it was our job
to speak for the victim
no matter what it took.
And to hell with the budgets.
Our job is to think, Warrick.
Machinery should never matter
more than our mind.
Try this.
Glass tube.
Air pump.
Cost about ten bucks.
Absorption agent?
Fresh out. Improvise.
WILLOWS:
And Miss Barrett says
that a Dennis Fram
had been bullied by
the deceased all year.
He spray-painted his locker
many times
always something to do
with his build.
"Skinny," "shorty"
that kind
of thing.
Dennis is slight
and Barry always
picks on him for it.
Can you arrange for us
to meet with Dennis?
Of course, but he
would never hurt Barry.
He's a good kid.
He's totally nonviolent.
Well, then,
this will be brief.
We can call him
from my office.
GRISSOM:
Cathy, you coming?
Oh, I'll catch
up to you.
Hey...
I need to
talk to you.
I didn't clean anything.
It's not about that.
How tall are you, Dennis?
Five-three and one quarter.
Have you washed your hands
in the last hour?
Yeah. Why?
Changed your shirt?
No.
I'd like to do a test
on your shirt if I may.
What kind of test?
Forensic.
What is that?
GRISSOM:
G.S.R.
When someone fires a weapon
gunshot residue plumes back
onto their hands
and clothing.
This means that you fired a gun
within the last
three to six hours.
Dennis...
The police are going to want
to talk to you.
BRASS:
So, you admit
you fired a gun.
DENNIS:
I was over at the shooting range
on Desert Way.
So the same night
that Barry Schickel was shot and killed
you were out
taking target practice?
I go every Monday night.
You can ask my sister.
She goes with me.
Where's your gun?
I rent different ones there.
Did you ever rent a .44 caliber?
Sometimes.
I'm going to see
my brother!
Get out of the way!
Denny, are you okay?
Got your call.
I'm fine, I'm fine.
We're conducting
a police investigation here.
My dad's back in town tonight
and you'll be sorry
you harassed my little brother.
Questioned.
A student was shot and killed
in this building tonight.
You know what?
Dennis has explained to you
about the gunpowder.
and I am sure
his sister will vouch
for his whereabouts.
And he's a minor.
Jim.
We'll be in touch.
Remember, breathe
through your mouth.
( gasps )
Metal plate.
Silver dollar.
Gambling chip.
( labored breathing )
And...
( coughs )
Aah.
Jacket
government issue, Army.
Ugh.
Pile of bones and that's it.
That's it?
No organs
no-no tonsils, no...
...soup?
Human soup.
Well, we are 73.5%
liquid, eh, Dave?
Add some bacteria,
a couple gases, and... voila!
Okay, I'll take Liquid Man's
jacket, see what I can find.
I'll cremate this.
What if we find
the family or
they find us?
A decomp this bad
can stink up
the entire building forever.
The sooner we dispose of this,
the better.
Not for our investigation.
Sorry.
( gasping )
Let me guess.
Decomp in an enclosed space?
Yeah.
Yeah, in a zip bag.
Lemons.
Lemons?
What?
Use lemons.
Huh. Hmm.
( "Can't Find My Way Home"
playing )
♪ But I can't find my way home ♪
♪ Still, I can't find
my way home ♪
♪ And... come down
off your throne ♪
♪ But I can't
find my way home. ♪
So how's your new
toy working out?
It's been downsized.
Bummer.
I know how you wanted
to see that thing work.
Well, it's the same difference,
really.
Air is drawn
into the glass tube
the chalk absorbs the chemicals
from the air.
And mass spec'll
break it down at the lab.
So why did you need
the expensive one
in the first place?
'Cause it was cool.
I'll see you in homeroom.
All right.
Barry Schickel
from the high school.
Dug three of these .44's
from his back.
First one cracked
his infraspinous fossa.
Second one entered...
past the interior angle
of the scapula
punctured a lung.
And the last one entered
just right
of the right anterior
sarratus muscle
pierced the heart.
The heart?
That makes no sense.
This is a special case.
See the scar?
DR. ROBBINS:
This guy was attacked before.
I'd say in
the last six months.
But not with a knife,
it looks like prongs.
Whatever it was, it
would've killed him.
If his heart
had been there.
Where was his heart?
Barry's upper body?
All his internal organs
are on the opposite side
of typical placement.
Dextrocardia?
Like Dr. No?
That only
presents in, what
.01% of the population?
Which was good for this guy,
until his luck ran out.
How long ago did you
say he was stabbed?
Six months,
hand-to-hand
combat.
Sound like something
your suspect would do?
No.
( sighing )
Hey, how's Liquid Man doing?
You mean Mr. Cartsen?
I found this, it's a...
name tag.
You know, Sara, a lot
of homeless guys
get these Army jackets
cheap at salvage stores.
Well, it's a start.
( gasping )
I'm going to get
Homicide to check
the VA medical database
for a "W. Cartsen"
with plates or pins.
Okay.
( Sarah gasping )
NICK:
Ugh...
What do you got?
I don't know.
I can't read an address
or a phone number...
God, it reeks!
Q.D. should be
able to, uh...
to bring something up...
( Sara vomiting )
Don't tell anyone.
About what?
( exhaling )
( knocking )
Sara?
Hi.
They told me out front
I could find you...
here.
( cheerily ):
Yeah.
Um...
I'll be right out.
Give me a mint.
You're going to need
more than one.
Just give me.
( chuckling )
( gasping )
This is
a nice surprise.
I wanted to see if you'd
like to have dinner.
Yeah.
Um... when?
Now, I'm on break.
Oh, well, I'm in the middle
of that D.B. from the gully.
He's still a John Doe
and we don't know the circumstances.
I smell.
No...
Well, not that bad.
I changed clothes--
the problem is that
it's human fat reduced
and it's attached itself to my
follicles and my pores, so...
You don't look good.
I need to get some air.
Okay.
Uh, no, you-you stay.
Uh, you've got that John Doe
to worry about and, uh...
Well, I can always stop by another time.
Great.
Okay.
Bye...
You smell like death.
I've heard.
You know, a real man
wouldn't mind.
( sighs )
BARRETT:
Have you talked
to Barry's parents?
GRISSOM:
I did; they had no idea
he'd been stabbed.
The older kids get
the less they talk
to their parents.
They talk to you,
though, right?
The guidance
counselor?
Who else may have
had it in
for Barry Schickel?
Look, he was very popular,
but he was a bully.
So there was probably
a dozen kids
who wanted
to see him dead.
Really?
I'd be walking by and...
he would punch me.
( laughter )
Everybody started
calling me "Flinch."
Even the teachers.
BARRY:
MOVE!
He was the meanest guy
I've ever known.
But the way he put you down,
it sounded funny.
If it wasn't you.
He'd wait for me, every day.
Lunch time, fourth period.
Take my food.
BARRY:
Yo, hungry? Ha!
Thanks for the sandwich.
Until I fixed him.
It was about half a year ago,
I went at him.
GRISSOM:
With a fork?
Stabbed him above
his left pectoral.
Yeah.
It still didn't stop him.
I mean, today was the first day
I could come to school
and not feel
like a moving target.
Where were you last
night about 6:00?
( chuckling ):
When Barry was shot?
Boxing practice.
Okay. Thanks.
I can protect them
from being called
a derogatory word for homosexual
or the N-word.
Everything else falls
under free speech.
No one's blaming you.
I am.
You know who did
this, don't you?
You have no idea
what these kids go through.
I listen to them every day.
Divorce, working parents...
Cliques.
And all they need is just one
person to believe in them.
Yeah.
But where does that
leave Barry Schickel?
That's your job.
Shut up. She was not.
I saw her in action.
Really?
Yeah, she was.
Catherine?
I was what?
I was just telling Nick
how you were a big bully
in high school.
A bully?
All right, I guess I was.
But, I mean,
not the kind
that people want to take
a gun out and shoot.
No.
No, no.
You were the kind
that guys fall all over
themselves trying to impress.
Like you, Nick, huh?
Oh, Nick, uh...
what were you in high school?
Me? I was, uh...
I was dependable.
Dependable.
Dependable jock,
dependable stoner?
No, never a strap,
never a smoker.
Just all-around
dependable guy, I guess.
He's trying to say
he was unpopular.
I was popular
with the right people
I can tell you that.
I can also tell you
what I wasn't.
I wasn't a Mac Daddy wannabe
with a Members Only jacket,
putting his swerve
on all the ladies.
What was wrong with those
Members Only jackets?
They were kind of cool
back in the day.
SARA:
Hey, Nick.
Ronnie's got something
on Liquid Man, says it's hot.
Good.
Hey, Sara, what were you
in high school?
Science nerd.
You changed...
( whispering ):
but you still smell.
Let's go.
So that leaves you, Warrick.
What were you?
Oh, I was short, I had
big feet, thick glasses.
You?!
Yeah.
I got pushed around
by all the guys
and never got any play
from the girls.
The girls didn't
even notice your eyes?
No, they used to tease
me about my eyes.
Called me names.
Aw. Well, what do they know?
They're your best feature.
I didn't have a best feature
in high school.
Looking back on it now
I can say I could see
both sides of it
thinking about this
guy Barry Schickel,
and how he was shot
and whichever kid did it.
I'm not saying it was right, but
I kind of understand, you know?
Yeah.
I wanted to hold off
on this matchbook
until it dried out
but then I realized...
Human fat never dries out,
it just gets waxy.
Exactly.
What I'm doing is adding pixels
at some points
and erasing pixels
at other points.
Got it.
"Roma..."
"Roman... nini's..."
Never heard of it.
NICK:
I have.
Nightclub for boomers
off the strip.
Thanks, man.
You bet.
O'RILEY:
Hey, Stokes.
Your "W. Cartsen"?
Yeah?
He's a Second Lieutenant
William Cartsen.
Served in the war,
wounded in action.
Got sent stateside
after they put him
back together.
They put a pin in his spine
and a plate in his head
31 years ago.
Walked out of the hospital,
hasn't been heard of since.
Okay. Come with us.
( beep )
What's the matter,
you don't trust me?
I trust you.
I got a boatload
of chemical components here.
Marijuana, bubble gum, cigars.
It's like every guy's
bathroom in America.
What doesn't belong?
How can I help you people?
Valet guy said
you're the manager.
Detective O'Riley,
Las Vegas P.D.
Stokes and Sidle
from the Crime Lab.
Crime Lab?
What's going on?
This man a patron
of your establishment?
Name's William Cartsen.
Not that I recognize, no.
Are you sure you haven't
seen him around here?
Wore an Army jacket,
might've been down on his luck?
Oh, you mean Moses.
Moses?
Yeah, guy had a beard
down to here, wore a robe
the Army jacket.
Stood out here scaring
every patron I had.
Hey!
The whole world is watching.
Bidi dou!
Guy was ruining my business.
So what'd you do?
I tried to reason
with him.
( Moses yells )
Hey!
Hey, buddy,
you've got to leave
my customers alone, okay?
Here.
Cash that and move on.
That's the last
I saw of him.
When was that?
I don't know,
about two months ago.
SIDLE:
That's funny
we found his body.
Coroner says he's been dead
two months.
We're going to want you
to take a little ride
with us.
Okay.
( computer beeping )
I checked out those kids
you talked to.
None of them was
even near the school
when Barry Schickel
was killed.
The only one who doesn't
check out is Dennis Fram.
WILLOWS:
There's a reason.
I can put him
at the crime scene.
Jim, can you call them
from the car?
Sure, let's go.
Put him there, how?
Well, I'll explain on the way.
No, no.
I'm going to stay here
with this, close to Warrick.
Okay. But you'll miss
all the fireworks.
( distant siren blaring )
I know I must sound
like the typical parent
but my son had nothing
to do with the death
of the Schickel boy.
We've placed him
at the murder.
What?
Here's the fingerprint
that I recovered
from Dennis' locker.
These are Dennis' prints
on file at school--
the Missing Kids
Prevention Drive.
There's a match.
Well, his own fingerprint
on his own locker
that doesn't prove anything.
Proves a timeline.
The alkyd particles
in the victim's spray paint
adhere and dry in 30 seconds.
( spraying noise )
Oxidation.
Dennis had to have swiped
the paint within seconds
of Barry putting it on his
locker for his print to take.
Well, how do you know...?
The janitor.
He keeps timed records
of graffiti.
Job security.
And Dennis left paint
on the door jamb
in the bathroom
where Barry was shot.
BRASS:
That's the timeline
of the murder, Mr. Fram.
We know every move
your son made
up until the gun.
That's why we want
to see your collection.
You're registered as having
two dozen weapons?
KELSEY:
Denny?
Ow...
It's okay, it's okay.
Come on.
We'll fix it.
This... does not belong
in a guy's bathroom.
Can we prove this?
I mean, there's got to be
a thousand different brands
of this stuff out there.
You still got that $10,000
e-nose you were using?
Oh, now you want
my tricked-out toy.
I just want the software.
Come on, drink up.
Here you go.
Good.
Just hold this
to your face, okay?
I'll be right back.
He's got a bleeding ulcer
from being bullied
by Barry Schickel.
( grunts )
Hey, shrimp,
want to go for a ride?
( laughter )
You don't know how
hard it was for him
every morning trying
to work up the courage
just to go to school.
( vomiting )
( coughs )
I thought my little brother
was going to kill himself.
And then someone killed Barry.
Yeah.
How tall are you?
Five-four... with heels.
Why?
No reason.
GRISSOM:
You grabbed a top note
of "floral"
and now we ask the software
to break it into ingredients.
Do you recognize any of these?
That's all from
one perfume?
Some of these perfumes
have, like, 750 ingredients.
( computer beeping )
"Chanteuse."
We can narrow it down
to one brand?
Yeah, the original application
for this program
was perfume companies.
You know,
testing new brands
stealing from the competition.
( phone ringing )
Grissom.
Grissom, we got a suspect.
But it's not who you think.
Let me guess.
Denny Fram's sister?
How did you know?
Vapor molecules.
See if you can get a warrant
for her perfume
and have Brass bring her in.
Her perfume?
Let's get back to my first
question, Miss Fram.
Where were you the night
Barry Schickel was killed?
I told you,
I was out driving around.
So what, your perfume just
wafted into the boys' room
all the way
from Highway 10?
Yes. I wear Chanteuse.
What's that got to
do with anything?
My mom used to wear it,
and... after
her car accident
I started to wear it.
Well, aromas have
fingerprints.
They're like a unique
combination of vapor molecules
that linger in the air,
long after the source has gone.
We isolated a combination
in the restroom
where Barry Schickel was shot.
It matches your perfume.
A high-end woman's perfume.
It's doubtful that any other
girl at the school wears it.
Wait, wait, wait...
She has no reason
to hurt Barry Schickel.
What about revenge
for her little brother?
I can't believe this.
That bastard Schickel
dogged my family
now he's doing it
from the grave.
Come on, Kelsey.
You come near us again
you do it
through my lawyer.
Wears her dead
mother's perfume.
Nice touch.
GRISSOM:
Might be true.
Scent triggers memory
more acutely
than any of the five senses.
Yeah?
Well, I smell a rat
in the Fram family.
So you didn't
hurt him.
You just put him
in your car.
Is that what
you're saying?
Back seat.
Then I drove him out of town.
I left him on the side
of the road, out by Red Rock.
You didn't maybe
zip him up in a bag
because he was
giving you trouble
anything like that?
( laughing )
No.
These...
are the handles
from the bag
that he was found in.
You see these prints here?
Can I see your right hand, sir?
Look, he was drunk.
He was rolling
all over my backseat.
So I put him in a
bag from my trunk.
Once we got out of town,
I just tipped him down the hill.
I figured he'd get out
once he slept it off.
The guy always shows up.
What am I looking at?
Homicide.
Look, I was just doing my job.
Hey...
treating another human being
like garbage is not a job.
It's a choice.
Paperwork. Later.
WILLOWS:
Dennis?
I need to talk to you.
You have to understand
anything my sister did
was to protect me.
You said that you went back
to the high school that night
after target practice.
I forgot a book I needed for homework.
And I knew Barry had been there.
I wasn't looking for him.
I had to go to the bathroom.
( glass breaking )
My dad's freaking out.
My sister won't come
out of her room.
I figure if you can
get the police
to make some kind
of deal for her...
Well, Dennis,
you haven't told us
that you explicitly saw
Kelsey shoot the victim.
She was in a stall. I couldn't see her.
BRASS:
Can I, uh...
Can I talk to you for a minute?
Excuse us.
He copping to anything?
He says that
his sister did it.
I don't think so.
Kelsey was "otherwise
disposed."
She got a parking ticket
the same time
the vic was shot
in an alley
behind a motel
off Fremont Street.
In fact, a lot of cars
got tickets that night.
Who's Jeremy Spencer?
Football coach.
Oh.
At a motel
with the high school coach.
No wonder she wouldn't talk.
Well, I paid "coach" a visit.
The guy's 23, just got engaged.
I mean, he'll testify
to anything
as long
as his fiancée doesn't find out.
He says that Kelsey
gave him a roll in the hay
asked him to intercede
with Barry-the-bully
and get the kid to leave
her little brother alone.
She didn't kill anyone.
So why is he saying she did?
Do you ever smell a fart
and end up
blaming the wrong guy?
Why do you think your
sister shot Barry?
Because.
Because why?
'Cause of the last time
he beat me up.
( retching )
I'll protect you.
I'll fix things
so he never comes
near you again.
She always keeps her word.
She asked Barry's coach
to help you.
That was her protection plan.
She was nowhere
near the high
school that night.
I smelled her perfume.
I saw Barry.
I saw the gun.
And I smelled
my sister's perfume.
( gunshots )
No.
You smelled her brand
of perfume.
But then who was it?
We recovered this from
your townhouse on a warrant.
Chanteuse.
We also
found the gun.
It hasn't been cleaned.
Well, I don't know
how to clean a gun.
That was my husband's.
You know how to shoot one,
though.
Do you know how many kids go
to school and kill
just to get relief
from the bullying?
You talked to them.
Boxing lessons
and target practice.
How long before one of them
came in here
and opened fire
on a hallway full of kids, huh?
I just thought
that one life was better
than 20...
or 30.
Or eleven.
Captain Brass ran a search on you.
Tetrick High School,
Tetrick, Arizona.
Eleven kids
shot a few days
after Columbine.
You were
the Assistant Principal.
I watched them die at my feet.
Just because some sophomore
couldn't take the jokes
about his glasses.
It says that you were left
with Post Traumatic
Stress Disorder.
You might want to mention that
to your lawyer.
I did this for my kids.
You know, Miss Barrett
as difficult
as high school can be for kids
eventually, it's over...
...but too soon
for Barry Schickel.
( school bell rings )
Rest in peace, Lieutenant.
Rest in peace.