Five! Baby, go!
Seven. Whoo!
Changing $100.
Change $100, go ahead.
(boisterous shouting)
Section G-3, all clear.
En route to H-4
then Soft Count.
(all screaming)
Section G-4.
Security Three
intersect at G-5.
Contain! Contain!
GRISSOM:
And the body count?
Five guards,
three civilians wounded.
One dead bad guy.
Armed robbers snatched
the lock boxes
from the two
high-stakes tables
right off the rolling cage.
Cash on wheels.
Busiest time of night.
Three women-- organized
and muscled.
Small time crooks, Jim.
Hey, they got away
with 250 K.
That's a mere pittance
to a Vegas casino.
Cashiers alone are sitting
on a million and change.
Small time or not
these ladies are dangerous.
Dangerous, yes.
Ladies...
no.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
WARRICK:
These guys packed enough
.45 caliber ammo
for a small army.
Security managed
to return a few rounds.
Nine millimeter.
Less than a year ago
security couldn't
even carry guns.
Times have changed.
Yeah.
The same M.O.
as Laughlin.
Last month, Cottage Casino,
men dressed as women
shot the place to hell.
In and out in
under five.
My bet was that that was
the practice run.
And the more
you practice...
MAN:
I don't know what
the hell's going on
with the world.
Everything's crazy.
I risk my life
just coming into work.
Makes you miss
the mob days, huh?
Back then, this never
would've happened.
And if it did, those scumbags,
they'd be dead,
every last one of them
and we would never
know about it.
Mister...
Mr. Duncan--
take a deep breath
and tell us
what happened.
We'd just made
a money transfer
to the rolling cages.
Then, bang--
the chandelier comes
crashing down.
Sounded like an explosion.
So I dropped to my knees--
took cover.
Anything else?
Yeah, I started praying
for the gunfire to stop.
Okay. Thanks a lot.
And check in with triage
before you leave.
Well, that was
helpful.
Actually, it was.
Gives us
a starting point.
The falling chandelier
distracts the guards.
Makes them easy targets.
(gunshots)
The armed robbers load up,
head for the exits...
Quick escape.
Chaos moving
in one direction
the money moving
in the other.
Can you imagine living out here?
It's peaceful.
Peaceful?
The town just lost five percent
of its population.
I thought you said
this was a single homicide.
Yeah, in a population of 20.
SIDLE:
We made it.
State trooper.
Two hours to drive
75 miles.
You guys got lost.
What's the rush?
Crime scene's
not going anywhere.
Yeah, but I am.
Body's behind the counter.
Dustin Bale--
store clerk.
Bullet through
the chest.
The register's empty.
"Officer Spencer..."
did you touch anything?
14 years as a state trooper.
I know how to secure
a crime scene
without contaminating
the evidence.
Sorry.
It's okay.
Look, I cover
97.5 square miles.
I got to book.
Vomit?
Not an expectorate.
Potato.
Blown to smithereens.
A poor man's silencer.
Now, why would an assailant
need a silencer way out here?
Last paying customer--
eight hours ago.
We just got the call.
The place is open 24/seven.
Why'd it take
so long?
SIDLE:
The assailant flipped the sign
on the way out
buying him time to get away.
WILLOWS:
But now without
getting his picture taken first.
It's plastic.
You're joking.
Nine volt attached
to a blinking light.
Real or fake, it didn't work.
MAN:
There was three of them.
They come from around
the corner, guns drawn
I think they came
from over there.
There were two of them.
WOMAN:
I said four.
There were four
of those lunatics.
They were everywhere.
Right.
Write it down.
I got it.
Thank you very much.
Excuse me.
I've interviewed
17 people.
No two accounts
are alike.
A Harvard professor
conducted an experiment.
Asked a bunch of students
to watch a basketball game--
count the number of times
the ball was passed.
Yeah. Groundbreaking.
During the game
a person dressed in
a gorilla suit
ran across the court.
Afterwards, the professor
asked his students
if they noticed
the gorilla.
50% responded,
"What gorilla?"
That's wonderful, Gil.
If I see a gorilla,
I'll arrest it.
The car was sitting
right here.
Did you get
a good look at it?
Make, model?
No. It was beige,
beat up.
Hazards flashing.
People leave their cars here
all the time.
I wait ten minutes
then call for a tow.
Car peel out?
No. The driver gunned it
but I didn't hear a screech.
Smells like burnt wood.
Motor oil?
No. No, transmission fluid.
But it's brown, not red.
Which means?
It's not the right color.
Extraction is
an art, Albert.
I like to think so.
So this is our cross-dresser
in the blue coat?
I.D.'d as Adam Brower.
Shot in the back
with a hollow point--
close range.
Mushroomed upon impact
maximizing trauma.
Caliber?
Forty-five.
The guards were armed
with nine millimeters
and they weren't
hollow point.
so...
he was shot
in the back
by one of his
own partners?
Someone didn't
want to share.
Wow. A fumette.
Did you get that
out of some museum?
Hey, don't
knock it.
It's still the best tool
for lifting prints
off cardboard.
Blow and print.
If you were in a hurry
how would you get back there?
Easy.
Jump the counter.
Exactly what
I'm thinking.
(electrostatic crackling)
Shoe prints.
Lay it out.
Suspect entered...
shoots the clerk
through the potato...
then hops up and over,
leaving behind shoe prints...
grabs the cash...
flips the sign from
"open" to "closed" and exits.
How old is the killer?
What are you thinking?
Shoe size is
five, six tops.
We may be looking
for a minor.
You want to see me?
Yeah.
This is the video surveillance
from the heist.
This camera was trained
on their entrance.
All the disguises
in the world
and they dress like women.
Ski masks are played out.
Red and Blue teamed up together
and took out the guards
in the rolling cage.
Black shot down
that chandelier.
Well, Blue's the decedent
I.D.'d as Adam Brower...
so enlarge Red.
No amount of makeup
in the world
could cover up that chunk
of Adam's apple.
That must be the one
that killed Brower.
.45 in the back at close range.
No honor among thieves.
Photoshop Black.
No stubble...
no Adam's apple.
Dressed
as a woman
among men dressed as women.
Now, see?
That's a disguise.
Fluorescent powders?
Eh, why not?
They're in the kit.
Protocol's black.
Since when do you care
about my choice of powders?
Assistant coroner
is four hours late
and we are stuck out here
until he transports the body.
And I haven't even heard
from Grissom.
I've never tried green.
I should never
have been sent
to this remote scene
in the first place.
I've got seniority.
I deserve--
no, I'veearnedthe
right to pick my cases.
If I start eating,
I will shut up.
Do you have a mirror?
Since when do you care
about your appearance?
I mean at a crime scene.
It's not for me.
Sorry.
We can't touch it.
I'm just getting a better look.
Oh, thank God.
It's about time.
Nice to see you,
too, Catherine.
Well, I smell the body.
Where is he?
Hey, David.
I wasn't touching him.
I know you better than that.
So, uh, what took you
so long?
I made a wrong turn
back at the fork.
You're a surfer now?
Dude, I rip.
We're 300 miles from
the nearest beach.
Surfing's just
a state of mind.
I got your page.
Where's my report?
Oh, relax, bro.
The GC Mass Spec's
working on it.
Should be done, um...
(spectrometer beeps)
now.
Transmission fluid.
Yeah, thanks.
Type F with Dexron.
So...
you should be reading
Car &amp; Driver
instead ofSand
and Surf.
Someone put the wrong type
of fluid
in the car's transmission.
See, Ford automobiles use
a thick, red, Type F
transmission fluid.
General Motors uses
a thinner, yellow fluid
with Dexron.
Now, when Dexron's
put into a Ford
it thins that Type F fluid.
Friction builds, gears grind.
The second gear
is usually the first to go.
Friction causes the engine
to overheat, in turn
cooking the transmission fluid
turning it brown.
Leak on the pavement
is the first clue
you've got a problem.
Congratulations--
you're looking for
a Ford with a leak.
Not just a Ford.
The getaway vehicle
has a stubborn second gear.
Which means
it can't get very far.
My guess is
it's already been dumped.
Before Mr. Brower
dressed up as a woman
and heisted a casino
he was a janitor
at an office park
off Flamingo.
Before that,
he was "out of town."
Fours years,
grand larceny.
Well, the manager's not in?
I got a warrant.
I got a key.
Whoo, tidy little camper,
isn't he?
BROWN:
Yeah.
What are we looking for?
Anything that links
Brower
to his co-conspirators.
Dirty laundry?
I'm thinking trace elements
in the clothes
could tell us where he was
before the heist.
I'm going to take it all
back to the lab.
Okay.
Let's see here...
Well, while you're at it
don't forget his wigs and bras.
Anything on
the shoe print?
Skechers.
Adult size five.
Female.
Well, at least we're
not chasing a kid.
How's the prints
coming?
WOMAN:
You two lifted
82 suspect prints.
43 are partial.
WILLOWS:
We ID'd one
from the "open/closed"
sign.
Great.
Not so great.
State trooper.
You got to be kidding me.
"Officer Moron"
contaminated the scene.
Yep. Well, I'll just
beef him to his captain.
Tough. I like that.
(beeping)
Match.
Print off
the register.
What have you got?
Tammy Felton.
Who's Tammy Felton?
A fugitive and
clinical psychopath
that Grissom and I
put behind bars.
She tried to play me
but I didn't bite.
Her biological parents
posted bail
and then she bailed on them.
Biological parents?
Tammy was kidnapped
as a child.
Raised by her kidnapper.
When she found out
the truth, she killed him.
Hey, finish running the prints.
Tammy uses people.
She wasn't alone.
Grissom!
If you're going to badger me
about your crime scene location,
put it in a memo.
You don't
read memos.
Do you remember
Tammy Felton?
I always remember
the ones that get away.
She's back.
She's been
to Cal Nev Ari.
She's a prime suspect
in our convenience
store homicide.
Grissom...
I need you, ASAP.
Please.
So, Ballistics sent me
a bullet from the casino.
It's a .45, so we know
it came from one
of the "ladies'" guns.
And this is
a special bullet?
No, but there was
a foreign substance
adhered to it.
And the substance
is special?
Not exactly.
Just get to the point, Greg.
Tomato, to-mah-to,
potato...
Wait a second.
There was potato
on the bullet?
SANDERS:
You bet.
Strange, huh?
There was potato
on the bullet
because there
was potato
inside the barrel
of the gun.
This bullet
is frommyinvestigation.
Right.
One of your armed robbers
may have used a potato
as a silencer
prior to the heist.
Tammy Felton?
Maybe.
Three armed robbers.
Adam Brower--
killed at the scene
Tammy Felton...
We're still
one suspect short.
SIDLE:
Cath, got another match
from the convenience store.
The print
on the outside doorknob
belongs to an ex-con,
Darin Hanson.
You know this guy,
too?
WILLOWS:
He ran with
Tammy's "father."
Mostly from the law.
So Tammy kills Dad...
and she and Darin Hanson
run off together.
A regular Bonnie and Clyde.
Just what Vegas needs.
GRISSOM:
Let me see, Bobby.
Yeah.
Projectile on the left,
.45 hollow point
courtesy of Adam
Brower's back.
On the right
a .45 hollow point
extracted from Dustin Bale--
dead clerk
at the convenience store.
Bullets confirm the story
told by the potato.
Same gun. Two crimes. One case.
Three suspects.
Adam Brower, deceased.
Tammy Felton, Darin Hanson,
still at large.
STOKES:
Hey, guys.
I just got a call from Brass.
We got a possible getaway
vehicle off I-93.
What makes you think
it's the right car?
It's beige
abandoned, '77
Mercury Cougar.
Mercury's a division of Ford.
I'll drive.
A trucker called it in.
Well, if that's the getaway car
there would have been a
secondary vehicle parked nearby.
Yeah. Check for treads, Jim?
Yeah.
Shall we?
Let's go.
If you were stashing a car,
where would you hide it?
All these bushes would
provide good cover.
Oh...
check out that dirt
displacement.
Yeah.
Skid mark; one tire.
Where's the other one?
There isn't one.
(engine revving)
Dirt to pavement
then the trail goes cold.
No damage. This car
was barely moving.
It was dumped.
Detail...
pop the trunk.
Thanks.
It's Tammy.
(flies buzzing)
Contusions on the anterior neck.
Streaking erythema
on the lateral aspect
of zone one.
Cartilaginous tracheal rings
are crushed.
Hey, Doc.
Catherine.
(recorder clicks off)
She didn't put up
a fight, did she?
How'd you know?
She was killed by the one
person in life she trusted.
(gagging)
Darin Hanson stared her
in the face
and she never saw it coming.
Put his thumbs
around her air pipe
and pushed.
(choking)
I swabbed her neck.
Affirmative
for epithelials.
I'll run them against
Darin Hanson's DNA.
Parents called.
They're on their way in to I.D.
How did they sound?
Oddly, relieved.
They finally know where she is.
I'm not pulling it.
I found similar dust on Adam
Brower's dirty clothes.
Check it out.
Real-life fairy dust.
Yeah, it turns grown men
into criminals.
What's the composition?
S-I...
O-2. Silica dust.
Each particle's
a hundred times smaller
than a grain of sand.
I thought you guys
were processing the car.
Yeah, um... what do you
know about silica?
It's used to make glass.
It's mined in open pits.
Why?
STOKES:
Silica found both on
Adam Brower's clothing
and the getaway vehicle.
There's an abandoned silica mine
outside Cal Nev Ari.
Whatdon'tyou know?
(sirens blaring)
Come here.
Motorcycle tracks
at the vehicle dump site.
Yeah, that smells nice.
Shouldn't smell at all,
if this place is abandoned.
Get your guns out.
Say hello to Darin Hanson.
Shot with a .45.
Execution style.
STOKES:
Adam, Tammy...
now Darin... all dead.
And we're out of suspects.
GRISSOM:
Three robbers
hold up the casino.
Tammy was in black,
Adam was the one in blue
and that leaves us Darin.
We found Darin
and Tammy's prints
at the convenience store.
Hours before the heist,
the clerk gets murdered.
(gunshot)
Shot with the same gun used
to kill Adam at the casino.
The surveillance video tells us
that Darin was the only one
in position to shoot Adam.
Why did Darin kill Adam?
SIDLE:
Greed.
Fewer slices. Bigger pieces.
Which explains why
he killed Tammy.
(gagging)
(grunting)
That's confirmed?
Epithelials on her neck
are a match to Darin's DNA.
So, Darin thought
he was getting the whole score.
But now he's dead.
So, who killed him,
and where's the money?
And we still don't know why
Darin and Tammy took out
the convenience store clerk.
Why kill a man for
a few hundred bucks
when you're about to steal
a few hundred thousand?
We've got more questions
than answers.
I just got off the phone
with the Laughlin CSI
assigned to last month's
Cottage Casino case.
He told me
the casino's cameras
captured four assailants,
not three.
Maybe Tower Club
surveillance
missed something.
Actually, it didn't.Wedid.
Tower Casino surveillance.
The screen on your left
the camera's trained over where
Tammy, Darin and Adam entered.
The screen on your right is
trained on the gaming tables.
Okay, check it out.
What are we looking for?
What, you missed him?
All right...
I'll play it again...
slower, just for you.
Now, keep your
eye trained
on the pit boss
and the chandelier.
He ducked before
the chandelier fell.
Yeah, before Tammy drew her gun.
Play it again.
(keys clacking)
GRISSOM:
Well done, Warrick.
You found our mole.
Pit boss' name
is Max Duncan.
Started working there
about three weeks ago.
Before that...
Let me guess.
Laughlin, Cottage Casino?
I'll call Brass.
He can make the arrest.
I'll meet him at the station.
Call you with an update.
Max Duncan?
Yeah. What the hell
is going on here?
You going somewhere?
What's it to you?
I'll tell you
how this works:
I'll ask the questions;
you give the answers downtown.
I'm calling my lawyer.
Good idea.
Max... are you clairvoyant?
Excuse me?
WILLOWS:
Surveillance tape
from the Tower Club Casino.
You ducked before there
was a reason to cover.
I saw a gun;
I hit the ground.
BRASS:
Okay, let's try this.
Why were you leaving town?
Trying to beat a murder rap?
I didn't kill anyone.
You forget about Darin Hanson?
Your car
was covered
with gray dust-- silica.
It places you
at the murder scene.
I didn't kill him.
Max...
I went there, but ...
I'm advising you not
to say another word.
No, I want to clear this up.
All right, I went out to the
mine, but I didn't kill Darin.
He was already dead.
All right, look, I...
I'll admit I helped him out.
I... I told him when
and where to hit.
That's why I ducked.
But that's it.
That's a lot.
WILLOWS:
And it still
doesn't explain
why you went to see Darin.
Max, that is enough.
Well, I went
to collect my share...
but the money was gone
Darin was dead,
and I panicked.
But I didn't shoot him.
You can't get me
for murder on this.
When someone is killed during
a commission of a felony
all the conspirators
are liable.
Darin Hanson shot Adam Brower
but you might as well
have pulled the trigger.
Let's make a deal.
Tell me, who else was involved?
Who killed Darin?
Look, Darin was the only one
that I spoke to.
I never even met
the other three.
Then we got no deal.
BRASS:
Officer.
Let's go.
You know what?
I kind of believe him.
Yeah, me, too.
He confirmed a fourth.
Darin plus three.
Just like
Laughlin.
So, the last man standing
killed Darin.
And he's still out there...
flushed with cash
and a .45 caliber.
JOHNSON:
Surveillance stills
from the Laughlin heist.
Four perps; we've identified
three: Darin, Tammy and Adam.
All deceased.
Yeah. All murdered.
JOHNSON:
That leaves one.
I.D. the "Unknown"
good chance we solve both cases:
Laughlin and Vegas.
Except all we got
is a guy in drag.
Well, that's why I'm here.
(typing)
I've divided the photo
into segments
removed the disguise
and rebuilt the original image
based on male
physiological norms.
Now, it's not exact
but you'll have an idea
of what your guy looks like.
That's Dustin Bale.
The clerk from the
convenience store.
Whoa. Hold on.
He was killed hours
before the Tower Club heist.
In on Laughlin, out on Vegas.
So, Darin
took him out first.
They cleared the register just
to make it look like a robbery.
But the pit boss said
it was Darin plus three.
Because he knew there were four
at the Laughlin heist.
Well, maybe he didn't know
that the clerk wasn't there.
He wasn't counting wigs.
He was hiding under
a blackjack table.
And we're back to
who killed Darin Hanson.
Bobby D.
Yeah?
We need your help.
Another round
from the casino heist?
Indirectly, yeah.
Well, tip didn't blossom.
Not a hollow point, so it's
not from Darin Hanson's gun.
No, it's from his head.
All right, 230 grains
gives us a .45 automatic.
What else?
Okay, normally, lands and
grooves are highly delineated
but these are smooth, polished--
which means
that your projectile was fired
from a polygonal barrel.
Be right back.
These are the only types
of .45 automatics
with polygonal barrels.
So, the gun that fired
your bullet
was either a Heckler &amp; Koch USP
or a Glock.
WILLOWS:
Narrow it further.
Well, that's
what I'm doing:
dissecting your bullet.
Hey, Nick.
Mm-hmm.
Count the stripes.
One, two, three
four, five, six.
Six lands and grooves
Mm-hmm.
with a right-hand twist.
Glock's got eight;
Heckler and Koch-- six.
You got your gun.
Let's run ATF.
Pretty unique weapon.
Expensive.
Not exactly what you'd buy
out of the back of a van.
(typing)
(computer beeping)
(clears throat)
Only take a second.
(printer hums)
See? Can I call it?
Only 18 registered in-state.
Ten in Clark County; seven
of them still in circulation.
Any names jumping off the page?
Just one.
It's out of left field.
About 75 miles out.
You're accusing me of murder.
And absconding with a quarter
of a mil, stolen money.
Where did you stash the cash?
I'm a state trooper.
How does a cop hook up
with an ex-con like Darin?
I can answer that.
It's all in a day's work.
(gunshot)
A potato silencer muffles
a bullet but won't silence it.
You went in
your gun drawn.
Take it easy, pal.
You should have
arrested them.
But something happened,
didn't it?
My bet, Tammy made you an offer.
Drop the weapon.
Hey, uh, let's be smart
about this.
You can take us in
or we can cut you in.
They still had pockets full
of cash from the Laughlin job.
They offered you
a finder's fee.
This isn't going to do it.
It'll hold you over...
till tomorrow.
Deal?
(car door shuts)
(engine starts)
What are you doing?
You patrol 97.5 square miles.
Is the Cal Nev Ari Mine a part
of your jurisdiction?
No. I'm east of the mine.
But you've been there
haven't you?
Where is the cash?
Jim, hit the
overhead, will you?
GRISSOM:
Silica is a crystal.
It reflects the light.
Even trace amounts
will show up.
(chuckles)
How about that?
(locker door opens)
(zipper unzips)
More than I'd make
in a lifetime.
Was it worth it?
You wouldn't understand.
WILLOWS:
That's right.
We make the big bucks.
SPENCER:
Look--
I was neverthatguy.
You know, that guy
that wins the jackpots
gets promoted,
catches the breaks?
It was right there.
Yeah, well, you're
still not that guy.
Get him out of here.
$250,000 turned
a career cop bad.
Yeah, well, he had his price.
We all do.