HELICOPTER PILOT ( over radio):
Control, this is Air One.
I'm at the trailer park 402.
There's a large gas main
construction fire.
Warrick, why don't you and I
take the perimeter
and work our way in.
All right.
Greg, you're with us.
I'll start the sketch.
How you doing, Nick?
Above ground, Wilcox.
Would you like
inside or out?
I'll take in.
BRASS:
We got two vics.
We think the girl
is Selena March.
She owns the trailer.
What about the male?
BRASS:
Nothing yet.
NICK:
This is a piece
of the roof
right here--
fiberglass
and particle board.
These things weren't built
to last.
They were built to burn.
This place is totaled.
The bed's collapsed.
My money's on meth lab.
SARA:
You know, Metcalf,
just because somebody lives
in a trailer park,
doesn't mean
they're a meth cook.
You guys are a real pain
in the ass, you know that?
Get used to it, pal.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
I'm just having a little trouble
understanding this
because you all
live so close together.
You mean none of you
saw the explosion?
Uh, I heard it.
Well, good.
When I came out about
five minutes later,
the whole place
was burnin' up.
Where do you live?
Right over there.
Uh-huh.
All right, let me get this
straight--
you heard a blast like that
coming from your neighbor's
and it took you five minutes
to poke your head out
and see what was going on?
I was watching TV.
I'm sure he was drinking.
No, hang around,
hang around.
Hey, hang around.
Did you find a man
in Selena's trailer?
Now why would you
ask that?
Was Selena a hooker?
I'm sure I don't know.
But one thing I do know,
that's not Selena's car.
( cell phone rings )
Yeah?
GRISSOM:
Catherine, we have
a 4-19 off Industrial.
Do you mind handling it?
So you get the team
back together
only to break us
apart again.
What kind of a perverse game
are you playing here, Gil?
!
Same one as usual.
Yeah, I'll cover it.
I'm taking Warrick.
Oh, hey, guys.
Good to see you.
Hey, would you tell Nick
I hope there's
no hard feelings
about that whole,
you know, abduction thing.
He hasn't returned
my calls.
He's been busy.
VARTANN:
Squad car found her about
a half hour ago-- no ID,
but there's a lot
of homeless in this area.
Looks like somebody took
something to her head.
Didn't find a weapon, but
my guys are still looking.
A shopping bag for a shirt,
rubber boots and a G-string.
Homeless stripper?
Well, this is
G-String Row, isn't it?
Why is there a ring
on your ring finger?
Because I'm married.
What?
VARTANN:
Congratulations.
How much
did you pay her?
No, seriously,
good luck with that, man.
I didn't even know
you had a girlfriend.
Oh, yeah,
it's a girl I've been dating
a couple months, Tina.
How long have you been married?
Since yesterday.
Did this, uh,
drive-through wedding
at Circus Circus Way,
you know.
Fun, fun time.
DAVID:
Hey.
Sorry I'm late.
Busy night.
We need a TOD, David.
Rigor's barely set, so not long.
Under four hours.
About as long as
Warrick's been married.
PHILLIPS:
You're married?
Congratulations.
Thanks.
Do you think
she was dumped?
Lividity is consistent
with the position
of the body.
So it's highly unlikely.
All right.
I'll check out
the strip clubs.
I'll go with you.
Well, there doesn't seem to be
any drug-manufacturing supplies,
but plenty
of ignition sources:
a hot plate, fondue pot,
gas stove, candles.
One leaky pipe's all it takes.
Which I haven't found yet.
GRISSOM:
Yeah, but even if you had,
that would only explain
the explosion in here,
not the ruptured
gas main outside.
Think I can help you with that.
I found this gas meter
over by the main.
Trailer blows,
this thing
becomes a missile.
One explosion leads to another.
Yeah, but where
did it all start?
Brass ran the plates on that
Acura near the trailer.
It's registered
to a Robert Durgee.
You get his photo
from the DMV?
Confirmed as the vic--
Henderson address,
mortgage broker.
Wife's name was
on the insurance card.
She coming in?
She wasn't home.
Brass is
tracking her down.
Excuse me,
Mr. Grissom...
An officer brought this in
off a call
from Flora Nevada Nursery.
They thought it might
have something to do
with the Walter Gordon case.
Female's lungs
were filled with soot.
COD is smoke inhalation.
Okay, that means the natural gas
didn't suffocate her.
Explosion probably
knocked her out
before the fire even started.
Yeah, male didn't even
last that long.
His lungs were clean,
but he suffered fatal crushing
injuries to his abdomen.
The pieces of debris
that were on this guy's body
were not heavy.
But the bed he was
lying in collapsed.
Explosion could've done that.
Let's photo-enhance
these bruises.
( clicks, beeps )
Yeah, yeah,
the UV light's definitely
bringing out the bruises
underneath the skin.
That looks like
a tire mark.
Maybe our gas explosion
just turned into a hit-and-run.
( typing )
Well, Robert said that he was
going to be working late.
So I went
to midnight bingo.
Alone?
Excuse me?
I was...
with a friend.
What was your friend's name?
Why?
Why not?
He's married.
Looks like the only person
in this thing who isn't married
is the dead girl in the trailer
with your husband.
You didn't know
he was having an affair?
No, I had no idea.
You have
a '96 blue Ford Ranger.
We're going to need
to take a look at it.
But my truck is in New Mexico.
My brother borrowed it
this morning, he, uh...
A wild guess: you have no idea
how to reach him.
Not until he gets back.
Why do you need to see my truck?
Let me tell you a story.
Once upon a time, you follow
your husband to a trailer park.
You see him slumming
with his little trailer bunny.
You waited for him
to come out...
When she pulls
the body back in,
before she can call for help,
you torch the place.
Kaboom.
The end.
That is the craziest thing
I've ever heard.
( chuckles )
Wouldn't even make my top ten.
So that's when the bereaved
Mrs. Durgee lawyered up.
Broadcast's out
on her truck,
and the warrant's
ready to go.
CURTIS:
I don't care
what he says.
Put him in the tank
and see if he wises up.
Sure as hell can't get
any dumber.
Detective Curtis.
Grissom.
I thought you were supposed
to be arresting people
in Boulder City.
Well, a spot opened up here
and...
I transferred in today.
Surprise.
Well, your mother
would be proud.
My mother made Captain.
You know, I'd just
qualified for my shield
when the sheriff
pulled my papers
and "volunteered" me to CSI.
I think my mom hated that
more than I did.
You won't miss the lab,
will you?
There's some things I'll miss.
I'll see you around.
( beeps )
So, Vartann and I struck out
on G-String Row.
You poor guys.
( laughs ):
Yeah, right.
You know what I mean.
No one recognized
the victim's picture.
Listen, Cath,
about this whole
marriage thing...
Yeah, that.
Yeah, that kind of threw me
for a loop.
Tina, right?
Yeah.
She must be
a very special woman.
I look forward to meeting her.
Yes, she...
The vic's blood-alcohol level
was .16
and COD was blunt-force trauma.
Smashed and then
smashed, huh?
Mm-hmm.
Any luck on the, uh...
victim's prints?
No work card, no record.
But the rubber boots
were standard-issue
Streets and Sanitation.
"E.V."?
Yeah, there's three
S&amp;S workers with those initials.
And it looks like an Eddie
Vonner was on duty last night.
Why would you want
to see my boots?
VARTANN:
You tell us.
Look, I know
it's against the regs
to pick up anything
other than trash,
but, I mean, come on.
She was barefoot;
she was stepping on glass
and crap,
so, yeah, I gave her my boots.
And she practically begged, so,
I gave her a lift.
So, you're just
a good Samaritan.
Oh, come on, it was pretty
obvious she didn't belong there.
Where?
Jefferson and K?
You ever see
the citizens that hang out
in that neighborhood?
When I see them,
they're usually dead.
Well, there you go.
I mean, come on, she...
I could tell, despite the...
well, the get-up, she was hot.
And, I mean, I'm not talking
like garbage truck hot.
I mean, she was like...
like limo hot.
VARTANN:
Listen, did she tell
you her name, or,
uh, how she ended up there,
anything?
She looked kind of embarrassed,
so I didn't push it.
So, I just... I dropped her off
down at, uh,
Western and Industrial.
Never left my route.
Why, did she, uh...?
She say anything about me?
She died a few blocks
from where you dropped her off.
( camera beeping )
If the wife torched the trailer
and caused the explosion,
you would expect
to see small debris
embedded all over
the inside of these walls.
There's nothing here.
( camera beeping )
Hey, hey... Sara.
Check this out.
This is a piece
of the exterior wall
facing the road.
With a tire mark on it?
Yeah.
There is blue paint
on this gas main.
Didn't mean anything
at the time.
Amber has a blue Ford Ranger,
right?
STOKES:
Uh-huh.
What if Amber follows
her husband to trailer,
sees him go inside,
totally freaks out.
Why wait for him to come out?
( engine revving )
( tire screeching )
( glass breaking )
Yeah. Yeah, just come
straight through.
Run him over in bed
with another chick.
SIDLE:
Trailer collapses,
fire breaks out, sweeps through,
and destroys practically
all evidence of a collision.
It's too bad
we don't have her truck.
We could match this
to her tires.
Well, '96 Ford Ranger,
stock paint.
Maybe I can match
the transfer to this.
( garbled radio transmission)
I'm starving.
There's a uni going out
for sandwiches.
Would you like me
to get you something?
No, no, you go ahead.
I'm gonna...
I'm gonna work on this.
( bird screeching )
( garbled radio transmission)
( heavy rock playing )
According to the garbageman,
she ran up from this direction.
Yeah?
Must be
where she got the bag.
Hmm.
Victim wasn't carrying
a cell phone.
She's in the wrong part of town
in her underwear,
scared out of her head.
She's gonna call her man,
her family, someone.
And she didn't
have a quarter,
so she called 911.
I'll print the phones.
I'll dump the call records.
Let's get
the traffic cameras, too.
The, uh, tread mark
on your trailer wall
is consistent with
Michelin 195/70/R14s.
What about
the blue paint scrapings
we found on the gas main?
You got a real thing
for blue paint.
You know that?
But, uh, this
isn't from
a Ford Ranger, or any Ford
for that matter.
It's a GMC paint.
STOKES:
Amber Durgee was cheating
on her husband,
maybe even wanted him dead,
but her truck didn't have
anything to do with it.
Right tires, wrong vehicle.
Mm.
Found something?
Part of a headlamp, maybe.
STOKES:
Well, I found
some blue paint transfer
on that chain-link fence.
As far as tracks go,
this place is a parking lot,
man.
They're everywhere.
Except between the gas main
and the trailer.
So, the trailer wasn'trammed?
I think we're looking
at the, uh, vehicular equivalent
of a through-and-through.
Car comes down the road.
Gas main acts acts
as a ramp.
Flying car.
That's what we're
gonna go with?
Okay.
The partial OEM number
on the headlamp piece
belongs to a
'97 Pontiac Sunfire.
Boy, that was quick.
Well, GMC paint--
tire model wasn't that tough.
I'll put out
another broadcast.
All right.
( camera beeping )
CURTIS:
Your broadcast was
for a blue Pontiac.
Patrol figured this
was worth a look.
How bad does a smell
have to get
before Parking Control
calls Homicide?
SIDLE:
No way this car was
at the trailer park.
Think we've got
a new case.
First citation was issued
five days ago.
Car's probably been here
at least six.
Six days in the summer heat.
( groaning )
GRISSOM:
And a trunk becomes a Crockpot.
Phew!
Looks like a male
and a female.
GRISSOM:
That could be an entry wound
in her skull.
CURTIS:
Well, if she was shot
in there, there might be bullets
and casing.
I say we process the car
in place.
Let's get rolling.
SIDLE:
Area is uncontrolled.
Evidence can be contaminated
or lost.
We need to get this back
to the lab.
Car condom.
( beeping )
( beeps )
WALTER GORDON:
Hi, CSI guy.
You're wondering
why you're here?
Because you followed
the evidence.
Archie? Archie?
Do you have anything
on pay phone dump?
Oh. Yeah.
The 911 call
about five minutes
before your garbageman
picked up the vic.
Then I matched timecodes
with the video
from the traffic cam.
( beeps )
Synched up
the audio.
911. What is your emergency?
BROWN:
Whoa!
Ma'am, just calm down.
That's our girl.
Will you tell me your location?
No. I don't know
where I am, okay?!
I don't know where I am.
I'm just...
Yo, ho, get off my phone...
BROWN:
Someone's getting territorial.
I'll put Vartann on it.
BROWN:
Vic loses her shoes.
Explains the boots.
Let see where she came from.
Rewind it a little bit,
would you?
Yeah.
( tape squealing )
BROWN:
Oh.
Stop. Hold it.
That looks like
an airport shuttle.
There's a logo on this side.
Yeah.
I can enhance that.
( beeping )
ARCHIE:
That's a limo?
This is Vegas.
It's a strip bar on wheels.
MAN:
I don't even pay attention
to the talent.
I just drive down
Industrial Boulevard,
from strip club
to strip club,
picking 'em up.
It's like bus stops.
Before you know it,
we're full,
the bus is on fire...
( dance music playing )
We call it
the "Champagne Ride."
It's nice.
So what do the girls get paid
for this?
The girls, they make
uh...
at least twice as much
as they do in the clubs.
Depending on what else
they ride.
( chuckling ):
Oh...
It's a pretty sweet deal
for the guys.
Hot chicks getting trashed
with no security
and nowhere to go.
And what happens when
the girls want to get off?
Usually, it's the guys
that are getting off.
I found something in there
besides body fluids.
Belongs to the victim,
Brooke Harris.
You dropped that girl off
in a war zone, man.
When the guy paying the tab says
he wants to stop, I just stop.
( music blaring, guys shouting)
Come on...
Stop it!
Back off, jerk!
Stop the bus!
Get her off the bus!
No, I don't want...
Look, strippers
are tough chicks, okay?
I figured she'd find a way home,
one way or another.
Brooke Harris was getting
calls from a gym?
Well, the "Giselle" number
went straight to voice mail.
The voice mail said
to contact her here.
And what's the word
on the husband?
Huh?
The husband.
Yeah... no,
according to his office,
he's away in Laughlin
on business.
We're still trying
to get in touch...
Swing those legs
up and around.
Yeah, like a waterfall...
you got it.
That's it!
So I called Brooke a few times.
So what? She was
one of my students.
You actually teach this?
Strippers have
the best bodies in town.
If you want the body,
this is how you get it.
Trust me,
I've been doing this
since before I had
my driver's license.
Well, workout is one thing.
What is a housewife
from Centennial Park
doing on a stripper bus
with pros?
She wanted it.
Come on...
No, really.
She loved
the attention.
Loved the fantasy.
She wanted to try it for real.
See how she stacked up
against some real talent.
And you let her.
Do I look like her mother?
You were teaching her a lesson.
If I'd wanted to do that,
I would've sent her
to Stripperama,
fed her to the wolves.
And drunk CEOs aren't wolves?
They're worse.
You know that.
That's why you
kept calling her.
So you could hear
all about it, right?
I was just calling
to see how things went.
CATHERINE:
Oh, really?
It's starting to sound
like I need a lawyer.
So I pulled all the ROs
from all the '97 blue Sunfires
in Nevada,
one name and address
just jumped out...
( loudly ):
Randy Swansiger.
Las Vegas Police!
Come on out, Randy.
STOKES:
Michelin tires.
Blue car.
Broken headlamp.
Hey, how's it goin'?
I'm Detective Jim Brass.
Remember me?
Hey, hey, hey, hey...
Whoa, whoa...
What are you guys doing?
BRASS:
You got a couple of DWIs
on your record.
What have you got to say
for yourself, Randy?
I was coming home...
been working late...
( chuckling ):
I guess I fell asleep
at the wheel...
Next thing I know...
crash-boom-bang!
The car still worked, so...
Drain plug's probably
under the carpet.
I think I found it.
Ahh...
Technically,
that makes you a cannibal.
Grissom would be proud.
( coughing )
Grissom would've tasted it
on purpose.
It's working.
♪ ♪
That makes 34 prints.
Jacqui's going
to love me.
You got something?
I think so...
Bullet fragment.
Copper-jacketed.
Rules out a .22.
See, it was worth it.
You better get ready for this
because this is going
to blow you away.
The rust-colored material
you found on the victim's
head wound...
was rust.
Plain old ferric oxide,
found on nearly every iron
object on the planet Earth.
Case breaker?
No?
As they say,
"garbage in, garbage out."
CATHERINE:
Um... the Champagne Ride
picks up strippers
near the clubs,
but not actually at the clubs.
Right. The owners
don't like that bus
coming anywhere near the clubs
because they don't make
any money off them.
Well, look, Brooke Harris wasn't
planning to die that night.
She had to have parked her car
somewhere.
Well, there's a secured
parking lot
not too far from where
the garbageman dropped her off.
So, if she parked
her car here...
why did she go here?
Hey, Catherine...
Yes?
Can we talk?
About this?
Sure.
You know, what happened
to Nick...
it just got me
thinking.
Life is so short, you know?
It's almost...
it's almost shorter
than we want to ever believe.
Live for the day.
Exactly.
So, I, uh...
I've been heading
to ask this young lady
I've been seeing, Tina,
to marry me.
You know that I'm happy for you.
Yeah?
Yeah.
But it also feels like
you're not so happy for me.
Warrick...
You know, the thing
that makes a fantasy great
is the possibility
that it might come true.
And when you lose
that possibility...
it just kind of sucks.
DAWSON:
Okay, Mr. Greg,
your most likely match
is a .44 round
recovered from
a drug-related shoot-out
in Mesquite five days ago.
Case is still open.
That's roughly two days
after the bodies ended up
in the trunk.
Maybe our vics
were the beginning
of a little crime spree.
Thanks.
SOFIA:
I ran the Grand Am's VIN.
Last RO was a tow yard
over by Nellis.
Vehicle's most likely
an impound,
sold under the table to some
scammer who faked his tags.
You're not going to get
far in that direction.
I know.
What about prints?
13 different IDs.
Some off work cards,
some off felonies
ranging from assault,
B&amp;E, cocaine trafficking.
Well, even if I do manage
to track them all down,
there's no guarantee any
of these were involved
with the vics.
Well, they didn't put
themselves in the trunk,
and unless they were shot
right there at the curb,
somebody drove
the car there.
You're the detective.
Go detect.
ROBBINS:
Fully developed
skeletal structure
consistent with an adult male.
The medial end of the clavicle's
almost fused.
Suggests he's about
25 years old.
Lack of prognathism
indicates he's Caucasian.
The female, however,
is prognathic...
and that suggests Negroid.
Unfused epiphysial ends
make her a teenager.
White male,
younger black female...
racially motivated?
SANDERS:
Could be a Son of Sam thing.
Summertime, couple on a date,
making out in the car.
Berkowitz used a .44.
ROBBINS:
Gunshot wounds
are most likely COD for both.
Female shows an entry wound
at the rear
of the skull.
Exit wound took off
most of her face.
Male has no
exit wound,
but the entry wound...
is pretty obvious.
( gunshot )
Bullet never left the skull.
That would explain
the bullet fragments.
What we need
are IDs.
SANDERS:
No missing persons
filed for Caucasian males
between 20 and 30
in the last two weeks,
but there are possibles
for the girl.
Hm.
Two cases still open.
13 seems a little young.
Could be a kidnapping.
The other one's 16.
This is one time it would
be better to stay missing.
I also brought
her toothbrush
and her hairbrush.
This one's
from her doctor.
Other's from
her dentist.
How long is it
going to take you?
That's hard to say.
Mr. James, was Clara by any
chance seeing an older man?
As far as I know,
she wasn't seeing anybody
but it wouldn't surprise me
if she was.
Clara wasn't smart
when it come to people,
talking to any
lowlife chump
who'd give her
the time of day.
The girl never did listen
to a damn word I said.
The older man...
um... could've been someone
she met at school?
Did she have a part-time job?
Gooeybunz, over on El Dorado.
We found a number of half-eaten
Gooeybunz in the car.
You know, Clara wasn't
really that smart
about her diet either,
but she hated those things.
Smell'd get
into her clothes.
By the time she got home, she
practically ready to throw up.
You find out who did this...
you let me know.
Yeah.
According
to Clara James' father,
Clara didn't eat Gooeybunz.
She didn't like them,
which means
it was either
the killer
or the male DB.
So we're looking for...
bite marks?
If we find
a good impression,
maybe we'll get an ID
through dental records.
You got it.
And the student
becomes a master.
I'm not seeing
any bite marks.
Me either.
It's not like they
were bitten at all.
More like torn apart.
Check it out.
They might all be in pieces...
but they're all still here.
No one ever ate
any of them.
Which is kinda weird.
I mean, why buy all of 'em
and not eat 'em?
I found this one
under a passenger seat--
intact, on the floor.
It escaped
the carnage.
That's not frosting.
I always liked the middle part
the best.
BROWN:
When she parks her car,
she's a hot housewife.
A few hours later,
she's just another freak.
It's my Mercedes, okay?
I can prove it. Just
give me the keys.
Show me ten bucks
or you ain't proving squat.
I don't have anywhere to go!
Brooke Harris
probably spent
ten bucks a day
on nonfat lattes.
Right.
She needed money
to get her car back.
Well, I don't see
any ATMs around here.
This is a bad place
to be broke.
Hey, you miss me?
Rusty flakes.
Hey, Michaels, did you put
this crime tape up?
Yes, sir.
Yeah, well,
you missed something.
There's blood on this rebar.
Where'd you find that?
I, uh... I just picked it up
over there...
May I ask you a question?
Do you recognize
this woman?
She's a thief.
She took
some money out of my hat.
Hey! Hey!
Stealing's a crime.
Hey, Michaels.
Think you might be able to
take this man into custody?
Tox confirmed that
the packet in the Gooeybun
contained cocaine,
and one of the prints that
I lifted off the Grand Am
was a felony conviction
for cocaine trafficking--
Joey Zack, drug dealer.
seems he liked to use Gooeybunz
to move his coke.
He's a nice regular
customer at Gooeybunz.
He used to chat up cute Clara
when he was there,
sweet-talks her
into a date,
and they both end up dead
in his bitchin' Grand Am.
Well, whoever did it
must've done it for the drugs.
GCMS on the
melted gloves
from your Grand Am.
A delicious confection
of sugar, gelatin, starches,
citric acid,
mineral oil,
Red 40, Yellow 5, Blue 1
and carnauba wax,
SIDLE:
Candy.
Gummy candy.
I'm partial to Jujubes myself.
Is it something I said?
Probably.
Joey Zack's print
was found on the radio,
which was tuned
to 107 FM.
Now, as far as I know,
there is only one place in town
where you can get gummies,
a generic cheeseburger,
and 107.1 gets anything
other than static.
( static )
Sorry, I don't recognize him.
Most of the time when people
come here, it's dark.
How about this?
You ever seen this car before?
No, all I remember
from the last two weeks
is what's playing 'cause
I've seen it 8,000 times.
Killer Punch. A big
draw for crap cars.
We're gonna need
to talk to your employees.
Oh, come on, please.
Is that really
necessary?
It's a homicide
investigation.
We could just call the
health inspector and...
see how many code violations
he has festering
in that concession stand.
Geez, fine,
knock yourselves out.
Jerry's on tickets...
Maddox runs the projector,
and Darryl's in concessions.
No. No, he quit last week.
Why?
He said he was gonna go live
with his parents up in Mesquite.
CURTIS:
Guy's name is Darryl Blakeny.
Small-time hood with priors
for B&amp;E and possession.
His prints were on the
steering wheel of the Grand Am.
SANDERS:
When he quit his job
at the drive-in,
he was in court-ordered rehab.
We figured Blakeny was one
of Joey Zack's customers.
One night, Blakeny
sees his coke dealer's Grand Am
at the drive-in,
and the fiend snaps.
( cocks gun )
Move, and you're dead!
Shut up!
All right, all right,
all right!
Give me the coke, Joey!
Give me the coke!
Do we know where he killed them?
We don't know where yet.
CURTIS:
Or why.
SIDLE:
Maybe the girl
started freaking out;
maybe Blakeny's just a psycho.
Anyway, uh, Blakeny
tossed the bodies,
and throws them in the trunk
and drives home.
The street where the Grand Am
was found
is a block away
from his last known residence.
SANDERS:
He leaves it there
collecting parking tickets,
skips town,
and uses the same gun
two days later in another
drug-related crime in Mesquite.
The scumbag's still in the wind.
At least he's in the system
with a double homicide.
That's not going to satisfy
Clara James' father.
Can she cook?
Is she a good cook?
Come on, Warrick.
Hey, Grissom.
We're taking Warrick
to the Pepper Mill
to celebrate his marriage
and to condemn
his elopement.
You in?
Did you invite
your wife?
I don't think I'm ready
to subject her to the crew
just yet.
WILLOWS:
I got to beg off, you guys.
Got to take
Lindsay to school.
All right.
Bye.
STOKES:
So?
I got one more thing to do.
All right.
Don't.
WALTER GORDON ( over computer):
So, breathe quick.
Breathe slow.
Put your gun in your mouth
and pull the trigger.
Any way you like,
you're going to die here.
Okay?
OTHER VOICE:
Perfect.
( recording winding
at high speed )
GORDON:
Okay?
OTHER VOICE:
Perfect.
How'd you know it
was going to be there?
If that "okay" had been meant
for Nick,
it wouldn't have been
in the form of a question.
I think maybe Walter Gordon
had an accomplice.
( typing )
Perfect.
Male or female?
It's, um...
hard to say.
The tape was pretty mangled.
Enhancement
and noise cancellation
increase intelligibility,
but it alters
timber and tone.
I don't know
there's any more I can do here.
You know,
Nick recorded a message
on the flip side of the tape.
You think maybe we should...
No.
This is between you and me.