( wind whistling )
( indistinct police
radio transmission )
Guy was on his way
to a landscaping job
in Palm Springs.
Saw a body sticking
out of the sand.
Well, out this far,
it's probably a body dump.
Looks like they starved
her to death first.
Well, Jesus fasted
in the desert.
Yeah, but he had a choice.
No clothes, no shoes,
no hair.
BRASS:
Maybe her dome was shaved
'cause she spent time
in the pen.
No right hand either.
Could have been
disarticulated
by a wild animal.
The only wild animal was
the one who left her out here.
Hey, Grissom.
Conditions are less than ideal.
Is it okay if we just do
a scoop and run?
Yeah, David, shoe prints,
tire treads-- all they are is...
Dust in the wind.
Looks like she was branded.
Emaciated, bald, and numbered.
What does that
remind you of?
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
PHILLIPS:
Branding.
A brand is a kind
of contract.
STOKES:
Tell that to a bull
when he gets stuck on
his rear with a hot iron.
In that case, it signifies
ownership.
To a Maori tribesman,
or a Marine,
it signifies belonging.
Did you get a liver temp?
Couldn't get
an accurate reading.
You want me to pull
vitreous from the eye?
Yeah.
One eye is much more desiccated
than the other.
Could be an infection.
Take samples from both.
The eye is sequestered space.
Changes that happen in the blood
after death,
happen more slowly
in the vitreous.
Could give us more
accurate levels.
Um... Dr. Robbins...
The optic nerve's been severed.
That kind of defeats the purpose
of an eye transplant,
doesn't it?
An eye transplant's
just the cornea;
it's not the whole eye.
David,
check the other eye.
This one's
still connected.
Clip it.
Nick, send both eyes
to DNA.
Yeah.
♪ ♪
Pull up a chair.
It's been a long,
strange trip
for this poor girl.
I found puncture wounds
around her glandular areas,
from large-gauge needles
commonly used
to draw out fluids.
Maybe she was undergoing some
kind of medical treatment.
What's in this?
I'm not sure.
I found it in her teeth.
Could be from her last meal.
Also, another
surprise:
She had a D &amp; C.
Abortion?
Maybe polyps, hyperplasia.
Infection?
And how.
Starvation shrinks
a lot of things,
but not your organs.
They're all abscessed.
Which explains why I couldn't
find the liver.
There's not much left.
What, some kind of flesh-eating
disease?
Necrotizing faciitis.
I've never seen
anything like this.
Typically streptococcus enters
through an open wound
and starts eating
through the skin.
Then uses the blood stream
as a conduit
to reach the internal organs.
In her case, the bacteria
started in her blood stream.
Means her skin is fine.
Maybe the puncture wounds were
used to put something in,
rather than take something out.
So Henry found oxycodone
and chlorpromazine
in both the right
and left eye.
Now, one kills pain
and the other puts
a lid on panic.
Chlorpromazine-- they give
that to mental patients.
Yeah, but this gets
so much weirder.
Because that dried up eyeball--
it actually belongs
to somebody else.
What?
See, the vitreous fluid
from her eyeball showed
that she'd only been
dead for a day;
but the DNA from the other
eyeball, well, it was male,
and it seems to have been
separated from its owner
for about a week.
So, I ran it
through CODIS.
And the eyeball belonged
to a Jack Landers,
who is a convicted
sex offender.
Would sticking your eyeball
in a woman's eye socket
constitute a sex offense?
Well, rape is legally defined
as putting an unwanted foreign
object into a genital opening.
So sexual... no...
But offensive... yeah.
Look, guy got out of jail
six weeks ago.
A weenie wagger
with two eyes.
As a parolee, he has to check
in with me once a month.
Missed our last appointment,
but before I could file
the paperwork,
he showed up here, across
from his halfway house,
thinking he's
Captain Crunch.
They thought he was
piped up on something,
but his urine was clean
and his high
hasn't faded.
Hey, Jack.
Captain Jack to you.
Ahoy, mateys.
Captain Jack,
these people want
to ask you
some questions.
Orphaned at the age
of five.
Stowed away on the
Good Ship Lollipop.
The sea...
is an evil mistress.
Spit me out and fed me
to the beast.
A puppet I am.
STOKES:
Hey, Sara, got your message.
No AFIS hits
on my Jane Doe.
So I put a bulletin out
to surrounding agencies
and the media.
Maybe somebody will
recognize her from the photo.
Where you at right now?
On the train
to Crazyville.
Did you get a peek
under the patch?
No, no. I left that
for the doctor.
Jack, look
this way.
( Jack mumbling )
I need you to sit
still for me.
Where's my patch?
Come on, look this way.
Draw my sword...
make you walk the plank.
Jack, were you in an accident
or a recent fight?
Captain Jack don't do
much recallin'.
Did he have an ocular tumor,
or recent surgery?
I have no idea.
He's a suspect in
a murder investigation.
Do you think
he's crazy, or...?
I think he's been lobotomized.
Jack, I want you
to undress and
put this on for me.
I want to do a CT scan
to confirm,
but in the '30s and '40s
lobotomies were often
done via the eye socket.
Right, right, but lobotomies--
they're not
common practice
today?
Hardly.
Nick...
Take a look
at his arm.
He's not a suspect;
he's a victim.
Jane Doe is number 19.
I know it's tough, but
we're going to need you
to identify
the body.
Fine.
Someone from
the coroner's
office will
get in touch with you.
For reasons I think
we both understand,
I would appreciate
some level of anonymity.
Sure, I'll do my best.
Thank you,
Captain Brass.
Thanks for coming in.
BRASS:
The Jane Doe
is Zoe Kessler.
Her mother saw
her picture on the news
and identified her
as her estranged daughter.
I did a DMV check,
and I have the victim's
last known address.
Good. I'll come with you.
There's something
you should know.
The mother's a friend
of yours.
Who's that?
Lady Heather.
Apartment 106.
Landlord was getting
ready to evict her.
"Freud, Goethe...
Rilke..." in German.
Briefe an einen jungen Dichter.
Nothing sounds good in German.
How did she get from Harvard
to here?
Practice, practice, practice.
How do you know
she was at Harvard?
Lady Heather told me.
She was very proud of her.
Well, it looks as though
she hasn't checked her mail
in ten weeks.
The postmark dates back
to November 12th.
BRASS:
She died yesterday.
Where's she been all this time?
This looks like an appointment.
"Betz, 11-12, 7:00 P.M."
( answering machine voice):
First message:
WOMAN 1:
Hi, this is Audrey
at the Betz Clinic.
We're just calling
to see how you're feeling.
Give us a call.
Second message:
Hi, this is Audrey
at the Betz Clinic.
We didn't hear from you,
and we have some followup
questions about your tests.
Please call us.
Third message:
WOMAN 2:
This is Citibank.
We're trying
to reach Zoe Kessler.
Betz Clinic?
Yeah. I'll check it out.
...at 1-800-555-01...
Heterochromia.
It appears Zoe had one blue eye
and one brown eye.
The pirate had one blue eye.
What happened to her?
We're trying
to find out.
May I touch her?
Go ahead.
This required skill...
and the infliction of pain.
Did you shave her head?
No, she was found like this.
Can you tell
if she's ever given birth?
There was some scarring
on her pelvic bones,
but given the condition
of the body,
it's hard to say for sure.
She always wore her
grandmother's ring
on her right hand.
Did you find it?
Hi.
I'm so sorry
about your loss.
But you need to ask me
some questions.
I'd like to know some things
about your daughter.
When was the last
time you saw her?
She dropped out of school
about a year ago.
I didn't even know
she was in town.
So you weren't in contact
with her?
No.
Can you tell me why?
What difference
does it make now?
Did she have any
medical conditions?
Not that I know of.
Because in November,
she participated
in a medical study
at the Betz Clinic.
Right after that,
she went missing.
Where was she found?
In the desert.
Just out in the middle
of nowhere?
Off Highway 55, near Sparks.
I have to go.
Betz Pharmaceutical.
Can you hold, please?
Thank you. Betz Pharmaceutical.
Can I help you?
He's on the line right now.
May I take a message?
And your phone number?
Here are the files on Zoe
Kessler that you asked for
in the warrant
along with a list
of everyone the was here
on November 12th.
Including the employees?
Yeah. The nighttime staff's
pretty minimal.
I was supervising that night.
What brought Zoe in?
Chronic insomnia.
She came in for an overnight
sleep study
but left early.
Was there a problem?
No. Some people just get
freaked out spending a night
in a strange place.
Happens all the time.
We'll need to see
those testing rooms.
As you can see, we try
to make the facility as normal
as possible.
Put a TV in there,
it wouldn't be half bad.
But that would defeat
the purpose.
We can't have anything
in there that would reveal
the actual time.
How do you monitor
your patients?
Our monitoring process
is twofold.
Electrodes measure EKG
and REM sleep,
and we have a vid cam
in the room
to help insure the
patients actually
stay in bed.
You worried
about hanky-panky?
Sleepwalking.
After the meds
are distributed,
we ask that the patients
assume a sleep-ready position.
Many people assume
they have insomnia
simply because they
don't get in bed.
What is your
screening process?
It's intensive.
There's a written
application,
a personal interview,
physical exam.
We only take people
in the normal range.
You'd be surprised
how many people just want
a pharmaceutical lullaby
these days.
No, I wouldn't.
SANDERS:
This clinic is like
Hotel California:
You can check in
any time you like,
but you might
never leave.
Zoe Kessler and
Captain Jack
were part of the same
sleep study.
How many other people
in the sleep study?
A dozen.
I have called
all of them
on the list.
They're intact,
and none of them
are numbered.
Zoe's car was found
at an impound lot downtown.
It was towed from Betz's
parking lot on November 15th.
Wolfowitz said Zoe
left in the middle
of the night
on the 13th.
With Captain Jack?
I don't know,
but according
to their records,
he also left early.
"Left early" seems
to be a euphemism.
I got the results for the sinew
in the girl's teeth,
and in this case,
the hand that feeds...
was her own.
She chewed off
her own hand?
Yeah. Now, I don't know about
you, but I would rather die
of starvation
than to eat my own hand.
Animals in traps
do it all the time.
You think she was trapped?
Like a rat.
A hand in the desert
is worth two in the bush.
Right now, the hand's
all we have to go on.
Okay, Grissom.
Come on.
What are we doing here?
What are the odds
that this hand is
not being eaten
right now by a coyote?
Hey, look, the condition
she was in,
she couldn't have gotten
very far.
Maybe if we find
the hand,
we find
the torture chamber.
Torture chamber?
All right, everybody
gather around.
Let me have your attention.
We're going to proceed forward
covering the immediate area
bordering the road
to the south,
the rocks to the west and
the dry creek bed to the east.
( flies buzzing )
Oh, you smell decomp?
You think the hand
is in that pile?
Maybe.
Let's get a sample.
Whoo!
( sniffs )
Whew!
The smell's coming from
these plants.
" Amorphophallus Titanum,
Corpse Flower."
Now who's going to have a plant
that smells
like decomposing flesh?
Somebody who's trying
to cover up the real deal.
LVPD!
You smell a warrant?
We can look,
but not touch.
I'm in if you're in.
All right,
here's the real catch-22.
If we open it up,
find something probative,
we can't use it.
But we can't find something
probative...
...unless we got the warrant
to open it.
Yeah.
That's funny,
you don't strike me
as the delayed gratification
type.
I'm not.
Grissom is.
Right.
There are some freaky-looking
plants in here.
Yeah, it's all about
genetic modification.
Well, if this is where they
genetically modify the plants,
there's got to be a house
around here somewhere.
"Jacob Wolfowitz."
Isn't that the same guy
from the Betz Clinic?
Yeah.
( clanging )
Mr. Wolfowitz?
Mr. Wolfowitz,
come out of there now.
We're from
the crime lab.
We need to speak
with you.
We can hear you, sir.
Just open the door.
He's not home.
Are you and Mr. Wolfowitz
acquainted?
No.
Why were you
at his house?
Breaking and entering.
Is that why we found
this etching in your handbag?
You were stealing it?
Yes.
Why?
Multiple reasons.
Which are?
You told me Zoe
was having tests
done at Betz.
I found out
who oversaw the tests--
Mr. Wolfowitz.
He lives close
to where you found Zoe.
If I'm caught stealing,
he may want the police
to investigate.
BRASS:
We know the woman
who broke into your house,
and you don't want
to press charges?
She's clearly disturbed.
She just lost her daughter,
and I was one
of the last people
to see Zoe Kessler alive.
I'm sure she was
just looking for
a connection.
You don't want us
to look around,
see if anything else
was stolen?
I live pretty simply.
I don't have anything
worth taking.
But I appreciate
your concern.
However, if he refuses
to press charges...
I'd have to ask myself what
kind of person would do that.
Someone with something to hide.
Precisely.
GRISSOM:
Why, uh, steal this?
It's one of the earliest
illustrations
of the Romulus and Remus myth.
It's printed from a plate.
Must be worth thousands.
So?
Well, it looks like
a page from a book.
I find that people
who don't respect books
have a general disregard
for keeping things whole.
So you think he stole it?
I think a pencil pusher
in a pharmaceutical lab
couldn't afford it.
BRASS:
How long have you
worked at Betz?
18... 18 years.
18 years. Oh.
But that's a long way
from your home
to your office,
isn't it?
I like the solitude
and, uh, space for my plants.
Did I do something wrong,
Captain?
Even if all this is true,
we still don't know
if he killed your daughter.
Too many coincidences.
You have to stay away from him.
You forfeited the right to give
me advice some time ago.
But thank you.
Ah, I believe this is authentic.
Iron-gall ink
from the 16th century
tends to turn a brownish color.
Especially when it's
been sitting around
for a few centuries.
See how the ink bites
into the parchment of the page.
Is that an acidic compound?
Gall inks are often made
with wine or vinegar.
Recipes were specific
to the manuscript illuminator.
So it is from a manuscript?
The edge appears
fairly pristine.
How could he remove it
from the book so cleanly?
My guess?
Classic spit and string.
Even if this tests positive
for DNA,
I'm gonna need the book
to match it.
Here's Zoe Kessler
at the start of her session.
And here she is
at hour number four.
( beep )
SANDERS:
Well, she doesn't
look freaked out.
Looks like shes's
sleeping like a baby.
Except...
Check it out.
SANDERS:
Okay, so she gets up...
gets out.
Look at the bottom
right hand corner.
( tape rewinding )
( VCR clicks )
See that shadow?
Somebody opened the door.
( VCR clicks )
Well, she didn't just
pop out of bed,
she was woken up by someone.
How much you
want to bet
that's Wolfowitz in the doorway?
( beep )
Here's Jack Landers.
A trip to the bathroom, maybe?
Except he never returned.
Wolfowitz works at the clinic.
He has access to both victims.
One victim was found
less than mile from his house,
which smells
like human decomp.
How do we get to him?
Rambar checked
the rare book collections.
This guy likes to steal
in his own backyard.
UNLV library
is missing plate 62.
It's enough for us
to get a warrant.
( background
police radio chatter )
I left him a couple
of messages at home.
And when I left
for the day,
I just saw him
like this.
I guess I didn't need a warrant.
No signs of trauma or blood.
The seat's wet.
He's wet.
Looks like he's in rigor,
which means he's been dead
for at least six hours.
You mean this guy's
been down here
in the parking lot dead
all that time
and no one noticed?
BRASS:
That's weird.
♪ ♪
( bone saw buzzing )
( bone saw clatters on table)
( grunts )
( rib cage cracks )
( scalpel dings )
I'm not gonna be able
to determine COD
until he's completely
defrosted,
and that could take a while.
How long does it take
to freeze an entire body?
To the core?
Two solid days.
His heart's completely frozen.
Before the Y,
I found bruises
and puncture wounds
all over his body.
Over the glands, too?
Yep. Same as Zoe.
So is this.
Test subject #1.
Gil, I saw him.
Yesterday.
He wasn't frozen.
I mean, maybe
he knew too much,
and someone at Betz sensed that
we were getting to close and...
So what? They dunked him
in liquid nitrogen?
Cryogenically froze him?
Well, I know
what I saw.
You've got to find
some explanation.
I'm on it.
( elevator bell dings )
What are you doing here?
I think I might be able
to help you.
I'm listening.
You would have liked Zoe.
She was a lot like you.
Thoughtful,
pragmatic, patient.
She was studying
psychology.
I appreciate that it would
have been difficult
to have someone like me
as a mother.
But if I stressed anything,
it was empowerment
and independence.
So when she called me
from Boston last year
to tell me that she was pregnant
with her therapist's baby,
I got angry.
Not with her, with him.
He violated an oath.
Not only was he married,
she was a patient.
A junior in college with her
whole life in front of her.
And you didn't want him
to screw it up.
I called the AMA,
filed a complaint.
They revoked his license.
Zoe stopped speaking to me.
Do she have her baby?
Your coroner couldn't confirm.
I assumed you might need
a DNA sample from Mr. Wolfowitz.
How did you get this?
The rage was stronger
than the repulsion.
People have used sex for
much less worthy causes.
When did you...
Last night.
You may not approve, Grissom,
but you can't arrest me
for sleeping with him.
He was consenting.
I am playing
by your rules.
But if I had it my way,
this man would die the
same way, my daughter died.
He's already dead.
What?
He's been dead for two days.
That's not possible.
♪ ♪
The dirt from
outside the barn
tested positive
for human DNA.
And I mean a lot of it,
over a dozen profiles.
And one of them
matched Zoe Kessler.
Her hand.
And although chain of custody
is a bit problematic,
'cause a plastic lunch bag
isn't department issue bindle,
the DNA from the condom,
it matches both the saliva
from the book page
and the dead guy,
Jacob Wolfowitz.
Thanks.
I have a question.
How do you have sex with a guy
who killed your daughter?
Revenge is an act of passion.
So, none of the fingerprints
from the car belong
to Jacob Wolfowitz.
They're all a match
to a John Sneller.
Who?
That's John Sneller.
Looks like Wolfowitz,
only younger.
Which explains how I saw
and how Lady Heather...
did a dead guy.
Identical twins.
I thought that
she killed him, too.
I would've.
I mean, I wouldn't have
slept with him first, but...
Same DNA, different prints.
So all the DNA that we
attributed to Wolfowitz,
could be Sneller's.
Which makes you wonder
who's on the autopsy table.
Sneller joined the army in 1985.
He was stationed at
a field hospital near Berlin
until about a year ago.
( knocking )
At which point, I think
that he came to Vegas,
put his brother on ice,
started impersonating him.
Good morning,
Mr. Wolfowitz.
Good morning.
I mean, I know this theory's
a little out there,
but given the evidence...
it's the only conclusion
that makes any sense.
Occam's razor,
principle of parsimony.
If you hear hoofbeats,
think horses, not zebras.
Given twins...
go with twins.
Everything is code four.
Well, this isn't
a torture chamber,
it's a time capsule.
Wolfowitz inherited this
place from his parents.
Took over the deed
about ten years ago.
Love what he's done
with the place.
I found a blue pill in the car.
Tox came back, didn't match
any known pharmaceutical.
Sampling the company candy.
( creaks )
Shabbat shalom.
Jewish?
( creaking )
Well.
( creaks )
GRISSOM:
It appears he was meticulously
documenting experiments.
This one looks like it
deals with craniometry.
I think he was
measuring skulls
to determine intelligence.
I think this is
a gynecological device
from a hundred years ago.
"Arbeit macht frei."
Work will set you free.
These words hung over
the gates at Auschwitz.
Zoe Kessler would've made
the perfect uberwoman
except for her one brown eye.
So I guess, uh,
what nature couldn't fix,
our Dr. Mengele could,
is that it?
Hey, check out the face
of the clock.
GRISSOM:
No numbers.
( groaning )
( creaks )
I'll call a paramedic.
This one's dead.
Massive blood loss
was the cause of death.
Hey, Catherine.
So Brass has put the
lockdown on the airport,
bus depot
and train station.
But so far, no Sneller.
Well, the other twin
didn't make it.
Well, speaking of twins,
we got a call from
Social Services.
Sneller was
their birth name.
But they were adopted
by a Jewish couple
named Wolfowitz.
That explains the Judaica.
I guess Jacob went nurture
and Leon went nature.
Maybe he went Nazi,
trying to kill the Jewish
half of himself.
"Those who want to live,
let them fight,
"and those who do not
want to fight
"in this world of eternal
struggle,
do not deserve to live."
"The only difference between
my research
"and that of the government
is funding.
"See: Tuskegee
CUS Naval Hospital.
See: pesticide testing
done by U.S. government."
( indistinct police radio
transmission )
Have you guys secured
the entire perimeter?
The house and the barn?
Yes, sir.
All clear.
( groans loudly )
( groans )
Heather!
Stop it!
No.
Let me finish.
You cannot do this!
No! Let go!
Let...!
No!
Please...
( cries )
Stop.
Heather.
( cries ):
Please...
I'm saying stop.