♪ ♪
( car door slams )
Hey! Where's my money?
You wait here!
( indistinct crowd chatter )
WOMAN:
You want to
come with us?
Oh, my God.
Come on.
♪ ♪
( gunshot )
( garbled radio transmission)
Gunshot wound to the neck.
No visible GSR.
Money on the visor.
It wasn't a robbery.
Dirt clods on the floor mat
look undisturbed.
Could be from the last fare.
I don't see any shell casings,
though.
Partition's closed.
Bullet-proof glass.
He was not shot from inside.
( camera shutter clicks )
Well, I got two bullet holes
in the passenger door.
That's a weird side of the car
for a driveby.
Maybe he wasn't shot here.
Maybe he just ended up here.
( talking quietly )
GRISSOM:
Excuse me?
Are you with
the Transit Board?
Yeah.
Do you have the dispatch log?
( garbled radio transmission)
Thanks.
Why's he leaving?
( camera shutter clicking )
Well, that's kind of
what he does.
Is this camera always on?
MAN:
Only on HBO.
It takes stills for ten seconds
when the door opens,
and then for the first
ten seconds of the fare.
We're gonna need
the pictures.
This is Catherine.
It's Gil.
How you doing?
I'm busy.
Checking up on me?
Why would I need to do that?
You tell me.
Look, I know
you tend to get
a little territorial
about your crime scenes,
and I don't want there
to be any tension between us,
so I'm giving you
fair warning.
Fair warning for what?
Hi.
( camera shutter clicking )
ROBBINS:
Julian Harper.
If it weren't
for the cyanosis,
I'd say he was doing
a photo shoot for GQ.
Yeah, I'm sure he wasn't ready
for this photo shoot.
ROBBINS:
Body temp's 95.
( camera shutter clicking )
That would make T.O.D.
approximately 3:00 a.m.
( camera shutter clicking )
BROWN:
Well, there's plenty
of drugs around here.
You think he OD'd?
Yeah, no edema.
Some petechia.
Could be suffocation
or strangulation.
But no ligature marks
or bruising.
However...
...some fibers under the chin.
( camera shutter clicking )
BROWN:
What are you doing?
It's for my scrapbook.
I've got a perfect spot
for him--
a place of honor between Tupac
and Entwhistle.
GRISSOM:
The taxi's last dropoff
was this address.
This guy's got dirt on
his shoes and pants.
There was dirt in the cab.
He's got to be the last fare.
So, somebody killed them both.
And if it's about money,
doesn't look like
this guy has much.
Well, I guess it's relative.
It depends on
who you are.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me
who are you, you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
WILLOWS:
Samay... Samay Thao.
15527 East Charleston Road.
That's a long way from here.
GRISSOM:
I count six shots
in his chest.
There were two in the cab,
one in the cabbie.
If the math is correct,
that's nine.
Suggests semi-automatic,
but I don't see
any shell casings here.
Yeah, there were none
in the taxi, either.
Killer could have
picked them up.
( sighs ):
To shoot a guy six times
in the torso, you either have
to be very close,
or a hell of a shot.
It's okay if I roll him?
Yeah.
( camera shutter clicks )
PHILLIPS:
Well, no through
and throughs.
We should be able to recover
some bullets from the body.
Hang on.
What do you make of that?
PHILLIPS:
Looks like he rubbed up
against something.
There's some paint
flaked off of that railing.
( gunshots )
( garbled radio transmission)
We got blood drops.
Gil.
This looks fresh.
Hey, Brass?
( man shouting in Laotian )
Las Vegas Police!
Put the gun down!
( shouting in Laotian )
Put it down.
( grunts )
( speaking Laotian )
I shoot... burglar!
( garbled radio transmission)
Julian Harper.
Wasn't he supposed
to be like, uh...
the next Brad Pitt
or something?
Yeah. Now he's the next
River Phoenix.
( garbled radio transmission)
CURTIS:
All right, Gerald.
Uh, they call me Blinky.
And what was your relation
to Julian Harper?
Best friends since
kindergarten.
Now I work for him.
What did you do for him?
Pretty much everything.
You know, bought his stuff,
hooked him up.
Drove him to
meetings.
Did you find the body?
I ordered room service.
I wanted to see
if he was hungry.
Boom, there he was.
Did you touch or move the body
in any way?
Uh, no way. No.
I watch those murder shows,
you know?
I know to just keep
my hands to myself,
and, uh, call the cops.
What is with the robe?
Did you pat him down?
He's packing a small,
friendly weapon.
Would you mind standing up
for us, sir?
Nah, bro, I-I-I...
kind of got the angle
of the dangle going.
The boing, boing,
boing.
CURTIS:
Stand up.
I, uh, took
a Prevalis on
the plane over.
I been pitching a tent
for, like, eight hours.
Yeah, I-I think I need
to consult a physician.
It's called a priapism.
Just in case you were wondering.
What else are
you on, man?
Oh, uh, nothing.
I mean, uh,
I smoked a little herb
at the club, but that's it.
What about Julian?
Oh, Jules? Oh, no, he, uh...
he won't even take aspirin.
You know, he's organic.
You know, treats his
body like a temple.
Well, we're gonna need a list
of everyone who was here
worshipping the temple.
Can I sit down?
Yeah.
( water running )
Did someone turn a shower on
or something?
You cleared that room, right?
Hey!
Are you okay?
Hey.
( coughing and retching )
CURTIS:
We need a medic!
( coughing and retching )
And a bag for stomach contents.
His name is Keo Vipraxay.
He barely speaks English.
He's South Asian,
I think.
Anyway, it's all clear.
Thanks, Jim.
Double-aught buck.
Standard shot is nine pellets.
That would account
for all the hits.
So you're saying that
a single shotgun blast,
through a security door,
took out two separate victims
in two separate locations?
Weird, huh?
GRISSOM:
The cab drops Samay Thao
in front of this building.
And the position
of the blood drops give us
a pretty good idea
of where Samay was standing
when he was shot.
He was a little shorter
than me.
Shots were centered
on his chest, about there.
( gunshot )
GRISSOM:
My guess is,
the cab was parked down there
the driver peeled out
when he got shot.
Vertical deflection down to
the cab is roughly 60 degrees.
Standard shot
won't spread that far.
The pellets must have
come through the screen.
( gunshot )
The old billiard ball effect.
The cab driver was
collateral damage.
Okay, but the man
with the shotgun
said he shot
a burglar.
What's here
to steal?
STOKES:
Semen on the bed sheets,
as well as every other
flat surface in here.
BROWN ( chuckles ):
Yeah.
I've got vodka, champagne,
cocaine...
STOKES:
Hey, hey.
Pantyhose.
( chuckles )
( exhales )
I've got some smudges over here.
I've got some footprints.
Looks like someone was standing
right there.
Was this guy just doing it
all over the hotel room?
If those are
his footprints...
where are hers?
Or her feet were up...
in the air.
You tell me-- you just
had your honeymoon.
You want to swab this?
I just don't understand.
I mean, who would want
to kill Julian?
I mean, he'd had
some weird fan mail,
but I don't think
any of those kind of people
would be able
to get in his suite.
Were you in his suite?
The ex-wife isn't exactly
the best person to have around
when you're looking
to get laid.
Was that your
choice or his?
It was mutual.
I'm strictly
his manager now.
So if you weren't
in his suite,
where did you go?
I was taking care of business.
( chuckles ):
Checked the boys in,
made sure the suite
was copasetic,
had a drink at Skin,
and played pai gow until
hotel security came to get me.
So how did you get
to be his manager?
When I was with him,
he was broke.
Then after the divorce,
I still... did his laundry,
paid his bills,
read his scripts.
After a while,
I wanted to get paid.
Now I get ten percent
of everything.
Look...
I need to make some calls.
Julian's parents, the studio...
Can we talk about this later?
Sure. But I need your
prints and your DNA now.
Tox shows low levels
of cocaine,
alcohol and Prevalis.
Rules out overdose.
Really? I guess
he was just
acting about the
clean-living part.
C.O.D.?
Asphyxia.
Asphyxiated how?
I don't know.
No broken hyoid.
That and the absence of ligature
marks or bruises
makes strangulation unlikely.
Did you find any fibers
in his nose or mouth?
Nope.
That doesn't rule
out suffocation.
Killer could
have used something
that didn't
shed fibers.
Or maybe they came from whoever
he was rolling around with
in bed.
Found, uh, lubricant
on his genitals,
probably from a condom,
and minor abrasions
on his penis,
indicative of vigorous,
prolonged activity.
Sex, drugs and movies:
the American dream.
Mm-hmm.
BROWN:
Your stomach contents
contain alcohol
and traces of triazolam.
Try-as-a-what?
It's a sleeping pill,
has you reading
the inside
of your eyelids
for a week.
I didn't take any pills.
We also found cocaine
in your bloodstream.
I guess you didn't
take that, either?
So I did a
couple of lines,
but I didn't
take any pills.
If I was gonna
take a pill,
I would've popped
E or a perc.
CURTIS:
Miss Villa, we found you
in Julian Harper's suite.
Were you ever in his bedroom?
( exhales ):
Who knows?
I don't even know how
I ended up in Blinky's room.
Oh, my...
I swear, if that guy
slipped me something...
Tell us what you do remember.
( exhales )
Um...
Me and my girls
were at Skin, and, uh...
Blinky came over and said he
was partying with Julian Harper.
And he said they had this
pimpy booth, so we went over.
♪ ♪
It didn't turn out
the way I hoped.
And the next thing I know,
Blinky's on top of me.
We could assist you
in reporting a date rape.
Thanks, but no.
It's not an offer, it's our job.
There's this Stuffmagazine
party at Ghost Bar tonight.
I'm not gonna make it harder
for me to get in
because I tattled
on Julian Harper's best friend.
I mean,
if I run into them tonight...
Julian Harper will not be there.
Trust me, he will.
The coroner finished the autopsy
early this morning.
He's dead?
CURTIS:
Yeah.
I was in Julian Harper's
suite when he died?
You're kidding me, right?
And being in his suite
makes you a suspect.
I am?
Yes.
So we're going to need to take
a sample of your DNA.
Oh, man.
I am so getting into that party
tonight for sure.
MAN:
Yeah, I remember that guy.
He's, like, Chinese
or something, real spun out.
He was on meth?
Well, he was
on something.
He was acting
all shady.
Downed a bottle of soda
before he even paid for it.
And that's how you knew
he was on something?
There ain't nothin' out here.
People here act messed up
because they are messed up.
The Metro Transit Board said
that he caught
a Sunstar Taxi
from this address.
I called it for him.
Anything to get that tweaker
out of here.
Any idea how he got here
in the first place?
All I saw him do
was walk through the door.
ROBBINS:
Samay Thao.
I don't even need to open him up
to guess C.O.D.
Ocular inflammation.
Laceration of the sclera.
Hurts like hell
when you get a grain
of sand in your eye.
Imagine this.
Bad night for Laotians.
What other Laotians
are having a bad night?
ROBBINS:
Solo traffic collision
on Mount Charleston.
Came in early
this morning.
Noy Vipraxay.
Vipraxay?
Well, that's a hell
of a coincidence.
Does it mean
something to you?
Yeah, he's got the same
last name as the guy
who shot him.
In fact,
Grissom said that
our vic over there
caught a cab at a gas station
near Mount Charleston.
I'll have auto detail
bring in his car.
Sounds like your double's
becoming a triple.
Unless you got any more
in your drawers?
Hey, Archie.
See if you can
help me out.
There was a smear on
the window at the hotel.
It came back saliva.
So I ran it through
CODIS, got a hit,
felony battery on this
guy, Willie Angel.
Now, he's a Las
Vegas resident,
but he wasn't a registered guest
at the hotel.
He has no affiliation
with Julian's little
entourage whatsoever.
I think I scoped
this guy earlier.
Really?
Yeah.
Do it up.
Yeah, there he is.
Mm-hmm.
( chuckles ):
Looking dapper.
All right.
12:31 a.m.
Gets off
on the high-roller floor.
Hey, 2:45 a.m.
STOKES:
Shopping bags?
There's no mall
on that floor.
He was shopping
at Julian Harper's.
Enough time to shop and kill.
( sighs )
The Palms issued
two card keys--
one to Julian, and one
to his boy Blinky.
But the database shows...
one, two...
three keys were used
to access the suite?
Well, assuming the third card
was Willie's.
You can't just walk up
to the front desk
and pull the "I lost my key"
scam on a VIP suite.
So...
how'd Willie get it?
Hi.
( yawning )
Sorry.
I just started seeing someone.
Had a bit of a late night.
Let me ask you something.
How do you know when it's gone
from just friends to more than?
Well, if you have to ask...
it's just friends.
She is making dinner
for me this weekend.
Are you the only guest?
Do her roommates count?
The splinter from your vic's eye
has four distinct layers.
Polycarbonate plastic,
aluminum, acrylic and dye.
Being an audiophile,
I prefer the sound of vinyl.
It's from a compact disc?
Well, how did it end up
in Samay Thao's eye?
Noy Vipraxay's car.
Easy for you to say.
Find anything?
Take a look at this.
Gravitational pooling
directly under
the steering wheel.
WILLOWS:
The car was found at the bottom
of a steep incline.
So he was leaning over it
when he bled out.
Except he wasn't.
Take a look. These were taken
at the crash site.
If he'd have bled out
in the position he was found,
there'd be blood on the door,
not under
the steering wheel.
So someone moved the body?
There was plenty of mud
at the scene,
and Samay had mud on his pants.
Maybe we can match
soil samples.
Hang on.
Trace came back on the splinter
that was in Samay's eye.
It was a CD fragment.
Samay was in this car.
SIDLE:
Hey, guys.
I got work card hits off prints
from the two dead Laotians
and the shooter.
We already know their IDs.
Well, did you already know
that they all worked together?
So Samay Thao
worked for you?
Yeah, runs
the dryers.
When was the last time
you saw him?
He's been off
a couple days now.
Did you know, uh,
Noy or Keo Vipraxay?
Sure. They work here, too.
They brothers
or cousins, or what?
Brothers.
Keo's older.
I hear they got six more
back in Laos.
They work swing--
they're on at 4:00.
Were they friends
of Samay's?
No! No way.
Keo and Noy are Lao Loum.
They're lowlanders.
Samay's Hmong;
he's in the hills.
They're born to hate each other.
Some tribal crap.
What kind of trouble
are they in?
The kind where
you stop breathing.
Noy's dead--
car accident.
Samay's dead, too--
Keo shot him.
( shouting in Lao )
( continues shouting in Lao )
You speak Lao?
And Thai,
Vietnamese, Tagalog.
I pulled a stint straight
out of high school.
I got Southeast Asia, lucky me.
Yeah, I know how you feel.
Did Keo tell you what happened?
I mean, his English
isn't very good.
No, we're, uh, we're still
waiting on an interpreter.
If you need any help,
you let me know.
Yeah, maybe... maybe
I'll take you up on that.
♪ ♪
( steam hissing )
Willie Angel?
You can't fool the eye
in the sky, Willie.
There's a lot of people
looking for you.
Okay, you got me.
What do you want?
Hey, what are you doing?
Hey, you can't do that.
Oh, this here says we can.
Ho-ho-ho!
Slick Willie.
Look out now.
You collect card keys, Willie?
I won at those places.
Really?
I hang on to them
for good luck.
Well, I bet you're
real lucky with this cheap
magnetic stripe
reader and
palm top, huh?
You know you can get
into most hotel rooms
in the city with this thing?
You take the old card key,
you input the room number,
a little magnetic encoding...
and Bob's your uncle.
STOKES:
You used the card
to open the door.
You get into his suite
and hide.
Julian comes back,
falls asleep.
You rob him blind.
But he wakes up.
So it's kill him
or go back to jail.
Right...?
Who the hell are you?
Stop, okay?
Stop.
( sighs )
I was in his suite.
And, yeah, I'm a thief.
But I didn't kill anybody.
You were in his suite
for over two hours, man.
That's more than enough time
to snag a couple shopping bags.
'Cause that sick, rich freak
wasn't going to sleep.
He was banging some blonde
for, like, two hours.
Talk to her.
We're talking to you.
( sighs )
I don't know what the hell
they were doing,
but when she left,
he wasn't moving.
I thought
he was asleep.
Then I saw the news
this morning.
If it's a killer
you're looking for,
talk to the girl
in the red dress.
We believe that Samay Thao
killed your brother
and tried to make it
look like an accident.
( speaking Lao )
Did you know about it?
( answers in Lao )
( speaking Lao )
( continues
speaking Lao )
He says he thought
Samay was there to rob him.
That's why he shot him.
JOHNSON:
The girl in the red dress
gets off
with Julian's entourage
at 12:57.
Then gets back on at 2:33.
Certainly looks like she's
been through something rough.
She forgot her pantyhose.
STOKES:
Good eyes.
Great legs.
Been a while, Arch?
Can you follow her out?
Yeah.
I just got this footage...
SANDERS:
Hey, I heard you
guys are having
trouble with the
Julian Harper case.
Who'd you hear that from?
Ecklie. He's putting me on it.
Man, you gotta quit
kissing his ass.
( chuckling )
All right,
fellas,
check this out.
Okay, that's Julian's manager.
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Hang on.
( typing )
That's got to be
at least a few Gs.
She a hooker?
I don't know, I think
she could be the killer.
Solicitation murder?
Manager pays to
have her client whacked.
She went
to the shopping arcade.
Wait a minute.
What kind of hired killer
takes their payoff
and goes to the mall?
JOHNSON:
I don't know.
This one put herself
on a mailing list.
Tally Jordan.
There's the phone number.
You call my cell,
I answer, we talk.
And then you guys show up
and arrest me at the pool,
in front of my friends.
Is that fair?
You left Julian Harper's
room at 2:33.
A couple of minutes later,
you're taking money
from his manager.
I'm not a prostitute.
Couple hours later,
Julian's dead.
Okay, this is crazy.
I would never even think
of killing Julian Harper.
I've been a fan of his
since he was doing
cereal commercials.
Oh, so you stalked him?
Is that it?
And then you killed him?
I'm in Vegas
for a speech tournament--
okay, a school-
supervised trip.
Does that mean that my school
is stalking him, too?
Is the club Skin
on your school schedule?
When I found out that Julian
was going to be in Vegas
at the same time
I was, I freaked.
Okay, I wanted a look,
an autograph,
or a picture at most.
And what I got was incredible.
Go for it.
You're the one he wants.
It was like I was
in one of his movies.
Until he kicked me
out of bed and...
and then I get
off the elevator,
and there's his manager
handing me a wad of money.
I tip all the girls
Julian's with.
So you're his pimp?
It keeps them from
running their mouths.
It protects Julian's image.
It's just a part of
managing his career.
I had sex with Julian
because I wanted to.
But you took the money,
and you bought
a purse with it.
I had a conversation with
Julian's lawyer.
And he said you weren't
only his ex-wife,
you were about
to be his ex-manager.
That piss you off?
His lawyers and his agents
don't like me.
They pressured him
to drop me.
But Julian and I are family.
That wasn't going to happen.
Eva said if anyone asked,
Julian was a gentleman.
Later he took me out and got me
a Katherine Baumann purse.
It's a much better story to tell
my friends.
GRISSOM:
Samay and Noy go for a drive
after work.
They stop at Mount Charleston.
( speaking Lao )
Samay kills Noy...
( grunting and groaning )
...and makes it look
like an accident.
And then he goes
to Keo's apartment
and Keo shoots him,
claiming self defense.
I don't buy it.
Keo shot him from
the other side of
a locked door.
He was waiting to blow
the guy away.
Which indicates that Keo
knew Samay was coming.
Maybe he hired Samay
to kill his brother,
and then he decided
to cut him out of the deal.
Noy had a life
insurance policy
issued through his union,
worth ten grand.
Life's getting cheaper.
Who's the beneficiary?
Keo was the primary,
but check this out.
Half the payout goes
to Joe Cavanaugh.
( speaking Lao )
He's not a court-approved
translator.
That's why I taped it.
I just didn't tell him.
So far, he's saying
what you asked him.
"You must help me.
"That's why I'm here.
Just tell them what
they want to know."
This is the part that's
different.
"There are many things I can
tell him about you,
"so you tell him this:
"Samay came to my home.
"I was afraid.
"I thought he was there
"to rob me or kill me.
So I shot him."
So our interpreter is hiding
something.
Well, that's not lost in
translation.
Mr. Cavanaugh, can you
come out here, please?
We're going to have
a private chat.
Let's go.
In the interview,
remember Keo said,
"There are many things
I can tell them about you"?
You didn't tell me that.
You left that part out. Why?
I told you what he said.
You're not arresting
me because I screwed
up my translation?
You're a co-beneficiary
of Noy Vipraxay's
life insurance, right?
So what?
I help my guys try to
get a little security
for their families.
I help them in a lot of ways.
Driver's licenses,
green cards...
Oh, what, what?
Out of the goodness
of your heart?
Come on, they have
to come to you.
Without me, they're back
in a rice paddy
making three cents a day.
Look, some of these guys
put me on their policy.
It's their way of
saying "thank you."
So when one
of your guys
kills another one of your guys,
you make money out of it?
We both know that
insurance companies
don't even investigate claims
under ten grand.
So you get a free pass.
You don't really think I'd have
somebody killed for five grand?
I've seen it done for
a lot less.
That don't
mean I did it.
There's new casinos
that open all the time.
They all got laundries.
I bring home 15 G's
a month on the side.
So I am not going to bend over
a dollar to pick up a dime.
Hodges, do you have
the results
on the fibers
that we dropped off to...?
Hodges?
He's asleep.
( shouting ):
Let me guess,
the fibers are wool.
Are you bagging Z's
right now, man?
I was just having
the greatest dream.
You were out.
It was the '80s and I had
this Don Johnson beard,
you know,
the Miami Vice stubble.
It just gave me this
air of danger.
My lady loved it.
Um, I found two types of
fibers on your guy's chin.
Cotton and
a polyester-
lycra blend.
Both dyed black.
Dyed black?
The bedding might
have been cotton,
but it wasn't black.
The comforter
and draperies
may have been poly, but they
weren't black, either.
I bagged some black socks
and some black pantyhose.
This could be the source of
the fibers.
He wasn't suffocated
with his crew sock.
Did you notice the burn mark
on the knot in these pantyhose
at the crime scene?
No. No, they were
all balled up.
I just bagged them
and tagged them.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, we've got
to get this to DNA.
STOKES:
I thought Greg was
in the field.
Is he back
in the lab?
I don't know.
We've got to clear this up.
It's like he's confused.
Lab, field, field, lab.
We have a lab on wheels.
How about you guys
just shut up, all right?
I'm doing this as
a favor for Ecklie.
It's a one-time thing.
He's still interviewing
lab techs.
You making overtime?
I'm taking one
for the team.
Mm-hmm.
Tell me about
these pantyhose.
Well, I found Tally's
epithelials on the inside,
which is no surprise,
since she was wearing them.
I also found black cotton fibers
on the outside--
highest concentration
near the crotch.
Insert joke here.
The vic had a pair of
black cotton socks.
Well, I did find black cotton
fibers under his chin.
Okay, transfer from the sock
to the pantyhose, to the neck.
So the sock was in between
the pantyhose and the neck?
Padding.
BCP, Breath Control Play.
Couples increase
their partner's pleasure
through strangulation.
And if you're not careful,
it leaves marks.
Yeah, this guy Julian Harper's
an actor,
so I'm sure he didn't want
bruises on his neck
to be showing on camera.
There were only two girls
in the suite.
Which one of them killed him?
Burnt pantyhose.
Okay, evidence
of sex games
gone wrong.
I don't see how we could
have missed anything.
There's no fireplace here.
I haven't seen
any lighters.
Well, something singed the hose.
Hey.
Hmm?
There's some burnt residue
on this lamp.
You know what I think?
I think someone tied him up,
and they couldn't get the knot
undone, because it melted.
So they panicked.
And they pulled the hose down.
STOKES:
I'll print the light.
I guess even having
an unlimited supply
of hot women
is not enough, huh?
Bondage sex with
your best friend?
It's cool,
you guys were
on the down low.
I don't understand.
Well, we found both your prints
and Julian's prints
on a light fixture
above the bed.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
We were not down like that.
Rise and shine, buddy!
Room service.
Dude, Julian?
( grunts )
BLINKY:
He did it to himself, man.
He did it to himself.
I took the pantyhose,
and I took them off the light.
And then I put his boxers
back on.
I wasn't going to let his mom
open up Us magazine
and see her boy like that.
Jules, he always did me right.
Now I just wanted
to do him the same.
I got the serial number
run down from Keo's shotgun.
He bought it last week,
two days before he shot Samay.
The guy's barely
scraping by,
and he spends $250
on a brand-new Mossberg?
There's a word for that.
"Premeditation."
Your brother gets killed.
You killed the guy who did it
with a shotgun
you just bought.
And end up
$5,000 ahead.
( speaking Lao )
In Nevada, that's murder one.
20 years to life.
Unless you get
the death sentence.
( speaking Lao )
What are my
client's options?
A full confession.
We make a recommendation
to the DA,
maybe he gets
murder two.
( speaking Lao )
I brought Noy here to help me.
What?
To work hard and save.
To bring our family here.
Our parent.
Our sister.
My wife.
Instead he waste the money.
On the DVD,
gambling, clothes.
Noy's life was worthless.
His death is not.
( knocking )
Griss, we closed
that actor case.
And?
Accidental death as a result
of auto-erotic asphyxiation.
Strangled himself to death
to enhance his own pleasure.
It was in the days
of public hangings
that people first noticed
that men would get erections
and sometimes
even ejaculate.
They called it
"the killer orgasm."
It's a waste.
Guy had everything--
money, fame...
Yeah, look where he ended up.