♪ ♪
( over radio ):
Does anybody have eyes
on our mystery guy?
Unit one, negative.
I'm on the main casino floor.
I'm heading over
to BJ pit three.
Copy that, unit one.
We'll be watching.
Just get out of my way.
Hey, just a second.
Go ahead,
tough guy, huh!
Break it up.
Break up!
Hey, aren't you...!
( screaming )
Shots fired. Main floor.
BJ pit three.
Dispatch, shooter is on the run.
All available security
to BJ pit three.
Boatwright's down.
Get an ambulance.
Find the shooter.
I don't see him,
I don't see him.
I got him.
Shooter's headed
for the slot carousel.
There he goes.
He's headed
for the guest elevators.
He's got a hostage.
Bring up the elevator cams.
Give me the whole tower.
Three across the board.
Get the police.
We need SWAT, now!
We got the suspect
holed up on three.
Floors above and below
evacuated.
Where's the negotiator?
En route.
At least an hour away.
Well, I'm here now.
Everybody out of here.
Get everybody out of here.
Clear.
( cocks gun )
Las Vegas Police.
Open the door.
( gunshot )
Well, I guess this is the place.
( over radio ):
Homicide at residence.
Viking Circle and Pico.
BRASS:
Just another
domestic violence case.
I wish I had a nickel.
Janice Cutler.
Shot in the mouth.
Single boy's
the only smart one.
Judy and I deal
with our marital problems
a little differently--
counseling, separate
vacations once a year.
She's never pulled
a gun on me yet.
BROWN:
I got a shell casing.
Nine millimeter.
That accounts for
the high-velocity spatter.
Where's the husband?
There was no car in the garage.
We can broadcast
out for him.
There's no other signs
of disturbance in here.
What about the rest
of the house?
BRASS:
Nothing obvious.
How many domestics
have you seen
where someone
got shot in the face
and nothing else
was disturbed?
What are you thinking?
That you married people
take things too personally.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
She's only been dead
a few hours.
Signs of sex
prior to death.
No vaginal trauma to suggest
it wasn't amicable.
Assuming the husband
had sex with her
and then murdered her,
he went from amorous
to murderous
in near record time.
Well, maybe you were right.
It wasn't the husband.
But no semen,
so I'd only be speculating.
What about the bullet?
Single gunshot wound.
Based on powder burns
and stipling,
muzzle was placed
inside the mouth...
( gunshot )
bullet then fragmented
in her head.
Explains why Warrick
couldn't find it at the scene.
Yeah, shooter wanted
to make sure he didn't miss.
This was somebody who was
emotionally close to her.
Gil...
Have you ever even been
close to getting married?
Once.
When I was younger.
Her name was Nicole Daley.
I asked her to marry me.
We were classmates.
She liked bugs, too.
I gave her
my grandmother's ring,
but my mother
made me get it back.
Second grade.
Was it the happiest day
of your life?
Me and Tina?
Happened so fast.
Time will tell.
Why don't you
take a look
at this phone here
and tell me what you think.
SIDLE:
Blood on the keypad,
away from the spatter.
A neighbor called it in.
If someone was in the house,
they'd have dialed 911.
Dispatch never got a call.
Maybe the husband
started to dial...
changed his mind
and took off.
Maybe. I just wish it was
a print and not a smudge.
Okay. Bedroom.
All right.
( camera shutter clicking )
♪ ♪
Hey.
I found these
in his jacket.
Looks like the husband
was planning a little vacation.
A little recreation
on the side.
I found this
under the bed.
And grass--
not the kind you smoke--
on the floor and in the closet,
but all the shoes
in the closet were clean.
So someone was walking around
here with grass on their shoes?
Maybe it was
the missing husband,
or a desperate gardener.
Who was mowing
more than the lawn?
Good call
on the grass stains.
Police officers
brought in your guy.
He was mowing a lawn
down the street.
Well, he must be
a great gardener,
because Mrs. Cutler
was paying him way too much.
Well... ( chuckles )
Wait till
you see him.
BRASS:
Mr. Johnson?
It's Timmy, right?
This is Sara Sidle
from the crime lab.
I didn't kill Mrs. Cutler,
if that's what you're thinking.
How well do you know her?
We live across the street
from the Cutlers.
We?
My family.
Mother, father, and brothers.
So you still live at home?
Until I graduate next month.
So mowing lawns
is just your sideline?
I don't play sports.
Helps with the tuition.
BRASS:
Did Mr. or Mrs. Cutler
ever invite you
in their house?
On a cold day, yeah.
Sometimes she'd
made me coffee.
But she writes you a check
every month, like yesterday.
Yeah.
Did she hand you
the check
in her closet?
Or in her bedroom?
You forgot your sock.
Okay.
Yeah, I was there.
I was hittin' the wife.
You had sex with her?
Yeah.
But it wasn't my idea,
all right?
She was...
She was really
unhappy in her marriage.
Me and Mrs. Cutler were
in the middle of it when...
when Mr. Cutler came home early.
( door opening )
He was supposed to be
at work all night.
Hide!
Yeah.
TIMOTHY:
I guess that's
when I lost my sock.
( grunting )
How was she, you
little son of a bitch?
Now get out of here.
Mr. Cutler was...
was so pissed, I...
I barely even recognized him.
You hear a gunshot?
No.
So Mrs. Cutler was still alive
when you left the house?
I don't know.
I think so.
I didn't see anything else.
♪ ♪
So, I hear your
marriage is on the rocks,
and you're shopping
for hookers?
( laughs )
No, but I think I found one
that Mr. Cutler likes.
Thumbprint on the front.
Four fingerprints on the back.
"Sally. Sweet apple pie."
Hmm. Do you really think
it's a good idea
to sleep with a girl
who advertises in a flyer?
Well, I don't really think
there's any sleeping involved.
Hmm.
Don't be shy, though.
Give her a call.
All right,
for your enjoyment.
( clears throat )
( phone ringing )
This is Sally. Who's this?
Hi. This is, uh...
Dirk... Diggler.
I'm looking
for a date.
What kind of date?
I'm taking a trip
around the world.
Want to go?
Yeah, I'll come with you.
You sure you can afford
the airfare, darlin'?
Is two G's enough?
Where you at?
3057 Westfall.
It's right off
of Charleston.
It's a single
level building,
all the way
in the back.
What do you look like?
Um...
I have a little
Tom Cruise thing going.
All right, half an hour,
and I'll be there.
All right.
( hangs up )
Yeah, right.
Ah, sweet apple pie!
The Cruiser.
Calling me to a
crime lab is cute.
It's still
entrapment.
( laughs )
Well, you're not here
about prostitution, sweetie.
Really?
No. I need your help
with a homicide.
Why don't you go ahead
and have a seat?
Thanks.
( sighs )
This man's wife was murdered
last night.
His name's Willie Cutler.
Was he ever a client?
We dated.
Yeah.
SALLY:
He was trying to play
the, you know,
"I'm a big baller" role.
Do you got a present
for me, baby?
He must have won
some big jackpot or
something--
I can tell when money's new.
He pulled this big wad
out of his Wal-Mart pants.
But he seemed harmless.
Kind of sweet,
actually.
He offered me
a deal on a vacation.
Deal? What, like
a travel agent?
I don't know.
I guess.
He offered me this.
I've never been
to Hawaii.
No...
No, me either.
I'd let you
take me to Hawaii.
Yeah, I'm working.
So am I.
( laughter )
WILLOWS:
"Tour historic Las Vegas."
History in Vegas
gets imploded.
It's probably just
a drive past the Flamingo
where Bugsy Siegel
took his leak.
"Closed"?
Now wait a minute.
It should be open.
Well, it looks like it is.
Oh.
Hello?
Anybody here?
Las Vegas Police.
Hello?
Catherine.
( softly ):
Control, this is CSI Willows.
We have a 419 at 4172 Hamilton.
A business:
Neon City Excursions.
Suspect may still
be on the premises.
( thudding )
Please! Please don't!
Don't kill me.
Please, don't kill me.
It's all right, sir.
We're not going to hurt you;
we're the police.
( groans )
( indistinct announcement
over PA )
Thanks. I'll take that.
DOCTOR:
All right, bullet wound.
Let's see what
the paramedics left me.
( groans )
Irregular laceration,
subcutaneous tissue only.
A few millimeters deeper,
it would have nicked
the intercostal artery.
That sounds bad.
Yeah. Would've been
a real mess.
You're a lucky man.
Flush out the wound,
dress it with
4 x 4 gauze,
start an IV,
hang cefazolin
and get some
blood work done.
Oh, and get him
a tetanus shot.
Ah, the warm
fuzzy feeling
of modern medicine.
Can I get something to wear?
Uh, yes,
in a few minutes.
I need to document
your wound.
Do you think you could
lift your arms for me
like this?
Thank you.
That's perfect.
Why don't you tell us
what happened.
Um. Not much to tell, really.
Uh... Cowboy Dan
had the office
working round the clock
for the last week.
We were putting together
a campaign for a new tour.
I just got back from breakfast.
I heard a shot, shouting.
( multiple gunshots )
( gasping and groaning )
I guess the guy didn't even
know I was there.
I was so scared,
I couldn't move.
So I just played dead.
Ow.
I don't even know
how long I was there.
And then you guys came in
and found me.
Do you think that
you could indicate
on this diagram
where you were standing
when you were shot?
Um...
I guess I was standing
somewhere around here.
Thank you.
Look, I really need
to call my wife.
I should have been home
by now,
and she's probably worried.
VARTANN:
Um.... Mr. Cutler,
when was the last time
you were home?
Um...
I guess it was, uh...
probably yesterday morning.
Why?
Mr. Cutler.
I am very sorry,
but... your wife is dead.
She was found shot
last night in your home.
Wh...?
( camera shutter clicking )
Single GSW
to the forehead.
Stipling makes it
close range.
At least he died
with his boots on.
( single gunshot )
WILLOWS:
Cowboy Dan gets it first.
The shooter finds
his next target.
( four gunshots; man groans )
Shoots him in the back.
SANDERS:
That's the vic's desk.
He was getting
a promotion.
Well, at least his day
started out
on a good note.
Looks like the gun's
been wiped clean.
Doubt we'll
get any prints.
So what do you got,
five nine-mil
shell casings?
Two went back with the body,
three... still in the walls.
So they're all accounted for.
So Willie Cutler must have been
standing along this line
when he was grazed
by the bullet.
Looks about right.
It's consistent
with his statement.
( camera shutter clicks )
And if the shooter
never saw him,
he got under the desk
really quickly.
I sure would have.
So what do you think, Greg?
Is Willie Cutler
the luckiest guy in the world
or the unluckiest?
I wouldn't want his luck
either way.
BRASS:
Geez, you lose your wife,
your boss, your co-worker,
all in 24 hours;
that's rough.
My heart goes
out to you, pal.
Really.
Thank you.
Looks like someone's
out to get you.
What do you mean?
Well, the way I see it,
somebody's out to kill you
and a lot of innocent people
are getting
in the way.
Yeah.
That's got to be it.
Who'd want to kill you?
I don't know.
Maybe it's
just some nutcase.
A guy sees me
on the street,
and I remind him
of somebody he hates.
Yeah, that's...
that's a pretty good theory.
Want to hear another one?
Sure.
Well, this one starts with
your wife banging the lawn boy.
Hmm?
Timmy?
Timmy.
What, you didn't know?
No.
Really?
'Cause according to Timmy,
you found him in the bedroom
and you dragged him
out of the closet.
Well, he's lying.
'Cause I wasn't home.
Oh, yeah, that's right.
That's right.
You were on the love boat
with Sally the hooker.
Look, my wife and I
had some problems.
You know, all
married couples do.
Hey.
I was getting
a promotion at work.
At least I thought I was.
So I threw myself
a little celebration.
I guess that makes you
a premature celebrator.
Tell me about that
work-promotion thing.
Why were you passed up?
Cowboy Dan just
couldn't bring himself
to promote a felon.
Yeah, no, I've-I've
read your record.
I mean, it's minor league.
I mean, like,
joyriding at 19.
Stupid kid stuff.
You know,
it follows you around
the rest of your life.
Oh, believe me, I know.
Look, here's
what we got here.
Cowboy Dan is dead.
The guy who got your promotion
is dead.
It seems to me,
that the one
with the most motive to kill
in this sad tale... is you.
I got shot, too.
Well... you know...
kinda.
Look.
( clears throat )
Last night
you wired 50-K
from your
home equity account
to a marker
at the Lucky Dragon.
So?
So, I mean, it wasn't
for Chinese food.
So maybe you hired
a professional killer
to hit your wife, your boss,
your coworker.
That's not true!
Told them to take a little,
you know, love bite out of you
to, you know, make you look
nice and innocent, you know?
I didn't kill my wife!
I lost this money
at the tables.
You know...
This has been
the worst day of my life,
and I still haven't
had a chance to see
my wife's body--
I want to leave.
But we're
not done here, Willie.
We're done!
You can't prove
that I killed
anybody
because I didn't kill anybody.
And if you're not
going to charge me,
I'm going to leave.
I want to see
my wife's body now!
BRASS:
Well, I pushed the guy
as hard as I could,
but there's a lot of
media heat on this one.
I had to cut him loose.
Well, he's got a bullet wound
and a dead wife.
For now, the evidence says
he's a victim.
Well, that's what
I told the unit
who's shadowing him.
♪ ♪
WOMAN ( over phone ):
Sunstar Cabs.
MAN:
Yeah, we had several pickups
from that office park
this morning, but, uh,
look, those drivers
are all off right now,
and they take one look
at my caller I.D.,
they ain't pickin' up.
All right, well,
what about drop-offs?
Oh, definitely got something
for you there.
Hey, Nicco.
Yeah?
You'll love this.
Nicco, tell these guys
about that guy, huh?
The drive-around-
all-night guy?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Pick him up
near Viking
and Pecos around 2:45 a.m.
That's right around the time
Janice Cutler was killed.
It's right
near her house.
Is this your cab?
Yeah.
Mind if I take a look?
Okay.
So?
He didn't know
where he wanted to go,
but he said I should drive
anyway, so I drive.
He sees a store,
he says stop. Buys a beer.
Then he says, drive, stop,
cigarettes, and drive some more.
I'm all around town.
Five, six hours.
Did you get his name?
Uh... I think it was Sammy.
Yeah. Yeah,
that's what he said.
He asked me
to wait for him
by this office place,
but by then it was
at the end
of my shift.
I told him, I got to
get home to my wife.
And he asked me,
do I love my wife,
and I told him, hey,
( chuckles ):
she loves me.
And he said,
I was a lucky man,
which I am.
And he left.
He gave me a big tip.
You need to check this out.
Is that the guy
who called himself Sammy?
Looks a lot like Willie.
Yeah. Yeah, that's the guy.
( computer beeps )
Yup.
That's the gun.
( computer beeps )
( beeping )
( beep )
BRASS:
So, Willie Cutler had
an older brother, Sammy.
Sammy did time in Chino
for grand theft auto.
Willie had a vehicle-related
felony on his record, too.
Yeah, the same incident.
See, Willie was a
first-time offender,
so he pled out.
But Sammy had a record,
so the judge gave
him a hard time.
So he got in trouble
on the inside.
He did an
extended sentence.
He got out six
months ago.
I got a fax from
the cab company I
want to show you.
Check it out.
They get called out
to that office park
where the shooting took place.
Driver said
the fare was a no-show.
"Requested destination--
Lucky Dragon Casino."
Hmm.
I sent a unit out
to look for Sammy.
You know, this could be
a revenge story.
Willie gets a life,
Sammy goes to prison.
Sammy gets out,
tries to get even.
Well, if Sammy was trying
to get even,
why did Willie keep quiet
about it?
He's his brother's keeper.
It's in the Bible.
This is the man
that we're looking for.
Please keep your eyes peeled.
He may have been here
last night.
I want you to cover
every square inch of this place.
Let's spread out; let's move it.
So, this is Sammy Cutler.
This is his mug shot.
It's a few years old,
and this is
what he looks like now.
Hey, Sara, you're working
the office shooting, right?
Yeah,
and the dead wife.
Autopsy reports
on the two D.B.'s.
Grissom wanted them ASAP,
and I was in the neighborhood.
Thanks. I'll pass
them along.
Somebody at the office
get knifed?
No.
Kind of looks like
a knife wound.
Victim survived
the shooting.
He said he was grazed
by a stray bullet.
Really?
This is an irregular laceration
with no defining features.
A grazing GSW is usually
accompanied
by some marginal abrasion.
There's none here.
Any idea what might have
caused a wound like this?
Yeah, lots of things.
Something sharp.
Hmm.
What's this blue discoloration?
SIDLE:
Kind of looks like ink.
Doesn't it?
Mm-hmm.
Catherine found this
under Willie Cutler's desk.
Thought the blood
was incidental.
Sodium rhodizonate is negative.
No lead in the tear.
No bullet.
So, Willie tried to make it look
like he was shot.
Grabs a ball point pin.
( groaning )
Drags it across his ribs.
Did I miss something?
Don't know.
We'll find out.
MAN:
We've been running a major
poker tournament here all week.
You know what the loser gets?
Baseball caps.
There's about 400 of them
down there right now.
Keep looking.
( computer beeping )
( beeping continues )
( keypad beeps )
( phone ringing )
Hey, baby.
What's up?
Nothin' much.
Where you at?
I'm at the Venetian.
Canyon Ranch,
getting a... manicure.
Hope you're in for a good
back scratching session tonight.
Who you talking about?
( laughs ):
What?
Me or the guy standing
next to you?
Look up. You see that little
dome above your head?
Give it a wave.
That's me in the surveillance
room, watching you lie to me.
Warrick...
Man, and I didn't even have
to call that show Cheaters.
You think you know
what you're talking about?
Don't even bother
coming home tonight.
I'll just text you
the storage space
your stuff'll be in.
You want to know what's up, huh?
What's really up?
I can see what's up.
You can't see a damn thing.
He's a V.I.P. host helping me
plan your birthday party.
I hope you enjoy
spending it alone.
( beeping )
Well, hey.
What are you doing?
Serology.
Serology?
Now, I read about that
in my History of Forensic
Science classes.
So, what exactly is
it you're trying to do?
Lattes Crust method
for determining blood type.
You know, for you,
I clear the decks.
I mean, I can just rush
your samples through DNA.
I need it faster than DNA.
And I don't need a full profile
anyway, just ABO type.
You mind if I stick
around and watch?
Don't you have
something better to do?
Yeah, I do,
but some guy's using my lab.
Okay, now as I recall,
the reagents have to be fresh.
Right? So,
where did you get those?
I keep some in my Fridge
for emergencies.
You got anything else in there?
Bottle of tequila, perhaps?
Severed head?
I don't keep tequila.
♪ ♪
( gunshot )
( keypad beeping )
Jim, you have
to bring in Willie Cutler.
Willie got loose.
He slipped our surveillance.
What's up?
We found high velocity spatter
consistent with the wife
on his shirt.
He was in the room
when she was shot.
He could have been holding
the gun.
Maybe they were working
together.
That would explain
what Sammy was doing
at the Lucky Dragon.
Willie lost a lot
of money there.
So either he did it, or
he's covering for his brother.
Yeah.
Maybe he's got
unfinished business there.
Yeah.
♪ ♪
Ow! Man, what the hell
is your problem?
Just get out of my way.
Oh, you're a tough guy?
Go ahead and go through me
then if you...
Huh? You think
you want some of this, huh?
Tough guy, huh?
Hey, break it up,
break it up!
Hey, aren't you...?
( woman screams )
Shots fired. Main floor.
BJ pit three...
( woman screams )
Get out of my way!
( grunts, elevator bell dings)
Hey! Hey!
Get off of me!
What are you doing? Help!
Shut up,
or I'll kill you.
Help! Help me!
( phone ringing )
This is a radio check.
Do you read me?
( phone continues ringing )
Copy that?
Kill word is "Jim."
( phone continues ringing )
Hello?
Hey, Willie.
It's me, uh, Jim Brass.
Remember me?
Guess what?
I'm right outside your door.
I will blow her head off.
I'll blow both
our heads straight off.
You understand me?!
Look, I understand.
I understand, Willie, I do.
Look, I just... I just want
this to end peacefully.
For everybody.
I'm not coming out.
Oh, I don't want you
to come out, Willie.
I want you to let me in.
Look, I'm not armed.
Look through the peep hole.
Why do you want
to come in here?
Just to talk to you, Willie.
I mean, you're a smart guy,
I think maybe you and I,
we can figure a way out of this.
Come on, check me out.
Okay, look,
I'm going to put the phone down
now, so you can see me, okay?
Look... no gun.
Hey, Willie.
It's me.
I'm alone, and I'm unarmed.
Close that door.
Either I walk out here
right now, or she dies.
Look... nobody's
going to die, Willie.
Not you, not her,
not me, not Sammy, not anyone.
You sure about that?
Oh, yeah,
I'm sure about that.
Then I want to talk
to my brother.
Okay, I can arrange that.
We have him in custody
downstairs.
You're lying!
Hey, you got the gun.
I'm not...
I wouldn't lie to you.
But I need you to do
something for me.
I need you to let this woman go,
and I'll dial up
your brother downstairs.
Where is he?
He's in the holding room,
which is in the basement
of the casino.
He was just
trying to help me.
Look, I'm just trying
to help you too, Willie.
Point the gun at me, not at her,
and let this
nice young woman go,
come on.
No way.
Point the gun at me, Willie.
You really have my brother?
Yeah, I'm gonna call...
Hold on.
I want to talk to him.
( keypad beeping )
( phone ringing )
Brown.
This is Brass.
Look, I need you
to get Samuel Cutler
on the phone.
I'm here with his brother,
Willie,
and he'd like to talk to him.
So, could you go down
to the holding room
and get Samuel Cutler
on the line and call me back?
Are you with Willie right now?
Yes, I'm with him,
and he'd like to speak
with his brother.
We're still looking for him
in surveillance.
It could take some time.
How much time?
I don't see his face,
she dies!
Okay, okay, okay.
Look, look.
I need you to get Samuel Cutler
up here as soon as possible.
Okay, Brass, we're
doing the best we can.
I want you to hang in there,
take care of yourself.
BROWN ( over phone ):
If he's in this casino,
we're going to find him.
Thank you.
He'll be here.
Okay? Now, I just
want you
to point the gun at me.
That's good.
Not at her.
That's it-- cause it's just
you and me now, all right?
I'm the hostage,
all right?
What's your name?
Jackie.
Jackie. It's going to be
okay, Jackie.
It's going to be
okay, Willie.
It's just you and me now.
This is all
going to be over soon.
Oh, yesterday,
I spent $5,000 on a hooker
because I thought I was
getting a $15,000 promotion.
When I went
to work,
I got the news that
I'd been "passed over."
So now you're five large
in the hole, hmm?
Well, way I saw it,
I was 15 in the hole.
So I went
to a cash machine
and I wired myself 50-K.
Every cent I own.
For a second I was up,
I was killin' em.
They were serving me cocktails,
and calling me "sir."
And then the pit boss
got involved
and I hit a bad streak.
So I called Sammy.
Bust, bust, bust, bust!
Damn it! God!
Ah, God!
What? What?
Willie?
What?
Let me get you
out of here.
What happened when you got home?
Things got worse.
I lost everything.
Our entire savings.
I'm sorry.
You stupid lowlife.
That was my money, too!
You are such a loser.
Just like your
degenerate brother.
( gasps )
( gunshot )
Sammy told me to stay put,
and he said I should
clean up the mess.
He said he was going
to take care of me.
Why didn't you
call the cops?
I can't turn him in.
And I knew I'd get blamed.
GRISSOM:
Willie Cutler's marker
was signed
by a blackjack
pit boss,
This is last night's
surveillance.
So the pit boss
gives Willie the heave-ho,
with chips still on the table.
Yeah, that's about
a $10,000 marker.
Casino owed him money,
that's why Willie went back.
And what about Sammy?
I haven't seen him.
I tried to find him myself.
I figured I could get him
to Mexico or something.
I drove around
for hours.
Nothing.
So I went back to my office,
and that's when I saw Cowboy Dan
and Roger.
And I knew what Sammy meant
when he said he was going
to take care of me.
He was going to give me
a clean slate.
He was going to kill
everyone that wronged me.
But she hasn't wronged you.
Jackie hasn't done
anything to hurt you.
So why would you want
to hurt her?
Let's cut her loose.
I don't want to hurt anybody.
That's right, Willie.
You don't want to hurt anybody.
You kill somebody,
even by accident,
you can never
take it back.
People never look at you
the same way again.
And you know what?
You can't look at yourself
the same way again, either.
( knocking )
SIDLE:
Griss?
You got to see this.
I found it on the Internet.
Me and Sammy?
( sniffles )
We used to be so tight.
Mm.
And that stupid car.
He always felt so guilty
about dragging me into that,
but it wasn't his fault.
He wasn't to blame.
Well...
( cell phone rings )
Just the phone.
Take it easy.
Yeah.
Jim? Sammy Cutler's dead.
He died in a car crash in Mexico
two months ago.
Willie had to know.
He's been playing us.
I got it, yeah. Thanks.
Hey, Willie.
Sammy's not coming up.
But I guess
we both know that, right?
Yeah.
It's a good thing
I have the gun.
Jim.