( wind whistling )
GIRL ( hoarse whisper ):
They came to... my house.
They had a fight.
They couldn't find
what they were looking for.
♪ ♪
( indistinct background
radio communication )
Sheriff?
Who, uh... who called it in?
Anonymous 911.
Listen,
we haven't had a murder
in all of Lincoln County
in ten years,
let alone a quadruple.
Without the bodies, I can't
confirm there was a murder.
No offense, Mr. Stokes, but
did you see the amount
of blood in that house?
Somebody's dead.
What do you know
about the family?
Jude McBride-- great guy,
stay-at-home dad.
Nina owns a local coffee shop.
Jeremy's a junior
in high school, smart kid.
Ten-year-old daughter, Cassie.
Pip-squeak.
Sounds like all that's missing
is the white picket fence, huh?
Yeah.
We don't even know
where to start looking.
Begin at the beginning.
♪♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
CASSIE ( hoarse whisper ):
I loved my family.
♪ ♪
Are we having
a Taster's Choice moment?
Grissom called me
from the airport.
He's teaching a Human Remains
Recovery class
at the body farm.
He said you needed backup,
and I figure you needed coffee,
but... looks like
you already took care of it.
Oh, no.
No, I didn't do it.
Coffeemaker's programmed
to go on Monday through Friday.
So, somebody cleaned up
Friday's coffee
and reset it to go off today?
You'd have to be alive
to do that.
Which means
whatever happened here happened
over the weekend.
Blood pools are dry, so,
crime scene's
at least 12 hours old.
There were at least
three major blood events--
here... here...
and up the stairs.
Without the bodies, we'll
have to confirm the source
of the blood through
DNA comparison.
I'll collect toothbrushes,
hairbrushes...
You know, it's possible
it wasn't the family
that died here.
The sheriff confirmed
the McBrides' cars
are parked out front,
and their cell phones,
car keys,
wallets are
all right there.
Can't get far
without those.
Mm.
It would also
seem to eliminate
robbery as a motive.
Yeah.
What a mess.
SANDERS:
If you're not gonna
clean it up...
why take the bodies?
Yeah.
Well, I'm gonna
start upstairs.
SANDERS:
I'll take outside.
( camera clicking )
♪ ♪
Based on their shoes,
Dad wore a nine-and-a-half,
Mom wore a nine.
Jeremy wore an eight-and-a-half,
and Cassie wore a one.
There is that men's
nine-and-a-half
between blood pool number one
and blood pool number two.
And the barefoot print
on the stairs looks smaller.
STOKES:
Yeah, they're consistent
with the mom, size nine.
No matches to Jeremy
or Cassie, though.
Let's just assume
they were shot.
Maybe they were
shot first.
There's no blood to step in
if you're first.
Or Mom could have grabbed
Cassie up,
try to take her away
from it all.
Bullet penetrated both bodies.
Could explain why there are only
three blood pools.
There are three other sets
of shoeprints.
One size 12,
two size 11.
Two of the sets appear
to be going back and forth
from the kitchen area
to the front door.
One set, and only one set,
headed upstairs
for the bedrooms.
I'll go up there
and see what I can find.
( rapid clicking )
SANDERS:
Sheriff Brackett...
did your deputies drive anything
up here with a hitch?
No. Why?
I got an odd-sized
tread here.
( camera clicking )
CASSIE ( hoarse whisper ):
I hate the taste of that stuff.
I like Nancy Drew.
She always gets the bad guy.
I knew all my lines
and Hansel's, too.
( girl giggling )
( door squeaking )
What is that?
If it's labeled correctly,
it's, uh, Cassie's laugh.
( girl giggling )
( giggling )
♪ ♪
Our man Jeremy's a bit
of an entrepreneur here.
Oh, yeah? How's that?
He's trafficking in term papers.
Whatever happened
to just flipping burgers, man?
I think I figured out
when all this happened.
Cassie never got
to her Saturday
morning chores.
I was really into gold stars
when I was a kid.
As opposed to now?
Whoa!
The McBrides must
have a broken meter.
Even if they left every
light on day and night,
it wouldn't add up to $2,000.
( clears throat )
Maybe Brass can
check it out.
I think this print dust
is getting to me.
Would you mind
finishing the fridge?
Do I get a gold star?
( dryly ):
Ha-ha-ha.
♪ ♪
Greg?
I found something.
Is it the bodies?
No.
Sweet Mary Jane.
The Emerald City.
SIDLE:
Explains the $2,000
electric bill.
And all the footprints
throughout the house.
It's a ganja graveyard.
SIDLE:
No...
it's motive.
Whew...!
Looks like someone shot
out the lock upstairs.
I found what looked
like fragments
of two bullets; they
may be too M-and-D
for a comparison,
but I could probably
get type and caliber.
BROWN:
Man.
If those suspects
got everything on those lines,
they made out like fat cats.
Yeah, but they were only
interested in the dried stuff.
If this was a territory war,
or something like that,
wouldn't the dealer
want to take the new growth,
to try to put these guys
out of business?
Maybe one of the customers
got greedy.
BROWN:
Well, we're talking about
getting rich, not
getting high, you know?
And these dry ones go
a lot faster than those.
The price of an ounce these days
is anywhere from $200 to $400.
Don't you guys think it's weird
that the McBrides did all this
with two kids in the house?
Yeah, if they
didn't care before,
I bet they do now.
( indistinct
radio transmission )
SIDLE:
Well, we took some
representative samples
of the green
plant material.
Okay, Ecklie's
sending out a tech.
I'll include it
with the other evidence.
Pioche P.D.'s going
to hold on to the rest
until we can secure it
for bulk transport.
How's it going with
the phone records?
No outgoing calls from the house
after 6:00 p.m. Friday night.
I scrolled through
Jude McBride's
recent cell phone calls.
No activity all weekend
until Sunday night.
Several incoming calls,
all from the same number.
According to Pioche P.D.
dispatch, it's the same number
as the anonymous 911 call.
So I had the phone company
cross-check it,
the guy's local:
Dr. Malcolm Parker.
I'll go check it out.
PARKER:
Be careful with
those stitches, okay?
I just put them in
a couple days ago.
Your mom will
kill me if it scars.
Okay.
Sorry about that, guys.
You had some questions?
You placed an anonymous
911 call Sunday night.
Said you were outside
the McBrides' house
and you could see
blood in the entryway.
SIDLE:
Right before that,
you called Jude McBride's
cell phone three times.
Late night house call...?
Dennis, do I have
to answer that?
It looks worse if you don't.
Well, Jude and I have a standing
Sunday night appointment.
For what?
You are aware that it's illegal.
Okay, look, I have no idea
what went on out there,
before I got there.
Hi, Jude, it's 8:00.
Where are you guys?
I called 911.
I didn't leave my name,
because...
because I didn't want to explain
what I was doing there.
You and Jude are making me
look like an idiot.
He's selling drugs,
and you're buying them.
Tell me something, Malcolm.
Are you high when you
treat my daughter?
Dennis, of course not.
And Jude was discreet.
He rarely sold
to anybody in town.
He sent most of it out of state.
Dr. Parker, what size shoes
do you wear?
What size shoe do I wear?
A ten.
And where were you Friday night?
I was here, doing rounds.
Hello, there.
Hi.
Can I help you?
I'm Sage.
I'm looking for Nina.
Yeah? So am I.
She left work early Friday
to see Jimmy Buffet in Tahoe.
But then she never showed up
at the shop today.
And what was your name again?
Sage.
Okay, yeah, maybe you
can help me out.
Um, the family,
what do you know about them?
Are they having problems?
Marital problems,
anything like that?
Are you kidding?
Jude and Nina had the
marriage we all wanted.
Really?
You know, uh,
your third eye
is so open right now.
Are you having visions
or hearing voices?
No.
I'm really sorry.
But you're radiating
this crazy feminine energy.
( chuckling ):
Really.
Mm-hmm.
Do you believe in past lives?
No, ma'am.
How come?
Because I'm just trying
to make it through this one.
I think you're doing
pretty well.
Hey... Sage.
Thanks.
Hey, Nick.
Well, there's no hits
off the fingerprints
from the kitchen cabinets.
Dozens of unknowns, none
of which were in the system--
no work cards, no prior crime.
So I expanded the search
to other databases,
and I did get one hit.
A Mark Horvatin.
17 years old, Junior ROTC.
His print was in the kitchen,
but not in blood.
Could just be a friend.
That was nice, dude.
That was nice.
You got smoked.
Hey, Mark!
Mark!
Hey, I'll catch up
with you guys later.
Nice game Saturday.
Hey, Dennis.
Listen, we should probably
go with Sheriff Brackett
on this one.
Oh, okay, Sheriff.
This is Mr. Stokes
from the Las Vegas Crime Lab.
What size shoe
do you wear?
Twelve.
Can I see the bottom?
Should I get my dad?
No, we're just talking.
Oh, yeah,
they're new, huh?
Yeah, I got them this weekend.
My old ones were thrashed.
STOKES:
Huh.
You know, when I played ball,
I used to stick all
my gear in the trunk.
Yeah, well, this is just easier.
Parking lot still
school property?
BRACKETT:
Yep.
Why don't you go ahead
and pop the trunk for me?
Go ahead.
CASSIE ( whispering ):
Daddy's garden was supposed
to be a secret.
Someone must have told
the secret.
BRACKETT ( over speaker ):
This doesn't look good, Mark.
Not a lot of places
you can get that much marijuana.
There's no way
it could be a coincidence.
Tell me where the bodies are.
( indistinct radio transmission
in distance )
I'm not finding any blood
in here.
Besides, four bodies would
never fit inside this car.
You know, maybe, the pot
was stolen after the fact.
Crime of opportunity?
What are you, his lawyer?
Whoever stole the pot...
...had a gun
and shot the lock
off the basement door.
Someone went to the ATM
at 10:03 Friday night.
Right in the window
of the murders.
Hand that over
to Sheriff Brackett.
He can run the account number.
I found this exact
kind of gum
in the driveway
at the McBrides'.
( groans )
This microscope I got from
the high school is a joke.
How am I ever going to prove
that this is the pot
from the house?
Where's that evidence
we collected?
All right, this is the bag
from the house.
And this is the bag
from the car.
The striations line up.
These bags
are from the same roll.
Nicely done.
STOKES:
Fellas.
We have a little problem.
Mark's not talking, not
even to pass the buck.
And his dad, Mark Sr.,
is a lawyer,
and he's challenging
our search and seizure,
saying that even though
we were on school grounds,
we lacked probable cause
to search personal property.
( strips off glove )
( sighs )
Blood pool closest
to the front door,
and the size nine-and-a-half
shoe print...
both in Jeremy's blood.
JUDE:
Jeremy, what's going on?
WILLOWS:
Jude stepped in Jeremy's blood.
Blood pool number two.
In the hallway,
between the foyer
and the kitchen.
( gunshot )
Nina's footprints,
dual contribution,
Jeremy and Jude.
Jude? Jeremy?
Is everything okay?
Oh, my God!
Jeremy!
( sobbing )
WILLOWS:
Blood pool number three...
( Nina shrieks, body thuds )
...Nina's blood.
Yeah, Nick,
I got the DNA results back.
Blood pools were confirmed
for mom, dad and Jeremy.
None of the blood was Cassie's,
so either her death
was a bloodless crime...
Or they took her alive.
Thanks, Catherine.
SIDLE:
How did Mark know
where the pot was,
if McBride was as discreet
as Dr. Parker claims?
DNA confirmed
to everyone but Cassie.
SIDLE:
Interesting.
Mm-hmm.
Mark knew the
pot was there
because of Jeremy.
Come on, I'm sure
Jeremy wasn't voted
the most popular
boy in school.
He's done everyone's
term paper.
He's a nerd.
So you guys want
to come over and hang out?
I could sell you some pot.
Now, where are you
gonna score fresh herb?
My parents are
going out of town.
My dad has pounds of it.
Yeah, so how does that end up
a quadruple murder?
One of them was stupid enough
to bring a gun.
I was talking to Tina
the other night.
She said something
to make me think.
( playfully coughing ):
Yoko Ono.
Tina's dad is
a Doctor of Anthropology,
so, one day, when she was
a little girl, she asked her dad
where on her body
her anthropology was.
You know, he's a doctor.
Mark's dad's a lawyer.
Maybe Mark was thinking
habeas corpus--
"body of the crime"?
"Body of the crime" is content
of the case, not an actual body.
Yeah, but a kid could
easily misinterpret.
Maybe he's thinking,
"no body, no crime,
no crime, no punishment."
Does Yoko Ono want a job?
BRACKETT:
Morning.
Hello.
My wife made muffins.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
We got a lead on the ATM.
The account belongs
to Jim Locke.
He's got a son named Peter,
the same age as Mark.
We pulled some
surveillance footage.
It's a little grainy,
can't see much.
I'll give it over to Archie
and see if he can clean it up.
Thanks.
All right,
I'll be in the car waiting
when you guys are ready.
All right,
thank you.
You feeling a little
homesick there?
You want to draw straws?
No.
Call me if you need me.
All right.
All right, let's head over
to Locke's house,
and see what we can find.
You coming?
No... No, you go ahead,
I'll catch up.
You think she's alive.
You don't?
None of her blood
was found at the house.
I think she was drugged, and...
she was lucky
if all they did after that
was kill her.
I don't think she was drugged.
She's a smart little girl.
She hid that cough medicine
in her shoe;
that's like hiding green beans
in your napkin, you know?
I hope you're right.
But everything in our experience
tells us they're dead,
all four of them.
Doesn't mean we just give up.
No one's giving up.
It's just that...
you're acting like
you're going to rescue a person,
not recover a body.
And on this job...
that's just not
usually the case.
I was rescued.
It was not your day to die.
When it's your day,
it's your day, you know?
I don't think
it was Cassie's day.
That looks like
the plant material
I found in
the McBrides' driveway.
And this looks like
the same wheelbase
as the tread you found.
BRACKETT:
We found something in Mark's car
that we think
might be Peter's.
Is that your
account number?
Yes.
Does Peter have access to it?
Sure.
He has a limit,
but he's never gone over it.
Mrs. Locke, when was the last
time you took the boat out?
Friday night.
Peter and some of
his friends
took it out
for one last hurrah
before it gets too cold.
Do you know which friends?
I was already in bed.
Sorry.
Do you mind if the CSIs
take a look at it?
Sure.
Have the boys been drinking beer
on the boat again?
( children shouting happily
in distance )
( dog barking )
( kids laughing )
CASSIE ( hoarse whisper ):
Everyone told me
I was the best Gretel ever.
SANDERS:
My dad used
to take me sailing
when I was a kid.
Do you know
what the inboard end
of an anchor rope is called?
"The bitter end."
This explains why
we're not finding any blood.
( phone ringing )
Hey!
STOKES:
Sara, did you find any gum
on that boat?
Any gum at all--
wrapped, unwrapped-- anywhere?
Yeah...
How did you know that?
I think Cassie
was on that boat--
alive.
I think she was
leaving us a trail...
of gum, "gum drops."
In the driveway,
in the car, on the boat.
It's like Hansel and Gretel.
Half the pictures I've seen
her in, she's chewing gum.
Nick, that's a bit of a stretch.
A lot of people chew gum.
You tell Sheriff Brackett
I'll meet you at the station.
Peter, we know
you were in Mark's car.
We found
your ATM receipt.
We also know you guys took
the boat out Friday night.
( on speaker ):
We know that there were
three people involved.
Who was the third?
Pete, we found your print
on a cough syrup bottle,
underneath
Cassie McBride's bed.
Your buddy Mark's not talking.
He's gonna pay for that.
Be smarter.
Do the right thing.
( computer beeping )
( computer beeps )
Dead bodies
don't suck their thumbs.
( PDA beeping )
How'd you hurt
your hand?
What's the matter?
She fight back?
You tried to drug her,
but guess what?
She was too smart
for you.
You coached
the little girls' swim team,
'cause you liked
to watch 'em
in their bathing suits,
is that it?
You're gonna answer me
right now!
No more screwing around!
Where is she?!
Where is she?
STOKES:
Okay, my guess
is the guys stopped
at the ATM to get cash for gas.
That's cash only,
and Eddie over there says
he filled the tank
to the top Friday night.
Can I talk to you
for a minute?
Sure, what's up?
I think I need to talk about
what happened at the station.
Oh, yeah.
I'm slightly concerned about
its effect on the case,
but more than that,
I'm concerned about
the case's effect on you, Nick,
and I'm absolutely sure
that, six months ago,
you wouldn't have
lost it like that.
I know, I'm sorry.
I apologize for that.
How much gas was left?
Three-quarters of a tank.
Took an eighth to get out
there, an eighth to get back,
and according
to the gas mileage,
on the Lockes' boat,
that would have been
about three miles out
from this launch point
right here.
Come on.
Nick?
Yeah?
This is the three-mile mark.
CASSIE ( quietly ):
I used to love going
to the lake,
but not anymore.
There's something there.
They killed my whole family.
( camera clicking rapidly )
Where's the fourth?
We only found three.
C.O.D.?
Gunshot wound to the chest.
Though it appears
to have gone
through his hand first.
Dad wrestled with the gun, huh?
( gunshot )
Anything else?
Contact wound
on the boy.
Shot up-close
and personal.
Mom was shot twice
in the back.
Not up-close.
Rinsed and ready for you.
.22... probably
from a revolver.
Six shots.
Four in the bodies,
two in the lock.
Well, that would explain
why we didn't find
Cassie's blood in the house.
They ran out of bullets.
Sara, the bullets pulled
from the bodies
were from
a .22-caliber revolver.
IBIS bounced back a hit.
They were entered into IBIS from
the Department of Wildlife,
for shooting a deer
with a small caliber handgun.
Firearm was returned
to the owner--
a Chris Daniels from Pioche,
Nevada.
( sports broadcast playing )
Hey, Dennis, what's up?
Hey, just in time
for steaks.
Mr. Daniels, do you, uh...
do you own a .22 revolver?
You know the answer to that.
You cited it and fined me
two hunting seasons ago.
Sir, I'm Sara Sidle from
the Las Vegas Crime Lab.
It's evidence in a
homicide investigation.
I'm going to need it.
Dad, how long on the steaks?
We're going to need
to speak to Luke.
What did you do with my gun?
If you did anything
to jeopardize
that football scholarship
of yours,
you're done.
BRACKETT:
Duck your head.
Found this in his pocket
when I patted him down.
Tested positive for blood.
As did these.
You just wanted to
intimidate Jeremy, right?
Scare him a little?
But Mr. McBride was still home
and he didn't scare so easily.
You guys have to go.
My parents are still home.
Dude, I thought you said
there were pounds of pot.
You guys got to get out, okay?
Please, just get out
of here, all right?
Jeremy! Jeremy,
what's going on?
What the heck?
Jeremy, what's going on?
( gunshot )
What the hell did you just do?
Mrs. McBride
came downstairs,
so you had to
shoot her, too.
Peter went upstairs
to deal with Cassie...
...while you and
Mark bagged the pot
and wrapped the bodies
in garbage bags.
But... Peter couldn't do it.
He couldn't kill Cassie...
...so he tried
to drug her.
You guys got
in Mark's car,
you went to the ATM,
you got cash,
you picked up
Peter's boat,
you went back
to the McBrides'
and you loaded the
bodies onto the boat.
You were out of bullets,
way out on the lake.
One small, loose end
to tie up.
Bring her over here.
No!
She can identify us!
There's no way
she's staying alive.
I said she was a strong swimmer.
I didn't say we could throw
a drugged ten-year-old
into the lake.
Did it make you feel like a man?
To kill a little girl?
♪ ♪
Stop the boat.
Let me out. Let me out.
♪ ♪
( respirator pumping
quietly )
( whispers ):
Hi.
You're welcome, sweetie.
They're in Vegas.
Their bodies are in the
coroner's office, honey.
Hey, Cassie...
I know when bad things happen,
it's hard to remember.
But if I give you some details,
do you think you could tell me
the story of what happened
to your family?
( hoarse whisper ):
Okay.
We'll go slow, okay?
And we'll just begin
at the beginning, okay?
( hoarse whisper ):
They came to... my house.
They had a fight.
They couldn't find what
they were looking for.
I loved my family.