911.
What is your emergency?
MAN:
Yes. There's been an accident.
What kind of accident, sir?
Please, ma'am, I need you
to send an ambulance.
Please, just hurry.
Sir, paramedics are en route.
Oh, my God!
Please, you've got to help me!
Please, hurry!
Sir, where are you injured?
What? No, not me, my wife!
De-fib.
What does that mean?
Sir, please stand back.
( steady tone )
There was an emergency call out,
the paramedics
responded.
They found
Mrs. Lester
in the back stairs.
They pronounced at 12:16 a.m.
And, of course, you walked
through the house.
We were responding
to a traumatic injury.
Our priority was
to assist the victim.
WOMAN ( over radio ):
141, you cut off
on the first and middle name...
BRASS:
That's Ray Lester,
the vic's husband.
WILLOWS:
Was he injured?
No, uh, that's
his wife's blood.
He said he checked
to see if she was
still alive
and he held her until
the paramedics came.
Wouldn't you?
You never met my ex.
Tequila will always remind me
of Señor Frog's.
BRASS:
Which one?
Cancun.
My honeymoon.
My dime.
Well, if you ever want
to go back, it's on me.
Is that a proposal?
HODGES:
It's like
the Red Sea in here.
The Red Sea's not red, David.
No, it's blue from afar and
transparent when held in hand,
like any other
body of water.
I was just speaking
figuratively.
I'm assuming
those boot prints aren't yours.
Please, I was just waiting
for you guys to clear a path.
Blame the paramedics.
This girl's head and spine
are perfectly aligned.
Yeah, when you fall down
the stairs, your head tends
to go in one direction,
your body in another.
I'll take a statement
from the husband
and the paramedics;
see if she was moved.
You know, twice
as many people
die each year
from falling down stairs
than from accidental gunfire?
You didn't just get back
from one of those coroner's
conferences, did you?
What are you thinking?
Led Zeppelin.
"Stairway To Heaven.
♪♪
♪ Who are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh! ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
( murmuring )
BROWN:
Hey, Sanders.
Hey.
Back stairs.
And, uh, you might
want to hug the wall.
Whew!
Did you ever hear
of Odor Eaters?
Never mind.
We don't get another boot
allowance till spring.
Well, I'll try
to get 'em back to you
before your next shift, okay?
Uh, one more question:
Did either
of you guys
move the body?
Didn't have to.
She was faceup.
I unbuttoned her blouse
to apply the leads,
but that's it.
We tried not to touch anything.
Once we saw that blood,
we knew you'd be showing up.
GRISSOM:
Becky Lester.
Catherine and I got here
a half an hour after
her husband called 911.
Edges of the blood pools
were already dry.
The pools themselves were tacky.
Which means she'd been down here
at least an hour or two
before you guys even got here.
Why did the husband wait so long
to call?
Good question.
Coroner won't touch the body
till Catherine and I are done
processing around it,
so, Sara, would you please
go up the front stairs
and work your way down
the back stairs?
You got it.
Warrick, could you
process the blood evidence
from the front door
to the back stairwell?
And if you'll notice,
she doesn't have any blood
on her feet.
So I can assume those bloody
footprints aren't hers.
Nick, Brass is in the study
with the husband
and he's waiting for you.
( camera clicks )
WILLOWS:
Hey, Grissom,
spatter on the wall
doesn't exceed 18 inches.
Well, that's consistent
with the fall.
Guys,
if she fell,
even if she was pushed down
these stairs,
I would expect to find smudge
marks on these walls.
Yeah, she would've
instinctively reached out
for leverage.
There are none.
Not to mention,
that if she was up here
before she was down there...
...she should've landed
headfirst.
The body position is
inconsistent with the fall.
Well, it's inconsistent
if she fell down the stairs.
Maybe she fell up.
Catherine,
can I borrow your micrometer?
Blood spatter measures
two millimeters.
Medium spatter.
Suggests impact
with a blunt object.
But if she was hit,
where's the castoff?
It is a low ceiling.
Pretty hard to swing a weapon.
Sometimes first blush
gives you a head rush.
I don't think
I moved her.
I mean, I cradled
her head in my lap.
Tried to wake her up,
but that's it.
So, you and your wife went
to Pieros for dinner,
got home around 10:00.
Got out the tequila,
then what?
I, you know, got comfortable...
then we went outside
and did a few shots.
How'd the tequila
get back inside?
Um, the phone rang
and it was my daughter Susan.
Your daughter?
Yeah, from my first marriage.
She's, she's staying
at Becky's dad's.
All right. It's Susan.
Oh. Hey, babe.
Uh-huh.
Okay.
It's boy trouble.
I'll take this inside.
What did you do after that?
Another shot or two and
then I guess I fell asleep.
And I woke up
around midnight.
And I figured that
she and Susan had just gotten
into one of their talk-a-thons.
I took the tequila and
the glasses into the kitchen
and that's when I saw her.
Oh, my God.
Oh, please!
Oh, please, please!
Oh, my God...
Now, is there any reason
you can think of
why your wife would be using
the back stairs?
From the kitchen,
it's closer to
the bedroom.
You never mentioned anything
about the bedroom.
Are you trying
to trip me up or something?
I mean, I don't...
maybe she went to,
uh, brush her teeth
or put on her nightgown.
I really don't know.
Okay, sir. I'm going to need
to take your clothing.
I'll go upstairs and change.
No, that's okay.
We're still processing upstairs.
You can remove them
right here
and I'll give you
a jumpsuit.
I'll close my eyes,
if you're shy.
Those don't look
like mosquito bites.
My wife likes to bite,
and I don't mind it, okay?
Okay.
Okay,
the husband says
he fell asleep,
he woke up
his wife was dead.
He's a good sleeper.
Yeah, I'm sure he's gonna say
something like that.
Anyway, there's a daughter.
She spent the night
at her grandfather's,
who lives a few blocks away.
I'm gonna check it out.
BROWN:
I'm ready.
The blue markers denote
the footprints.
They're all consistent
with the husband.
The footprints are associated
with gravitational blood drops.
The yellow markers denote
the paramedics' boot prints.
And what about this
here, on the counter?
It's a single
blood drop.
I'm thinking
that's from when
the husband reached
for the phone.
That's a good observation.
What do you got in the bag?
This...
is a bloody paper towel
I found in the trash.
It's too textured to print,
but Sanders talked
to the paramedics,
who confirmed
that it wasn't theirs.
I'm thinking it was from
the husband
when he tried to clean up and
saw it wouldn't be too easy.
Lucky for us.
♪ ♪
Hey.
Husband slept in the other room.
His reading glasses are
on the nightstand.
Clothing's in the dresser.
That's odd.
A man and a woman, who
don't share a bedroom,
arrange to have a night alone,
send their daughter
to a relative,
go out to dinner,
have drinks by the pool,
but they sleep
in separate bedrooms.
Maybe one of them snored
or had insomnia
or liked to work at night.
Or maybe they were suffocating
each other
and he couldn't breathe.
Sexual lubricant.
It's half empty. Sticky.
You know, you don't have to
sleep in the same bed together
to have sex
or...
have romance.
I'm going to go see the doctor.
I'll grid the house.
I don't understand.
Becky was in perfect health.
Can I see her?
I'd like to see my daughter.
BRASS:
Well, her body's with
the coroner, sir.
There will be an autopsy as
a part of our investigation.
But you said she fell.
Yeah, um, if you don't mind,
I'd like to ask you both
a few questions.
Anything.
When was the last time
either of you saw her?
When she dropped Susan off
yesterday evening,
she came in for
a few minutes.
Said she was headed home
and out to dinner with Ray.
And that's the last time
you spoke with her.
Yeah.
No.
I called her.
A little after 10:00,
after Grandpa went to bed.
What did you talk about?
Why is that important?
Well...
Stupid stuff.
My best friend Jamila
and I, we both like Leon.
And I know,
friendship first.
I just wanted Becky to say it,
you know?
Uh, yeah, okay.
Thank you.
Thank you, Susan.
Susan, would you give me
a moment with the detective?
SUSAN:
Okay.
You said you found my daughter's
body on the stairwell?
That's right.
You're aware that Ray's first
wife, Susan's mother,
was found the same way?
Well, now I am.
They said Susan's mom died
of a stroke.
But you don't think so?
I never had any reason
to doubt it.
So how would you, uh,
how would you characterize
your daughter's marriage?
Ups and downs.
About a year ago, Ray's business
went under.
And Becky works
for Western Airlines.
They've been downsizing
since 9/11.
It's been rough.
Yeah.
Mr. Stein, does your son-in-law
have a temper?
Do I have to answer that?
You just did.
Becky Lester, 32.
Final meal, pasta.
I can't tell you the variety
of the noodle,
but there was a white sauce
with clams.
And I found some blood
in her stomach.
Her tongue was lacerated
perimortem.
She probably chomped down on it
when she hit the stairs.
I sent a blood sample to tox
and Nick asked for
teeth impressions.
Husband claims she's a biter.
Fine line between
pleasure and pain.
But who doesn't like to cross it
every once in a while, right?
Anyway, um, I don't know
if it's probative,
but there's semen
in her vaginal vault.
Sperm motility and
positive acid phosphates
suggest intercourse
approximately
six to 12 hours
prior to death.
Yeah, I'm mostly interested
in cause.
Exsanguination from
five lacerations:
Two to the forehead,
one to the right temple,
and two to the occipital bone.
Are they consistent
with a fall?
Yes, but I'd expect to see
hand fractures as a result
of the impact,
and there are none.
Are they consistent with
blunt force trauma?
Sure, but if the husband
bludgeoned her,
there'd be fractures
to the skull.
And there are none.
None.
Well, you've given me
a lot of information, Doc,
and none of it very helpful.
You want fries with that?
Robbins said the vic
bit her tongue.
Theoretically,
she could've expirated
the blood on the wall,
providing an alternative
explanation
for the medium velocity spatter.
Do me a favor,
check it out.
Well, it looks like
two millimeters.
Same as the blood at the scene.
So, maybe it was
just an accident.
GRISSOM:
As she tried to get up,
she expirated the blood
on the wall.
She failed to regain her
footing, impacting her temple
and then she bounced on her
occipital bone.
So we've got two theories, both
supported by physical evidence.
Yeah, if we ever find a murder
weapon, my theory's done.
Well, I know that there was
no blood found in the car,
so it's unlikely that Ray
took a drive to dispose
of the weapon.
Hey, ready for a quiz?
Guess how Ray's first wife died?
Wait. She had a stroke
on a stairway.
Robbins told me.
Is that the autopsy
report?
No, these are medical records.
There was no autopsy.
Jackie Lester had
a heart condition.
Three weeks
before she died,
she was admitted
to a hospital with vertigo.
She ignored the doctor's
warnings,
didn't take her medication.
Family physician pronounced it
a stroke.
WILLOWS:
Well, if she wasn't cremated,
it's not too late for
a postmortem examination.
Judge Witherspoon is issuing
a court order for exhumation.
Now, look,
I just came from the DA.
I gotta tell you,
he's already made up his mind.
Husband and wife, home alone,
all that blood,
shaky alibi.
Plus, he says,
"He just looks guilty."
How does one "look" guilty?
You know,
I'm just a messenger.
What do you think
the chances are
he didn't do it?
Well, what do
you think
the chances are
we're going to give you
an answer
before all the evidence is in?
Greg...
Becky Lester had a B.A.L.
of point one-eight.
And I found trace
amounts of Diazepam.
Thanks!
Hey, I heard the
coroner found semen,
so I tested for
birth control.
Estrogen and progesterone
levels were spiked.
Where did you hear about
the coroner's findings?
Actually, I read
the report.
Maybe I don't want to be a
toxicologist my whole life.
I mean, you went from
DNA to the field,
and I guess you're kind
of a role model to me.
A role model, huh?
Yeah. By the way, where
do you get your hair cut?
( sniffs )
Quick. How many teeth
in the human mouth?
Without wisdoms? 28.
Yep, and the 28 teeth
in Becky's mouth
do not match
the bite impressions
on her husband's body.
I guess Ray found himself
another set of pearly whites.
Look, I loved my wife.
But, a year into our marriage,
she told me that
she wasn't into sex anymore.
And, uh, she went frigid on me.
Asked me to move
into the other bedroom.
And you were okay with that?
Well, I kept hoping things
would get better.
And we had fun and we
respected each other.
And she was a
great mom to Susan.
I'm still confused
about the bite marks.
I found a way to make our
relationship work.
You found yourself a vampire?
I met a girl online.
She liked biting.
I liked being bit.
It just seemed like a good
match, and it never got sexual.
Uh-huh.
And, uh, what is her name?
I know her as
Buffy227@gmail.com.
And your wife
never suspected anything?
We'd meet at a motel...
every few weeks.
I'd tell Becky
that I was going out for a bite.
It was consensual
and it wasn't sexual.
It was not cheating.
But you never told your wife?
I didn't tell Becky everything
I did every minute of the day,
but that doesn't mean
that I was unfaithful.
When, exactly, was the last time
that you had sexual intercourse
with your late wife?
Four years ago.
Rosy Palm and Thumbelina are
the only action that I get.
Uh, wow, you know, uh,
a joke like that
doesn't quite seem appropriate
for a distraught husband.
I'm just answering
the questions.
Mr. Lester, did you know that
your wife was having an affair?
The day that she died,
she had had intercourse.
Are we done here?
For now.
( computer beeping )
JOHNSON:
Ow... ooh.
She's hot.
But I still wouldn't
let her fang me.
No, no.
I'm with you.
Was the video encrypted?
Uh, no.
I was processing
Ray's computer
and it was just sitting
on the desktop...
in a folder called
"Dental Records."
STOKES:
Did you get an I.D.
on Buffy?
JOHNSON:
Grissom got us
an administrative subpoena.
ISP sent over
the subscriber information:
Dr. Jeri Cohen--
aka Buffy227--
is a dentist.
Are you kidding me?
I could not make this stuff up.
I'm not ashamed
of my predilection.
Assuming both parties
are healthy,
biting can be orgasmic.
Huh.
Dr. Cohen, where
were you last night?
Home alone, like most nights.
Ma'am, we're here
to talk about
your relationship
with Ray Lester.
Well, I wouldn't call it
a relationship, per se.
There was no sex, no commitment.
We'd meet at a motel room,
once or twice a month.
You e-mailed Ray
digital video
of your sessions together.
Ray bought me that camera
for, uh, my birthday.
It was fun.
If you say so.
The Kama Sutra says
that any place on the body
that can be kissed
can also be bitten.
Except the upper lip,
the interior of the mouth,
and, of course, the eye.
It also goes on to describe
eight different ways
to bite your partner.
Ray liked "the broken cloud."
Teeth...
are sexual organs.
( clears throat ):
Um, Dr. Cohen, did, uh...
did, uh...
Ray.
...Ray ever mention his wife?
He told me he was married.
It wasn't a problem for me.
He said they made
better friends
than lovers and she was
a good mother, that's about it.
Was he violent?
Ray?
No, he was nothing like that.
See?
No bite marks.
I'm the aggressor.
Ray just lies there
and takes it.
He's a real sweetheart.
( clears throat )
Uh, ma'am...
Would you mind
biting down on this for me?
You know I wouldn't.
They don't tell you about
this part of the job
when you're training
to become a CSI.
Come on, after
five years,
at least they don't
smell anymore.
Always with
the silver lining.
Right.
You ready?
( lid creaking )
Well, hello, Jackie Lester.
On three.
One... two...
( grunting ):
Three.
If you two don't mind...
...we'd like some alone time.
♪ ♪
You done with your
alone time, Doc?
Just completed my prelim,
but check this out.
Subgaleal hemorrhages,
consistent with
lacerations
to the occipital bone.
So both of Ray's wives end up
dead at the bottom of the stairs
with lacerations to the head.
If my full autopsy
confirms murder,
you maybe looking
at the first
serial stairway killer.
If there was
a murder weapon,
it was not in that house.
We searched everywhere.
What's in the bag?
Sex lube, found
at the crime scene.
Autopsy revealed that Becky
was sexually active.
Ray claims that
they've both been celibate
for the past four years.
And you wanted to see
if her lover's prints
were on that bottle.
Two viable prints, both
in a light coat of lube.
One was Becky's and the other
is an Adam Gilford.
Work card is in the system.
He's an executive
at Western Airlines.
Lovers and co-workers.
That never works.
If Ray did find out
about the affair,
that's motive.
GILFORD:
Of course I knew Becky Lester.
I'm her boss.
I'm the one who hired her.
Hard to believe
that was six years ago.
And it's such a tragedy.
She was loved.
By some more than others.
Excuse me?
Mr. Gilford, we know
that the two of you
were sleeping together.
Becky wasn't in love with Ray.
They'd stopped
having sex.
If they divorced,
she'd owe him alimony,
and Becky didn't think
that was right.
Becky told you that?
She told me
everything.
She and Ray were
living on vapors.
They'd just taken
a second on the house.
She also told me that Ray
was hiding money from her--
the insurance payout
on his first wife.
Look, if you suspect
she was murdered,
I can tell you why Ray did it.
We're listening.
At Western Airlines,
VP's and above
receive corporate
life insurance policies.
Quarter mil payouts.
Last week, a round of
pink slips went out.
We both got hit.
Two weeks, she would
have been out of here.
And the insurance
policy, suspended.
And Ray is the beneficiary.
He killed her
just in time to make a killing.
DA's planning
to file charges
against Ray Lester--
tomorrow,
after an ADA stops by
the crime lab
for a full briefing.
That's too soon.
Tell me about the first wife.
Preliminary investigations
suggests foul play,
but we've got nothing definitive
until she's fully posted.
And the physical
evidence
in Becky Lester's death
is completely ambiguous.
The DA figures he'll
make a headline while you find
corroborating
evidence.
You think he's guilty, right?
I don't think that yet.
Oh, um, am I
interrupting?
No.
Brass just called
with a heads up.
Since when does the DA's office
tell us when we're ready?
When the case is high profile
and the DA is feeling heat
from the sheriff.
Look, you'll just walk him
through the evidence.
You won't bias your reports
or skip anything ambiguous.
It is what it is.
If the DA wants to shoot
his wad too early,
we can't stop him.
Okay.
Sarah and I may have
uncovered motive.
In the last two weeks,
Ray filled out
five loan applications.
200 G's a pop.
All denied.
With his wife dead,
he is the beneficiary
of a $250,000 policy.
Huh.
I wonder what
he needed the money for.
I was... being blackmailed.
Um, someone found
out about Buffy.
I... I got a letter
and a photo in the mail.
They wanted 200 grand
or the....
Otherwise, they'd share your
biting secret with your wife.
Yeah.
Our marriage
was having enough problems.
I mean, you're covered
in those bite marks.
Didn't your wife ever ask
where they came from?
She hadn't seen me naked
in a long time.
I just...
I would've been humiliated
if she found out about Buffy.
She was a great mom.
And she kept... she kept me sane
when my business went under.
You still have
the blackmail note?
Yeah. I couldn't risk
letting Becky find it.
Soon as I opened that letter,
it went right into my briefcase.
I've got the only key.
( computer beeping )
"Send $200,000
to P.O. Box 4976,
"Searchlight,
Nevada, 89431
"within two weeks
or I'll send photos
to your wife."
P.O. Box was through a private
company, paid for in cash
with a pseudonym: Abe Lincoln.
Ninhydrin picked up
six distinct prints.
Five were
matched to Ray.
What about the sixth?
Becky Lester.
Hold on.
Ray told Brass that
Becky never saw that note,
which means
he was lying.
If she read the note,
then it's possible
that Ray freaked out,
bludgeoned her to death.
What if Ray's telling the truth?
Well, Catherine,
if he was,
her fingerprints
would not be on this note.
Unless she touched the letter
before it was sent,
which would make her the sender.
Well, that doesn't
make any sense.
Becky thought that Ray was
squirreling away money.
Maybe this is her way
of getting her hands on it.
She used his fetish against him?
She blackmailed her own husband,
knowing that he would pay up,
so she wouldn't
find out his secret.
That's ingenious.
And really sad.
( chuckles )
If it's true.
Well, if Becky's saliva's
on that envelope,
it's indisputable.
This is a blood clot.
Take a look.
Huh.
The blood's continuous.
Comes from deep within
the parenchyma.
The first wife had a stroke
and it was fatal.
What about
the scalp lacerations?
Perimortum.
So she must've hit her head
on the stairs on the way down.
Well, I can't tell you
about the second wife,
but this was a natural.
That's
the Western Airlines logo.
Over the past few years,
corporations have begun
embedding their insignia
into the stationery
for security purposes.
( phone rings )
If Becky wrote the note,
she wrote it at work.
This is Catherine.
Oh, yeah. I'm on my way.
For the record, I think
you're filing prematurely.
As always,
I value your opinion.
But I'm confident in our
decision to move forward.
But, come on, Grissom,
granted the first death
was a natural--
but two dead women,
married to the same guy,
found in a stairwell?
Lightning doesn't strike
in the same place twice.
Actually, it does.
The Empire State Building
gets struck
20 times a year.
Let's just run the case.
WILLOWS:
Sorry,
I got held up.
No, you're just in time.
Ms. Willows,
would you bring
Mr. Sinclair
up to speed?
I'd be happy to.
Ray and Becky Lester
were unhappily married.
She was having an affair
with her boss, he was indulging
his biting fetish.
They were having
financial problems.
But Becky believed that Ray
was hiding money.
Two weeks ago, Ray received
a blackmail note
demanding 200 grand
or the wife finds out
about Bite Girl.
Well, we have just confirmed
that the blackmailer and
the wife are one and the same.
Based on what?
The envelope
of the ransom note.
DNA was a match.
The wife was blackmailing
the husband?
( chuckles )
Never underestimate
the deviousness
of a malcontented spouse.
He found out and he killed her.
We don't have any evidence
to support that.
Run the timeline.
Couple got home
around 10:00 p.m.
They went outside
and had some tequila.
At 10:08,
Ray's daughter
from his first
marriage phoned.
Becky went inside
to take the call.
How long did they talk?
It's not in Brass' notes.
Well, I have the phone
records here, so...
Uh, the call lasted...
two minutes?!
I thought the husband told Nick
it was a marathon call.
Yeah, I'm just seeing this
for the first time here. Um...
The incoming call did not come
from the grandfather's house.
I'm gonna
call this number.
( dialing )
( line ringing )
You've reached the home office
of Ray Lester.
Please leave your details
after the beep.
( line clicks )
Susan called her stepmother
from inside the house.
Did anybody process
that office phone?
The office was away
from the crime scene.
We, uh, checked it
for a murder weapon,
but that's about it.
I'll get an investigator
over there.
Unless you're in
too much of a hurry.
There it is.
Greg...
there's a fingerprint in blood.
Detective,
what's going on?
Mr. Stein,
where's Susan?
Is everything okay
with Dad?
We have a warrant
to search your house.
A warrant?! What?
Would you both please step
outside with this officer?
Can I get my homework?
Well, uh...
Sure.
That'd be all right.
Okay.
I'm gonna need to see
inside your backpack.
It's just my books and stuff.
I'd like to see
what you're studying.
What did you hit her with?
I want to talk to my dad.
Why don't we take
a ride downtown.
You can call him
from there.
Nice work.
♪ ♪
My stepmom was a bitch.
Susan, you're
not helping.
Please, stay quiet.
BRASS:
Excuse me for a minute.
GRISSOM:
You know, I guess
this could explain
why Becky's skull
was lacerated
and not fractured.
She wasn't strong enough.
I had to protect him.
Protect who, Susan?
Susan!
Protect your father?
Protect your father from what?
She was gonna leave him.
So that's why you killed
your stepmother,
to protect your father.
Last week, I skipped soccer
practice and came home early.
( Becky laughing )
BECKY:
You are so damn
brilliant.
( Becky and man
laugh together )
MAN:
I just found
the digital video
and printed out
the stills.
BECKY:
"Dental Records."
I married a moron.
( both laughing )
GILFORD:
Did you check
the P.O. box today?
Empty, but he's got
another week.
Ray's whipped.
He brought up
counseling again.
The idiot would die
before letting me in
on his freak-ass fetish.
My dad only married Becky
because of me.
Explain that to me.
Well, he thought
I needed a mom
and that's why
he stayed with her.
Blaming herself
for the marriage.
She doesn't seem to blame
herself for ending it.
So you waited for your
granddad to go to sleep
and you snuck out
of the house,
snuck back into your house,
then you called your stepmom
from your dad's telephone line.
Pretty tricky.
And then, you must've...
hid somewhere.
I hid in the closet.
I told her we had to talk and
that I knew about her boyfriend.
Uh, hey, Dad.
Is Becky there?
Could I talk to her?
All right.
It's Susan.
Hey, babe.
Just tell Dad
you'll take the call inside
and meet me in my room.
Okay.
It's boy trouble.
I'll take this inside.
( grunts )
Are we done here?
Almost.
We're almost done.
You know, Susan,
there was a bloody paper towel
left in the trash.
Can you tell me about that?
I put the phone back
in my dad's office
and I walked back
to Grandpa's.
Where was your father
when you killed your stepmother?
He was outside.
Asleep.
GRISSOM:
Did you catch that?
Timeline is off.
Curious.
You want to talk
to the dad
and I'll call the DA?
Sure.
You knew.
What?
Your daughter killed your wife
and you knew it.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Susan attacked Becky as soon
as she went into the house.
But you admitted
to having another drink.
You would've heard the attack.
I'm sorry, but
that's what happ...
You went into the house
and found Susan wiping blood
off of her hands.
You sent her back
to her grandfather's.
You came up with a story
to tell the cops,
and then called 911.
You were protecting
your daughter.
And now she's protecting you.
You can't prove it.
Well, either way,
you have to live with it.