( music plays )
♪ ♪
( doorbell rings )
( knocking on door )
( dog barking )
( garbled radio transmission)
The decedent's name
is Christina Adalian, 28.
Gunshot to the temple.
Her sister
is over there,
just came in
from L.A.
When no one answered the
door, she looked inside.
Saw her sister
on the floor.
The playpen with the baby
was next to the body.
Police officers
kicked in the door.
Where's the father?
Well, according to her sister,
she's a single mom.
They lived alone.
Lividity suggests
she hasn't been moved.
Liver temp is 92 degrees
which means she's been dead
four to five hours.
Wound pattern and GSR suggest
a tight contact shot.
BRASS:
Consistent with suicide.
Oh, there's a note
on the white table.
"Joey is better off without me.
Christina Adalian."
Postpartum depression so bad,
it leads to suicide?
Sister was feeding the baby.
Where'd she get the bottle?
The fridge is full of bottles
of breast milk.
( camera clicks )
Mom stocks the fridge
and kills herself,
knowing her sister
was going to show up.
She wanted to make sure that her
baby was quickly found and fed.
SIDLE:
David,
do you mind if I render
the gun safe?
Better you than me.
One shot fired.
Sara, check out the blood
on her hand.
There isn't any.
The gun is spattered
in dried blood.
She wasn't holding this gun
when she was shot.
And what appears to be, is not.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really want to know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ The Bible tell me
who are you, you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
Honest.
I am good with kids.
I'll get a hotel.
I'll stay in town.
I know we've been
over this before.
Like I said, he'll be
placed in Child Services
until appropriate custody
can be determined.
That's just the way it is.
I'm sorry.
Metro just arrived with
a baby seat. We're ready.
All right.
I'd really like
to go with him.
Okay, after we're finished,
an officer will take you
to the facility.
Finished with what?
Well, we have
a few more questions.
And, uh, CSI has to take
your fingerprints.
We won't take long,
believe me.
Well, what about his bottles?
They're in a cooler
in the officer's car.
( baby cries )
Ma'am.
( crying )
It's okay.
It's gonna be all right.
( crying )
Hey, buddy.
It's okay.
Can't find a red pen anywhere.
Well, maybe the killer
brought his own pen.
Or took it with him
as a souvenir.
( cell phone rings )
( cell phone beeps )
Okay, guys.
I swept the perimeter.
I think someone jimmied
the back kitchen door.
Now, I printed the doorknob.
Nothing but smudges.
Check out
the fresh scrapings
there on the doorjamb
and the striker plate.
Looks like forced entry
with a metal object.
Some black and white particles.
Want to hand me a hinge lift?
Good eyes.
( cell phone rings )
( cell phone beeps )
Who do you keep avoiding?
Ecklie.
Ah, that means
you should answer it.
No, he just wants to yell at me
because I'm late with
the personnel evaluations.
It can wait.
No, it can't.
No one on your team receives
cost-of-living adjustments
until those evaluations
are turned in.
Well, she kind of
has a point.
I do like to take the wife out
to dinner every now and then.
Mm-hmm.
I'll do them as soon as
I get back to the lab.
Last time I saw my sister
was over a year ago.
She was just beginning to show.
She'd gone through
a really bad breakup
and couldn't stop crying.
Is the ex
the baby's father?
I'm not sure.
Well, we need to contact
him regarding Joey.
It would be helpful
to know his whereabouts.
I only know his first name.
Evan.
But Christina referred to him
as "the jerk."
They met at a church social
a few years back.
Christina complained he wasn't
very Christian-like.
But that was part of
the attraction, if you ask me.
He was older.
Didn't want to get married.
You know, Christina never said
he was the father.
So there were other guys?
No. As far as I knew,
Christina was a prude.
She'd turn red if somebody told
a dirty joke.
I always thought she was
a virgin until...
Until she got pregnant.
Yeah.
Excuse me, have either
of you two seen Grissom?
He's in the house.
Sofia.
Hey, Catherine.
Grissom, Ecklie's been
looking for you.
Is your cell not working?
What are you doing here?
Well, apparently, I was a CSI,
then a detective,
but now I'm a messenger.
You're needed at the lab ASAP.
Why?
I have no idea.
But
theundersheriff'sundersherriff's
camped out in the break room.
I'll have Greg run down
the gun's serial number.
Nick is covering
the autopsy.
Warrick and I will finish
the processing here
and I'll keep you
posted.
( sighs ):
Thanks.
What would you do without me?
Grissom.
Conrad. Sheriff.
It's always lovely
to see you fella,
but I'm right in the middle
of a crime scene.
We have a situation, Gil.
Preston Breckman
who's on trial
for the murder
of Joanna Whitson.
Yeah, I know.
She was a friend of yours.
I'm sorry.
I was her godfather.
Grew up with her dad.
Two weeks before
she was murdered
I gave a toast
at her sweet 16.
Well, they say
it's a slam dunk case.
You would think.
We've got an eyewitness
who saw him stab her.
Hair, fiber, even DNA
from the killer's tobacco
indict Breckman.
We got the right guy.
Then what am I doing here?
Defense has called
entomologist Mark Thayer
as an expert witness.
He's a gun for hire.
He's gonna say that the
insect activity on the body
proves defendant was out of town
at the time of the murder.
And you want me to refute
his testimony?
When does he take the stand?
Half an hour.
Look, he's been on the list,
but the D.A. assured me
he was unavailable.
Gil, we need you to listen
to his testimony.
Prosecution may need
your assistance on cross.
I'll do my best.
No mystery here.
Penetrating gunshot wound
to the right temple
killed our Virgin Mary.
I sent the bullet
to ballistics.
Virgin Mary?
Hymen's intact which means
she's never had intercourse.
But she gave birth...
caesarean scar.
So other than
divine intervention,
how do you explain
this miraculous conception?
Well, the most obvious
explanation would be frottage.
You mean dry humping?
In Sex Ed,
Nick, they teach that
rubbing body parts is safe.
But since the hymen's
not a barrier to semen,
there's still a risk
of pregnancy,
not to mention STDs.
Right. Sperm meets labia,
all bets are off.
It's all about gravity.
Thanks, Dr. Ruth.
The test fire bullet matches
the evidence bullet.
That confirms the gun found
at the scene was used to kill
this, uh...
Christina Adalian.
You run the serial number?
Yeah, of course.
Anyway, Greg,
your two-inch Colt
was originally purchased
in 1986
by a Mr. Duane McWane
from Henderson.
Good luck.
Thanks.
Well, as you can see, the life
cycle of the black blow fly,
from egg to larva to puparium
to adult,
is like clockwork.
So, to be clear, we can use
the fly's lifecycle
to accurately determine
the precise day
the victim was killed.
That's correct.
The victim was murdered
in a woodsy area near Lake Mead.
In that vicinity, how long would
it take for the blow fly
to lay eggs in Joanna Whitson's
body?
Within minutes of her death.
Is that true?
Mm-hmm.
Doctor, based on your review
of the blow fly activity
as documented by CSI,
can you tell this jury
the exact date Joanna
was murdered?
THAYER:
CSI found puparia on the body,
but no adults.
So that means that the victim
had been dead for 15 days.
The body was discovered
November 15.
So based on your analysis,
the victim was killed
November 1?
That's correct.
Defendant was in Mexico
'til November 3.
We think he killed her
on the 4th.
Well, he's still got to prove
his timeline.
Dr. Thayer, this timeline you
suggest-- from egg to puparia,
has this been documented?
I documented it myself.
In fact, in preparation
for this trial,
I videotaped a black blow fly
breeding on a pig carcass.
Now, this videotape will
illustrate that the timeline
from egg to puparium is,
in fact, precisely 15 days.
Your Honor, on this video tape,
I have relevant footage
of Dr. Thayer's experiment.
With your permission,
I'd like to play it
for the jury.
Have you seen this tape?
No. Objection.
Your Honor, the defense
never produced that tape
for our review.
We haven't had the opportunity
to examine its authenticity.
It's not our fault.
It was never requested.
Is that true, Counselor?
The defense is playing games,
Your Honor.
We subpoenaed the expert's
files, reports
and opinions.
But, apparently,
they've conveniently
construed the subpoena
too narrowly.
They're acting
in bad faith, Your Honor,
and cannot expect
this court to usurp...
Your Honor, Your Honor.
If I may...
You may not.
You blindsided the court.
You knew that the ADA.
would want to see that tape
and you deliberately
withheld it.
How much time do you need?
We won't know
until we review the video.
Fine.
The defense
is to hand over the tape
and all associated evidence.
The jury is dismissed
until 1:00 p.m. tomorrow.
( gavel bangs )
Send everything
over to the lab.
I'll be there.
Your black-and-white particles
were composed
of plagioclase,
biotite, hornblende
and pyroxene.
Diorite granite.
You remember your geology.
Yes!
Wow.
Actually, senior year
I took "Rocks For Jocks."
I dated the TA.
Lucky guy.
I'm sure you got an "A."
As a matter of fact, I did.
Mm-hmm.
You're married?
Don't flirt.
Anyway, uh, diorite
granite is used
in high end bathroom
vanities.
Was there any recent
construction at the house?
No, I processed the bathroom
and the countertops
for some kind
of plastic laminate.
Made a few calls.
There's only one
slab yard in Clark County
that works
with Diorite.
It's on Alonzo Avenue
across the street
from the old theater.
Hey, take it easy
with that Thassos.
It's the last shipment
of the month.
Sorry about that.
Sure, I know Christina.
Dated one of my guys.
Real sweet gal.
Used to bring donuts around
before they broke up.
Her ex happen
to be working today?
Yep.
His name's Evan.
( grinding )
Well, I'm sorry
to hear about Christina,
but we broke it off months ago.
I haven't seen her since.
WARRICK:
Really?
Is she dating one
of your co-workers?
Huh?
Well, we found marble particles
in her house
and we identified the stone.
It came from this facility.
See, Mr. Peters,
we know that you
and Christina
technically never
had sex,
so when you found out
that she was pregnant,
I'm guessing that
you felt that she
cheated on you.
How in the hell do you know
about my sex life?
I mean, that had to have made
you really angry, right?
Well, that's why I dumped her.
And fine, I saw her
a couple of days ago.
She called me
in a panic.
Dingbat had locked herself out
with her damn baby
still inside the house.
Thought I had
her spare key.
I didn't.
She sounded hysterical,
so I went over to help.
( panting )
( Christina gasps )
You followed her
into the house?
Well, she wanted to talk.
What did
you talk about?
All right, get this.
She tried to tell me
that God got her pregnant.
( laughs )
If that's true,
the Big Guy owes
me an apology
'cause she was
my girlfriend.
He should have
asked me first.
Why did you lie to us?
Claim that you hadn't seen
her in months?
Well, you guys were
investigating her murder,
and I want to stay out of it.
Well, it's too late
for that, my friend.
We need your DNA.
Open wide.
The day I got married,
I got rid of my gun.
The wife didn't
want it in the house.
You sell it?
No, I gave it
to my paralegal.
I'm an attorney.
Look, it's just a handgun,
so I wasn't required
to register the transfer.
What's your paralegal's name?
Rita Day.
She left the firm
years ago.
She's a paramedic now
at Emergency Care Ambulance.
You still keep
in touch with her?
I get a card
every Christmas.
All right, well, thanks,
Mr. McWane.
Look, just, just
so you know,
she only got that gun
for her own protection.
Whatever you're investigating,
Rita didn't do it.
( beeping )
How is it going?
Well, according
to my experience
and all three of
these textbooks,
the P. Regina would develop
from egg to puparium in 11 days.
Great.
That discounts
Thayer's testimony
and puts Breckman in Vegas
at the time of the homicide.
Yeah, but his demonstration
speaks for itself.
There's no visible puparia for
15 days, just as Thayer asserts.
And jurors might
be more receptive
to video documentation
than books.
The science
in these textbooks is sound,
but the tape is more than enough
to get reasonable doubt.
Well, there's
no doubt in my mind
that Thayer worked his science
to get the answers
the defense needed.
We just need to know
how he did it.
Could he have altered
one of the variables?
I've reviewed his documentation.
He purchased the pig
from a reputable dealer.
He conducted the experiment
at a private lab
with eyewitnesses,
controlled all variables
to replicate the
conditions at Lake Mead
during the time in question.
65 to 73 degrees,
no precipitation,
on and on.
Can you conduct
your own experiment?
Sure, if the judge
will give me 11 days.
Well, we know
that's not gonna happen.
I'll have Archie
review the video footage.
Maybe he messed
with the time code or something.
I'll let you know.
So I heard that my predecessor
in DNA had all these
you know,
personal hygiene issues.
Well, just for the record,
I'm not like that.
I have always been
very touchy-feely.
I mean, I used to work in
San Francisco, you know.
So... every day we
started with hugs.
Uh-huh. Yeah.
That must've been
nice for you. So...
Hey, how about
lunch tomorrow?
Just you and me.
Cause, see, I-I figure
that you gotta know
where the bodies are
buried around here.
So to speak.
Is that why you paged me?
No. No, um...I compared
Christina Adalian's DNA
to Baby Joey's, and guess what?
Mother and son--
they're not mother and son.
At least not
genetically speaking.
There's no relation.
And Evan Peters
isn't the father?
Nope.
So assuming that there was no
big baby mix-up at the hospital,
I'm thinking that Christina
Adalian had to be a surrogate.
Surrogacy...
that would explain her hymen.
Hello.
Her hymen was intact,
which is consistent with
in-vitro fertilization.
Yeah, but there's one problem.
A surrogate's not supposed
to keep the baby.
The surrogate is supposed to be
a gestational carrier
who returns the child
to the biological parents
after it's
been born.
Yeah, that is a problem.
( knocking )
Hey, Gris.
I reviewed your videotapes.
Checked for insertions,
deletions, omissions.
They're all authentic.
You're certain?
Oh, yeah.
I de-interlaced the video,
checked the head switching,
the HBI-VBI
looked for in-out signals.
The tapes are clean.
Sorry.
Did you blow up the frames?
Yeah.
One every six hours.
They're in Layout,
when you're ready.
Okay.
WILLOWS:
Oh, hi, Archie.
Hey.
I just finished your eval.
And?
In the comments section, I noted
that if you had my job,
these evaluations
wouldn't be late.
Thank you.
So I understand that you're
going up against Mark Thayer.
The guy's an ass.
He used to be a
competent scientist.
We actually co-authored a paper
together ten years ago.
I believe greed has
gotten in his way.
Well, I've seen him
on the stand.
He manipulates evidence.
He manipulates people.
The public assumes
that scientists are ethical,
but many of us are no better
than politicians, evidently.
So do you think that Thayer
is presenting the jury
with faulty forensics?
I know he is.
I just don't know how.
Videotapes are clean.
The science appears sound.
How's your case going?
Huh. I don't know who killed
Christina Adalian,
I don't know
how she got pregnant
and I don't know the identity of
the baby's biological parents.
It's always good to know
what you don't know.
Sure, I know Duane.
He's a good boss.
I just hated
being cooped up
in an office building
all day.
He claims he gave
you his gun
several years back.
Yeah, sure. Why?
It was recently used
in a homicide.
Damn.
Well, I'm sorry.
So, the gun's
no longer in
your possession?
Lost the Colt in a poker game
years ago.
Do you remember
who you lost it to?
I was drunk
as a skunk.
Met these guys
at a bar.
Lost a small fortune
trying to keep up
with their raises.
Can you tell me anything
about the guy who won the gun?
Well, he's an older guy,
at least 50.
I remember guys
were calling him "Cy,"
but that wasn't
his real name.
He had this large mole
between his eyes.
"Cy," short
for "Cyclops"?
Yeah. I swear I thought
that thing was winking at me.
Thanks for your help.
No problem.
( both chuckle )
Oh, ducks.
That's a new decorating choice.
I now have to share this office
with the day shift supervisor.
She's got some kind of thing
for waterfowl.
What's up?
Warrick and I tracked down
Joey Adalian's birth
certificate.
Christina's named
as the mother,
father's unknown.
We also found another
document in her desk.
It's a registration form
for an organization
called Project Sunflower.
They find mothers
for abandoned embryos.
Abandoned embryos?
According to literature,
Project Sunflower believes that
every fertilized egg or embryo
is a baby from the moment it's
created in a laboratory dish.
Fertility clinics
freeze fertilized eggs
for their clients
undergoing
in-vitro fertilization.
Often, the clinics freeze more
eggs than they ultimately need.
And Sunflower tries
to find women willing
to gestate
and raise the leftovers?
Uh-huh.
Project Sunflower promotes
itself as doing God's work.
I knew a stripper who claimed
the exact same thing.
So, is there any chance
that you have a record
of the baby's
biological parents?
Not yet. But I do have
an address for Sunflower's
local chapter.
It's a tragedy.
There are over 400,000 embryos
currently in cryobank storage
in the United States.
Pre-born children
suspended in time.
If I understand your program
correctly,
you take these embryos
and you place them
in available wombs.
We seek out special
unselfish women
who are prepared
to adopt
at the embryonic stage
of development.
We believe that
the soul is infused
when sperm meets egg.
That's when life begins.
Are you aware
that throughout much of history,
the official church
position held that
a child's life
begins when the mother
first becomes aware of movement?
Oh, that's your opinion.
In the 16th century,
the Pope proclaimed
that embryos less than 40 days
old are not human.
That is not my opinion.
You've had an abortion,
Miss Willows?
Huh. No. Thank God
I decided not to
have one.
But we are not talking about me,
Dr. Ryan.
Are you a medical doctor?
I don't care
for that insinuation.
Oh, it's just a question.
I take it
that's a no?
I have a very busy afternoon.
What exactly can I do for you?
I have a question.
Do the biological parents
get to meet the embryo adopters?
Of course.
If you are going
to give up your
pre-born child,
you'd want to approve
of his or hers future
parents, right?
Uh, one of your
special women,
Christina Adalian,
was murdered.
We're going
to need the names
of her son's biological parents.
I am, I'm sorry to hear
about Christina.
I conducted her
intake interview personally.
A lovely woman.
Our records are confidential.
I'm sorry.
We can get a court order.
So get one.
♪ ♪
Ecklie said the tape
might be authentic.
Seems so.
Grissom, I don't know
what to do:
instruct the DA to offer
second degree?
I mean, I can't risk
letting this guy back
back out on the street
but to plead this out
after what he did
to someone I loved.
I need some guidance here.
I can't tell you what
to do, Sheriff.
No, you can't.
But you can tell me
where we stand.
What are you doing?
Circling blowflies.
Why?
'Cause dead flies tell no lies.
The signature
is definitely hers,
and you're right,
she wrote the note
under duress.
Have you been able
to analyze the ink?
Thin-layer chromatography tells
us the red dye is consistent
with a standard Coda pen.
But find the pen. I should
be able to match it to the note.
You can match ink?
I can match its flow.
What do you notice
about the ink?
Uneven distribution?
The pen socket
that holds
the ball in place
was askew.
( woman sobbing )
The cockeyed socket caused
ink disruption
as it flowed down to the paper.
The damaged socket
is quite common
in sheet-writing
instruments.
Lucky for us,
the uneven distribution
of the ink
will be unique
to the pen that
wrote the note.
Hey, Professor.
Looking good.
You know
how sometimes
fact is stranger than fiction?
Yeah.
Brass got the court order
for Joey Adalian's
biological parents:
a Kenli and Dan Johnson
in Seven Hills.
We also found
Christina's will.
Guess who she named
as Joey's guardians.
Kenli and Dan?
Excuse me.
You're right.
A single woman adopts
a leftover embryo
from an
infertile couple
and upon her death agrees
to give the child back
to its biological parents?
Who gave up the embryo
in the first place?
You happen to have an address
for this Mr. and Mrs. Johnson?
Let's go.
Oh, hey. How's The
Way of The Gun?
It was lost
in a poker game.
Did you get
the winner's name?
No, but he has a large mole
between his eyes
and his nickname's "Cy."
That's all I got,
so sorry.
Greg, never apologize
for doing your job.
Okay.
Dan and I were desperate
to have a child,
and the doctor said
our only hope was
in-vitro.
Where is your
husband now?
He...
He passed away.
Are you sure I can't
get you something?
No, thank you.
Thank you, Mom.
You're welcome, baby.
It's been almost a year.
We were coming home
from a movie
when we were
broadsided.
The guy kept going
and Danny
never woke up.
WILLOWS:
I'm so sorry.
Can I ask you...
did you ever
conceive a child?
My body kept
rejecting the procedure,
so we tried
three times
and then called
it quits.
Had you ever considered
a surrogate?
It's very expensive.
Danny just was never comfortable
with the notion that...
Well, we just figured
we weren't meant to be parents.
And that's why you decided
to give away your embryos.
Yeah, I had seen a flyer
at the clinic.
Are you aware that one of those
embryos was carried to term?
Dan and I pre-screened
Christina,
and we went to see
Joey and her once a month.
So that's why
when I got your call,
I just don't know who'd want
to hurt such a sweet girl.
According to Christina's will,
you were named Joey's guardian.
Yes, that was very important
to Christina.
She's not close
with any
of her family,
so I've already called
Child Services, and as soon
the lawyer reviews the will,
I'm supposed to pick him up.
Well, if you don't mind,
I'd like your permission
to take a look
at the clothing that you wore
two nights ago.
You can't possibly think
I had anything
to do with this?
It's protocol. The victim
was shot at close range.
I wore the white blouse.
We're going to need to take
all the laundry
back to our lab.
You never found the guy
who killed my husband,
and now you're wasting time
looking at my dirty clothes.
That's fine.
Take it.
Why did the fly, fly?
Because the spider spied her.
Catherine's daughter told me
that when she was three.
Do we have results?
Thank you.
Oh, hey, Ecklie said
you wanted to see me.
Yeah. A Dr. Ryan called and said
that you verbally harassed her?
I met Dr. Ryan in the course
of my investigation.
She runs an organization called
Project Sunflower.
Philosophically, I completely
disagree with the organization.
Perhaps I expressed myself.
Which means?
I'm pro-choice.
I'm in favor of stem cell
research.
I'm sorry she felt harassed,
but my comments were
in response to her statements.
I don't think I was out of line.
You should have cited
Leviticus 17:11.
"The life of the flesh
is in the blood."
Taken literally,
life doesn't begin
when the sperm meets the egg,
but 18 days later.
When the embryo is infused
with blood.
Is that your position?
Well, if I were speaking
with a woman
who prefers theology
to science,
it's a position
she'd find tough to refute.
So are we having a philosophical
discussion here,
or am I being reprimanded?
I don't know.
I got to go to court.
What?
Your white blouse.
The results are printing.
It seems like you
and Grissom
were having a fairly
intense conversation.
Can I ask...?
Tell me about the blouse,
please.
I ran the S.E.M. over
the adhesive disks
and confirmed
gunshot residue.
You found clothing
in a laundry basket
that tested positive
for gunshot residue.
So what?
That doesn't mean my client
killed anyone.
It proves that she fired a gun,
Carol.
I've never fired a gun.
I've never even touched a gun.
CAROL:
Catherine, I'm sorry,
but if I understand
your forensics,
the GSR test does not, in fact,
confirm that she fired a gun.
I mean, it's possible she rubbed
up against someone who did.
Theoretically.
I cared about Christina.
I'm sure that you did.
But looking into Joey's eyes
and seeing your husband,
must've torn you
up inside.
And the only person standing
between you and your baby
was the victim.
Okay, don't respond to that.
When was the last time you
actually saw Christina?
Two days ago. I took
them to lunch.
What were you doing
two nights ago,
around 11:00 p.m.?
I was home all night.
Can anyone verify that?
My mom lives with me,
but she wasn't home.
That's gin rummy night.
What's going on in there?
Kenli had nothing to do
with this.
Mrs. Walkey, I need your help.
Your daughter claims
that two night ago
she was home
watching television.
Can you confirm that?
Well, of course. I was with her.
Thank you.
If you had to guess,
what's Kenli's dress size?
Four, maybe six.
I found blood spatter
on this blouse. Size 12.
There're two women that live
at that house.
Only one is a size 12.
I don't need an attorney.
I've done nothing wrong.
Would you mind emptying
the contents of your purse?
First you go after Kenli,
now me.
A few hours ago, you guys
were saying
there was gunshot powder
on Kenli's blouse.
You make a mistake?
No, it was probably transferred
from your blouse,
the one that you wore
that night.
I have a warrant to search
your person
and your home.
Please empty the contents
of your purse onto the table.
A red Coda pen.
Joey...
is...
( sobbing )
better off...
...without me.
Please don't do this.
Oh, God, please.
Sign it.
Sign it!
You knew that her sister
was coming for a visit,
so the baby
would be okay.
You killed her
and then staged the scene.
( crying )
( baby cries )
You have a wild imagination,
Ms. Willows.
Is this your husband?
Arnold.
He passed away.
Two years ago, May.
He looks like a poker player.
You can tell that
from his photo?
Actually, it's...
the mole between his eyes
that's his tell.
Why are we talking about Arnie?
Because you used his gun.
The gun he won in a poker game.
Are you going to put me in jail?
That's how it works.
And the baby-- he goes
with Kenli, right?
I'm sure that Child Services
will follow
the dictates
of Christina's will.
Then it was all worth it.
My baby has her baby.
That's all that really matters.
Did you ever consider
that Christina Adalian
is somebody's baby?
We each protect our own.
That's how it's done.
Officer, would you please escort
Mrs. Walkey to lockup?
MAN:
As you can see, on day 14--
plenty of larvae,
commonly known as maggots,
but no puparia.
Finally on day 15,
you'll notice the puparia
swimming in the brown liquid.
Based on that evidence,
I can reliably conclude
that Joanna Whitson
was killed on November 1.
You're absolutely certain
of that timeline?
Yes.
Thank you.
No further questions.
Your witness.
We have no questions
for Dr. Thayer.
But I now call to the stand
Dr. Gil Grissom
as a rebuttal
expert witness.
JUDGE:
Dr. Thayer, you're dismissed.
Dr. Grissom, please approach
the stand to be sworn in.
Raise your right hand.
Do you swear
to tell the truth, the whole
truth, so help you God?
I certainly do.
You may be seated.
Dr. Grissom,
you've had a chance to review
Dr. Thayer's tape
and associated evidence,
is that correct?
Yes.
Do you agree with his finding
that Joanna Whitson
was murdered 15 days
before her body was discovered?
No.
Can you please elaborate?
Our crime lab analyzed
fly larvae
that was taken
from the pig
used by Dr. Thayer
in his demonstration.
Apparently, they digested
dimethyldithiophosphate
and T-mulz Light Aromatic.
A toxin commonly known
as malathion?
Yes.
I believe the malathion was
sprayed onto the pig's skin.
How would malathion affect
a fly's life cycle?
It would delay the time it takes
for puparia to appear.
Specifically, the malathion
would delay oviposition.
Oviposition?
Laying eggs.
Without malathion, adult flies
would immediately
lay new eggs on the pig's flesh.
But with malathion,
oviposition would be delayed
up to four days.
A four-day delay would mean
that Joanna Whitson died
on November 4, not November 1,
Is that correct?
Yes.
Is there any scientific
rationale
for spraying a pig
with malathion
before documenting
a fly's life cycle?
Objection.
Overruled.
The only rationale I can think
of would be jury manipulation.
Every entomologist knows
that early oviposition
is undetectable
because flies lay
their first round of eggs
inside body openings.
Anyone reviewing
the tape would assume
that the eggs were being laid,
when in fact they were not.
If our lab had not
tested the flies
for toxins,
we would never have known that.
Nor would the jury.
Thank you. No further questions.
Counselor, your witness.
Uh, we have no questions
at this time.
Oh, in that case,
we are adjourned
until 9:00 a.m.
tomorrow morning.
I want to talk to you.
I have nothing to say to you.
You impugned my character.
What character?
Uh, excuse me,
Dr. Thayer.
What the hell do you want?
Well, to inform you that you
have the right to remain silent.
The D.A.'s filing
charges for perjury
Oh, my God...
and obstruction of justice.
We won't be accepting
a plea.
This is all your fault.
I hope so.
Grissom.
Great work up there.
Actually, the work
was done in the lab.
When I took this job,
I heard
a lot of things about you.
If you ever need a favor,
if I can help you in any way...
You know Sheriff,
you could help me.
I'm late delivering my team's
personnel evaluations.
I'll tell Ecklie.
He'll backdate your
cost-of-living adjustments.
Thank you.
So, Grissom, I'm not sure
of your ambitions,
but if you're interested in
taking on more responsibility,
maybe a promotion,
I'd be glad to pass...
You know, Oscar
Wilde once said,
"Ambition is the last refuge
of failure." I'm fine. Thanks.