( tires screeching,
police sirens wailing )
( automatic guns firing )
These guys are hard core.
Who are they?
( gunfire continues )
Tell Control these guys
have automatic weapons!
Probably A-Ks!
With me!
Three-David-34,
be advised subjects
are firing
automatic weapons,
possibly AK-47s.
All right, we're coming up
on a T-intersection.
Get ready.
Three-Boy-Seven,
pursuit approaching
a T-intersection on Jefferson
and Third.
( gunshots )
OFFICER:
We're going
to get killed!
Not if you do what
you're supposed to do.
OFFICER:
Three-David-34,
suspect Caprice has T/C'd.
Intersection Jefferson
and Third.
When you get out,
keep your head down.
They're out of rifle ammo!
( screaming )
They're running.
I'm going left.
You go right.
Going to take these guys.
You guys, move on up.
Three-Boy-Seven in foot pursuit
of two male Latinos.
One east, one west
on Third Street.
Requesting backup.
OFFICER:
Three-David-34,
officer down.
Requesting immediate backup
and paramedics.
I'll stay with him.
I'll take care...
( sirens blaring )
Que paso?
Nada.
Adentro, adentro.
Cuff him.
Dame una ambulancia, puey.
I don't speak Spanish.
Back inside,
back inside.
You okay?
Yeah. You?
What are you doing?
Put it down.
Yeah, sorry.
I was just trying
to secure his gun.
He's not going
to use it anymore.
Stop! Police!
Don't move!
( metal clanging )
SOFIA:
Brass, suspect's in custody.
Copy.
Control, this is Brass.
Situation here is Code 4.
We have three suspects
in custody.
One is on the run.
You know it's going
to be a long shift
when you get the
call to respond
to a command post.
Yeah. Warrick...
we need everyone
from Grave.
But park
on Wall Street.
Jefferson's taped off
all the way back to Lincoln.
The suspect was last seen
running south.
These buildings have been
searched and cleared.
Okay, move south one block.
Check each apartment.
This guy's armed
and dangerous.
You got a lot of witnesses
claiming to have seen
what happened.
Okay, good. Let's get some vans
down here,
bring them all to the station.
What happened out here?
I was one of
the shooters.
So was Sofia,
so you know the deal.
That's really all
I'm allowed to say.
I see Detective Ortega
had a hard head
for my ass
handling the case
Just our luck.
DETECTIVE:
Caprice full of shooters
opened up
on two of our guys.
One's down.
Is Bell
going to make it?
He's DOA.
Three suspects
are dead.
Fourth outstanding.
Excuse me...
guys, hang tight.
I'm going to get
some rides.
Take you down
to the station, okay?
I want to get
your statements.
BRASS:
Yeah...
Yeah.
ORTEGA:
Good, good.
I'll stay with them.
I'll collect their
firearms and ammo.
All right.
Good luck.
Thank you.
Hell of a day, man.
It's just beginning.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really want to know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me
who are you, you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
OFFICER:
GSW victim
matches the suspect.
You shoot him?
No, sir.
Found him this way.
DETECTIVE:
Bike strap...
This isn't our suspect.
This is a kid on his way
to school.
Where's his bike?
There was no bike.
Put out a broadcast.
Suspect may be on a bicycle.
We need medical transport.
Code Three...
Okay, everybody around here
has got a video camera
or a cell phone camera.
They'll all be
taking pictures.
I think we all know
how to operate
in front of a camera.
Don't be caught
picking your nose.
GRISSOM:
Catherine's back
at the station,
collecting the
officers' guns.
This is the main crime scene.
So Nick, you and
Sara, take this.
There's two additional
crime scenes
down the alleys behind Third.
Warrick, you take
the west alley,
I'll take the east.
And what do I get to do?
Go back to the lab
and wait for a phone call?
This is a running gun battle
that started 20 blocks back.
You get that.
That's got to be, like, a mile?
Who's with me?
SARA:
A bunch of
pissed-off locals
with shot up cars.
Awesome.
WARRICK:
You'll be all right.
DAVID:
Grissom,
heard anything about Bell?
He died, David.
Is this gun
in its original position?
The arresting officers kicked it
clear of the suspect.
Nobody's touched it
since I've been here.
Well, there's
no bullet holes
in the back.
That's always good.
How many times was he hit?
I don't know.
Officer, can you remove
these handcuffs?
Sure.
You have anything I can wipe
these off with?
Yeah.
Thanks.
Looks like three went in.
All right, leave him here,
David.
Warrick's D.B.'s in
the other alley just over there.
You did a hell
of good job out there.
Yeah, not good enough.
Has Bell's wife
been notified?
The Sheriff's on his way
to the house now.
BRASS:
You know, she's pregnant
with their third kid.
We all know the risks.
Hey...
( sighing )
I remember
my first shooting...
I appreciate the sentiment.
( whispering ):
We're not supposed to talk
to each other
till we give our statements.
You're right,
you're right
You're up.
Curtis, make yourself
comfortable.
Okay.
This is Detective
Nestor Ortega.
I am in PD Interrogation
taking a statement
from Captain James Brass
regarding the officer-involved
shooting
that occurred around 0643
hours this morning.
CSI Catherine Willows
is present to document
and collect
Captain Brass's firearm
as evidence.
Ready?
Yeah.
You're not a patrol unit.
Why did you get involved
in the pursuit?
Detective Curtis
and I were just closing
a robbery case
and, uh, we stopped
for a bite to eat.
DISPATCHER:
... all units in the vicinity.
Three-David-34 is in pursuit
of a dark Chevy Caprice
southbound on Paradise
toward Desert Springs.
That's right near here.
We joined the pursuit
on Desert Springs.
So you elected to back up
the officers.
Yes.
Were the suspects
shooting at the time?
Yes.
Could you tell the types
of firearms they were using?
Well, the two guys in the back
had rifles,
maybe AK's.
The other two had handguns.
I'm not sure what type.
REPORTER:
We're flying
over Third Street
where just this morning,
police were involved
in a deadly shootout.
Looks like a porcupine.
There's not enough room
between rods
for a human being to fit.
No, Bell and Adams
must have really been
swerving and weaving.
78 bullet holes.
And Bell wasn't hit
until he was outside the car.
I heard Bell was a rookie,
barely off training.
It was just his time,
I guess, huh?
Suspect will be
getting a ride
with the coroner.
A little
street justice.
Civilians okay?
Some old lady's
going to need stitches.
The kid on the bike's
critical in surgery.
You guys okay here?
I'll call and have the suspect's
vehicle towed to CSI.
I'm going to start digging
bullets out of people's houses.
I was just reloading
and continuing firing.
I don't know what hit him.
( gunshots )
Bullets were flying.
There were multiple rounds.
It was chaos.
At what point did Carolyn Davis
go in foot pursuit
after the two
suspects?
After the driver went down,
the other suspect,
I guess he felt
it was getting
too hot back there.
And they were shooting
the entire time?
Oh, yeah. I mean, it was like,
you know, those movie guns;
they never run out of bullets.
I don't go to the movies.
Oh.
What happened next?
The next thing I remember...
the next thing I remember
is Bell.
Bell went down.
( gunshot )
He was...
he was just a kid.
MAN:
Todo lo que vi fue la policia
disparando!
MAN 2:
Yo ohi que uno de ellos
ya se habia calmado cuando
le metieron un balazo!
Are they saying
what I think they're saying?
"Policia hirieron
esos muchachos en la espalda"?
Yeah. They claim they saw
the cops shoot the suspects
in the back.
Hey, not to mention
there's an innocent kid
in the hospital.
See? Another
one they killed!
Where's his gun!
CAVALIERE:
Hey, let us do
our job here, okay?
WOMAN:
Mi hija vio a sus policias
disparle a un nino
en la espalda.
Senora, donde esta
su hija, huh?
Queremos hablar con ella.
La policia se la llevo.
Usted vio algo de lo que paso?
No?
Nobody saw anything.
I don't think
this is police issue.
Look, these folks were
suspicious of the cops
long before this happened.
Now this is now your circle
stories get started.
The story keeps changing
till you don't know
what the truth is
or whose story
it was to begin with.
So, uh, so the suspects saw
that we were kind of distracted
helping Bell, and they took
the opportunity.
I went on foot pursuit,
you know.
They, uh... I can't run as fast
as I used to,
I mean,
so I lost them.
But that's when I heard
the two shots.
No, I heard shots coming from...
the east.
How many?
Three.
OFFICER:
Get down!
( four gunshots )
Four.
And they sound
a lot louder
than a nine-millimeter.
The suspect had a gun
in his hand.
Oh, yeah, definitely.
I kicked it away
when I cuffed him.
Did you fire any shots
in the alley?
I didn't have to.
Captain, hand over your firearm
to CSI Willows.
Any magazines?
Uh...
I must have used them..
WILLOWS:
Captain Brass's service pistol
was received
with an empty magazine
and one live round
in the chamber.
Well...
It'd be smart to have ammo
before you go running
into a gunfight.
I didn't find any
cartridge casings
in this alley
from the dead guy's gun.
Just these three
nine-millimeters from our cop.
So he must have
been out of ammo.
Yeah, but he had to know that
he'd get shot holding a gun
whether it was loaded or not.
Why didn't
he just toss it?
Maybe he didn't know he was out.
Heat of the battle.
I mean, we're not talking
rocket scientists.
That doesn't make him suicidal,
though, does it?
Officer Adams,
I'm sorry for your loss.
If you'd like a few minutes
to say good-bye...
Okay, partner...
I guess I was pretty
rough on you.
Maybe not rough enough.
You're the best rookie
I ever trained.
I have to leave you now.
I'll, uh, I'll talk to Tracy.
Try to make her understand.
Drop in on the kids.
You were a good cop.
CAVALIERE:
Geraldo Zamesca.
High school football star.
Full scholarship to USC.
Got a bullet
lodged in his spine
Condition's critical.
Can we get the bullet?
Not unless his condition
improves or he dies.
SWAT guys going
house-to-house
breaking down doors.
They're the ones
who found him.
They were going to
blame us for this, too.
CSI's processed
the scene?
Not much to process.
Some blood stains
off the ground
Nine-millimeter
cartridge case.
Cops are shooting nines.
Guilty until
proven innocent.
DANILO:
This is my wife,
Geraldo's mother.
We want nothing
but the best
for our son.
That means we will
decide if you go in
and get the bullet,
not the police.
DANILO:
You got that?
Kid's family?
Yeah.
Danilo Zamesca,
a local business man
that lives in the 'hood,
but dines uptown.
( camera shutter clicking )
WOMAN:
Perro porque la policia
le disparo aqui nuestra casa?
Nosotros no hicimos nada.
Porque la policia
nos disparo?
I-I'm sorry.
I don't speak Spanish.
Que... no entiende, que...
Nos hubiera matado.
Die algo para que ella
entienda.
She wants to know why
our house got shot at.
I don't have the answer to that.
I'm sorry.
Es que usted no me puede
decir nada?
No vio lo que hicieron?
Que si fueran mis hijos?
Que voy hacer
sin mis hijos?
( sobbing )
So, what do you think
that is?
Well, it's not blood,
it's not rust.
Where did Grissom
find that?
In an alley off Third.
'Cause see, those
scrapes and gauges
look like road rash.
Like when you toss a gun
out of a moving car.
You'd be the one
to know about rashes.
That's my brother, man!
What'd he do?!
My baby! My baby!
You killed my son!
My baby!
You cops murdered my son!
Miss,
You murdered my son!
calm down, okay?
I'm sorry for your loss.
I'm with the crime lab.
Talk to one
of the detectives. Miss...
I don't need to!
Look, police brutality!
He's hitting me!
Can I get some backup
here, please?
Now you want my other son, huh?
Is that what you want?
I just want
to do my job here.
What, lie
for the police department?
Can we lock this place up
and move that crime tape
down another block?
OFFICER:
Officer Mitchell,
come into the west alley.
Bring two uniforms
with you.
These people think if they catch
us doing something wrong,
they sue and win the lottery.
Yeah. We don't do
anything wrong,
we got nothing
to worry about.
My son should be
in school today.
He should be
playing football.
Instead, he's lying
in a hospital bed.
Why?
Because the cops decided
to shoot first
and ask questions later.
Anybody remember the last time
the police had a running
gun battle down the Strip?
No? That's 'cause
it's never happened.
Summerlin? Never.
Seven Hills?
No way.
But down here, hey..
( sobbing )
My son, Geraldo,
was a good boy.
He was a great
football player.
Fearless out there.
He had a chance
to do something
with his life.
To be better
than his father.
And now...
I may outlive my son.
Because the police shot him
before he could tell them
who he was.
Before he could tell them
he was an honor student.
I want to invite everybody here
who cares about
what happens in the community
to come to Queen of Angels
tonight, 6:00 p.m.,
to pray for Geraldo's life.
And I want to say
out loud, right now,
to Sheriff Burdick,
this will not stand.
You, sir,
will be held to answer.
I mean it.
I'm not going away.
A police spokesman confirms
that department officials
are looking into all allegations
of brutality
and misconduct.
Sheriff Burdick could not be
reached for comment.
Here is what we know so far...
Nobody gives a crap
about a dead officer.
I don't see them
lighting candles for Bell.
...this morning
with a car chase.
The pursuit ended
in a shootout
at Jefferson and 3rd Street
between a heavily armed suspects
and police.
WILLOWS:
Detective Curtis'
service pistol was received
with one magazine containing
three live rounds
and one live round
in the chamber.
During the gun battle,
were you aware
of the other officers positions
relative to you?
They were in front of me
and... and to my right.
No, my left.
Did you continue to be aware
of their positions
after the suspect
took off running?
( gunfire )
Uh...
Bell was in front of me...
but he was down
behind his car.
Do you remember Officer Bell
being shot?
Um...
S-Sorry, what was the question?
I asked if you remember
Officer Bell being shot.
Do you need a moment here?
No, no, that's
all right.
She's going to do just fine.
Uh...
Make sure you check Bell's vest.
I think he took one
in the chest.
Detective Ortega, Catherine,
can you step out
for a moment?
We're not done.
So how are we doing
on the suspect
that got away?
Jose Fausto.
Identified through
prints in the car.
He's got a long rap sheet.
Dogs lost his scent.
SWAT guys checked
the building-- nothing.
Gang unit's beating the bushes.
Word on the street is
we shot two unarmed men
and a high school kid.
We got I.D.'s
of all three dead suspects.
Multiple felonies,
drugs, immigration violations.
They're all members
of the 18th Street Chucos.
Also driving
a stolen car
shooting automatic
weapons
at a police car.
These guys aren't
exactly altar boys.
West alley, I got eye-witnesses
saw po-po plant the gun.
East alley, I got an old lady
who swears
she saw Ricardo Estevez
with his hands raised
before he was killed.
These witnesses credible?
I don't know.
Listen,
if the suspects
don't have guns
in their hands,
we can't shoot them.
Well, let's not get ahead
of the evidence.
CAVALIERE:
Okay, one more thing.
The family of Leandro Chavez
is suing the department
for wrongful death.
Claims we delayed
treatment.
Medium caliber bullet--
transected the
femoral artery.
Major artery. Fatal wound.
( gunshot )
( screaming )
Take a look. What's missing?
All of the organs
seem to be in the right place.
Look closer.
Okay.
Kidneys are...
a bit pale.
Liver is light tan.
Right.
Not a lot of blood.
Dead at the scene.
He bled out.
Bingo.
The wound was not
immediately fatal.
It took a while.
This is going to look bad.
David, it is what it is.
Why did you leave
a downed officer?
Sergeant Adams told me he had
the situation under control.
So I went
to back up Officer Davis,
who ran off in...
this direction.
I caught up with him here.
( click )
Davis' slide was locked back.
He was out of ammo.
So the suspect had a gun
pointed at Officer Davis.
Of course.
That was why I fired.
100% sure?
Yes.
What did you do next?
What are you doing?
Put it down.
Yeah, sorry. I was just trying
to secure his gun.
Okay, he's not going
to be using it anymore.
Officer Davis was acting
on survival instinct,
not training.
It was understandable
under the circumstances.
I don't think so.
Want a ride?
No, I'm just going
to go home.
You sure?
Yeah.
( sliding click )
Okay, the first
communication
I received
from Three-David-34
was at 06:43:37.
This is Three-David-34
requesting immediate backup.
New suspect vehicle
Adam-Robert-Charlie-208, Nevada,
dark Chevy Caprice,
four suspects.
Suspects are armed.
WOMAN:
Copy, Three-David-34.
What did Bell mean by
"new suspect vehicle"?
Can you take it back
to the last communication
before that call?
Control, this is Three-David-34.
We'll be 487, 12000 block
of Roosevelt
on David-Nora-Charlie-130,
Buick Regal.
WILLOWS:
A 487
is a traffic stop.
You were pulling over
a Buick?
That's correct.
Why'd you leave the Buick
and start following the Caprice?
Didn't leave the Buick.
The Caprice cut in.
( siren wailing )
Why'd he do that?
Don't know.
The next thing I know,
we were taking fire.
Forgot all about the Buick.
WILLOWS:
Did you see
where it went?
I was kind of busy.
Hey, you done yet?
Grissom, am I
on overtime?
Of course.
Did everyone else go home?
No.
Good to know.
Well, I finished
about ten blocks so far.
That's 98
cartridge cases.
Let's see-- double L,
A to Z's 26,
That's 38 bullet impacts.
Good.
Pursuit started ten blocks
farther down.
You're halfway done.
I've got like three or four
hours more work left.
Can I have some help?
Everybody's busy.
I think you missed one.
( phone ringing )
Grissom.
Hey.
I just interviewed
Sergeant Adams.
He and Bell were making
a routine traffic stop
when the Caprice cut in.
The initial vehicle was a...
A Buick?
I hate it when you do that.
Lucky guess.
I'll call you back.
How'd you know that hubcap
was connected to the case?
I'm a trained
observer, Greg.
No, really.
How long do you think a
perfectly good hubcap like this
would sit around out here?
There's a freeway
on-ramp
about two blocks away.
Check and see if there's
any traffic cams
between here and there.
You know, you scare me
sometimes.
It's kind
of freaky.
You ever bet
on the ponies?
I prefer poker.
Horses are hard to control.
Make sure you document
these skid marks.
He said "skid marks."
( snickering )
( gunshot )
Oh-ho-ho! Yeah!
That's what I'm talking about.
I got over firing AK's
a long time ago.
Hey... Mustache Boy,
come over here
and check this out.
Get a load of that.
Whoa.
What are the chances
of that happening?
Like one in a million.
The bullet jammed
this cylinder.
You know, I couldn't clear
this gun at the scene.
I should've noticed
these bullet fragments.
I guess I got distracted.
Well, the bullet had to come
from Officer Davis's pistol...
but if you're the suspect,
don't you know
your gun's getting hit?
I think it would have felt
like a normal recoil.
Besides, it was like
the Wild West
out there.
You don't have to tell me;
I know it was crazy out there.
You know, I pulled 78 bullets
out of one car.
Davis just got lucky.
This suspect had
one live round left.
It saved Davis's life.
Well, there you go.
Proves he was pointing the gun
at the officer.
See you in court;
stroke one up for the good guys.
We still have to place it
in Rosario's hand.
( woman sniffles )
This is, uh, Gil Grissom
from the Crime Lab.
This is Officer Bell's wife.
Mrs. Bell, I'm so
sorry about the loss
of your husband--
he was a fine man.
( sobs )
( sobbing )
Why are they crying?
McKEEN:
Um, why don't I
drive you home.
They're crying for the man
that killed my husband.
What did you say?
You heard me.
If you did a better job
of raising your son,
I wouldn't be here.
Don't you tell me
how to raise my children!
You should be ashamed!
( man shouting in Spanish )
How dare you!
( gunshot )
You run the gauntlet?
Yeah.
Ferro-tracing his hands?
I'm trying to prove Rosario here
held the gun.
Good old
pyridyldiphenyl triazine.
I'm hoping this stuff reacts
to the traces of iron
that may have been
left on his skin.
It'll further
refute any argument
that the gun
was a plant.
GRISSOM:
That could be the back strap
of a gun.
Yeah. That would do it.
Detective,
do you have a moment?
Uh, yeah, I'm kind
of busy-- what is it?
I picked up a junkie
for possession,
outside a fleabag motel
off Fremont.
And what?
And... last night,
he spotted your shooter.
Let's talk to him.
You know this guy?
What if I do?
What'll it get me?
He's a cop killer.
Gets you nothing.
Hey, no need
to get hostile.
Hey, man, you don't
know what hostile is.
Will it at least
get me a ride home?
( quietly ):
Come on...
Okay, okay.
I-I do a lot of business
at the Lucky Seven Motel.
And that guy checked in
last night.
He scored a little something
to help get him some sleep.
But he didn't pay.
He just flashed his piece.
Nine-millimeter?
Yeah.
He wanted a... a girl,
and I gave him a number.
That dude's bad news.
I want to give him to you.
Glad you're here.
I'd like to get this
one off my table.
Found a rather large
contusion on the left chest
just below the nipple.
Well, that location
is consistent
with the bullet Catherine found
embedded in his vest.
It's like getting
kicked by a mule.
You'll want to see this.
Through-and-through.
Entrance wound just
below his left ear,
exited below
and to the front
of his right ear, severing
the right common carotid.
( gunshot )
( gasps, grunts )
That's your C.O.D.
Fortunately,
he never felt a thing.
Left to right, back to front.
Mm-hmm.
Only cops were shooting
in that direction.
Are you saying Bell was hit
by friendly fire?
Maybe not so friendly.
Who's in the room?
Some john, I don't know.
Shh!
Is that him?
Mm-hmm.
I couldn't wait
to get out of there.
He was acting real nervous.
Now I know why.
I took care of him;
he's asleep.
So you're not gonna
bust me, right?
Take her out of here.
( officers shouting )
Police! Let me see your hands!
Do it now!
Get on the floor!
Down!
That's our guy.
He's carrying a nine.
MAN:
Clear.
We'll run this gun
against the cartridge case
from the poor kid on the bike.
I'm guessing you didn't
save up for that one, huh?
( two gunshots)
( yells )
You shoot an innocent kid in
the back just to take his bike?
You piece of crap!
Get up!
Hey, you're gonna wish
you kept running.
They hate cop killers
in Vegas,
you hear me? Huh?
Come on, let me get
dressed up first, huh?
We got a jumpsuit
just your size, don't worry.
( indistinct conversations )
( gunshot )
( Fausto yells )
Down! Everybody down! Down!
Where did that come from?