( tires screeching )
( garbled radio transmission )
BRASS:
A truck driver making
a delivery found him.
T.O.D.?
About two or three
hours ago.
GRISSOM:
Neck contusion.
Looks like he went down
fighting.
GRISSOM:
Any ID?
Just this.
Palermo room key.
Nice clothes.
Well, they do make the man.
He's got some kind
of transfer on his pants.
WILLOWS:
Yeah, and on his shirt.
So what's a guy dressed
for a party
with a key to this hotel
doing out here?
I don't know.
But the party's over.
♪ ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
Got smudges that look
like white paint up here.
Similar to the trace
on the vic's clothes.
Same down here.
So whatever it is,
it must have been wet.
I don't see any
wet paint signs up here either.
( crowd murmuring )
MAN:
Two performances nightly
of Palermo's fabulous show,
"The Girls of India."
Now on display
at Palermo Jewelers--
Diamonds at Romanoff's.
The room is registered
to a Jeffrey Powell
of Van Nuys, California.
He check in
with anybody?
No. The reservation
was for one person.
He checked in yesterday,
paid with a
corporate credit card.
Do you remember
the name of the company?
Sheritown Inc.
We're going to need access
to all of the surveillance
footage from tonight, all right?
You got it.
Okay.
Two glasses.
Think our vic got lucky?
Oh, yeah.
He got lucky, all right.
He got lucky
with a blonde.
Jeans...
full of holes.
Must have been wearing
them a long time.
Either that or he just bought
them an paid a fortune.
I remember my first time
to Vegas.
I got one of these--
Guide to blackjack.
Everybody dreams of hitting it
big out here, don't they?
Yeah, well, if that ever ends
you can kiss Vegas good-bye.
STOKES:
We have a winner.
Jackpot.
Ooh, Sasan.
Cost him more than all of his
other clothes put together.
There's some kind
of blue powder trace
on the pocket.
Nicky, take this.
California driver's license.
Company credit card.
Amateur Speedway Association
card.
Guy liked fast cars.
Except he was driving
a Toyota.
No cash.
This sounds like
a classic trick roll.
Kid from out of town
on a lucky streak--
I cannot lose tonight!
he's an easy mark.
Get him up to the room...
loosen him up...
jump him and dump him.
Mom was right--
always wear
clean ones.
Because you never know
what could happen.
What do you think that is?
Why don't you take a whiff?
Why am I always the guy
who has to sniff the shorts?
'Cause it's your job.
You do it.
Red wine.
It's not on his pants.
What about the shirt?
No.
So he must have changed
after the mess.
Oh, I already went through
his pockets.
Of course, I was double-gloved.
Clothes are brand new.
Hmm...
Looks like a callus.
STOKES:
There's a long-haired blonde.
Yeah, I've been watching this
for a while now.
Time stamped 10:52 p.m.
He entered his room
a couple of minutes later.
Manager said the last time
he used his card key
was 10:54 p.m.
MAN:
We look forward
about an hour...
Jeff leaves his room alone.
STOKES:
He doesn't have
a jacket on.
He's probably not
going too far.
So he gets off the elevator,
goes into the casino,
and nine minutes
later,
same blonde goes down
in the elevator.
Mm-hmm.
Grab that.
Print that.
After the vic
gets off the elevator,
I lose him in
the casino crowd
for about 15 minutes.
How do you lose him?
Aren't there a hundred
cameras in there?
And at four hours
of video each,
that's 400 hours of video
I got to go through.
The vic was found
at the loading dock
off the shopping arcade.
He's heading for
the arcade here.
That's the last time
I've got him on camera.
There's no surveillance
in the arcade hall.
Only in the individual stores.
Freeze that.
Enhance that bag.
The vic was wearing
a Sasan jacket.
There's a Sasan boutique
in the arcade.
I'm going shopping.
But you were working
last night.
Yeah, we've been
short-handed.
Do you, uh, do you
recognize either one
of these people?
No. Sorry.
How about this?
Recognize that?
Sure. That's from
the new Spring line.
The leather's like skin.
It's incredible.
Show me that picture again.
Now I remember.
He bought
a whole outfit.
Even wanted underwear.
We don't sell underwear.
Credit card receipt,
anything like that?
He paid cash.
He was flashing a wad.
Mm-hmm. Buy
anything for her?
Nothing.
She didn't need anything.
Looked perfect.
Was making my job
real easy.
That guy would have
bought anything
she wanted him
to, Mr. Stokes.
Thank you.
I found extensive contusion
involving the anterior
aspect of the neck
with hemorrhage
in all the strap muscles.
The thyroid, cricoid
and arytenoid
cartilages are all
multiply fractured.
The hyoid bone
is fractured as well.
The blunt-force trauma
to the neck?
Yeah. COD is asphyxiation
due to obstruction
of the airway.
Took a few minutes
to die.
Any idea of the source
of the BFT?
Well, I enhanced the contusion
on the neck
using UV photography.
Looks like there's a defined
edge on the weapon.
Yeah, that could be anything.
How about prelim tox results?
Well, tox detected
methamphetamine, sildenafil
and oxycodone.
Stimulant, erection
and a painkiller.
Party in a pill.
Where was that
on my wedding night?
( siren wailing )
SANDERS:
Does this couple look familiar?
Sweet red Ferrari.
F-360 Spyder.
When did you see them?
Last night-- I brought
the car when they left.
Around 8:15.
They're gone
a couple hours.
The car-- pfft--
was amazing.
Did they happen to tell you
where they were going?
No.
Do you know what time
they got back to the hotel?
Uh, a little after 10:00.
The guy gave me
a Benjamin.
I kept an eye out
on that baby,
I didn't want any of
these other maniacs
putting their paws on it.
What about the girl?
You ever seen her before?
I don't think so.
She strike you
as a working girl?
I'll say this,
if she was hooking,
then she was top shelf,
just like that car.
I felt kind of like
that garage guy
in Ferris Bueller's
Day Off?
You know, he likes
the car so much,
he takes it out for a spin
for, like, the whole day.
Not that I'd ever do that.
Of course not.
Whoa, look,
I had nothing to do
with the damage
on that car.
I mean, it was pristine
before they took it out.
They were in an accident?
How bad?
Look, any scratch on
that beauty is a tragedy.
And this was, like, a dent.
You know what? They looked
like they didn't even care.
Anything else
I can do for you?
Um, thanks.
Lenny.
Lenny Andretti.
No relation.
The trace for your
vic's jacket pocket
was primarily talc.
Blue baby powder?
No. Take a look.
Birefringent crystals.
Pretty.
What are they?
It's a mixture of
silica and axolite,
two abrasives.
But when found with talc,
it suggests only one use.
And that would be?
In 1897,
William Spinks received a patent
for what came to be known
as "Spinks Billiard Chalk."
You may be surprised to know
that cue-tip chalk
does not contain chalk at all,
it is a mixture of
axolite and silica.
The abrasives give grip to
the tip when it hits the ball.
Stop trying to make
that sound dirty.
Out vic had a callus
on his hand.
Mm...
Don't.
Which means that
he was probably playing
a lot of pool.
Where do you go in this town
to shoot stick
with a hot blonde and a Ferrari?
BRASS:
There's at least a half a dozen
of these high-end pool halls
in Vegas.
The word on the street is
a lot of out-of-town money
comes through here.
WILLOWS:
Well, it's closer to Palermo,
it's a good place to start.
Hey, buddy, how's it going?
Have these two been in lately?
No.
It's pretty dark in here,
wouldn't recognize my own mom
if she came in.
It wasn't so dark
you couldn't count your vig
from that game over there.
It's not illegal to bet
on a pool game in Nevada.
But it is illegal for
the house to take a cut
without
a gaming license.
I don't see one
on the wall.
That's because nothing
like that's going on here.
BRASS:
So, if we asked everyone
in here, no one would say
that you're taking
a piece of the action?
Let me take another look.
Sure. Knock yourself out.
I never seen the guy.
Girl's kind of a regular here.
Name's Heidi.
So, I guess your eyes
do get used to the dark.
You know where
we can find this Heidi?
Oh, man...
BRASS:
You know, I don't see
that license anywhere.
Look, here's what
we're going to do.
Get on the phone.
Call Heidi.
Tell her a distinguished
gentleman has just come in
with a large wad of cash
looking for some action.
That'd be me.
Heidi Wolff?
How you doing?
I'm Jim Brass,
Las Vegas Police.
Can I talk to you
for a minute?
About what?
Do you know this guy?
No.
Apparently,
you think I do.
Oh, I know you do.
You want to tell me
how he turned up dead?
So you spent the night
with Jeff Powell.
And he was alive
when he left me.
Oh. He left you?
Yeah. Believe it or not.
Look.
He was getting
kind of weird on me.
Hey.
Where you going?
Don't worry, I'll be right back.
You know, I think I may just
have to fall in love with you.
So I put on my clothes
and I got out of there.
I was looking for fun,
not a lifetime
commitment.
Is that what you call fun?
Rolling a guy,
taking his money?
I didn't take his money.
Heidi, Heidi, ho.
Look, we know Jeff was waving
around a large wedge of cash.
And the money was gone
when we found him.
You're an expensive date, Heidi.
I'm a professional gambler.
Probably the only one in Vegas
who declares every dollar.
You can check my tax returns.
We checked
the hotel sheets.
We had sex.
Is that against the law? No.
No.
We won some money shooting pool.
Is that against the law? No.
You gave him drugs.
Is that against the law?
Yeah.
Look, here's
the way I see it
breaking down.
You left the room
nine minutes after he did.
You went downstairs.
You checked
with your partner.
You killed the kid,
you took the cash,
end of story.
Let's get this straight.
He was a sweet kid
and I'm sorry he's dead,
but I had nothing to do with it.
And I'm done talking.
SANDERS:
According to the DMV,
of the 12 Ferrari F-360 Spyders
registered in Vegas,
only three are red.
Two of them are privately owned,
and a rental company
has the third.
Since the vic owns a Toyota
in L.A.
and Heidi Wolff
drives a Beetle...
You figured this would be
a good place to start.
Welcome to
Extravagant Auto.
Robert Rhoda.
If what you're dreaming
about's on four wheels,
I can get it for you.
Actually, we're looking
for a red Ferrari Spyder.
The lady likes fast cars.
And I just happen
to have one.
But it got into
a little fender-bender,
so it's going to take a day
or so to get it fixed.
We'll take it as is.
Looks like paint transfer
on the left rear quarter.
Clear coat's been peeled
front-to-back.
Which means the Ferrari was
the faster vehicle.
The Ferrari is always
( camera clicks )
Ooh.
Nice dent
to the front bumper.
RHODA:
You're looking at $15,000
of damage there.
Who rented it?
Can't help you with that.
Our customer records
are confidential.
In any case, we're not making
a police report
about the damage.
No need to,
we're impounding it.
( car door opens )
What?
Looks like the interior's
been cleaned.
I'll call auto transport
and have them tow it
back to the lot.
( camera phone beeping )
Mr. Rhoda, what are you doing?
I'm documenting my loss.
I'm filing for crime victim
compensation.
( camera phone beeping )
( machine whirrs )
Grissom?
Hodges confirmed
the paint transfer
on the Ferrari is
a black acrylic enamel.
That doesn't
narrow it down much.
Well, it gets better.
It's a GM paint,
with traces
of fiberglass
reinforced plastic.
Which means, we're looking
for a black Corvette.
I'll have Brass
put out a broadcast.
Nick ran the vic's
credit card.
"Sheritown, Inc." is
based in L.A.,
run by a guy named
Mick Sheridan.
I'm going to meet him
at the P.D.
Mick Sheridan
the movie producer?
I grew up watching
his action blockbusters--
car chases, ninjas,
cyborg death machines.
We used to make
body armor
out of tinfoil, and
re-enact the scenes
all over
the neighborhood.
What about you, you were
a Green Beret kid?
Secret agent?
I'm not telling.
And stay away
from my tinfoil.
( siren wails )
I'm sick about this.
Of all kids.
Jeff.
I can't stop crying.
You want something to drink?
Oh, thanks, uh...
Small Pellegrino,
room temperature.
POLICEMAN:
Sure thing.
( office door opens, closes )
Mr. Sheridan, can you tell us
anything about this girl?
I don't know her.
Jeff must have
met her here.
I loved him
like a son.
Smart.
Hard-working.
I hired him right
out of law school.
What kind of work
did he do for you?
An assistant.
He wanted to learn
the movie business
from the bottom up,
like I did.
Oh, right,
you used to be an actor.
Yeah. But I had a nasty habit--
I wanted to eat regularly.
And didn't want to work
as a waiter to do it.
Did Jeff have any
nasty habits?
We found several different
drugs in his bloodstream.
BRASS:
What was Jeff doing
in Las Vegas?
Um... About a month ago,
when he was making copies
of my divorce settlement,
he spotted a provision
that my wife's lawyer
had rephrased.
My lawyers
had missed it.
He saved me
millions of dollars.
So to thank him,
I gave him a vacation.
You give him any cash?
Couple hundred bucks,
corporate credit card.
Told him to have fun.
Fun, huh?
Yeah.
I'll be regretting that
for the rest of my life.
I guess the
broadcast paid off.
Black Corvette.
Parking enforcement
found it abandoned
off Durango near Russell.
Right between the pool hall
and the Palermo?
Yup.
( camera shutter clicking )
This would have been impossible
to drive away.
Yeah.
Bummer.
Please tell me there's
something more to this
guys and cars thing
beside the obvious penis
extension metaphors.
So you want me to lie?
Red paint transfer.
( engine revving )
( brakes screeching )
I'll get a sample to Hodges.
See if he can
match it to the Ferrari.
It's a rental.
Extravagant Automobiles?
No. Zenith?
Yeah, night to be
in the car rental business.
Driver's name is Randy Bolen.
Local address.
Let's go talk to him.
( distant siren )
"Randy Bolen.
"Misdemeanor
possession, assault,
"felony possession
for sales..."
You can't help
but break the
law, can you?
What's with the forehead?
Well, you got
that bruise somehow.
Want me to add leaving the scene
of an accident to the list?
It was a fender bender.
Not my fault.
Sure about that?
Yeah.
Because your car and the Ferrari
were both rented.
So what? It's a coincidence.
You're a local.
Why did you need to rent a car?
I can't afford one all the time,
so I rent one when I can.
What were you doing all night
before your fender bender?
What was I doing?
I was shooting pool.
Place called The... The Cue-T.
How'd you play?
Did you win any money?
You know, you win some,
you lose some.
( applause and cheering )
I guess that would be lose some.
How much?
Ten grand.
That's a lot of money
for a guy like you.
( scattered laughing
and clapping )
I've had worse nights.
( Curtis laughs )
Yeah, I'm sure you have.
You're having one now.
These the guys you played?
Yeah.
Now, there's a coincidence,
because they were
in the Ferrari,
which makes you
a very sore loser.
( engine revving )
( thudding )
( brakes screeching )
( tires squealing )
Okay.
So I rubbed him a little.
It was a stupid thing to do.
Not as stupid as killing him.
What, that kid-- he's dead?
Yeah.
I want a lawyer.
According to
his record,
Randy Bolen used to be a
professional stunt driver.
Must not have been
a very good one.
He teaches at that
track off Boulder Highway
where middle-aged guys get
to act out their
Grand Prix fantasies.
Mm-hmm, okay.
A guy like that gets beat
by a punk kid on the street,
it's gonna be an assault
on his manhood.
He's got a temper.
Okay. I'll see
if I can place him at the hotel.
I'll let you know.
Hey, Arch.
Hey.
Surveillance footage
from the Palermo?
Yeah.
I just found something
really interesting.
That's the blonde
from the elevator.
There she is again.
And here's Jeff Powell.
This is where his
evening begins,
when he meets her
for the first time.
( beeps )
Ooh.
She didn't look too happy.
Yeah.
Keep watching
when she points
at something.
Keep your eyes
on her wine.
( beeps )
You think that was on purpose?
Well, sure looks that way.
Take a look
at this.
( whirring, beep )
Girl was loaded.
It's safe to say she wasn't
after him for his money.
Hey.
Warrants came through
on the rental agreements.
Jeff Powell went a little crazy
with his corporate card
and rented the Ferrari himself?
No. Heidi Wolff rented it.
The reservation was held
in her name
by a company called
Caprice Unlimited.
This is where
it gets interesting.
Caprice Unlimited also rented
Randy Bolen's Corvette.
What kind of business is it?
All I know so far is that
they're unlisted.
Well, nothing's entirely
unlisted these days.
Caprice Unlimited.
Mm-hmm.
( beep )
"Caprice Unlimited."
"Anything is possible."
Sounds like a sex business.
What are you going to say?
Uh, something other than,
"A guy is dead, and it looks
like you're involved."
MALE VOICE ( on phone ):
You've reached
Caprice Unlimited.
Leave a message;
we shall call you.
Not taking calls.
Let's see if they're making any.
( computer whirring )
Triangulation's
consistent.
Caprice Unlimited
made the calls
from this address.
According to the building owner,
Caprice is only
renting it
for two days.
MAN:
No, not quite.
Oh, yes.
Perfect.
You two,
go get your
costumes and
find out
what's expected of you.
Why don't you wait
for me inside?
MAN: ( clears throat ):
I'm sorry.
This is a private residence.
My name is Gil Grissom,
this is Sara Sidle.
We're with the Crime Lab.
Anthony Caprice.
There's no crime here.
That was a job interview.
Over $150,000 has been
spent on this event.
It's for several
golf club salesman.
They're from
Kansas City.
Japanese formality
will mesh very nicely
with their inherent
Midwestern
restraint.
Their idealized
woman-- submissive,
but in control--
becomes the geisha.
I get it.
You're one of those companies
that stages fantasies, right?
Everything appears real,
but it's all been worked out
in advance?
These scenarios take
weeks to craft.
I learn everything
about my client's
wants and his desires,
all without him
even knowing.
Secret longings--
they have a... a
kind of electricity.
They're often
much more visible than
we would want them to be.
And, uh, Jeff Powell's evening--
the girl, the car,
the billiards--
all paid for
by Mick Sheridan?
Never heard of him.
Who did pay?
A benefactor.
Wishes to
remain anonymous.
GRISSOM:
Somebody rich who likes
to manipulate people probably.
Everybody likes
to be in control.
You don't have to
be rich to want that.
( chuckles )
If you're so law-abiding,
why did Heidi Wolff
and Randy Bolen
lie to the police
about what happened?
Did you tell them to do that?
All my employees have
a very strict
non-disclosure agreement
that they have to sign,
although, I'd never expect them
to lie to the police.
Maybe you just asked them
the wrong questions.
Here's a copy
of Mr. Powell's scenario.
Every event that they talked
about was meticulously planned
in advance and timed
down to the minute.
And his murder?
Tragic.
But it's not in my script.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I have a hot tub
to calibrate.
Oh.
And may all your dreams
come true.
Well, I hope this means
you know what happened to Jeff.
That's the first time
that the tower
yanked back my Gulfstream
on takeoff.
No kidding.
Well, there's always a
first for everything.
We can talk in here.
Something wrong
with your office?
No.
You seem to have bad luck
with the people
who work for you.
If that's a joke, it's
in pretty poor taste.
Three years ago,
you were busted
with an eight ball
of cocaine in your luggage.
You claimed that your personal
assistant had planted it.
That's because he did.
The charges against
me were dropped.
The poor kid
had a serious problem.
I got him into a program.
Understand he's doing
better now.
I hear you bought him a car
to shut him up and take the rap.
The media spins every...
The media.
We found an ounce of cocaine in
Jeff Powell's personal effects.
He was buying drugs for you.
I don't do drugs.
And I had no idea
that Jeff had a drug problem.
Last time, you bought a car,
this time, an elaborate fantasy
to shut him up.
Problem is, he's dead.
And that makes you
responsible.
Captain Brass...
you've seen
too many of my movies.
I'd like to call
my attorney now.
SIDLE:
The script for Jeff's fantasy
starts with Heidi and Randy
renting the cars at 6:00 p.m.
Then it says Randy
drives the Corvette
to The Cue-T
and waits.
WILLOWS:
And Heidi takes the Ferrari.
Finds Jeff
at the Palermo bar.
SIDLE:
Her instructions were:
"Act upset.
"Make up story about abusive
high roller boyfriend.
Allow Jeff to offer comfort."
Sorry. I'm really okay.
No, I'm not.
Anything I can do for you?
It's my damn boyfriend.
Any guy would help a beautiful
woman in distress, right?
Some guys are intimidated
by beauty
or fear rejection.
Evidently, Caprice knew Jeff
well enough
to know he'd want to help her.
Heidi's next
instructions were:
"Repay subject's kindness
by buying drink."
Which she then accidentally
spills on his clothes.
Insists on buying him
a new outfit,
one that he couldn't afford
on his own.
SIDLE:
Everything was scripted
down to the minute--
the clothes,
The Cue-T,
the car.
Sheridan told Caprice
that Jeff had been shooting pool
since he was a kid.
So betting on
and winning
a big money game was probably
just part of the fantasy.
Yeah, and he was a NASCAR fan.
So the whole staged car chase,
narrow getaway
was everything he dreamed about.
As was the partying
in his hotel room.
And the sex.
SIDLE:
Not quite.
According to
the script,
"Your employment ends
with the good-night kiss.
"You are not
requested to perform,
"nor compensated for,
"any activity you initiate
beyond this point.
Should nature take its course,
you are on your own."
( laughing )
GRISSOM:
So the staged fantasy
ended at Jeff's hotel room.
Which means he was off script
when he was killed.
STOKES:
I don't get it.
After a night like that,
I would have felt like Superman.
Why leave the girl?
The victim got to
the shopping arcade
15 minutes after
he got off the elevator.
It's not that long a walk.
I need to know what he was
doing during that time.
There's your guy.
Whatever he's reacting to
is off camera.
Somewhere in the direction
of the baccarat tables.
When the blonde came up to the
vic in the bar the first time,
she pointed
in that same direction.
What's going on over there?
He's playing solo
with the dealer.
That's ten or 20,000 a hand.
Guy's a whale.
Your vic's really going at him.
You know, Heidi was only
supposed to tell a story
about a high roller boyfriend.
Maybe she actually
picked somebody out.
( stomps feet )
What are you doing?
I've been looking at video
three days solid now.
My butt fell asleep.
Wait a second.
I've seen those guys
behind him somewhere else.
Hang on.
Jeff went from the casino
to shopping arcade,
And right behind him,
it's them.
Same guys.
Well, call me Ishmael.
Why?
You need to read more, Arch.
GRISSOM:
Jeff was a winner at everything
he tried that night.
And he was
falling in love.
Which can make a guy do
some pretty stupid things.
So anytime more than
$10,000 hits the table,
the casino's required
to I.D. the player.
Which may help us
harpoon a whale.
Yep.
MAN:
What's the occasion?
We're investigating the death
of the young man
on the casino's
loading dock.
Are you familiar
with this guy?
That's Dennis Kim.
Flies in four,
five times a year
from Seoul to
play baccarat.
Very generous player.
We reserve a table exclusively
for him while he's in town.
He still in town?
Yeah.
He's at his table right now.
Player has two.
Bank.
Mr. Kim, we need
to speak with you for a moment.
Yes?
Do you recognize this man?
Why?
He's dead.
Just before he died,
he was talking to you.
Oh, yes, I remember him.
He was shouting about some girl.
Hey you!
Hey! Guess what?
Heidi, she doesn't need you
or your money anymore, man.
That's right. Because she has
everything she needs now--
love and respect.
So you go ahead and play
your little card game.
All right?
'Cause you the playa.
But I'm the man.
The man.
Crazy boy.
Did you guys
see where he went?
( speaking Korean )
Well, we're gonna need
to take those shoes.
White paint.
And if I don't permit this?
We'll just hold your men
until we get a warrant.
( speaking Korean )
Kamsahamnida.
WILLOWS:
The bodyguards dragged Jeff
through the service corridor.
Between the drugs
and the confidence,
he must've put up
quite a fight.
Hey!
Most likely, he was
still alive when they left.
They probably thought they just
had taught him a lesson.
They did:
Don't confuse
fantasy with reality.
SANDERS:
Well, hush money or
not, you have to admit
that whole fantasy night thing
was a pretty cool gift
from a very generous boss.
Greg, don't you have
a birthday coming up?
Why, yes, Sara, I do.
I'm thinking ear-shredding rock,
a beautiful model,
boatloads of sushi
and latex.
Eh, that was last year.
I think fantasies
are best kept private.
STOKES:
Hey.
Want to know why Jeff left
the girl and went downstairs?
Okay.
This was dropped off
at the Palermo.
Manager sent it over.
Nice rocks.
STOKES:
Jeff must have spent the ten G's
he won playing pool on it.
Gift wrapped,
never picked it up.
WILLOWS:
Yeah, there was
a jewelry store
right across from
the service corridor entrance.
Most I ever spent on a girl.
Most I ever held
in my hand at one time.
You know, the biggest fantasy
in Vegas
is that everything here
happens by chance.
Nothing here
The odds are set
before you get off the plane.
You know, I'd settle
for a birthday breakfast.
Now that is a fantasy.