( woman screams )
( gasping )
CURTIS:
Vic's name's Christina Hollis.
She's a sales agent
for the building.
Neighbor said she just came
running out of her unit,
delirious
and hysterical.
Sexual assault?
Definitely.
I'm gonna go with her
to the hospital,
see if I can
get a statement.
GRISSOM:
Video cameras.
That's good for us.
Vic probably thought it
was good for her, too.
Excuse me, hi,
can you identify yourself
for the camera, please?
PRODUCER:
Just look right in the lens.
What is this?
It's a reality crime show.
We're following you
for this investigation.
Sheriff promised
full cooperation.
We got that memo.
They're Hard Crime.
That's us-- we're the guys
who put the folks
who look in the microscopes
under the microscopes.
Right.
You see, it's good P.R.
for the department.
Try not to bust
their chops, okay?
PRODUCER:
You ever see the show?
It's got a lot of forensics.
There's too many
forensics shows on TV.
BRASS:
The door knob,
the frame, the strike
plate are all clean.
No sign of
a forced entry.
So she might have
known her assailant.
Either that
or he talked his way in.
Hey, hey, hey.
Stay behind
the crime tape.
PRODUCER:
Don't cut.
Mr. Grissom, can you please
describe what you're seeing?
A long night.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really want to know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me
who are you, you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
I don't understand.
Why am I here?
Miss Hollis,
you've been assaulted.
Who...?
I...
You don't know
who did this?
What was the last
thing you remember?
I don't know.
Oh, my God.
Okay, this isn't right.
Why isn't this right?
Why don't I look right?
Christina, it's okay.
No, it's not okay.
It's not okay.
Why don't I look right?
I don't underst...
Why are they st...
Why are they staring at me?
Stop looking at me!
Nurse, get in here!
( sobbing )
It's okay. It's okay.
NURSE:
I did a wet mount
from a vaginal swab
and got 4-plus
motile sperm present.
So she was raped
within the last few hours.
No condom means
he's not in the system
or he doesn't care
if he gets caught.
Guys like this,
they keep doing it.
PRODUCER:
Excuse me, Detective.
Can I ask you
a question?
Detective.
You try something like that
again and you're gone.
I don't a give a damn
what the sheriff says.
We never put anyone on screen
without a signed release.
You invaded her privacy
at her most vulnerable moment.
I am trying to give
the crime a face.
Yeah, well,
we're going to lose an hour
waiting for her to calm down.
That's on you.
I apologize.
It won't happen again.
Look, can I just ask you
what you've got there?
It's a sexual assault evidence
kit and blood sample.
I've seen date rape victims
in similar dissociative states.
We're going to run a tox screen,
see if she was drugged.
You were a CSI, right?
Yeah.
And now you're
a detective.
So which side of
the fence do you prefer?
It's the same side.
( camera clicking )
( camera clicks )
WILLOWS:
Candles burned down.
A bouquet in the trash.
( camera clicking )
Flowers and candles--
sure seems like a date.
Some date.
( camera clicks )
There's a void
in the wax.
Some kind of white
flaky substance.
This looks like blood, but...
I think it's nail polish.
BRASS:
Hey, how's it going?
According to your supervisor,
you were doing maintenance work
on the 11th floor
at 5:00 a.m.
What were you fixing
at 5:00 in the morning?
I was just clocking
a little overtime.
Management said they wanted
a few extra coats of paint
on three, seven and 11.
Got to keep everything
nice and pretty for the tenants.
You know, the security guy
didn't see you on his camera.
Why is that?
Yeah, well, that guy
doesn't see much.
Service elevator's out.
We have to use the stairs.
God forbid the tenants
ever have to look at one of us.
You got a master key
to all the apartments?
Yeah.
But we only go in
if a tenant specifically
asks us to fix something.
You ever fix anything
for Christina Hollis?
Nope. Never.
You're running a little low
on duct tape, my man.
Yeah.
It's holding up
half the building.
Two pieces of duct tape,
both have been swabbed
for DNA and fingerprinted.
Grissom wants you
to compare adhesives.
He's looking for a match.
Okay.
That'll take
a laser ablation test.
That's good.
Why's that good?
Well, laser ablation
is both visual and dramatic.
Are you looking
for the video crew right now?
I would think that
they would be looking for me.
Relax, man, the show's
only an hour long.
Laser ablation
takes, like, six.
Yeah, but when
they cut it together,
it'll only take 30 seconds.
HODGES:
Ran laser ablation on
the duct tape samples.
Not a match.
So she wasn't tied up
with the maintenance man's tape.
Mm-mm.
What about the rest
of the trace?
White powder was
primarily biological,
so I kicked it
back to DNA.
It did contain some
glassy particles.
Might be industrial
diamonds.
And the yellow
reflective flakes?
My next priority.
( scoffs )
That's a waste
of film.
JOHNSON:
The victim came out of her
apartment around 5:00 a.m.,
so I've been
working my way back from then.
In the previous seven hours,
37 people came and went
from the 11th floor,
21 of them male.
So the assailant could
be any one of them...
assuming that our guy
didn't take the stairs
which, of course,
aren't monitored.
Okay, now, here:
This guy got off on the
vic's floor at 10:32 p.m.
There's no footage
of him coming back down.
And check this out.
( beeping )
He brought flowers.
How romantic.
But I don't think this was
a first date.
( beeping )
Guy had his own key.
So he could've been with
the victim the whole night.
Pull the best image
of his face you can,
and get a
printout to Brass.
I'm on it.
PRODUCER:
Ms. Willows,
hold on a second.
All you have
is a guy's face.
How do you figure out
who he is?
Good question.
PRODUCER:
Guys, we're good to go.
( clears throat )
So what have you found
so far?
I lifted two identifiable prints
off the bouquet wrapper.
How do you know they belong
to the suspect?
We don't,
but one matched a print found
on the duct tape, right here,
used to tape up the victim.
Unfortunately, that print's not
in our database.
So your suspect
doesn't have a record?
Apparently not, no.
Well, how do you find a guy
who's not in the system?
( chuckles )
You just got to get creative,
you know?
I mean, the flowers... came
from a small shop off-strip.
Took the suspect's image
to the clerk,
showed it to him.
He gave me
a credit card receipt.
From that receipt, I got a name.
That name gave me
a driver's license.
Dwight Reynolds.
Police are bringing him in now.
Great, okay.
Clear and concise,
thank you.
Thanks.
Yeah, well, we have to do it
in court all the time.
If you can't explain it
to a jury,
then the bad guy usually walks,
and we don't like it
when the bad guy walks.
CURTIS:
Unit picked him up
at the Double Down.
He was plastered.
BRASS:
What'd he blow?
One nine.
That's almost enough
to wash away your sins.
Well, we're going to have
wait until he sobers up.
No, no, let's not wait,
let's move on this.
I think we got a chance.
Look, why don't you come
in there with me, huh?
Maybe pop a few buttons?
( chuckles )
No, seriously.
See how he reacts.
If he tries too hard
not to look,
it could be
a guilty conscience?
Yeah, maybe,
something like that.
If he is the guy,
and we interview him now,
anything he says could
be thrown out of court.
It's worth a try.
What do you think, huh?
Let's go.
How's it going?
Okay.
Did you know
a Christina Hollis?
Yeah, we used to date.
You seen her recently?
No.
Then how come
we found your prints
on some flowers at her place?
I dropped some flowers off...
but I didn't see her when I did.
You had a key?
Yeah.
She likes me to come over
sometimes, you know?
Help her move stuff.
Oh, come on, what really
happened, huh?
You went over
to move some stuff,
and she wasn't in the mood,
is that it?
I told you--
I didn't see her.
( door rattling )
( Barry White song
playing inside )
She was playing Barry White.
Everybody knows what that means.
I guess it wasn't my night.
You're lying!
We found the flowers inside
her apartment, in the trash,
and you didn't use the elevator
to leave.
I was pissed.
I tried to walk it off.
I figured 11 flights down,
it's better than a cold shower.
Christina Hollis was tied up
and brutally assaulted
in her apartment last night.
What?
And you were there.
Is she...?
She's alive and talking.
Last night?
The guy who with her was...
was doing that to her?
I could've stopped it.
SIMMS:
So the powder that you found
on the bedroom floor
was actually
keratinized skin cells.
They belong to the vic,
and morphology suggests
that they're probably
from her cuticles.
Cuticles?
Mm-hmm.
Nail polish,
diamond particles...
Maybe she was giving
herself a mani and pedi
before the assault.
I don't know about you,
but if I could afford to live
in an apartment like that,
I'd be in a spa every week.
Yeah, I hear you there.
Thank you.
Mm-hmm.
Wendy ran the semen,
no hits in CODIS.
Yeah, the, uh...
ex-boyfriend
didn't match any of the prints
on the duct tape, either.
SAE found oral,
vaginal and anal smears
positive for semen.
Degraded and intact sperm
suggests multiple deposits.
Which means that
he probably raped her
on and off,
for a long time.
Yeah, well, tox came back--
lorazepam in the vic's blood.
I didn't find any
prescription bottles
in her apartment.
No, nor did I.
Lorazepam is
a hypnotic sedative,
and I know in high doses,
it causes acute amnesia.
Maybe that's what he was
counting on to cover his tracks.
Well, it usually takes an hour
for a drug like that to kick in.
How did he subdue her
in the meantime?
Low-profile entry, sedatives,
duct tape--
I mean, if he's not a serial,
he will be soon.
Hey, there, gorgeous.
I'm going to be running
with the trace
from the victim's
apartment.
Would you mind bringing
me up to speed?
Certainly.
Take your time.
PRODUCER:
Did you page us?
Um...
No. Mm-mm.
According to the gas
chromatograph
mass spectrometer,
the glossy red drop you found
on the footboard was...
nail polish.
Well, that's not unusual
in a woman's apartment.
What is far more intriguing
is the reflective yellow flakes.
Follow me to the Fourier
Transform Infrared Microscope.
Hodges, what's wrong
with you?
Nothing.
PRODUCER ( whispering):
Guys... stay with the girl.
As you can see, the flakes are
fluorescent reflective lenses
bonded to an aramid backing
by a special polymer layer.
And it's used exclusively
in the reflective trim
of firemen's turnouts.
You're telling me there
was a firefighter
in the victim's bedroom.
Hmm...
Thanks.
Thanks, Hodges.
Anytime.
Yeah, all right, okay,
let 'em roll.
But you're buying
the lobster.
Yeah, right.
See, one of the guys
gets on TV,
that guy has to buy lobster for
the whole company, you know?
These guys eat well--
lobster thermidor!
Check it out.
So, according to dispatch,
you responded to an alarm
at the Omni condos
last night?
Yeah, at 6:58 p.m.
We were on scene in
about four minutes.
Three smoke bombs on three
different floors,
three pains in my ass.
There's no major damage,
just paint and wallpaper.
We were there
about a half hour.
What'd the arson guys find?
They didn't find much.
The smoke bombs were made
out of soda cans.
Kids, Internet, you do the math.
It's all in your lab.
Really? What for?
A couple guys from
the day shift were gonna
compare 'em to those bombs we
found a couple of weeks ago.
What are you talking about?
Apartment building
over on Paradise.
Smoke bombs started a fire,
one woman died.
We still don't have a suspect
in that.
BRASS:
Were you on the scene?
CAPTAIN:
I saw it after.
Smoke bomb was too close
to the wall, the whole place...
Which of your guys were up on
the 11th floor at the Omni?
I don't know.
I'd have to ask around. Why?
A woman was raped
last night.
You think
one of my guys did it?
I'm not saying that,
but we found some evidence
that a fireman
was near her bed.
You came here to accuse
my guys of this in
front of the camera?
No, no, no.
Settle down, settle down...
The hell I will.
No wonder they call you Brass,
because you really got a set.
Aw, come on, Sparky...
SIDLE:
Excuse me, gentlemen.
Captain, uh,
which of your guys...
wears a yellow reflective stripe
on their turnouts?
Nobody; department's
color is orange.
SIDLE:
The reflective flake we found
in Christina Hollis' apartment
was yellow.
Then you're not looking for
a Las Vegas fireman.
JOHNSON:
According to surveillance,
the victim came home
at 6:19 p.m.
And the firemen were
in her building
at approximately 7:00.
They took the stairs, so we
don't have them on this camera.
Now take a look at this...
WILLOWS:
Well, he certainly
looks the part.
He touched the door
with his bare hands.
Might get prints.
The time code says 6:36 p.m.
but the alarm went out at 6:58.
That's 22 minutes later.
What kind of fireman
comes before the fire?
Someone who knows
it's coming.
PRODUCER:
Uh, Mr. Grissom, we may
have missed that.
Could you say it one
more time for camera?
( indistinct conversation )
PRODUCER:
You ever hear
the saying,
"Only the dumb
ones get caught?"
Yeah...
but we catch
the smart ones, too.
And this guy's
definitely smart.
He lights smoke bombs
on three different floors
so as not to call attention
to his target.
Victim sees the smoke, sees him,
and opens the door.
( knocking )
!
Fire department,
open up.
I mean, who wouldn't
trust a fireman, right?
CURTIS:
It takes a lot of
courage to do this.
Thank you.
And if you change your mind
about the camera,
all you have to do
is say so--
no one ever
has to see this.
No, I want him to see it.
He'll watch it
in jail.
Okay, so,
you said you were
beginning to remember
what happened?
Yeah, a little.
Can you tell me
what he looked like?
Um...
No, not really.
It's mostly, uh...
just feelings.
Feelings.
Of what?
I know he raped me.
What I remember
most...
it was, um...
( sniffling )
He...
He kept...
He kept touching
my feet.
( sniffling )
He kept touching
my feet.
( police sirens wailing )
A foot fetish is
a visual pathology.
The suspect would have had
to be close enough to the vic
to see her toes
and then get aroused.
We live in a desert, Gil.
You want to see
a woman's bare feet,
all you have to do
is look down.
( footsteps approaching )
Door in the
parking structure
was like the arm
of a slot machine:
smudge city.
Anything useful
from the janitor?
Yeah, he gave us
a full description.
Said he looked
like a fireman.
( sighs )
Well, between eBay,
uniform shops,
and national manufacturers,
there's about a hundred
different places
that you can buy
yellow-striped turnouts.
Maybe he was a fireman
in another city.
Maybe.
What's that?
When I was at
the firehouse,
all of the air tanks
were rigged
with the valves on the bottom,
like this one.
But our guy...
his valve is on top.
A real fireman probably
wouldn't make that mistake.
His air line isn't even
rigged to his mask.
It's rigged to
a second mask
on his side.
Maybe he put something
in the tank to subdue her.
He used lorazepam.
Eventually.
But this guy was
somehow able to get her
from the door to the bed
without a struggle.
I bet he used nitrous oxide.
That stuff will knock you out
real fast.
And it's undetectable in
the blood after a few minutes.
Pretty easy to come by.
And it would explain
the valve on top.
It's liquid under pressure.
It would spill
if it were upside down.
All you need is
a driver's license
and a deposit
for the tank.
If this guy
bought nitrous from
a local distributor,
there's definitely
a record.
Check it out.
Come on, Tina.
Like, I'm the only one
working doubles here.
Oh, so it's my fault
that we have strange schedules.
Great. Go out with your friends.
I'm sure you'll be seeing Robert
again tonight, too, huh?
You know what?
It's fine.
I got to go.
Have a fun time.
PRODUCER:
This a bad time?
No. Great time.
What can I do for you?
What are
you working on?
I'm examining smoke bombs
recovered from, uh...
the victim'scondo,
and comparing them
to smoke bombs
from an arson case
a couple of weeks ago.
How do you know
which is which?
I mean, how do
you tell them apart?
Well, so far, I've only opened
up one item from each case.
CSIs, when we work a case,
we take extensive notes
at the scene,
and photos of each item.
And, uh... they're
very similar, I know.
But, based on the construction
and the components,
I'd say these two bombs
were made by the same person.
PRODUCER:
So I guess this is a
slow day at the morgue.
You can't really
predict this job.
Today it's like this,
tomorrow it's a bus accident.
So I am here.
Albert.
Yeah?
Did you find
the blood sample
I called you about?
Female arson fatality.
C.O.D. is smoke inhalation.
Partial tox came back
carboxyhemoglobin and cyanide.
I need a test
for lorazepam.
Blood's on its way to Tox.
You recall any other
sexual assault victims
that tested positive
for lorazepam?
Uh... Nothing comes to mind,
but I'll check my files,
confer with Toxicology.
Thanks.
Yeah.
A slow day is a good day.
These people lived
on the same floor
as the female arson fatality
from two weeks ago.
Tox on the
arson victim
came back negative
for lorazepam.
So maybe she
wasn't the target.
PRODUCER:
Ms. Sidle, is this
what you guys call
a "fishing expedition"?
We call this
following a lead.
Forgive me, but it's
not very much of a lead.
What's that supposed to mean?
Well, this case is even
colder than the one you'reon.
You'd almost be better off
if you had a new rape victim
and a fresh scene.
That might be true,
but that is definitely
not the outcome
that we're looking for.
WOMAN:
I didn't really know
the girl who died.
I still can't
believe what happened.
It's just awful.
Tell me what
you remember.
I was alone in my apartment
Saturday night.
Hello. What's new, right?
I was reading or something.
And then, suddenly,
there was someone pounding
on my door.
Can you describe
what he looked like?
Well, he was fireman.
I mean, he was wearing a mask.
It all happened
pretty quick.
Why?
We're looking for a rapist
who masquerades as a fireman.
He uses smoke bombs
to get
his victims to open their doors.
He knocked on my door.
Are you saying you think
he was going to rape me?
It's possible.
You know, I was pretty freaked.
When he was standing there
in front of me...
Just before he left,
I swear, for a second,
it felt like he wasn't
going to let me go.
Turnouts were a dead end.
And there's nothing to track
off of the smoke bombs.
I've got hundreds
of names of people
who purchased
nitrous oxide in
the last six months.
What? You got
to narrow that down.
That is narrowed down.
Okay. Our rapist
is a foot fetishist.
That's what gets him off.
He has to see his
victim's feet somewhere.
If we can figure out where,
maybe we can find him.
What do the victims
have in common?
Christina Hollis.
African American. Single.
Lives and works
at the Omni.
She lives on the 11th floor,
so there's no real way
for a peeper to see in.
And she uses
the gym, but not the pool.
Stephanie Daniels
lives across town.
Caucasian. Also single.
No gym membership,
but she does use the pool
at her apartment complex
regularly.
There's a couple
of adjacent buildings.
It's possible that
somebody could see
into her place
with a telescope,
but she has shades and curtains.
I kind of doubt it.
So they have
nothing in common.
Sure, they do.
They both have feet.
We may have
a third victim
who may also
be our first victim.
Tara Weathers. Last month,
she claimed
she was drugged in a bar
and woke up in her apartment
with her toes freshly painted.
They did a tox
on her at the time.
Found lorazepam in her system.
Well, she does have nice feet.
And the nail polish
looks like a similar shade
to Christina Hollis'.
Yeah. So the pattern starts
a month ago.
Our guy drugs Tara Weathers
in a bar,
takes her
to her apartment,
paints her toes, leaves.
Two weeks later, he steps it up.
Poses as a firefighter,
places smoke bombs
in an apartment building,
only things don't work out
the way that
he planned.
The building
catches fire,
and he runs.
He waits a couple more weeks,
he does it again,
but this time
he goes all the way.
Yeah. And now he's escalating.
Where does he go from here?
Tara Weathers?
I'm Jim Brass,
Las Vegas Police.
This is Catherine Willows
from the Crime Lab.
What do you want?
Well, we're here to ask you
about the incident
you reported to
the police last month.
The nail polish thing?
Yeah, the nail polish thing.
You guys said I should
consider myself lucky,
that there was
no real crime anyway.
Well, we may have
been wrong about that.
I knew it, that's what I tried
to tell you the first time.
BRASS:
The guy who drugged you
is a rapist
and a murderer,
and we're looking to stop him
before he does it again.
Are you serious?
Very.
We're trying to understand
what you have in common
with the other victims
that might lead us to him.
Now he has a foot fetish.
He's into feet.
Is there any way that
he could've... seen your feet?
Um...
I-I... I don't know.
Where do you
buy your shoes?
All over.
Do you go to a gym?
No, not really.
Pool?
No, never.
I burn easily.
I'm a legal secretary,
I don't get out much.
My work starts early
and it goes late.
The firm is so conservative,
we're not even allowed
to wear open-toed shoes.
I notice that you do yoga.
Yeah.
Where?
Out on the balcony.
It's practically the only
fresh air I get.
Anybody in those apartments
has a clear view
of her bare feet.
PRODUCER:
So how'd you get the warrant?
The tenant's name was
on the nitrous oxide list.
Las Vegas Police.
Open up,
we have a warrant.
Open up, police.
Open it.
Let's go.
No, no, no, you're not
going in there, no.
Can you please take this in,
it's a flashlight cam.
It'll record anything
you point it at.
All clear.
Thanks.
Perfect view of Tara's balcony.
Yoga flyers from all over town.
Guy's got everything he needs
for a pedicure.
Hey, check this out.
God bless the internet.
Fireman's air tank case.
Where's the tank?
( cell phone blips )
Yeah, this is Brass.
I want to put a broadcast out
on Richard McQueen.
That's M-C-Q-U-E-E-N.
Copy.
( cell phone blips )
Candle wax on the camera.
There, send it to the monitor.
( siren )
( garbled radio transmission)
( sirens )
( grunting ):
Stay down!
Las Vegas P.D.!
Las Vegas P.D.,
break it up!
Break it up!
What the hell's
going on here?
Smoke bombs.
We caught this creep
sneaking away.
My guys tried to stop him.
She wouldn't let me
touch her feet.
You should see
what he did?
( sighs )
Women are four times
more likely than men
to be the victims
of a sex-related murder.
And men are ten times
more likely than women
to be the murderer.
It's just the way it is.
Is that your daughter?
Oh, yeah, these
are old pictures.
She's a teenager now.
With all the things
you see on this job,
do you ever worry about her?
Are you kidding?
I keep a vial of her
blood in my freezer.
Like as a DNA sample in case
you need to identify her?
Well...
One thing you learn
doing this job
is that bad things happen
to people who never expect it...
every day.
Yeah, we got a confession.
He didn't choose women's feet,
women's feet chose him.
He lit candles, he played music,
he thought he was on a date.
But did he explain,
you know, why he did it?
Oh, yeah. Oh, sure.
His mother was a hooker,
she put him under the bed
when she did her business,
her feet dangled
over the edge of the bed.
He watched her feet,
they were perfect.
You know, I don't know
if it's true.
What about
the fireman thing?
I don't know, I guess he wanted
to be a fireman when he grew up.
Didn't you?
Look, juries love explanations,
they want it nice and neat.
They don't want to know
we live in a random world,
they want meaning.
It's that simple.
So how do you cope
with a day like today?
What do you do?
What do you want me to tell you,
that I go home, I get drunk,
I go to a bar,
I stay out all night,
I don't sleep... huh?
That's not the truth.
You know what happens?
I take care of myself,
I sleep very well.
How well did you sleep
after you learned
you killed that fellow officer
in that shootout last year?
Uh, yeah.
Oh, is this... is that...
Oh, is this what this is about?
Who've you been talking to, huh?
What, you come here
with your camera
and you roll
a little film and...
what, you think you know
what it's like to be a cop?
You?
You're all done.
You're all done with this.
Get out of here.
The truth is
if there isn't any evidence,
we have nowhere to go.
So you feel you did
the best you could?
Yes, I do.
Do you think
forensic shows
are just teaching
the criminals
how to get away
with crimes?
Everyone learns from science.
It all depends
on how you use the knowledge.
( camera beeps )
Keep going, go inside
for a close-up.