REPORTER:
This is Channel 8 News
reporting with an update
to yesterday's wild police
pursuit and shootout
where three suspects
and one police officer
were killed by gunfire
at Third and Jefferson.
Shortly after being taken
into custody,
Jose Fausto, the last suspect
was gunned down
by an unknown...
( gunshot )
( prisoner screams )
Down! Everybody down! Down!
CAVALIERE:
Somebody shot this guy
in front of all these cops?
They did not want him
talking to us.
This was not some
doped up drive-by.
The shooter had skill.
Just one shot went through
the ten ring.
How'd they know
Fausto was here?
I don't know.
I bet you he tried to reach out
for help, you know?
Maybe money or a ticket
out of here.
I'll check the phone records
and see if there was any calls
in or out.
Glad I'm not Vartann.
He's got to tell
the UnderSheriff.
MCKEEN:
Are you seriously
telling me
our only live suspect,
a cop killer, was gunned
down in your custody?
I'm sorry
to say yes, sir.
And you didn't catch
the shooter?
That's also correct, sir.
Stop calling me sir,
you worthless...
( sighs)
Where's Grissom?
ECKLIE:
He's on his way.
All right, let's start
without him.
ORTEGA:
Sergeant Adams and Officer Bell
were making a routine traffic
stop on a Buick.
Before they were able
to effect the stop,
a stolen Caprice intervened.
Adams said they just cut him
off and started firing.
They were followed in pursuit
by officers Davis and Carroll
and detectives Brass
and Curtis.
The, uh, Caprice TC'd
during the pursuit.
And they just kept firing.
We got three of them
off of prints.
Priors for narcotics
and connections
to the Mexican Mafia.
And additional set of prints
from the Caprice
came back to Jose Fausto,
the guy shot
at the motel.
I've heard enough about him.
Why would these knuckleheads
pull in front of a police car
making a traffic stop
and engage us in a gunfight?
If the Buick was moving drugs,
maybe the Caprice was providing
security,
keeping the cops
and rival gang members away.
We don't have the Buick,
so there's no evidence
to confirm that.
Well, if these guys were a bunch
of drug-dealing thugs,
why on the news
were they unarmed
and we shot 'em
in the back?
'Cause that's what
the eyewitnesses are saying.
And that we shot
an innocent high school kid
riding his bike.
Uh, Ricardo Estevez,
male Hispanic, 22,
shot in the alley east of Third.
Three entrance wounds to the
front torso, none to the back.
Ballistics matched the bullets
to Sergeant Carroll's gun.
Recovered a .45 auto
next to the body.
ORTEGA:
Captain Brass states the suspect
had it pointed at the sergeant
when he came around
the corner.
We have eyewitnesses
who claim that they saw the
suspect with his hands raised
just before he was shot.
Can we resolve this?
Sergeant Carroll
partially confirms
eyewitness accounts.
When Captain Brass approached,
he momentarily took his eyes
off the suspect.
When he looked back,
the suspect was holding a gun.
Probably pulled it
from his waistband.
There's no evidence
to place the gun in the
suspect's hand at that point.
What about the guy
in the other alley?
Salvador Rosario, 19,
also shot in the front.
Autopsy's pending.
Chemical tests show
that he held a gun.
You're not going
to believe this.
A bullet from Officer Davis'
gun hit the suspect's revolver,
jamming the cylinder.
That would mean the revolver
had to be pointing
at Officer Davis.
There are several eyewitnesses
who claim that they saw him
plant the gun on the body.
It wasn't planted.
It was mishandled.
Mishandled by who?
Contrary to policy,
Officer Davis prematurely
picked up the gun.
Detective Curtis instructed him
to set it back down,
which he did.
What are you doing?
Put it down.
Sorry, I was just trying
to secure his gun.
An eyewitness seeing that
certainly could misinterpret it
as planting a gun.
MCKEEN:
Please tell me you've got some
good news.
I have the autopsy findings
on Leandro Chavez.
He died of survivable wounds.
Bled out
at the crime scene
waiting for transport.
Dame una ambulanica quey.
I don't speak Spanish.
There's justification for this.
I can't wait to hear
what that is.
Paramedics prioritized
transport of the injured.
Downed officer first,
civilians next.
By the time
they got to the suspect,
he'd passed on.
Just a little retroactive
birth control.
See, this is the problem
that the community
has with us.
You don't speak Spanish, so you
think they don't speak English
and then when you run
your mouth...
All right, keep on point here.
Which one of these buttheads
shot Officer Bell?
We have reason to believe
that Officer Bell
was killed by friendly fire.
( gunshots )
It was a through-and-through,
and we haven't recovered
the bullet yet.
It's a big crime scene.
Unacceptable.
Get back out there
and find that bullet.
I don't care
if it takes everybody you got
working around the clock.
I said we haven't found it yet.
I didn't say we weren't looking.
♪ Who... are you?
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ I really want to know ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ! ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
I'm supposed to do
whatever it takes
to find that bullet.
Don't worry
about the overtime.
As soon as day shift
comes in,
I'll send them
out, too.
Hey, Grissom.
So Warrick recovered
a nine-millimeter pistol
from Fausto's motel room,
and I matched it to the
cartridge case
from the kid
in the hospital.
I also found
the kid's bike there.
Shot him in the back
for his bike. Great.
Hey.
I left you a couple of messages.
Oh, yeah... I haven't
gotten to them yet.
Sorry.
You're on administrative leave,
though.
You should be home
getting some rest.
Yeah, I tried.
But I...
can't stop thinking about
this... this Bell shooting.
It's understandable.
Grissom, I think
there may be a possibility
that maybe... I shot him.
Sofia... we can't discuss
the investigation.
It's, it's something I remember
when I was giving my statement.
Then it's already
on the record.
No, something
I didn't mention.
Sofia...
Please listen to me.
Bell was between me
and the suspect.
I was shooting over his cover,
which is a violation of policy.
I was, I was just trying
to stay alive.
But if I did it, I...
Hey, Grissom,
I have a question.
Sofia?
You're on administrative leave.
I know.
You should not be
in this building.
I was just talking to a friend.
If I can't talk to a friend,
who the hell am I supposed
to talk to?
Any friend outside
the department.
And how many friends outside
of work do you have, Sarah?
Maybe I should go
talk to my mother.
Oh, no, sorry. I forgot.
She's a cop, too.
I can recommend a departmental
psychologist.
All right, then.
This was a really bad idea.
I'm sorry.
Hey, listen.
One of the officers
searching for the shooter
found an expended cartridge
up there on the seventh floor.
That would put him
in the right position.
Freemont Street's not far.
It makes
for an easy escape.
Good job.
Nice.
.223 Remington.
Most likely from a semiauto.
Didn't even bother
to pick it up.
Yeah. Wasn't afraid
of getting caught.
I'll give it to Bobby.
Have him run it through IBIS.
See if the gun was used before.
( over radio ):
Vartann, this is Cavaliere.
We've recovered an expended
.223 cartridge case
from a building
overlooking the motel.
It's on its way
to the lab now.
Scene here is secure.
Patrol just called.
They found a 411-A behind
5203 Maryland Parkway.
Sounds like it might be
the Buick Regal.
I'm going
to head over there now.
CAVALIERE:
Buick Regal, no plates.
You run the VIN?
Yeah. It came
up stolen.
Yeah. It's a good chance this
is the car we're looking for.
Yep.
Torched it to destroy
any evidence.
Let's get this thing
towed back to the lab, okay?
You got it.
ORTEGA:
Sergeant Adams,
this is your standard
after-shooting walk through,
okay?
Now I want you to describe to us
exactly what happened
yesterday morning.
We were southbound
on Roosevelt.
Bell observed a male
and female Hispanic
having a domestic
dispute.
Where were they?
Over in that last spot.
They got out
of a green Geo Metro.
Walked this way.
By the time we'd turned
around,
they'd gotten
into the Buick Regal.
They were driving away.
She was pregnant,
about to pop,
just like Bell's wife.
He said we should
pull 'em over.
Which way'd they go?
Southbound on Roosevelt.
As soon as we turned
on Desert Springs,
the Caprice cut us off.
Okay, thanks.
Hey, hang around
for about a minute
or two, okay?
I'll give you
a ride home.
Your thoughts?
I wonder if that camera works.
Well, it's worth checking out.
Come on. I'll even let you
buy me a donut.
I got to the end
of my road.
And?
Well, the suspect
started shooting
near the intersection
of Jefferson and Desert Springs.
That's nearly 20 blocks north
of the crime scene.
All ammo evidence was
7.62-millimeter
casings and bullets.
Only AK ammo?
No police cartridge cases
or bullets?
Not one out of 233 items.
But cops don't get
to shoot car-to-car,
only bad guys do, right?
Oh, hey, Greg.
Been on vacation?
Look, I know the undersheriff's
on your back,
so I figured I better
get to you quick.
Okay, you got to me.
Found red clay chips and dust
in the gouges
on Ricardo Estevez's .45.
He was the guy
that was in the east alley
with Brass.
Red clay chips?
Traces consistent with
roof tiles and clay pots.
Who keeps their gun
in a clay pot?
That would be no one.
Trace evidence is fresh,
so it definitely
came from the alley.
In a crisis, you can
always count on me.
Doesn't he bug you?
No more so than anyone else
around here.
Sara, will you come with me
to the east alley, please?
I thought my top priority
as per the undersheriff
was finding the bullet
that went through Bell.
Well, this is per me.
Come on.
It'll be fun.
Okay.
Sara?
Yeah?
Call Hodges at the lab.
Have him bring
two exemplar .45s out here.
I'll get Ortega to bring
Brass and Sergeant Carroll.
Are... you gonna tell me
what's going on?
What goes up... must come down.
So, where exactly
was Estevez standing
when you guys saw him?
Right there,
facing this way.
That's right.
And he had a gun in his hand.
He had a gun
in his hand.
And I shot a, uh,
armed suspect
who'd been shooting
at the police, sir.
I believe you.
But the witnesses
may also be right.
Look, don't make this
some intellectual exercise
for your own
personal amusement.
Check it out.
Hodges, stand over here.
Yes, sir.
Right here.
See that roof?
It's red clay.
Toss one of the guns up there.
Actually,
they're Bobby Dawson's guns.
He made me sign
for them-- I'm sure
he wouldn't appreciate
if we brought them back damaged.
Technically, they're myguns--
so toss one up there.
Just for the record, I've never
really been good at sports.
Sara?
Yeah.
How does that prove
the guy tossed the gun up there?
You recovered it
from the ground.
There's a cracked tile
up on the roof.
I found a series of scratches
stretching from the
cracked tile to the
end of the roof.
I found scratches
and red clay dust
in the suspect's .45.
GRISSOM:
It explains how
the witnesses
could see Estevez with his hands
up, and Sergeant Carroll
then saw him with a gun
in his hand.
The gun's still up there.
Sara...
try it again.
Stop! Police!
Get down!
Don't move.
There you have it.
WILLOWS:
There's the Geo Metro.
There's the Buick Regal.
Oh, she's pregnant,
all right.
Doesn't look like she
wants to go with him.
He's not giving her
much choice.
So, just how bad was the meeting
with the undersheriff?
Worse than the dentist.
Better than the proctologist.
Mm.
ECKLIE:
What's he doing?
Looks like he's pulling out
a hide-a-key.
ECKLIE:
Means the car
was waiting for them.
Whatever they were about to do,
they weren't going to do it
in the Metro.
WILLOWS:
Hey, Nick?
Hey.
Have you checked the
inside of the wheel wells?
No. I was having
too much fun in here.
Oh, yeah, I can see that.
Um, well...
since you're already dirty,
would you mind checking out
the left rear one for me?
Yeah, sure.
Thank you.
What are you looking for?
I am looking for something
to hide a key in.
Okay. Although, most hide-a-keys
are held on with a magnet,
which would've been demagnetized
by the heat
of the gasoline fire.
Right.
Nope.
Well,
it probably fell off
at the location.
Maybe. Auto transport
usually sweeps up the debris.
Good luck with that.
( heart beating steadily )
( gunshots )
( heartbeat continues )
MAN:
My son was riding his bike
to school.
Today he's in a coma.
But when he wakes up,
when he... opens his eyes again
and smiles at his mother,
he will see all the... flowers
and cards that he's been sent
from total strangers
wishing him well and...
praying for his recovery.
Sheriff Burdick h-hasn't called.
I've left so many messages
I've lost count.
It's inconvenient, I know,
but I have questions.
Who did this to my son?
Why did they do it?
No one wants to answer me?
If the cops didn't shoot him,
why won't they talk to me?
If I have to go to court
to find out,
if I have to sue
each and every officer involved,
I'll do it.
I will put the sheriff
in front of a jury
and get my answers there.
( phone rings )
McKeen.
Yes, sir. I saw the news.
I still think we should wait
to issue a statement,
at least until the lab
has something concrete.
Hodges, it's not so
much that these guns
are my babies, okay?
It's just that in order
to replace them,
I got to go to Property,
got to locate another gun,
fill out all that paperwork,
so all I'm saying is,
I would appreciate
not being left out
of the loop, okay?
I'm only a soldier in this war.
The general gave me an order,
and I followed it.
DAWSON:
Whatever.
I've finished checking
this batch for trace.
Bobby, police said they entered
my cartridge case
from the sniper into IBIS.
It has become my priority,
or so I was informed
by Under Sheriff McKeen--
give me about an hour?
Okay.
I got blood.
Where's it from?
Expended bullet, Torres house,
candle in the living room.
That's our
through-and-through.
DAWSON:
Looks like a copper-jacketed
nine-millimeter,
consistent with cop ammo.
( grunting )
Brass, Sofia,
Adams, Davis and Carroll
were all shooting nines.
Compare it with their
firearms ASAP.
I'm gonna go
tell Grissom.
Looking for something?
At least this car still has
a nice hubcap.
Where'd you find that?
On the pursuit route, Jefferson,
about ten blocks north of Third.
Well, I've been through
this car twice.
There's no evidence
of cartridge casings, blood,
drugs of any kind.
So there was nothing
here to begin with,
They cleaned it out pretty good
before they torched it.
Hey, Nick, Grissom.
We found the through-
and-through bullet.
Bobby's doing a comparison.
I sent a sample of blood to DNA.
BRASS:
Hey.
I'm glad you called.
I've been thinking
about you.
Good. Yeah,
I wasn't sure.
How you doing?
I've gone a little crazy.
Yeah. It's the waiting.
You know, I've been
suspended or disciplined
like six or seven times,
and it's always the same,
the waiting.
What you never forget is that
you know, a police officer
lost his life.
( gunshot )
I have seen it so many times,
I don't know
if it's real or not.
Jim, it's like
he's looking at me--
like as if he... as if he knew.
Sofia, you got to get it
out of your head; that's poison.
You telling me
you're not thinking about it?
Oh, I'm thinking; I'm thinking
about a lot of stuff.
Let me tell you something.
You know, when I was a young cop
in Jersey,
there was this kid--
responded to an
all shots fired.
Never got a radio call,
never knew what hit him.
I was the first officer
on the scene--
a patrolman, too.
You know, it tore up the
department pretty good.
Everybody was all twisted and...
but we managed somehow to...
I don't know,
get through it, some way.
Who shot him?
It really doesn't matter.
It does matter.
I could see Bell's face
when I was shooting him,
which means I was...
I was shooting near him.
I made a mistake.
I shouldn't have fired.
No, come on. It was chaos.
You were just responding
to a situation.
It was instinct,
it was training.
No.
Don't, don't
think that way.
I'm always going to be
the cop who shot a cop.
There's the green
Geo Metro.
Okay, you
come with me.
You two cover the back.
Stay with her.
( knocking )
Police! We have
a search warrant! Open up!
Hey!
Suspect on the run!
He's gonna meet you here.
Come on. Let's go.
We have her, Detective.
Wow. You had the baby
and got your figure back
in one day.
That's impossible.
Believe me, I know.
My wife's had
five kids.
Oh, Tina, baby-- no.
Peanut butter
without the jelly?
She's trying to get me
to cut down on sugar.
but this is ridiculous.
Here.
Thanks.
Do you ever want to be a cop?
Every time I get
a speeding ticket, yeah.
No, I mean like guns
and car chases
and "Put your back against
the wall," that kind of stuff.
No, I prefer the scientific side
of law enforcement.
Me, too.
( phone ringing )
Brown.
Hey, Catherine.
We got the couple
driving the Buick.
Female wasn't pregnant.
She was a mule.
Really.
Found her rig for transporting
narco inside the house,
and unless these guys were
in the mail order business,
I think they were
being shipped drugs.
BROWN:
And delivering them
to the guys up the food chain.
Yeah.
You think these are the same
guys who whacked Fausto?
It's the best lead we've got.
You were a passenger
in a stolen vehicle
that failed to yield
to the police.
We've also connected
you to a drug ring
which was responsible
for the death of
a police officer.
Miss Guerro?
You're looking at prison time,
so think about it.
Whatever you could tell
us about these guys
will be in your best interest.
Surveillance footage
from Angie's Donut Shop
shows you
carrying drugs
and getting into
the delivery car.
That alone gets you ten years.
Okay, this is
your last chance
for your client to
help herself out.
You don't understand.
We had no choice.
They would have killed us.
Who would've killed you?
There is nothing that
you can do to me
that is worse
than what they can do.
I'm done.
I'm not talking no more.
Mr. Contranos has served time
for narcotics possession.
He's been deported
three times
for entering
the country illegally.
This time, we're going
to throw away the key.
MAN:
Mr. Contranos has no interest
in speaking to you.
We're talking about
the difference between
life without parole
and the needle, here.
He's prepared to do his time.
Grissom, I managed
to get a hit
off of that sniper
cartridge case.
Links up to a drug rip-off
in L.A. last year-- unsolved.
What about the phone records
from the motel?
Fausto made one call about
an hour before he died.
We ran it down to a
disposable mobile phone.
So is there anything I can tell
the undersheriff?
Yeah. Dead end on Fausto.
You tell him.
I got your results
from the blood on the bullet.
It definitely belongs
to Officer Bell.
This is my first
deceased police officer.
I heard that his
wife is pregnant.
Wendy, you understand
that this is confidential.
Yes, sir.
And you can't discuss it,
even with your coworkers.
I understand what this means.
Hey. Warrick tell you
about the IBIS hit?
Yeah.
How are you doing
with Bell's bullet?
I was confirming my findings.
Don't want to make any mistakes.
Does that mean
you have results?
The bullet has the right GRC's
for a Sig-Sauer.
Sergeant Adams
carries a Beretta.
Carroll, too.
Davis has a Glock, so
that rules him out.
However, both detectives
Brass and Curtis carry Sigs.
But take a look.
There's hardly any jacket left.
Means there's almost
no chance of identifying that
to a specific gun.
What if you had more time?
Could you do it?
Sorry, boss.
I mean, there's just no way
I can tell you
who shot Officer Bell.
You know, based
on the dates
of these address labels,
it appears that Carlos
and Bianca
were receiving
two to three
drug shipments a day.
So the dogs hit on the boxes?
Yes, and Narco found
trace amounts of cocaine,
for whatever that's worth.
Well, the return
addresses are
all bogus,
the couple is not talking,
and all four suspects
are dead.
There's nothing more we can do.
Okay, Nick, the cruiser's
right front tire
is 19 feet, 5 inches
from the south curb.
Sara, the detective unit's
left front tire
is five feet to inches
from the south curb.
All right.
Nick, you be Brass.
Sara, you be Sofia.
Good.
I'll be Bell.
Officer Bell was crouched down
behind his door.
Gris! I can't see you from here.
You're blocked by both cars.
Yeah, me either.
I'd have to shoot
through both cars to get to you.
I processed them both--
no shots
entered from the back.
Can you see me here?
Yeah, I can see you.
Yeah, now.
What would make Bell stand up
in the middle of a gunfight?
Maybe he had
to change positions.
We know that the suspects
were starting
to run, right?
Okay, he popped up,
took one in the vest.
Let's assume that.
We'll line up the exit
trajectories
with the apartment window,
and we'll use lasers,
but we may have to wait
until it's dark.
WILLOWS:
We're turning on the lasers.
Is the candle in position?
Ready on this end.
Let me know when the beam
hits the candle.
Good to go!
Uh... good height.
Move it six inches to the left.
Six inches to the left.
Oh, no, no. My left.
He meant the other left.
Right there.
Perfect.
I'll call you back.
Okay, we got the exit.
Now we need the entrance.
Sara, turn your laser on.
The path of my laser is off.
Yeah, it's a bad angle.
Move it to the left.
Gris...
Hmm?
It's blocked
by the car.
It's not possible.
Turn it off.
Nick, turn yours on.
Mine's been on the whole time.
It's still blocked.
Raise it up.
He stood up.
Well, your call was
a little cryptic.
Must've got the results
from the ballistics test.
We did, but it
was inconclusive,
so I went back to the
intersection and ran
a reconstruction.
Well, I don't know how you
reconstruct a war zone.
You have no idea
what it was like.
I mean, it was a fire fight.
Have you talked to Sofia?
It wasn't Sofia.
You must have stood up...
fired at the suspects
over the black and whites.
Officer Bell stood
up at the same time,
right into your
line of fire.
Fausto shot him
in the vest, which
spun him a little.
At the same time,
you hit him in the neck.
( sighs )
Oh, I-I swear,
I was behind the car, I...
I-I stood up?
Sheriff wants me to
present our findings
at a community
meeting in an hour.
( sighs )
Don't keep 'em waiting.
ORTEGA:
I just received
a report from the
Shooting Review Board.
You've been cleared.
You can go back to work.
Thank you.
( indistinct voices )
Hello. My name is
Dr. Gil Grissom.
I'm the night shift supervisor
for the Las Vegas Police
Department's Crime Lab.
( murmuring fades )
I'm not a police officer;
I'm a scientist.
You work for the cops.
That makes you a cop.
You're not on our side.
( loud clamoring voices )
Actually,
I'm a forensics expert.
( murmuring fades )
My job is
to identify,
collect, and examine physical
evidence from a crime scene,
to determine who did what to
whom and how did they do it.
I've been asked to come here
today by the mayor
and Sheriff Burdick to present
our analysis of the evidence
in this case to your community.
Why aren't they here?
Why should we believe
your evidence?
( loud murmuring )
Physical evidence
cannot be wrong.
It doesn't lie.
It's not influenced by emotion
or prejudice.
( murmuring fades )
It's... it's not confused by
the excitement of the moment.
I'm here, in God's house,
to explain to you the truth
about exactly what happened
the other day.
I'd like to start by showing you
some photos.
This is a bullet
that was recovered
from the Kevlar vest
of Officer Daniel Bell,
now deceased.
What about my son?
What-What does the evidence say
about my son?
Okay, if you like,
we can start there.
Please.
This photo is a comparison of
two cartridge cases.
The one on the right was found
next to your son.
The one on the left
was test-fired
from Jose Fausto's pistol.
As you can see, there are
corresponding individual marks
on both cartridges.
These are unique,
like fingerprints.
It means that they were
fired from the same gun.
It proves that while attempting
to escape from the police...
Jose Fausto shot your son
Geraldo in the back.
Why would he do that?
We recovered your son's bicycle
from Jose Fausto's motel room.
Your son was on his way
to football practice.
( gunshot )
( groans )
It appears that Jose Fausto
shot your son
so he could use his bike.
( indistinct voices )
Jim, I was just on
my way out, but if you
want me to stay...
No, I-I think I
can handle it.
I think.
Thanks.
Okay.
( indistinct voices )
( sighs )
The Shooting Review Board wants
to talk to you.
You're going to have to explain
your tactical decision
for shooting in the direction
of a fellow officer.
I'm ready
when they are.
As far as I'm concerned,
there's no question...
it was a bad shoot.
I'll have to
live with that.
( sighs )
( chuckles )
Oh, whoa!
Hey. What's your name?
Jeannie.
Well, that's a pretty name.
Is that your mom over there?
Huh? Okay,
be careful, Jeannie...
♪ ♪
( voice breaking ):
Mrs. Bell... I'm Jim Brass.
I know.
I want you to know...
if there's, um...
if there's any, um...
( gentle sobs )
( whispers ):
I know it wasn't your fault.
( weeping )
I... I'm...
I'm so sorry.