( thunder rumbling )
( phone ringing )
MAN:
LVPD. Officer Mularz.
May I help you?
Is there somebody there?
( whispering ):
I'd like to report
a murder.
Your name?
Hello?
Is there somebody there?
The body can be found
at 1812 White Oak Road.
I'd like to help you.
Please identify yourself.
Send someone
to pick up the body.
( indistinct
radio transmission )
BRASS:
So an anonymous call
came into metro
about an hour ago.
Investigating officer
found the dead body.
The coroner's inside.
The, uh... the door
was open.
Unlocked.
So the house is owned
by the decedent,
Hayden Bradford.
Neighbor says he lives alone.
The floor is covered
in hair.
Has he got a cat
or a dog?
Nope.
But as you
can see
our dead guy is...
I guess you could say
he's hirsute.
"Hirsute" is
an understatement.
It's like
he's wearing a pelt.
( cell phone buzzing )
Hey, David,
would you
grab that?
( buzzing continues )
Thanks.
A missed call
from a Michelle.
She called six times
since 3:53 p.m.
Liver temp's 80 degrees.
Been dead around 12 hours.
Which makes T.O.D.
around 3:00 p.m.
PHILLIPS:
Explains why he didn't
take her calls.
C.O.D.--
bullet to the chest.
These strands are smooth,
not coarse.
They're human.
Are the roots intact?
Yeah.
Evidently,
this guy was shedding.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
WILLOWS:
Hey, Dave, James.
Hey, Dave, you've got
to pick it up.
Lift with the knees, Super Dave,
lift with the knees.
Yeah.
Thanks, I...
have done this before.
SIDLE:
Hey.
WILLOWS:
So, Brass gave us
a quick briefing.
How can we help?
Warrick and I are processing
the interior, room to room.
So that leaves the perimeter.
Thanks.
Well, this victim definitely had
a lady in his life.
That's odd.
There is not a single
feminine touch
in this house.
Michelle.
Christmas, 2004.
It's got to be the same Michelle
that tried to reach him
six times on his cell phone.
Broken window.
Yeah.
It slides.
The front door was locked.
The killer probably broke
the window
and exited out the front.
I'll need to print
the window, but, uh...
why don't we get
to this first.
Doesn't look big enough
to have done the job.
We have a print.
"Hey, Jackass--
"this is your last chance.
Pay your debt or I'll hunt
you down."
Makes our job easier when
the suspect prints
out his motive.
He has an e-mail printout
from CasinoDan@gmail.com
to Misterbradford@gmail.com.
Well, that ain't
no anthill.
That dirt's fresh.
Looks like something's
buried there.
Oh, my God...!
.32 Beretta.
Victim was shot, right?
It's going to be hard
to get a print,
but I'll get it
to ballistics.
GRISSOM:
Well, we knew
he was hairy.
I didn't realize
the full extent.
ROBBINS:
Hypertrichosis.
I've only read about it.
Excessive hair growth.
Genetic.
Extremely rare.
His case was relatively mild.
In some individuals, hair grows
everywhere
except the eyes and the mouth.
The human werewolf syndrome.
In Mexico, there's a family
30 members
are afflicted.
Two of the teen boys were
recently adopted
by the national circus.
Great. The bearded lady,
the dog-faced boy--
Physical deformities
as family entertainment.
I cleared a path
for the bullet.
I figured
you'd want to get this
to ballistics ASAP.
Thanks, Al.
You know, Gil,
we're all intrigued
by our nightmares,
and when we watch freak shows,
basically we're all thinking
the same thing.
Yeah, I'm glad they're not
looking at me.
Hey, Archie.
Hey.
Please tell me you've
I.D.'d Casino Dan.
Yep. The ISP provider
sent over the subscriber
information
for a CasinoDan@gmail.com.
It's registered to a Dan Nobler,
who runs
a gambling Web site.
SANDERS:
If I wanted to visit Dan in
person, where would I go?
Well, the server for
CasinoDan.com is in Argentina,
which allows him to skirt
U.S. gaming laws.
However, he's got a Nevada
business license.
And I have the address.
Anything else I should know?
Uh, well, I don't know
if it's relevant,
but he recently opened
an account
with Peopledectors.com.
Who was he looking for?
I don't know.
I'll triage
the computer's hard drive.
Reconstruct
the deleted e-mails.
I'll get back to you on that.
Can I help you?
You Dan Nobler?
Yeah.
We're from
the crime lab.
We need to ask you
a few questions.
Look, if you're here
about my business,
you can save it
for my attorney.
No, actually we're
inquiring about a
Mr. Hayden Bradford.
You sent him
some threatening
e-mails.
Bradford is a lying
son of a bitch.
Care to elaborate
on that?
I run an online
gambling business.
Bradford had an account,
ran up $10,000 in debt
and refused to pay.
Isn't it true in
online gambling
you have to submit
your credit card,
prior to gambling,
to insure your losses?
That's true.
And when Bradford was winning,
it wasn't a problem.
But when his luck changed,
he called his credit card holder
and said the charges
were fraudulent.
The credit card company
issued a charge back
and I got screwed.
Is that when you decided
to hunt him down?
Look, I wrote him an e-mail
hoping to scare him.
Sorry. I was angry.
If I write an apology,
can we drop this?
No, Mr. Nobler, I'm sorry,
we can't do that.
Mr. Bradford's dead.
Any other questions,
contact my lawyer.
We're done here.
You see that?
Yeah, the guy's a jerk.
No, he wiped
his feet on the mat.
I'm hoping to get a little
trace evidence here.
Yeah, you see these pebbles?
They look like the same ones
that were found
at the crime scene.
Fire in the hole!
Bobby.
Hey.
So, that, uh, buried gun
y'all recovered,
wasn't used
to kill Bradford.
WILLOWS:
GRCs aren't even close.
Most bullets are copper,
but take a look
at the fatal bullet.
It's silver.
How do you kill a werewolf?
( knocking on door )
No one's home.
We want to see the wolfman.
Yeah, well, he's not
available right now.
I am trying
to prep him
for autopsy.
Wow.
And I thought Robin Williams
had hairy arms.
Can I touch him?
You mean "pet" him.
No!
You may not touch
or pet the decedent.
Is it soft like fur or...?
I was supposed to have
him prepped hours ago.
Please.
Okay, you guys gotta go.
Relax, Dave.
It's not every day
that Chaka ends up
on a slab.
Yeah, I need you to leave.
Whoa.
Fine, but if I get
a sleestak in my lab,
and you want to see it,
I'm gonna get cranky.
Mr. Moyer, you're here
about Hayden Bradford.
Do you know him?
Of course.
He's one of my closest friends.
Yeah... Yeah, I'm sorry.
We found his body this morning.
You didn't recently try
to break in his home...
did you?
Excuse me. What?
We found a rock
by a broken window,
With your
fingerprint on it.
( chuckles )
Is that funny?
No. It's just. uh...
last week we were
playing toss with a ball.
That still doesn't explain to me
how your fingerprint got there.
There was glass everywhere,
so I knocked out
the loose pieces.
You guys being good friends...
you were aware of his
medical condition, right?
That he was a hairy S.O.B.?
Yeah. Of course. Why?
Do you know why anybody'd
want to hurt him?
He's a friendly, quiet guy.
I've known him
since high school.
He's been dating my sister.
Oh, God.
She doesn't know
yet, does she?
Who, Michelle?
Yeah.
I tried to call
her cell phone and...
She's at my parents,
in Pahrump.
Her cell's probably
out of range.
But you can get me their home
number, address, all that?
Sure.
But if it's okay, I'd...
I should break the news
to her in person.
I've been waiting for you.
Sorry. I headed out
as soon as I got your page.
Really? 'Cause, uh...
I left a voicemail
several hours ago.
What's up?
The anonymous call
was traced to this phone booth,
so I figured
you'd want to process.
SIDLE:
There is fingerprint
powder on the phone.
Yeah, I got bored waiting.
I thought you might
need some help.
No usable prints,
but check out the floor.
SIDLE:
There's a lot of hair.
Similar to the crime scene.
The victim was killed 12 hours
before this call was made.
If that's his hair,
what's it doing here?
The hair isn't Hayden's.
The chromosomes are XX.
Female.
Yeah.
So I took the liberty
of comparing the
sample's DNA
to the victim's DNA.
There are seven alleles
in common.
Brother and sister.
Mm-hmm.
She's likely our
anonymous caller.
Yeah, well, given the amount
of hair that you collected,
she's also probably
a very hairy woman.
Wendy, can you
do me a favor?
Hmm?
Can you see if any of the
follicles from the crime scene
are a match to the hairs
from the phone booth?
You want to see if the sister
was in the victim's house.
If she was,
she's not just the caller,
she's a suspect.
I hear the vic
has a sister.
A twin sister, in fact.
I tracked down the victim's
birth certificate.
He was born to a Rita Bradford
in Fresno, California.
Ms. Bradford
apparently had twins,
Hayden and Allison.
There's no record
of any other children.
I'm assuming you
contacted Allison.
Well, that's where
it gets odd.
Allison Bradford has never
filed with the IRS,
has never had
a driver's license,
has never filled out a W-2.
How do you go through life
without a paper trail?
She's dead.
There's no record
of a death certificate.
We found her hair
in the phone booth.
And DNA just confirmed
that some of the hair
follicles that we collected
at the crime scene
are hers.
Well, other than hair,
when you and Warrick
processed the house,
did you find any
evidence of a sister?
No, but we were
not looking for one.
We are now.
♪ ♪
Catherine, I've covered
the kitchen.
I've found no evidence
of a sister living here.
Ditto for the bedroom.
I think I'm gonna take
a look outside.
I'll do the same.
Thanks, guys.
( grunts )
WOMAN:
Please go away.
Allison?
ALLISON:
This is my home.
I would like you to leave.
Allison...
I need to talk with you.
Can you please come out?
I'd rather not.
Allison, my name is
Catherine Willows.
I'm with the Las
Vegas crime lab.
I know that you suffer
from hypertrichosis.
I understand why you would
rather not talk with me.
But we need to discuss
your brother's murder.
Would you please come out?
May I...?
Would you step out?
Please?
You want to see
what I look like?
No, I... No.
I don't want you to
have to hide from me.
Allison...
I'm a scientist.
Excess body hair
does not evoke fear...
or morbid fascination.
It's simply a genetic quirk,
like...
blue eyes or flat feet.
It's nice to
meet you, Allison.
How can I help you,
Ms. Willows?
What can you tell me
about your brother's murder?
No one knows I live here, so
when we get a visitor,
I go to my room.
Yesterday, around 3:30,
the doorbell rang.
( doorbell ringing )
Just a sec!
And when I came out
of my room, Hayden was dead.
Why did you wait 12 hours
to call the police?
Because I didn't want
the call traced to the house,
back to me, so...
I waited till
midnight, and then
I walked to a pay phone.
You weren't supposed to find me.
Do you have any idea why someone
would want to hurt your brother?
No.
He was my only friend.
( whimpers )
He was my connection
to the outside world.
What about your parents?
I never knew my father.
My mother died when
we were teenagers.
No one else knows
that you exist?
I hope... I hope you'll help me.
Help you-- with what?
Staying secret.
It's best for everyone.
Hey, Grissom, you got a second?
Did you know the word "werewolf"
was derived
from the Old English word
"wargwolf," which is
a synonym for "serial killer"?
No, I didn't.
Imagine if you had
some deep, dark secret...
something that brought you
tremendous shame.
but instead
of being able to hide it away,
you had to wear it
out on your skin,
so that the first time anyone
saw you, they saw your secret.
You talking about Allison?
Yeah.
Catherine said she's scared
to death of people
and what they'll think of her.
Well, if that's the case,
why not try electrolysis
or depilatory lasers?
With that much hair--
be a lot of scarring,
and a great deal of pain.
Plus, imagine how
expensive it would be.
What have you got?
Well, I just ran into Archie.
The decedent used a company
called peopledetectors.com
to try to locate his mother.
Catherine spoke to Allison.
Their mother's dead.
Apparently not.
She's alive and well,
and has an address in Henderson,
so I'm gonna go out
there, check it out.
Hey, Nick.
Yeah.
Bring her back here, will you?
Sure. Why?
I want to talk to her.
Find out why a mother
would play dead.
Oh, good,
you're here.
I love an audience.
Well, don't expect
any applause.
What do you got?
I compared pebbles
from the crime scene
to the pebbles
from Dan Nobler's doormat.
They're consistent
with each other--
a composite commonly known
as pea gravel.
The pebbles weren't
the only trace elements
I found
in that doormat.
I also found several
slivers of glass...
glass consistent
with a broken window.
I'm here about pebbles
and glass.
Come on.
Look, this is ridiculous.
I mean, we're talking about
trace evidence on a doormat?
Come on.
Besides,
I read the file.
A guy named Brent Moyer already
admitted to breaking the window.
WARRICK:
This is true; he did.
But we believe
that Mr. Nobler here
stepped in the
shards of glass.
Listen, neither the glass
nor the pebbles
are probative
on their own,
but together, they put
your client at the crime scene.
Not to mention,
his threatening e-mail
gives us motive.
Fine. I was there.
Dan...
No, look, I get ripped off
by jerks all over the world.
This guy was a local.
I knew his address
and, yeah,
I wanted to shake him down.
Let him know that by declaring
credit card fraud,
he was stealing from me.
Okay, I'm listening.
A few days ago,
I went over to his house.
Then I started thinking,
"What if this guy's
like twice my size?"
I figured I should get
a look at him
before I had
our "conversation,"
so I went around back...
( shards crack, tinkle )
Hey...
Hey, hey!
At first, I thought
he was wearing a costume,
but then I realized, it was...
it was real hair.
Disgusting, right?
What happened next?
Well, when the dude saw me,
I took off.
Why?
Uh, he was a freak of nature.
I no longer wish
to speak with him.
♪ ♪
Hey, man.
Hey.
What are you smiling about?
Oh, I was just thinking
of The Howling II;
the werewolf bitch.
I don't care what anyone says.
It was much better
than the first one.
Is it?
Yeah, yeah.
I got the whole
anthology.
Want to borrow it?
No, thanks. I would like to know
about my bullet, however.
I assume it was homemade
since the manufacturer
doesn't sell it in silver.
Right.
Simple clamshell mold.
92.5% pure with trace amounts
of copper,
nickel and chromium lead.
Elemental properties
are consistent with
sterling silver jewelry.
And sterling silver
has a high melting point.
Someone went through a lot
of trouble to make it.
Sorry I didn't get here sooner.
I was pretty upset.
Michelle, your relationship
with Hayden, was it serious?
We were engaged.
I can't believe he's gone.
The day he died,
you called him six times.
There was a golf tournament
on ESPN that night.
He wanted me
to tape it for him.
I was trying to reach him
because I was at my folks' place
and the VCR was broken.
Sounds so silly now.
I'd like to see him...
to say good-bye.
He's with the coroner.
Michelle, I understand
that you were at your folks
and you were trying
to get ahold of Hayden
on your cell,
but we were unable
to reach you on it.
Can you explain?
I called Hayden so many times
that my battery died.
I'm sorry.
Do you have any idea
who could have done this?
You know about his condition,
right?
It made him
really sweet.
I mean, it was like he was
constantly trying to make up
for his physical imperfections
by doing everything perfectly.
He was the perfect
boyfriend,
the perfect lover,
my best friend.
I don't know what
I'm going to do without him.
WOMAN:
I was in labor for 27 hours.
They didn't want to come out.
Who could blame 'em.
Mrs. Bradford, why does Allison
think you're dead?
I thought
it would be easier.
Easier than what?
I did the best
I could, Mr. Grissom.
Their father couldn't
look at 'em.
Took off when
they were a few weeks old.
Babies are supposed to be cute.
Mrs. Bradford...?
At the time, we were living
in Fresno.
Family, friends stopped
visiting.
They were scared of my children.
Especially Allison.
She... she looked like...
When she started nursery school,
the kids teased her,
called her names, made her cry.
So you moved to Vegas and
decided to keep her a secret?
It was best for everyone.
But she became completely
dependent on me,
and for 18 years,
I took care of her.
I'm sorry, but I still
don't understand
why she believes you're dead.
One day, Allison wanted to take
a walk... outside.
I didn't want anyone to see her.
We had a fight.
I locked her in her room--
my own child-- because
she wanted fresh air.
At that moment,
I knew I needed
to leave.
I told Hayden to tell her I was
in a car accident.
Two days later, he put on
a black suit,
told her he was going
to my funeral.
And she didn't go because
she couldn't leave the house.
You thought it would be easier
for her to accept your death
than your abandonment?
Please don't judge me.
I spend enough time
doing that.
I'm just trying to find out
who killed your son.
I haven't seen either of them
for seven years.
I wouldn't have any idea.
You know, Mrs. Bradford,
your daughter's all alone now.
It's not too late
for you to go back to her.
And tell her what?
That I faked my death
to escape from her?
How do you say that
to your own flesh and blood?
What's up with the 911?
David didn't notice the victim's
lividity at the crime scene
because it was obscured
by his body hair.
But when we shaved him...
Well, check out his left side.
So it was on his side
where the blood settled.
Correct,
but he was found faceup.
So, uh, somebody moved him
several hours postmortem.
There's more.
Vic was found
on a hardwood floor,
but when David brushed
his body hair for trace,
he found blue carpet fibers.
Well, there was blue carpet
in the sister's room.
Hayden was shot
through the chest,
it would have exsanguinated
on impact.
Any blood in the sister's room?
I'll get back to you
on that one.
( knocking )
Allison, it's Catherine.
I need you to step out.
ALLISON:
Who else is there?
There's another woman with me.
Allison, I'm Detective Curtis.
I need to get
inside your room.
Thank you.
♪ ♪
ALLISON:
I don't know
anything about it.
You can't expect us
to believe
that you live
in a secret room
that only you go into,
yet you can't explain why
your bed is covering up blood.
Did you kill him?
What?!
Did you?
Hayden's all I had.
He's the only one that knew
about me.
Why would I kill him?
Because he was going
to leave you...
for Michelle.
That had to have
been scary for you.
You think
I'm some sort of animal?
I wanted him
to be happy.
I loved Hayden,
I wanted him to be happy.
Did Michelle
know about you?
No, but he said that
he was going to tell her
and that she was
going to move in here
and she would accept me--
Hayden promised.
Allison...
if you didn't kill him,
who did?
Okay, I'm sorry.
We can do this here
or we can take this downtown.
No, please.
Please.
I know that you're scared...
but you have got
to tell us what happened.
The doorbell rang.
I went into my room.
Allison,
where's the gun?
I... I...
Damn it, Allison,
where's the gun?
( gunshot )
And when he was shot,
what did you do?
I hid.
Behind the door.
Was the television on?
No.
It's busted.
It hasn't worked in years.
So you had a pretty good view
of the living room
through the reflection
in the tube.
What did you see?
Freak.
You're sure that it was Brent?
I've seen him
through the peephole.
They were best friends.
Okay, um...
let's just go back to the gun.
A couple of days ago,
Hayden said he saw a guy
sneaking around the back.
So he bought me
a gun for safety.
But I don't like guns
so... I just buried it
in the backyard.
Yes, we found it.
Allison...
why was it so difficult
for you to tell us the truth?
I think you're going
to make me testify and I won't
do that.
I want Brent to go to jail, but
I won't be the sideshow freak.
Well, we can try to build
a case without you.
You can't get a warrant
unless she goes on record.
Well, just hear me out.
We have a rock with Brent
Moyer's fingerprints on it.
Yeah, but Allison told you
that Brent entered
through the front door.
The rock is extraneous
evidence, isn't it?
Well, let's just leave
Allison's testimony out of it.
We simply inform the judge
that our suspect's fingerprints
were on a rock that may have
been used to break a window
at the murder scene.
If you have no qualms
about filing the petition,
then file it.
Oh, no, I don't
have any qualms.
It's just that
my moral compass
doesn't always point in
the same direction as yours.
So if I tell you not
to file it, you won't?
I'd take it
under advisement.
Why, is that what
you're recommending?
How many times have
we been prevented
from getting a warrant
when we knew
we had the right guy?
Way too many.
Right.
So rock and roll.
( knocking on door )
Las Vegas PD.
We have a search warrant.
What's going on?
Please step outside.
Why would I kill my best friend?
CURTIS:
That's a very good
question.
A bullet clamshell
isn't enough for
the DA to file.
What am I missing here?
Our trace lab analyzed the
silver found in the bullet mold.
It's identical composition
to the bullet in the victim.
DA says it's a slam dunk.
Hayden was going to marry
my sister.
Brent, I recommend that...
I couldn't let that happen.
He was diseased.
Wasn't a problem for me.
But my sister deserved better.
So you killed him?
Did you see his body?
Hayden was a monster passing
for a Regular Joe.
My parents blamed me
for introducing them.
You know, the werewolf disease,
it's hereditary.
It means my sister
could've given birth to freaks.
And the silver bullet?
Figured it was appropriate.
So you left your parents',
you went back
to your place
to make the bullet
and then you went over
to Hayden's.
Yeah.
So it was premeditated.
I guess you can forget
heat of the moment
as a mitigating
factor here.
I did the right thing.
My sister's
out there waiting.
Since I confessed,
can I at least go out
and talk to her?
Explain why I did it.
Why don't I do that for you.
Ms. Moyer...
your brother confessed
to killing Hayden.
After our last conversation,
I checked the TV listings.
There was no golf
tournament that night.
I think you were calling
Hayden to warn him about Brent.
I had just announced our
engagement to my family.
Brent flipped out.
I was upset.
Everyone was yelling at me.
I went for a long walk
to clear my head.
And when I got back,
Brent was gone.
He told my parents
that he was going to
"speak" with Hayden.
But you had your doubts.
My brother has a temper.
Why didn't you
tell us this before?
When Brent called and told me
that Hayden was dead,
he said that if
I told you guys...
if I implicated him...
He threatened you.
It's okay.
You're safe now.
Allison...
what are you going
to do now?
I'll be okay.
It's not like when I was a kid.
I can pretty much get anything
I need off the internet.
WILLOWS:
And you're set with money?
ALLISON:
I'll manage.
Allison, I have
every confidence
that you're going to be
just fine here, but...
if you ever need anything,
would you please give me a call?
I-I will, Ms. Willows.
Catherine.
I haven't been completely honest
with you.
I told you
my mother was dead,
but that's not true.
I'm not sure I follow.
Hayden told me she was
in a car wreck
and I called the funeral home
to send flowers.
They had never heard of her,
so I called the local
hospitals, same thing.
Recently, I contacted
peopledetectors.com
and, apparently,
she lives in Las Vegas.
She just couldn't live with me.
WILLOWS:
So you were the one that
contacted peopledetectors.
ALLISON:
Yeah.
When my brother was out,
I used his computer.