( grunts )
CURTIS:
Stacy Vollmer was last seen
practicing alone
on the school tennis court
that Friday at around 9:00 p.m.
The clothes she was wearing
were found in her locker.
Her body was discovered
near the football field
by the landscaping crew
the following Monday morning.
Can you tell us
the exact location of the body?
She was dumped in a flower bed,
wrapped in a shower curtain.
( sirens blaring )
CSI arrived an hour later,
excavated the body
and began processing the
scene.
SINCLAIR:
Dr. Robbins, can you tell us
how Stacy died?
ROBBINS:
Beneath this laceration,
I found a complex fracture
of the occipital bone.
Multiple shards of bone were
driven into the occipital lobe
of the brain,
resulting in massive bleeding.
The cause of death was
cerebral hemorrhage,
consistent with a single,
sharp blow to her head.
A search of the
defendant's home
yielded a
laundry hamper
containing the
clothes he wore
the night of
the murder.
SINCLAIR:
Did you find any blood
or DNA on the clothes?
No. We determined
they had been bleached.
Isn't bleach used to destroy
blood and DNA evidence?
Objection: argumentative.
SINCLAIR:
Withdrawn.
What else did you find
in the house?
Human hairs consistent
with the victim
were discovered in the drain
of the bathroom sink.
DNA was extracted
and was also matched
to the victim.
And based on this evidence,
police arrested Marlon West.
That's correct.
SINCLAIR:
Thank you, Mr. Stokes.
No further questions.
The State now calls Hannah West.
ALLRED:
Your Honor,
defense reiterates
our objection.
She's a 12-year-old girl.
JUDGE:
We've been through
this already, counsel.
The defendant's sister is being
called as a hostile witness.
That means the district attorney
is permitted
to ask leading
questions.
Be nice.
Now, Hannah,
isn't it a fact
that on the night
of Friday, December 2, 2005,
your parents left you
and your brother,
the defendant,
home alone?
They went away for a...
Yes or no, please.
Yes.
SINCLAIR:
And isn't it
also a fact
that you and your
brother were not together
between the hours
of 6:00 and 10:00 p.m.?
Well, Marlon--
he didn't really...
Yes or no?
Yes.
SINCLAIR:
Thank you, Hannah.
I'd like to say something...
No further questions,
Your Honor.
Cross-examination?
Absolutely, Your Honor.
Uh, Hannah,
wh-what were
you trying to say?
Objection:
calls for a narrative.
Overruled.
ALLRED:
You go ahead, Hannah.
You say
what you need to say.
Marlon didn't kill Stacy.
( crowd murmuring )
I did.
And I was wearing this
when I did it.
♪ ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
Good news is Judge
Crawford denied
the defense's
motion to dismiss.
Of course he did.
She's just a mixed-up kid
trying to protect
her older brother.
All the evidence
points to Marlon.
Yeah, and all the jury's
going to remember
is a little girl
in a bloody shirt
confessing to murder.
That's reasonable doubt
on a silver platter.
All right, then we have to prove
that Hannah could not
have done this.
Exactly.
We'll need a week
to reexamine the evidence.
Judge gave the D.A.
a 72-hour continuance.
Come on...
Best he could
do, Nick.
Now you go do your best.
MARLON:
Everybody thought
Stacy was so...
special.
She thought so, too.
She wasn't.
Stacy was a stuck-up bitch
and a miserable person.
I just put her
out of her misery.
( sighs )
I killed her and I put her
in the ground.
That's all I've got to say.
The judge suppressed
the video
because a child advocate
was never brought in,
even though Marlon
had waived his rights.
We really didn't need
a confession out of him.
The case against this kid
was solid.
It started out as a prank:
a sabotaged showerhead.
( explosion )
( shrieking )
PH tests later revealed
the presence
of a strong
base substance
which was
later identified
as sodium hydroxide.
Sounds like Marlon packed
the showerhead
with elemental sodium.
A high school chemistry
favorite, yeah.
Just add water,
and instant kaboom.
BROWN:
Those out-of-order signs
must've been part
of his game.
You funnel the victim
to the right showerhead.
Did you process these?
Yeah, I matched
the spindle marks on the paper
to a laser printer
in the high
school library.
Accessible to any student.
Mm-hmm.
"Multiple fragments of metal
penetrating the skin and dermis
"as deep as
the superficial musculature
of the back
and neck."
The showerhead explosion
didn't kill her.
No, no, it did not.
What happened
to the shower curtain?
STOKES:
Well, the vic was injured,
disoriented.
She grabbed the first thing
she could to cover up and ran.
( shrieking )
STOKES:
The intermittent blood trail
started in the locker room
and headed down a hall.
So Marlon followed her out
just to hear her squeal?
Or chased her out, yeah.
There's no way
to know.
Either way, she ended up
at the bottom of the stairs.
The size of the blood pool
indicates that the fatal wound
occurred there.
Do you have
any physical evidence
that would conclusively rule
Hannah out as a suspect?
Well, yeah-- she's
four-foot-three and 65 pounds.
The crime just required
more strength than she's got.
How old is she?
Twelve.
In high school?
She's a high school senior.
She skipped
six grades.
She's a prodigy.
Which means she has the brains
for murder.
Yeah, but not the brawn.
The body was moved
from the high school building
across a
football field
and then hastily buried.
The vic's car was then driven
two miles from campus
and parked in front of the house
of a kid named
Scott Baird,
Stacy's boyfriend--
I think possibly to frame him.
Was he ever a suspect?
No. He plays varsity hoops.
He was out of town
on an away game.
I found blades of grass
with blood on them
near the vic's car--
nondescript tracks
headed towards
the next-door
neighbor's house.
Marlon West.
Yeah. This kid's been
in trouble before.
Multiple fights, threats.
It just got out
of hand this time.
Marlon West
killed Stacy Vollmer.
His little sister's just trying
to exonerate him.
♪ ♪
Hey, Nick.
Hodges, did you get
the soil analysis back
on Hannah's shirt?
Matches the site
of the body dump.
Really!
So does this make
Doogie Howser-ette your killer?
Uh, I kind of doubt it.
Don't be so sure. It's not easy.
What isn't easy, Hodges?
Being profoundly gifted,
knowing that everybody
knows that you're always
ten steps ahead of them.
It's a lot of pressure.
Some days, you feel
like you're just
going to snap.
I know the feeling.
SIDLE:
In his confession,
Marlon basically said
that Stacy deserved to die.
He was alone
in that opinion.
Everybody loved Stacy--
parents and students.
4.0 GPA, varsity tennis
team, homecoming queen.
She even took a public
virginity pledge
with some of
her classmates.
Did they have those
in your high school?
No.
Do you believe
that Marlon killed her?
I was looking
right into his eyes
when he told
me he did it.
There's no doubt
in my mind.
CURTIS:
Two confessions,
one crime.
We don't get
that a lot.
When did you last
speak with Marlon?
The day the police came
to my house and arrested him.
You don't visit him?
My parents won't let me
see him in jail.
Bad environment.
Marlon didn't put me up
to this.
He was trying to protect me.
It would've been wrong
to let him be punished
for something I did.
You don't think
I could have done it.
Neither one of you.
That's a big job
for a little girl.
Not if you have
the right tools.
Smart kid like you...
knows your brother's suffering.
You feel bad,
you want to help,
so you fabricate some evidence.
If you thought
that the evidence was fake,
I wouldn't still be in jail.
Aren't you going to ask me
why I did it?
Would you like to tell us?
I throw off the curve.
When I'm in a class,
people who usually get A's,
suddenly get C's.
Stacy was applying
to Harvard.
She wanted me
to dumb myself down.
I said no.
She didn't like that.
( indistinct chatting )
Uh... babies use the wall dryer.
( laughter )
So you killed her
because she messed up your hair?
No.
I'm used to pranks like that.
I get them most every day.
But Stacy...
didn't stop there.
She had to take it
to another level.
And she used Scott to do it.
Scott Baird, Stacy's boyfriend.
I was his tutor.
SCOTT:
You know,
I was really pissed off
at Stacy when I heard
about the whole...
hair dryer thing,
but her... her friends
had put her up to it.
Stacy wanted me
to give you something.
It's a
peace offering.
I think you'll look great
in it at the Spring Formal.
Oh, you are so going.
You like him.
He's on the basketball team.
I'm 12; I'm not allowed
to like him, but...
I went anyway.
( rock music playing )
Over here.
( laughing )
( camera shutter clicks )
( laughter )
The pictures were up
on MySpace that night.
I got a ton of e-mails.
You put sodium in the showerhead
to get back at her?
A prank for a prank.
I thought that there'd be
a few sparks,
that she'd freak out
and that'd be it,
but the nozzle exploded.
Stacy ran... and fell
down the stairs...
and died.
I tried to cover it up.
You miscalculated.
I guess I did.
You rang?
Got the DNA results on the blood
from Hannah's sweater.
Stacy.
Hannah.
So she fabricated
evidence,
and put her own
blood on the shirt.
Maybe, maybe not.
The soil on the shirt was
consistent with the dump site.
Hannah could've been
at the scene.
She could have cut herself
burying the body.
Or she could have gone
back to the field
at any time
within the last four months
and rubbed her shirt in
the same kind of dirt.
And counted on us
to make the match?
Well, that's just plain
scary smart.
I mean, my daughter's
a few years older than her,
and the most important thing
on her mind right now
is how much belly button
to show off at the mall.
( chuckles )
Never thought I'd be grateful
for that.
WOMAN:
You have to understand.
My child's not capable
of murder.
I assume you mean Hannah.
Of course.
Well, Marlon's your child, too.
Marlon's from my wife's
first marriage.
He's more like
his father.
( latch clicks )
STOKES:
This is Marlon's room.
No kidding.
It's pretty much
the way I left it.
The bleached clothes
were in the hamper.
But the real action...
was in here.
Shared bathroom.
Very Brady.
Pulled Stacy's hairs
out of the sink trap
the first time through.
And I found
some burn marks
around the
bathtub drain.
pH tested positive for
sodium hydroxide, so...
I figured Marlon
probably did a test run.
The scope of the warrant
only covered Marlon's room
and other common areas
of the house.
I popped my
head in here.
Nothing in plain
sight at the time.
Was this here before?
It wasn't
in plain sight.
I didn't check it.
Looks like Hannah
won the science fair
with a project
about sodium.
Hannah's just trying
to help Marlon.
So they're close?
No, not really.
Sometimes I think
if they didn't share a bathroom,
they wouldn't see each other
at all.
What do you mean?
They're on different
academic tracks.
Never take any of
the same classes,
and travel in completely
different social circles.
From what we understand,
Hannah doesn't really have
a social circle.
The other students bore her.
Hannah spends most of her time
with her teachers.
And Marlon?
I guess...
I guess he spends most
of his time alone.
( camera shutter clicking )
"Rainbow party"?!
Yeah, it's a party game
where boys get the girls
to wear different
colored lipsticks
while they have oral sex.
Boy with the most colors wins.
Supposed to
be trendy.
So much for
"Spin the Bottle."
Carrie.
"Weird high school girl
"gets humiliated
at the prom,
only to exact
her revenge."
Hannah wanted us to find this.
Maybe.
Question is,
did she read the book before...
or after the murder?
We had Hannah's I.Q. tested
when she was eight.
It's 177.
She really is one in a million.
Hannah's special.
She's an indigo child.
Indigo child?
A new breed.
Hannah doesn't just
see the world,
she sees through it,
through people,
with an intuition
none of us can comprehend.
She's compelled
to help others,
whether they're worth helping
or not.
♪ ♪
Ah, the shower curtain
the vic was wrapped in.
Yeah, I had Mandy
run the unknowns
from the original case
against Hannah's prints.
She got a match.
Okay.
But Hannah uses those showers
after gym class.
This curtain was used in
the handicapped shower.
Why would she do that?
Probably hiding her body.
She's 12.
She hasn't reached puberty.
Undeveloped teen girls
are very self-conscious.
Mm-hmm.
Four... fingers,
closely spaced.
Grabbing, maybe.
Could be from Hannah
dragging Stacy's body.
Hannah weighed 65 pounds.
Stacy about a hundred.
Dead weight.
Plastic slides on grass.
It makes it easier.
It's certainly possible.
D.A.'s not going to
like the sound of that.
( door shuts )
MAN:
Sodium demonstration
is always
a real crowd pleaser.
( chuckles )
It's ended up in a senior
prank more than once.
I keep it over here,
under lock and key,
but, unfortunately, the lab's
always getting broken into.
It's certainly possible
Marlon got the sodium from here.
Everyone have
their goggles on?
( students shouting )
Which is precisely
what I told the cops
four months ago.
You need gloves
to handle elemental sodium.
Of course.
It burns skin.
We keep it in kerosene
to stabilize it.
Do you think it's possible that
Hannah could have stolen it?
Hannah would
never do that.
I'm just wondering
if it's possible.
She obviously has access
to this room.
Ms. Sidle...
I've had my share of good
students over the years,
but Hannah...
Sometimes, right in the
middle of a lecture,
I'll catch her
staring at some
little thing in the yard--
a tree, a squirrel...
and all I can think about
is how much I wish
I could see it
the way she does.
If Hannah came
up and asked me
for a chunk of sodium,
I'd give it to her,
just to see what
she would do with it.
The victim's car.
Originally impounded...
in front of
Scott Baird's house.
Traces of blood and soil
consistent with the crime
were found
in the front seat.
Now, if Hannah's the killer,
she had to drive this car.
Well, it's got adjustable seats,
tilt and telescoping
steering wheel--
it's certainly possible.
Soil and blood
on the carpet.
That was in the report.
But this wasn't.
( tool ratcheting )
( grunting )
I'd say the killer
moved the seat.
Yeah.
12-year-old killer, huh?
Starting to look
that way, yeah.
I bet that Grand Theft Auto
had something to do with it.
Mm, I don't know.
I don't think Hannah's
really the video-game type.
Never know.
Between you and me, I actually
think it's a ton of fun.
( beeping )
WEBSTER:
Print is a match
to a Scott Baird.
Isn't that the
victim's boyfriend?
MR. BAIRD:
Two people confessed
to the murder,
and now you're
accusing my son?
Kids do stupid things.
Marlon covers for Hannah,
Hannah covers for Scott.
Dad...
Don't say a word.
DNA confirmed your fingerprint
in Stacy's car,
in Stacy's blood.
Scott loved Stacy.
We all did.
And when whoever
killed her
parked her car in my
driveway to frame my son,
I understood why
you had to talk to him.
But this?
That's it.
We're leaving.
Come on, Scott.
This is the only chance
you're going to get.
If you walk
out that door,
you're under arrest.
I want a lawyer.
I want to talk.
Scott.
Without my dad.
( over speaker ):
This is ridiculous.
I asked you guys
to rule out one suspect,
now we have three.
If he's willing
to talk,
I'd say we
caught a break.
The father's going to sue.
Oh, I'd put
money on that.
CURTIS:
Okay, Scott.
You said you
wanted to talk.
Let's talk.
This doesn't get back
to our families, all right?
My dad's a deacon,
and Stacy's dad is, too.
They'll never understand.
They won't hear
anything from me.
I was pressuring Stacy
to have sex.
She kept resisting.
It was that stupid
virginity pledge
that she had taken
at the high school.
I told her that I loved her,
and that nothing should
get in the way of that.
Not even God.
I take it that convinced her.
Yeah.
I mean, really?
You really do?
Yeah.
I love you.
I love you with
all of my heart.
There was a little blood.
Not a lot, but...
After, she...
she started feeling guilty,
so I went back into
the front of the car
and I tossed
the condom.
And... then I...
wiped my fingers
under the seat.
( phone beeps )
HODGES ( over phone ):
Hello?
Hodges, Stokes.
Listen, there's a bloody
fingerprint in the back freezer
from Stacy Vollmer's car.
Pull it and test it for
spermicides and lubricants.
We need it quickly,
all right?
HODGES:
I'm on it.
If it tests positive,
it will clear him.
Yeah.
Which means we're down
to Malcolm and Hannah.
Right back where
we started.
SCOTT:
Stacy said that
she was afraid
that God would punish her
for having sex.
I told her
that was crazy.
Guess I was wrong.
SIDLE:
Archie is not
getting much off of
Hannah's computer.
Most of her files are
encrypted AES-256.
It's going to be nearly
impossible to crack.
What do you mean
by "most"?
Well, it's not much,
but apparently Hannah
had I.P. access
to the laser printer
in the high school library.
Same one that printed
the "Out of Order"
signs for the shower.
If she printed those signs,
it shows intent.
Mm-hmm.
Ah, teen lust.
Starts with some chemistry,
and then you mess around
with some biology,
and once you have
some experience
"under your belt,"
then you introduce the physics.
Apparently,
chivalry is not dead:
the bloody fingerprint
tested positive
for nonoxynol spermicide.
So much for the boyfriend.
If we can't pin this on
Hannah or Marlon,
they could both walk.
You could flip a coin.
I have a better idea.
( bell rings )
I bet you really
liked high school.
Yeah, playing football,
chasing girls,
books when I wanted
to learn something--
what's not to like?
Hey, guys.
Hey.
This is Darcy,
my wife Tina's niece.
SIDLE:
Hi, Darcy.
STOKES:
You were right; she's
about Hannah's size.
More or less.
Stop talking about me.
Hey, that's the best part!
BROWN:
That's what
the pause button's for.
It's time to work,
it's child labor day.
Okay.
Crime started
right here.
( explosion )
Think you could reach that?
BROWN:
It's kind of hard
to sabotage
a shower head you can't touch.
STOKES:
Depends on what's
behind the curtain.
Look at that.
Just like the one
in Hannah's bathroom.
Try this.
SIDLE:
Hannah had access
to the chem lab,
and she knew
how to handle sodium...
( explosion;
Stacy screaming )
SIDLE:
Stacy would not have known
what hit her.
Or where she was going.
( screaming )
Stacy landed here
and bled out
from the trauma
to her skull.
Darcy, why don't you put
those headphones back on?
Like I didn't hear
what you guys just said?
Hannah could have done this.
Maybe.
But the next part,
that was the toughest.
( Darcy grunting )
DARCY:
It's too heavy!
BROWN:
Come on, you're
almost there!
It's building
character!
SIDLE:
It's slow going,
but you're doing it.
Yeah, so far.
That's okay.
Look, even if
she makes it to the grass,
you think she could've
pulled the body
the entire length
of the football field?
There were scratches on
the shower curtain--
the body was dragged
at least part of the way.
SIDLE:
There's no way Hannah pulled it
the entire distance.
Not by herself.
They did it together.
DARCY:
So...
Did I help the dead girl?
If Marlon and Hannah
committed this crime together,
then they're probably
still working as a team.
It's all part
of the plan:
he confesses,
then she confesses.
Muddy the waters enough,
they both get off
on reasonable doubt.
Mm-hmm.
Well, if we can't get
one to implicate the other,
we're screwed.
I don't get it.
What's wrong with you people?
You want me to confess?
Again?
Fine, I will.
Marlon, you need
to confirm
that you're willing
to talk to me
without a parent
or lawyer present,
just a child advocate.
I already said that was okay.
I killed Stacy, what else
do I have to tell you?
Well, the truth works for me.
I like the truth.
HANNAH:
Look, I don't need a lawyer,
and I don't need my parents.
I just want to do what's right.
Hannah, taking the blame
for something you didn't do
may be noble, but it
doesn't make it right.
That's deep.
Okay.
It happened like this:
Stacy humiliated me,
I wanted revenge.
Yeah, and you knew that
there was no way you were ever
going to get it by yourself.
STOKES:
You moved the body,
you buried it...
I know I did; I was there.
What's the problem?
Well, the problem is what
happened in the locker room.
I mean, you're not
the kind of guy
who puts sodium in a shower head
to get back at somebody.
You just trip them
in the hallway.
So you think I'm too stupid
to have done it.
Great, join the club.
I don't think
you're stupid, Marlon,
I didn't say you were stupid.
But this is Hannah's game.
The whole way.
Uh-uh.
I broke into the chem lab.
I stole the sodium.
Me.
All by myself.
It takes skills
to handle a chemical
like that properly.
And, quite frankly, man,
you just don't have the skills.
Your prank went bad,
and Stacy
ended up dead.
That's what I said.
Marlon helped you
bury her.
No. Why won't you believe me?
Marlon wasn't there.
Stay away from Hannah.
She had nothing to do
with this.
No, no, she had everything
to do with this.
You two were working together
from the beginning.
Just leave her alone.
SIDLE:
Marlon helped you
move the body.
He didn't!
You expect me
to believe
that a little girl like you
lugged a hundred pounds
of dead weight
the length of a football field
by yourself?
No, of course not,
that's why
I had to use the cart.
What cart?
The electric cart.
The one the landscapers
were using.
It was just sitting there,
right outside the door.
( computer mouse clicking )
( computer beeps )
Wait a minute.
I got something.
Let me clean up this image.
I see a cart, Sara.
So Hannah could be telling
the truth.
It's enough
for reasonable doubt.
Great.
Thanks, Warrick.
BROWN:
Yeah.
STOKES:
The evidence says
either one of them
could have done it,
but I think
they were in it together.
Okay, I'll proceed
against Marlon
for the murder and bring charges
against Hannah
for conspiracy.
Another trial?
You sure you want to go
through all this again?
SINCLAIR:
Stacy's parents
and the community
will have my ass if I don't.
Well, then maybe
this is good news.
I was just going
over Sofia's notes
from the original
investigation.
The night of the murder,
Hannah and Marlon's parents
had left them alone
in the house.
A pizza was delivered to
the residence around 9:00 p.m.
That's right around
Stacy's T.O.D.
So, did anybody talk
to the delivery guy?
Yes, and at the point that
Sofia did, a month had passed.
Now, the delivery guy's
at the house all the time.
He recognized photos
of both kids,
but he could not be sure
which one answered
the door that night.
But one of them
did answer the door.
So that means
they were not together
at the time Stacy was killed.
Yeah. So much for conspiracy.
We're right back
where we started.
Where we are is in the crapper.
Look, I have to disclose
the cart.
Defense is going
to eat me alive.
STOKES:
Marlon's your guy.
He's your guy--
just because Hannah wasn't there
doesn't mean
she didn't help plan this.
Well, I sure hope it's Marlon,
because he's the one
we have on trial.
I stand by the
case we filed.
I agree.
The girl's just trying
to protect him.
Sara?
This was more about brains
than brawn.
I think Hannah did it.
Two out of three.
In my world,
that's called an acquittal.
High school.
Even if you're popular,
or a jock, or a brain...
it can be hell.
Everybody here remembers
what it was like...
what it was really like.
Now take a look
at Marlon West.
Take a good, hard look.
Not popular...
not a jock... not a brain.
Now imagine what it must
be like to be Marlon West
day after day after day
in the sociological
pressure cooker of high
school.
This imposing, struggling
outsider like Marlon
resenting someone
like Stacy Vollmer,
who made it look
so easy to be popular,
athletic and smart.
That strong resentment
was already festering
when Stacy made
Marlon's sister the object
of a typical high school prank.
And that is when Marlon,
his resentment
boiling over, crossed a line:
He stalked Stacy.
You've seen and heard evidence
illustrating the elaborate pains
he took to rig a shower head
to torture Stacy,
how he forced her
to run and fall,
and watched her die
in a pool of her own blood.
You know, for the first time
in his life,
Marlon feels like a hero.
He's not
invisible anymore.
He's a killer...
and he is guilty
beyond all reasonable doubt.
ALLRED:
"Reasonable doubt."
You know,
I'm not surprised
to hear the prosecution
say those words,
because its case offers nothing
but reasonable doubt.
Access to sodium?!
Marlon couldn't find sodium
on a periodic table
of the elements,
let alone
a locked supply closet.
Access to library printers?
Do you really think
a kid like Marlon
spends any time in a library?
The shower head--
yes, Marlon's tall enough.
He could reach it, but he still
would have had to have handled
a volatile chemical
with expert safety precautions
in order to orchestrate
an explosion.
I mean, ladies
and gentlemen,
do you know
how to do that?
I don't know how to do that.
Right? You'd have to be...
a genius.
Marlon?
Not a genius.
You know, one
of the underpinnings
of our justice system
is that it is better
to send a hundred guilty men
free than to imprison even one
who's innocent.
Marlon West
is an innocent man.
Reasonable doubt compels you
to find him not guilty.
( phone ringing )
( second phone starts ringing )
Defendant shall rise.
Madam Foreman,
what is the jury's verdict?
FOREMAN:
On the sole count
of murder in the first degree,
we, the jury, find
the defendant, Marlon West...
not guilty.
( sobbing )
JUDGE:
So noted.
Court orders the defendant
released from custody.
Ladies and gentlemen
of the jury,
thank you
for your service.
Court is adjourned.
( gavel bangs )
OFFICER:
Sign here.
Hey, there.
Did you come
to say bye?
No. Actually, you and I
are going to be seeing
a lot of each other.
If you thought
the DA wouldn't prosecute
a 12-year-old for murder,
you were wrong.
He wants justice for Stacy
and her family.
Of course.
He's a totally linear thinker.
Most of you guys are.
Shame on you,
Ms. Sidle.
Come on, Hannah.
You don't need
to listen to this.
Mom, just give us a second.
You were saying?
Here.
( sighs )
Hannah, with your gifts,
you could've done
anything you wanted,
and you picked murder.
You can't take
that back.
You're worried
how I'm going turn out.
Of course I am.
I know it seems
like a really long time,
but... in five years,
the Stacies of the world
would've been behind you.
Let me guess.
You were a smart kid in school.
Maybe you feel
we're a little bit alike.
There aren't many people
like you.
That's what my parents
always say, too.
The last four months,
all they cared about
was the effect of the trial
on me... not Marlon.
It's been that way
ever since I was 14 months old
and started spelling words
with plastic letters.
It's so unfair,
and nobody ever sees it.
He doesn't deserve
to go to jail.
If I get convicted,
what's the worst-case scenario?
I mean, I'll be out
in five years
with an undergraduate
degree.
There's no "Son of Sam" law
in Nevada--
that was ruled
unconstitutional--
so I'm free to write a book
about all this.
The story'll
be worth millions.
Freaks are always
good box office.
You're not a freak.
When's the last time
you had to sit down
to be eye-level with a murder
suspect who was standing up?
Hannah, you are smart.
So I've been told.
But you're not smart enough
to get away with murder.
I think I am.
A lot of people
are smart enough
to get away with murder.
You probably are, too.
But you have to be really smart
to make people think things
happened that never did.
What do you mean, exactly?
Please don't worry about me.
I'm going to be fine.
( whispering ):
I didn't kill Stacy.
Marlon did.