( bell rings )
( indistinct
radio transmission )
( siren wails in distance )
Hey.
I was happy to hear
the Review Board cleared you.
It's been a rough time,
but I'm dealing with it.
Anyway, a kitchen worker
found him.
Say a lot of
homeless people
hang out here.
Says the vic was
unfamiliar to him.
Creased khakis,
Oxford shirt, new shoes.
This guy had a home.
Well, I checked
the front pockets, no ID.
Back pockets?
I was leaving that for you.
BRASS:
Looks like some blood
around his lips.
Maybe somebody punched him
in the mouth.
What do you think?
Cranberry sauce.
( chuckles ):
I know.
Happy Thanksgiving.
♪ Who... are you?
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
( indistinct
radio transmission )
( siren wails in distance )
WILLOWS:
This place used to make a hell
of a meatloaf sandwich.
You ever eat here?
GRISSOM:
Not since the chef blew his
brains all over the kitchen.
PHILLIPS:
I eat here all the time.
I like the chili.
GRISSOM:
T.O.D., David?
Based on liver temp,
he's been dead around two hours.
WILLOWS:
Looks like he was knocked out
and thrown out.
And there's some metallic
silver residue on his cheek.
What's this gunk in his hands?
Mashed potatoes.
There were mashed potatoes
in the Dumpster.
No fingernails...
on either hand.
WILLOWS:
Maybe he was alive inside there.
Digging to get out.
Or he had really bad
table manners.
There's some scarring on his
wrist, but not on the other.
Look what I found in his pocket.
"Aunt Jackpot's Pretzels."
Oh, now, they make
a great pretzel.
Maybe that's why he's got
that smile on his face.
( indistinct
radio transmission )
CURTIS:
419 times two.
Double murder?
Husband and wife.
SIDLE:
Beat-up car in a Lexus
neighborhood.
CURTIS:
We ran the plates.
R.O. doesn't live here.
We're tracking her down.
STOKES:
"Bitch on Wheels."
Can't wait to meet her.
Alarm was triggered
at 11:45 p.m.
The monitoring company
notified P.D.
when the homeowners didn't
return their call.
Patrol finally arrived
at 3:32 a.m.
Residentials are a low priority.
They're usually false alarms.
Not this one.
Michael and Lori Tinsley.
Kitchen door was open
when we arrived.
His wallet was in his pocket.
Her purse was on the counter.
Cards, cash, TV, stereo,
it's all still here.
STOKES:
If this was a robbery,
they missed all the good stuff.
The coroner should be here
right now.
So, uh, I'm gonna go see
what's happened to him.
Well, looks like she
exsanguinated out her jugular.
Abrasion on his forehead.
No visible blood.
Blonde hairs on his shirt.
Both victims are brunette.
Blonde hairs on the wife, too.
And possible skin scrapings
under her fingernails.
Maybe she got a piece
of her attacker.
( muffled scream )
If her neck was sliced
with a knife,
it was probably serrated.
The wound's too jagged
for a straight one.
SIDLE:
Check out that record
collection.
The cabinet door's open.
Alphabetized.
Classic rock.
Looks like several records
have been removed recently.
I'll dust for prints.
Smudges in the blood trail.
Ovoid shapes suggest
directionality.
Satellite stains also suggest
suspect moved this direction.
Judging by these gaps, I'd say
entire catalogs are missing.
There is good money in vinyl.
Especially if it's rare
and well-preserved.
Who would kill somebody
over a bunch of records?
Something's missing between
the Beach Boys and Billy Joel.
BOTH:
The Beatles.
Loose strike.
Would have been pretty easy
to get in from back here.
They have a dog.
Sofia said the door was open;
maybe he took off.
Blood stains stop
at the grass.
Sprinklers are on now,
kissing the evidence good-bye.
Hey, Nick.
Yeah?
There was some blood
on these dog bowls.
Considerable.
( thud )
( rustling )
( flies buzzing )
( soft whining )
I'll call Animal Control.
DR. ROBBINS:
Stomach is massively distended.
Human stomachs have a volume
of about one liter,
a little more than a quart.
But they have the
ability to expand
and hold up to four liters.
But looking at this guy,
I'd say he was packing
around six.
And that's your COD.
( coughing )
Asphyxia due to mechanical
compression of the lungs
due to gastric dilatation.
His stomach expanded,
leaving no room
for the organs.
It's going to keep me on my diet
for a couple more weeks.
Let's take a look.
Ooh, the guy
was a walking buffet.
Multiple contusions.
He's got a band of dead tissue
on his wrist.
No fingernails.
Cuticle's are inflamed
and still intact.
They weren't pulled off.
They were bitten down...
At first I thought
tortured and force fed,
but the usual signs of force
feeding are absent.
No abrasions on the mucosal
surface of the lips.
No aspirated food
in the airways.
So what are you thinking now?
He ate himself to death.
Do you recognize
this face?
MAN:
I know exactly who that is.
Man, dude's crazy.
Dude got a name?
No name.
Oh, but I got a wallet.
What, he left it behind?
More like he threw it.
Pretzel, thank you,
please.
Hey, pal.
Where's your manners?
Just one pretzel, please.
Just a quick, fast one.
Come on.
No, no.
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
I said no!
Excuse me.
See, salty pretzel's $1.50.
Only a dollar
in the wallet.
Jerk.
Hey, and I took
the money, by the way.
I didn't care.
Oh, I saw that.
Sports Promotions.
Man, I seen
his gut, man.
He don't look
like he no athlete.
They're calling poker players
athletes these days.
Seen the guts on them?
Hey, can I get
a pineapple cinnamon?
Oh, okay, good choice.
Thank you.
( Touch-Tone beeps )
( line ringing )
WOMAN:
O198. Please leave your message
after the tone.
All right, let's take
a look at our Cujo.
( soft whining )
Yeah, she's ferocious.
STOKES:
Yeah, yeah, I'm petrified.
So what's the outside chance
of rabies?
She's not salivating excessively
or showing any signs
of hydrophobia,
but rabies doesn't
present immediately.
She'll be quarantined
for the next ten days.
Well, other than rabies,
what would make a dog
attack its owner?
Abuse?
Abused animals
may turn violent.
Head traumas may induce
unprovoked aggression.
And there's always
springer rage.
Yeah, yeah,
I hate that show, too.
( chuckles )
It's a form of epilepsy
associated with several breeds,
including springers
and retrievers.
Man's best friend will back you
into a corner and attack.
Five minutes later,
she's licking your face
as if nothing ever happened.
I'll suppose you want
bite impressions?
Yeah, I'll prep the microsil,
if you prep the pooch.
This car is registered
to you, Ms. Halter?
Yeah. So?
And why was it
in the Tinsleys' driveway?
I lent it to Michael;
his Beemer's in the shop.
I want it back.
This was not meant
for public transit.
And your relationship
with Michael Tinsley is?
Why is that any
of your business?
I'm his girlfriend, okay?
How does his wife
feel about that?
Not my problem.
They're separated,
getting divorced.
Michael lives with me.
I want to talk
to Michael now.
Were you at Lori Tinsley's
house last night?
No. I've never been inside
that psuedo Cape Cod dump.
If you've never been there,
then how do you know it's
a pseudo Cape Cod dump?
I know her taste.
Well, your fingerprints
were at the scene.
In fact, you helped yourself
to the record collection.
That's why I'm here?
Because you think
I stole some albums?
What did Michael tell you?
Not much.
Look, he said Lori was planning
on selling his vinyls.
So, last week, when she
was out and he was at work,
he gave me the keys,
the alarm code
and a list of albums
he couldn't live without.
( dog panting )
( dog yelps )
Michael's owned those records
since high school.
He has the White Album,
autographed by Paul McCartney.
And he didn't break into
the house himself because...
Because he needed an alibi
in case Lori pressed charges.
Look, I am trying
to be helpful here,
but I'm not saying
another word
until you let me
talk to Michael.
You have the right
to remain silent,
but Michael Tinsley
and Lori Tinsley are dead.
( beep )
♪ ♪
Oh, nice look.
That'll guarantee
you the chicks.
Silvery material
on your vic's face
was Graftobian
theatrical makeup.
Moonlight Silver is the color.
( laughing )
Okay, look, I can't stand
the smell of hot dogs.
They make me sick.
So, all this stuff
was in the vic's stomach?
Among other things.
You know what the worst
kind of burp is?
Hot dog burp.
You know, like your dad's
just letting them loose,
or maybe the ex-girlfriend.
Well, as you can see,
he wasn't much of a chewer,
which was very lucky for us.
Made it easier
to identify the food.
Cake, mac and cheese,
pretzels, pasta, beef, shrimp,
fish and, of course, hot dogs.
Food normally takes two
to four hours to digest,
which means he
ate all of this...
In two to four hours
before he died.
How many hot dogs did he eat?
Approximately 20.
God, ugh.
Do you think we might be able
to ID the makers of the hot dogs
from the ingredients?
No.
Believe it or not,
most hot dog companies are very
proprietary over their recipes.
Well, how about through
the griddle marks?
Oh, yeah, sure.
I'll just run it
through the Hot Dog
Appliance database.
When was the last time you saw
a branded logo on a hot dog?
WILLOWS:
Looks like those
novelty chatter teeth.
Weird.
You think
that's weird?
Check this out.
Go ahead. Dig in.
WILLOWS:
"Circus Town Buffet."
"All-U-Can-Eat."
♪ ♪
I know exactly
who that is.
How could I
forget him?
Hi, we've got a problem.
Hurry up before the food's gone.
I called Security
to kick him out.
When they arrived,
he was gone.
Kick him out?
Sign outside says,
"All-U-Can-Eat."
Look, he was taking it
a little too far.
Well, he paid, didn't he?
Yeah, cash.
So he still
had his wallet.
Do you have any surveillance
on your register?
For the $1.99 buffet?
That would be a no.
And are those the only
hot dogs that you serve?
Yeah, we're famous
for our cocktail wieners.
You should try one.
I think we need a couple
of cocktails first.
DNA confirmed all the blood
at the crime scene
is Lora Tinsley's.
Sofia talked to
their divorce lawyers.
Michael and Lori were
fighting over everything--
the house, the cars,
her jewelry.
When she found out that he
was stealing his stuff back,
she had the locks and
the alarm codes changed.
Well, Michael did send
his girlfriend Missy over
to retrieve his vinyl,
but last night
he broke in himself,
not to mention she was home.
That's kind of asking
for trouble, isn't it?
Yeah, divorce
is war, huh?
Sure glad I don't
have that problem.
Yeah, me either.
Hodges.
I'm not done with
your samples, okay?
And I just received the
fingernail scrapings.
Well, I sent
the scrapings to DNA.
DNA kicked them over to me.
There were no biologicals
in the sample.
Have you processed
the hairs yet?
That, I have done.
All the hairs lifted
off the victims' clothes
were consistent with each other.
There's a sample
under the scope.
Root is shaped like a spade
which is indicative of canine,
and the scale pattern
is consistent with
a golden retriever.
Oh, yeah, the victims
have a golden retriever.
Well, if you'd cracked
that mystery at the scene,
you would've saved me
a lot of time.
I've been working like a dog.
You know, studies have found
that pet owners have
lower stress levels.
You should check that out.
Well, I had hamsters growing up.
My mother hated them.
She said
they stank up my room,
but I just loved to watch them
spinning on their little wheels.
One day I came home
and they were gone.
Somehow they'd gotten
out of their cage.
How much did your
mother hate them?
They ran away.
♪ ♪
( beep )
( saw buzzing )
( clink )
Michael Tinsley was shot?
Yeah, the bullet penetrated
the base of the brain
and lodged
in the occipital lobe.
The hemorrhage
was intracranial.
Looks like a .22 caliber.
Yeah, the scalp abrasion
was probably incidental.
We did not check the house for
GSR; we didn't know he was shot.
That's understandable--
the entry wound wasn't visible--
but check this out.
Some people will put
anything up their nose.
So, Michael Tinsley breaks
into his own house,
the alarm goes off,
all hell breaks loose.
She shoots him, the bullet
goes up his nose,
and then what?
Kahlua freaks and rips
out the wife's throat?
It's possible, which is
another reason I prefer cats.
The Tinsleys died
at home... alone.
So, where's the gun?
I went shopping.
Bought every brand of hot dog
for sale in Las Vegas.
Who's paying for it?
You mean the lab's
not going to reimburse me?
No.
Well, I couldn't identify
the chatter teeth logo,
so I figured I could
physically match one of these
to the one found in the
victim's stomach, you know?
Maybe comparing
that twisty thing at the end.
Sounds like a good idea, Greg.
I'm still not paying for it.
Fine-- guess I'll just eat hot
dogs for the rest of the year.
"A hot dog at the ballpark
tastes better
than a steak at the Ritz."
Well, I can tell when
you're quoting something.
Who said it?
Humphrey Bogart.
Mm.
Did you know
that the term "hot dog"
was actually coined
at a baseball game?
New York Polo Grounds,
somewhere around 1867.
A German butcher was selling
what he called "dachshund
sausages" out of his pie wagon.
He put them on a roll,
so that his customers
wouldn't burn their fingers.
He'd yell out
"Get your dachshund sausages,
they're red hot!"
Soon, all the vendors
at the Polo Grounds
were selling them, too.
But they were too lazy to say
"dachshund sausages,"
so they just called them
"hot dogs."
Now there's over
50 major brands.
Good luck.
I'm rooting for you.
Well, hopefully I find a wiener.
♪ ♪
EMCEE:
Gut check, one, two!
Gut check!
Ladies and gentlemen!
Time for the bib sheets.
Today's match will include
some of the most famous
gurgitators in the sport.
Let's start with
one of the finest:
The godfather of the sport
has a mouth so big
he speaks in Surround Sound,
ladies and gentlemen.
Three-time lasagna-eating
champion Antonio Colletti.
Patty Cake, Patty Cake,
baker's man,
she can eat a cake
faster than anyone can.
Current cupcake champion and the
most elegant eater in the sport,
Patty Cake Newton.
Our most vocal gurgitator...
There's the chatter teeth logo.
BRASS:
E.X.E.F.
Wasn't that the name
on the business card
you found in the vic's wallet?
I think we just found
our Digger James.
...he's said to have
two stomachs!
Undisputed popcorn shrimp
champion,
James "Spare Tank" Patterson.
( belches loudly )
And finally,
known for his jaw strength,
trains with his pit bulls,
three-time rib champion--
today he will be wearing
the E.X.E.F. hot dog camera--
Marty Mayron,
"The Meat Machine!"
( crowd cheering )
All right, gurgitators,
you have 12 minutes
to eat your way into history.
They're diving
straight in there.
Marty Mayron going
with the Japanese,
dipping his bun in lemonade
to make it go down easier
and then biting that hot dog
into little pieces.
Not to be outdone, Miomoto going
for the double Japanese.
Colletti, the old pro,
double fisting it,
double dunking it.
That is a Heimlich
waiting to happen.
...is not fooling around--
he's doing a reverse Japanese:
Bun first,
hot dog afterwards.
Sort of a "dachshund chaser."
Still pushing it,
going old school,
like a little kid trying
to impress his grandmother
at Thanksgiving dinner.
Patty Cake going mostly cakey
on that one.
You can almost see the icing
on that hot dog.
Colletti having a bit
of a problem.
Something's slowing him down.
Whoa!
Antonio Colletti,
a reversal of fortune.
That's an immediate
disqualification,
and, of course, disgusting
for all of us to watch.
Wow.
Well, which one
do you want?
The guy in the silver
face paint or Digger James?
I don't know--
slimy stuff is your thing.
I don't want
to get mustard on my suit.
I'll take Digger.
Do I have a choice?
( cheering )
BRASS:
Hey, you recognize this guy?
DIGGER JAMES:
That's Jerry.
By far, one of the best walk-on
gurgitators I've ever seen.
So you gave him your
business card, right?
I'm the U.S. rep
for the E.X.E.F.
All right, E.X.E.F.--
what exactly
does that stand for?
It's the Extreme Eating
Federation.
We're one of the most popular
leagues in the sport.
Pounding down hot dogs,
that's a sport?
Since the early days of man.
You got 30 Neanderthals in
a cave and a rabbit walks in,
you have a competitive eating
situation, my friend.
We have rules, records,
prize money.
Some of our top
competitors earn
up to a half a million
dollars a year.
We're on cable.
No kidding.
Well, what does all this
have to do with Jerry?
Everything.
Jerry had undeniable
gastro-intestinal fortitude.
He took third in
yesterday's competition.
That qualifies him for
the finals in Atlantic City.
It made the Las Vegas Post.
Hm.
Sports section.
( cheering, whooping,
applause )
Can I keep this?
Sure.
Thanks.
I'm telling you,
with proper training,
Jerry could've proudly
represented the U.S.
and taken back the Golden Weenie
from the Japanese Champion.
Yeah, got to get
that Golden Weenie back.
Uh, so after the tournament,
did you see Jerry?
Paid him, gave him my card,
left him to celebrate.
Any idea who
he was celebrating with?
You want a sample
of my face paint?
Yeah, it's part of
my investigation.
Oh, it's still moist.
That's good for me.
I didn't do anything
to Jerry Gable.
Okay, in the beginning,
I admit I was a
little pee'd off
that I lost to the guy.
But then I learned
what a disturbed
individual he was.
Couple more!
Just, just, just, just,
a couple... couple more!
Has anybody got more hot dogs?
( shrieks )
Please!
What are you trying
to prove, huh?
Just give me more!
Trying to be a big guy,
tough guy, huh?
Please, please!
( whimpering, crying )
And what happened
after the friendly hug?
Some guy in a hat came by,
took him out of here.
Is that the guy in the hat?
Sure is.
( dog barks )
♪ ♪
So I found the
murder weapon.
It slipped under
the living room couch--
presumably when
Kahlua attacked Lori.
Well, a dog did attack Lori,
but it wasn't Kahlua.
The bite marks
on Lori's neck
are inconsistent
with Kahlua's teeth.
Oh, which means Kahlua
gets to walk.
Check out this left canine.
SIDLE:
The tooth is chipped.
All the dog hair we found
at the crime scene
was consistent with
a golden retriever,
which suggests
there was another
golden retriever in the house.
It could've attacked Lori,
fled out the kitchen door.
That is like saying
there's a second shooter
on the grassy knoll--
they only had one dog, Nick.
I'm calling Animal Control.
We're looking for
another golden retriever,
one with a bad tooth
and rotten disposition.
Little late to be
going to court.
No, I'm not going to court.
I'm taking my lady Tina to that
new Cirque show at the Wynn
and I forgot my tickets
in my locker.
That's nice, but if you're
looking for something
to tide you over,
look no further.
Busy night.
Figured the lab could use
a little lovin' from the oven.
Oh, your wife made a pie.
I made the pie.
Strawberry rhubarb.
I'm impressed.
Let's take it easy with
the cutting there, Doc,
it's starting to look like
the hit-and-run
on your table last week.
Just try it.
Thanks.
You know, it's vegan.
Low fat, low sugar,
low carb.
Low taste.
Catherine, Catherine, come here.
I need your opinion on this.
Try this.
No, thank you, I just came from
Nel's Hot Dog Eating Tournament.
I'm really done
with food.
It's good.
I was watching that
on cable.
Some Japanese guy ate,
like, 64 hot dogs
in 12 minutes.
Yeah.
He's was the most
famous guy in Japan
behind Yao Ming.
Yao Ming is Chinese.
Try it.
They ought to make it
an Olympic sport or something.
Please?
No, I can't go there.
I can't.
You know, if you want to
cleanse your taste buds,
I suggest you try
Doc Robbins' pie.
Really.
Yeah, that's why
you're leaving it behind.
I got an ID
on Dumpster guy.
Brass is tracking down
a current address.
Prader-Willi.
No, his name was Jerry Gable.
No, Prader-Willi Syndrome.
A rare gentic disorder
that causes ceaseless,
uncontrollable
excruciating hunger.
It's as if your stomach
was truly a bottomless pit.
That could explain why
after consuming 22 dogs,
he wanted more.
Could also explain why he was
found in the Dumpster.
He followed the food.
Prader-Willi Syndrome is
characterized by short stature,
hypotonia, almond-shaped eyes,
and obsessive fingernail biting.
That kind of fits
the victim's description.
Sufferers are born with
a flawed hypothalamus.
Normal hypothalamus receives
a signal from the stomach--
"I'm full, stop eating."
( cheering )
GRISSOM:
But with Prader-Willi Syndrome,
the signal never reaches
the brain.
They're always hungry.
Like having a full tank of gas,
and gauge is stuck on empty.
Guy's like Jerry are monitored
their whole lives.
Constant supervision
24 hours a day.
You remember the scar tissue
we found on his wrist?
( grunting and groaning )
I think it's possible
that our vic
spent most of his life
in restraints.
So either he escaped or...
someone set him free.
In which case, they'd be
responsible for his death.
I heard your case
has gone to the dogs.
Oh, Hodges, heel.
No, better yet,
play dead, man.
Play nice,
I'm throwing you a bone.
The fingernail scrapings
from your female vic
was baking grease.
How does that fit
in the puzzle?
Hey.
According to
the court records,
the Tinsleys weren't just
fighting over property,
they were also engaged in
an expensive custody battle.
Custody over what?
They didn't have any kids.
They had Kahlua.
And evidentally,
yesterday both parties agreed
to let the dog decide
for herself.
According to
Michael's girlfriend,
the dog was his,
but Kahlua chose Lori.
MICHAEL:
Kahlua, come.
Come here.
( clapping ):
Come.
Come here.
Kahlua, come.
Come.
Kahlua.
I think I know why.
Lori greased up
before the big face-off.
Kahlua, come.
LORI:
Come, Kahlua.
Kahlua, Kahlua, come.
MICHAEL:
Come, come here.
Kahlua, come here.
Come.
A dog's sense of smell
is 25 times more
sensitive than humans.
Bacon grease would've been
pretty irresistible.
Question is...
"Did Michael know that Lori
was playing dirty?"
( cell phone rings )
Stokes.
Yeah, all right, cool.
Our suspect is in custody.
MENKEN:
Animal control
picked her up
near Centennial Park,
called the number on the tag,
left a voice mail.
Dead people
don't return calls.
New collar, new tags.
Kahlua.
Same name.
Spoke to Animal Control.
Kahlua number two was adopted
the same day as the murder.
You want to guess
the adopter's name?
Michael Tinsley.
You bet.
He adopted Kahlua's
doppelganger.
Left tooth is chipped.
Confirm's ID.
She doesn't seem very ferocious.
You want to see ferocious?
Yeah.
( barking )
How did you know?
When the guys loaded her up
into the Animal Control van,
they slammed the door
and she went off.
So the gun acted as a trigger.
She heard it and attacked Lori.
MENKEN:
Probably abused
in the past.
If they'd known,
they never would've
put her up for adoption.
Michael broke into the house
intending to swap dogs,
hoping that Lori wouldn't even
notice the difference.
( doorknob rattling )
( alarm blaring )
You don't give
a damn about Kahlua!
You just don't want me
to have her!
You care more
about that stupid dog
than you did me!
For once
you got it right!
( alarm blaring )
( gunshot )
( snarling )
When Kahlua number two took off,
Kahlua number one
came out of hiding.
( whining )
The police showed up,
she got scared ,
went back to her closet.
Their marriage ended
in a dog fight,
and only the dog survived.
BRASS:
So I called about
a dozen Jerry Gables.
One had an answering machine
for Jerry and Suzie Gable.
This apartment is listed
to Jerry and Suzie Gable.
Here's Suzie.
( knocking )
Las Vegas Police.
Please tell me you found Jerry.
Okay, so who are you?
I'm Susie's boyfriend.
All right, Susie's boyfriend,
what's your name?
Look, I don't have
anything else to say.
Hey, that's
my easiest question.
Hey, you don't want
to give us your name, fine,
but you better explain
why Jerry's not in this chair.
All right, look, I'm going
to print this restraint.
And when I find your
fingerprints all over it,
I won't need
to ask you again.
Okay, okay, all right.
He escaped.
All right? I was supposed
to be watching him,
and I conked out for a second,
and by the time I got up,
he was gone from his chair.
He escaped?
So, what, the guy's Houdini?
Trust me.
He may have been slow,
but he was manipulative.
Yeah.
Look, how do you deny
a 30-year-old man food?
I mean, I felt like
I was torturing the poor guy.
Yeah, I told you
them Vikings suck.
All right, I'll meet you
at the Circus Town book.
Can I go
to Circus Town with you?
I heard the buffet there
is yummy.
No.
( indistinct TV audio )
My plan was just
to drop him off at the buffet
while I went back
to the sports book.
By the time I got back...
oh, man...
Hey!
( glass clinking )
I couldn't help myself.
I had to sign him up.
So let me guess--
you blew his winnings
at the sports book?
Well, what was he
gonna do with them?
He's been strapped to a damn
chair his whole life.
You know, you managed
to supersize a combo
of two deadly sins--
greed and gluttony.
Shame on you.
So what's he doing
in a dumpster?
I don't know, was there
food in the dumpster?
'Cause when we were
on our way home,
Jerry was still hungry.
Wanted to hit up Krispy Kreme.
And by the time
I could tell him no,
he was running off
down the street.
I looked for him all night.
Yeah? Where's Susie?
I knew I shouldn't have left
Jerry with my boyfriend.
I'd been calling to check in.
He wasn't answering.
I could tell something was up.
Why did you leave
your brother
with somebody
you didn't trust?
There was no one else.
I had to get
this surgery today
or my insurance wasn't
going to cover it.
Couldn't you have left him
with a family member?
We have no family.
Our parents died
in a car crash years ago.
What about some kind
of professional help?
I'm a waitress, Miss.
I... I don't make much.
There's a really nice
institution in Summerlin,
but it costs a $100,000 a year.
And the last babysitter I hired,
Jerry beat up
trying to get to the fridge.
I swear to you,
I really tried to take
care of my brother.
I really...
did the best I could.
( chuckles )
Jerry took third place?
Yeah.
I bet he had
the time of his life.