( people laughing and talking)
WOMAN:
Focus all your intention
on the crystal
for your highest truth.
What is your first question?
YOUNG WOMAN:
I want to know
if he loves me.
I see red.
That can be passion.
The connection between you
is very strong.
I see blood.
There's danger around you.
Well, my parents do hate him.
I'm getting a name Ray. Ray.
and a letter "B."
Uh, when, when we put the name
Ray with the letter "B,"
does anything come up for you?
We don't know
anyone named Ray.
And my boyfriend's name
is Stuart.
There's something
else-- "R."
Ro-ro... rode,
rode, rodeo.
Is he connected to a rodeo?
Is he taking you
to a rodeo?
I don't think so.
I'm getting another image.
Um... an arm.
It's a one-armed cactus,
but it's not in the ground.
And then it's cold.
I don't usually tell people
when I see bad things
but the danger
is so strong
I can feel it.
Okay, this is stupid.
You're scaring us.
Don't go.
Come on.
Don't!
( tires screech )
Jerk!
( indistinct radio call )
Say hello
to Anna Leah
and Lori.
You may remember them.
A few years ago
they stole a car
and found
a severed head
in the trunk.
How could I forget that?
Well, now they found
a dead psychic,
Sedona Wiley,
in the occult shop.
She said there was
danger all around us.
I mean, we almost got hit
by a car
right here,
and then she's dead.
Wait, I'm confused.
You left and then you came back?
Yeah. I forgot
my sunglasses.
200 bucks.
This officer will take
you downtown
to take
your statement, okay?
Greg?
Hey.
I thought I paged Warrick
on this.
Yeah, about that,
uh, we traded days.
Because?
Well, uh, it's a long story,
but the short answer is
I have an expertise
in the occult.
Huh.
Hello, David.
What do you know?
Gunshot to the chest.
Liver temp is 98 degrees
which is odd
unless she's running
a fever.
It means I can't
give you an accurate TOD.
Sorry.
Bullet was a through-
and-through.
Based on lividity,
the body wasn't moved.
What's in the back room?
A small office.
Probably where she did
the readings.
There's, uh, incense, pendulum,
jar of marbles.
They're used
for divining.
It's hipper
than the old crystal ball.
Where did you say your expertise
comes from?
Oh, my grandmother, Nana Olaf.
She was a psychic.
She didn't have a store.
She just had
a kitchen table
and she prognosticated
for free.
She had a sixth sense.
And the family thinks that
I might have inherited it.
Okay.
What am I thinking?
That I'm due for a promotion?
I'm thinking you should focus
on your other five senses.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
Got some blood drops over here.
Connected to the blood pool?
No.
Maybe the killer
cut himself?
I'll swab it.
Gil, you ever been
to a psychic?
Would it surprise you if I had?
Yeah.
Surprise. So go ahead
and run it for me.
Sure.
Uh, cash register's empty,
which could mean
robbery gone bad.
The shot
was a through-and-through.
Bullet went into this wall.
Haven't extracted
it yet.
Shot was fired along this line.
Which puts the shooter
on the far side of the body.
Well, if it was a robbery,
why'd they trash the place?
Well, I can think
of two reasons:
One, the shooter was on drugs
and did it just to do it.
or there wasn't enough money
in the register
and he decided to look for more.
Go on.
Well, uh,
he figured that the victim
must have had a purse
or a safe somewhere...
and terrorizing her
is one way
to get her
to give it up.
They didn't take her purse.
( fast forwards tape )
WILEY:
I'm getting a name: Ray. Ray.
and a letter "B."
Um, when, when we put the name
Ray with the letter "B,"
does anything come up for you?
GIRL:
We don't know anyone named Ray,
and my boyfriend's name
is Stuart.
Ray Bans-- "Ray B."
WILEY:
There's something else.
"R," ro, rode. Rodeo.
Is it connected to a rodeo?
Is he taking you to a rodeo?
GIRL:
I don't think so.
I'm gettin another image,
an arm.
A one-armed cactus,
but it's not in the ground.
And then it...
I usually tell people when I see
bad things, but the danger...
Grissom?
...is so strong...
Take a look out there.
What do you see?
A one-armed cactus.
And take a look
at these labels.
"Rhode... eo."
They spell rodeo.
Power of suggestion, Greg.
I think that
the victim saw
images of the
crime scene.
Grissom, I think she foresaw
her own death.
Before you ask,
no, I did not find
her third eye.
What did you find?
Center-mass shot
front to back.
Large caliber bullet.
Clipped her aorta.
C.O.D. was exsanguination.
She bled out.
David said
she was running hot.
There's no signs
of infection
but I did find trace amounts
of a white powder
in her nasal cavities
and lungs.
Possibly cocaine-induced
hyperthermia.
I ordered
a full drug panel
and sent a sample
to Hodges.
It could be a hallucinogen.
In some native cultures,
shamans use peyote
to call forth visions.
Al, when someone sells love
potions and magic spells,
the only visions they see
are dollar signs.
Five right 44, consistent
with a Smith &amp; Wesson,
but no hits in IBIS.
Whew, somebody used
some heavy artillery
on that psychic.
And remind me again
why you didn't show
up at the crime scene?
'Cause your former
lab boy begged me for it.
He offered to take
my next holiday on-call.
I thought he was nuts,
but I wasn't going
to pass him up.
To be honest
with you, Grissom,
my wife's having a hard time
with my schedule.
She's spending a lot
of time alone.
I didn't think it would
be that big of a deal.
Well, you should
have cleared it with me.
And by the way,
you're still on the case.
All right.
I paged Greg.
I don't know where he is.
That's okay, 'cause Warrick
is now backing him up.
What do you got?
There's too many prints
and there's too many hits.
I need some help.
Can you talk
to Ecklie,
please?
I'll do what I can.
What about the cash register?
I ran those per Greg...
per you.
All the prints belonged
to the victim except for two.
Both of which were
a match to a Reese Bingham.
His work card's
in the system.
Okay, I'm on it.
The State has a law that murder
committed during the commission
of a felony
buys you the death penalty.
Do you understand that?
This has to be a mistake.
I don't even eat meat.
Or cheese.
I won't even hire
an exterminator.
Your prints were found
at the crime scene.
I haven't been
to any crime scenes.
You been to any occult shops
lately?
Yeah, I work
next door to one.
You want to explain to me
why your prints were found
on the cash register?
The owner's my friend.
Did something
happen to her?
You don't know
that she's dead?
No.
She was
killed
and then robbed, and your prints
are on her
cash register.
Okay, yeah, wait...
I can
explain that.
Start explaining.
I work at a vegetarian
restaurant.
We make these soy burgers.
Sedona was
hooked on them.
So, you know,
she'd order,
I'd deliver.
So you're a soy-burger-making,
vegetarian delivery boy, hmm?
Look, she's always busy
doing a reading
or whipping up
some kind of potion.
She told me to take
the money out of the drawer.
Give yourself a tip?
Soy burger and fried
was $6.95 plus tax.
I'd take a ten.
You delivered
to her last night?
No.
Was it your day off?
Like most nights,
I work until 6:00
and then I like... to go
to the Stripperama.
I thought you didn't like meat?
( chuckles )
Is there anyone
who can confirm that?
Well, yeah.
She got a name?
Girls aren't allowed
to tell you their real names,
but I call her Star
'cause she has these...
blue stars tattooed
on her hips.
And it kind of looks
like a meteor shower
when she dances.
Would you stand up, please.
I can go?
No.
You can strip down
to your skivvies.
Excuse me?
You want some music?
Hey, Jim.
Packey. What are
you doing here?
Aren't you retired?
I'm here on business.
Business? I thought
your only business
was playing golf.
Any leads on
your dead psychic?
Why? What's the interest?
You looking to make a bet?
I knew the victim.
A few weeks ago I went to see
her about the Wallace case.
So you're still hunting
the white whale, huh?
15 years, no arrests.
Still burns me he used
to be one of us.
I really wanted to catch Wallace
before I retired.
So you talked to a psychic.
Jim, she told me things
that she couldn't possibly know
about this case.
She also told me
that Claire Wallace
was murdered by her husband
and he buried the body
in Summerlin.
Too bad she didn't
give you an address.
( chuckles )
Forget it.
No, hey, come on, Packey.
Come on, come on. Sit down.
Sit down.
Look, Jim, I interrogated
him at least a dozen times.
And I never got a rise
from the smug bastard
until the last time--
until I repeated what
this psychic told me.
So you think Wallace killed her
because...
He was afraid she'd eventually
lead me to the body.
I even scheduled
another reading with her, but...
Did he know her?
Did you tell him
her name?
Of course not.
Well, if he didn't know
who she was...
All right, all right.
At least do me the courtesy
of running Gordon Wallace's
prints against any prints
found at
the crime scene.
Check the case file.
The last interrogation tape's
still in there.
You'll see.
Gil, I need a favor.
( dance music playing )
MAN:
Most of my girls
have tats.
He said they were
shaped like stars.
What color?
Blue.
That'd be Tammy.
She's at the bar.
Help yourself.
Thanks.
Hey.
Greg, what are
you doing here?
Oh, Grissom said
you're backing me up.
Can't back me up
if I'm not here.
The next time you
screw me up with Grissom,
I'm going to back you up
right off a cliff.
Oh, come on, Rick,
ain't no thing.
We're working the case.
Flash the badge,
no cover charge.
Get to see the ladies.
Let's go.
You must be Tammy.
Yes.
Is there a quiet place
where we could talk?
You got
the dime,
I got the time.
Unfortunately,
the Crime Lab
doesn't have
a budget for that.
Greg Sanders,
Warrick Brown.
Las Vegas Crime Lab.
Well, we get the bottom
of the barrel around this place.
Who's in trouble now?
He is.
Have you seen him?
He comes in all the time.
Smells like nasty pickles.
Was he here last night?
Yeah.
Let's see, I go on
around 7:00.
He was in the front row waiting.
Hung around
all night.
Then he waited in
the parking lot to say good-bye.
So he was stalking you?
( chuckles ):
No, nothing like that.
He's harmless.
Like you, sweetie.
WILLOWS:
Hey, Gil,
if you're swamped,
I can always cancel
my vacation plans.
We've got it covered.
Good, 'cause I really
wasn't that serious.
What are you working on?
A favor
for Brass.
Oh, the Wallace case.
Yeah, I wanted on this
way back when.
But I was the new kid,
and my supervisor
wouldn't let me do it.
I probably would
have solved it, too.
Is there
a new lead?
I'm not sure yet.
I heard Jameson dug
30 holes
in the desert looking
for her body?
37 actually.
That's dedication.
Or obsession.
You know, my sister
lived near the Wallaces
out in Henderson.
Their fights
were legendary.
I was at
a barbecue one time,
I heard them screaming
at each other from
three blocks away.
Made me and Eddie seem
like amateurs.
Where are you and Lindsay
going this year?
Disneyland. With the parents.
Quality time with Dad?
Oh, yeah.
And Sam wanted to take us
on the Tangiers jet
but my mother refused.
Said it wasn't
the tradition.
So now we're driving.
Yeah, that'll be
a hell of a road trip.
Have fun.
Say hi to Sam.
Will do.
Still working on
those prints
from the occult shop.
Thank you for talking
to Ecklie.
He sent me some help.
Good. I have one more for you.
This is LVPD.
It's not going to be
in the AFIS
Criminal database.
I'm going to have to do
a manual comparison.
It's going
to take longer.
Is he a suspect?
He's a person of interest.
Hey, Henry, what's up?
My job can get a little
mundane sometimes...
Not today.
I'll second that
and raise you a stripper.
Okay, sure...
Anyway, the powder on
your victim's nose and lungs
is atropine.
It's used to dilate pupils,
control bladder problems
and it can be fatal
in large doses.
Atropine comes from
a plant, right?
Belladonna.
Also known as deadly nightshade.
Most people don't know
it grows wild throughout
the Southwest.
The psychic had that
in her shop.
Can you tell
from the blood work
whether she absorbed enough
for it to be lethal?
Levels were fairly low.
No other drugs detected.
So, no.
But if she hadn't been shot,
it would have made her sick.
What about hyperthermia?
Definitely. Why?
The vic's temperature
was elevated.
Belladonna would
help explain it.
Later.
Hey, I'm on a break.
I'll see you in 20.
Vending machine's on
me if you give me
your results first.
No, make it dinner.
Me and you?
Me, you and
my friend Julie.
Okay, but I get
to sit in the middle.
Deal.
So the isolated blood drops
from behind the register
are not a match to your vic.
In fact, they are male.
Really?
Can I have the file?
Later.
So, Mandy says that
you have a suspect.
The guy have any cuts?
Warrick didn't find any,
and the suspect
had an alibi.
But I think you just
broke the case.
How'd I do that?
Well, one of the broken jars
at the store
contained belladonna,
which is a poison.
The vic only
inhaled it,
but if the killer had
an open wound,
he not only
inhaled it...
it went directly
into his bloodstream.
I need to check the hospitals.
Got to hand it to you,
Sanders-- nice call.
They brought the guy
in after he ran his car
up onto a median,
right behind the Las Vegas sign.
That's like ten blocks
from the crime scene.
Yeah.
Name's Damon Mitchell.
Showed symptoms
of narcotics withdrawal.
According
to the police report,
he ran his car off the road
up onto the median.
No damage to the car,
no injuries.
But he's apparently hyped up
on something.
What do you got, Doc?
Well, the lab just confirmed
his blood is positive
for atropine.
So I'm starting him
on an IV drip
of physostigmine.
You swab that wound
on his hand yet?
Right when he came in.
Swab's still around?
Saved it for you.
It's in the biohazard bag.
Mr. Mitchell?
I'm Detective Vega.
( distorted voice ):
Mind if I ask you
a few questions?
Oh... man.
Your face is melting.
I think I'm going to puke.
Make sure you book him
when he gets sober.
JAMESON:
I got a psychic who can
communicate with the dead.
The FBI uses her
to locate people.
Your dead wife's
been talking to her.
Says her spirit is stuck
in Summerlin.
She can't cross over
until the bastard who
murdered her is caught.
Psychic says, it's you.
GRISSOM:
Watch this again.
( tape rewinds )
JAMESON:
Your dead wife's
been talking to her.
Says her spirit is stuck
in Summerlin.
She can't cross over
until the bastard
who murdered her is caught.
BRASS:
Yeah, Packey, said he got
a rise out of him.
Right when he mentions
Summerlin.
So, old Packey has
been punching holes
in the wrong part of the
desert all these years, huh?
Sir?
Yeah?
You said you wanted the print
results as soon as I got them?
Yes.
I tried to run
Wallace's ten card,
but the finger rolls
were too sloppy.
So I used the latents
from the crime scene
against the AFIS
civil database,
knowing he'd be in there,
'cause he used to be a cop.
Did you get a hit?
Yeah, I got two.
Uh, Wallace's prints were
on the inside
of the door handle.
That places him at the scene.
Well, what do you know?
Were the other ones Greg's?
No. They were another cop.
A... retired
Detective Patrick Jameson.
Yeah, Packey said he went
there to get a reading.
WEBSTER:
Yeah. Found a few on the table,
then there were a few more
on the broken jars
that were found behind
the counter.
Why was he behind the counter?
Come on. Why would Packey want
to kill Sedona?
I need to talk to you.
You heard
about the strip club?
I hear about
everything, Greg.
Then that ear surgery
paid off.
Our first lead didn't pan out,
but I got a better one.
Damon Mitchell crashed
his black Chevy
into a median only ten blocks
from the occult shop,
right around the time
the psychic was killed.
His prints match latents
we found at the scene.
He was hospitalized
for what turned out to be
belladonna poisoning.
And get this--
He worked the National
Finals Rodeo last year.
Slam dunk. I'm meeting Vega
at P.D. in 20 minutes.
We have one more lead
to follow up
before we call this
a slam dunk.
What lead?
I don't think your
sixth sense is working
as well as you'd hoped.
Are you accusing me
of something?
Oh, come on, Packey,
you know how this works.
I'm just trying to put
the pieces together.
I went to Sedona's shop
for a consultation.
I brought her
Claire Wallace's sweater,
from the car we found
at the airport.
And for your information,
I signed it
in and out of evidence,
per chain of custody.
Okay...
I also showed her
a couple of photos.
She did her thing;
I paid her; I left.
So you were only in the back
of the shop?
You've been there.
You know you have to walk
from the front
to get to the back.
Now, come on, Jim.
You want ask me something?
Don't be shy.
Somebody trashed the place,
and we found your prints,
on the pieces of broken glass.
And you think, what, I did it?
No, but I want to know
what your prints are doing
on those glass jars.
( sighs )
She had all these weird
powders and fairy dust,
and something called
a gris-gris bag.
Said she had
her mojo working.
Seemed sketchy.
I figured she was dealing.
Oh... I don't know, Packey,
that's a stretch.
Come on, Jim. You know
these hippy-dippy types.
They love their drugs,
so I questioned her.
Got a lesson in alchemy.
Have you ever seen
a wolf's heart?
A dried bat?
Well, I held 'em.
Satisfied?
( sighs )
Can I get some more water?
We're all out.
Mr. Mitchell,
are you into psychics?
No. I'm not...
I'm really thirsty.
Doctor said push the fluids.
We know that you went
to an occult shop.
Yeah, you left
your fingerprints
and your blood
at the location.
And according
to this tox report,
you were most likely
poisoned at the same place.
( sighs )
Okay. I was there,
but I didn't kill
that little con artist bitch.
Then why lie about it?
'Cause I didn't think
you'd believe me.
I'm in enough trouble already.
Give it a shot.
( sighs )
My wife is a junky.
She's a psychic junky.
She spent our entire savings
on consultations,
tarot readings
and other garbage.
Thousands of dollars.
I told her she had to quit
seeing this woman.
That was my mistake.
The week after, Sedona
starts having these visions
of me cheating.
You ever try to defend yourself
against a psychic's vision?
I bet that pissed you off.
So you got revenge by...
I went down there
to confront the bitch
because she ruined my life.
You want to know
what she said to me?
You want your wife back?
That's going
to cost you $5,000.
What?!
Cash.
I will look into her
future and I'll tell her
that she takes you back,
and you live happily
ever after.
She tried to extort
more money from me
after she had already
taken it all.
I lost it.
You think this is funny?
Mr. Mitchell, do you own a gun?
No. Look, when I left there,
she was alive.
What time was that?
It was after 9:00,
around... closer to 9:30.
Then where'd you go?
Uh... I went around the corner
to the liquor store
for some bourbon.
But before I even opened it,
I started to feel whoozy.
You know, then... everything
kind of went sideways.
The cops find the gun
or the stolen cash
in the vehicle?
No. Only a full bottle
of bourbon.
But he could've ditched
the gun.
Well, the victim took him
for several grand.
He's not ditching the money.
Tight suit, baby.
Actually, it's not.
Um, I've only gained
a couple of pounds,
and I tend to gain...
No, I mean it,
looks good on you.
I see. Well...
Thank you, Warrick.
So, what's with the ghetto?
I was with Conrad and the mayor
at the city council
budget meeting,
requesting more funds
for you slackers.
So you probably didn't have
any time to get some work done?
Au contraire.
Multitasking is my forte.
In fact, I shared your results
with the city council.
Fine crime fighting,
courtesy of your trace lab.
The gold flecks
that you pulled
from the cash register
was iron pyrite,
commonly known
as fool's gold.
What was it doing
in the cash register?
It's also known
as prosperity dust.
It could be for good luck.
Didn't work for Sedona Wiley.
( hammering )
Jim Brass.
Been a long time.
How's it going, Gordon?
This is Gil Grissom
from the crime lab.
So, Gordon, where were you
the night before last
between 6:30 and 10:00.
Well, I'm working 24-7
for Joslynn Raines
while she's in town,
so I was here with my crew
until 10:00.
Raced over to the airport,
picked up my brother.
Flew in from Florida,
landed around 10:30.
Brought him back here
for the last show.
You ever been
to the Sixth Sense Occult Shop?
( scoffs )
What? That's funny?
Nah, it's just, I...
I thought you were busting
my chops
for your boy, Jameson.
Yeah, I was there,
earlier this week.
Joslynn wanted to buy
a love potion.
Despite her
killer looks,
the young lady is unlucky
in the romance department.
You don't believe me?
Let's go ask her.
Hey, Joslynn
Can you spare a minute
for the, uh, boys in blue?
Friends of yours?
Sure. Nice to meet you.
Love your city.
So you got a pen,
or...?
Um, Miss Raines,
were you at the Sixth Sense
Occult Shop earlier this week?
Yeah. Gordie took me.
I got a reading,
picked up a few things.
Uh-huh. Did, uh, did Gordie
go inside the shop with you?
Mm-hmm.
He goes where I go.
I offered to pay to clear his
aura, but he wasn't in to it.
It's good for his soul.
Are we done?
You're going to need to...
exit out the front.
Maybe we can get
a warrant
and match the glass
in Wallace's shoe
to the glass we found
at the scene,
and then tie him
to the murder.
I don't know how.
Glass breaks all the time.
It's not a unique event.
Plus, he admits
to being in the shop,
which accounts for his prints.
You know, maybe
Packey was right--
maybe Wallace did kill
that psychic.
Well, he'd only kill her
if he also killed his wife.
This is the map I've
been working off of,
and each of these
red stickers
represents
a hole I dug
based on different
information.
Now, most were around the house
he owned in Sunrise Manor.
These were near his, uh,
brother's place,
and a few near
his sister's place.
That's where they grew up,
in Henderson.
So you never looked
in Summerlin?
No reason to.
It says here,
when Wallace was a cop,
he worked
the Northwest substation,
that includes Summerlin.
Yeah, but he hadn't been
on the job that long,
and Summerlin is
out of his comfort zone
and a long way
from where they live.
No, he... he had better options
closer to home.
So, where would
his parameters be?
Well, he'd pick a place
where people don't normally go.
Wallace worked Northwest
from January 1990
to August '92.
He responded to like 20 crime
scenes in Summerlin.
If we just limit it down
to the remote location...
Let me look at that.
BROWN:
Summerlin's changed a lot
over the last ten years.
Yeah, but there's two...
three, possibilities.
I got an idea.
( garbled police radio
transmissions )
Back in the day,
squatters were
always camping their
RVs in this area.
That's what brought
Wallace up here.
Illegal dumping of human waste
on public lands.
( beeping )
( rapid beeping )
Grissom!
I've got something!
GRISSOM:
Metallic signature.
This could be
the abandoned septic tank.
Time to find out.
( garbled police radio
transmissions continue )
( panting )
( Brown grunts )
Clear!
Mrs. Wallace, I presume.
Hey, Greg.
You missed some.
( sighs )
Well, one more spider bite
won't make a difference.
But you,
being the bug guy,
would probably enjoy
being bitten.
SANDERS:
Could be a rib.
It's too small.
Did the Wallaces
have a kid?
No. That was part
of the marital discord.
SANDERS:
Check this out.
Claire Wallace did have a dog.
Yeah. Yeah,
I interviewed her sister.
Said Claire had
a little bulldog named, uh...
think it was Sneakers.
Took him everywhere with her.
What's this around the neck?
GRISSOM:
It's a wire.
JAMESON:
Killed the dog.
He had to kill the dog
to make it look like
Claire took Sneakers with her.
Otherwise, nobody'd believe
his story.
SANDERS:
No collar or tags down here,
but I found this...
whatever it is.
Really thin,
high-bridge nose.
All indicate Caucasoid.
GRISSOM:
Any chance at an I.D.?
Well, so far, everything's
consistent with Claire Wallace.
Unfortunately,
because she was in a metal box
in the desert,
DNA's not likely viable.
I sent samples
of the long bones
to Wendy anyway,
but I don't expect results.
Dental records?
( sighs ):
The, uh, killer knocked out
most of her teeth.
Roots are still in the bone.
She was brutalized.
Cause of death?
I noted three separate
and distinct fractures:
one on the right side...
and two distinct fractures
on the left side.
We were able to identify
the missing skull fragments,
but when I tried to fit them
back together, I couldn't.
There was deformation
of the bones.
Pre or peri-mortem,
the human skull has
an elastic quality,
so when there's a fracture,
the pieces will change shape.
But post-mortem,
the bone is brittle,
and when it's fractured,
the pieces retain
their shape.
It's not unlike breaking
a vase or a bowl.
The pieces all fit together
like a jigsaw puzzle.
So based on the fractures
to her skull,
it appears she was struck in
the head three separate times,
and since the pieces
won't fit back together,
blunt force trauma to her skull
is your C.O.D.
Did you know
that there are
approximately 280
bones in a dog's body?
Yeah?
Well, the, uh, forensic vet
should be here soon.
Hopefully, he'll be able
to determine
whether this is
a French bulldog.
I'm thinking
this dog was an amputee.
Based on what?
This contraption.
Looks like the, uh,
canine equivalent
of a wheelchair.
My grandmother had a neighbor
whose dog was hit by a car.
The dog lived,
but the doctor had to amputate
the hind legs mid-femur.
This is the hind femur,
or what's left of it.
You see how it was cut?
You know, if Sneakers here
was a handicapped dog,
I.D.ing it just became
a whole lot easier.
If we can I.D. the dog,
it'd at least give us
a compelling argument
that the body found
was Claire Wallace.
Yeah, but even with a cause
of death of blunt force trauma,
we still don't have enough
to arrest him.
So what, we focus
on Sedona Wiley?
Well, it's like
a Chinese puzzle.
She knew who Wallace was,
but Wallace didn't know her.
Greg's suspect,
Damon Mitchell,
claims that she tried
to extort money from him.
So maybe
she hit up Wallace, too.
JOHNSON:
702-555-0122.
That's GW Security.
That's Wallace's company.
She called that number
three times
in the last week or so.
She was reaching out to him.
She called him again four days
before she was murdered.
Upping the ante, maybe.
WILEY:
Hi.
GRISSOM:
Maybe Wallace went there
to intimidate Sedona.
BRASS:
So she was
shaking him down
when he went in the
store to shake her up.
You know, Wallace said
it was the singer's idea
to go in there, not his.
Yeah, he also said
he didn't murder his wife.
You know, the girls said
something curious--
the two that found
the body.
I didn't think
it was important at the time.
When they left the store,
a car almost ran them down.
( tires screeching )
Jerk!
So, your hand made contact
with the hood of the car?
You bet it did.
I was born in Manhattan.
Well, I'm going to
need an impression
of your palm and
your fingerprints.
If it helps nail the guy, sure.
BRASS:
Do you remember anything
about the vehicle?
Was it a car,
a truck, SUV?
I think it was a car.
What color was it?
It was red.
Stuck in my head
after what the psychic said.
Blood red.
( indistinct chattering )
Voila.
WALLACE:
You dragged me out
of the show for this?
You're dusting
my car?
You sad old man.
Is this all you have
to live for?
Palm prints on the hood
of the car
appears to be
a solid match
to Anna Leah.
Who's that?
She's a good witness
who places your car
outside the shop
on the night of the murder.
Maybe I was in the neighborhood.
It's not a crime to drive
around Vegas.
I was only in
that shop once,
and I got my own witness.
You got nothing.
Our warrant also includes
your shoes.
You like 'em? They're new.
Threw the old
ones away.
May I take a look
at your wallet, please?
What for?
Because I can.
You didn't make a purchase
at that shop, did you?
Already told you that.
Gold flecks...
similar to the substance
we found
in Sedona Wiley's
cash register.
You took the money
to make it look like a robbery.
JAMESON:
We got him.
BRASS:
You know, Packey, you've been
waiting a long time for this.
Why don't you take him down?
I couldn't get you
for the murder of your wife,
but you are now
under arrest
for the murder
of Sedona Wiley.
You have to admit,
it's, uh, pretty eerie--
Sedona's visions
of her own death.
Yeah. Maybe you
should ask Nana Olaf
to contact her,
see how she's doing.
Yeah, I know you're a cynic.
I just think
that you can have beliefs
and still be a scientist.
I agree.
The problems arise
when people mistake
their beliefs
for the science.
I've been reading her notebooks.
Take a look at this.
"She is in Summerland...
"but there is chaos
and darkness surrounding her.
She is in Summerland,
but she can't cross over yet."
Sedona said Claire Wallace
was "in Summerland,"
not buried in Summerlin.
What's Summerland?
Pagans believe
it's a mystical place
where souls go to rest
before they reincarnate.
So Jameson heard Summerlin...
Because he was desperate
to solve the case.
Then when Wallace
heard Summerlin...
he assumed
Sedona was the real deal.
The power of suggestion.