( dance music playing )
( music ends )
( moans quietly )
Hey, lady.
Hey.
I can't sleep.
You want to try
to eat something?
Yeah.
All right.
I'll go get him.
You get dressed.
Ahren?
Ahren...
( gasps )
( whispering ):
Ahren...
BRASS:
Okay, Ahren Green,
29 years old,
lives here with Bianca Desmond,
that's the brunette.
The blonde is
Chelsea Wannamaker.
She was just
spending the night.
One was asleep,
one was in the bathroom.
They said Ahren was probably
working on his bike.
( camera shutter clicking )
PHILLIPS:
His pupils are dilated.
Lividity is consistent
with body position.
Looks like he bled out
from a stab wound
to his upper leg
or pelvic area.
Well, in my experience,
I found that most threesomes
end up being one too many.
So, David, uh...
check and make sure
that they didn't
pull a Lorena Bobbitt.
Take a look.
No, we're good.
My man's all there.
We're...good.
Something must
be wrong his gear.
He could be partying
with two hot chicks inside,
but he's out here
working on his bike
at 4:00 in the morning?
Maybe he wasn't invited.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
SIDLE:
Hold out your hands, please.
And the other side.
What were you doing
right before Ahren was killed?
Cleaning.
With what?
Bleach.
It's the only thing that works.
Okay.
You know, you could put
some clothes on if you want,
if you're cold.
She won't let me
back in my room.
( camera clicking )
Man, I give this guy
an "A" for organization.
He's got a spot for everything.
Why is that helmet over there?
GRISSOM:
Maybe he threw it,
defending himself.
( screaming )
Yeah, but he looked like
he was in pretty good shape.
It'd be kind of hard
for one of those women
to wrestle him
down.
Not if she walks softly
and carried a big knife.
How long
have you known Ahren?
Six months.
Did, uh, did he have any enemies
that you know of?
No, I mean...
I don't know.
You don't know...
I mean, you two
lived together right?
Yeah, but we were still getting
to know each other.
I see.
We met one night
at Light.
He was in town
for a motocross race.
It was love
at first sight.
I asked him
to come back here,
and he never left.
We actually just decided tonight
to move to Colorado together.
What, just pick up
and leave all this?
My father has a cabin
where we could stay.
Did Ahren have a job?
Yeah. Motocross racing.
Right.
You said that.
He's a professional athlete.
And you, what about you?
What do you do?
I'm in fashion.
Mm-hm.
What's the matter?
I have the worst luck with men.
What do you mean?
They're either jerks
or they leave me,
or they get killed.
What's wrong with me?
What do you got?
Well, I wasn't sure
if I should call it in
as a 419 or a 401A.
Hit and run?
You tell me.
STOKES:
Mm, I don't know.
When you run, you
usually take the car.
The vic's Sylvia Mullins.
Works in one of
the offices upstairs.
The security guard
found her.
Did you run the plates?
That's why I went with the 419.
R.O.'s the vic.
Hit with her own car
in her own spot.
Ms. Mullins must have been
working all night.
You know, tax season.
She's an accountant?
Has her own firm
up on 11.
Did you see anything
on your monitors?
Uh, no.
But I heard
the crash.
I sort of fell asleep.
We're going to need
to see your tapes.
WILLOWS:
Cell phone, a shoe
and a briefcase.
Probably lost them
all on impact.
STOKES:
Looks like she saw
the car coming.
Impact's pretty
evenly distributed.
The car hit her
straight on.
Most cars have to be going
at least 14 miles an hour
to trigger the airbag.
Well, I can't be sure,
but it looks like somebody
popped the ignition.
Carjacking gone bad?
Vic gets off the elevator,
walks to her spot...
...on the phone, distracted,
catches the guy
stealing her ride...
He runs her over and splits.
Pedal to the metal.
Hey.
ALS is lighting up
everywhere.
Evidently she bleaches
everything.
So there could be
some false positives.
Yeah, including her teeth.
Check out
the cabinet.
SIDLE:
Lots of teeth whitener
and acne cream.
Are you thinking
what I'm thinking?
Speed freak.
Definitely.
Maybe she killed
Ahren in the garage
then came up here to
take a Silkwood shower.
Okay, but she's claiming
she loved him.
What's her motive?
Uh, we started out at Light
and then we went to Road Runner,
and from there we were
at Double Down,
and then Copper K,
and then we ended
up at Drai's.
Drai's, that's
a good place to end.
So what are you on
besides meth?
Not meth.
Glass.
Uh-huh.
We did some coke
at the club,
had a couple of drinks.
There was this guy
that gave us these, uh,
these blue pills,
but I had to come
home and lie down.
Ecstasy.
We only do this when we're,
when we're clubbing.
I mean, it's just a hobby,
it's not a habit.
We have it
under control.
Well, the dead guy
from the garage
might beg to differ.
Eww, busy.
If Bianca killed him, and then
came up here to take a shower,
wouldn't she have left a trail?
Maybe.
It appears she missed a spot.
( gunshot )
( soft rattling )
( phone ringing )
Las Vegas Coroner's Office.
David, it's Warrick.
Have you washed the body yet?
I just got started,
but I can be done by the time
you get here.
No, stop.
I uh, just found a bullet.
I have no idea who fired it.
Do me a favor:
test his hands for GSR
and run it through
the flouroscope.
No problem.
Thanks, David.
Who brings a gun
to a knife fight?
The winner?
The killer knew how
to steal a car.
No prints?
No.
No, it's wiped clean.
Hey, Arch.
You get anything off
the parking garage camera?
Um, sort of.
STOKES:
What's up
with the focus?
That's what I was wondering,
too.
Check out what happened
about an hour earlier.
It's an old security cam.
Adjustable focus ring.
Killer was camera shy.
For good reason.
This wasn't a carjacking
gone bad.
It was premeditated.
If he touched the camera,
maybe I can get some prints
off it.
Keep working
the video, Arch.
See if you can get
us a face.
Yeah.
ROBBINS:
Fluoroscope detected
no bullets.
But there are peri-mortem
bruises on his wrists
and forearms,
look like defensive wounds.
C.O.D.?
The weapon went pretty deep.
Punctured the femoral artery.
I'd say he bled out
in a matter of minutes,
if his dilated pupils
are an indication
of amphetamines
in his system.
The faster the heart rate,
the faster the blood pumps.
Here, take a look.
The fatal blow.
Weapon appears to have
a triangular shape.
Angle of entry
was upwards.
Like a cornada.
I'm sorry.
A cornada-- occupational
hazard for matadors
during a bullfight.
The bull rears up
and gores them.
So just find a bull
with a bloody horn,
and you've got
your killer.
So your "soda-can killer"
was a copper-washed .22.
Now I could only get general
rifling characteristics--
six lands and grooves
with a right-hand twist,
um, but...
But not enough individual
characteristics
to run it through IBIS.
Exactly. Sorry, man.
That's all right.
Hodges.
Your victim did not have
GSR on his hands.
Okay, what about
metallic trace
from the garage floor?
Thank you, Hodges,
for performing
that incredibly
elaborate test
requiring copious concentration
and an advanced degree.
So you don't have
any results
from the metallic trace
on the garage floor?
But I will.
That's the beauty of me.
MULLINS:
Well, Mr. Miller, what
I would recommend
is adding some tax-deferred
investments
to your portfolio.
Like a ROTH IRA.
That's be perfect for you.
MILLER:
I never got what that
ROTH stood for.
( click )
( tape fast forwards )
MULLINS:
Hey, Kelly. Have a seat.
GORDON:
Thanks for seeing me.
I know you said we didn't have
to do this in person.
No, I'm really glad you came.
Kelly, your father loved
you very much.
A little too much.
I just wanted to talk
about his estate.
Is what he did
going to affect it?
Well, it's kind
of complicated.
( click )
( keypad beeping )
( phone ringing )
WOMAN:
District Four,
Parole and Probation.
Yeah, this is Nick Stokes
with the Las Vegas Crime Lab.
We're trying to reach
Kelly Gordon's parole officer.
That's me.
Great. I need Kelly's
contact information.
Sure, but I gave her permission
to go out of town.
Her bus left a couple
hours ago.
Oh, hey, I'm glad
you're here.
I got the results back
from the blood on
Bianca's bedroom floor.
The dead guy?
Uh, no.
It's a male, but it's not
a match to Ahren Green.
Then I ran it through CODIS
and I actually got a hit.
Justin Cole.
He's in the system
for statutory rape
a couple years back.
Among other things.
So, why am I here?
What, you getting homesick
for the train tracks
behind Union Plaza already?
Bianca Desmond.
Girl's like an oven in there.
Used to love it in there.
How long ago was that?
A few months.
Did you stop by recently
to check out the competition?
No. We lost touch.
So it wouldn't bother you
to know Bianca's moved on,
and she's living
with another guy.
It was good while it lasted.
We found your blood
in her bedroom.
And her dead boyfriend
in the garage.
( chuckles )
That's funny?
Nah.
Just... Bianca's all
fun and games
until someone
shoots you in the leg.
When was that?
Six months ago.
BIANCA:
Hey, sweetie, I went shopping
with my mom.
I'll be home late.
There's some candy for you
on the table.
See you then. Love you.
( gunshot )
( yelling )
MAN:
Stay away
from Bianca.
So I packed my stuff and left.
Did you report it?
Nah. Still on probation for
that "she-looked-18" incident.
This the guy who shot you?
Didn't really get a good look.
I was too busy bleeding.
You go to the hospital?
Sort of had my own
anesthesia thing going on.
So whatever happened
to the bullet?
Yeah, see, human tissue
sticks pretty darn good.
And I can't
scalpel it off,
because I might damage
the bullet's characteristics.
So, uh... so I guess we wait.
WARRICK:
Half of these tools don't match
the size and the shape
of the wound.
And the ones that do,
don't have blood on them.
The killer could
have wiped it off.
I don't see why the killer would
have used a tool anyway,
when he had a gun.
Maybe Ahern disarmed him
and he grabbed
whatever was handy.
Take a look at this.
This guy was tweaker organized.
There's a place for everything.
Except for this.
It's got no space
in the pegboard
and it doesn't match
any of the sets.
How about that?
Got anything else?
Nope.
Print it.
♪ ♪
Hey, Tom Harper?
Detective Jim Brass,
Las Vegas Police.
May I ask you
a couple questions?
Do you know
a Bianca Desmond?
Sounds familiar.
You know she's at
1330 Wildflower Lane.
Oh, yeah, right. Her.
I installed some DSL lines
there a few days ago.
She answered the door
in her panties.
So you've got that hard hat,
tool belt thing working
for you, huh?
I wish.
Kind of girl that makes you
happy to be a man,
know what I'm saying?
Yeah, I kind of remember.
Anyway, we found a tool
with your prints on it
in a garage,
next to a dead guy.
Whoa.
I-I lost an awl
at a job recently.
It must have been there.
Well, we're going to need
to confirm that.
Could you get me
a work order?
Yeah, sure.
Um, I'll pull one
from the office.
I'll run it right over.
Kelly, where you going
in such a hurry?
I have relatives in Provo.
I was going to visit them.
I cleared it with my P.O.
You gonna tell me why
a state trooper
pulled over my bus
and yanked me off?
You know a lady named
Sylvia Mullins?
Yeah.
Did you have a meeting
with her yesterday?
Yeah. So?
So why did you have
a meeting with her?
Sylvia's handling
my dad's estate.
Hmm.
She's the trustee.
What's going on here?
Ms. Mullins was found
in her parking garage...
crushed by her own car.
And you think I have
something to do with it.
When you worked
in the prison garage,
did you just learn how
to fix cars
or did you learn
how to steal them?
Are you kidding me?
Does it look like
I'm kidding you?
You waited for her
to get out of work
so you could let her know
how you felt about her.
( engine starts )
Sylvia was my dad's friend.
She was helping me
get back on my feet.
How I felt
was grateful.
CSI puts me
in jail for something
I didn't do.
Do you really think
I'm going to kill somebody
the minute I get out?
Hold out your hands.
Ms. Mullins' air bag
deployed on impact.
Air bag dust gets everywhere.
It's really hard
to get rid of.
Not if it isn't there.
So the soda can bullet
and the leg bullet
are from the same gun?
Yeah. Bobby was able
to pull more stria
off the leg bullet,
but still no IBIS hits.
So what about
the phone guy, huh?
The utility man's
always a shade-ball.
As much as I love
your generalizations,
actually,
this time you're wrong.
The metallic scrapes on the
garage floor were titanium.
The phone guy's tool
was carbon steel.
Remember we thought
that they
might be dealing meth?
Brass went ahead
and subpoenaed
the phone and bank records.
Guess who's paying
Bianca's mortgage?
A Mr. Harry Desmond.
Happy Harry?
Gas n' Sip Harry Desmond?
Who's your daddy?
No wonder she didn't work.
He owns 50 Gas n' Sips in Vegas.
Well, Harry was nice enough
to leave us a voice message
that was listened to and saved
the night of the murder.
Bianca, honey, it's Daddy.
I got your message
about moving to Colorado
with Ahren.
You can borrow the cabin,
but we need
to talk about this move.
Call me, Princess. I love you.
And this
is the Desmond cabin
in Telluride.
Oh, maybe Mr. Desmond is trying
to protect the family fortune.
Or the family jewels.
I got the results back
from all those sex stains
on the sheets.
Three donors: Ahren, Bianca
and Chelsea.
I guess they were having
a little threesome.
Yeah, I just really hope
he was only doing one woman
at a time.
Chelsea is Bianca's mother.
Look, I know
what it's like
to want to kill
your daughter's boyfriend.
I don't pick fights
that I can't win.
I kill this one,
I got five more dipsticks
waiting to take his place.
I'd just be pushing
the rock up the hill.
Besides,
I was in New York
yesterday.
Yeah, but you didn't want
them to move away together.
I wanted Bianca to get a job.
My biggest mistake
in life?
Giving my baby everything
she ever wanted.
Your wife doesn't seem to mind
your lifestyle.
When Bianca was a teenager,
they fought like cats in a sack.
It's good they've been
spending time together.
Do you know what they're doing?
Well... they're shopping,
dancing...
You know, girl stuff.
They're sleeping
with the same man.
Look...
there was no good reason
for Chelsea to marry me
back in the day.
I had a little money.
Nothing like
what we have now.
She was half my age
and ten times better looking.
I thought if I kept her
on a long
leash...
maybe she'd never stray
that far.
You the kind of guy that likes
to keep guns in the house?
Yeah, of course.
I'm going to need to see them.
Hey, Catherine,
I just got back trace
on Kelly Gordon's fingernails.
I was looking
for air bag dust,
but all Hodges found was air.
Well, join the club.
No usable prints on the
parking garage camera either.
Okay, I'll have Sofia release
her from holding.
Those the vic's phone records?
Yeah.
From her office.
Lots of international calls.
A lot of 345s.
Mm-hmm.
Where's that?
Cayman Islands.
Popular with scuba divers
and money launderers.
I called a few of the
numbers; all banks.
Suggests offshore accounts.
It's not illegal,
but it is very anonymous.
It's also a good way
to siphon money away
from your clients.
That's a leap.
Hey, somebody wanted
this woman dead.
GORDON:
Hi, CSI guy.
You wondering why you're here?
Because you followed
the evidence.
Because that's what CSIs do.
So breathe quick, breathe slow,
put your gun in your mouth
and pull the trigger.
Any way you like,
you're going to die here.
Okay. Perfect.
You're going to die here.
Hey, Archie.
Hey, I did my best
to enhance
the parking garage footage,
but I just can't get an image
on the killer's face.
If you got a couple
of minutes,
I need a voice comparison.
Yeah, what do you got?
Kelly Gordon's voice on tape.
I want to see
if it's the other voice
on the Walter Gordon
audio file.
Grissom told you.
No, but he obviously
told you.
Nick, uh...
You know what?
Forget about it.
If this girl's involved,
that means she's capable
of murder.
It's all cued up for you.
Her voice is first.
Grissom, it's Warrick.
None of the guns Bobby
test-fired were a match
to the bullets,
but Chelsea Wannamaker purchased
a .22 in her name
that was not picked up with
the warrant for Harry's guns.
Okay. I'm on it.
Mrs. Wannamaker.
Wow, that's a hell
of a rock.
I'm surprised
I didn't see that
the other night.
Well, I don't feel safe
wearing this to a club.
Is that why you own a gun?
Well, I used to.
But my gun was stolen
out of my purse,
one night when we went out.
Is there something you want
to say to me?
You trying to buy back some time
there, Mrs. Wannamaker?
Life's short,
but it doesn't end at 40.
Oh, I agree with you.
But it must be tough
for Bianca
to have the kind
of mother that'd sleep
with her boyfriend.
The thing with Ahren
the other night
shouldn't have happened.
We were on Ecstasy...
and a line got crossed.
Oh, yeah.
Lay down.
Okay.
I'll come back.
All right,
you come right back.
( sighs )
Oh, Chelsea, I'm... I'm sorry.
I totally thought
you were Bianca.
That felt so good.
Bianca came in and found us.
I wish it never would have
happened.
What's that, getting busy
with her boyfriend
or getting caught?
I want into the living room
and I let the two of them
talk it out.
Next thing I know,
she announced that
they were moving to Colorado,
so it seemed to me
like they worked it out.
SIDLE:
Freud would have a field day
with this family.
Dad loves his daughter,
but Mom only sees the
daughter as competition.
And everyone wonders why
Bianca can't meet a nice boy.
Bianca eats nice boys
for brunch.
Las Vegas Crime Lab.
Oh. Sara.
Bianca,
can you hear me?
We need an ambulance.
Dispatch, this is CSI Brown.
We have a woman down.
We need a paramedic.
Hey, Bianca.
How you feeling?
Mr. and Mrs. Desmond...
It's Wannamaker.
She's never changed her name.
Ms. Wannamaker,
I'm going to need
a few moments alone
with Bianca.
You never should've told him.
My father's an optimist.
How do you think
they stayed married
for 20 years?
Bianca, I'm going to assume that
whoever did this to you
also killed Ahren.
And I'm also
going to assume
that you know
who that is.
I think you need
to stop protecting everyone
from themselves.
I can't.
Excuse me.
I just need to check
the swelling.
How's the tenderness?
It's fine.
I hope you feel better.
Nurse... Nurse?
Can I get that glove
you were just using?
I'm Sara Sidle, I'm with
the Las Vegas Crime Lab.
Here you go.
Thanks. Uh, I'm also going
to wait around for the SAE kit.
She refused.
Hey, Grissom...
You want to talk to me?
Yeah, sit down.
I heard that Kelly Gordon
may be a suspect
in your murder case.
Yeah.
Is that a problem?
No.
No, it's not a problem.
And by the way,
I heard the tape.
I did a voice comparison.
SYLVIA MULLINS:
ROTH IRA, that'd be perfect
for you.
Sylvia Mullins is the other
voice on the tape.
She's Walter Gordon's
ex-business manager, so...
I'm pretty sure she had
something to do
with my kidnapping.
But now she's dead.
Yeah.
So... it's over.
Yep.
Good.
I think Bianca is
covering for her father.
Well, we figured out the sticky
stuff on Bianca's neck
was creosote.
It's a timber preservative
found on fences, telephone poles
and railroad ties.
Justin lives on
the train tracks.
And he's pretty tweaked out.
Yeah, but he didn't
shoot himself.
And I think that
if he had done it,
Bianca would've told us.
What is it?
Telephone poles.
Tom Harper's work order
for Bianca's DSL line
was dated December 18.
December 18...
fell on a Sunday.
How many workers you know
work on a Sunday?
Is this the original document?
Yeah.
I'm on it.
Always the utility guy.
♪ ♪
SIDLE:
There were two different inks
on the work order,
which means the date on
the work order was compromised.
Tom Harper made a service call
to Bianca's house
not in December, but ten months
earlier, in February.
Why would the guy lie?
It appears that
he was a lot more to her
than just the phone guy.
Our bachelorette
was a very busy girl.
Phone calls from Bianca to Tom
are in yellow,
from Bianca to Justin
are in blue,
and from Bianca to Ahren
are in pink.
There was always overlap.
Bachelor number one:
Tom, phone guy--
strong showing from
February 18 until June-ish.
She called him two,
three times a day.
And then around June 5,
bachelor number two
enters the picture-- Justin.
Ten days of overlap
and then all the calls to Tom
stopped until...
The week Justin was shot
and moved out.
Exactly.
Ahren entered the picture
about five days later
in mid-September.
At that point,
all the phone calls
to the other guys stopped
until just about
a week ago.
When she started
calling Tom again.
Every time this chick calls Tom,
somebody gets shot.
It's like thermite.
Thermite?
When you combine two seemingly
harmless elements--
aluminum and rust--
press them together, add heat...
it creates an explosion so hot
it'll burn through steel.
Powerful
but uncontrollable.
It burns and burns
until it burns itself out,
finally consuming both elements.
I guess some people
just shouldn't be together.
Tom Harper! Come on down!
You made me find you twice,
Tom, that's a drag.
What's the problem?
You know, I think you saw Bianca
in her panties
more than once.
SIDLE:
Now those could change a man.
And it looks like they did.
BRASS:
You know,
it's fill in the blank.
If it walks like a stalker,
talks like a stalker...
I'm not a stalker.
Then what's this?
Excellent service?
Here's the top of the telephone
pole near Bianca's house.
Ahren was tapping
your girl,
so you started tapping
her phone.
I only listened when I
thought she was in trouble.
Look, her father called her
at 7:00 a.m. New York time,
that's 4:00 in the morning
in Vegas.
You had to be
on the pole to hear it
because we were on the scene
an hour later.
HARRY DESMOND:
Biana, honey, it's Daddy.
I got your message about moving
to Colorado with Ahren.
Stay away from Bianca.
Who are you?
You're not taking her
to Colorado.
The hell I'm not.
( gunshot )
I just wanted her to be happy.
With you and no one else.
No.
Those other guys were jerks.
I only wanted
to scare him off.
Oh, like you did with Justin?
That worked.
Yeah, but Bianca didn't come
running back to you,
so I guess
you had to scare her, too.
What are you doing here?
I came to see you.
I think you
should leave.
Your mom wants us
to be together.
My mom?!
Let go!
Her mother and I weren't
always going to be around
to clean up her messes.
Wait a minute.
Are you telling me that Chelsea
asked you to hurt these guys?
So you have some lunatic
stalker telephone repairman
claiming that I told him to kill
my daughter's boyfriends?
Give me a break.
We have multiple calls
to him from Bianca's house
and it was not her.
We also have
on the record
that you called him
from your cell.
Coincidentally,
right around the time
Justin was shot
and Ahren was killed.
We call that solicitation
for murder.
But you'd probably call it,
what, good mother?
I love my daughter.
Yeah, apparently, a lot
of her boyfriends, too.
I called Tom.
I asked him to scare
Justin away.
He was after Bianca
for her money.
I mean, we have
to protect ourselves.
Yeah, but Ahren didn't love her
for her money.
What was wrong
with him?
So he was good enough for you,
but too good for your daughter,
was that it?
I mean, finding a soul
mate is hard enough,
but competing with your mother,
that shouldn't be an issue.
That goes against...
I don't know, nature.
I was attracted to Ahren...
and I was just trying to keep
him away from Bianca and me.
Lady, you unleashed
an unstable man
that you knew was in love
with your daughter.
You had to know that that
was not going to end well.
WILLOWS:
Oh, hey, Nick.
Nick.
Yeah?
We caught a break.
The security guard
confessed.
No.
Archie isolated
a frame of the killer
turning the focus ring.
She did it.
Las Vegas Police!
Open up!
Kelly Gordon,
you're under arrest
for the murder
of Sylvia Mullins.
Stand up.
Stand up!
Care why I did it?
Doesn't really matter now.
She told me my dad
didn't leave me anything.
He never would've
done that.
He loved me.
So you killed her?
The ransom was her idea.
She didn't get
the money.
She took it from me.
She's ODing.
She's ODing right now.
Call a paramedic.
Vicodine, INH, methadone.
Kelly! Kelly!
Kelly!