( eerie tones playing )
SWAT LEADER ( distorted ):
Get the paramedics.
Hang in there, Jim,
hang in there.
Right here.
Good job.
Sir, sir, can
you see me?
Sir, can you hear me?
Sir, stay with me.
Sir?
He's got a
pulse of 120.
( distorted,
indistinct chatter )
PARAMEDIC:
55 year-old male,
GSW left anterior chest,
entering at the level
of the deltoid and AC joint.
Minimally responsive.
He's a cop.
Tachycardic in the 120s,
BP's 86 over 40 and dropping,
02 stats in the 80s
with assisted ventilation...
Okay, we're losing a
lot of blood here.
We need two
large-bore I.V.'s.
Run the fluids wide,
he's extremely hypotensive.
Absent breath sounds
on the left.
Likely pneumothorax.
Let's put in a chest tube
and pressors for that BP stat.
( machine beeps )
He's in V-fib!
( undistorted ):
Paddles!
( high-pitched whine )
( heart monitor flatlines )
Three hundred!
Clear!
Come on. Come on!
Come on.
Three-sixty!
Clear!
BRASS:
I envy these parents who live
in ignorant bliss
because I know how my daughter,
Ellie, lives.
I know the company she keeps
and I know what she does
to get by.
And... anyway, I mean,
I'm... I'm...
a couple of nights ago
I'm in LA and sitting in my car
on Hollywood Boulevard
watching her work a corner.
And my eyes are playing tricks
on me because I don't see
what she's doing,
I see what she was.
I see a little six year-old girl
with a ponytail,
playing with crayons...
...singing a little tune
to herself.
It's... I don't know,
all I want to do is save her.
But the thing is,
you know,
if something happened to me...
I don't think
Ellie would, uh... care.
So I'm asking you
to do me this favor.
There's no one I trust more
with my life,
or my death... than you.
Captain Brass
was shot twice.
First bullet
lodged in his vest.
Second entered through
his axilla, hit an artery,
and is lodged near his heart.
He's has internal
hemorrhaging.
Any neural damage?
We won't know
until we stop the bleeding.
If we stop it.
Have next-of-kin been notified?
For medical purposes, I
have his power of attorney.
You may have a decision to make.
I'll let you know.
( ringing )
Grissom.
Yeah.
Okay.
D.B. in Henderson
on the train tracks.
I'll take the first watch.
You go work.
CURTIS:
I just spoke
with McKeen.
I heard it's bad.
GRISSOM:
Pretty bad.
They're trying
to stabilize him.
The last train passed
through here an hour ago.
The engineer thought
he saw a body
on the track, but
couldn't stop on time.
He radioed dispatcher,
who called 911.
No I.D.
Probably decapitated
by the train.
Well, if scavengers
nicked his clothes,
they left a nice pair
of riding boots.
They probably
didn't have time
to finish the job
before other trains
roared through here.
Well, the engineer
isn't saying anything else
until his union rep gets here,
which... could be a while.
I'll let you know.
Great.
You know, there's not a lot
of blood on the ground
for a decapitation
like this.
Well, we don't know
how far he was dragged.
Where's the head?
I'll find it.
Hey, Nick.
Yeah?
I think I found a toupee.
Our vic may be bald.
Thanks, that will help me
distinguish it from the other
severed heads I find
out here.
Whoa.
What a waist.
♪ ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
GRISSOM:
David, are you getting
the liver temp
or performing acupuncture?
Well, his liver's not
where it's supposed to be.
Do you think this is some kind
of birth defect?
What do you think?
I think I feel fat.
Yes.
Got the liver.
Suicide?
SIDLE:
A guy loses his shirt
at the tables,
decides to take a permanent nap
on the tracks.
( train whistle blows )
( man screams )
Well, he died with his boots on.
SUPER:
You don't have to go
through the dude's mail.
Name's Manny Rupert.
He's a new tenant.
Paid first and
last in cash.
We got a lot of party
people around here.
You know, so there's
loud music every night,
but this dude was
pumping tunes
at 7:00 in
the morning.
You know, I knock on
the door, I go in,
that's when I see the dude
all laid out on the bed.
Mm-hmm.
Uh, figured I
better step out,
call in the big guns.
That's you.
Um, listen...
if my good citizenship is not
going to be appreciated here,
maybe I just don't call
the next one in, you know?
Just stay here
and shut up.
I'll be back to
take your prints,
assuming they're not
already in the system.
Um... okay.
( indistinct radio
communication )
Which of the seven deadly sins
are not represented here?
Petecchial hemorrhaging.
Could be from vomiting
or asphyxiation.
This guy was rolling
on all cylinders.
He was bound to throw a rod.
Or somebody
threw it for him.
Pillow or a hand on the face
certainly could've
done the trick.
ROBBINS:
Well, based on
the lack of rigor,
T.O.D.'s three
or four hours ago;
tell you more
after we clean him up
and open him up.
Wallet's empty.
WILLOWS:
You know what they say,
it's not a real party
till somebody breaks
something.
I got blood.
I got a noisemaker.
Bullet holes.
Somebody shot out the mirror.
No apparent gunshot
wounds on the vic.
Let's get busy, boys.
( train whistle blows )
( shutter clicks )
( stream flowing )
♪ ♪
This man's organs
were displaced.
It's similar to the way a
pregnant woman's internal organs
get rearranged to compensate
for her expanding uterus.
Some of these blisters
are fresh.
But there's evidence
of scarring and irritation
going back years.
It all suggests a consistent
long-term pressure
on the waist.
So what,
torture or self-inflicted?
I don't know.
But either way,
it must have been agonizing.
I'm beginning to sense
that COD was not
decapitation.
There's
a bullet hole...
COD, shot to the head
with this.
It looks like lead.
.44 caliber is my guess.
That's a cannon.
SURGEON:
We managed to stop
the bleeding,
but his condition
is critical.
What are the options?
We could try
to remove the bullet.
What are the risks?
If we go in, the vertebral
artery could be impacted.
He could bleed out
or stroke out.
Permanent incapacitation.
And without surgery?
The bullet could migrate
into the artery
and, again, cause a stroke
or kill him.
Or it could stay there
for years and do nothing.
He might never wake up.
What are the odds?
Mr. Grissom,
this isn't a casino.
I don't give odds.
It's your call.
Do it.
( phone line ringing )
ELLIE:
Hi, it's Ellie.
You know the drill.
( beep )
Ellie, this is Gil Grissom
from the Las Vegas Crime Lab.
I'm a friend of your father's.
I'm sorry to have to tell you
this, but your dad's been shot.
And his condition is serious.
I think you should
come and see him.
It would help him a lot.
Please call me at 702-555-0141.
White residue
on your vic's so-called waist
was topical cortisone,
prescription strength.
The guy had
an itch.
He was doing
more than scratching.
Topical doesn't get absorbed
into the bloodstream.
But Henry says
that the guy's blood
was flooded with cortisone.
That makes sense,
as much orthopedic pain
as the guy was in.
You checking out my waist?
I'm a 32-incher myself.
Same as in college.
Oh.
Congratulations.
Women aren't the only ones
who feel the pressure
to look good.
Time was, having a rotund belly
was a sign of
prosperity and success.
Now it just means you're
a lazy glutton, not getting any.
Fibers.
The fibers from the
victim's long johns
are consistent with the fibers
found in the burned-up clothes.
STOKES:
Means those were
the clothes he was wearing.
Raw wool, dyed grey.
Did you get a manufacturer?
No one from
my database.
But I did find
pomegranate berry extract,
used to turn wool
dye in the 1800s.
STOKES:
Insect activity
all over these fibers.
Maybe moths or mites.
Check it out.
HODGES:
Means that the fabric was old.
Vintage clothing, maybe?
Maybe.
Did you analyze
the bone fragments?
I'm only one
highly-gifted person.
( sighs )
I'll let you know.
You been to the hospital?
They're prepping
him for surgery.
I'll keep good thoughts.
Mr. Party Till I Drop.
His blood alcohol level
was .28.
Point two-eight?!
That's barely conscious
for most people.
That's like falling-down drunk.
Drunk just gets you
in the door.
We're also talking cocaine,
opiates, barbiturates,
methamphetamine,
MDMA, THC.
Serum was milky white
with triglycerides.
Wow.
If it was illegal, fun or nasty,
this guy was into it.
Yeah, I'll say.
I just analyzed
the secretion swabs
you collected from his body.
Was there enough for DNA?
Oh, yeah.
The donor's female.
She's consistent with both
the blood from the mirror
and the pubic hair
from the victim's mouth.
And then I ran
the profile through CODIS,
and you got really lucky.
She's a local prostitute.
She's in the system
for a trick roll.
ROBBINS:
There's evidence of sexual
activity in every orifice,
including his ears.
WILLOWS:
You joking?
No.
We've got pubic hairs,
vaginal secretions.
Maybe he suffocated
during oral sex.
Would you care to move on
to stomach contents?
Guess we're done
with the appetizers.
Well, the main
course was
enough alcohol and cake
to cater a wedding.
Well, at least
he went out in style, hmm?
ROBBINS:
Alone, maybe none of it
would've been fatal, but
taken all together...
Means he died with
a smile on his face.
Among other things.
( chuckles )
( door opens )
Hey.
Just came from the hospital.
Oh.
No, no.
Traffic fatality.
Sorry.
( woman speaking over intercom )
GRISSOM:
Where's McKeen?
I sent him home.
Just kidding. He went
to get something to eat.
Brass just went into surgery.
You two have known each
other for a long time.
We've worked together ever since
he came from New Jersey.
Just between you and me,
does he always wear a suit?
Like when you guys
go to dinner,
the movies or whatever it is
you do when you hang out.
'Cause I got
to tell you,
thought of him in a sweater
kind of freaks me out.
We don't "hang out," Greg.
No kidding.
I just assumed...
ELLIE:
What do you mean
consent was given?
Nobody has asked my consent
to do anything,
and I'm his daughter.
NURSE:
I understand
you're upset, miss,
but there's no need
to take that tone.
ELLIE:
Look, I'm just here to
see my father, okay?
He's a cop.
He's in surgery.
The only thing
you can do right now
is take a seat
and wait until he gets out.
Excuse me, Ellie?
What?
I'm Gil Grissom.
Thanks for coming.
So I guess you're the
one who's in charge.
How long is his
surgery going to take?
Probably a few hours.
Look, I just got off a
bus, I would really like
to take a shower and change
and maybe get a little rest.
Do you have the
keys to his house?
No.
Well, you're a cop, right?
How 'bout you just let me in?
You know, there's a motel
just down the street.
I'll get you a room.
Do you want to
check my arms?
Go ahead.
All right? It looks like
Daddy already told you
all about me.
I don't even know why
I bothered to come.
How's it going?
You okay?
I'm okay.
That's a...
man in a corset.
Corset-training.
A venerable practice.
Maybe for Scarlett O'Hara.
Since when was it
equal opportunity?
In Victorian times,
it was considered
a staple of masculine attire.
Students in British
boarding schools
were encouraged to lose
an inch a year
from the time they were 14 on.
I guess I should feel comforted
that sadistic ideas of beauty
aren't restricted to women.
Mm.
It's called a wasp-waist,
which is revealing.
A wasp is from
the insect group
hymenoptera.
The notion of hymen
indicates virginity.
In predacious wasps, the
genitalia no longer functions
as a reproductive organ.
It's used as a stinger.
Go in for sex and get stung.
Pretty much every man's fear.
Mm.
The victim was shot,
body dumped, clothes burned.
The corset, too.
The bone fragments
that Nick found
at the crime scene
were whalebone,
which is what they used
to make corsets out of.
Where did you learn
so much about corsets?
I have my sources.
MAN:
The embroidery is Chinese, silk.
The lace is made
from hand-tatted linen thread.
Ribs are pure whalebone.
They don't make them
like this anymore.
I'm sure the whales
appreciate that.
How many, if any,
do you sell to men?
More than you'd think.
Many men with back problems
have remarked how much better
a boned-tabbed
Elizabethan corset feels
than a steel back brace.
Oh.
Let's focus on your customers
that don't have back problems.
Ms. Sidle, people's private
lives are their own business.
I don't want to...
Mr. Phillipe, I have a dead man
with a 19-inch waist
and no way to identify him.
Any help at all
would be appreciated.
Do you have a picture?
I have a head shot.
( hyperventilating )
Oh, my God, that's, uh,
that's Caleb Carson.
He comes in
once a year for a re-stitch
and reinforcement.
Is he into pain, masochism?
I don't know.
How about cross-dressing?
I seriously doubt that.
How come?
Mr. Carson never spoke much,
but he was the type of man who,
when he came into the store,
if I were sitting down,
I'd immediately stand up.
He treated me
like a servant.
And, truth be told,
he actually made me
feel like one.
I'm going to need his address.
Colonel Caleb
"C.C." Carson.
1864.
SIDLE:
Resembles
the victim.
At least from the neck up.
These are Civil
War-era photos.
CURTIS:
They didn't
smile much back then.
Subjects had to hold completely
still for five minutes.
Otherwise, the
exposure would blur.
It hurt to
hold a smile.
Bet these hurt more.
It's the same caliber
killed the vic.
They don't make 'em
like they used to.
♪ ♪
( "Dixie" and gunfire
play on recording )
♪ ♪
Warrick just called
from the hospital.
They got the bullet.
How's he doing?
He hasn't regained
consciousness yet.
This fellow seems
to have lost his way.
Is this Gettysburg?
You into military history?
My dad was.
Used to spend the summer
touring Pennsylvania in an RV,
so I could learn things.
You were a lucky girl.
Pickett's Charge, I think.
The Confederates advanced
from this position
to Cemetery Ridge.
They marched to their doom,
but kept their honor.
Carson obviously
was a Son of the South.
Looks comfortable.
GRISSOM:
Well, he was into
discipline and
self-denial.
This corset ties from the back,
which means Mr.
Carson couldn't have tied
the laces by himself.
He had to have help.
Seems to run in the family.
Oh, I don't
really know. I...
You know what?
Let me call you back.
Ellie?
Hey.
You know your father's
out of surgery.
Yeah. How's he doing?
It's a little too early
to tell, but I know
when he wakes up,
he'll be happy to see you.
You think so?
I know so. You look good.
Yeah, you mean, I don't look
like a crack whore anymore?
That's not what I meant, but no.
Does he ever talk about me?
That's a no.
Look,
what do you want me to say, hmm?
It's not really about
you right now, okay?
But the fact that you're here
is saying a lot.
Yeah, well, thanks
for clearing that up for me.
Remember that trick roll
that you pled out last year?
I have no idea what
you're talking about.
Your DNA in our database says
that you do.
We found your blood
in Manny Rupert's apartment,
with him lying there dead.
If you Belushi'd the guy,
maybe you didn't mean to.
Now would be the time to say it.
Look, I'm the victim here.
Funny, you don't look dead.
( heavy sigh )
Look, the whole night
started out normal, okay?
I mean, he paid for everything.
He was kind of fun.
( cork popping )
And he was up for anything.
I mean, there was champagne,
E, coke, cake.
And he wasn't even
bad-looking.
So, how did it go so bad?
Well, usually, a guy is good
for maybe one or two.
This guy wanted more after six,
if you know what I mean.
No "off" switch?
No, not even close.
It's getting kind of late.
No, look, you're not...
you're not going anywhere!
Okay, honey, you need
to get some rest.
No. I paid
for the whole night!
( gunshots, screaming )
Son of a... Ow. Ouch. Ow.
He was whacked out,
but he was alive when I bolted.
Well, that's a
great story,
but it doesn't sound
like it was worth the ten G's
that we found in your purse.
I earned that money.
Don't take it personally,
but you are not
a $10,000-a-night girl.
Are you finished processing
those prints
from Manny Rupert's
apartment?
Does it look like I have?
So far, the decedent's prints
are everywhere.
Got them on liquor bottles,
drug paraphernalia, the gun,
the dishes.
Are you looking for something
in particular?
We're looking for
anything the hooker
might have touched.
We're thinking she might
have slipped him something
that pushed him
over the edge.
Uh...
I got her prints
off of the bedpost,
the chair, and a soda can.
She didn't touch the booze
or pills.
Maybe she's in AA.
Hmm.
Maybe she's
not a killer.
I just can't believe it.
I've been with Mr. Carson
for years.
How do you mean?
Nothing like that.
I was his driver.
I take it you got my
fingerprints from my work card?
That's right.
They were on one
of Mr. Carson's corsets.
I was also Mr. Carson's dresser.
What did that entail?
In the 19th century,
a dresser's job was
to help gentleman soldiers
with their equipment.
So you dressed him
in Rebel drag.
If you're asking,
did I lace his corset,
of course.
Every morning.
Did it hurt?
Absolutely.
But he controlled the pain.
When was the last time
you saw him?
Yesterday morning.
At the house.
No.
At a duel.
A duel?
Where?
Gettysburg.
( gunfire )
( cannon fire )
( screaming )
( indistinct shouting )
( men shouting )
If all you do
is Civil War recreations,
why were you
and Caleb Carson having a duel?
Ugh! Apparently,
I offended him.
Honey, I'm right in the
middle of Cemetery Ridge here.
I care what
we have for dinner.
Well, check the cupboards...
Sir!
( grunts )
You dishonor
the dead.
Damn it, Caleb, that was my wife
I was talking to.
My great-great
grandfather spilled blood
on this hallowed ground.
Oh, really?
I didn't know
Gettysburg was in Nevada.
I demand satisfaction.
I challenge you to a duel, sir!
( heavy sigh )
Okay. Fine.
Let's do it.
I'd never reenacted a duel,
so, uh,
we agreed to meet on the field
of honor with our pistols.
And real bullets?
No, no, not
in my gun.
No, I figured we were just going
to blast some powder
and then go out for pancakes.
Caleb wanted
a little more authenticity.
Guns at the ready and...
one, two,
three, four, five,
six, seven, eight,
nine, ten.
( screams )
( men shouting
in distance )
But this isn't a recreation,
you know.
He really shot me.
Almost nicked the bone.
It's a good thing
my second was there.
He's a male nurse.
CURTIS:
A man
shoots you,
and you don't call the police?
He shot me 'cause
I was taking a cell phone call.
What do you think he was going
to do if went to the cops?
When that
bullet hit me,
I ran for my life.
I jumped in my car
and got the heck out of here.
What about him?
Oh, we-we carpool.
Colt .44?
Yeah.
Is that your dueling pistol?
We're going to have
to take that with us.
Why?
I, too, demand satisfaction.
( men shouting )
Ready?
Ready.
BOTH:
One, two, three,
four, five, six,
seven, eight,
nine, ten.
( camera shutters clicking )
I got blood drops.
Heading way from Mr. Carson.
Consistent
with the duelist's story.
( screams )
( camera shutter clicking )
I got something here, too.
This could be the blood
that we didn't find
at the train tracks--
It's a lot of blood.
( camera shutter clicking )
Maybe Carson was killed here.
( muffled voices on intercom )
Yeah, she's here.
Been drinking a ton of coffee
and going outside for smokes;
on her cell.
Not real sociable, you know?
You want me
to keep an eye on her?
GRISSOM:
It sounds like you already are.
Nah. I'm off the clock.
I'll stick around
for awhile,
let you know
if there's any change.
Thank you, Nick.
Did you compare the bullet
from the victim
to this pistol?
Uh, no, not yet,
but, boss,
I don't think
that's your murder weapon.
And you know this how?
Uh, here,
I'll let Hawkeye show you.
What is that?
DAWSON:
Well, Hodges will
have to confirm,
but I'm pretty certain
it's cream of wheat.
So he's a cereal killer.
Snap, crackle and pop.
Uh, the dried powdered
wheat particles actually
augments the smoke, and, uh,
seals the gunpowder
in the cylinder.
Which would be perfect
for Civil War reenactments.
Yeah. I don't think
that Colt's fired
a real bullet in quite a while.
BROWN:
Miss Rupert,
as far as we can tell,
your brother died
from diabetic shock.
What? How?
Well, it seems
that he went
on a bender.
He consumed
a great deal of alcohol, sugar
and narcotics.
Did he party
like this a lot?
No. No.
He was just diagnosed
as pre-diabetic.
So he was aware
of his condition.
Yeah.
Do you like that
this was self-induced?
( sighs )
You know,
our family has a history
of heart disease and diabetes.
Both our parents died of
heart attacks in their 40s.
Two of our
grandparents, too.
Well, Manny turned 40 last week
and he acted
like it was a death sentence.
You know, but he...
he always said,
"You can't fight bad genes."
You know, he had a vasectomy
when he was 22.
Never got married,
just didn't see the point.
So he just... gave up?
He quit?
You don't know what it's like
to live with a death sentence
hanging over your head.
No. You're right, I don't.
No.
But I've seen what it's like
to not have a choice.
And he did.
He could have fought it,
but he just chose not to.
You know, I just lost my
brother, and you're judging him?
How dare you.
I'm-I'm so very
sorry for your loss.
Am I interrupting?
No.
I just got a heads up from
a friend in payroll at PERS.
Ellie Brass just called
about Jim's pension.
She wanted to know
how much there was
and was she
a beneficiary.
This girl is circling
like a vulture.
Jim doesn't need this kind
of energy around him now.
Now...
Ellie's been in
a lot of trouble with the law.
It wouldn't be difficult
to chase her out of town.
Well, I'm sure
he'd appreciate the offer,
but I don't think
he'd want you to do that.
Excuse me.
I got the DNA results
for your decapitated
Civil War corset victim,
and the blood from the field
is a match to Carson,
but the epithelials
on the toupee
from the train tracks
are not.
So, were any of your suspects
wearing a rug?
I can think of one.
Please be careful.
That's a very expensive piece.
I don't understand
why I'm here again.
It's not a crime
to lose your hair.
Depends on where you lose it.
SIDLE:
If it's on
the train tracks
near a decapitated body
with the victim's blood on it,
it's usually a crime.
Mr. Kimble,
would you like to revise
your prior statement?
Or would you prefer
to wait in a cell
while we match toupees?
It was an accident.
Which part?
I suppose mostly the part
when I shot him.
I could see
the insanity in his eyes.
( gunfire, yelling )
Mr. Carson, you shot him!
You really shot him!
And I intend to kill him.
Get out of my way!
KIMBLE:
Please!
( gunshot )
He was really going
to kill that man.
If it was an accident,
you should have called 911.
I couldn't let him
be found like that.
His corseting was private.
You're right,
it's much better
to have his body found stripped
and dumped on some train tracks.
His great-great-great
grandfather died trying to stop
a Yankee train
from entering Virginia.
Legend has it he stood
square on the tracks
firing at the engineer
until the train ran him down.
Mr. Carson spoke
of it frequently.
He said it was
an honorable death.
I was just trying
to give him the same.
All right, look, are you
guys arresting me or what?
Hey, don't get in my face.
All he told me
was bring you here.
Hi. Come in.
This is your dad's office.
Yeah, I can read.
Have a seat.
Why?
Why not?
( chuckles )
That's the reason
we asked you to come in.
That's like loving a puppy.
That's easy.
You know,
did you ever think
that maybe he's better off
just lying there
and not waking up?
A lot easier.
DOCTOR:
Every patient is different,
but for now,
no change is good news.
( cell phone ringing )
Excuse me.
Hi, Lindsey.
I know, I told you that
I might be a little while.
No, I said that we
could try and see a movie.
Hey, you know what?
I've got a friend here who
is fighting for his life.
I would appreciate
a little understanding.
I will talk about this
with you later. Good-bye.
How old?
Fourteen.
Supposedly.
I got one of those
in high school myself.
World's pretty small
at that age.
It feels pretty small
to me right now, too.
WOMAN ( over P.A. ):
Code Blue alert.
( monitor beeping rapidly )
( beeping slows
and stabilizes )
( monitor beeping steadily )
( weakly ):
Hey.
Have some water.
Thanks for not pulling the plug.
Your, uh, fan club is here.
( sighs )
I don't know.
Most people want to die
in their sleep, I suppose.
Never know that it's happening.
Like a crime scene.
Surprise, you're dead.
I'd prefer to know in advance
that I was going to die.
I'd like to be diagnosed
with cancer, actually.
Have some time to prepare.
( sighs )
Go back to the rain forest
one more time.
Reread Moby Dick.
Possibly enter an international
chess tournament.
At least have enough time to say
good-bye to the people I love.
I'm not ready
to say good-bye.