♪ ♪
( gunshot )
Feel like getting high?
Do I have to?
Hey, this is Stokes.
I need a lift
to Convention Center Drive.
Looks like somebody had some
late-night target practice.
Three Boy Does.
No I.D.s.
Nobody saw anything.
Nine-millimeter shells
all over the place.
That's a lot of racket.
Somebody heard something.
Only ones who did
thought it was
the fireworks
show at the Wynn.
Good luck.
GRISSOM:
What do you think?
Time of death: 3:17 A.M.?
Shot through
a Flavor Flav clock.
Haven't seen one of
these since high school.
Old school's the new school.
So, what do you think?
This has got to be
a gang war, huh?
Well, if it's a gang war...
these kids were outgunned.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
No personal effects!
No keys, no I.D.!
Nothing!
Either these kids
were traveling light,
or they were
robbed blind.
And who the hell
would rob them up there?
Andre the Giant?
Hey, Doc, is it just me,
or did something crush his legs?
Well, first off...
...looks like he is a she,
and something
crushed her legs.
What do you think
this is?
That's your job.
Yeah.
Well... I did find casings
in such a wide distribution...
and a lot of them
were flattened,
so it suggests to me
that the killer was moving
when he was shooting.
( gunshots )
Drive-by?
Yeah, with
a hit-and-run chaser.
What up, country?
So, the bullet is
practically smooth.
I mean, no sharp-edged
rifling marks.
Which means
it was probably fired
from a polygonal barrel.
Did you run
cartridge casings yet?
Yeah, yeah, and got
an IBIS hit off of a
firing pin impression.
Murder weapon
is an H&amp;K MP-5.
That's a $2,500 firearm.
That's not
your typical street piece.
Yeah. It registered
to LVPD.
Really?
Yeah.
Those babies are
very popular with
law enforcement,
and that one
is issued to SWAT...
and reported stolen
during a drug raid
on Vegas Valley and Sandhill...
six months ago.
♪ ♪
Hodges, you
getting anywhere
with that steel
rod we found?
Your steel rod is part
of a custom hydraulic cylinder.
Size and shape is a match
for a brand called "Red's."
BROWN:
Oh, this guy was driving
a street hopper.
Low-riders get
little clearance...
I'm sure he was more busted up
about his ride being damaged
than the three kids he whacked.
Hmm. Also found
paint traces on the rod.
Color is Chesapeake
Blue Pearl.
It's from a Dupont line
called "Brilliantz."
Mostly used on
show vehicles.
Red's auto parts are
individually serialized.
Shouldn't be too hard
to find out where it was sold.
Cool.
A'ight, G, so...
Don't make me shoot you.
GUY:
Crime Scene Investigation.
Hell, I love a bloody scene...
DNA and all that.
Look, you give me
a serial number,
I can definitely figure out
who bought it.
Yeah, yeah,
here you go.
A'ight.
This is
the old style cylinder.
Give me a second.
Yeah, man, this, uh...
serial's not showing up.
You said "definitely."
Yeah, but these
old serial numbers
sometimes get erased
from the system.
I mean, it's happened, you know?
Sounds like the wrong name
might've just popped up.
No name popped up.
What's the matter, man?
You worried about having
some hard times if you give
your homey's name up?
I'll get a warrant.
You don't mind taking
a break for a while,
sitting on the curb while
we get some cops up in here.
Look, man, I don't need that
kind of a scene around here.
How 'bout we do this?
How 'bout you let us
muscle you off
your computer,
and we can get the
information ourselves?
That way, if
you're ever asked,
you can say there was
nothing you could do.
You can let us do
our jobs, and we'll
be out of your hair.
I can live with that.
Good man.
BROWN:
Jeremiah Calvin. 59391 Sandhill.
That's the same part of town
where the SWAT cop lost his gun.
STOKES:
How long ago
did I call for backup?
About 15 minutes.
( sighs )
Dispatch,
this is unit 3D7.
We are 465
at 59391 Sandhill.
ETA on that backup?
DISPATCHER ( over radio):
Unit 3D7,
ETA approximately five minutes.
Copy that.
We'll sit tight.
Hello. There's
our gangster ride right there.
With a gangster in it.
Yep.
Look at that.
He saw us.
I think I'll go
get him now, man,
before I lose that boy.
STOKES:
Go for it, go for it.
Dispatch,
this is unit 3D7.
Suspect is on the move.
It's a, uh,
royal blue Chevy Impala
northbound
on Valley View Drive.
License 4-2-3-
Nora-Queen-John.
Northbound.
DISPATCH:
Copy that.
I'll inform the backup.
STOKES:
Dispatch, westbound Hatteras.
Westbound Hatteras.
Northbound Sequoia.
Dispatch,
northbound Sequoia.
Dispatch, uh,
this is unit 3D7.
Suspect has pulled
into an alley
on the 7700
block on Eastern.
Requesting backup.
We've got two on the way.
They're stuck behind a TC
on Maryland Parkway.
Hey, what are you doing?
I told you little punk...
airport cops
to stop riding me, man.
BROWN:
Son, get back
in the car.
You get out the car!
All this old Crime Scene stuff
followin' me, man.
Y'all think you're all cops?
Y'all ain't cops.
STOKES:
That's right,
we're not cops.
We're mad scientists.
Back away from
the vehicle
and let me see your
hands right now.
Dispatch, we got
a code three.
Hey, hold on, man,
you calling for backup?
Your backup or my backup?
Son, you trying to win
the wet tee shirt contest?
My partner here's
a great shot.
Yeah, you're real cute
with that gun, too.
I'm not going to
tell you again.
You know what, man?
I've had so many damn guns
pointed at my face, I feel
right at home looking at yours.
Let me see your hands.
How you know
I won't shoot your man?
Huh? How you know I ain't
got something at my waist
pointed at your
man right now?
You know,
hollow points'll go
right through the door.
( sirens blaring )
BROWN:
You want to shoot me, huh?
( Stokes shouting indistinctly)
Whoa, whoa, hey, right here.
He was reaching
for something.
Check him
for weapons, Mitch.
It's cool. He's clean.
He's clean?
I don't need no gun for you!
Just be cool.
Come on,
Just be cool,
just be cool.
I'm telling you, man,
I'm ready to file a
complaint right now.
And that not-a-cop
better be lucky I
ain't suing his ass.
Maybe I will.
Look, man, I wasn't
even doing nothing.
Hey.
All I did
was ask him...
How'd things go
with Ecklie?
Not good.
CALVIN:
I wasn't speeding...
Don't worry.
I'll go and talk to him.
No, don't talk to him.
BRASS:
You want to tell me
what your car was doing
at the scene of a triple
homicide two nights ago?
Wait, hold up,
h-hold up, man.
Let's get
this straight.
I don't own a car.
You can check
the papers.
That's my
Grandpa's ride.
So you borrowed it
two nights ago?
No, I didn't.
I was working, man.
I deejay over at O.G.
If you don't believe
me, you could ask
Jeni, and Rocker Jules, and GG,
and Lina, and Blaze.
You know, I had
my first five-some that night.
And there wasn't no
homicides goin' down.
You could believe that.
I'm happy for you, man.
So, what, are you pinning
this rap on Grandpa?
Yo, man, my grandpa was
a gangster back in the day.
You'd be surprised.
Yeah, I'm really not surprised
by much anymore.
We have a warrant
to search your house...
and I bet I find a crime
to go with every gun.
If I'd killed those kids...
you would never find a gun.
( knocks on door )
Las Vegas Police.
We have a warrant
to search the premises.
MAN:
Come on in.
( TV playing )
Costs money to fix a door.
Thanks for knocking.
OFFICER:
Clear.
Got any guns in the house, sir?
I don't allow that garbage
in here.
Where's Jeremiah's room?
End of the hall.
Got nothing.
I'm going to need you to
verify the whereabouts
of your grandson
Jeremiah two nights ago.
How the hell would I know?
Man, you're making me
miss my program.
It's not like I got that TiVo.
WILLOWS:
Mr. Calvin?
Whose room is next
to Jeremiah's?
Morris'.
Did Morris ever
drive the car?
Go ask him.
Where is he?
He wasn't in his room?
He's been in there all day.
Morris?
( grunting )
Control, this is CSI Willows.
We need an ambulance.
Hey, Morris,
somebody's coming for you.
He doesn't have a bad attitude,
he has Clostridium tetani.
Tetanus.
I extracted this
from the wound in his calf.
DOCTOR:
Bacteria on the stable
got into the bloodstream
releasing toxins that enabled
muscular contractions.
That's why they call it lockjaw.
No wonder he wouldn't talk--
he couldn't.
How long before he can?
Take couple of days
for the antibiotics
to flush it out of his system.
Well, he doesn't have
lock-wrist.
You got a pen?
We match your blood
to the staple gun,
it puts you
at Convention Center Drive
and you go down
for three murders.
You have anything
to tell us,
now's the time.
( camera shutter clicking )
( automatic gunfire )
Hey, so the car was
definitely at the scene.
Blood on the soft-top was a
match to one of the vics.
And Morris Calvin
was there.
DNA confirmed
that it was his blood
on the staple gun.
( gunfire )
( staple gun fires )
( cries out )
( gunfire )
Yeah, but we don't have
a murder weapon
so we can't confirm Morris
was the shooter.
There's a ton of
unknown prints on the car.
GSR in the backseat.
Had to be other people involved.
If we could ID the vics,
it might tell us
who'd want them dead.
Standard procedure
for a drive-by
is shoot as much as you can
as fast as you can, right?
Then leave as fast as you can.
So why did Morris
get out of the car?
Maybe the vics
had something he wanted.
The only thing the
victims on the ground had
on them were the clothes
on their back.
And the kid in the palm tree,
empty satchel.
Vega ran the vics' past the guys
in the Gang Unit.
Nobody recognized them.
And tox panels on them
all came back negative.
There were no drugs
in their system,
no personal effects.
I doubt they were
even packing.
They were packing posters.
Are you suggesting that they
were killed for their posters?
Maybe for what was on them.
All right, now
wait a minute,
Grissom, there were posters
all over that street.
Man, we have no way of knowing
which posters they put up.
Well, you got the staple gun.
Figure out what they stapled.
♪ ♪
( machines humming
rhythmically )
Hey, slick.
I saw my P.O. yesterday, guys,
so you can just go home.
Parole officer didn't
bring us here, cousin.
A poster did.
If you're trying to stick me
with some kind of
child porno thing
or something
sick like that,
I'm not your guy.
I do mainly concerts
and conventions
and have
for the past 20 years.
I'm cheap, fast,
and open 24/7.
Just like my ex-wife.
You have any idea
where this came from?
You know, maybe.
The wall of fame.
This is where my customers
can appreciate my work.
Let's see here.
Yeah, now
this is a classic.
Now I know about
"Chicks Gone Nutz"
because of
their booby videos
but "Dudes Gone Nutz"
now... ( chuckles )
that really busts my belt.
You know, wait a second...
I think I've seen
that guy before.
It's Dollar. He's a rapper.
No kidding.
Those dudes are nuts.
Yeah, well,
everybody goes nuts.
Any idea who ordered
up the poster?
Skinny little black kid,
day before yesterday.
One of these?
Oh...
Man. That's too bad.
Yeah, there he is.
How did he pay?
Wad of cash.
Interframe artifacts.
It's a still frame from a video.
I'm afraid we're going
to deplete your wall of fame--
that posters coming with us.
I did a search on Dollar.
His real name
is Jessie Cleveland.
Vegas street kid made good,
first CD went platinum.
Brass is contacting
his managers.
Here he is.
I'm guessing this is not
his next album cover.
I hope not.
So when I went online,
I found the usual things...
websites, photos,
and this...
DOLLAR:
Playa, look, dawg,
you know what I'm saying,
I got stacks of cash
in the back, man,
I got jewelry, I got Black
American Express cards.
I got whatever you want, man,
take it all, dawg.
MAN:
Put your face in the bed,
your ass in the air,
and say what I want you to say.
I'm Dollar...
from "Dudes Gone Nutz"
and I liked it...
( exhales heavily )
I like to take it...
Video was mirrored
on a dozen rap sites.
It's all over the net.
This ain't right, dawg.
So this is a rap thing?
Biggie and Tupac?
Who's the bitch now?
You got it, dawg.
If these guys would shoot
somebody over lyrics,
they'd definitely
kill over this.
Yeah.
WOMAN:
Mr. Dollar
left strict instructions
not to be disturbed.
Well, that's too bad
'cause we're conducing
a murder investigation.
Las Vegas Police.
Open up.
So what are you
waiting for?
Thank you.
Hey, Jim, check it out.
Hitting on 21.
Looks a lot different,
doesn't he, all pimped out?
Yeah. Don't kid yourself.
He's getting pimped
in that video.
Excuse me, but if
Mr. Dollar's not here,
you're going to
have to leave.
We haven't even checked
under the bed yet.
Yeah, and
what's with
all the boxes, clothes?
It's MAGIC.
BRASS:
You know,
for a concierge, you're not
really very helpful.
It's a convention, sir.
MAGIC-- Men's Apparel Guild
In California.
It's the largest fashion show
in the world.
With every rapper,
there's a clothing line.
They all
come to MAGIC
to promote it.
Biggest party in town.
Hmm.
So what kind of car
did he drive?
Um, sir, his vehicle's
still in valet.
There it is right there.
Yeah, is that it?
It's the only one with
22-inch rims; it's got to be.
BRASS:
What's that?
Open this up.
( groaning )
Where we at, man?
You're outside your hotel, sir.
Don't worry, we're gonna
get you out of there
and get you
medical attention.
Man, is you crazy?
Look what I got on.
I got all these
people around here, the press.
Man, let me know when
we get to the hospital, man.
He's got a point.
My prints? The hell
you want my prints for?
I'm the guy that was forced
to wear the bikini, remember?
I was in a trunk.
I was in two trunks.
Three teenagers were killed
on Convention Center Drive.
They were shot down
putting up posters of you.
Man, there's posters
of me all over town.
Got a record coming out.
I know.
I like the album cover.
DOLLAR:
Where'd you get that?
Like you said,
they're all over town.
We need your prints so that
we may exclude you as a suspect.
Yeah, right.
Go ahead, take my prints.
So what's the story
with the video?
Man, I left
the Sean John party, swerving.
Big bubble butt on one hand,
bottle in the other.
Went back to the room
and I passed out
before I could even
get my lay on.
When I woke up,
I had a gun and a video camera
shoved in my face.
Y'all know where that ended up.
Next thing I know, I'm in
my luggage with a fat-ass lip.
BRASS:
What'd the guy
look like?
I don't know.
He had on a mask.
Anyone following you
at the time?
Man, I was so blunted
and liquored up,
I have no idea.
DOLLAR:
Yo.
Listen, man, y'all find out
who did this for me,
like, I'm telling you, like,
I'll take care of you.
I'll give you a whole
new closet full of suits.
Like, whatever you want.
Like, you'll be popping tags
for over a year.
Like, you'll be
the freshest cops
on the street, I swear.
Why would somebody
want to do this to you?
Man, why wouldn't they?
I've been dealing with beef like
this my entire life, you dig?
I bought my first bulletproof
vest when I was 15 years old,
and I wore it to school.
Them putting me
in that bikini, man,
that poster ain't nothing, man.
I'm lucky to be alive.
STOKES:
Okay, look,
why "Dudes Gone Nutz"?
I don't know, man.
I did some guest spots on the
little "Chicks Gone Nutz" video.
You know, the girls
flash their thing things.
Dudes just jealous, man.
I dodge haters for a living.
I got more enemies than
some countries got people.
Give us some names.
It'll be a long list.
Griss, we are not
having any luck
identifying the three
teenagers from CC Drive.
It's been two days,
no one's come forward.
Without an ID, it's like
they never even existed.
We need to get their
faces out in the public--
newspapers, billboards.
Well, maybe
you could breathe
a little bit more
life into them.
Yeah. I'm pretty good
at mouth-to-mouth.
KENDRIC:
Gentra just loved
the hip-hop music.
And it kept her
out on the streets.
She actually wanted to
be a rapper herself.
She did a couple
of talent shows.
Didn't do too well.
So she joined
a street team.
A street team?
Groups of kids who
hit the streets
to promote their
favorite rapper.
It kept Gentra
around what she loved.
Do you know which rapper
she worked for?
Hi-Def.
That's what he
calls himself.
The State of Nevada's
willing to pay
to send your daughter
back to California for burial.
I couldn't afford
to bury my husband.
In that case,
she'll be cremated.
I'll make sure
you get the remains.
You send her ashes to Hi-Def.
♪ Convict ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
( hip-hop music playing )
♪ That's right ♪
♪ Shady ♪
♪ Convict music ♪
♪ Guess who's back ♪
♪ Still here, haters ♪
♪ Akon and Obie ♪
♪ Trice ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ What you gonna
do with it, A ♪
♪ What you gonna do ♪
♪ Take 'em on back
to the street ♪
♪ That's why I keep
the thing on my side ♪
♪ Stepping with the mind state
of a mobster ♪
♪ You see a ... pass by ♪
That's our guy.
CURTIS:
The one with the tats.
That's Hi-Def.
STOKES:
Looks like Dollar's
crew is here, too.
All the rappers
come to MAGIC.
Go ahead, I'll catch up.
♪ 'Cause you will get hit,
pray I don't face you ♪
♪ It's risky, the chick
tend to rise out his temper ♪
♪ His history, snitch,
who decided he's a member ♪
Afternoon.
You must be in
the wrong spot.
This isn't the
security hut.
We need to talk
to Hi-Def.
Can't wait till after the show?
Either you get him
or we will.
♪ Superman drawers,
only phoniness ♪
♪ Never came to par ♪
♪ He had us ♪
♪ A true neighborhood actor ♪
♪ Had his back for days ♪
♪ Now we see through him
like X-rays ♪
What do you cops want from me?
You ever see these kids?
HI-DEF:
Never.
I have. They're from
our street team.
They look kind of weird
in those pictures,
but Ray never smiles.
They're dead.
What?
They've been
gone three days.
You didn't notice?
Don't look at me, ma'am.
I never seen those kids
before ever, sorry.
Look, we've got kids
coming and going all the time.
It's hard to keep up.
I mean, I know who they are;
it's Ray, Marvin and Gentra.
Do you know
their last names?
No, I'm sorry.
Well, do you know
where they got this?
Probably the same place
I got this.
Hey, guys.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
How you doing?
Let me get
one of those for you.
Here you go.
No, thanks, man,
I'm all set.
You know, personally,
I think it's a bad idea
to hit on blackjack.
Well, you know,
that's just how we do.
We never bust.
I know all about Dollar.
What's your
connection?
Are you a cop?
I work with
the police department, yeah.
Crime lab. My
name's Nick Stokes.
Drops. And let's just say
Dollar pays the bills.
The video just showed up
on my desk.
First day
of the show.
It was in a plain
manila envelope.
So you put it on the net.
I never said that,
but things happen.
Did Hi-Def and Dollar
have a beef before this?
Yeah, a couple
of years ago,
Dollar did song
called "New Vegas."
Talking about how Las
Vegas is the new New York.
Hi-Def is New York.
He and Dollar been punking
each other ever since.
What's the deal with
these street teams.
What's going on?
DROPS:
They do all the filthy,
dirty, grimy promo for Dollar.
Snipe posters, give away
stickers, pass CDs around.
Nothing new.
You know, three kids
were murdered
the other night doing
the exact same thing.
What can I say, man?
These kids run the streets, bro.
Anybody at any given time
can run up on them
and try and lullaby their ass.
Yeah, I don't know about that.
They were putting up posters
of your boy Dollar--
ones that made him
look a lot stupider
than just hitting on blackjack,
you know what I mean?
Take a look
at these kids.
See if you recognize
any of them.
Nope.
Show them.
Nice suit.
Glad to see
you dressed
for the occasion.
No.
Eh, sorry, Crime Lab,
Nick Stokes.
Nobody here's got a clue.
Yeah, okay.
Oh, well, what do you know?
There goes one of my birds.
Sorry, got to go.
Peace.
I'll see you
soon, dawg.
Yeah, whatever.
Look, you need any more posters,
just scream at me.
Hey, Tweety!
Tweety!
Hey.
Mandy matched two prints
off the photo
that you gave to Dollar's
street team
to the unknowns that I found
in the low rider.
Mm-hmm.
One was
on the passenger side door,
the other one was
on the steering wheel.
Hey, yo, yo, yo,
make sure you tell him
about that crazy new suit line
we got coming out.
( Drops speaking Japanese )
Now what?
I'm here for Drops.
Hang up.
( whispering )
I'm expanding into Asia.
No kidding?
Where's your
street team?
They're grubbing-- they went
down to the Cafe Hospital.
You know, they're kind of
Benigni over that Waldorf salad.
( chuckling )
They're murder suspects.
Get them up here.
( sighs )
This is very disappointing.
( men speaking indistinctly )
Yo, gentlemen,
on the wall.
I didn't shoot nobody.
Please, you got
to believe me.
I just wanted to
drive that car.
Morris was always
bragging about it.
I'll believe you if you tell me
what really happened.
I was picking up an order
for Drops.
I saw that poster
on the wall.
I just told the other guys
what I saw.
Look, I know I shouldn't
have done that,
'cause as soon as I
did, Morris wanted
to see the poster.
Morris would do anything
for Dollar.
You know, Dollar's his life.
He only has Dollar
in his iPod.
No one else.
So then you went to CC Drive.
Yeah.
We just waited for them
to show up.
Who is "they"?
Some other snippers.
High-def street team.
Morris didn't care
who they were,
as long as they was putting up
them posters,
they was dead to him.
Morris, hurry up, man--
you just said
you were gonna scare them.
Nah, man.
that poster makes Dollar
look like a ho.
Dollar's nobody's ho.
( gunshots continue )
I ran them over.
After he got the first one...
he said he had to get the rest.
( gunshots )
He shot the second one next,
down off the palm tree.
The last one almost got away.
( gunshots )
What was Dante doing
during all of this?
I was just riding shotgun,
watching Morris.
You didn't do
anything about it?
He was out of his mind.
Where did Morris
get the gun?
It was in the trunk.
He said his brother swiped it
off some dumb-ass cop.
Where is it now?
Broken apart and thrown away.
Pro style.
Looks like you
and your buddy
are gonna get broken apart
and thrown away, too.
I guess there's nothing else
to say.
Guess not.
DOLLAR ( over computer ):
This ain't right, dog.
MAN:
Now who's the bitch? Huh?
Who's the bitch now?
( computer beeping )
( beeping continues )
I figure Dante
had that revolver
when he was going up
and down those poles.
Grip gets thumped,
chips off in
the satchel.
Wood grain seems
consistent,
This means Dante
made the video.
You said Dante
works for Dollar.
Mm-hmm.
He's a fan.
Why would he humiliate
someone he respects?
I don't know.
I don't know, but on the video,
Dante did say,
"Who's the bitch now?"
So... you could say it
got a little personal.
So... get personal.
♪ ♪
Yo, what's up, it's your boy
Dollar, from Chicks Gone Nuts.
We're out here in Vegas, baby.
We got whatever you want--
chicks, jewelry.
We got the bottles.
Come holler at us, you know.
( TV clicks off )
Mm.
So you obviously
know Dollar.
You know, your brother
has been arrested
for felony kidnapping
and assault
and accessory
to murder.
Now if there's anything
that you know
that can help us understand
his motivation,
now's the time to tell us, okay?
STOKES:
Tisha...
what happened
to your face?
About a year ago,
during Black Spring Break,
Dollar caught me walking
through the MGM.
He was hosting
this Chicks Gone Nuts video.
Said he'd give me $500
to put on a bikini
and jump on his hotel bed.
I needed the money...
so I did it.
I got my money and went home.
Couple months later,
Dante came busting into my room
with the tape.
He cussed me out,
then forgot about that, too.
Until my dad saw the tape.
He called me a whore
and a slut.
He had his car keys in his hand.
He cut up my face, my chest,
my stomach.
I haven't seen him since.
And Dante
blamed Dollar.
He couldn't find Daddy.
He wouldn't blame me.
STOKES:
So he joins
Dollar's street team
to get close to him,
close enough to sneak
into his hotel room
and videotape him,
the same way he videotaped you.
I know he didn't mean
for anyone to die.
He just did it for me.