You know, first
time I had sex
was in front
of a fire...
on a bear skin rug.
It was so romantic.
( wry laugh )
Gee, and all this time...
I thought you were still
a virgin.
( snickers )
Yeah, right.
You only asked for my number
'cause you heard I was easy.
Oh, you found me out.
I did.
( both laughing )
Cheers.
Oh, my God!
( smoke alarm beeping )
( indistinct background
radio communication )
Alert Homicide and CSI!
♪ ♪
Chimney extends about four feet
from the roofline...
...assuming the vic
was average height...
and didn't curl up...
head should be right about here.
Good!
Okay.
Whew!
Smoldering flesh has the
stench of burnt pork...
except much worse.
I smell a little decomp, but
mostly the fireplace down below.
The body's really positioned
too far to be in that condition.
Which means... the vic was
charbroiled somewhere else,
tossed in the chimney,
and smoked.
♪♪
♪ Who are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who ♪
♪ I really want to know ♪
♪ Who are you? ♪
♪ Oh, come on tell me
who are you, you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you. ♪
( bricks clattering )
STOKES:
Check out that mold.
It's just eating away
at the flesh.
That much mold would
suggest he was burned
at least a few days ago.
He?
I measured
the pelvic bone--
sub-pubic angle's
less than 90 degrees.
He's male.
Any suggestions
on how to proceed?
Wrap and roll.
Great.
Okay, you get the head.
On three...
Yeah.
One, two... three.
Mm! He's lighter
than I expected.
Most of the muscle and
flesh have burned away.
He's pretty well
drained of fluids.
He probably weighed twice
as much when he was alive.
Well, that would explain
how the killer was able
to carry him up to the roof and
then foist him down the chimney.
Yeah.
Get him to the morgue.
I started the fire
and the smoke
just started pouring out.
And it was just the two
of you in the house.
Yeah.
I had just gotten off work;
I came over for a night cap.
So how long have you known
each other?
Mm... a few months.
Do you live alone?
Yeah. Divorced.
Have a son in college.
Did you hear anything up on
the roof in the past week or so?
Well, no, I was out of town
on business till yesterday.
And when was the last time
you used the fireplace?
A few months ago...
around Christmas.
BRASS:
I mean, there was a dead man
in your chimney.
Didn't you notice anything
when you lit the fireplace?
Martin's got a rat problem.
Um... the little suckers
get caught in the traps,
and just stink
for a couple of days.
We smelled something,
but we figured it was...
...a rat.
SIDLE:
Excuse me, Mr. Sidley?
There's a ladder leaning against
the side of the house...?
Yeah, that's mine.
It been there since...
about New Year's, when I took
down the Christmas lights.
I'd like to get a set
of your fingerprints.
I'm going to be dusting
the ladder for prints.
I'd like
to eliminate yours.
Yeah. Sure.
♪ ♪
Crispy on the outside,
tender on the inside?
Crispy though and through.
Based on the melted fibers,
he was probably wearing
a polyester shirt.
Well, synthetics are just
plastic polymers.
They melt instead of burn.
What's that?
Oh, some sort of plastic.
I found it where his shirt
pocket would've been.
I'm thinking maybe
a credit card.
Good, good. I'll work it up;
try to get an I.D.
Catherine...
Yeah.
Do you remember this
Caroline Fitzgibbons case?
About a year ago?
Of course I do, yeah.
Missing person,
we never found her.
BROWN:
Yeah, she was a minor,
allegedly having an affair
with a Mr. Martin...
...Sidley?
Ugh, yeah,
what a creep.
She's an aspiring photographer.
I recently purchased several
of her self-portraits.
Mr. Sidley, her father says
that she was headed over here
the day before yesterday,
and he hasn't heard
from her since.
Would you mind if we come in?
You know,
now's not a good time.
So, unless you have a warrant,
the answer is no.
What are you guys
doing here?
We were hoping that
you'd invite us
to help out with
your investigation.
Invite you?!
Warrick and I were looking for a
missing person about a year ago,
and we tried to get a warrant
to seach this residence.
The owner denied us access.
Now that it's a crime scene,
it's fair game,
if you're part of
the investigation.
You're picking up
what we're putting down.
Well, I've processed
room-to-room,
photo-documented,
sketched the layout...
Feel free to dig
a little deeper.
I'm gonna dust the chimney
for prints.
I'll be on the roof
for awhile.
( scanner beeping,
whirring )
I'll take "Video Spectral
Analysis" for 200, Nick.
Yeah, it's a charred piece
of plastic
found in
Chimney Guy's pocket.
It may be a credit card.
I'm trying to get
some I.D. off of it.
That's a gym membership card.
How do you know that?
The logo in the corner--
it's Burt's Gym--
I belong
to the one on Flamingo.
Oh, yeah?
You, uh... been pumping iron
there, Greg?
Yeah, a little, uh...
Muy Thai.
It's competitive
kickboxing.
Gotta balance weights with
cardio, you know what I mean?
Yeah, okay, thanks.
Anyway, I'll, uh, check it.
Maybe I can get
a membership name.
Oh, you won't.
Member names are
printed in black ink.
VSA only brings out the colors.
( VSA unit beeping )
All right. Maybe it'll help us
clear up the photo.
Nice.
♪ ♪
( camera beeps )
( shutter clicking )
♪ ♪
( camera beeps )
BROWN:
Well, hello, Caroline.
She was, what, like 16?
Isn't it a felony to purchase
pornographic pictures
of a minor?
Well, believe it or not,
exceptions are made
for photographs
with serious
artistic or scientific merit.
Oh, yeah. These look
real scientific.
WILLOWS:
I don't make the rules.
So I found a large, diffuse pool
of fluorescence
here on the wood floor.
It's consistent with bleach
or some other
cleaning compound.
Bleach on a wood floor, huh?
Mm.
I presume
you pheno'ed it?
It was negative for blood.
What are you doing?
BROWN:
I'm looking
for the tiniest crack
between the planks.
You know, you can scrub blood
off a surface,
but you can't scrub beneath it.
Yeah...
( board clatters )
WILLOWS:
We got blood.
( scoffs )
As I told you last year,
I knew Caroline professionally.
We had coffee a couple of times.
She was a promising
photographer;
I'm a collector;
we had a lot to talk about.
WILLOWS:
How many times is
"a couple of times"?
I don't know, five or six times
over a month or two.
Were they dates?
Well, we weren't having
sexual relations,
if that's
what you're getting at.
Was she ever in your house?
Yeah, I invited her over
to see my collection.
Look, I'll admit that
I was attracted to her,
but when she told me
her real age,
I told her,
it was inappropriate
for us to see each other.
How very responsible of you.
And you had that conversation
how many days
before she went missing?
LAWYER:
I'm sorry,
but we're not here
to talk about Caroline,
all right?
So unless you're
on some kind
of cold-case
fishing expedition...
We found an old blood pool
in your living room.
You want to tell me about that?
Don't answer that.
Ms. Willows,
let's get something straight.
You found a body
in the chimney, so you searched
his house for clues,
but you had no legal right
to look for any evidence
unrelated to this case.
We were just working
the scene.
( clears throat )
This piece of wood was
pried from you living room.
The surface was scrubbed
with a cleaning agent,
but we found a spot of blood...
right there.
You mean, you ripped up
my damn floor.
What is going on here?
As soon as this is over,
I intend to file
an emergency motion
to limit the scope
or your warrant.
I also intend
to file a motion
in limine to exclude this
evidence,
which was illegally seized,
in violation of my client's
Fourth Amendment rights.
This house was processed in
accordance with CSI protocol,
but do what you have to do.
You've been coming at me
since day one,
and I'm starting to resent it.
Martin...
You have
a problem with me
because I appreciate
younger women?
I had nothing to do
with that girl's
disappearance.
You want to come after me?
You're going to regret it.
Your client has
a bit of a temper.
Well, if you don't have
any questions
pertaining to the dead
body in his chimney,
we're done here.
Sit down. Please.
Gentlemen,
this is Nick Stokes.
He's a colleague of mine.
We found identification
on the decedent in the chimney.
STOKES:
A gym card.
Actually, it was found
in his pocket.
The crime lab restored
the charred image,
but we couldn't get a name.
We we're hoping you
could help make a positive I.D.
This belonged to the person
in my chimney?
Yes, sir. You recognize him?
Well, this is-this is Tad.
This is my son.
Let me guess:
he burned to death.
I can't confirm C.O.D.
Come on, Doc, this
isn't a hard one.
His bones are fractured;
check out the femur.
It's not uncommon
to find
bone fractures
in fire victims.
The body produces heat,
causing the long bones
to contract and fracture.
Well, that's right,
but check out the chips
in the skull.
Bone chipping is also
a symptom of extreme heat.
ROBBINS:
Very good.
So, if we didn't know better,
fire could be
the cause of death.
What are you getting at?
You see the blood spot
on the interior of the forehead?
Yeah...
As far as I know,
fire can't explain
a subdural hemotoma.
No. No, it can't.
Our victim suffered
blunt force trauma,
prior to going up in flames.
( computer beeping )
♪ ♪
( beeping )
How are you doing
on the prints?
Well, all three prints
from the chimney are
consistent with each other.
I compared them
to the homeowner's prints
and his son's prints;
the work card's
in the system;
there's no a match.
I'm running the print
through I-AFIS.
What about the print
from the chimney cap?
There's not a match
to the chimney prints,
not a match
to either Sidley.
There's no hits on I-AFIS.
I'm sorry.
Not your fault.
( computer beeps )
At least you got
yourself a match
for the chimney prints--
A Jonathan Wax,
from Henderson,
served four years
for attempted rape.
He was released
six months ago.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
MAN:
I served my time.
What do you want with me now?
"Attempted rape."
What exactly happened?
Pepper spray.
That stuff really stings.
Uh, what can you tell me
about, um, Tad Sidley?
Who?
Sorry.
Maybe you remember him
a little more like this?
( chuckles )
Holy mother...
He was murdered, set on fire,
stuffed in a chimney,
and the only prints
on the chimney are yours.
You said the last
name was Sidley?
Uh-huh.
Well, I worked a Sidley place
out near Lake Mead, right?
What were you doing
on the roof?
That's what I do--
Chad's Chimney Sweeps.
I clean fireplaces and chimneys.
I was out at that Sidley
place about a month ago.
You can call Chad.
I remember that place.
Man, that guy had
one big-ass chimney.
I don't suppose you saw a body
while you were there?
Look, I may be an ex-con,
but even I would've dialed
9-1-1.
Catherine.
Excuse me.
I just got a call
from the D.A. about you.
Martin Sidley's attorney
filed a motion to suppress.
Oh, it's just posturing.
There's no way that our search
violated his rights.
Fortunately,
the judge agreed with you.
Good.
But...
we have been warned:
future searches of the residence
are limited to areas
specifically pertaining
to the case at hand.
And I think it's best
if neither you nor Warrick
went back to the house.
Well, hopefully,
we have to.
Hey.
I was able to get in touch
with Caroline's father.
He's on his way
back to his house to pick up
his daughter's toiletries,
and he'll meet us back here.
We're trying to get
a DNA sample
from Caroline's
personal effects
and compare it
to a blood drop
that was on the
living room steps.
Incidentally,
I was able to speak
with someone
at WLVU.
Tad Sidley
was a student there,
with the roommate.
Now, Doc Robbins told me
the kid had been dead
for at least two weeks.
I'd be interested in talking
to the roommate
to find out why no one
reported him missing.
Absolutely.
Come with?
Yeah.
Okay, guys, good luck.
Thank you.
( muffled music playing )
Can I help you?
This is Tad Sidley's
dorm room, right?
Yeah...
Look, whatever he did,
I wasn't involved.
When was the last time
you saw him?
I-I don't know.
A couple weeks ago.
And why didn't you
report him missing?
Look, Tad's
a third-year freshman.
Or as he likes to call it,
"a three-peater."
He disappears for weeks
at a time.
What happened to him?
He was murdered.
May we come in?
Were you and Tad
good friends?
ROOMMATE:
No, not exactly.
Why not?
Look, I study
my ass off.
When Tad's here,
he's baked for breakfast,
lunch and dinner.
He's distracting.
He blares his music.
He invites
his friends over to party.
He is... or was...
inconsiderate.
Fortunately,
he wasn't around much.
Any idea who killed him?
Look, the guy was
a pain in my ass,
but everybody else
seemed to love him.
His dad's
totally loaded,
and Tad was
pretty generous.
Catherine...
Don Fitzgibbons
and a phone number.
Caroline's dad.
What do you know
about this?
I never noticed it.
You mind if I take
it with me?
Go ahead;
take whatever you want.
Look, there's this rumor
going around campus
that if your roommate dies,
you get an automatic 4.0
for the semester.
You know, because
of all
of the
traumatic stress.
Who... who should
I talk to about that?
♪ ♪
Roof trace analysis.
Afraid it's not going
to be very helpful.
Why?
Polyethylene plastic.
Compounds used in about
a million different products.
I hope that's not
all you got.
I don't understand.
If you found blood
in Sidley's house,
why isn't he in jail?
I mean, can't you
at least hold him
until you determine
whether or not it's Caroline's?
That's not my decision
to be made.
Unfortunately, the DA
feels that we need more.
( derisive snort )
It's just like a year ago.
It wasn't enough
that I believed
that Martin was sleeping
with my daughter...
that she disappeared
on the way to his house.
Ms. Willows, the man paid her
$800 for her photos
and told her she had
a great eye.
I brought her brushes
and combs.
Anything else
I could find.
Think you'll be able to get
enough DNA off that stuff?
Oh, yes, absolutely.
I know the cops say
that if you don't find
them quickly,
you don't usually
find them alive.
But every time the phone rings
or there's a knock at the door,
my first thought...
my first hope
is that, uh...
it's Caroline.
Mr. Fitzgibbons, we found
your name and number
written on a Post-it
in Tad Sidley's dorm room.
Can you explain
how it got there?
When you guys were first
investigating her disappearance,
you couldn't get access
to Sidley's place,
so I appealed to his kid.
Okay, look, I may not
like my old man,
but he's not
a killer.
And if you think
he is,
go to the cops.
The cops can't
get a warrant.
I'm not saying
he hurt Caroline,
but maybe there's something
in your house
that will help me find her.
I'm sorry, okay?
I'm sorry.
I can't just...
Look, maybe you could
just talk to him.
Convince him to let me
take a look around the place.
Look, I see my dad
once a month...
when I pick up my check.
He's not going
to listen to me.
All right,
if you change your mind,
give me a call.
Anytime.
Unfortunately,
I never heard from him.
Ms. Willows...
if the blood you found
matches my daughter's DNA,
tell me that the bastard's
going to jail...
for the rest of his life.
So the DNA I extracted
from the hair
on Caroline's brush
is consistent with the blood
found on the wood floor.
Thank you.
Case closed.
Now wait a minute.
We only found a single
drop of blood.
No doubt Sidley's
attorney will argue
that Caroline may
have cut herself.
He already admitted that
she was in his house.
Oh, come on, you saw the amount
of fluorescence on that floor.
You don't use a bucket of bleach
to clean up a paper cut.
Yeah, and you don't get
a murder conviction
off of a single drop
of a victim's blood.
So you need to find the body.
That would certainly help.
CURTIS:
Sorry to interrupt.
As per protocol, Metro flagged
Tad Sidley's credit cards.
A couple of hours ago
someone used
his Amex to purchase gas
in Seven Hills.
Is that someone in custody?
Unfortunately, the Gas and Go
cashier ran the card manually.
So by the time the credit card
company flagged the purchase
the guy had taken off.
But the station has
video surveillance
and the cashier claims
he could ID him.
Have you told Nick and Sara?
Nick's in the AV lab now
with the videotape
and the cashier.
So the next time this someone
uses the credit card...
We're all over it.
You sure you remember
this guy
who stole
Tad Sidley's credit card?
For sure.
It was a platinum
and the guy was like young.
I mean, I couldn't even
qualify for a Visa.
Grissom, meet Larry.
Larry's from
the Gas and Go.
Thanks for
coming in, Larry.
Oh, for sure.
Wait.
Stop... stop the video.
Yeah, I remember
that jacket and the blond hair.
That's his sweet car
right behind him.
Lucky son of a bitch.
I drive an '82 Buick.
Nick, try the unsharp mask.
Yeah, that's it.
That's him.
That's your dude.
That's Tad Sidley.
That was the name
on the credit card.
Is this video from today?
Yeah, I downloaded
it myself.
Well, if that's
Tad Sidley,
who's in the morgue?
Hey. Thanks
for your help.
No problem.
I laid out the photos
and sketches.
Thank you.
What are you looking
for exactly?
When we showed up
at the scene a year ago,
Sidley wouldn't let us
into his house.
I'm guessing because
the body was still inside.
He knew you'd
detect the smell.
Kind of like Telltale Heart.
Edgar Allan Poe.
Guy commits a murder and buries
the body
under the floorboards
of his house.
Catherine, I got to tell you,
I don't see anything probative.
WILLOWS:
Are both these sketches
drawn to the same scale?
Yeah, half inch
equals a foot.
All right...
The attic is above
the living room.
They both share
the same chimney.
SIDLE:
Yeah?
What are you thinking?
The east wall of the house
is 17 feet
from the chimney
in the living room.
But that same east wall
is only 14 feet from
the chimney in the attic.
When you retrieved
the body,
did you excavate
the entire chimney?
No.
We just removed the bricks
from the west-facing side.
( drill motor whirring )
There's no question
that somebody extended
the brick exterior
of this chimney.
There's a slight
color disparity
between the old
and the new bricks.
It's hollow.
There's no clay backing.
This is just a facade.
Catherine...
We found her.
She was still bleeding
when she was brought here.
Which means that her heart
was probably still beating.
This isn't
The Tell-Tale Heart,
it's The Cask of Amontillado.
She was sealed into a wall
and left to die.
( siren wails )
CURTIS:
I just got your page.
Did he stick around?
Yeah, we explained
the situation,
and he thinks
it's hilarious.
( chuckles softly )
Tad, Detective Curtis.
I'm glad to see you're okay.
Yeah, me, too.
Uh, he said you wanted
to talk to me?
Yeah. Where have you been
for the past few weeks?
Tijuana, L.A.,
quick stop in Santa Barbara.
Just got back this morning.
Any idea how your gym membership
got into a dead man's pocket?
( chuckles )
No. I'm sorry,
I didn't even know
it was missing.
I'm-I'm not exactly big
on the weights, you know?
Look, uh...
I'm late for a movie.
You mind if
I get out of here?
Sure.
I'd just like to get
your cell phone number.
Gonna ask me out?
It's just in case I have
any further questions.
ROBBINS:
Caroline did not go gently.
Defensive marks?
Ten on her right forearm.
( screams )
Another three
on the left.
Oh, no! Aah!
And several more
on the palms.
( screaming )
Catherine, there are tears
on her labia and hymen.
Too much time's past
to check for semen.
But she was raped.
We found a potential blood
pool in the living room
and another much more
substantial one
in the attic-- is that
consistent with your findings?
Yeah. Caroline was stabbed
four times,
twice to the abdomen,
one to the spleen,
one to the intercostal artery.
No vital organs
were penetrated,
which means she would have
bled to death slowly.
Probably stabbed
in the living room
and then moved to the attic
where she continued to bleed
until she died.
Is the chimney guy
still in your drawer?
Yeah, right over there.
What's going on?
Tad Sidley is alive.
We assumed that
this guy was Tad,
based on a gym membership
card we found on his body--
we were wrong.
This guy is now a John Doe.
Does his father know?
Not yet.
Well, I'm on my way to P.D.
to meet up
with him and his lawyer--
I'll give him the good news.
McWANE:
Like I've already told you,
Caroline and I
were friends.
Now, if you keep this up,
I'm gonna file a harassment
charge against you, personally.
Ms. Willows, on the phone
you said that you had
new information
regarding my client's son?
Yes, I will
get to that.
But first I wanted to
let both of you know
that Caroline's body was
recovered in Mr. Sidley's attic.
What?
The coroner confirmed
that she was raped,
stabbed and bled to death.
McWANE:
Wait a minute.
You searched
the house again?
Ms. Willows,
I thought that
the judge was
perfectly clear.
I searched the chimney,
specifically,
in accordance with
the original warrant
and subsequent limitation.
I didn't do it, I swear,
You live alone,
Mr. Sidley...
and you have no idea
how her body got bricked
into your attic?
( quietly ):
Oh, come on.
What happened?
Did she say no
one too many times?
Ms. Willows, you are
way over the line.
If you didn't kill her,
Mr. Sidley, then tell me,
is there anyone else
who had access to your house?
Who else could have
raped Caroline under your roof?
I know what happened.
Martin...
No.
I've been covering too long.
I need to tell the truth.
I was out of town,
I came home early.
I heard noise
coming from the attic.
He told me that they'd
been seeing each other...
What's going on?
Dad...
...that they'd gotten
into a fight,
and he raped and killed her.
I should have told
the police, but...
she was already dead.
He's my son.
I wanted to
protect him.
( quietly ):
Son of a bitch.
( chuckles, sniffles )
( exhales )
He's lying.
Do you want to tell us
what actually happened?
I have no idea
what really happened.
I met her once... at the house.
A month or so later,
I see her on the news--
she's missing.
I can tell you that
for two weeks after that,
he wouldn't let me
anywhere near the house.
Claimed that he was painting,
and he didn't want me
breathing in the fumes.
He killed her.
I'm sure of it.
Well, if you'd like to have
a word with your old man,
I'd say now would be the time.
Hi, Dad.
Heard everything.
Tad...
Son, you're...
Yeah. I'm not dead.
You're dead to me.
( phone rings )
This is Catherine.
Hey, Cat,
when you're done at P.D.
can you head over
to the print lab?
There's something
you're gonna want to see.
I'm on my way.
Hi.
I know why a John Doe
was stuffed down
the Sidley's chimney.
When you and Warrick
were working that
missing persons case,
you couldn't get a warrant,
and Martin wouldn't
let you in, right?
Right.
Don Fitzgibbons tried
to gain access
to the house
through the son...
But the son
wouldn't cooperate.
I think he knew
that if the house
became a crime scene,
CSI could get in there.
Well, it's a logical theory,
but to kill someone and
stuff him in a chimney
in hopes of getting information
on your missing daughter...
( typing )
Check out the screen.
On the left is
an unknown fingerprint
I lifted off the chimney cap.
On the right is a partial
I lifted off of Don Fitzgibbons'
post-it you took
out of Tad's dorm room.
Now, the print on the post-it
is only a partial,
but it's a match
to the chimney cap.
I also found trace evidence
on the roof.
Polyethylene plastic.
Don Fitzgibbons works
at Desert Palms Hospital.
I just got off the phone
with the administrator.
The hospital's body bags
are made out of...
Polyethylene plastic?
Don Fitzgibbons has access
to those body bags.
It's true.
All of it.
You gonna arrest me?
You just admitted to murder;
I think you know the answer.
Hold on.
I didn't kill anyone.
And the body in the chimney?
( sighs )
I took the body
from Desert Palm Hospital,
from the morgue.
He was already dead,
John Doe.
Auto accident
in a stolen vehicle.
Car exploded, he was burned
beyond recognition.
Ms. Willows, I stole a dead body
and I trespassed,
but that's it.
And Tad Sidley's I.D.,
did you place the gym card
on the body?
You're a mother, right?
Yes.
Why do you think I did it?
You wanted Martin Sidley to know
what it's like to lose a child.
( sniffles )
When I was in Tad's dorm room,
I snagged it.
I scorched
the surface of the car
to make it look like
it belonged to the John Doe...
to make Martin believe
that it was his son.
I'd hoped that you'd be able
to restore the image.
( sniffles ):
Look...
I wish I could say
that I was sorry
for the trouble
I've put you through,
or the-the petty crimes
that I've committed,
but I didn't hurt anyone...
and Martin Sidley
is behind bars,
and my daughter's
getting her funeral.
And that's all I wanted.
( sighs )
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry that we
couldn't find your daughter
without your help.