( dog barking )
( barking continues )
Tucker's barking.
Probably
another coyote.
( barking stops, creaking )
( clattering )
WOMAN:
What are you doing?
Call the police.
( whispers ):
Do it!
( rustling )
Freeze!
I said freeze!
I'm not afraid to use this.
Nobody move.
Oh, my God.
PHILLIPS:
No wallet, no I.D.
( beeps )
80.6 degrees.
He's been dead around 12 hours.
Broken nose, broken cheekbone.
Somebody worked him over
pretty good.
There's a piece of his shirt
that's missing.
That doesn't look like
a tear from a struggle.
It looks like it got
snagged on something.
( camera shutter clicks )
There's heavy foot traffic
but no blood.
It's got to be a body dump.
Could be.
But why here?
Dispatch didn't say
anything about another body.
It's Tucker, their dog.
He was found dead
with his tongue hanging out.
I don't know,
I guess they must've
slipped it something.
We'll get its blood to Tox.
The homeowner said
that nothing was missing
in the house but food.
They get a look
at the intruders?
Yeah, the husband says
they were dirty,
you know, like filthy,
like they hadn't showered
in months.
Didn't know if there were five
or 50 of them.
Where is he?
( crickets chirping )
The Orionid
meteor shower.
You never get a view
like this in town.
Hm. So, uh, is this part
of the investigation?
No. But we're here,
and it's beautiful.
Footprints
going in both directions.
They came and they went.
So dump the body,
raid the refrigerator.
Maybe they had
an appetite for murder.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
( indistinct radio
transmissions )
Well, it's no secret
how they got in.
( chuckles ):
Whoa.
Looks like somebody
had a Super Bowl party in here.
They had some
kind of party.
Suspect made a mess.
Seems like they were looking
for junk food.
Somebody had sticky fingers.
( grunts )
It's a big desert.
About 25,000 square miles.
And the nearest
town is Pahrump.
That's about 30
miles from here.
But I got water.
We can share.
Who are you today, Moses?
Yeah, Jim, uh...
( chuckles softly )
Grissom and I are going
to take a little walk.
Hey, Doc.
Hi, there, Nick.
I've lost count as to
how many broken bones
this guy has.
Multiple fractures
to the spine, ribs,
pelvis, skull.
Multiple lacerations
and contusions.
No vital response
to the injuries.
Perimortem.
Yep.
He was dumped in a backyard
by a whole bunch
of other people.
Do you think they could've
beat him to death?
Nick, it took a lot of people
to do this.
( camera shutter clicking )
♪ ♪
Dirty dozen.
GRISSOM:
I count five distinct treads:
boots,
shoes, sneakers.
Drag marks are always
right in the middle--
thin, parallel lines.
The vic's shoes were
scuffed at the toes
so he must've been dragged.
Well, whoever they are,
they like junk food.
Who doesn't?
You ever seen
the pyramids?
Does the Luxor count?
Eh, what do you think?
I haven't even been to New York.
I'd like to see the pyramids
one day.
Keep walking,
we could come upon them today.
So you like archeology, huh?
Oh, yeah.
Whenever I want to feel small.
GRISSOM:
Smoke?
I found the point of ignition.
Molotov.
( explosion )
( distant machine humming )
You hear that?
Sounds like a motor.
Think someone's in there?
( humming continues )
This looks like
some sort of observation post.
Maybe used to monitor
nuclear tests.
Half of Nevada
was a weapon site.
Stop.
You're not going any further
without backup.
BRASS:
Catherine,
where the hell are you guys?
That's a good question, Jim.
I think we're about
three miles northeast
of the Copeland house.
In front of some kind
of military installation.
Hello, Catherine.
Jim, can you hear me?
I'm losing...
You're breaking up. Jim?
( radio static )
Lost him.
Well, we got two choices:
Go back...
or go forward.
( door clanks and creaks )
( generator humming )
I don't hear anything
but the generator.
After you.
Las Vegas Crime Lab!
Anyone here?
( water dripping )
I count 11.
Me, too.
WILLOWS:
They're so young.
And number 12 is missing.
GRISSOM:
Maybe that was the guy
we found in the yard.
( slamming )
Who's there?!
Las Vegas Crime Lab!
Identify yourself!
Don't shoot, don't shoot.
LVPD.
Captain Brass radio'd us.
Said you might be in here
and need assistance.
Well, unfortunately, we're not
the ones who need the help.
♪ ♪
( camera clicking )
Hey!
Hey, Nick.
How many we looking at, Doc?
11 total.
And it's hot.
You got to move.
Okay.
MAN:
Yeah, 80 feet underground,
no A/C.
Thought I was going
to suffocate.
MAN 2:
I can't even get
down there. Claustrophobic.
♪ ♪
Just keep on going.
( camera clicking )
Oh, man.
What is this place,
a mini Jonestown?
I don't know if they
drank spiked Kool-Aid,
but they drank
something.
Smells like alcohol.
I'll process
the bottles.
♪ ♪
( clicks button )
( musical choir of voices
playing )
♪ ♪
Well, I've
matched the shoes
from all the bodies
in the bunker
to the impressions that
we found at the scene.
SIDLE:
You got one extra.
It's a size eight
athletic shoe.
I can't account
for it.
It doesn't belong to the guy
who was dumped there,
and I've already ruled out
Mr. and Mrs. Copeland.
So one of the people
that dragged that body
through the desert
did not die in the bunker.
The mythology here
appears to be similar
to the Heaven's Gate cult
in California
several years ago.
They committed
mass suicide to shed
their earthly bodies
and hitch a ride
on a spaceship hidden in
the tail of the Hale-Bopp Comet.
Well, these earthly bodies got
a good workout first.
Big room, big
bed, light show.
This cult
was about getting laid.
Jim Jones
and Charles Manson
used sex to manipulate
their followers.
I'm guessing
they were timing
their ascension to the Orionid
meteor shower last night?
So while you were watching
shooting stars, they were dying.
There's 12 bunks in there,
one bed in here.
There should be 13 bodies.
One prophet,
12 apostles.
And two people are missing.
Maybe they caught the spaceship.
Well...
would you settle
for a flying saucer?
♪ ♪
( screaming )
VIN plate on the burned-out car
came back
to a Vivian Bentley.
She died two years ago
at the ripe old age of 90.
Car was never
re-registered.
Dead end.
Not exactly.
I also found a melted name tag
with a sunburst logo.
Figured I'd let my fingers
do the walking.
You scanned the
Yellow Pages.
I knew the first
three letters.
By the way, do you know
how many companies
in Las Vegas
start with S-U-N?
I so don't care.
Well, only one has
the sunburst logo:
Sunview Travel Agency.
Vivian's grandson,
Ty Bentley, works there.
I pulled his DMV photo.
That's the guy that was
dumped at the house.
Brass is going
to check it out.
How are we doing
on the other I.D.s?
Including the one that
you just made, we got one.
Ty hasn't been here
for the last two days.
Didn't even call in.
This is his desk.
It's really not like him.
Is he okay?
Ty work here full time?
Yeah. Puts in more hours
than anybody.
Was he a member of any
religious organizations
that you know of?
I don't know.
It never really came up.
Something happened to him,
didn't it?
Yeah.
So the last time you saw
him was two days ago?
He's worked here over a year,
never raised his voice.
Then this strange looking
customer came in.
Ty must've known him...
I want to talk to
Emma, you freak!
She's moving on, boy.
Would that customer's
information
still be in
the computer?
Nobody's touched it since.
Should be the
last entry.
Do you know the
person in this photo?
That's Emma,
Ty's girlfriend.
Well, ex-girlfriend.
They broke up last year.
Here we go.
Last customer was
a Joseph Diamond.
Booking a trip to
Australia. Sydney.
One way.
( snickers ):
Any good news, Mandy?
A little bit.
A male d.b. at the bunker
matched your partial
from the kitchen door.
So far, he's the only one
with a record.
Matthew Dickens, 19.
Busts for petty theft.
College student.
Yeah, very impressionable.
When I start my religion,
that's where
I'm going to recruit.
MAN:
I remember him. Matt Dickens.
We used to call him Hollywood.
He was in our, uh,
our freshman dorm.
He was a...
Religious
studies major.
Right.
Hard core Trekkie, too.
( chuckles ):
Mars bars.
Right.
That dude loved
junk food.
He smoked a ton of weed.
Guy was a loser.
What do you mean?
His parents sent him
loads of cash.
He spent it all on dope,
and then he stole stuff
to get more dope.
According to the registrar,
he was taking classes
till the end of term
last fall.
Why did he leave?
He started
hanging out
with some other losers,
and they convinced
him to drop out.
Yeah, there was a redhead.
She was hot,
but in a... in a
weird kind of way.
Hollywood was a moron.
One week, the guy's
saving the whales,
and the next week,
he's American Taliban.
Yeah. He was totally
into that girl.
She have a name?
Emma.
Was this her?
Is she dead?
They're all dead.
Emma was working Hollywood
with some old guy named Diamond.
Working him?
Yeah, they
were running
some kind of
religious scam.
Emma tried to recruit me...
with her hands down my pants.
She did that to me, too.
No kidding?
Yeah.
Anyway, uh,
the second she
started talking
about outer space
and transcendence,
I blew her off, 'cause
I do not waste time
on crazy chicks.
She was really hot,
though.
That was almost
a year ago.
Then the last time
I saw Hollywood,
he was with some other freak.
A notch down, though. Abbey...
I think her name was.
They said they were going
to some better place.
I thought they meant UCLA.
( both chuckle )
Nick, I have a real low signal,
you're cutting in and out.
Say that again.
STOKES:
I said
all the prints on the bottles
belong to the victims.
The prints on the funnel
came back unknown though.
And what about the blood
in the elevator shaft?
It matched to Ty Bentley,
but we can't confirm
he was murdered.
For all we know,
he fell down that shaft.
No, that's unlikely,
after all they torched his car,
dragged his body three miles
and dumped it
in the Copelands' backyard.
Anything on the liquid
in the bottles?
STOKES:
Yeah, Tox results
just came back:
40 grams percent ethanol.
Now, that's about 80 proof.
Kind of smelled like vodka,
the cheap stuff.
Nobody dies from a martini.
No,
but you add ten grams percent
of Ketamine and they do.
Well, that's enough
to kill a horse.
Yeah, or the Copelands' dog
for that matter.
Ketamine's a disassociative
anesthetic
which means
they were hallucinating,
having out-of-body
experiences...
So I was wrong,
they did take a trip.
Well, there are
a lot of different ways
they could have killed
themselves,
so I'm guessing
that was the point.
Ten percent grams of Ketamine
times 12 bottles,
that's 300 milliliters
of Ketamine?
Can't score that on the street.
Well, we didn't find
any ephedrine,
which is generally used
to cut Ketamine.
Veterinarians use
liquid injectable Ketamine
as an animal sedative,
so Sophia's checking
with the local vets now.
What did autopsy say
time of death was?
3:15 a.m.?
Between 3:00 and 3:30.
How did you know that?
That's when
the Orionid meteor shower
passed over Vegas.
Ask him if they all died
about the same time.
Nick, was TOD
same for everyone?
Approximately.
It varied with body weight.
Took between 12 and 20 minutes
for them to die.
Ketamine's really
hard on the stomach,
it induces vomiting.
I think a combination
of alcohol and the drug
just slowed their lungs.
Ultimately, they died
of respiratory arrest.
WILLOWS:
Okay, thanks, Nicki.
Got to go.
Did you notice
those buzzards earlier?
GRISSOM:
No.
But something sure
smells good to them.
Say "ah."
Ah.
Ahh...
Sore throat, you say?
Okay, I don't see
any inflammation.
Take off your shirt, please.
Can't we just make out?
I'm working, Mr. Brown.
I don't care, Mrs. Brown.
There's nothing wrong with you.
You're just working too hard.
What time you get off shift?
Midnight. You?
Who knows.
I got to get back to work.
WOMAN ( over loudspeaker):
Dr. Curry, please check
with the message center.
Don't even say it, Warrick.
I didn't say anything.
You got to admit though,
working around the ex is
a little strange.
It was a long time ago.
It was a year ago.
You have to trust me.
I do trust you.
Look, there's still so much
that we don't know
about each other yet.
Okay?
But we've got the rest
of our lives to figure it out.
GRISSOM:
Are you having the same mirage
I'm having?
A silver Beemer in the middle
of the damn desert?
Yeah.
Nice wheels.
Somebody sure went out of
their way to hide this car.
Well, you can sure smell
what the buzzards are after.
Decomp.
WILLOWS:
Fits the description
of the leader, Joseph Diamond.
Guess he never made it
to Australia.
Something tells me
this wasn't a suicide.
Like this tire iron.
Convenient weapon of choice.
Well, assuming this is Diamond
and Ty Bentley was
a spurned lover
and not a member
of the cult...
we're still short one body.
Which I believe makes that body
our number one suspect.
( machine beeps )
( whirring )
WOMAN:
"Thank you for writing, your
father and I miss you so
much."
MAN:
"Money's kind of tight,
I hope this helps.
Send more when I can."
WOMAN:
"Mom and Dad went to the police
to report you missing.
Please come home,
even if it's just a visit."
MAN:
"I don't understand what
you're doing with your life.
Your roommate says
you left your things behind."
MAN 2:
"I wish you could tell me
why you need this money."
MAN 3:
"Mom says you joined a commune.
"She's mad.
"Hey, Dad sent the money.
When you talk to Mom..."
WOMAN:
"No more money until
I hear from you.
I love you."
BRASS:
The FBI keeps tabs
on high-risk groups,
cults,
religious fanatics.
They were good enough
to fax this over.
Makes good reading.
"Joseph Diamond,
a.k.a. Sirus Bent,
a.k.a. Kelvin Adams..."
Yeah, he founded a group called
"Soul Salvation"
in Tulsa in the mid-90s.
A few years later,
same thing in
Guadalajara, Mexico.
"Recruited susceptible youths,
keeping them isolated
for nine months to a year."
Yeah, prior to the arrival
of the mother ship,
which they can only enter
in spirit form,
leaving their temporal vehicles,
their bodies,
behind.
Mass suicide.
Attempted mass suicide.
They woke up--
probably with a hangover--
and both Diamond
and their money were gone.
And in both cases,
his disappearance coincided
with a meteor shower
just like the one last night.
Only last night everybody died.
ROBBINS:
Depressed fracture.
Well, we found a tire iron
at the scene.
That would do it.
What about TOD?
Well, it's hard to say.
Desert heat,
locked in a trunk...
Both can make liver temp
actually rise.
What about relative
to the other bodies?
Did he die before
or after the others?
ROBBINS:
Given the degree
of decomp,
it appears that he died
before the others.
I can run some chemical tests,
but that's going to take
some time.
PHILLIPS:
What's this?
Hmm, looks like a money belt.
Gives new meaning
to "strapped for cash."
Diamond was running
a cash business.
He had all those kids
write home and ask for money.
His return address was
a P.O. box that I found.
I didn't find
any undigested pills
in the victims'
stomachs.
BROWN:
We assumed that
they were ingesting
a liquid Ketamine.
So what are these?
MAN:
Zolpidem.
Popped one
when I went to Europe.
Six hours sleep,
no hangover.
Are there enough pills
in that bag to kill 11 people?
Well, if only one person
downed all these,
yes, it'd be lethal.
But divvied up, no way.
Zolpidem's a pretty safe
sedative.
And from what we know,
Diamond was a con man,
not a murderer.
SANDERS:
Hey, I lifted a partial
off that tire iron.
Matched it to a print
that Nick lifted off
the funnel from the bunker.
Whoever whacked Diamond mixed
the Ketamine cocktail.
So who brought the Ketamine
to the party?
( barking )
They had a break-in
the day before yesterday.
Has it been forensicated?
Not yet.
Not much stolen, so...
It's a low
priority for CSI.
Expensive equipment,
pharmaceuticals--
doctor even had
his laptop open
on the desk.
They obviously knew
what they wanted
Hmm, and where
to look for it.
Drugs have been
alphabetized.
Missing drug was
between Ivermectin
Otic Suspension
and Methocarbamol.
"K" for Ketamine.
Yeah. They took it all.
Okay, well, it's
probably an inside job.
Just get me a list
of current and former
employees, and we'll...
go from there. Thanks.
Wow, it's alphabetized.
Now what are you doing?
You'll be dusting for prints.
I'll help.
Okay.
That's Emma.
That's our daughter.
( sobbing )
Excuse me, sir.
Mrs. Spencer
isn't here.
Her daughter went to
college with Emma.
They disappeared
at the same time.
Uh, we both
received letters
from them last month.
Spencer, you said?
Her daughter's
name was Abigail.
Well, ma'am, you see,
the letters that we recovered
were damaged.
Not all of them yielded a name.
Well, perhaps she was luckier
than me.
Ma'am...
would you be able
to identify Abigail?
Absolutely.
Nick, you have that employee
list from the vet's office?
The prints found
at the clinic break-in
are a perfect match
to the ones lifted
off the tire iron
and the funnel.
Abigail Spencer.
She was a cult member.
She used to work for your vet
until last year,
and she's missing.
Her W-2's in the file.
I'll call Brass.
( knocking at door )
BRASS:
Mrs. Spencer?
Yeah?
I'm Detective Jim
Brass, Las Vegas Police.
Do you have a daughter
named Abigail?
Yes. Why?
We have a warrant to
search these premises.
A warrant? What for?
Your daughter
is wanted
for questioning
in the murder
of Joseph Diamond.
I haven't seen Abigail
in almost a year.
I have no idea
where she is.
The bed's still warm.
Where is she?
( panting )
( chokes )
( coughing )
Take me with you.
( rumbling )
( helicopter blades whirring)
MAN ( over helicopter speaker):
Freeze! Remain where you are.
Abigail?
You pumped my stomach?
Yeah. Just in time.
Are you disappointed?
They're all up
there right now.
In rapture.
A higher plane
of existence.
No wars, poverty,
politics.
Our bodies are
just shells.
They're worthless.
Well, how come you didn't die
with your friends?
And why exactly
did you kill Mr. Diamond?
He was the most beautiful person
I ever met.
( Mr. Diamond telling stories,
overlapping each other )
We found your fingerprint
on a tire iron
that was used
to split his head open.
He always said we'd be tested.
I was taking a walk
when I spotted a car
parking about a mile away
from the compound.
Whose car is this?
Where have you been?
I received a message last night
from the Orionid.
I have to move on,
spread the word.
What about us?
Come with me, Abbey.
We'll do it together...
somewhere near a beach.
We're ascending tomorrow night
to the mother ship.
You're a smart girl.
Just two or three of these,
and everyone will get
a real good night's sleep.
Time to get
out of town.
Everyone's parents have
been really good to me.
I got 40 grand.
I knew the others
would be looking to me now.
But you didn't tell them,
did you?
We were on a schedule.
And fortunately, you knew
where to find something
a little stronger
than Zolpidem?
It was important
that no one suffered.
Ty Bentley suffered.
That was unfortunate.
Ty must've followed Diamond
back to our compound.
I'm sure he was looking
for his ex-girlfriend, Emma.
These people are freaks, Emma!
You're coming with me!
This is my family now.
Fine. I'm coming back, and I'm
bringing the cops with me.
( screaming )
Emma lost it,
said we couldn't
leave his body there.
The others started
to get restless.
And as you said,
you were on a schedule.
The peak of the meteor shower
was 3:00 a.m.
We agreed to dump the body
where it would be found...
given a decent burial.
And then you went back
to the compound...
and you used the funnel
to distribute the Ketamine
and vodka.
I had to be the last to drink.
Did you watch them all die?
What was it like?
( coughs )
They just died.
And you went home
to your mother.
I know they're all up there...
happy... healthy... perfect.
You don't believe we're alone
in the universe?
Abigail...
I'm sure if there is something
out there
looking down on us
from somewhere else
in the universe,
they're wise enough
to stay away from us.