( big band music plays )
♪ ♪
Good evening, Mr. Braun.
Go right in.
♪ ♪
( gun cocks )
( laughing )
Woo!
I haven't been this
out of breath
since I bet Frank Sinatra
I wasn't ticklish.
( laughter )
In a few minutes, there'll be
cake and champagne,
so stick around;
the party's not over yet.
( laughter and applause )
You've got eight minutes
to change.
I'll come help you.
No, no, no. I'm fine.
Go get the cake ready.
And, Eve...
light the candles.
Oh... hi.
Oh, hey, happy birthday.
Um, I got to go soon...
I got to go do my show.
So...
For years,
I did two shows a night,
partied with the boys for hours,
got a little sleep,
played some tennis,
gave interviews,
got on stage
and did it all over again.
That's talent.
You've got a look.
Pace yourself, honey.
BRASS:
Lois O'Neill's bedroom...
the stuff dreams
are made of.
Or nightmares.
Did, uh, Miss O'Neill
tell you about this guy?
BRASS:
We don't know
where she is.
She disappeared
about an hour ago.
Her assistant went looking
for her, found the victim.
ID'd him as Tim Duke.
Gun left on the body...
isn't that how the mob
used to do it?
Well, back in the day,
Lois O'Neill was famous
for singing and dancing.
She was also famous
for being the girlfriend
of Tony Constantine...
One of the founding fathers
of Vegas.
Looks like a bank vault.
Well, the founding
father has placed
a high priority
on home security.
Have we been in there yet?
No, it hasn't
been cleared yet.
I'll go get the combination.
SANDERS:
Ricochet marks.
( shutter clicks )
Possible bullet fragments.
Bullets here, body there...
Moving target, maybe.
Gentlemen, this
is Eve Girard,
Miss O'Neill's
assistant.
Would you open
the vault, please?
I'll be downstairs.
( lock clicks )
Thank you.
( whimpering )
Just get it over with.
GIRARD:
Lois!
Oh, my God!
Oh...
I thought this was
my last birthday.
♪ Who... are you?
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
In the middle of the party,
you went upstairs to change.
Isn't that unusual?
( laughs ):
No, I...
I always wear one outfit
to greet guests,
another for dinner and dancing,
and another
for dessert.
Thanks.
So, uh, Tim Duke,
the waiter... did you
know him before this?
He worked the Children's
Hospital dance a few weeks ago.
He was charming.
I thought he could use the job.
Right.
I was changing.
I'd ordered a drink brought up.
( gunshot )
( grunts )
( groaning )
He was crawling,
trying to get away.
( bullets ricochet )
And then I heard another shot.
( imitates gunshot )
( sniffles and cries )
That's, uh...
That's when I knew
it was a mob hit.
Look, if you
find his family,
I'd like to do
something for them.
I mean, after all, if he hadn't
come in just then, I'd be dead.
Who'd want to kill you?
Do you have
a first name, Sanders?
Greg.
Greg...
Do you...?
Thank you.
Hot off the press.
I didn't hold back.
I named names.
After all this time, I thought,
who'd care?
Well, maybe you thought wrong.
( camera shutter clicks )
Based on liver temp,
been dead one to two hours.
It looks like two shots--
one to the chest,
and a through-and-through
to the head.
SIDLE:
Not a lot of blood.
Shot to the heart: sometimes it
collects in the chest cavity
rather than bleeding out.
A thousand...
When I was a waiter
back in college,
if I had three twenties in my
pocket, it was a good night.
At Chuck E. Cheese,
that was a good week.
Crack vial?
Could explain the cash;
maybe he was dealing.
And these...
( sizzles )
Found a crack vial
on him,
and $1,000 in cash.
WILLOWS:
Presidents, movie stars...
A drug-dealing waiter
isn't the kind of guy
usually associated
with Lois O'Neill.
On the other hand...
Tony Constantine.
( chuckles )
What?
WILLOWS:
The Copa Girls from the Sands.
That's Lois O'Neill.
That's my mother.
"Happy Birthday
to my Beautiful Doll!
"Love always, Tony"?
I thought he was dead.
Dead, like Jimmy Hoffa.
The only guys who know
aren't telling.
STOKES:
This party is organized
like an invasion plan.
"6:15: bar set up
and ready.
"6:25: Lois greets
guests in foyer.
"7:15: Lois changes
into her dinner outfit."
Talk about attention
to detail.
From the security cameras on
the perimeter of the building.
What about
the interior cameras?
With all
the extra measures,
Lois felt
they weren't necessary.
Frankly, I think
she just didn't want
to be caught on tape
first thing in the morning.
Hmm, I'll need a list
of all the guests
who were here tonight.
Guests and staff,
their affiliations
and recent accomplishments...
Lois likes to personalize
conversation.
Everyone's still here.
You're thorough.
Well, that's my job.
♪ ♪
Grissom, do you have any
idea who's in this crowd?
I sure do.
"Under-sheriff
Jeff McKeen.
"Arrival: 6:38 PM.
Wife: Amanda.
"Recent accomplishment:
"ran marathon
for Children's Hospital,
placed tenth
in his age group."
Good job, Jeff.
More than one
of these VIPs
has the governor's
home number,
which is why
my phone's been ringing
with orders
to let them go.
Well, no one on this list
came late or left early,
so everyone here is still
a suspect, until they're not.
STOKES:
And based on our
interviews so far,
only a few people actually
left the room
when Lois O'Neill was gone.
Who?
Among others, her... a pop
star known as Li'l Cherry.
She was due onstage
at Mandalay Bay
half an hour ago.
Keep her and anyone else
who left the room.
Let the rest go.
Found this handkerchief
hanging off the balcony.
I'll get it to Hodges.
Good.
By the way... Sam's here.
He's one of the guests
who was out of the room
when the murder occurred.
Well, I should say hi
to dear old Dad.
Hi, Sam.
Mugs.
Sam, when you left this room
tonight, where did you go?
Upstairs?
Just walked around downstairs,
saying hello to the old ghosts.
You know, I introduced
Lois and Tony,
back when I was
a floor manager.
She was in the line
with your mother.
Mm.
Maybe Mom fell for
the wrong gangster.
Lily was a sweet girl.
But Lois...
she had to be a star.
A real coal miner's daughter
from Frackville, Pennsylvania.
But once she met Tony,
she never had to go back.
You always were a sucker for
a hot dancer, weren't you, Sam?
Me and Lois-- I love her,
but I like to be in
the driver's seat.
Like this dancer
I'm seeing now--
she's working tonight;
that's why I came stag.
Must be serious.
That's the first time
you haven't asked me
how Mom's doing.
She's fine, by the way.
Mr. Jensen.
I'm Nick Stokes.
I'm with the crime lab.
I'm familiar with
your daughter's case.
Sorry for your loss.
You knew Mr. Constantine, right?
Were there any
other friends
of Mr. Constantine
here tonight?
Yeah, there were
friends here.
And enemies.
You want to elaborate a little
bit more on those enemies?
Stokes, you trying to get me
in trouble?
Hey, man, I'm just trying
to get to the bottom
of what happened here
tonight.
Several witnesses said they saw
you leave the room. Alone.
I went outside to have a
cigarette-- told her I wouldn't
smoke in the house.
Filthy habit.
Trying to quit.
Mm.
Frickin' cops won't
let me go.
Yeah.
Miss Cherry?
Bye-bye.
I'm with the crime lab.
I need to ask you
a few questions.
( scoffs )
( keypad beeping )
CHERRY:
Hey, it's me. Are they
freaking out backstage?
What the...?
Excuse me...
Please?
Where did you go
when Miss O'Neill
left the ballroom
earlier this evening?
Uh, the bathroom.
Do you recall what time
you came back?
What, do you punch a clock
every time you take a leak?
Did you know the victim--
Tim Duke?
I don't know
anybody, okay?
My publicist made me
come to this thing.
I guess Lo-Lo needed
somebody with a pulse, so...
May I take a look
at your handbag?
I got a show to do.
I've got 2,000 people waiting
for me right now.
We can get a warrant,
but you'll get out of here
faster if you
let me see the bag.
Get your hands
off of her!
Well... now I don't need
a warrant.
I don't know how that crack
pipe got in my purse, so...
There. My client denies
the pipe is hers,
denies any drug use,
doesn't know the victim
and has no prior relationship
to Miss O'Neill.
There's nothing to discuss.
The pipe was in your possession.
Plus, you were displaying
symptoms of crack use publicly.
CURTIS:
And you were at a recent party
where the victim, who
also used crack,
was working.
You admitted to leaving the
ballroom after Miss O'Neill...
Coincidences don't make
a homicide.
You recognized Tim Duke
and you needed a fix.
Come on...
I don't got it.
I told you before.
Come on, man.
Look...
Here, man. See?
What are you gonna give me?
Hey!
Oh! Really!
You wiped down the gun
with a handkerchief...
No one has established
that my client had a gun.
And you didn't want to be seen
leaving the bedroom,
so you climbed down the balcony
to rejoin the party.
Which is how
you scraped your knees.
( laughing )
Okay, I'll admit I was outside.
But...
It's in your best interests
not to...
It's cool. Um...
It wasn't just, uh,
Lois's birthday tonight,
it was also my bodyguard's
birthday,
and I scraped my knees
giving him his present.
CURTIS:
You're going to need to cancel
your shows for awhile.
We're holding you on possession
of paraphernalia,
and unlawful use.
What do I have to do
to make you believe me?
I already had my birthday.
ROBBINS:
All right, areas
of callus here.
Old fractures...
ribs...
This guy must've worked
some pretty rough shifts.
That must be the
bullet, right there.
Yeah, I'll yank it
in autopsy.
What's that happening all around
the nose area?
ROBBINS:
It's a nose cage.
Nose has been wired to the
skull to hold it in place.
We find them sometimes
in boxers, accident victims...
You ever see one on a waiter?
Wow! You know, Lois had
her first sexual experience
on her ninth-grade field trip
to the state capitol...
with the governor.
I found the bullet hole.
Could you bring
the Sawzall?
Well, you know, this place is
a piece of Las Vegas history;
you don't want to just go
and chop it up.
It's a crime scene, and there's
evidence under the floor.
Yeah, but we don't know exactly
where it is, so...
...I thought
we'd let "Hawkeye" here
do a little exploration for us.
Sure.
I wouldn't want to damage
priceless, 40-year-old
carpeting.
No.
( machine whirring )
What's that say?
Pull it up.
Ten grand brick.
Benjamin bit the bullet.
"In God We Trust."
If she has a vault, why is she
keeping cash under the floor?
No more room under the mattress?
Easy access in case
you need to rewire.
Or steal a million.
Hey.
Mandy got an AFIS hit
off the vic.
His aka is Tim Duke, but his
real name is Vincent Pullone,
a one-time Golden Gloves
wannabe.
That would explain
the prior injuries.
Yeah, well, so
does his rap sheet.
The guy was busy: multiple
assaults, theft...
Is that the
surveillance footage?
STOKES:
Yeah.
I've been through the footage
throughout the entire day.
I've got the party staffers
coming in
and out the back door.
But, get this--
same time, different entrance.
BROWN:
Well, that's our vic.
STOKES:
Yeah, a couple minutes
later.
Now, here...
around the time
of the murder,
same car... pulls up...
waits.
Freeze that.
Can you get a plate number?
Yeah.
( typing,
computer beeping )
BROWN:
Nice.
STOKES:
Nevada 295,
Ocean, Henry, Union.
BROWN:
"Nanci... Mc... Ma..."
McGinnigle...
McGonigle.
McGonigle?
I'll run it through Brass.
Handkerchief is linen.
Edging appears to be
hand-stitched.
Pretty nice rag to be
wiping a gun off with.
Oh, so it was positive
for gun oil.
Yeah. And the
diphenylamine test
was also positive
for oxidizers and partially
burned gunpowder.
Uh, negative for
prints or DNA.
So, Mandy wasn't able
to lift any prints off
of the cash we found.
Fingerprints are just oil, water
and amino acids, Greg.
They don't last forever.
No kidding.
You ever hear that expression
"old money"?
This stuff was ancient--
some of it's signed by
Eisenhower's Treasury Secretary.
Series dates
all before 1965.
Same with the grand
we found on the vic.
Ancient?
( clattering in distance )
O'NEILL:
Set them down...
GRISSOM:
Miss O'Neill!
Nice to see you.
What's all this?
An army travels on its stomach.
I wanted you and your people
to know how grateful I am
for all you've done for me.
Well, thank you.
But, uh, we can't accept
anything that might influence
the outcome of the case--
it's our policy.
Oh, come on.
Cold cuts...
a little shrimp salad.
Shrimp salad...
( clicks tongue )
I know what we can do.
Have your boys
take it down the street
to the St. Vincent
homeless shelter.
They need it more than we do.
Well... ( huffs )
Having fun
with my book, Greg?
Oh, yeah.
That beach party...
Hoo-hoo-hoo.
Marilyn Monroe and
the President...
Swing-a-ding-ding.
By the way, Miss O'Neill, we
made an interesting discovery
under the floor
of your bedroom.
I was hoping you
could tell us about it.
Under the floor...?
You tell me.
Approximately one million
dollars in cash.
( laughs )
What do you know.
Tony always said I'd be taken
care of.
If you don't know
anything about the money,
maybe you know
someone who does.
SANDERS:
Benny Dunbar,
Jimmy the Crumb...
You'd have to ask Tony.
Where is the money now?
It's in our evidence vault.
Oh. And, uh...
when will it be returned?
We have to finish our
investigation first.
You do that.
You know...
( sighs )
the boys who want me dead
have been doing this
a lot longer than you have.
I need you to catch up.
Fast.
Oh, and remember, when your
tummy starts to rumble,
I tried to help.
There. There, that piece
of paper, zoom in on that.
( computer beeps )
See if I can enhance that.
( typing )
STOKES:
What is that, a bar code?
Looks like a PDF417...
two-dimensional bar code.
Can you decode it?
I think so.
JOHNSON:
Okay, it's an airline
boarding pass,
last night:
Vegas to Philadelphia,
then on to Rome, and Sardinia.
Two passengers: Nanci McGonigle
and Vincent Pullone.
Vincent Pullone was
the vic's real name,
and he arrived
at the crime scene
in Nanci McGonigle's car.
JOHNSON:
According to the airline global
distribution system,
she boarded the flight,
he didn't.
He was busy being dead.
Your fingerprint was on the
light fixture in the hallway.
You knew
about the money.
When the light fixture
shorted out,
Lois wanted it replaced
right away.
I did it myself,
and I found the money.
How much did you take?
One bundle-- 10,000.
I-I still have most of it.
Did you tell
Miss O'Neill?
No. And that was wrong.
But it was also wrong of her
to hire me as a book editor
and use me as a personal slave.
How well did you know
Vincent Pullone?
A.K.A. "Tim Duke."
( sighs heavily )
Not very well.
But well enough to give him
a thousand dollars?
We were dating.
He needed the money.
If you were dating, why was
he planning to fly to Sardinia
after the party
with Nanci McGonigle?
He didn't mention her.
Someone in the house gave
him the tickets.
Well, not me.
( bullet clanks )
Sounds like
the bullet to me.
Yeah. Deformed, medium caliber,
consistent with a .38.
Take a look at the heart.
Bullet passed into the base
of the right ventricle,
crossed
the intraventricular septum
and destroyed the AV node.
Heart stopped on impact.
Right. Bullet then exited out
the back of the left ventricle
and entered the vertebral spine,
transecting the spinal cord.
( gunshot )
( bullet thuds )
Could the victim have
crawled around
after suffering
that kind of damage?
Negative. He would have been
paralyzed instantly.
Could the shot to the head
have occurred first?
You are "O"-for-two.
Check out the brain.
There's no blood
in the wound track.
Nope.
So his heart had already
stopped pumping.
From the absence of blood,
I'd say that this shot was
at least ten minutes
after the shot
through the heart.
Lois O'Neill claims
that she saw
the victim crawling away
after she heard the first shot.
Well, maybe Lois' memory is
a little flawed.
Oh, no.
She has a great memory.
♪ ♪
( soft jazz music plays )
( indistinct conversation )
( laughter )
The gang's all here!
BRASS:
We need to ask you
some questions.
Well, please, sit. I-I have
no secrets from Bobby...
my guardian angel.
Yeah, we've met.
Isn't that right, Bob?
Uh, yeah, that's right.
Please, sit.
How often do you get invited
to the best table in town?
I know you must be hungry.
Miss O'Neill,
we found some inconsistencies
in your account
of last night's events.
Wha...?
You said that you saw
Tim Duke crawling away
after you heard
the first shot.
( sighs ):
Yes.
It was horrible.
According to our autopsy,
the first shot paralyzed him.
He would've been unable
to move.
O'NEILL ( stammering):
Well...
It-It all happened
in such a flash...
( gunshot )
( grunts )
( groaning )
Uh...
JENSEN:
All right.
She's the target.
She told you all she knows.
( chuckles )
This has been fun,
but... we have to go.
Beauty sleep.
Speaking of which...
When is that ugly yellow tape
coming off my bedroom door?
Just as soon as we finish
our work, I promise.
Anymore questions...
just call.
SANDERS:
Tuna...
and the homeless are dining
on shrimp salad.
Lucky clydes.
"Lucky clydes?"
Is that lingo from Lois' book?
BROWN:
She say anything
in that book
about all that dough we found
under her floor?
Not exactly.
But she does say back in '65,
Vegas was getting
a little bit too hot for Tony C,
so he had to take a powder
for a while.
And dig this: while he was gone,
the famous Pan Am heist was
pulled off back east.
The famous Pan Am heist?
And, compadre, in the next
chapter,
Tony builds Lois the house.
Connect the dots, buddy boy.
( chuckles )
All right,
this is what we got so far:
We got a loser boxer,
who's a crack head,
probably selling drugs--
and someone buys him
two tickets to Sardinia.
Why?
Maybe somebody wanted
Lois dead,
knew that Tim
had access
and that he needed the
money for a drug habit?
Are you saying that he was
a hit man
and not an innocent bystander?
Well, it would make Lois' story
correct--
that she really was the target.
Yeah, but who killed him?
And why?
SANDERS:
Consider this nutty notion:
Tony's not worm food,
he's around;
he finds out that Lois went
canary and wrote the book,
so he hires some protection,
someone who'd be at the party.
SIDLE:
Whether Tim Duke was a hit man
or not,
he could have been the target
all along.
BROWN:
Yeah, yeah.
Then you go whack him
when he's working around
every VIP in town. Sure.
Sure. Especially if Lois was
an accomplice.
Or, dare I say, the killer.
Well, I don't see homicide
anywhere on her schedule.
( laughs )
Wait a sec...
That's Lois' dinner outfit,
and that's the dress
she was wearing
when we opened up the vault.
Let's test them both
for blood and GSR.
SIDLE:
Looking under "formal"...
( typing )
Dress number 161.
130, 131, 132...
Got to admit,
this is some kind of closet.
Uh, it's 1-... 61.
Oh. 161--
hanger's empty.
She got rid of the clothes?
It's possible she sent
them to the cleaners
to get rid
of blood and GSR.
We can get a warrant.
Well... she wouldn't have sent
her jewelry to the cleaners.
( typing )
Got it. Drawer 19.
Oh. How apropos
that she's named names.
A canary diamond.
SIDLE:
Want to bet the birdie sings
in the key of GSR?
♪ ♪
Mom?
What are you doing?
Where's Lindsey?
She's on a sleep-over.
So kill me.
And I had dinner
at Drai's with the girls.
Filet to die for.
Drai's...
The girls like to spend.
( sneezes )
Red wine always makes me
two of the Seven Dwarfs:
Sleepy and Sneezy.
( sniffs )
Where did you get
that hanky?
A friend.
A friend who was at Lois' party?
( sighs )
Now don't get mad, Catherine.
You can't be
seeing Sam?
And why not?
Oh, for one thing,
he's a player.
I don't expect monogamy
from him.
I can't believe this.
And I am not promising that
he'll get it from me, either.
What are you doing?
Put it in the envelope.
Why?!
Because we haven't cleared
Sam as a suspect.
He can't be!
He has been so wonderful to me
these past few weeks.
Oh, this has been going on
for weeks, huh?
We have a history together,
Catherine.
We were young together.
Some day, maybe
you'll understand.
( siren blares )
You want to see
me, Muggs,
all you need
is a phone.
You lied about being
in Lois O'Neill's bedroom.
I was in that bedroom once.
In 1967.
As a gentleman,
I would prefer not going
into details.
Your handkerchief puts you there
when the waiter was shot.
One of these?
Lois and I were going over
old times.
She got a little weepy.
What she did with it
after that, I don't know.
My housekeeper made me
a dozen for Christmas.
I've only got half left.
So quit giving them away.
Oh... you're mothering me.
You know, Sam,
this is the second time
that I thought
that you might be
a killer.
Come on,
you know better.
The thing is, I don't.
It never occurred to me
for a minute
that this is something
that you wouldn't have done.
And that wouldn't bother me,
except you're dating my mother.
Look,
I'm being good
to Lil this time around.
Give us a chance.
Give me a chance.
You'll see.
Making up for stabbing
one showgirl
by being kind
to another. Hmm.
If you weren't my daughter...
What?
What would you do, Sam?
( door slams shut )
Vanity, thy name is Hodges.
This isn't
what it looks like.
I actually like
my gray hair.
The few that I have.
Hodges, don't you know
that gray hair
can be very attractive?
The ring?
The ring.
The ring was positive
for GSR.
That means Lois
could be the shooter.
I guess we'll have
to bring her in.
One of your guys take
the crime scene tape down?
Sara and Catherine
cleared the scene
about two hours ago.
Miss O'Neill,
Las Vegas Police.
Miss O'Neill?
♪ ♪
SANDERS:
Wow, it's the end of an era.
From the containment
of the blood,
it appears she was shot
while lying down.
Asleep...
or surprised by
someone she trusted?
Nick just found out
that Tim Duke's airline tickets
were purchased by
a credit card
under the name
of Double-X Associates.
That's Lois O'Neill's company.
How do you know that?
She was the double-kiss girl.
SANDERS:
Yeah, you can't
say her name
without kissing twice.
Lois O'Neill--
Kiss-kiss. XX.
Huh.
Well, Nick also found out
that the only two names
authorized to sign on that card,
were Lois O'Neill
and Eve Girard.
She looks perfect, doesn't she?
Except for these smudges
on her eyelids.
Grissom,
you know I was
looking into
that Pan Am heist
in '65?
On your own time, I hope.
It's related
to our case.
I just got off the phone
with the FBI lab at Quantico.
Bobby Dawson
sent them ballistics
on the gun we found
on Tim Duke.
And?
It's a match to the gun
that was used
to kill a guard
in the Pan Am heist.
So I sent them serials
on the cash we found.
Also a match
to the Pan Am heist?
Right-o, daddy-o.
Congratulations, Greg.
This is Doc Robbins' preliminary
autopsy report
on Lois O'Neill.
When he opened her up, he found
that her body was riddled
with advanced tumors.
Wow.
She knew she was
going to die.
That's why she
wrote the book,
'cause she knew that
if she was gone,
there'd be nobody left
to tell the true story.
You read it.
Do you think that's how
she wanted to go out?
No.
But, uh...
looking beautiful-- yeah.
In all the papers-- yeah.
Murdered...
Only if she was the one
who called the shots.
Yeah.
( chuckles )
Oh, we had some good times.
You knew she had cancer?
No, she had guts.
She staged her exit
like a pro.
The book, the party...
She only made one mistake--
she hired an amateur.
Tim Duke?
Also known as Vincent Pullone?
A wimp and a thief.
Lois would give you
all the cookies you wanted,
but you stuck your hand
in the cookie jar...
she'd chop it off.
Try to relax, honey.
This'll be easy.
I'll be on the bed,
one shot.
Don't be sloppy.
What the hell?
What do you care?
You're going
to be dead anyway.
Nobody steals from me.
Why'd she ask Duke, not you?
She didn't want to involve
an old friend.
Until yesterday.
BRASS:
Yesterday afternoon,
Lois O'Neill wired
$250,000 to your sister
in Sarasota.
Now you were Tony C's driver.
The only one he trusted
to bodyguard Miss O'Neill.
You took care of her
right until the end.
Well, who else do I have
to take care of?
My guess is she offered
you the money,
but being a friend
you refused.
So she sent it
to your sister instead.
( chuckles softly )
She sent it to my sister.
You know,
you've got a choice
between checking out
all shriveled up, in a hospital,
or at home, looking like
a million bucks.
Any guy who'd do that
for a good friend,
he's okay by me.
If you see Tony, tell him
I love him.
Doll...
you're going to see him
before I do.