♪ ♪
Stop!
CROWD:
Why do we always come here?
Open 24 hours.
Everything in Vegas is
open 24 hours.
It's cheap.
STOKES:
Smells like bacon in here.
Slide over.
That scene took forever.
We were there like,
what, nine hours?
Eleven.
A dead lawyer
and 200 eyewitnesses--
it's going to take a while.
Come for a wedding,
stay for the funeral.
Why do
we always eat here?
It's tradition.
SIDLE:
Ah, tradition.
Like becoming
property exchange
between your father
and your husband?
Oh, that's not
what a wedding is.
It's a public declaration
of love.
I'm with Vince Vaughn
on this one.
Dozens of horny,
single women
with access to an open bar
and coupling on their mind.
WAITRESS:
Weddings are a Rorschach.
Everybody sees
what they want to see.
My first five were good.
ANCHOR:
Noted criminal defense attorney,
Diane Chase was killed
yesterday...
SANDERS:
We haven't even gone
back to the lab yet,
and we're already on TV.
In a tragic twist, Ms. Chase
was killed while attending
her son's wedding.
She was best known for taking
on the toughest cases,
and it was her defense
of high-profile, organized
crime associates
that really made her a name
in legal circles.
If it was
an intelligent question,
I'd stop to answer it.
ANCHOR:
Most recently,
she represented Dino Fatelli
of the Fatelli crime family,
who was sentenced to life
last month
for the brutal slaying
of casino mogul Remy James.
The stones on these guys--
to take her out
at her son's wedding?
Pass the cream,
will you?
Dude, where's your car?
It's parked right...
( tires screech )
Incoming.
I'll talk.
You guys just look apologetic.
All right, let me see
if I understand this correctly.
You let one of the members
of your team drive
his personal vehicle
to a crime scene investigation;
and then,
even though there was
a perfectly good crime scene
vehicle there,
that personal car was crammed
with every bit of evidence
collected
at a major murder investigation,
because two of you
were maxed out on overtime.
And then the driver,
of said car, instead of securing
that evidence in the lab,
gave priority to his need
for runny eggs.
And the aforementioned vehicle
was stolen from a parking lot
filled with police cars.
Is there anything I missed?
GRISSOM:
Just this:
Even if we recover
the vehicle,
the chain of custody
has been broken,
so all the evidence
has been compromised.
No judge will allow
any of it
to be admitted into court.
Also, we released
the crime scene,
so it, too,
is compromised,
leaving us nothing
to go back for.
Thank you for clarifying
the situation.
( car door closes )
It could've been worse.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
We were seated
at a booth,
with clear visual
access to the vehicle.
A delivery truck pulls up,
blocks our view.
For how long?
Two, three minutes, tops.
What kind of truck?
Bread, dairy...
I can't remember.
BRASS:
Did you have an alarm?
Yeah. Yeah, it didn't go off.
Are you sure it was locked?
Yeah, absolutely.
And I have a tracking system
on my truck, too.
I called it in as soon
as I realized it was missing.
Okay. I'll follow up.
There's about a dozen places
to hide a tracking system
on a car.
I'm sure
the Fatellis know 'em all.
CURTIS:
No broken glass.
No bolts from a disengaged
transmission.
No tire treads or skid marks.
Hey, Jim.
I need a ride.
( chuckles )
Internal Affairs Bureau is
coming to take our statements.
They'll want to know
what's been lost.
So let's not make ourselves
look any worse
than we already do.
Write down everything--
evidence collected,
interview notes, etc...
Every detail.
No one leaves
until they've given their
account of the event.
( rock music plays )
( cell phone beeps off )
( exhales )
So aside from
the accident,
Mrs. Lincoln,
how was the show?
Not good.
Fatelli was handled
by the day shift.
Let's pull the file.
And compare it to what?
We've got no crime
scene photos.
I have mine, but they're
only of the ballroom.
But every wedding these days
has a videographer.
We got to get the video.
♪ ♪
( shutter clicks )
( clippers buzzing )
Oh. Hey, Grissom.
I'm sorry to hear
about the setback.
Yeah, well, it's all
about the body now, David.
There was a vital response
in the ligature marks
around her ankles.
So she might have been
unconscious,
but she probably was
still alive
when she was tied
to the car.
Yeah, all the significant trauma
was to the back of her head.
We'll know more after autopsy.
UNDERSHERIFF:
So you tell me how
I'm going to spin
this thing.
I've got a dead lawyer,
a known enemy
of the department,
who made her career
picking us apart.
And now, we've
lost the evidence
in her murder.
Even I don't buy it.
The Fatellis are
on our radar.
Press is going
to eat us alive.
Six month trial,
we finally get Fatelli
shipped off to Lompoc.
He's not even in the state.
How long are his arms?
I talked to the feds.
They're checking
the call logs, visitors' logs.
It's going to look like
the CSIs were paid off.
Nobody's going to believe
that this was an unfortunate
series of coincidences.
So my choices are:
we're idiots, or we're dirty.
So which are we?
It was a big scene.
I threw tons of stuff
into the back of your truck.
Figured I'd just sort
it out later.
Print lifts,
swabs, my camera.
Well, maybe if we talk it out,
it will help.
I started with the
"Just Married" convertible.
Well, thankfully, that didn't
get stolen. Where is it?
Because of possible Fatelli
involvement,
the undersheriff ordered
it swept at the scene
before they brought it back
to the lab.
It could be hours.
Did you get
anything from it?
Prints...
I remember David saying...
"You'd think she'd know better
than to wear white
on the bride's big day."
So there we were
at Cupid's Kiss,
a Nuptial Neverland
where the cheese factor
was dangerously high
and the flowers were
obviously fake.
Can the love be real
when the flowers aren't?
( speaking gibberish )
Oh, you really have a thing
about weddings, don't you?
Hey, I didn't interview them.
It was just my impression.
SIDLE:
Hi, there. Hi.
I'm, uh, Sara Sidle.
I'm with the crime lab.
Bryce Gundy, groom's side.
Did you guys decorate
the wedding car
with those beer cans?
Yep.
Did you drink
all the beer first?
Yep.
Awesome.
Did you also tie the groom's mom
to the bumper?
Nope.
Um, I'm going to need to get
your fingerprints
so I can compare them
to the prints
that I got off the car.
Cool.
You are aware that
someone has died?
Nobody's going to miss her
except her son
and her cell phone provider.
Oh, what do you mean?
She's creepy close to Adam.
Must have called him
15 times a day.
Huh.
Do you mind just putting
your finger right here?
Oh! Okay, Mr. Gundy...
I think I love you.
Yeah, thank you.
You need to sit down.
Have a club soda.
Um, um, excuse me,
you dropped this.
Sorry about him.
( laughing )
Why do the jerks
get all the tail?
Sara Sidle, crime lab.
I'm, uh, Mikey. Best man.
Brother of the bride.
Yeah, it's, you know.
Yeah.
Hey, this is a pretty
crazy-ass situation, huh?
They say it's good luck
if it rains on
your wedding day.
What do you think
about a dead body?
What do you think?
I think my sister's
better off.
You ever think
about getting married?
Um...
I'm just saying,
you know,
I think Bryce could make
an honest woman out of you.
( laughing )
Oh, look at that--
your rejection broke
his little heart.
STOKES:
Should I put flirting
in the case file?
I was printing.
He was flirting.
Uni found the tracking
device from Nick's car
in a trash can,
a couple blocks from the diner.
Pro job.
Has it been to Prints?
Well, no.
But if it was the Fatellis,
it's going to be clean.
Yeah. Nick's truck has
no street value.
The value was
what was inside.
Did you get a number?
No. No, I didn't get anything.
She must have put it
in my pocket.
Mindy.
You think she'd know better
than to wear white
on the bride's big day.
STOKES:
The perfume of American
beauties was everywhere.
Though a rose
by any other name
would have smelled
just as sweet
on a day with that much love
in the air.
Ladies, hi,
how you doing?
Hi.
I'm with the crime lab.
My name's Nick Stokes.
I'm going to need to print
you both, okay?
Mindy Faberge.
Bride's side.
Um, can we go
in and change.
I can't get warm.
Cindy Jansen. I think
she's still in shock.
You were in the wedding party.
Did you spend most of the day
here with Ms. Chase?
She was on her
best behavior.
Outside that toast
she gave.
There you go.
Thank you.
Um, well, I think that
was the alcohol talking.
So, she was a drinker?
By the end
of the toast,
she was
slurring her words
and swaying all over the place.
I almost felt bad for her.
Anyone interested
in the wedding DVD?
Yeah.
( all agreeing )
Courtesy of Frank Rosetti,
owner of Cupid's Kiss.
All right, where
do you want to start?
ALL:
The toast.
Everyone...
Everyone.
I want to thank your for coming.
You know, the Bible says,
"Love is strong as death,"
and as mother of the groom,
a wedding is bittersweet.
You are giving up as much
as you are gaining.
In some cases you are giving...
Oh... up much more.
To hell with it.
I'll wing it.
My Adam...
He studied at Oxford.
He went to Harvard School
of Business.
And of all the intelligent,
wonderful, beautiful women
he met along the way,
he ended up with Jill.
Plain, little Jill.
There's nothing wrong with her.
But what's right with her?
I mean,
even her name is boring.
( chuckles )
Adam, it's all right
to take a lover.
You just don't have to end up
marrying her.
I mean, do you really want
to shallow
our gene pool like this?
Oh...
Oh, I want to thank you all
so much for coming.
Oh, I love you, Adam.
MAN:
Hey, hey, good comedy, Diane...
Justifiable homicide?
( video continues indistinctly)
Thank you all for coming.
I love you, Adam.
You talked to the bride.
This seems like motive.
Do you think
she did it?
When would she have
had the time?
You'd think she'd know better
than to wear white
on the bride's big day.
GRISSOM:
Spring is but a song,
where love and laughter
are not wrong.
The blossoms of desire
do belong,
and Harmonia axyridis
fly along.
JILL:
For the past six months,
she made my life hell.
And so I told anyone
who'd listen
that she should die
a fiery death.
So now everyone's going
to think that I killed her.
Would you like to be
more specific?
Okay, well,
when we got engaged,
she ran into the backyard
and she screamed,
"Why, God? Why me?"
Okay, she wore white today.
She invited Adam's
very, very attractive,
very, um, single
ex-girlfriend.
When she found out
that I had registered
for sporting goods,
she went behind my back
and she changed
the registry to housewares,
saying that I'd better learn
how to cook, okay?
I'm a vegetarian,
and she demanded roast beef.
Um... Oh, and then...
then there's the toast.
The... the toast.
Are you trying to make me think
that you didn't kill her?
I would never do that to Adam.
I honestly don't know how such
an amazing man came
from-from... that.
Look, it wasn't
just me, okay?
She fought with everyone today.
She fought with the valets
and the bridesmaids
and the waiters.
The caterer-- I thought for sure
he was going to poison her.
Want to see a crime scene?
I'll show you a crime scene.
Come here. Come here.
Look at this, huh?
What this woman had against
the color peach--
I've never seen
anything like it.
"If you think you're serving
that flesh-colored abomination,
and I'm paying for it,
you can think again!" Boom!
I'm a 42-year-old paisan.
She scared me.
I wouldn't be surprised if her
pantyhose rebelled against her
and tied themselves to the car.
The dame was a pill.
I swear to God, she may
have taken two or three
years off my own life.
Weddings are a blood, sweat
and tears marathon, my friend.
I'm on a tight schedule.
12:00 noon, I got first intro
of the couple.
12:30, salad course.
12:45, first dance.
1:00, chair dance, chicken
dance, broom dance--
I don't care.
I'm equal opportunity.
1:30, main course.
2:15, first toast groom's side.
If the best man
shuts his mouth,
at 2:16 we have
the first toast
on the bride's side.
3:00, we cut the cake.
3:30, bouquet toss.
That's a tight schedule.
She would have barely had time
to go to the bathroom.
I don't sell bridal diapers
for nothing.
He was kidding about
the diapers, right?
You're way too pretty
to be a cop.
I need to ask you about
your brother, Dino Fatelli.
Dino always was
the bad seed.
I heard you guys share
the taste for blood.
I once was lost,
but now I am found.
You and your brother
keep in touch?
Yeah, yeah.
Last thing he said was he didn't
like the food at Lompoc.
I told him
to call his lawyer.
It's too late now.
Where were you
yesterday afternoon?
You want to crawl up my ass?
You can take a number.
No thanks.
50-to-one, Freddie the Feddy
is out there right now
talking to you guys.
UNDERSHERIFF:
Did you know
you were made?
Yeah. Not even Diane Chase
could keep
these guys out of jail.
And we figure it's just
a matter of time
before we get
something on Sylvano.
Like another murder?
Sorry.
He didn't kill the lawyer.
Runs numbers out
of his bar all day.
Trying to pass
a kidney stone.
Hates his wife
and his girlfriend.
I hear everything.
Could order one
of his guys to do it.
The brothers like
to be hands-on.
And all we're hearing
is them bitching
about how somebody
snatched their M.O...
ROBBINS:
Based on my dissection,
I've detected
two separate events.
I believe that
this puncture wound
happened first.
The object lacerated
a cerebral artery
creating a subdural hematoma.
Then subsequent blows
to her skull,
from a ride behind the car,
created additional fractures
which caused diffuse bleeding
on the brain,
resulting in her death.
So punctured and bobbled?
Yeah.
I autopsied the Fatellis'
original victim.
They're sadists.
First Remy James is dragged
behind the Cadillac,
and when he wouldn't talk,
they shot him
in every joint.
And when he still
wouldn't talk,
they finished him off
with a shot to the head.
The Fatellis don't mostly
kill someone.
So you took the perimeter
of the scene, right?
Yeah.
Well, I saw this guy
in the shadows.
Archie blew it up.
He looks more like
a suspect than a guest.
That face look familiar?
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, I caught that guy trying
to sleep one off in the bushes.
That's the groom's old man.
Wow, I thought my wedding
was bad.
Where is he?
I sent him
to detox, in the tank.
BRASS:
See, that's the problem
with being a deadbeat dad.
If you're not around
for the bad times,
they don't want you around
for the good times.
I didn't... I'm not...
Let's just cut right through
the lie-and-deny part
of the chat,
and I'll tell you
what I know.
My mother was a powerful woman;
she had a lot of enemies.
My mother and Joe
worked so hard
to make this day perfect.
It seems silly now.
They had a fight
about the gifts, then...
then there was a disagreement
with the bridesmaids.
And my mother accidentally
brought the wrong dress.
Then the dinner was wrong,
and the cake was wrong.
And my father showed up.
What, he wasn't invited?
Um, no.
My parents are divorced.
I think that's why today
was so hard on her.
The wedding brought up
a lot of issues for her.
She sacrificed
so much for me.
Single parent, grad school.
She was a champion.
My father is... unstable.
For years, he's had
a drug problem.
FATHER:
She told him that.
I don't believe that bitch!
You do or you don't have
a drug problem? Which is it?
Don't take everything you see
at face value.
15 years ago, Diane decided
she wanted to go back to work.
And I encouraged her.
But then she became... driven.
And I was slowing her down.
She got nasty.
I got depressed.
I started taking
antidepressants.
She was mortified.
Said it wouldn't look good.
I said, "Hey,
I'm not one of your clients.
I'm your husband."
"Not anymore," she said.
She filed
for divorce.
And she said it was because
the drugs affected my libido.
We hadn't had sex
for eight months
before I started
taking the drugs.
Did you have an altercation
with her at the wedding?
Yeah. Yeah.
Because of the meds,
I don't drink very much.
I did today because
I thought it would
take the edge off.
It put the edge on.
Good to see you.
Hi. How are you?
It's great...
Excuse me.
You were not invited.
I read the papers, Diane.
They teach literacy
at the halfway house?
I didn't
come here to fight.
You're not here at all.
He's my son, too.
I wouldn't be
so sure of that.
I stuck around
to see the ceremony.
I even saw a little bit
of the reception.
I was sleeping it off
when your guys found me.
So you didn't kill her?
No. But you better check
to see if she's really dead,
because I don't think
you can kill the devil.
Nick, you drew Mr. Chase's blood
at the scene.
His BAC was .28.
That was at 4:00 p.m.
And officers drew it
again at the station
an hour later. It was .22.
So he was in
the elimination phase.
That means, when the victim
was tied to the car,
his blood alcohol level
was even higher.
Mr. Chase was blotto.
He couldn't have
tied his own shoes.
Assuming whoever took your
truck is the killer,
Mr. Chase was in the tank.
He couldn't have done it.
One suspect down.
Speaking of downers,
Ms. Chase liked her diazepam.
Blood levels were somewhere
between therapeutic and toxic.
That's... that's weird.
Her ex-husband told Brass
she was very
anti-psychopharmaceuticals.
As a toxicology tech,
I'd say often those who
adamantly oppose the D-train
are its most frequent
passengers.
But, since she
is deceased,
I was able to get
her medical records.
No diazepam scrip.
So she got daffy
on someone else's pills.
That explains Mindy's
account of her behavior.
And the toast.
Doesn't explain how she was
conked out, tied to a bumper.
I might know what happened.
You'd think she'd know better
than to wear white
on the bride's big day.
SANDERS:
A dame was dead,
but enough about her.
The air was hot and heavy
with wrong,
making me thirsty.
Thirsty for a tall drink
of water.
That's when I saw her--
a flower--
but not the kind
you pin on a lapel.
She was long-stemmed.
SIDLE:
All right, Raymond Chandler,
we get it.
SANDERS:
And those weren't
just Miracle Bras.
They were creating
four Wonders of the World.
I'm Greg Sanders,
with the crime lab.
I need to
take your prints.
That's quite a case
you got there.
Is that your
magic kit?
Or your toy box?
You don't seem to be very upset
about what happened.
Sweetheart, I've had
so many martinis,
I'm both shaken
and stirred.
Numbing the pain?
Look, we're not
going to pretend
to be all liquid
and soft, okay?
All that's
missing here
are the striped socks.
Ding, dong,
the witch is dead.
So you're not a fan?
Cruella made me
wear underwear today.
No one makes me
wear underwear.
I'll do you
if you do me.
SIDLE:
They did not.
So how does that help
explain how Diane Chase died?
I'm getting there.
Okay, ladies,
let's slow it down.
When was
the last time you saw Diane?
In the hospitality suite.
I came in to fix my hair.
She was complaining
of a headache.
Next time I saw her, it was
bottoms up, Mommie Dearest.
So I headed behind
the pink curtain,
where the girls go
to get glossy.
A little shine here,
a little pouf there.
A little...
Well, I don't exactly
know what that was,
but I liked the feel.
Marriage was looking
like a lucrative endeavor.
And that's when I saw it.
Just a few drops.
I thought the blood
could have been incidental--
nosebleed, shaving accident.
But, what if, high as a kite
on a slipped Mickey,
she slips-- and bam!-- straight
to the back of the skull?
The arrow
was four-sided.
It would leave
a diamond-shaped wound.
They match.
If the initial wound
was accidental,
why was she panty-hosed
to the back of a car?
Don't know yet.
Narrows the field
of suspects down to someone
who had access to that suite.
Where's the statue?
In your car.
Ah!
I know every piece
of evidence regarding
this case is precious,
given the circumstances,
so I just wanted to let you know
that I've moved Ms. Chase's
fingernail scrapings
to the top of my
extensive queue.
Composite substance.
You're never going
to believe this.
Egg whites, sugar, butter, milk,
food coloring.
How did you know?
Butter cream frosting.
She had an incident
with a wedding cake.
Are you done?
You know, you and me,
we're not the marrying kind.
The intricacies of our nature
can never be understood
by just one woman.
Would you close the door,
please?
From the other side.
Sara? Sara?
Are they here?
No. They're still held up with
that officer-involved shooting,
but the Bomb Squad
has cleared the convertible.
Oh. Finally.
Something to process.
I thought you said
the snowboards were
in the suite.
I did.
Then what's the case
doing in the trunk?
So you asked me to follow
her comings and goings
and her food and drink intake.
As far as I can tell,
she didn't touch her soup
or salad.
And the main course?
And what did Diane
have to drink?
Um... I only saw her
with two glasses,
both champagne,
first one around 2:00.
But maybe she was hitting
the bar, because look:
This is 15 minutes later.
Oh, my.
The waiter gave her a second
glass for her toast,
which I watched five times.
And that was it.
When was the last time
she was on camera?
Well, her exit was neither
polite nor discreet.
I know I may just be a grease
monkey, but I drive a tow truck,
and I think I know a little
something about getting hitched.
And these two... uh...
there's more.
Uh... I think these guys
are in it for the long haul.
Making friends over here.
No, but seriously,
uh...
I don't mean to get
all sentimental
or anything,
but these two
are going to have
a lot of sex tonight.
And.. what?
What? Are you embarrassed?
She's embarrassed.
I'm her older brother.
I changed her diapers.
That was 2:25.
Would you
play that again?
I know I may just be
a grease monkey,
but I drive a tow truck,
and I think I know
a little something
about getting hitched.
Yeah, Jim. Check into
a Mikey Shoemaker,
the bride's brother.
Run his wants and warrants.
And also look into the location
of his tow yard.
Thank you.
So?
Need your hands.
I thought
you'd never ask.
I need you to
reprint the bumper
because the tape lifts
were stolen.
Anything to
keep me awake.
Uh-oh! Looks like we had some
bride's little helper going on.
Diazepam.
Just filled. Rx calls
for six
ten-milligram pills.
Two left.
40 milligrams would match
mom's blood level.
Jill gets some pills
to calm herself,
decides to calm
her mother-in-law instead,
and make everybody happy.
Okay, the blood
from the snowboard bag
was a match
to Mother Chase.
That could have been
what they used
to transport her
from point A to point B.
Yeah, "they" is right,
'cause I also found
two female
epithelial contributions.
One on each handle
of the bag,
and then one
of the same females
was also a match
to the DNA
from the knot
in the pantyhose.
We could compare them
to the buccal swabs
we collected...
if we still had them.
Well, we'll just have
to recollect them.
All 200 of them?
Yeah, and since we can't leave,
someone else is gonna have
to recollect them.
This is crap!
I've been waiting on I.A.B.
for...( snaps gloves )
...14 hours.
I'm tired...
and I kind of smell,
and I don't have a freakin' car.
Hey, buddy.
Hey.
How you doing?
You all right?
Hey, this,
this sucks, man.
I didn't do anything wrong,
and everybody's looking
at me like I'm the bad guy.
If I had to do it
all over again,
I'd do the exact
same thing.
Nick, Nick...
I mean, how do I fix
the situation?
Nick!
It was already screwed up
to begin with. What?
I loaned one of
the bridesmaids my jacket.
She was wearing black.
There was no reason
to ALS.
Blood must have transferred
from her
to my jacket, to me.
I didn't want to contaminate it
by pulling it over my head,
you know?
That was good thinking.
All right.
Hey, Wendy,
Uh-huh?
I don't know
if you'll be able
to get anything off of this,
but I want you to compare
the female epithelials you found
on the snowboard bag
against the napkin that I have
in my right front pocket.
Come on.
( laughs )
So that was a good call
on the bride's brother,
Mikey Shoemaker.
He had a prior conviction
for car theft.
Where did you find
Nick's truck?
In one of the paint bays
of his auto body shop,
right next
to a delivery truck.
We're looking
for Mikey now.
Well, I watched
the rest of the
wedding video.
He may have stolen
the car,
but once Diane disappears,
Mikey never leaves the party.
Maybe he wasn't
acting alone.
Hey, Pip.
How you like
your new ride?
Hey, look.
They fixed it.
Oh. Oh, that's not funny.
Oh, it's a little funny.
Where did you get that?
Unis found it
in a Dumpster
behind Mikey Shoemaker's
body shop.
He went through
all that trouble
to steal the car
and that's where
he ditches it?
Well, they didn't find
any biological evidence,
and he probably hocked
the cameras,
but at least I've been reunited
with Love's deadly arrow.
You know that's not going
to stand up in court, right?
Well, Negative Nelly,
I know that, and you know that,
but the suspects might not.
We have to convince them
that we know what happened.
Do we?
We're close.
Can you put the U.V.
filter on the camera?
Sure.
How did you...?
I didn't,
until I processed it.
But I was thinking
the statue
punctured her
in the back of the head,
which means
one of three things
might have happened.
Either she was stabbed by it...
Well, the statue looks
a little unwieldy.
Or she accidentally
fell on it.
But with no one to blame,
why wouldn't someone
just call 911?
Which leaves us with option
number three:
she was pushed.
Lucky for us someone had
something on their hands.
Something that left
good ridge detail
I'll swab it for trace.
Prints are a match
to a bridesmaid, Lacey Finn.
She's in the system?
Yeah, she was a cocktail
waitress for a short time.
Of course she was.
And I pulled the prints off
of this pill bottle,
but I didn't find a match.
Which means the bride
didn't do it
because as a nurse,
she'd also be in
the system.
Correct. However,
I did find something.
Look at the prescribing
doctor on that label.
I was cross-checking
with the guest list,
and guess who the good doctor's
wife is.
Mrs. Valerie Whitehall.
She's also a bridesmaid.
Well, she knew
where the pills were.
She had access
to the suite,
so maybe Jill didn't
poison mom, Valerie did.
A little bonus in the bubbly.
I got the results
from Mama Chase's
suit jacket.
What's the trace?
Hair gel.
Lacey said that she went
to fix her hair.
Where's that Sara chick?
Oh, Romeo,
I don't think
that you have time
for romance.
You're being charged
with grand theft auto,
obstruction of justice
and conspiracy to murder.
Okay, I will cop
to everything but the murder.
Well, if you didn't
commit the murder,
why did you steal
the car?
Look, the lady
was already dead, all right?
And then, then
you guys show up
and this bridesmaid
comes up to me
and starts asking
me all these questions
about my tow truck.
Which bridesmaid?
The hot one.
Next thing I know,
she wants to be the Bonnie
to my Clyde.
Asked me to steal this car
and trash all the evidence.
So you committed grand theft
auto to get laid?
Ever stolen a two-ton piece
of machinery?
It is way
better than sex.
And finding a girl
that doesn't want to kick you
to the curb for it?
I mean, come on.
That is just hot.
Besides,
I hadn't gotten
a wedding gift
for my sister yet.
So I don't have
a match
to one of the handles
to the snowboard case,
but, um,
your napkin girl...
That Mindy Faberge?
She got to be
a bridesmaid.
Yeah.
She matches
the other handle.
Well, she was in the suite
with the gifts.
She could have touched
it then.
You paged?
We think that each
of the bridesmaids
is responsible for killing her.
Not individually,
but working in cahoots.
Each one played
their part.
Did you know the original role
of the bridesmaid
was to act as a human shield
against the bride's enemies?
Women would dress
similar to the bride
in an effort to confuse
and outsmart evil spirits
that might try to overtake her
on her wedding day.
Wow, for somebody
who's anti-wedding,
you certainly know
a lot about it.
I'm not anti-wedding.
I'm just anti-stupid--
you know, people who do things
for the sake of tradition
with no clue as to why.
Anyway, let's start
at the beginning, shall we?
Valerie kindly gets
mom a drink.
Then during her toast, Diane
starts to feel the effects.
( chuckles )
By Mikey's toast, she decides
that she's toast.
...a little something
about getting hitched.
I know what you did.
I'm going to have
your husband's medical license,
and I'm going
to have you put away
for attempted murder.
SANDERS:
Lacey overhears
Diane's paranoid
yet correct ramblings
and eventually follows her out.
You okay?
The gall of you
to ask me that!
You know I'm not okay,
you little tart.
You're all just
as bad as she is.
Don't get mad.
Valerie was just trying
to make you feel better.
Oh, by giving me
a controlled substance?
You are going down
for conspiracy!
All right!
You know what, lady?!
That's enough!
SANDERS:
Leaving her incapacitated
but not dead.
STOKES:
At which point Lacey
tells Mindy and Cindy.
They formulate a plan.
( flesh tearing )
Oh, God!
Once we get her
in there,
what are we going
to do with her?
Oh, um, let's make it look
like it was, um, Forelli...
Fratelli brothers?
Fratelli brothers.
We'll just make it
look like they did it.
Oh, my God.
They tie her to the car,
chuck the bag in the trunk,
return to the party.
( all clamoring )
Got it, yes!
SIDLE:
And everyone
just continues along
with the joyous
festivities until...
( cheering )
I'm not a bad person,
and we didn't exactly kill her.
I mean, I like to think
she killed herself
because she was crazy.
She did crazy things
to our friend.
I mean, who hates
a pediatric nurse?
Granted, we'd all been drinking,
but she drove us to it.
We did what we had to do.
Sisterhood is powerful
this and powerful that.
She was on a total trip.
There was no way Jill could
endure a life of that.
I just... I wanted to shut her
up with the drugs,
but that backfired...
leaving us...
...no choice.
She was coming at me.
I just, I just defended myself.
I didn't mean to take her down,
but once she was, I...
I felt nothing.
There she was just,
just staring at me,
and all I could think
was...
"Thank God."
Grissom?
I.A.B. is here.
Lovely.
You should know that while
waiting for I.A.B.,
we recovered the car
and solved the case.
UNDERSHERIFF:
Well, this is not
a "No harm, no foul"
situation.
Disciplinary action
may still be taken.
Okay.
So who wants to go first?
I don't think it matters.
I'm sure our stories
are all the same.