Red. Hey.
( chuckles nervously )
You look good, man.
It's been a while, hasn't it?
Haven't seen you forever.
Of course, you know that
better than anybody.
I'm... surprised
to see you here.
Actually, you know what,
I'm not that surprised.
Listen,
I'm glad you dropped by,
'cause there I've been meaning
to talk to you about.
No, I-I just wanted
to say...
( silenced gunshots )
( bullet casing clinks )
( silenced gunshot )
( radio plays )
( tires screeching )
( gasps )
Oh, my God!
Oh, my God.
( groans )
Are you...
Are you okay?
Yeah, yeah, I'm...
I'm okay. I'm okay.
I-I am so sorry.
I was on the phone,
and I was going too fast,
and I just...
Oh, God, um...
I'm going to call 911,
and I'm going get
you an ambulance.
I'm fine, honest, I am.
Okay.
Really, it's nothing.
At least, can I just...
I'm going to call the police
and make a police report.
I'd really rather
you not do that.
I'll tell you why.
I don't, uh,
I don't have any insurance.
No, no, no.
That's okay. I do.
Look, it was my fault;
I know that.
And that is exactly
what I will tell them.
My dad just said,
if I ever got into an accident
that I had to make
a police report.
Can I tell you
something, sweetheart?
You're drunk
right now, okay?
And you hit me.
Now, that's a DUI,
and if you call the police,
they're going to take
your license away,
and they're going
to throw you in jail.
Now, what I'd like you to do
is get in your car,
drive yourself home and forget
that this ever happened.
Can you do that?
I'm fine.
Go on.
I'm fine,
honest, I promise.
You go.
( groans )
( shutter clicking )
BRASS:
Her name is
Ally Sullivan.
She's
the registered owner.
Patrol unit investigating
the wreck, found the body.
So far, we have nothing
on the other car.
Where's the nearest
traffic camera?
Four blocks north.
We've been
pulling bodies
out of this neighborhood
twice a month, it seems like.
I think that's actually
an improvement.
Yeah.
Well, it's a cold night.
I'm going to get you
some coffee and donuts.
Nine-nine-nine...
five-five-two.
Most people would have
called 911.
Well, there's a seat-belt
contusion on her shoulder.
So... she survives the crash.
She gets out of the car,
She dies on the street?
Internal injuries maybe.
Maybe.
How'd the car end up
in this position?
It looks like
she caused the wreck.
SIDLE:
Usually, the guy who hits
is the guy who runs.
GRISSOM:
Well, either way,
they left the scene,
so it's still a hit-and-run.
And this girl's dead.
That makes them a murderer.
( sighs )
It's late.
I was worried.
Sorry.
Love you.
I love you, too.
♪♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really want to know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me
who are you, you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
Ally was out late all the time.
I never worried about her.
She liked night clubs?
MAN:
She liked the club business.
She wasn't a party girl.
She wanted to be a VIP hostess.
( shutter clicking )
Way you do that in this town
is you...
get your face out there,
meet the right people,
be seen.
I taught her to be responsible.
If there was an accident,
call the police.
Help anyone who needed it.
I'd say to her all the time,
no matter
how pretty are today,
someday,
all that will be gone.
She knew that.
She knew she had
to treat people with respect.
She always did the right thing;
that's why I don't get it.
Whoever was in the other car...
I don't care why they left.
All they had to do
was call an ambulance
instead of leaving her
there to die.
ROBBINS:
C.O.D. was
hyper-extension
of the neck
with a rotational snap,
resulting in a ruptured
vertebral artery,
mid-cervical.
Mid?
Yeah.
Most MVA's break down low
or up high, don't they?
That's why I don't think
the accident did it.
The injury was
more consistent
with a stranglehold.
ROBBINS:
The head was rapidly twisted
relative to the spinal column.
She would have been
dead within a minute.
Whoever killed this poor kid
knew what they were doing.
I don't like Gruyere, Daddy.
No Gruyere in it, sweetie;
I promise.
All right, egg me.
Hello, Mommy.
I'm cooking.
I see that.
Good morning, honey.
Morning.
Yeah, well, the jury's
still out on that
as far you're concerned.
You must have had
quite a night.
Yeah. I guess
I lost track of time.
That Joey's a dog.
If you don't watch out, he's
going to get you into trouble.
I kind of doubt that.
I wouldn't worry, though.
It won't happen again.
These days, I'm all
about you, baby.
I'm the baby.
I know. I know, but daddies
can have more than one baby.
Yeah,
pretty talk, talk, talk.
Here, wait, wait.
Try this, try this.
Maddy made them.
Mm, it's delicious.
Very good.
I'm glad you shaved.
I barely recognized you
under all that scruff.
Hadn't quite finished that.
BRASS:
Hello, rapist.
MAN:
Man, I'm not a rapist.
I was a date rapist, which is
not even the same thing.
And besides, back then,
roofies were in.
So you miss the action
of the good old days, huh?
It's not like that.
It's not like that at all.
What's it like?
Can I get a soda, too?
I'm, like, parched.
You want to tell me what your
fingerprints are doing on a cup
in a dead girl's car?
Uh, yeah, yeah.
I was out at Jet...
( over microphone ):
I was kind of faded, I guess.
Um, I bumped into Ally,
and she offered me a ride home.
I needed it.
So that's what you were
doing on Harmon Road?
Yeah, Ally don't care
where I live; she's a cool girl.
You were close?
Oh, yeah.
Were you banging her?
Nah.
BRASS:
So, what, are you like,
pen pals? Girlfriends? What?
No, look, we really
didn't talk that much.
But we would text
all the time.
That's, like, when
you use your cell phone
to send, like, you know, words.
Yeah. I know what
text messaging is.
Fine.
Sorry.
Look, I'm telling you
the truth,
you really couldn't
get Ally on the phone,
it's all texting with her.
Well, what do you want my DNA?
You want me to pee into a cup?
You want my underwear?
Whatever you want, you got it,
cause I didn't kill Ally.
BRASS ( over microphone ):
I'll tell you what I want.
I want you to write down
exactly where you were
last night and when.
Think you can handle that?
HALL:
Can I get a soda?
BRASS:
Shut up and write.
HODGES:
Paint scrapings
from your vic's bumper
are consistent
with a '91 to '96
blue Ford.
So that narrows it down
to a few thousand cars
in the greater
Las Vegas area.
Yeah, but the car you're looking
for is also a piece of crap.
Make and model I get,
but unless you have
a new test
that quantifies
"crappiness"...
Actually, take a look.
SIDLE:
Firebird's on the left,
blue Ford on the right.
What's the gray-blue
in the middle?
A mixture of Rustoleum
and house paint.
The killer's car had
exposed primer.
Swanky.
( door opens )
Might have found a few letters
from the license plate.
"Y-K-A."
You found a witness?
No.
Just behavior.
But according to
Ally Sullivan's father,
she was the type of girl
that might have noticed
the license plate
of the car that hit her.
And according to her
good friend,
she preferred
text messaging
to leaving voice messages.
She was dying, right?
Disoriented?
I don't know, but maybe
she thought she was texting
when in fact she just
dialing her phone.
( phone keys beeping )
That's a bit of a long shot.
Yeah.
It's still a shot.
NEWSPERSON ( on TV ):
Good evening, I'm Paula Francis.
A weekend of sordid crimes
has Las Vegas Police
working double-time.
MAN:
Come on, admit it.
Come on.
That's a little smile.
Come on...
Huh? You know
you're crazy about me.
I want you to come back.
As soon as you're done,
come back.
Joey? Joey?
Hey.
You don't hit on a cocktail
waitress at the bar.
Go sit at a table,
then she's got a reason
to come over and serve you,
and it's less obvious.
Hold on. Wait, wait.
The househusband's giving me
tips on women?
I married a cocktail waitress.
Janice-- cocktail?
This crappy little joint
in Cleveland.
Really?
Mm-hmm.
I'm not looking
to marry this
this broad.
Although, she might
think so.
At least for tonight.
Ah.
Joe, you're, like, 40-something,
right.
Shouldn't you be toning
it down a little?
Tone it down?
Karl, I'm looking
to take it up a notch.
I got, like, ten
more years of fun left
and my wingman's
got a curfew.
No?
Why'd you bail out
so early last night?
I missed my family.
You're so sweet.
You should work
for Hallmark.
I'll send them my resume.
MAN:
It wasn't the smell that got
my attention, you know?
Usually when I find a body,
it's, uh, it's very,
um, raunchy.
It's called "decomp,"
in case you're interested.
I'll remember that
for next time.
If it wasn't the smell,
why did you check the room?
Rent is due
every week.
What's his name?
We ask for cash, not names.
We take who the casinos won't.
Someone's got to do it.
You touch or move anything?
First thing I did
was call you guys.
Got you on speed dial.
And finally, in local crime,
an update
on yesterday's tragic death
of Vegas party girl
Ally Sullivan.
Police are still examining
all the evidence
from the gruesome crime scene.
Detectives tell Eyewitness News
they have little to work with.
And something that stumps them:
What was the motive
for the killer
in this violent end
to a young and beautifu life?
REPORTER:
Mr. Sullivan,
when was the last time
you saw her alive?
What are you people thinking?
Think I'm going to say
something magical,
bring Ally back to me?
I'm not talking to you people.
Mr. Sullivan,
what was your
daughter doing
in that section of town?
You think it was drug-related?
ANCHOR:
Police are hoping that passersby
or other eyewitnesses
will come forward
to help the investigation
of this terrible murder.
If you have information
that might help police,
you are urged to call
LVPD at the toll-free number
on the screen.
Control, this is
Detective Curtis.
I'm at 1773 Twain,
Riviera Suites.
I got a 419. I need CSI.
You know, I think I've been
called out to this place before.
I think I've processed
this very room before.
Liver temp is close to ambient.
But lividity is fixed.
And rigidity starting to pass.
So he's been dead
for at least 20 hours.
".380 Auto."
That's Federal ammo.
.380s make a lot of noise.
It's odd that
no one heard
anything,
even in a dump like this.
"Walther PPK."
Two shots in the body,
one to the head.
Sounds like
a professional hit to me.
Looks like the killer used
Armor All.
The gun is clean.
Looks like the victim
was doing
a little cleaning of his own.
He was a 12 Stepper.
Trying to make amends.
He was on step number nine.
Apparently
not enough.
Well, it's pretty
obvious he came in
through the window.
Whew. One thing's for sure,
this killer's lugging around
some pretty big dogs.
Oh. Hey, Grissom,
I just ID'd those fibers
you found
on Ally Sullivan's necklace.
They were not from
her jacket or her dress.
They're made of lambskin
and rabbit fur.
You know, just between
you and me,
I used to carry
a rabbit's foot.
I mean,
I'm not superstitious.
It's just, I figure
why take the chance?
You know, as a kid,
my grandfather used
to have a rabbit farm.
Is this our Ford Taurus?
Once upon a time.
Told you it was
a piece of crap.
The vehicle was abandoned
near a junkyard
off Boulder Highway.
By the time they checked
the plates,
it was already in the crusher.
Plates and paint are a match
to your BOLO.
Did Brass run those tags?
Yeah, it was last registered
to a Betty Grinly in Henderson.
She passed away last month.
Gasoline. They torched it.
So he burns the evidence
near a junkyard
so that they'll find it
and dispose of it. Clever.
Looks like we're dealing
with a professional.
Professional what, though?
Ally Sullivan was killed
over a fender bender.
You're right.
He probably just
loved his car
and has a really
bad temper.
And he likes pineapples.
Ah, yeah, I remember
that Taurus.
Cheap and reliable.
That combo always sells.
Could you give me a description
of the person who bought it?
Honey, I'm not even sure
I can tell what you look like.
All I remember is
he came off the bus...
he walked right up
with a big wad of cash.
I put him in that Taurus,
and 15 minutes later,
he drove off the lot.
Did you get
a transaction record?
Let's see. Taurus, Taurus,
Taurus, Taurus...
Ah, here you go.
This is for
a '99 Jeep Cherokee.
It sure is.
Um, hold it.
It's over here.
How's that one look?
Not so great.
( beeps )
The coroner's bullets
matched the Walther,
but Bobby found
an additional striated mark
on the O-jive,
so he went back to the gun.
There was threading
inside the muzzle.
Killer used a silencer.
Slightest imperfection
in the barrel
of a silencer could explain
these scratches on the bullet.
Oh. Also explains
why no one heard anything.
But
leave the gun,
take the silencer?
Well, you can't legally
buy a silencer,
and those things are hard
to make.
If the silencer was homemade,
we might have been able
to match the killer's
tool marks.
Assuming we ever find this guy.
I don't know who would go
through this much trouble
to kill a nobody like Nash.
WILLOWS:
Well, he was a somebody
to the killer.
( beeps )
Hey, people, Amanda Congdon
from rocketboom.com
with this week's creep report.
If you were planning on
checking out
that new club, Bubbles,
down near Harmon and Twain,
you might want to think twice,
because the corpses are really
piling up down there.
The body of Clayton Nash vas
found just two blocks away
from the site
of Ally Sullivan's murder,
and the killer's still
at large.
Is this just another
crime spree,
or the work
of one deranged maniac?
Don't ask the cops.
They don't have a clue.
Remember, Amanda warned you.
JANICE:
Carl?
Mm.
What are you doing?
Oh.
Not even ready
for dinner.
I was checking
our stocks.
Well, you're not wearing that
to the Eiffel Tower.
I'll throw some clothes on.
Hurry up. My mom's waiting
for Maddy.
I don't want
to lose that table.
Two seconds.
Okay.
Well, now, who's that
beautiful girl, huh?
( laughs )
( keyboard clicking )
( beeps )
( whirring )
( beeps )
( beeps )
( keyboard keys clicking )
( beeps )
♪ ♪
So, you drive
Route 107 Southbound
during the week, is that right?
6:00 a.m.
to 6:00 p.m.
Yeah, I'm a
morning person.
Now, is there any chance,
any chance at all,
that you remember this guy?
I know it's not
the best picture.
Oh, yeah.
I let him out on stop "E" around
4:30 day before yesterday.
Oh, you know, you get hundreds
of people on and off
your bus every day.
We got to be sure--
are you sure you remember him?
I look at every face
that steps on my ride.
I saw the movie Speed--
I'm not gonna be hijacked.
Well, you know, actually Speed,
it... it wasn't hijacked,
it was wired to explode.
Whatever.
Well, all right.
What exactly do you
remember about him?
He paid in cash,
told me to keep the change--
everybody else uses a bus pass.
He was a real gentleman--
tucked-in shirt,
new shoes...
Nice smell.
Kind of stands out
on my route.
So I guess you remember
where you picked him up, then?
He came walking out of
the desert like Moses himself.
SANDERS:
So the bus driver said
the guy got on here?
You sure this is
a working stop?
You know, the Cat bus stops here
59 times a day.
SANDERS:
For what?
Construction workers,
hikers,
migrants.
The name on the
driver's license
was fake, but
the picture's
got to be real.
I'm gonna go... wave it
around the neighborhood.
Okay.
( vehicles revving )
Assuming our guy's
not from around here,
how'd he get here?
The same way they did.
SANDERS:
Every time I come
to the desert,
I see porno mags.
Who brings spankables out here?
STOKES:
It's probably just trash
blown in from off the street.
Nobody throws away porn.
They're like heirlooms.
Passed on down
the family tree.
Hey, Greg.
Come here and check this out.
A single set of ATV tracks
goes off the trail
back there into here--
killer could've dumped the ATV
and then got on the bus.
Whoever was here
had some big shoes.
Not necessarily big feet.
Multiple socks.
Another precaution
to cover your tracks.
Assuming it's our guy.
STOKES:
I'd say
it's our guy.
And I think he just
gave us the finger.
I have an update for you.
The burned gloves
that Nick submitted
are lambskin
lined with rabbit's fur.
They're consistent
with the fibers found
in Ally Sullivan's necklace.
Good.
Thanks.
Mm-hmm.
WILLOWS:
I'm guessing that Clayton Nash
had a record.
1985, aiding
and abetting,
extortion in '87,
armed robbery in '92,
assault in '95,
uh, loan sharking
the same year.
I get the drift.
But, uh,
take a look at this--
it's FBI surveillance.
What is this, summer camp?
Well, not the kind
you want to send your kid to--
they're bank robbers.
All of them?
Apparently, Nash
and his buddies
would get together every year,
talk shop, hire hookers,
play flag football.
Nash did mostly grunt work--
driver, lookout.
Never handled the cash.
He got busted
in an armored car heist
in Ohio ten years ago.
Testified against practically
everyone he'd ever worked with.
Well, that certainly explains
why someone would want
to kill him.
Most of those people
in the picture
are either dead or in prison.
Who isn't?
Give me a Heine, please.
What is that?
Anybody should be
drinking water, it's
me, let me tell ya.
Really blasted my quads.
Let's do shooters.
Wanna?
Let's pretend... that
you're wearing a suit,
and let's pretend
we're in your office,
and let's pretend I just
cut you a big check
for your services
because you are still
my damn lawyer.
All right, man, all right,
I'm listening.
There's some stuff I need.
No particular order.
Credit card blanks?
DMV license blanks?
What is this?
No questions.
Laminating machine,
blank bar code labels.
What are you doing?
What makes you think
I can even get this stuff?
I know the guys
you represent.
I'm one of 'em.
I need the stuff fast.
Don't let me down.
GRISSOM:
There was no reason
to connect the two murders
until ballistics matched
the silencer we found
in the desert with
the gun you found
at the Riviera Suites.
Two murders, same killer.
SIDLE:
Here's how we think
things went down.
The killer drove
his ATV into the desert,
concealed it in the brush,
takes a bus to a used car lot
and buys a blue Taurus.
BROWN:
Then he drives
to the apartment,
puts a cap in Clayton Nash,
gets into his car
and drives away, free and clear.
It's a good plan, well executed.
Yeah, right up until the point
that Ally Sullivan
smashed into his car.
Collateral damage--
he killed her
so she couldn't
identify him.
BROWN:
Okay, that all sounds great.
How do we find the guy?
WILLOWS:
We know his original target,
Clayton Nash.
Small-time hood who gave up
a lot of his big-time cronies.
He's got a list of enemies.
How many guys got convicted
off Nash's testimony?
Seven.
Three of them
are still in prison.
One is dead,
one is out on parole,
and two served their time
and are now out.
So we have
three potential killers
and nothing to tie them
to either crime scene.
SIDLE:
Not quite.
I ruled out most
of the prints
from Ally Sullivan's car--
the vic, the father,
her boyfriend--
but there were a few
unidentified partials.
It's not enough detail
to run through AFIS?
GRISSOM:
Well, if this guy
is a major case felon,
then his prints are definitely
in the system.
I dusted every inch
of that apartment window.
He never took off his gloves.
( grunts )
You going somewhere?
The fake ID cards?!
The staying out all night,
and then this mysterious
ATV ride in the desert.
You gave me the ATV
for my birthday.
I ride it because I love you.
Yeah, at 3:00 in the morning?
Yeah.
Uh-uh.
You're planning a job.
I'm not planning a job!
You know
I don't do that anymore.
You're a liar, Karl.
You're lying!
Honey, listen-- honey!
Janice, look...
I had to take care
of something.
And what's that
supposed to mean?
I killed Clayton Nash.
You even think about Maddy?
Your daughter?
You promised...
on her life,
you promised!
No more robberies!
I don't do robberies anymore.
Now you just kill people.
He was a rat.
Oh, Karl.
All the waiting.
All the maneuvering,
the lying.
I did it.
And I did it for us,
for this family.
I kept money in our wallets.
I invested it, so all you had
to do was watch football on TV.
And Nash was the reason.
The reason that you had to hide
the money and live on the run.
I never got caught!
And I never
would've got caught,
except for that...
that lousy junkie
who gave me up.
I only had one rule:
you never talk!
And he talked.
And you jeopardized
everything we have
for some scumbag that
nobody gives a damn about.
Janice, he called me
four weeks ago.
He said,
"I'm in town for a while.
Maybe we could we get together."
He had something to tell me.
Tell me what?
"I'm sorry?
I'm sorry I stole seven
years of your life."
I-I couldn't let it go.
Oh, God, he had it coming.
And you were
careful, right?
So what's with the fake IDs?
Karl?
You don't make mistakes.
I didn't.
Somebody else did.
A girl named Ally Sullivan.
The... The girl on the TV?
Oh, Karl!
Oh, God, she was just a kid!
She crashed
into my car
right after I did Nash.
She was gonna call the cops.
I had to do it.
I had to.
I want you to go up the stairs.
I want you to kiss Maddy.
I want you to tell her
that you love her...
and I want you to get out
of this house.
WILLOWS:
Karl Cooper.
At age 19, he was
an Army Ranger.
By 42, he was one
of the most successful
bank robbers
in U.S. history.
He pulled off dozens
of heists,
going back two decades,
all without killing
a single person,
and he was known
to his bank-robbing
buddies as "Red."
He doesn't have red hair.
Well, he got the nickname
because he was always
in debt... "in the red."
Do we have In The Red's address?
Last known
was the U.S.
Federal Penitentiary
in Marion, Illinois.
When Nash gave him up,
Cooper plead guilty.
He served the full
seven years term.
He got out, dropped off
the face of the earth.
( typing )
STOKES:
The tire model
is a Dunlop KT-345.
I checked with
the local dealers.
The only ATV that uses
that particular type of tire
has only been on the market
for about a year.
It's called the Yamaha Raptor.
So I got the list
of the names
of everybody in Las Vegas
who's recently bought one.
The only Cooper on the
list is female-- Janice.
Well, Karl Cooper had
a girlfriend back in Ohio,
a Janice Hanford.
I mean, she
could be Cooper now.
Do we have her address?
Yeah. It's, uh,
second page.
I think you
broke the case, Nick.
( tires squealing )
Maddy...
Sweetie, come
with me, okay?
OFFICER:
Las Vegas police.
Open up!
Janice Cooper?
Yeah.
We're looking for
your husband.
He's not here.
Don't take it personally,
but I'm not going
to take your word for that.
You guys never do.
Look around all you like.
Please step outside
with the child.
It's for your own safety.
Like I said, he's not here.
Mommy doesn't like you.
Really? Well, that's too bad.
She hardly even knows me.
Maddy, you
be nice, baby, okay?
Definitely. Let's all be nice.
STOKES:
Jim...
ATV has the
right tires
and there are plenty
of machine tools
and parts back there to build
a silencer.
Where's Karl?
Go to hell.
All right. Here's the way it is.
You're going to jail,
she's going to Child Services.
End of story.
I've had cops in my face
for half my life.
You don't scare me.
( phone rings )
Well, maybe that's
your lawyer now.
Hello?
Just answer yes or no--
are the cops there?
Yes.
Are they threatening
to take Maddy?
Yes.
That's what happens
when you marry a crook.
I think they're
tracing this call.
I'll take that phone.
Hey, Officer.
Yup?
I'm going to make your day.
Uncuff him,
will you, Mitch?
Karl. Don't do
anything stupid.
Palms out, please.
I know the drill.
So, tell me...
Where'd I go wrong?
You killed two people.