Come on!
♪ Regeneration ♪
♪ Of your cybersonic soul ♪
♪ Transforming ♪
♪ Time and space
beyond control ♪
♪ Rise up, resist ♪
♪ And be the master
of your fate ♪
♪ Don't look back,
live for today ♪
♪ Tomorrow is too late ♪
So nice to see
Black Sabbath again.
Saw them in '78 at
the Spectrum in Philly.
Around the same time
I saw the Dead
at the Winterland
Ballroom.
Little bit
of a different vibe.
♪ You don't want to be
a robot ghost ♪
♪ Occupied inside
a human host... ♪
You sure this is where we're
supposed to meet the guy?
Backstage, man, after the show.
I still think it's a bad idea.
Look, this reporter's just gonna
follow you around
for a few days.
He gets his story.
We all go home.
Mayor's happy,
all right?
A little positive PR
wouldn't hurt.
What?
I said a little...
(chuckles)
♪ All right, okay ♪
♪ All right ♪
♪ Till they set you free. ♪
Come on!
(cheering)
(song ends)
So, Ozzy, another
incredible gig.
The new album is
entitled 13, am I right?
That's-that's correct.
The album's kind of like a...
a modern sound,
but there's no denying
it's a Black Sabbath album.
Still got the Black Sabbath
vibe, you know?
Listen, I think we got it.
Thank you so much.
Thank you. Nice one.
I'm sure
you don't remember this,
but you were actually
my first interview ever.
I was?
The Ultimate Sin Tour, 1986.
Really?
I-I don't remember.
The concert or me?
I don't remember 1986.
(chuckles)
Really great to meet you.
Thanks for you time again.
You're very welcome.
Best of luck with of the tour.
All right, thank you.
Sheriff Ecklie,
good to see you.
John Merchiston,
Savoir magazine.
D.B. Russell, CSI.
It's a pleasure
to finally meet you.
I was reading up about
your exploits in Seattle
catching the Gig Harbor Killer.
Real thriller.
I'm not sure
that three days
with us will, uh, reach
that same level of thrills.
I sense a certain reluctance
on your part.
I just don't see the value,
to be honest, you know.
Another story about cops.
Hardly cops,
are you?
I mean, you're the, uh,
nation's number one crime lab.
Sworn to uphold the law
in the land of the lawless.
I-I've got a working
title, actually.
(cell phone ringing)
It's, uh, "Police as Paradox
in Sin City."
There's your positive
PR for you.
Yes.
Um, I'm afraid
I'm gonna have to go.
I got a 419.
Dead body.
Sounds like we're off
to a good start.
Okay, all right.
Go get your stuff.
You just signed yourself up
for the grave shift.
RUSSELL:
What the hell is this place?
These are porn stages.
Used by a local
production company.
They're currently
out of town.
I assume you've met...
Yes. Mr. Merchiston
and I went over
the ground rules, right?
I brought my own latex.
Yeah, now you don't
touch anything. Clear?
You know, I did a piece
on Scotland Yard,
so I had to pass
their forensic field training.
Impressive,
Sherlock.
Keep your hands
in your pocket.
Welcome to the Love Motel.
New partner, Jim?
Oh, uh, John Merchiston, this
is, uh, CSI Julie Finlay.
RUSSELL:
Mr. Merchiston's
a reporter,
and he's embedded
with us
for a few days.
All right, fill me in.
Jane Doe.
Mummified body.
So, she's been here at
least a couple of months.
You'd think so,
but according to the owner
of this fine establishment,
not so.
What do you mean?
Production on
Lambskin Linings Playbook
ended Monday.
The company, uh,
picked up,
went to an adult
convention in Miami.
The place has been
locked up for 48 hours.
At least until it was
broken into this morning.
FINLAY:
Skin under the neck
is opened up.
You can see the hyoid bone.
It's broken.
So she was strangled.
What is that? (sniffs)
That sweet, flowery
smell-- what is that?
Well, obviously, you guys
don't hang out in strip clubs.
Yeah, I-I thing it's called
"Honeysuckle," um...
"Honeysuckle" something.
What's it called?
Honeysuckle...
"Summer."
"Honeysuckle Summer."
That's it.
Personal experience?
I never reveal a source.
It's odd, though,
isn't it, that there's
this new stripper smell
on an old stripper body?
That's not all
that's new.
Lingerie still has
the price tag on it.
Okay, all right,
so maybe she was a stripper,
maybe she wasn't.
Either way, killer strangles
her, mummifies the body,
breaks in, stages her
to look like a porn star.
Yeah, trying
to give us all a show.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
So, all this work, what do
you think the message is?
Could be a twisted vendetta
against the porn company.
Brass is running down
all the employees
past and present.
Attention to detail,
all the way down
to the Bible
on the nightstand.
Could be our killer's obsessed
with sin.
(chuckles)
What is that?
I don't know.
Bunch of zeroes carved on it.
It opens.
(gasps)
That is a black widow.
That's the Steatoda grossa.
That's the "false black widow."
Harmless.
Says you.
Beware of killers bearing gifts.
If we can restore
her prints
or extract DNA,
maybe we can get an I.D.
Of course, there's no guarantee
she'll be in the system.
Could be we'd have more luck
if we restore her face.
Oh, it's a little late
for that, Doc.
Not necessarily.
You're thinking Dr. Stevens.
Who's Dr. Stevens?
He's developed rehydrating
techniques to identify bodies
found in desert environments.
The process,
it not only
restores the skin,
but it restores the vital
organs, everything.
We can do
a full autopsy.
There's just
one problem.
And what's that?
There's always a risk
the process could destroy
additional evidence.
Well, right now,
getting an I.D.
is our best shot
at catching this killer.
I agree.
I'll run the bath.
♪ ♪
ECKLIE:
Doc really pulled off a miracle.
He gave us a face?
Yeah, but we still
don't have any I.D.
Facial recognition in
Missing Persons came up empty.
What about her DNA?
Same story.
Nothing in CODIS.
Well, maybe if we go
public with her photo,
someone will
recognize her.
It's worth a shot.
Hey, M.
Hey. Look what Doc found
during autopsy...
inside her chest cavity.
Killer inserted it inside
her mummified heart.
ECKLIE:
Gold charm?
Hooker with
a heart of gold.
Someone's got
a sick sense of humor.
Get it to Hodges. Thank you.
Shall do.
Bye, Dad.
All right, see you.
Oh, how goes it with
Mr. Savoir Magazine?
He's a bit of an ass,
but the longer he's with us,
the more of that
positive PR you'll get.
What's your expert opinion
on this, uh...
on this little trinket
that the killer left behind?
I don't know, man.
The, uh, numbers
could mean something.
They could be symbols,
couldn't they?
I just got back from Luxor.
The one in Egypt.
I was doing an article
on the tourist trade there,
or the lack thereof.
I don't know.
Hieroglyphics are just
in my mind right now.
Hieroglyphics, symbols,
you know.
Right.
Do you mind
if I touch this one?
(chuckling): No, go ahead.
Thanks.
The spider's definitely
a dramatic touch,
wouldn't you say?
That's the pill bug
you're smelling.
It emits a chemical
to deter predators.
It's impressive, your, uh...
your knowledge of entomology.
I had a good teacher.
Going public with
the photo of our victim
really paid off.
You remember "Miss Kitty"?
RUSSELL:
She recognize the victim?
She only wants
to talk to you, so...
Hey.
Miss Kitty,
nice to see you again.
You, too.
Oh, and it's not
"Miss Kitty" anymore.
I don't use my street name.
I use my real name now.
Angela Banner.
Said you're out
of the game now, right?
Yes, and that's why
I know Megan.
She's the girl that was killed?
Megan Ramirez.
She was a stripper.
Did porn on the side.
Like me, she wanted out.
And I was helping her
through the Fellowship
of Fallen Angels.
Oh, the stripper church
downtown?
Brother Larson's ministry.
Brother Larson.
We're working to save girls
like Megan.
Now, when was the last time
you saw her?
Two months ago
at a support meeting.
And then she just...
disappeared.
But that's not all.
Since then, all of these
girls have disappeared.
They haven't come to
counseling, to meetings,
to fellowship suppers.
And you know they got to eat.
In spite of your
valiant efforts
to save these girls,
some of them may not want
to be saved.
If they had any doubt,
they would've come to me
or Brother Larson.
They wouldn't
just up and leave.
Y'all have to do
something
so that these girls
don't end up like Megan.
Excuse me.
Look, Nancy, that's all
I know right now.
No, I mean, it's... I don't have
any more information.
No, you don't have
to do that.
All right.
I got to run.
Okay, bye-bye. Bye.
Your daughter Ellie
is one of the girls
who may be missing.
I'm so sorry.
Well, you know,
I had to call my ex-wife Nancy,
tell her that, you know,
Ellie's in Vegas.
Left out the real trouble
that she might be in.
Nancy's flying out?
Yeah, tonight.
You know, ever since Ellie's
been in Vegas,
I've been trying
to track her down.
Just to reach out,
connect, you know?
When I saw that picture,
I mean, it was
like a stab in my heart.
Okay, look, you said yourself,
we don't know for sure
that something's happened
to these girls.
But we know what happened
to one of them.
All right, look,
we-we have this information.
We'll get it out
to everybody.
Now, if Angela's right
and these girls are in danger,
we'll find them.
WOMAN:
I called as soon
as the hospital
received a missing persons
photo from your office.
So, you say her name
is Teresa Hill?
Mm-hmm.
It's nice to finally
have her name.
Oh, so she came in
as a Jane Doe?
Two weeks ago.
Been here ever since.
She was found
in the alley
behind the motel,
strangled and left for dead.
Well, I'm sure
she's been processed,
but I'm gonna need
to examine her on my own.
I understand;
do what you need to do.
Okay, thanks.
Mm-hmm.
(monitor beeping)
Hey.
That from the evidence locker?
Personal items.
Day shift collected them
when they were processing her.
According to Angela,
Teresa advertised online.
Her angle was that she claimed
to be a virgin,
auctioning off her virtue.
(shutter clicks)
Typical hooker stuff.
Condoms, lipstick...
(gasps)
What is it?
Charm bracelet...
with a gold heart pendant,
just like the one
Doc took out of Megan Ramirez.
There are no coincidences,
right?
(phone chirps)
It's Nick;
he's following up
on one of our missing girls,
Chloe Rudolph.
They find her?
Yeah.
Like you said, no coincidences.
SANDERS:
Whoa, you sure
weren't kidding.
How long do you think
she's been like this?
About 12 hours,
I guess.
She seems to be in full rigor.
You know, Angela Banner's file
said that Chloe
Rudolph here worked
for a food fetish porn site.
People paid to
watch her eat.
The, uh, camera went live
about an hour ago.
That's when the calls
started coming in,
and the ISP
traced it back to this address.
This her place?
No, it's her boyfriend's.
And where is he?
He's in the freezer,
chilling with the ice cream.
(freezer closes)
Well, boyfriend's C.O.D.
is obvious.
What about hers?
Well, petechial hemorrhaging
suggests
that she choked on dessert,
but that's not
your typical chocolate.
Schistocerca gregaria.
Chocolate-covered locust.
Just when you thought it
couldn't get any sicker.
Wonder if there's
a spider inside.
Not this time.
Well,
that's three
bodies now, Greg.
And another one clinging to life
in the hospital.
We got ourselves a serial.
I don't think we're looking
at death by chocolate.
Hyoid bone's broken.
She was strangled.
M.O.'s with the female victims
is consistent.
HODGES:
As are other elements
of the killer's signature.
I did notice this odd pattern
of abrasions on her back.
(device whirring)
That's disturbing.
"Thou shalt not
bear false witness."
That's from the
Ten Commandments, right?
Number nine, I think.
The lettering
is so defined.
(beeps)
To do something like this,
you'd have to create
the bruises under the skin
right around the time of death,
knowing that they'd only
be visible during autopsy.
He wanted us to see this.
Here, now.
Talk about a signature.
RUSSELL:
Religious references,
Bibles, wooden...
whatever the hell these are,
bugs, gold hearts...
Yeah, usually a killer
has one signature.
This guy is all over the page.
He doesn't seem to have a
specific type, either.
I mean, he's even killed
a guy now, right?
A pimp.
All right, so based on
what Angela told us,
the seven girls who seem
to have gone missing
all disappeared
around the same time.
Eight weeks ago.
Now the guy's dropping bodies
on his own time table.
FINLAY:
Two weeks ago,
Teresa Hill
is found strangled, survives.
Last night, Megan Ramirez
is found dead on a porn stage.
RUSSELL:
This afternoon,
Chloe Rudolph dead
with her pimp in the kitchen.
In flagrante delicto.
Death by chocolate.
Yeah, do you mind
not sitting on that, please?
Sorry.
You got any issues
with the couch?
No, no, knock yourself out.
Does anybody else think
it's odd that, um,
the killer didn't actually kill
the first girl?
Maybe he was interrupted.
The alley crime scene
was not staged.
RUSSELL:
I don't think so.
I think the guy's methodical.
I think he wanted us
to find her the way we did.
I actually agree
with you on that,
based on my research
of the Gig Harbor Killer.
You've got to admit
there's all these similarities.
The, uh, well,
quasi-religious themes
and the presenting
of one gruesome tableaux
after another.
This is not Gig Harbor.
Yeah, I know that.
But, you know,
just-just like that case,
we do need to start
at the beginning.
Yeah, Angela came to us,
concerned about girls missing
from the stripper church.
Right, so if we want
to retrace their steps,
that's where we need to go.
MAN:
I'm not here to preach
damnation and hellfire.
I'm not gonna preach at all.
I'm just a messenger
sent here to share my story.
The story...
of a man
who used women
for his own gratification,
for the urges of others
in the almighty pursuit
of money, power,
a sweet set of wheels.
(inhales sharply)
How's it working out for you?
Shh.
Not so good.
That voice,
you can call it God,
you can call it conscience.
It's what made me see
a different path.
Proverbs.
"Let not mercy and truth
forsake thee.
"Bind them about thy neck.
Write them upon the table
of thine heart."
Ooh.
Lord Almighty,
God...
writes his name
upon your heart
because...
when your heart breaks,
his word falls in.
Pray with me,
brothers and sisters.
Excuse me.
Pray with me.
Can I help you?
Yeah, we're with the police.
Look, I don't mean
to be rude, but, uh,
a lot of us in here
have had run-ins with the cops.
We don't want
to scare anybody away, so...
if I can help you find
who you're looking for...
ANGELA:
It's okay, Jake.
I can handle this.
Hi, Kitty.
It's Angela now.
What can I do for you?
SANDERS:
We'd just like
to ask you and Brother Larson
some more questions
about the girls.
LARSON:
There's not a lot more
I can share with you guys
beside the information
Angela's already given you.
Well, you certainly have
a lot of followers.
How do you suppose
they found
their way here?
I don't have followers,
and the people,
they found their way here
the same way I did;
they hear the call.
Brother Larson
takes his ministry
to the streets, to prisons,
to shelters,
and those he saves
become congregants,
and many of them
are volunteers like me.
SANDERS:
You happen to have
a list of names
of the congregants?
There are no names here.
Uh, like that sign says,
"only fellowship."
(chuckles)
Well, with all due respect,
your fellowship
is taking quite a hit.
I mean,
with two dead women,
another one
barely hanging on.
This place is a sanctuary.
It's outside these walls
where the souls are hunted.
Is this your
Great Awakenings Bible, Brother?
Yes, it is.
So do you always make it a habit
to carve your books out
like that?
When the spirit moves me.
You mind if I borrow it?
May it bring you comfort,
brother.
You know,
I find it curious.
Women go missing
every single day,
and the police don't
lift a finger,
and yet when one of
their own daughters,
like Ellie Brass, is lost,
they will part the seas
and tumble down the
walls to find her.
You question my mission,
I question yours.
WOMAN:
You know, in the 16 years
that we were married,
I never saw the inside
of your office
at the Newark PD.
Nancy, you know,
you didn't really have
to fly all the way out here.
You remember what happened
the last time
you tried to find her
in Los Angeles by yourself?
You know,
I don't have the will
to listen to a whole recitation
of my past failures, okay?
I-I can't beat myself up
anymore about this.
Okay.
I didn't tell you this
on the phone,
but Ellie had
your engagement ring,
and then she sold it
to another girl.
I guess, uh,
she needed the money.
So you saw her, then.
Yeah, about a year ago,
she stopped by my place in
Jersey City with this guy.
He seemed nice.
Really? Did he know
about her problems or drug use,
prostitution?
She said she was gonna tell him.
Well, you say Ellie's here.
I'm here, Vegas.
What's going on?
"What's going on"?
I-I'm looking for her.
Don't you think I know
when you're lying?
You were a lousy husband,
but you're a great cop.
Find her.
MERCHISTON:
I must say, running diagnostics
on a computer
seems incongruous
for a man of action.
You just gonna stand there
watching me like that?
I was thinking.
Oh.
Hey, I got DNA and prints
off of Larson's Bible,
and I got a hit in the system.
Before he was
Brother Larson,
Daniel Larson
was a street hustler
working the Alphabets.
Priors for pandering,
pimping.
At the time of his last arrest,
he was found in possession
of a firearm.
A .38.
It's the same caliber
as the bullet
we pulled out of the pimp
in the freezer.
Maybe that's his
weapon of choice.
It sounds like you've
got your man, doesn't it?
That might work for your editor,
but it doesn't work
in a court of law.
We need a weapon.
Yeah, and besides,
all of the Bibles and dowels
at both crime scenes
were wiped clean.
(beeping)
Well, this is interesting.
It looks like
the Webcam broadcast
of the food fetish show
was turned on remotely.
How?
By a computer
at the Fellowship
of the Fallen Angels.
(sirens wailing)
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
where you going?
I'm going with you, aren't I?
When the smoke clears,
I'll call you.
Till then, just sit tight.
SANDERS:
Well, let's hope our man of God
surrenders peacefully.
I'll be waiting by my phone.
Daniel Larson!
LVPD!
♪ ♪
LARSON:
I need you to pray with me now.
Pray on change. Pray on hope.
Pray on a life
free from the bondage of sin.
Because... oh, yes...
(over speaker):
the forces of darkness
will tempt you.
They will beckon to you.
They will beckon
to you on every corner.
(woman screams)
(woman screaming and sobbing)
Stay still!
You need to stay still!
Angela?
Get off of her!
You don't understand.
Get off. Angela!
Let go of me!
STOKES:
Right there. Don't move.
All right, don't worry.
Do not move.
We're here for you.
(grunts)
BRASS:
What kind of game are you
and Larson playing, Angela?
You come to us with names
and faces of missing girls,
one of them my daughter.
Right? And Larson's
taunting us with messages
from the crime scene.
You're wrong.
Brother Larson and I
had nothing to do with this.
We were trying to help.
Mr. Russell, you know me.
What about the young woman
we found you with?
The one strapped to the bed.
She's an addict.
Detoxing. She can't
go to the hospital.
Where's Larson keeping
the rest of the missing girls?
Where's my daughter?
I don't know.
You're lying!
You know what?
You're the reason
Ellie was on the street.
So don't accuse me of something
you got only yourself
to blame for.
I'm out of here.
Please say you believe me.
Where's Brother Larson
right now?
I don't know.
MERCHISTON:
She says she
doesn't know
where Larson is,
but I've got a pretty good idea
of where he was.
And I've got a
concussion to prove it.
You think she's
telling the truth?
RUSSELL:
That woman
saved my life once.
She may have unwittingly
recruited converts
for Larson, yes, but...
I do believe that...
she was genuinely
trying to help those women.
What about Brother Larson?
That's another story.
One I haven't
figured out yet.
Well, I have been
giving some thought
to the, uh...
to the way in which
the scenes were staged.
Stage-managed,
if you like.
Take a look at that bed.
And the table
and the lamps.
And then, if you look
at the dessert scene,
you can see the plates
and the cakes,
all ring shaped.
Even in the alley way,
which didn't appear staged.
But if you look again,
you've got a bicycle,
a discarded mirror
and a shattered clock.
Just like the wooden dowel.
We thought they were numbers.
Zeros.
He's playing games with you.
Well, your killer's a
man of many signatures,
but the one thing that seems
to be constant-- these rings.
No, they're not rings.
They're circles.
♪ ♪
We've been trying to figure out
why this guy
had multiple signatures.
Actually, I think
that he got
all of his inspiration
from one place.
Dante's Inferno.
The Nine
Circles of Hell.
First Circle, Limbo.
We were wondering
why Teresa Hill survived.
It's because he
wanted her to.
She's in a coma.
She's in limbo.
FINLAY:
Megan Ramirez.
Porn Star on a porn stage--
lust.
Chloe Rudolph,
at the dessert table--
gluttony.
RUSSELL:
And her boyfriend
who turned her out--
greed.
All staged to look
exactly like engravings
from a 16th century volume
of the Divine Comedy.
You said he was
giving us a show.
I'd say this looks
more like a sermon.
Yeah, I agree.
And he's not done.
There are other
missing women.
This guy's gonna drop bodies
until we stop him.
MERCHISTON:
Anger, heresy,
violence, fraud, treachery.
Yeah, I've seen
this movie before.
So has Brother Larson.
FINLAY:
Anger is obviously next.
But how does this
really help us?
It gets us into his head.
Beyond that,
I don't really know.
Well, to quote
a famous man from Seattle,
identifying the killer's
signature is the first step
in making the hunter
become the hunted.
This is why I don't do
interviews anymore.
Well, considering we have
so little evidence on this guy,
(phone beeps)
I'll give you
a quote from me.
Sometimes we have to wait
for a killer to make a mistake.
I think he just did.
Brother Larson.
I'm CSI Russell.
And I'm confused.
I understand I'm being
charged with a homicide.
Three, actually.
One attempted.
Teresa Hill,
Megan Ramirez,
Chloe Rudolph and her boyfriend,
Greg Lee.
Ballistics on the gun
found in your car
when we picked you up
matched the bullet
taken from
Greg Lee's head.
You also used the computer
in your church
to activate
Chloe Rudolph's Webcam
so that we would find her
when you wanted us to.
It would seem
I have enemies
who seek to undo
my good work.
Let's talk
about that work.
Mm-hmm.
We went through
your cell phone,
and we found
photos of women.
Including all
of the dead girls.
A shepherd watches
over his flock.
I think that this
shepherd chooses them
very carefully for who
they are, what they are.
Limbo. Lust. Gluttony.
I think you obsess
over them,
and then I think you
punish them for their sins.
It's come
to Jesus time, Brother.
You tell me where
the rest of the girls are.
Where is Ellie Brass?
I am a sinner.
I am not a kidnapper.
And I am not...
a murderer.
And I'm not a believer.
These are not my crimes.
Look, man, these
girls going missing,
I got nothing to
do with that.
My only crime-- my only crime--
is making a little money.
Selling a
little tail.
Go on.
I take these girls
off the street, pal.
I give them a better life.
I introduce them
to a better class of john.
So, you're still a pimp,
is what you're saying?
And the pictures
I sent online...
a client who reached out
to my ministry.
Does that client
have a name?
(chuckles)
Anonymous.
Arrangements are
always the same.
I send him pictures and bios,
he picks a girl.
I drop her off at a corner.
A car comes.
Up until now,
my little lambs have always
found their way home.
Why should I
believe any of this?
I confessed my sins
already, pal.
I will not bear
the sins of others.
And you prosecute me wrongly...
another body will drop,
and that'll be
your cross to bear.
Besides, if you
catch this guy,
you're gonna need me.
And I need an
assurance of freedom.
Are you kidding me?
You don't have anything
to bargain.
Ellie Brass?
She isn't missing.
I spoke to her this morning.
I know where she is.
Yeah. (chuckles)
I call my lawyer.
We make a deal.
I then give you
a miracle.
Prodigal daughter
returned home.
ECKLIE:
Think Brother Larson's
playing us
for fools?
RUSSELL:
Greg processed
his home computer.
Found online messages
from Anonymous,
just like he said.
Guy even put in a request
for another girl for tonight.
Yeah, but that could just be
a smoke screen, couldn't it?
And elaborate alibi.
ECKLIE:
Yeah, it could be.
Greg run trace on the computer?
All the messages came
through a file-sharing site.
We could try for a warrant,
but there's no law
against posting pictures.
It's another
dead end.
So, if Larson is just a pimp
and Anonymous
is the guy doing all this,
how are we ever
gonna get to him?
Morgan has a plan.
One that I think the DA
will be very interested in.
Let's hear it.
Anonymous is requesting
another girl for tonight,
to add to his collection.
So let's give him one.
Use Larson to do it.
MERCHISTON:
We know the guy
posts pictures,
the women get dropped off
on the corner
and taken up
to his flat.
Obviously,
you have someone in mind.
Yeah. I worked undercover
in L.A., Dad.
I know what I'm doing.
You never dealt with anything
like this in L.A., Morgan.
Right now, I'm not
your daughter; I'm LVPD.
And now you're
the sheriff.
You're gonna have
to make tough decisions.
I really don't need you
to tell me...
All right, whoa, whoa, hey, hey.
Come on. Come on.
Take a deep breath here.
Obviously, Morgan
is taking a huge risk
by doing something like this.
But without
an undercover operation,
we are all just sitting around
waiting for another body
to drop.
You got into the killer's mind.
Maybe I can get
into his home.
Get him to reveal himself.
Now, look,
the crime scene suggests
this man's a narcissist.
He's a showoff.
He can't help himself.
He likes to brag,
so maybe he's going to brag
to this young lady.
Morgan's plan
is a good one.
And there are
other daughters
who are out there
right now in danger
and fathers who are
worried about them.
We know one of them.
I need to do this, Dad.
BRODY:
How do I look?
Looking good.
Unit one, you're in position?
MAN (over radio):
Roger that.
Unit two. Nick? Greg?
Yeah, we got eyes on her.
(sighs)
Looks like it's on.
We're on the move.
ECKLIE:
Copy.
♪ ♪
(knocking)
Well, well.
Pretty as a picture.
Please.
Come in.
Are you an
art lover?
Not really.
You an art collector?
No.
I just like
beautiful things.
Even when they're about
something hideous,
like suffering...
damnation...
hell.
Think we got our guy.
Got an I.D. on him yet?
Yeah, I'm running
his address right now.
Oliver Tate.
Doesn't have a criminal record.
M.D., Ph.D.
Works for a biotech company.
TATE:
And,
truth be told,
I am man of science.
Guess that explains
all this stuff.
This stuff...
are the tools that man
has used to seek knowledge.
To look
deeper into the mysteries
of the world,
to educate the beast.
This is really cool.
What is it?
TATE:
My prized possession.
It's kind of an abacus
from the 16th century.
They're called
"Balliol's Bones."
I don't like this.
She's in control.
She's gaining his trust.
(cell phone beeps)
Be right back.
RUSSELL:
When did this arrive?
Around, uh, midnight.
I couldn't sleep.
I went down to the bar
for a drink, and when I
came back, it was
outside my door.
Okay.
Is that blood?
What the hell is that inside?
Looks like a flash drive.
TATE:
This...
is for you.
Anger.
Well, you are
the angry girl.
At least that's what
Larson promised me.
You care to tell me why?
You first.
Tell me why
a good-looking,
rich guy like you
has to pay for company.
Pleasure, of course.
Pain, too?
It's my experience
that women like you
who want to be bad...
who want to be
punished...
have one thing
in common:
daddy issues.
BRODY:
You know me too well.
Brother Larson told me
you have certain...
tastes.
Oh, don't worry,
I don't bite.
Wouldn't matter if you did.
You're the one
in control here.
You can do
anything you want to me.
You want to hear
a dirty little secret?
(Brody giggles)
It turns me on
when men talk
about their conquests.
Their...
previous adventures.
Don't you want to turn me on?
I know I am not the first girl
to ever receive
a present from you.
So, come on.
We've got all night.
I'm not going anywhere.
Take off your clothes.
TATE:
I like to see
what I'm paying for.
I shouldn't be here.
Unit one, what's your 20?
MAN:
We're in the lobby.
I want you up
on that floor--
I want you close.
I'm coming there now.
Anything happens, you radio me.
I will.
Lovely.
I just hate
unnecessary adornment.
TATE:
Oh, sorry.
Did I hurt you?
No.
(scoffs)
Suddenly, I'm not in the mood.
(laughs)
Did I do something wrong?
Maybe another night.
But you said you
liked what you saw.
Oh, I do.
My driver
will take you back.
RUSSELL:
Fraud.
Eighth Circle of Hell.
You think he made her?
SANDERS:
I don't know.
We should pick her up.
That's not the
plan, Greg.
I don't know,
something's not right.
Well,
if he didn't make her,
we might still have a chance
to get this guy.
SANDERS:
Vehicle's on the move.
So are we.
MAN: Tell them.
Ellie!
ELLIE:
Daddy, help me.
(Ellie screams)
MAN: Tell them!
ELLIE: I have sinned.
(slap, Ellie screams)
We have sinned,
and we'll be punished.
"We have sinned"?
Oh, hell. All right.
What's happening?
Can't talk now. Where's Morgan?
He threw her out.
No, he didn't.
Greg.
Stop the SUV.
Just reestablished visual.
Copy that.
Let's hit it!
(siren wails)
(tires screech)
Get out of the car!
Now! Get out!
Let me see your hands.
Put them on the hood.
I said on the hood!
STOKES:
I know you.
You're that kid from
the stripper church.
Nick! She's not here.
I told you we
should've picked her up.
Where is she?
Where's who?
The girl!
Where's the girl?
I don't know what the hell
you're talking about.
Boy, you out
of your mind?
Huh?
Russell.
Morgan's gone.
Dispatch, we have a 444.
Officer needs assistance.
Alert Sheriff Ecklie.
What the hell is going on?
The killer's got Morgan.
And Ellie.
He's got them both.