♪ ♪
(electronic music playing)
GIRL:
Water!
(crowd cheering)
(grunting)
(whimpering)
(gunshots)
(screaming)
(explosive whooshing)
(cheering)
(recording):
This is Gil Grissom.
I'm unable to answer your call.
Please leave a message.
(beep)
Hello, Gilbert.
Happy anniversary.
Hope you're out there
celebrating.
And it's official--
time differences really suck.
Uh, look, I miss you.
I'm going to try
and call you back later.
It's been a while, you know,
since we really caught up.
I love you.
No, I'm taking
good care of myself.
Matter of fact, I had... I had
leftover pizza for breakfast.
I'm kidding, honey.
I know you're needed up there,
but I need you down here, too.
Love you, too,
sweetheart.
Bye-bye.
Welcome to the joys of
long-distance relationships.
Yeah. I don't know
how you do it.
Boy, I tell you,
even postmortem,
this place
is taking me back.
So you big on electronic
dance music, then?
No, music festivals,
where they play real music.
You know, I was actually
at the original
Humboldt Folklife
Festival, 1972.
Yeah, I never
heard of that.
(scoffs)
Yeah, youth,
wasted on the young.
Yeah, around here,
youth is just wasted.
Detective Moreno.
Looking good there, buddy.
Catch you
on your day off, did we?
No, no, no, no.
I'm on the clock.
This is, uh, one of Vice's
busiest weekends of the year.
SIDLE:
What happened here?
We have an unknown
male assailant.
He shot four or five rounds
into the crowd.
Panic gave way
to trampling,
a couple people
got grazed,
and one fatality.
No I.D.,
no bracelet, either.
Maybe she didn't
pay to get in.
This whole area
is fenced in.
I'm thinking she,
uh, crawled under.
Explains all the dirt
on her clothing.
MORENO:
Single GSW to the back.
And exit wound.
Through and through.
(shutter clicking)
David?
What's this pattern
on her arm?
PHILLIPS:
Looks like a standard
four-plus-one.
Somebody grabbed hold
of her pretty tight.
Bruises and nail gouges.
Whoever grabbed her is missing
a couple of fingernails.
Any witnesses?
Oh, we got a whole rave
full of witnesses.
Only problem
is they're all tripping.
Reports range from sketchy
to hallucinogenic.
Although a couple people did say
that they saw her come in
with another girl.
Another girl.
Uh-huh.
What happened to her?
Don't know.
Well, hopefully,
she's still running.
You know, this doesn't seem like
a random shooting to me.
Think she
was targeted?
And the other one
got away.
Yeah, but for how long?
Okay, looks like that girl
is our witness, then.
Maybe our next victim.
Unless we catch up with her
before the shooter does.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
(indistinct chatter,
radio communication)
(shutter clicking)
FINLAY:
Surprise, surprise.
You found a mushroom
at a rave.
Uh, wrong kind
of mushroom.
Psilocybin, the, uh, fun ones,
they grow in meadows and fields,
and have dark spores
and little gills.
So you can't have any visions
or talk to God if you eat that?
No, you eat one of these,
you'll be
talking to Saint Peter.
Genus: Agaricus,
endemic to the desert region.
So maybe this is where
our girls came from.
There's a whole lot of desert
here in Nevada.
Maybe this little devil
will help us
narrow it down a bit.
(whimpering)
(gunshot)
(shutter clicking)
What is that?
Nitrous oxide.
Hmm.
This tank took
an incredible journey
all the way from
this cart carrier
back over there.
I'm thinking one of
the shooter's bullets
punctured the tank,
causing the N2O to blow.
(hollow clanging)
And the pressure was so high
that the metal deformed outward
while the gas escaped.
Witnesses say the tank
was breathing fire,
but nitrous oxide
isn't flammable.
Yeah, but it is a
potent oxidizer,
providing more oxygen
than the atmosphere.
All it needs is a spark.
Raver lights up.
"Smoke on the desert,
fire in the sky."
I was just lighting up,
my cigarette,
and I heard
these two bangs.
You know, loud.
Bang! Pop! Pop!
And this fire comes raining
down, you know, like a dragon.
And my hand was, like,
more baked than me.
Dragon aside, uh, did you see
the girl get shot?
Oh, yeah.
Poor little flower, yeah.
Was there anyone
with the "flower?"
Oh, yeah.
John Lennon.
Uh, or Kurt Cobain.
I could only
see their aura.
Um, oh, you know, I got some
of it on my smartphone.
About five megapixels.
Would that be better?
(phone beeping)
(helicopter flying overhead)
Hi. CSI Brody.
What happened to your arm?
I was dancing, got in the
way of a flying tank.
Since when do they let patients
treat themselves?
Oh, well, I'm a
medical intern.
I figured the paramedics
were busy enough.
You do seem kind of lucid
for this crowd.
Yeah, well, I don't drink,
I don't do drugs.
I just came
to dance off some stress.
If you were dancing
by the tank,
then you must have seen
the girl get shot.
No.
What about the shooter?
Sorry.
When I heard the shots,
I hit the dirt.
Tried to get small.
Well, I'm still going to need
your information.
Hey, uh, the girl
who got shot,
is she going to be okay?
Jane Doe,
number 12-608,
a malnourished female
between the ages of 16 and 20.
C.O.D. is a single
gunshot wound to the torso,
perforating the heart.
(door opens)
Victim presents evidence
of persistent,
chronic trauma.
And abrasions on the wrists
consistent with ligature
restraints, possibly shackles.
General muscular atrophy
and posterior bed sores
suggest victim was subjected
to imprisonment
for an extended period
and confined to a bed
or other flat surface.
Sexual assault?
There's only one reason
to keep a girl shackled
and on her back.
She was a sex slave.
I can count on my hand
the times I've taken comfort
in seeing someone on my table.
You know, I'm not sure I buy
that whole "they're
in a better place" angle.
Given her condition,
I am having trouble
imagining a worse place.
Sara, this girl has
never been to a dentist
or a doctor.
She suffered years of neglect.
We've both seen
victims like this.
Even if they survive,
they're never going
to be made whole.
She should have had
a chance to try.
Well, witnesses saw her
running away
from the shooter.
Have you considered
the possibility
she was running from her captor?
Human trafficking's a
multi-billion dollar business,
and if that's what this is,
there may be more
girls out there.
We know there's at least one.
If we can find her,
maybe this
little girl's death
won't be for nothing.
BRODY:
How many smartphones
did we collect?
SANDERS:
Fifty-seven,
plus a dozen clips
from YouTube.
I hate electronic music.
Not today, you don't.
It's the only way I could
sync up all these clips
so we can watch our
crime scene play out
as a music video.
(electronic music blaring)
Now, most of the phones were
turned towards the stage,
so no sign of our killer.
Hold on.
Zoom in on the tank.
Can you get a better angle
on that pink fur?
I have so many angles...
...we might as well be there.
(crowd cheering, music pumping)
(gas hissing)
BRODY:
Dancing stress off, my ass.
Kitty was dealing nitrous.
(gunshots)
(metal clanging)
(nitrous tank hissing)
(explosive whooshing)
SANDERS:
She tell you she was also
playing doctor?
Amanda.
Didn't recognize you
without your ears.
CSI Brody, uh...
what are you doing here?
Can I help you with something?
I'm sure you can.
I'm looking to
score some nitrous.
I've got rounds.
This is called
distribution
of a chemical solvent
to induce euphoria.
It's a Class D misdemeanor,
and at the very least,
it's enough to
lose your license.
It's a victimless crime,
all right?
I wasn't hurting anybody.
I'm not here to debate
the war on drugs.
You tried to help
the dead girl.
What about her friend?
What about her?
I think you tried
to help her, too.
Look, I don't want
to lose my career
for doing what
I took an oath to do.
She was... freaked-out,
she was scared,
so I hid her in my car
where I could take care
of her injuries.
There were police
officers everywhere.
You could've
told someone.
I couldn't, all right?
I've been around
freaked-out people before.
She was...
she was like an animal.
She wouldn't talk.
She just kept staring at me
with these wild eyes.
So why did she trust you?
I don't know.
Her friend was dead, and...
I tried to help her.
I guess she clung on to me
because she had nobody else.
Where is she now?
No, no. She's
photophobic.
She can't handle
the light.
(laughs softly)
So, what was the plan?
You were just going to leave her
in the basement forever?
(sighs)
I was hoping she'd calm down
and I could admit her.
See for yourself.
It's okay.
It's okay, honey.
She's here to help you.
My name is Morgan.
What's your name?
Do you speak English?
¿Habla español?
Oh. It's just my kit.
I'm with the police.
I need to take some samples.
It's just cop stuff.
I tell you what.
How about I do everything
to myself first...
...and that way, you
can see it doesn't hurt.
(shutter clicks)
(shutter clicking)
See? Not so bad.
Right?
Can I see your hands?
Tus manos...
por favor.
(shutter clicking)
Now I need
to take some DNA.
Doesn't hurt.
Want to try it?
♪ ♪
Thank you.
Stay with her.
I'll be right back.
(panting quietly)
(beep)
Russell.
I'm at Desert Palm.
I found her.
Our missing girl.
(voice breaking):
Russell...
they cut out her tongue.
ROBBINS:
Based on my examination,
the bulk of her tongue
has been removed.
The anterior margin's
jagged and irregular.
Not a surgical removal.
What'd they use?
If I had to guess,
a household tool, pliers maybe.
How recent is the injury?
ROBBINS:
Scarring and healing suggests
the removal occurred
at least six months ago.
Does it prevent her
from speaking?
Well, with that
kind of damage,
I'm afraid she's not going to
be doing a lot of talking.
RUSSELL:
Thanks, Doc.
Yeah.
Why the hell
would somebody do
something like this?
Power. They wanted
to silence her
or punish her,
maybe both.
(long sigh)
She has, uh...
ligature scarring
on her wrists and her ankles,
just like the dead girl.
I think they were
held together, but...
she doesn't have any
signs of sexual abuse.
She looks to be a couple of
years younger than her friend.
Maybe... maybe the older one
was trying to protect her.
That's consistent with
witness testimony at the rave.
Listen, she knows
who did this to her,
and it's probably the same
person who shot her friend.
So what? She can't tell us.
Maybe. But she
still has a voice.
Job interview?
(chuckles)
No, my friend.
I was in court.
So, Russell said you had
some information for me?
The mushroom
on the dead girl's sandal
is Agaricus deserticola.
It's extremely poisonous,
found in deserts
of the Southwest
and Northern Mexico.
Wow.
That really narrows it down.
Thank you very much.
Fear not, I've left
no tongue unturned.
Whoa. That's a little rough,
don't you think?
Humor is my way of
dealing with the horror.
It's a crass and essential
defense mechanism-- otherwise,
I couldn't do my job,
especially in
cases like these.
Okay, uh, getting
back to my job.
Yeah, please.
It's time
for a little fun
fact about fungi.
They're like these little
biological sponges.
Whatever's
in their environment--
nutrients, toxins,
elemental metals--
they absorb it all.
I performed micro-FTIR,
and I hit pay dirt
on our fungi, confirmed
the results on XRF,
and found a high concentration
of one particular metal.
There's tungsten in
them thar hills.
Tungsten.
Now, that's found
deep underground.
We could be looking
for a refinery here.
Or...
a tungsten mine.
And there's only one
in the area of the rave.
So, we're looking
for mushrooms.
(chuckling):
Yeah.
I got to say,
you CSIs have a...
an interesting job.
Well, you seem to find
one of us interesting,
that's for sure.
Ah... okay.
And how's that
working out for you?
Let's just say Finn
is, uh, different.
Ah, different
can be good.
Besides, she's really
hot, don't you think?
Oh, she's hot.
And cold.
Hey.
What's with the third degree?
Watch your step.
What do you mean,
"watch your step"?
Mushrooms.
MORENO:
Sorry.
Look at that.
(beep)
Well, if the
shoe fits...
Good work, Cinderella.
STOKES:
Well, it's the same size
and same pattern
as our victim's shoe.
Okay, so the rave
was due east, right?
Yeah. A couple
miles that way.
So, where do you think
the girls were coming from?
♪ ♪
(beep)
(exhales)
STOKES:
Well, the disturbance
in the ground cover
tells me the girls
ran down the hill.
(distorted, echoing):
Come on, let's go.
There's a road
right over this hill.
Highway 238.
Smugglers' Alley.
I can't tell you
how many busts
I made on this road.
Ooh. You smell that?
Mmm, cow pies.
Getting homesick on me?
(laughing):
Yeah, I'm getting there.
We got footprints.
They seem to start right here
in this hay and sawdust.
Yeah, here we go.
What do you got?
That's an R-FID tag.
Radio Frequency Identification
used on cattle.
And that... looks like the last
of the shoe impressions.
So...
the girls started
running from here.
Where does this road
come from again?
Bullhead City.
Look at these
tire impressions.
Looks like a semi.
Yeah.
Could be looking
at a cattle hauler.
And I'm thinking
a lot more than that.
This road's notorious
for drug trafficking,
human trafficking,
all sorts of trafficking.
You know, what
I don't get is,
if our girls are
really on that truck,
why stop and let
them off here, right?
STOKES:
There's another set
of tire impressions here.
That's a passenger vehicle.
Yeah, narrower
wheelbase.
Looks like an accident.
STOKES:
Involving...
a red vehicle.
And the other one was blue.
Pieces of a headlamp
here, too.
Okay, so we got skid marks,
and the car forced
the cattle hauler off the road.
But... what do you think,
road rage?
(vehicle rumbling)
Yeah.
(tires squeal, vehicles bump)
STOKES:
I mean, if the truck
did come to a stop,
the girls could have had
a chance to get away.
Well, if we can I.D.
the truck and the driver,
we can find our shooter.
(phone ringing in distance)
(gasps)
Hey, hey, it's okay.
You're safe.
You're in the hospital.
It's okay.
(siren wailing in distance)
I know it-it seems
like a scary place, but...
it's actually not that bad.
My dad was here
recently,
and... and he ended up okay.
You're going to be okay, too.
I don't know
if you can understand me.
what happened to you
or where you've been, but...
I want to help you.
I know why you can't talk.
(sighs)
But I-I thought maybe...
you could write down the answers
to some of my questions.
Can you try
writing your name?
What-what about your address?
Where-where you live?
Your house?
Your mother's name or...
your father's name?
What about the girl
you were with? Your friend?
Can you write her name?
(sighs)
Um...
Well...
this is... my name.
Morgan Brody. That's me.
This is my address.
In Green Valley, and this
is my best friend's name.
David Hodges. (laughs)
At first, I didn't
like him very much.
He was...
kind of weird.
But, you know, he's actually
a really sweet guy.
He's smart and... funny.
Our parents are dating,
which is so weird.
Sorry. Way, way
too much about me.
Thank you for trusting me.
What is this?
(sighs)
The man who killed your friend--
did he do this to you?
(quiet crying)
(sighs)
(sniffles)
Hey. Hey.
I'm going to find him,
and I'm going to make him pay
for what he did to you.
I promise.
This is all she gave me.
RUSSELL:
No name, no address.
Just a drawing.
What do you think?
Jail cell?
Or barred window? Flowers?
Our girl was
a prisoner.
Maybe this
was her view
of the world. Maybe this is
where she was being held.
Doesn't help us
with a location, though.
STOKES: No, no.
But we may be getting closer.
I tracked the girls
to Highway 238.
There was clear evidence
of an accident
involving a cattle hauler.
Cattle hauler.
Yeah, yeah.
We found an R-FID tag
at the scene.
RUSSELL:
Two girls, chained, caged.
You know, treated like cattle.
It's not a stretch to think
the driver
of the hauler is our guy.
Or just a delivery man
who was part
of something much bigger.
Yeah, but how do we track
that down?
Okay, well, the truck
was coming from Bullhead City.
We found red and blue debris
from a big rig in the highway.
It was definitely
in a fender bender.
So, Moreno checked
with D.O.T.
Got a list of all red
and blue cattle haulers
moving through Bullhead City
in the last 24 hours.
Got an I.D.
on our murder weapon.
.41 Ruger Magnum.
Greg printed up a list
of registered owners.
What are the odds?
Two lists.
Oh, here we go.
"Oliver Ruiz, El Paso, Texas."
Pulling him up.
(keyboard keys clicking,
computer beeps, trilling)
SIDLE:
Got a name and a face.
Now we just got
to find him.
Oh, I bet he's still
in the neighborhood.
He only half-finished
the job.
(computers trilling,
distant phone ringing)
Hey, there you are.
Uh, I ran the swab you
gave me from the girl,
the one without
the tongue.
Sorry. You know
who I mean.
You got a hit
in Missing Persons?
No, not on her, and not
on the dead girl, either,
but I did get
something.
What?
A definite familial match.
The girls were related?
It's a classic 25:50:25.
I did a linkage ratio.
SIDLE:
Sisters?
That narrows down
our cases quite a bit.
BRODY:
She couldn't even write.
Not her name.
Not anything.
She could only draw.
Tells us they were abducted
as small children.
Never even been
to school.
BRODY:
Our girl
is between the age of 15 and 16,
which means
we're looking for two sisters
who were abducted
at least ten years ago.
(computer trilling)
SIDLE:
Here's something.
2001, Prescott, Arizona,
two sisters went missing.
Jacinta Flores and Rosa Flores.
(computer chirps)
SANDERS:
It's hard to tell.
I can tell.
That's our girl.
SIDLE:
Father told the police
that the mother took off
in the middle of the night
with the kids
and took everything.
Is there any theory
as to where they went?
SIDLE:
Mother does have family
in Mexico.
So, mom goes south
of the border.
Something happens to her, or-or
she just unloads the girls.
And they end up
in the sex trade.
Is there contact info
for the father?
SIDLE:
No.
But the investigating officer
in Prescott is listed.
Wait a minute.
It looks like the father has
kept in touch all these years.
He contacts Prescott PD
every couple of weeks
to follow up.
I'll call the IO.
Thanks.
All right, keep me posted.
And hey, post that
truck driver's photo up
all over that hospital, okay?
He could show up.
Yeah, yeah, we're on it.
Hodges is working
on the R-FID tag as we speak.
Stay tuned. What's up?
Uh, well, my union says
that I get two 15-minute
breaks and a half-hour lunch.
You give me something,
I'll give you something back.
Okay. How about a story?
Mmm, should I lay down?
Mnm, no, you're good.
I'm-I'm eating...
It's called
"Journey of the Mexican Cow."
Chapter One: "Ow!
My ear has just been pierced
with an R-FID tag."
Chapter Two: "All aboard!"
(Hodges imitates
a vehicle revving)
"Everything
you've ever wanted to know
"about my so-called bovine life
is encoded in my ear,
which is then uploaded to a
database as I cross the border."
I know what
R-FID tags do.
"Beep. Hola.
Howdy. I've just crossed."
Pshh.
"Now I've reached
my final destination."
Please tell me this story
has a final destination.
Yes, because our cattle
hauler's shipment,
including our
burger-on-the-hoof friend here,
reached the end of the line
at a feedlot in Pahrump.
When?
This morning.
Oh. Give it to me.
Moreno. Stokes.
We narrowed down
the search area.
We?
The truck's last known location
was a feedlot in Pahrump.
RUSSELL:
Listen to me--
I know you wanted
to catch the guy, but...
you did good work today.
You're bringing
this girl home to her father.
What do we even tell him?
Um... (sighs)
well, you know,
he's been looking
for his children for years.
Yeah, and now one of them's
dead, and the other's...
Wait. Hold on.
Mr. Flores? Hi.
I'm CSI Russell.
This is CSI Brody.
Hi.
I would have been here sooner,
but I was on a job.
HVAC replacement in Havasu.
They told me about Rosa.
I'm so sorry for your loss.
Where's Jacinta?
She's sedated.
The doctors say
she should recover
from most of
her injuries.
What do you mean,
"most of her injuries"?
Sir, she's...
BRODY:
You should know Rosa
did everything she could
to protect her sister.
Jacinta has been
through hell,
but it could have been
a lot worse.
She's a fighter.
Mr. Flores,
you need
to prepare yourself.
It's been 11 years.
Why? What happened to her?
Oh, my God.
(crying quietly)
Ah, that's so much time.
She's not a child anymore.
She... she's a young woman.
(crying)
(sighs)
Can I see her?
RUSSELL:
Actually, you know what?
Why-why don't we, uh...
why don't we let her sleep
for a little while, okay?
Let us buy you
a cup of coffee.
Yeah.
Come on.
(speaking Spanish)
(garbled radio transmission)
Where'd you find him?
I found him sleeping
in his cattle hauler
at a truck stop.
Take this piece of
trash to the box.
(man grunts)
I found these in the
cab-- .41 Mag ammo.
Same caliber as
the murder weapon.
Where's the gun?
Scumbag probably tossed it.
Who is she?
I found her hidden
in Ruiz's truck.
(siren wails,
garbled radio transmission)
(gasps)
You're safe now.
That guy's not going
to hurt you anymore.
We're collecting evidence
that could put him away
for a very long time.
STOKES:
But we need your help.
We know what he did...
to those girls.
And you do, too.
What he did to them, he
was going to do to you.
And he's going to do to
other girls unless you...
You're wrong!
He's a good man.
He would never
hurt anyone, ever!
How can you say that?
He's my cousin.
Your cousin?
He tried to give me
a better life.
I-I lived in Juarez,
and got caught up
with bad people.
Ollie offered
to take me north.
I never saw those girls before.
I didn't even know
they were in the truck.
Not until the accident.
I felt a jolt.
Then I heard voices arguing.
(indistinct shouting)
That's when I saw the girls.
They were running.
They were scared.
It wasn't Ollie's fault.
The other man ran us
off the road.
STOKES:
Was the other man
chasing the girls?
Your cousin told me
about the guy
who ran you off the road
last night.
Forget about
all the immigration laws
you've broken.
The ammo we found in your truck
put a hole through that girl
and killed her.
Now, if you don't start
talking, you're the one
that's going down for it.
It's as simple as that, man.
Oh, yeah, Ollie...
if I were you,
I'd listen to the man.
Habla.
I was just driving.
This car came out of nowhere...
forced me off the road.
This guy in a hoodie
comes out acting crazy.
Starts telling me,
"Where are the girls?"
I told him I didn't know
what he was talking about.
Then he grabs me.
I got scared.
I reached for the gun
underneath my seat.
Before I can do anything
with it,
he ripped it out of my hand.
He told me he'd kill me
if I talked to anyone.
Where did he grab you?
Interstate 238.
Just outside...
No, no, no.
I'm talking about
where on your body
did he grab you?
Henry didn't find any
secondary DNA on Ruiz's shirt.
I, however, did find
trace amounts of a chemical.
R-502.
Very unusual, rare...
Mind if I just...
Thank you.
A rare refrigerant used in
air conditioning.
Primarily older
HVAC systems.
Oh, my God.
Is there a problem?
Yeah.
The girl's father...
his business is HVAC systems.
(gunshot)
Hey, D.B. What's up?
What?
Where is she?
Oh, well, you just missed her.
She was discharged.
Her dad said he
was taking her home.
Why the hell would you pull
your uni off the door? The girl
is the victim of a predator,
and you basically
just sent her
right back to him.
Are you done?
You are going to be.
What are you going to do?
Run to daddy to complain?
Is that all you have?
No, I got a lot more...
Hey, Morgan.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Take it easy.
Detective.
Sir.
You want to walk me
through this?
Tell me what happened?
I can tell you
what happened...
Hey, stop.
Stop.
(sighs)
What your CSI
is not hearing
is that the father
is the legal guardian.
And the doctor is the one
who released the girl,
not me.
And this was at a time
when our number one suspect
was a cattle hauler,
not the dad.
You called the father
and actually had him
brought here.
And I accept
responsibility for that.
Unlike you
and the rest of the...
Hey, hey, you know what?
You guys
can work this out later.
Right now, we're dealing
with a textbook sadist.
If you think
he was taking it easy
on Jacinta before,
can you imagine what he's
doing to her right now.
So can we please focus
on how to find them?
Yes, sir.
Thank you.
Guy's driving a blue Taurus.
Arizona plates.
Got a broadcast out,
AMBER alert,
and have the PD staked out
outside of his house.
Look, he's too smart to go home.
I agree.
This is where he took her.
This is what we have to find.
OLLIE:
Yeah, yeah, that's him.
That's the guy
who took my gun.
And he's the one
who chased after those girls.
He's their old man.
He's been abusing them
for years.
He used your gun
to kill one of them.
And now he's
got the other one.
And she's going to be dead, too,
if you don't help me out here.
How can I help?
I pulled your truck log.
This is the route you took
from Juarez to Pahrump.
Stopped at a weigh station
in Fort Mohave.
The next one was Pahrump.
Now, between Mohave
and Pahrump,
your truck gained 220 pounds.
I thought the scales were off.
It must have been the girls
sneaking on.
And did you stop anywhere
between Mohave and Pahrump?
Yeah, yeah,
I stopped to eat
in Bullhead City.
The rave was here,
off Highway 238.
Tungsten mine is
three miles away.
And Bullhead City is here.
Which is where the girls
got on the truck.
We know they were
traveling on foot.
And they couldn't
have gotten
more than a couple miles.
So wherever the father
was holding them
had to be in the area, right?
So we're looking around here.
Which is still a needle
in a sandbox.
Except we do know
what we're looking for.
Jacinta drew it for me.
Flowers.
I just see a whole lot
of desert.
Maybe we're looking
for a house.
You know,
with a garden.
Or a farm.
One that's
harvesting wind.
Maybe Jacinta
wasn't drawing flowers.
You know this
is all your fault?
You got your
sister killed.
She was a good girl.
She didn't mouth off to me,
like you.
But we took care of that,
didn't we?
(helicopter blades whirring)
Nah, false alarm.
You think someone's
going to come for you?
It didn't have
to be like this.
But you ran away.
Right? Hmm?
You're the one
who broke up
this family!
And for what, huh?
Look where you are now.
You're back home with me.
I am the only one
who ever loved you.
(tires screeching)
(gun cocks)
MORENO:
Don't move, or I will
turn you to pink mist!
On your knees!
I smell gasoline.
STOKES:
Drop the lighter.
(lighter clicks)
Drop the lighter!
Jacinta!
STOKES:
Morgan, stop!
BRODY:
Jacinta!
Where's the key?
STOKES:
Morgan!
Search him.
He's got a key.
STOKES:
See if he's got
a key on him.
Don't worry.
It's going to be okay.
All right?
All right, we're going
to get you out of here.
You're going to be fine.
Let's help you up.
Let's go.
We got you.
Relax, huh?
(indistinct radio transmission)
All right?
Yeah.
MORENO:
Watch your head, okay?
Wouldn't want
to hurt you.
(sighs)
You know, for a CSI...
you make a pretty good cop.
Today, I think that honor
goes to our friend over there.
No doubt.
Your father
told the police that...
your mother ran off
with you and your sister
to Mexico.
He lied.
Is your mother dead?
She found out what he
was doing to Rosa?
And you were next?
Rosa wasn't
going to let that happen.
She was going to get you
as far away
from him as she could.
Your sister saved your life.
(sighs)
It's over.
You're safe now.