(various indistinct
conversations)
(glasses clinking)
WOMAN:
Happy birthday!
MAN:
MAN 2:
Thank you!
What's this?
I, uh...
took a total shot in the dark.
Please tell me I'm right?
Uh, yeah, actually, you are.
Well, in that case,
happy birthday.
How did you know?
You seem to be celebrating.
And I noticed how you keep
watching that party over there.
God. It's that obvious, huh?
Two forks.
Of course.
You can't eat
birthday cake alone.
All right, then, well,
I guess I should blow out
the candle, huh?
Unless you want me
to sing "Happy Birthday."
No. No, please.
Um...
Hope your wish comes true.
Thank you.
Excuse me.
Can we grab another bottle
and an extra glass?
Unless the party's over.
No. No, I'm not driving.
It's a present
to myself.
Day at the spa,
room at the hotel, dinner...
Why not? Treat yourself, right?
You deserve it.
(sighs)
Thank you.
You saved my night.
You were a definite upturn
in my night, as well.
All right, so, where to?
Twelve.
12 it is.
18 for me.
(bell chimes)
Well, this is you--12.
I know.
Suddenly, being alone
in my hotel room
doesn't sound
like that much fun.
(sighs, clears his throat)
(elevator bell dings)
Sara?
What are you doing here?
Checking out.
You spent the night?
Why are you here?
We have a body up on 18.
Homicide.
Oh, I'll ride up with you.
Just can't stay
away, can you?
(chuckles)
(sighs)
Happy birthday,
by the way.
(low, indistinct conversation)
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
(camera clicking)
Hey.
Thought you had the day off.
I need to talk to you.
Sure. Can it wait a second?
No, it can't.
Okay.
I know him--the victim.
What do you mean, know him?
I was in his room last night.
That room?
The one with the body?
I was having dinner downstairs,
he came up to my table,
I ended up in his room.
I was there an hour,
maybe a little more.
Nothing happened.
You need to sit down
with a detective,
and give him a statement,
tell him everything.
Every detail.
(camera shutter clicking)
(indistinct radio communication)
(sighs)
Taylor Wynard.
Won't be going back home
to Carson City.
I count seven stab wounds,
but, uh,
no defensive wounds.
So he didn't put up
a fight, huh?
Maybe the first penetration
hit a vital,
took all the fight out of him.
(grunts)
STOKES: Which would mean
the next six was somebody
working out
some serious issues.
SANDERS:
Someone he knew, maybe.
He had company.
STOKES:
Lipstick says a lady.
Well, I'll scan
these fingerprints,
bounce 'em back
to Mandy,
see if anything pops.
Hey, what steak dinner
doesn't come with a steak knife?
Knife's missing?
Could be
the murder weapon.
Weapon of opportunity.
Means this wasn't
necessarily premeditated.
RUSSELL:
Guys...
we got a problem.
(phone chimes, blips)
Sara--prints on the wine glass
belong to Sara.
(chuckles):
Say what?
That's right.
Sara just told me
that she was here last night,
in this room.
That's all
I know right now.
But it doesn't
change anything.
We still work the evidence
like we always do.
SIDLE:
We left the restaurant
and went up to his room
around 10:00.
I was probably
there an hour.
We sat and talked.
That was it.
Are you sure
about that?
Your fingerprint
was on a wine glass.
Uh, it was about
the third bottle,
by my count.
It was my birthday.
So you were up in
his room for an hour,
and then,
the night ended?
Why? I mean, what happened?
Nothing happened.
Um...
I got a text, uh,
from someone wishing me
a happy birthday.
Someone?
The text was
from Gil Grissom.
Uh, that's your husband, right?
You already checked
my phone records?
So you got a text
from your husband,
then you ended
the night abruptly.
Now, your date...
Hey, he was not my date.
The guy... how did he react?
Was he angry?
Why would he be angry?
You're in his
hotel room.
There's been a lot of drinking.
He has to be thinking, you know,
this is headed to bed.
I don't know
what he was thinking.
But I went back to my room,
alone.
Okay, well, according
to the keycard reader
on your door,
that was at 11:15.
That sound about right?
(sighs)
Yeah.
Tell me about the
phone call at midnight.
What phone call?
You called the victim
at 12:04.
Your cell to his.
The call lasted
for eight minutes.
No... no, I didn't.
I checked the phone records...
remember?
So what was she doing
here, anyways?
It--it doesn't
even make sense.
I don't even really think
we should talk about it.
But I rode up
in the elevator with her,
and she didn't say anything.
Greg, I'm serious.
I really don't want
to talk about it.
All right?
Let's just
try and do our job.
(siren wails in distance)
Hey, come check this out.
SANDERS:
That's Sara's.
I recognize it.
CRAWFORD: After the phone call
that never happened,
what did you do?
I didn't do anything.
I was asleep.
I've been having
a little trouble at night,
so my doctor
prescribed some pills.
You took a sleeping pill?
On top of all that alcohol?
Yeah, I did.
The key card reader
on your door said
you reentered your room
at 2:49 a.m.
Crawford, that's impossible.
I never left my room.
Do you want to check
the log for yourself?
You see my problem?
It's your whereabouts
from midnight to 3:00 a.m.
(water trickling)
Well, this isn't
looking good.
Found damp towels
in the bathroom.
Hair in the drain is
definitely not the victim's,
but the length and color
are consistent with Sara's.
Okay, you want to process the
bed, or you want me to do it?
I'll do it.
Sheets are gone.
Greg, someone
removed the evidence.
Just a warning.
It's been a while
since I've stuck someone.
(laughs)
Hodges is the expert.
I don't think you want
to be around Hodges
and a sharp object right now.
How come?
He thinks I cheated on Grissom.
Might as well have cheated
on God.
In Hodges' eyes,
you pretty much did.
So, that's the general consensus
around here,
that I cheated
on my husband?
BRODY:
You know,
I never met Grissom.
He was gone before I came.
But the fact that I've
never seen him around...
I understand.
Morgan, nothing happened.
Okay.
Point is, I wouldn't judge
you if something did.
Once we run a tox screen,
we can extrapolate back to
establish last night's levels.
FINLAY: I figured he'd have
to be really good-looking
to get Sara's interest.
Do you mind?
You're talking
about people we know.
Are we Team Grissom
or are we Team Sara?
Which one are we protecting?
I see no reason why
we can't protect both.
Clearly, they're going
through tough times.
We should be respectful of that.
I wasn't not being respectful.
It just seems like people here
are a little more upset
about Sara's possible infidelity
than the fact that
she is a suspect in a homicide.
Is that the murder weapon?
I hope you can tell me.
It's from the hotel.
They've got hundreds
just like it--
but there was one missing
from the room service cart
in the victim's room.
Blade length looks
to be about right.
Handle would be consistent with
the hilt marks on the victim.
I'm as certain as I can be
without having
the actual weapon in my hand.
Well, we will try
and get that for you.
Hodges?
Ah-ah-ah!
Do not come in here.
As far as this lab
is concerned,
you do not exist.
Look, I know you're
angry, but I...
Oddly enough, this is not
a matter of my feelings.
It's purely practical.
I've just spent
the last three hours
scrubbing any and all hint
of you from this lab,
so as to eliminate
the possibility of
contaminating any evidence.
You enter here, I have
to begin all over again.
So you're not mad at me.
I didn't say that--
I merely said that's
not why I barred you
from my lab.
Okay, well, you know,
I actually came here
to tell you what happened.
And taint my objectivity?
Let's let the evidence speak
for itself, shall we?
FINLAY:
Hey. How you holding up?
I'm not sure.
I--I've never been in
this situation before.
How can you tell?
Yeah, well,
don't let Hodges
be the determining factor.
Do you think Nick and
Greg are back yet?
I--I feel like I really
need to talk to them.
Sara, go home.
You need some distance.
I should be here;
I need to help.
You can't; you know that.
Just get out of here.
Go home, take a bath,
do something to take
care of yourself.
Really, this is the
last place you should be.
(alarm keypad beeping, blipping)
(shower running)
(remote beeps,
mellow instrumental music plays)
(clunk, then low whirring)
(low whirring continues)
I--I don't know
how it got there.
You know, I wanted
a glass of water,
and I noticed that the
dishwasher was running,
so I opened it...
So it was running
when you got home.
Maybe.
I wasn't paying attention.
Nick, somebody
is screwing with me.
Who?
I have no idea.
SANDERS:
I checked the entire house.
No sign of
forced entry.
Well, who else has a key
or knows your alarm code?
You guys, Grissom, that's it.
Look, somebody was here.
I mean, it was probably
the same person that
killed Taylor Wynard.
If that's true, I'm sure
we'll find evidence of it.
What do you mean,
"if that's true"?
Relax, okay?
We're on your side here.
But you also need
to be on our side.
Remember how we said
we're a family?
That means that
we have to start telling
each other the truth.
What are you talking about?
Found this in
your bedroom.
What is it?
Photos.
RUSSELL: So this is you
and Taylor Wynard, right?
I'm having trouble
with you lying to me
like this, Sara.
I didn't lie to you.
It was... an omission.
You can spin it
any way you want,
I still got a problem with it.
Yeah, but this proves what
I've been talking about.
Okay? Someone else
is behind this.
Sara... you knew the victim.
You know how bad this looks.
At the time,
I didn't think it was relevant
to what happened at the hotel.
Well, when did you meet him?
When was this?
Two weeks ago, it was
the first and only time
that I saw him, and when he
came to my table last night,
it was a complete surprise.
What's going on?
Come on.
Pills, alcohol--
this is not you.
STOKES: Yeah, according
to the tox report,
ten hours after the fact,
your blood alcohol level
was still .03.
And your sleeping pills,
the zolpidem,
point-nine milligrams a liter.
That's impossible.
Not point-nine.
I--I took a single
five-milligram
sleeping pill--there's no way
that it could metabolize
for ten hours and
still be that high.
That's not the point.
It's your behavior
that's worrying me.
I mean, you lied to me,
you lied to him.
And I know
it's not my place
to comment on your
personal life, but...
You mean my cheating
on my husband?
Truth is, he's not
my husband anymore.
Why? What happened?
Ask him--I'm sure he had
my best interests in mind.
So...
yeah, I--I've been
struggling a little bit.
All right, well,
if anything changes,
I'd appreciate a call.
Thanks.
No sign of the
missing bed sheets.
They were probably thrown
in with the hotel laundry,
in which case,
they're as good as gone.
Mm. Well, if this is
the murder weapon,
there's no way
to know for sure.
Pheno came back negative.
There's no blood,
no tissue... nothing.
Could have all
been washed away.
Yeah.
Well, I guess we can say
that it's consistent
with the murder weapon,
and that it was found
in Sara's house.
Well, she didn't kill anybody.
It's no crime
to not want to be lonely.
I just finished
processing the hair
from the victim's
shower drain.
It's a positive match
for Sara's.
Okay, so she showered.
Why lie about it?
All right,
would you still
think it was a lie if she
didn't remember the shower?
Sara had a considerable level
of zolpidem in her system--
a sleep drug
that is associated
with all sorts of bizarre
sleepwalking behaviors.
Yeah--
sleep-eating, sleep-driving...
Almost always,
the subject doesn't remember the
event afterwards.
Okay, so you're suggesting
that Sara sleep-showered
and doesn't remember?
I am suggesting
that if that's the case,
we have to consider
any other sleep-acts
she might have
been capable of.
Murder--
certainly a possibility.
Incidentally,
don't you think
that one of us
should call Grissom?
No.
One of us
should not call Grissom.
STOKES:
I wish you would've
said something
about you and Grissom
splitting up.
He's so revered around here,
there's no way that I
don't come out looking
like the bad guy.
Come on, I would've
drank with you.
That's my necklace.
SIDLE: Why is my necklace
on the monitor?
Sara...
Nick, did you
find that necklace
in the hotel room?
Sara, you shouldn't
be seeing that.
Nick, listen to me, okay?
I wasn't wearing
that necklace last night.
That necklace was at my home
in my bedroom.
You heard what Russell
just said--now, come on.
Just tell me--did you
find that necklace
in the hotel room?
Yes.
Now, come on, let's go.
Come on.
SIDLE:
Ronald Basderic.
Been terrorizing Edie
for six months.
I tried to help her
get a restraining order,
but the judge denied it.
MAN:
Edie, is that creep
still stalking you?
SIDLE:
You terrorized her.
You kept her awake at night.
She was afraid
to walk home.
It's because of you
that she stayed,
and now she's dead!
I know it's you, Ronald.
You wanted me
to know, right?
That's why you left
the necklace?
I honestly have no idea
what you're talking about.
The necklace that Edie gave me.
Because I helped her
when she wanted
a restraining order
against you.
You watched every move
she made back then.
I'm sure you were stalking her
when she bought it, right?
You really don't
look well, Sara.
I wonder if you're
not experiencing
an unusual amount
of stress lately.
I'm worried about you.
You killed a man, Ronald.
Why?
Why did you do that?
Because I helped Edie?
Because I...
because I stood up to you?
But you were wrong
about me then, Sara.
What makes you think you're
not wrong about me now?
You've been following me;
you've been stalking me.
You took
those pictures.
You somehow arranged for Taylor
to be at the hotel.
And did I somehow make
you go up to his room?
Did I force your
infidelity on you?
Stay away from me.
Speaking of which,
have you called
your husband?
Have you told him about the
tough day you're having?
Tell you what,
let's do it together.
I have his number right
here on speed dial.
(speed-dial beeping rapidly)
(phone clatters across floor)
You're not gonna walk away
this time, Ronald.
That's a promise.
Hey, um...
am I out of my mind, or are you
hiding evidence from me?
Well, we're definitely not
hiding evidence from you,
so it must be
that other thing
you just said.
Yeah, I just found out
that you've recovered her hair
in his shower drain.
Which we only just
confirmed for ourselves.
And we told you.
What about the knife?
She had the murder
weapon in her home.
We don't know that's
the murder weapon.
I know this detective badge
may be new,
but I've been a cop
long enough to know
how to read between the lines.
That's the difference
between what you do
and what I do.
I don't read between
the lines--I stay
with the evidence.
And right now,
there's no evidence
that says that Sara
killed Taylor Wynard,
only that she was
in his room.
In his room,
having an illicit affair...
under the influence of alcohol
and prescription drugs,
lying about her activities.
Look, there you go,
between the lines again.
Look, I am not gunning for Sara.
I do not want a CSI
to be guilty.
But I want to try to protect
the rest of you guys as well.
And I keep thinking,
if this were anyone else,
we would've made
the arrest by now.
SIDLE:
It's Sidle. I told the la...
S-I-D-L-E.
I'm with
the Las Vegas Crime Lab.
I need the phone records
for Ronald Basderic.
No, you see,
I don't have the warrant,
but if you get me
his phone records,
I will get you
an administrative subpoena
as soon as I'm back
in the office.
How about that?
I have to call you back.
(knocking on door)
Hey.
Akers.
Uh, you need to
come with me, Sara.
What's going on?
Just... grab whatever you need,
please, and come along.
MAN:
What are you gonna do?
CRAWFORD: Any possibility
you're overreacting?
She was waiting for me.
She stalked me.
She came to my work.
Just...
♪ ♪
(sighs, clears throat)
There he is. Crawford.
Where is she?
You processed her?!
I had to.
She got herself
on camera this time.
(door opens)
Greg, I--I never
touched him.
He's setting me up--
he set me up
at the hotel,
and he's setting me up now.
SANDERS:
Why were you even there?
Russell tells
you to go home
and you go
to Basderic's workplace?
I know. I--I screwed up, okay?
Yeah.
But I'm telling you
that Basderic is the one
behind this, okay?
He left Edie's
necklace because
he wanted me to know
that it was him.
Where's the rest of it?
That's all there is.
There's only the one camera.
But, Sara, the D.A.
has more than enough
to charge you with.
You were clearly
the aggressor here.
No. Look at that!
No, he knew
exactly where to stand
for the camera.
He--he...
he lured me to that spot.
The only physical contact
that I had with Basderic
is on that video.
Then how did he get
those injuries?
Greg, how long
have you known me?
You know
I didn't do this.
RONALD:
She's unstable.
I can't be the only
one who sees that.
And yet she's permitted
to carry a gun and a badge.
Does that seem wise?
Before today, when was
the last time you saw CSI Sidle?
Not since the last time she
falsely accused me of murder.
The massacre at Frank's Diner.
Where I lost my Edie.
Is that what she did today?
Did she accuse you
of murder?
Yes.
Someone at a hotel.
To be honest, I didn't
follow everything she said.
She seemed
disoriented and confused.
And what about
right before
the altercation?
Do you remember
what was said exactly?
Are you asking
if I provoked her?
Is that her defense?
That this is my fault somehow?
I asked her to
leave me alone.
She persisted.
Feeling threatened, I pulled out
my phone and called 911.
That's when she attacked me.
Hey. How's she doing?
Honestly, I'm a
little worried.
(sighs)
STOKES:
She's got to be struggling
over this breakup with Grissom
and just not talking
about it, you know?
Feeling isolated
from the rest of us.
Yeah, so she goes
and she beats the crap
out of Basderic?
Well, she says she didn't do it.
Her clothes
are helping her case.
I just examined them--
there is no hint of trace
or any transfer evidence.
Well, there you go.
After the beating Basderic took,
that would be impossible.
Yeah, which means
Basderic is lying.
He probably beat himself up.
You know, Sara thinks
that Basderic committed
the hotel murder;
that the whole thing
is an elaborate setup
aimed at her.
Let's start talking
about what that would take.
If Basderic wanted
to pull this off--
kill Taylor Wynard and
frame Sara,
what would that require?
You would have to know that Sara
was gonna be at the hotel.
Well, that wouldn't
be that hard to do.
She made the reservations
online a couple of weeks ago.
You just got to hack
into her e-mail.
Okay. What else?
He'd have to be able to get
in and out of her house,
and her hotel room,
while she was still in there.
And... he would have to arrange
for the victim to be
at that hotel as well.
SANDERS: All right, assuming
that Basderic is the one
who took those photos, he knew
about their previous encounter.
STOKES: I mean, it's been
four months since
Frank's Diner--he's wanted
to get back at her ever since.
And who better than a crazed and
obsessive sociopath to do it?
He set her up.
There's got
to be evidence of it.
Yeah, we just
have to find it.
Thank you...
for whatever strings
you pulled to get me
out of here.
Wasn't me.
Thank Basderic.
(scoffs)
He's not pursuing charges.
He does have this
for you, though.
Restraining order.
Mm-hmm.
You're kidding me.
Sara, you're out.
That's a gift.
Now just... take it
and stay away from him.
RUSSELL:
Gun, I keep.
You're on leave
until the department
can figure out
what to do with you.
And, Sara, next time
you're struggling
with something, anything,
come talk to me.
It's important for both of us
you know you can do that.
(phone chimes)
Sorry, look, I--I got
a bunch of messages here
from the care facility
that looks after my mother.
In San Francisco?
No, no, I moved
her down here
about six months ago. Although
I don't see her any more often
than I did
when she was up north.
Oh, great--she got her hands
on a bottle of alcohol.
She's in the hospital.
Just what I needed.
Hi, uh, I'm looking
for Laura Sidle.
Thanks.
Sara.
Hi, Mom.
Oh, sweetie.
I'm so sorry.
Mom, you can't
be drinking,
you know that.
You know what happens
when you start.
You can't drink like that.
I'm sorry.
I really am.
I know.
(sighs)
I know you are.
I pray and pray for you.
All the time,
so that you wouldn't
turn out like me.
Mom, I'm fine, okay?
Just--just rest.
Just--just try
to rest right now.
But what about the man?
What man?
At the hotel.
You killed him.
You stabbed him.
Just like I stabbed your father.
Who told you that?
Who did you talk to?
Your friend. Ronald.
He's very nice.
So sweet.
♪ ♪
(whirring)
(computer blipping)
Hey.
What's up?
Hotels have a device
that allows them
to override the keycard slot,
and according
to the log,
someone did exactly that
and entered Sara's room
just before midnight.
Which means the killer
could have taken her phone,
and would explain the midnight
call she said she never made.
Then it would
let the killer
steal the key
to re-enter the room later.
He's taking a big risk
though, with her asleep.
I mean, what if she woke up?
Well, if she did,
she has insomnia on a level
the world has never seen.
I tested Sara's
sleeping pills.
They had been
tampered with.
Super-sized,
if you will.
They contained more than double
the prescribed dosage.
Safe to say,
she was knocked out.
So Sara was set up.
Now we just got to prove
that it was Basderic.
BRODY:
Hey, take a look at this.
These are
the shower drain covers
from both Sara
and the victim's rooms.
The micro-scratches on the drain
covers don't line up
with the surrounding rings.
But... when I swap them...
Look.
SANDERS:
A perfect match.
That's how Sara's hair got
in the victim's room.
Someone swapped
the drain covers.
All right, my turn.
So these are video stills
from hotel surveillance
the night of the murder.
BRODY: All right,
what am I looking for?
This guy. Right here.
Now, he seems to be
in all the right places
at all the right times.
Yeah...
but with that hat and
those glasses, it's hard to say.
It could be anybody.
True.
But check this out.
Here's Basderic
leaving work, the same day.
Now, look at the shoes.
Atlantic Oxfords.
And notice the pants?
There's a coffee stain
or something right there.
Now, if we
compare the two...
BRODY:
Same stain, same clothes...
same guy.
Nice.
Which means now
we can put Basderic in the hotel
the night of the murder.
STOKES: Question is,
what does he really want?
I mean, why would he plan it out
the way he did?
Well, he's obsessed with Sara--
he wants to get back at her
for belittling him
for stalking Edie.
STOKES:
Okay, but what's
his endgame?
If he just wants
to frame Sara for murder,
he could've left
the bloody knife
at her house-- then she
really would've been screwed.
Instead, he washes it off. Why?
Same reason
he didn't press charges
for the assault.
He doesn't
want her locked up;
he wants her out.
Which means
he's not done with her.
And I think I know why.
Russell, during
the Frank Steiner murder
Sara and I turned up
a previous court case
that involved Basderic.
I remember, civil suit--
he collected damages
after somebody
assaulted him, right?
The point is
that Basderic drew the guy in.
He harassed and stalked his wife
until the guy
finally came after him.
Then Basderic shot him
in self-defense.
Now, Sara already
has the restraining
order against her.
And she's on record
for having assaulted the guy.
So if she goes after him,
he could legally shoot her
and get away with it.
That is the revenge
that he's after.
He doesn't want to frame her,
he wants to kill her.
Where's Sara now?
I don't know.
She won't answer her phone.
(keypad beeping)
(phone buzzing)
(buzzing)
(engine roaring,
siren whooping)
(tires screech)
Another ambush
by Las Vegas's finest?
No, we just want to have
a friendly conversation, Ronald.
Is that a weapon
you're carrying?
The gun is registered.
I have a permit
to carry it.
I'm gonna have to relieve you
of it anyway.
Just...
while we're talking.
Make sure nothing
goes sideways,
nobody gets hurt.
We know you were at the hotel.
Well, that's awfully vague.
Am I supposed to know what
you're talking about?
You know exactly what
I'm talking about.
Last night, when you stabbed
Taylor Wynard to death.
And you have
evidence of this?
Or am I supposed
to just...
offer up a confession?
Is that why
you're here?
No.
I'm here to give you a warning.
If you hurt Sara...
She attacked me.
I'm the one who
has to be worried.
Maybe we should
take you in.
We could hold you
for your own protection.
That won't be necessary.
Next time--
should there be
a next time--
I'll be ready.
Next time's with me.
I'm free to go, am I not?
Nick...
I won't let you hurt her.
Can I have my gun, please?
You be careful with that.
(engine revving,
tires squealing)
SIDLE:
Leave the light off.
What do you want?
What do I want?
I'm gonna stop you.
I didn't want to do this.
I didn't want
to come here.
But you made me,
Ronald.
You discredit me at my job,
you get me arrested,
you go after my mother?!
You don't really think
you can get away with this.
I don't really care.
Somebody needs to stop you.
You have ruined
so many lives.
And now I'm gonna ruin yours.
(gun clicks)
Don't bother.
I removed the firing pin
when I was in your house.
Don't worry,
I'll put it back.
After.
This is exactly what
you wanted, isn't it?
You planned all of this right
down to this minute right here.
Well, at least now
you can appreciate
what I went through.
The months of planning,
the attention to detail.
Did you even notice?
Seven stab wounds.
I stabbed him seven times,
just like your mother
stabbed your father.
You're sick, Ronald.
I watched you, Sara.
I read your e-mails.
I witnessed
your adolescent groping
outside the bar.
You know, I had
to pay Taylor to meet you
at the hotel?
I told him we were
friends, that I didn't
want you to spend
your birthday by yourself.
I even sprung for the dessert.
And now I get to kill you.
Just do it already.
(three rapid gunshots)
You're done, Ronald.
This time for real.
What did I tell you,
Ronald?
I said I won't let you hurt her.
Blanks.
You switched my ammo.
No, he did.
Must be yours.
Guess I, uh, got
mixed up somehow.
CRAWFORD:
There you go.
Yeah.
Right. Come on.
Ugh! No!
I do not need
that damn chair.
I can walk just fine.
Well, I know, Mom, but
the hospital has rules.
Since when were you one
to follow rules?
What was it you
used to tell me?
If, um... somebody
wants to do
something nice for you,
why get in their way?
I did say that, didn't I?
All the time.
You were full of good advice.
Too bad I didn't take
any of it myself, right?
Oh... (groans softly)
There are so many things
I wish... I had
done differently.
And most of them, I...
I can't change now.
But one thing I...
would like to try
and change...
is the way
things are between us.
Maybe we could...
visit once in a while.
(sniffles)
I just want you to be okay.
I'm fine.
I'm great.
I think people would
understand if...
you want to take
some time off.
No, I'd rather get
right back in.
You sure?
Where else would I want to be?
Okay.
(pours coffee)
Little late for an intervention,
don't you think?
Well, I just...
I just thought...
We.
We... just thought
that it might be a...
good idea to talk.
SANDERS:
Or listen.
Whatever you prefer.
Have a seat.
I didn't mean
to shut you guys out.
I didn't tell you
about Grissom and me
because I didn't
believe it myself.
You know, we made that
dinner reservation together
before we split up, and...
as I sat there alone
in the restaurant...
...I honestly expected him
to show up.
I think that we all
like the idea...
of you two being together.
And maybe it was because
that was our way
of--of hanging on to him
just a little bit, you know.
But if it's over...
it's over.
Hey, you can't sit
around waiting forever.
STOKES: And you'll
always have us.
(laughs)
(Stokes laughing)
Like it or not.
Thank you.
Thank you
for not giving up on me.