All right, we are in
the processing room.
This is the center
of the slaughterhouse.
This is where Walter Simms
was finally killed
in a shootout with the police.
And this is where we are going
to try to contact his ghost.
(clattering)
I definitely sense
a presence in here.
A very strong presence.
Yeah, my whole body
feels strange.
Hair on my arm's standing up.
I'm gonna roll my EVP recorder,
see what we get.
Walter Simms, are you here?
Come on, Walter.
Talk to us.
You still lingering?
Relishing the seven
sadistic murders you committed?
I'll tell you what I'm sensing.
It's the boys.
Their pain.
God, do you feel that?
I know the terrible
things you went through,
but it's okay.
No one can hurt you now.
Guys, uh,
I'm gonna go in the room
where the boys were held.
Maybe it'll be easier
to make contact in there.
Okay.
I'm gonna set up for some
EMF measurements. Doug.
You want to go check out
the hanging room?
All right.
(device beeping)
It's been 20 years, and still,
the feeling in this place,
it's...
it's hard to describe
other than to say it feels...
...heavy.
This is where Walter Simms
did his dirty work.
I want you to show yourself,
Walter.
Make yourself known.
Maybe this will entice him.
Yeah, that's right.
Just like the one you used
to butcher those boys.
Why don't you come and get it?
It's right there.
Or are you too afraid
because I'm not some
defenseless little child?
(metallic jingling)
The hooks are moving.
(jingling)
He's here.
(jingling continues)
(screaming)
(screaming continues)
Owen! Owen! Owen!
It came from this way.
Where's Doug?
Where is Doug?
(screaming continues)
(screaming stops)
(woman whimpering)
WOMAN:
Are you okay? Owen?
(panting)
(whispering):
What is that?
(Carrie screams,
Owen yells)
(screaming continues)
(siren wailing)
Really cheery place.
Yeah, yeah,
tell me about it.
I spent a lot of time here
working on the original case.
What do you mean,
original case?
Oh, uh, 20 years ago,
the security guard,
Walter Simms--
he lived in a
trailer on-site.
This guy, Simms,
abducted seven boys
over a nine-month period,
brought them here
and killed them.
Mmm.
And I mean
really grisly stuff.
So he ended up
dying here himself.
After escaping
his sentencing hearing,
he shot it out
with the PD.
So you're saying
that this homicide
is related to the
original case.
Yeah, the victim tonight
is rigged up
just like the boys were.
The hook,
the evisceration--
exactly what Simms did
20 years ago.
You know,
if I didn't know any better,
I'd say that old Walter
was back from the dead.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
PHILLIPS:
I remember I was
in sixth grade
when all this was going on.
Walter Simms--
called him "The Butcher."
Of course, we didn't know
it was Simms at the time.
We just knew
that kids were disappearing.
Kids... my age.
And even after
Simms was killed,
his legend lived on.
They say that if you say
his name three times,
he'll come back to life
and gut you.
Maybe that's what happened
to our victim.
Let's try it.
I'll conjure him up.
You slap the
cuffs on him.
Walter Simms.
Walter...
Don't! If you want to do that
sort of stuff,
you could do it when I'm gone.
Let's go.
Oh, you can really see
why this place spawned
so many ghost
stories, huh?
Oh, yeah. This place creeps
me out in all kinds of ways.
Slaughterhouse...
This is why
I stopped eating meat.
Yeah, really.
So, no murder weapon?
No. Smear is from one
of the victim's partners.
They're the ones
that found him.
The male slipped
and fell in the blood
trying to get the victim down.
Did our people touch this?
No. You think
it's been moved?
Well, there's blood
on the bottom,
but it wasn't in the blood pool.
There's no memory card.
Somebody must have taken it.
Hold up your arms.
Okay.
I mean, man, this is just crazy,
you know?
I'm gonna need you to give me
your clothes at some point,
since you fell in the blood.
Yeah, sure.
I got others in the car.
I mean, God, I just
can't believe this.
I mean, seriously,
Carrie, can you?
So, uh, how long have you been
doing this... ghost hunting?
I don't know.
I've always been sensitive,
you know, to... things
from the other side.
But working with Doug
and Owen-- that's new.
A few months, maybe?
And you were filming
for some TV show or something?
No, it's, uh, for
the Internet, mostly.
A lot of people do this.
They upload videos.
It's... it's
really nothing.
Well, it's not
nothing anymore.
I mean, holy crap,
if we have definitive proof
of the spirit world
crossing over like this--
I mean, are you kidding me?
Owen, just stop!
Doug's dead.
(sighs)
You don't really think
your friend was killed
by a ghost, do you?
You haven't been inside,
have you?
I've been in a lot
of haunted places,
and I've never felt
anything as strong
as what I felt in there.
That's why I wear this.
It's always
protected me.
(footsteps approaching)
I'm gonna ask you
one question.
Then I'm gonna give you
one chance to answer it.
Where's the memory card that
was in your friend's camera?
I don't know what you mean.
He was filming, right,
with the camera?
So where's the memory card
that was in it?
I... (scoffs)
Okay. I'm gonna have
to confiscate all of
your shooting equipment.
No, wait.
Okay, okay, uh,
I-I took it, okay,
but I-I need it.
I mean, what if Doug
actually filmed his killer?
Yeah. What if?
I'm Captain Jim Brass,
Las Vegas Police.
You the property manager?
Thomas Pope.
My firm is developing
the property.
So you've been told
what happened?
Just that somebody was killed.
One of the ghost hunters.
Oh, so you knew
they were here?
Yeah, yeah, they had permission.
My boss approved it.
I handled the paperwork.
They signed about a million
liability releases.
Thank God, right?
I guess.
Look, I... I didn't mean it
to sound like that. I...
Can I ask what
happened exactly?
We don't know yet.
You know, I warned my boss
that something bad
was gonna happen.
I knew it.
What do you mean, you knew it?
I spent some time inside here.
There's a feeling.
A feeling?
So you people take
all the time you need.
The minute you're done,
I'm knocking the whole
place down-- the building
and all the ghosts inside.
Hey, Doc.
A little shorthanded,
are you, today?
Normally, you
don't call me in
until you're done
with all the scary stuff.
Normally, but I wanted you
to see something
on the victim David brought in
from the slaughterhouse.
Heard the murder was reminiscent
of a previous crime.
Well, that's why you're here.
The killing
wasn't just reminiscent.
It was an exact duplication
of the original crimes.
So, killer did
his homework, right?
I don't see how.
The original victims
were all juveniles.
Their autopsy reports
were very closely guarded.
They were never made public.
And the M.O. unique enough that
it couldn't just be by chance?
I would say not.
The incision
the killer made--
it isn't a straight cut
like a butcher
or a hunter would make
when dressing an animal.
It waivers
to the left, to the right,
and then back again.
It's almost as if
he was carving an "S."
"S" for Simms.
Seems like every town has
a place like this that all
the teenagers know about.
Yeah, their parents don't.
Obviously, it's not
impossible to get in here.
Which means our ghost hunters
may not have been alone
last night.
Morgan.
Come look at this.
It's a shrine.
To the seven boys
who were murdered here.
Some of this stuff looks
like it's been here forever.
Yeah, and some of this stuff
looks like it's...
pretty new.
Someone's been coming
here and making
offerings to these kids.
Or to their ghosts.
What?
Did you hear something?
No.
No, it's nothing.
BRODY:
Hey.
Did you notice...
if our female ghost hunter
from earlier
was missing
an earring?
SANDERS:
No.
That's not hers.
Makes me wonder whose, then.
So, let's say you're the victim.
It's dark.
Your back is turned.
You're filming.
I swing this hook hard enough
to bury it in your back.
Well, that would be more
than enough to incapacitate me
so you could hoist me
up into the air.
And then it's just a single
slash with the blade.
Yeah. So there's no reason
it couldn't have been
one person working alone.
All right, let's Luminol
everything, make sure we didn't
miss any blood.
(phone ringing)
It's for you.
Do you want it? SFPD.
I'll call them back.
I'm gonna hit the lights.
Okay.
Whoa.
Oh, my God.
There's blood everywhere.
Must be animal blood.
This is the kill room.
Floor must be
porous enough
that the blood
is still present.
I'm going to go do the hallway.
Finn?
Yeah.
Come here
and look at this.
Wow. Everybody's
going in and out,
tracking the old animal blood
without even knowing it.
There's the wheel marks
from David's gurney.
Mm-hmm.
And look over there.
There's one set of prints
going the other way.
The hall dead-ends.
Where would they be going?
Looks like they walk
right through the wall.
Or right up to it.
There's got to be some reason
whoever left these
came down here.
There's something in here.
Yes, there is.
Hey. I think Hodges
caught us a break.
Check this out.
What am I looking at?
You're looking
at footage from one of
the ghost hunter's cameras.
The surviving male,
Owen Webber.
Now, according
to his statement,
he was alone in the processing
room during the murder.
Which it looks
like he is, right?
Well, keep watching there.
You see that?
You mean that little glitch
in the picture?
That's more than just a glitch.
His camera shut off
for 98 seconds.
That might be enough time
to commit the murder.
That's more than enough time.
(knocking)
RUSSELL:
Oh!
Look at you. You got
yourself a murder weapon.
It was stashed just outside
the murder room.
Killer probably planned
to go back and get it later.
What makes you say that?
Well, because he didn't bother
to wipe off his fingerprints.
You got prints?
Victim's partner. Owen Webber.
Well, it's about time.
When am I gonna
get my gear back?
You're not gonna
get your gear back.
What?
Well, your gear
is what we now
call evidence, Owen.
Well, I know that it's evidence.
That's why I need it.
The online paranormal groups
are going nuts
over what happened to Doug.
I need the proof.
I need to show them
that it was Simms.
Sit down.
And let's talk
about what you did to Doug.
STOKES:
You recognize that, Owen?
It's mine.
I brought it along
to the slaughterhouse.
Sounds like premeditation.
Uh, no.
I-I... I brought it
to excite the spirits.
We use objects,
something
emotionally significant
to the dead to provoke them.
I mean, come on, man,
that's Ghost Chasing 101.
That's Murder 101.
What?!
Why else did you
turn off the camera
right before Doug was killed?
I didn't turn off the camera.
My battery pack went dead.
Don't you check your batteries
before you start?
Yeah, of course I did.
And they were both full.
But spirits can siphon
the power away.
That's how they get the energy
to materialize.
Come on, Shaggy.
My BS meter is redlining
with all this ghost science
of yours.
What BS?
The knife
provoked Walter Simms.
The battery
provided the energy
he needed.
The very fact that Doug is dead
is proof positive
of what I'm telling you!
Owen didn't kill Doug,
I'm telling you.
Because you
believe a...
ghost killed Doug?
Because I know Owen.
He would never.
Well, right now,
the evidence says otherwise.
You went into the
slaughterhouse, didn't you?
(sighs)
You know now
what I was talking about,
those little boys...
The only thing
I felt in there...
was cold.
If you'll excuse me.
Why are you denying your gift?
Your grandmother is still
with you, you know.
Even though you try to push
her away, she's still there.
What do you know
about my grandmother?
She had a funny name.
(chuckles)
Olaf, was it?
And she was a psychic.
Seems to think you are, too.
You share her gift.
What do you want from me?
Your help.
You heard those boys.
I know they were trying
to say something.
I-I just don't know what it is.
I'm sorry,
but I can't help you.
Thanks, but...
I don't want that.
You need it.
ANDREWS:
What are all these?
Tools of the trade
for the modern ghost hunter.
E.M. pump,
motion sensors,
thermal imager, EMF detectors.
Ghost Meter Pro? Really?
Someone actually makes these?
That's not a toy.
I just spoke with Nick.
Apparently the interrogation
was less than fruitful.
He's hoping that we can find
a way to pinpoint
the exact location
of the suspect
during the time of the murder.
But both his cameras
were off, right?
His cameras were off, but
his EVP recorder was still on.
EVP?
Electronic Voice
Phenomenon.
Ghost voices we might
otherwise miss.
The point is, even though
we don't have picture,
we have sound.
Ah. And you think
you can use the sound
to figure out
where the suspect was.
That is the idea, yes.
So, why do you need me?
You mean, aside from the fact
that I greatly admire your mind
and abilities?
The job requires going back
to the slaughterhouse,
and that is something
that I don't relish doing alone.
Hey, Jules?
Do you got a moment?
Sure.
Want you to introduce
you to Scott Tunnicliff.
CSI Finlay.
Nice to meet you.
Scott's kind of
an expert
on Walter Simms
and the slaughterhouse murders.
Wrote a book
back in the day.
Ah. You working on a sequel?
No, actually, I brought him in.
He had considerable access
to the investigation
at the time.
My uncle was...
undersheriff, so admittedly,
I got... special treatment.
But I brought along
all my old
raw research material
if it'll help.
Tell her your
theory, Scott.
I've always felt, uh,
Simms had an accomplice.
Uh, someone to help
lure the boys into the car.
RUSSELL:
Yeah, look at this.
This is a photo
of Simms.
That's a real boogeyman.
Yeah, not
really a face
that kids would flock to.
There were witnesses
to three
of the abductions.
The statements were the same.
The boys approached
Simms' car,
climbed in
on their own accord.
So, might be Simms had help.
FINLAY:
Who's this woman?
She's in every trial photo.
She was a trial groupie.
Showed up every day,
never took her eyes off Simms.
Was obsessed with him.
RUSSELL:
Why?
What do you see?
Her earring.
It looks exactly
like the earring
Morgan found
at the slaughterhouse.
If it is, she was there.
So, where is she now?
(shouting)
How was that?
HODGES:
All right,
do it again.
This time, a little higher
like on the recording.
(higher-pitched shouting)
All right, I think you nailed it
on that last one.
Pretty sure we can pinpoint
where Owen was now.
Yeah.
No way he was the killer.
He was in this room
when the murders happened.
Of course, that means
that our killer
is still on the loose, right?
(chuckles)
(gasps)
(sighs)
How'd we do?
I hope you got
what you needed.
My throat
is killing me.
Well, we cleared
Owen as the killer.
Did you see all this
low-end activity
running through
the center?
Yeah, it's some sort
of low-frequency wave.
Seems to be present
everywhere in this place.
But we can't hear it
because it's...
Because it's below
the human range of hearing.
It's infrasound.
Can you, uh, pitch it up?
Raise the frequency
until we
can hear it?
Mmm.
(low, rumbling tone)
Yeah. You know, there are
studies that actually suggest
that infrasound could be the
scientific cause of hauntings.
The vibrations create sensory
phenomena suggestive of a ghost.
Fascinating. Yeah.
Mm-hmm.
You'll have to show me
those articles some time.
We could test the theory now,
by finding the source
of the low-frequency waves
and eliminating it.
Science!
Wow. Who's the crazy?
Ah, you can tell
right away, right?
This woman was obsessed
with Walter Simms.
Mmm.
She was at his trial
every single day.
Yeah, we've dealt
with a few women like this.
I'll never understand it.
So, I think she could be
our killer.
But there is no record
of her name.
I did a facial recognition
search against our database,
and I got nothing.
Why not try running one just
against Internet images?
She didn't hide from
the camera before.
Why should she be
any different now?
All right, let's run it.
Who knows?
You know, maybe she's...
turned her life
around by now.
That one.
Monica Downs.
Wow, she even has a
Friend Agenda page.
Hmm.
20 years has done nothing
to cure the crazy.
The basic theory
behind infrasound
is that, even though
we can't hear it,
it still has a physiological
effect on us.
The low frequency waves
cause vibrations
in different parts
of our bodies.
(beeping)
Getting stronger.
I hear some other
noises, as well.
Here, this way.
Okay.
So, as a result,
people experience
butterflies
in the stomach, chills,
hairs standing on end...
Check, check and check.
Not realizing
there's a physical cause,
people attribute
all these sensations to...
...a haunting.
Feeling's getting
stronger here.
Definitely oppressive.
Yeah.
This is it. This is what's
generating the infrasound.
Oh, well, here's an idea:
Let's turn it off.
Uh...
(fan whines)
(chuckles)
That's amazing.
The oppressive feeling's gone.
The chills, the stomach...
It's gone, right?
Yeah.
All these years,
the sensation everyone's had
that this place is haunted...
It's perfectly benign.
There's nothing
bad here at all.
(woman screams)
Aah!
WOMAN: No! No!
(metal clanging)
Okay, what is that?
Oh, no, nothing bad
can happen here.
There's no haunting.
It's just sound waves!
Shh.
This way.
We got blood.
ANDREWS:
Oh, God, it's one
of the ghost hunters.
Your infrasound
can't explain that.
Yeah, it's Hodges.
We need help.
So...
it looks like
she was sitting there,
in front of the shrine.
Killer surprised her, maybe.
Hit her as she
turned around.
The bat was here already.
You remember?
It was part
of the toy collection.
What I can't figure out
is why she came back here
in the first place.
She came because of the boys.
She told me she was still
hearing their voices.
She wanted...
to talk to them.
Well, she's talking
to them now.
We need to find out who else
has been coming here,
bringing all these toys.
Better bag them up
and get them to Henry.
What? What is it?
Her EVP Recorder.
Must have fallen
when she was struck.
CARRIE (over recorder):
I'm sorry for all
the horrible things
that were done to you.
What can I do
to bring you peace?
Please, I know you're here.
I can feel you.
Don't be afraid. Just reach out.
Talk to me. Give me a sign.
Funny, kind of looks
like you're...
waiting to hear an answer.
You don't know this about me,
but, uh...
when I was younger,
I used to be...
kind of psychic.
I know.
But my grandmother, she had it.
And I guess I inherited it.
(chuckles) Why have I
never heard about this?
When I became a CSI,
I felt like I had to choose:
science or...
the other.
I chose science.
So, now you've
reconsidered?
Yeah.
I mean, 'cause of Carrie...
and what I feel in this place.
But I-I thought the feelings
came from the infrasound,
the vibrations from
the ventilation fan.
Henry turned it off,
and since then,
I-I don't feel a
thing anymore.
That's just it.
I still do.
CARRIE:
I only want to help you.
That's all I want,
is for you to have peace.
Where did you... God, no...
(metal thuds, clangs)
(gasps)
(children laughing)
Did you hear that?
Yeah.
Sounded like laughter.
Like kids. No, play it again.
(Carrie screams)
(metal clangs)
(children laughing)
Ow. Ow.
You can't possibly
know what I know.
Blinded by the confines
of corporeal reality,
you're both woefully ignorant
of what waits on
the other side...
Got your trial groupie.
Ma'am, that's enough.
That was quite a ride.
For you.
Good luck.
She's a nutcase.
Yeah, a nutcase
with blood on her shoes.
Your shoes
and this shoe print
that we found
at the murder scene...
they match.
Match, match, three on a match.
And that's bad luck,
you know.
Want to talk
about bad luck?
You stepped
in a dead woman's blood.
(chuckles)
I remember you.
You do?
From Walter's trial.
I do.
How wonderful.
Now, do you remember being
at the slaughterhouse earlier?
I do.
I went to talk
to Walter and my boys.
Your boys?
Yes, that's what I said--
my boys.
My family.
The family that Walter
created for... us.
BRASS:
So, when when you
talked to Walter,
did he tell you to kill Carrie?
How about Doug?
(giggles)
BRASS:
Huh?
I didn't do that.
But I... I know who did.
You do?
He didn't know that
I was there watching.
Ticktock, like a watch.
BRASS:
Tell us
who you saw do this.
It was one of my boys.
Mine and Walter's.
Kids, you know?
I should probably
have a talk
with him...
if you'd like.
(children laughing)
Morgan said it was eerie.
She wasn't lying.
Yeah.
That came just after
the killing?
Yeah.
But listen.
(hiss, children laughing)
Now, I'm pretty sure
the laughter's real.
But it's prerecorded.
How do you know that?
Watch the screen
as I play it,
and I'll freeze
the wave form.
(metal clangs)
(hiss, children laughing)
Now, right there,
just before the laughter,
there's a high-frequency hiss,
almost, and then it
dies out immediately after.
(children laughing, hissing)
What is it?
Well, it's got to be the speaker
on whatever device is playing.
It powers up
just a fraction of a second
before the sound comes out.
So the killer played a recording
of children laughing
just after the murder?
That might be even sicker.
♪ ♪
(machine beeps, whirs)
Hey, just finished
DNA analysis on the toys.
And?
I found DNA from
a single source
on every single one of them.
What about the murder weapon?
Same DNA, same as
the rest of the toys.
Let me guess.
It belongs to the psycho
groupie, Monica Downs.
Actually, no.
The source was an unknown male.
Suggests that Monica Downs
is not the killer.
ANDREWS:
It gets stranger.
Finlay gave me DNA
from the original investigation
of the Simms murders.
Cops collected one
sample from Simms' car
that was never identified.
Matched the DNA on the toys
and the baseball bat.
So we're saying the killer
was in Simms' car 20 years ago.
In the front seat of Simms' car.
All the DNA
from the boys
who were killed
came from the back of the car.
Well, it sounds to me
like we're back
to looking for an accomplice.
Certainly does.
A male,
obsessed with the crime,
enough knowledge of the details
to be able
to re-create them perfectly.
What do you think?
Yeah.
(chuckles)
Then come back here
and rub our faces in it.
Well, his alibi checks out.
He said he was at
a book signing,
he was at a book signing.
What about the DNA?
Sent it to Henry,
but I'm afraid it's only
gonna confirm that...
he's not our guy.
Oh, hell.
Well...
(both sigh)
I still like our theory.
Looking for the old accomplice
in the current murders?
I mean, we know he's a male.
We know he was
in Simms's car 20 years ago.
What we don't know
is where he is now.
Exactly.
All right, just-just play
with me for a second.
Monica Downs said that she saw
Carrie's killer, right?
That it was one of the boys.
Monica Downs is crazy.
The boys are dead.
All right, all right,
but what if they're not?
Russell, the cops
found all seven bodies.
What if there was
an eighth?
(sighs)
What-what if... what if Simms
abducted an eighth boy
and forced him
to be his accomplice?
Cops finally catch up
with Simms and put him in jail,
boy runs away.
Which means he might
still be out there.
(clears throat)
What are those?
Missing persons reports
from 20 years ago.
When Simms was
snatching up kids.
Yeah.
I found three other boys
that disappeared within
that timeframe
who were never accounted for.
Well, only one of them
has a photo.
Yeah, as far
as the other two go--
uh, Brian Oden grew up
on the streets.
There were quite a few homeless
that reported him missing.
And Jonathan Harris
grew up in foster care.
Everybody just thought
he ran away,
including PD.
FINLAY: So, any one
of these could be
Simms' eighth victim,
our so-called accomplice.
How do we I.D. him and find him?
FINLAY:
This kid was
in Simms' car.
Okay, his DNA is in there.
He must have left prints.
But PD ran the prints
20 years ago.
Yeah, but he was a juvenile,
so he wasn't in the system.
You're right.
Got to be over 30 by now.
Maybe that's changed.
Hey.
Where are you going?
If anybody's
looking for me,
just tell them I had to
step out a little while.
You going to the slaughterhouse?
I thought
we wrapped all that up.
The place is about
to get torn down.
If I don't do this now,
I'll never get the chance.
Greg, what do you really expect
to find there?
I don't know.
Maybe nothing.
Or maybe I'll be able
to reach out to Carrie,
and with her help,
maybe to the boys.
You know how that sounds, right?
Yeah. Crazy.
But it doesn't matter.
I have to do this.
♪ ♪
Here we go.
Got a hit on the
set of prints
from the glove box
in Simms' car.
What's the date of birth?
June 8, '81.
Means he was 11 at the time.
Okay, so this has got
to be our eighth kid, right?
SARA:
Scroll down.
Wait a minute. I saw him.
Where?
At the slaughterhouse
that first morning,
talking to Brass.
Well, who is he?
He manages
the property.
Thanks again for coming
down to let me in.
I really appreciate it.
No problem.
(door creaking)
After you.
You know, in a couple of days,
this whole place will be gone.
Bulldozed
to the ground.
The building,
everything inside.
What were you
hoping to find?
(sighs)
I don't really know.
Well, but you're here.
Right?
You must have some idea.
You want to talk
to them, don't you?
(children laughing)
Sorry. It's, uh,
my kids' ringtone.
It's my wife calling.
Don't.
Just drop it!
Haven't enough people died here?
BRASS:
Thomas Pope-- family man,
wife and kids, good job,
an education, but that's only
half of who you really are.
See, Thomas Pope
is an invention.
You made it up.
He doesn't exist before
about 12 years ago.
Your real name is
Jonathan Harris, isn't it?
When you grew up,
you were passed
from one foster
home to another
until one day
your luck really went bad
and you were abducted
by Walter Simms.
No, you're wrong.
You're mistaken.
Well, we found your DNA
in Walter Simms' car,
along with your fingerprints.
We're not wrong, Jonathan.
We know who you are.
I am not Jonathan.
I am not that damaged
little boy, not anymore.
I know you feel responsible
for those other boys,
the ones who were killed.
Isn't that why
you still bring them toys?
You were 11 years old.
You were a little boy yourself.
It wasn't your fault.
But they won't let me forget.
They blame me.
They torment me.
And I can't make
the voices go away.
You were there.
You had to have felt them.
Tell us about the ghost
hunters, Doug and Carrie.
I didn't want them inside.
I tried to tell my boss
that it was a bad idea.
Why was it a bad idea?
Because I knew
what would happen.
I knew that they
would learn my secret.
I have worked very hard
to get past everything
that has happened
and build a new life.
If they found out,
I would lose everything,
everything that I have
built as Thomas Pope.
But I-I mean,
how are they gonna find out?
Who's gonna tell them?
From talking to the boys.
The ghosts of the boys?
I couldn't let them talk
to the boys.
Hey.
Do you have a minute?
I do.
Uh... back before
I came to Vegas,
I worked up in San Francisco.
I helped put away this
guy-- true sociopath.
He posed as a cop,
pull women over at night,
sadistically assault them.
We found 17 victims.
I suspect there were more.
You're talking
about Lyle Brinks, right?
Yeah.
I had no idea
you were a part of that.
He's up for parole.
The cop that I worked
with-- she's worried that
he actually stands a chance
of release.
Okay. What can I do?
I need a few days.
I-I... I want to be there.
I want to testify,
make sure that doesn't happen.
I understand.
You got it... but,
you know, while you're
up there, do me a favor.
You know, take some time off.
It's been a rough
couple of months.
You deserve it.
(laughs)
Okay.
Hey.
Great job today.
That must have been
really scary.
I'll tell you,
when I heard that laughing,
I sure as hell wasn't laughing.
(laughs)
You know, I... I think I owe you
an apology from earlier,
implying that you
were crazy.
You know, as much
as this is our universe,
surrounded by science every day,
I still like to think
there's room
for a spiritual side.
Well, no apology necessary,
but it's accepted.
Thank you.
But who knows?
I mean,
maybe you're right.
Maybe this whole
thing is crazy.
What? Why you saying that now?
Well,
when I was at the slaughterhouse
with Pope,
I was doing everything I could
to hear or feel anything
from Carrie
or the boys, and
I mean, there I was
with the killer standing
right behind me,
and none of them bothered
to send up a signal,
or a-a single
ghostly warning sign?
(laughing):
Yeah.
Yeah, you would think, right?
But I think...
someone was looking out for you.
You made it out of there okay.
(sighs)
Let me buy you breakfast.
Deal.
But I'm driving.
Of course you are.
Let's go.
(locker door creaking)