MAN (over radio):
Foxtrot 1-5-Tango, L.A. Center.
Please clarify your situation.
Foxtrot 1-5-Tango,
do you copy?
please respond.
Hey, Gil, just wanted
to hear your voice.
It's kind of a slow night here.
Give me a call
if you get a chance.
MAN:
Las Vegas Approach,
L.A. Center.
Be advised you have
inbound traffic.
They are not responding.
MAN:
Roger that, L.A. Center.
I've got him on radar.
Do you have any idea
of his intent?
MAN:
He radioed an emergency,
said he was inbound.
No contact
for almost 12 minutes.
MAN:
Foxtrot 1-5-Tango,
this is Las Vegas Approach.
Low-altitude alert.
Climb immediately.
Repeat, climb immediately.
(cell phone buzzing)
(phone vibrates)
WOMAN (on video): It's crazy!
All these lights--no wonder
you can see this place
from space.
Oh, my God!
Did you see that?
(video turns off)
This was shot
about 40 minutes ago,
right before
a charter aircraft
nosed into the ground
at Tresser Park.
That's just a mile
off the Strip.
This is NTSB investigator
Doug Wilson.
He's gonna be leading
the crash investigation.
You-you two guys
worked together before, right?
Yeah.
On an NTSB crash scene
when I worked
at the San Francisco Crime Lab.
Right now, we have
very little information.
Where did the flight
originate?
LV Regional Airport,
heading for Chicago.
18 minutes out,
the pilot reported
an unspecified emergency,
turned the plane around,
and after that, radio silence.
RUSSELL:
From the moment
it turned around,
made a beeline for the Strip.
And almost, as you
just saw, slammed
into the Mediterranean
Casino Tower,
missing it
by about half a dozen feet.
So you're thinking
this wasn't an accident?
I'm not sure.
But it's certainly a mystery
why the pilot
stopped communicating
with the tower,
why the plane nose-dived
near the Strip,
what happened
on that plane.
All questions
we need answers to.
Answers we're hoping you CSIs
can provide through evidence.
RUSSELL:
So, was it
an accident
or foul play?
This is what we need
to find out.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
MAN (recorded):
Vegas Approach,
Foxtrot 1-5-Tango.
Got a situation here.
Requesting permission
for immediate return.
Boy, it's not a lot to go on
for a distress call.
That's what I thought,
until I enhanced the audio.
(recorded): Vegas Approach,
Foxtrot 1-5-Tango.
Got a situation here.
Requesting permission
for immediate return.
MAN 2:
Hey, where the hell are you...?
There's another voice
in the cockpit.
Sounds agitated.
FINLAY:
Yeah.
Could be a hijacker.
So far, we've
only found one body
in the cockpit wreckage.
It's got to be the pilot.
FINLAY:
Keith Mannheim,
co-owner of LVM Charter.
Well, we also found
additional remains.
How many bodies?
Can't say.
With a charter plane this size,
there's no requirement
for a passenger manifest.
As for how many were on
the aircraft and who,
well, we're gonna need
your help with that.
NTSB has secured
the crash site, right?
Nick and David Phillips
are coordinating
the recovery
of human remains.
They're already on scene.
Morgan and Greg are heading out
to collect personal effects.
Could help
with identifications.
Right.
What about the black box?
Still haven't
recovered it.
Was about to head back to the
site; could use some help.
Two of you have worked
together before--you probably
have your own shorthand.
It's a good idea.
All right,
let's get to work.
Lot of eyes on this.
We need answers.
SANDERS:
You know, I think
I should drive this time.
Thank you.
Oh, 'cause you're
scared of going
more than 20 miles per hour?
Hojem-Sanders!
I was hoping I'd see you!
Hey, Donna.
What are you doing here?
Are you looking for me?
Me, actually.
Which means you
must be Morgan Brody.
Yes. Hi. I am so sorry.
We just got a call out,
and I completely forgot
about our appointment.
Appointment?
How do you two...?
Doc Robbins
recommended Donna.
He was blown away
by your genealogy
work on his family.
You said on the
phone that you had some
family history for me?
I did, and it's
on my desk.
But...
I'm so sorry,
we have to get to a crime scene.
Oh, that's all right.
You go do what you have to do,
and I'll work here.
Believe me, there's
a lot of Brodys out there.
Oh, Brody's actually
my stepfather's last name.
I'm interested in Ecklie.
Oh, your biological
father. Of course.
Don't tell me.
You still trying to prove
he's not your dad?
(laughs)
Uh, just kidding.
Christmas is coming,
and I want to get my dad
something special,
so I thought maybe
a family crest.
How wonderful. Okay.
You go do your thing,
and I'll get to work here.
(quietly):
Thanks.
(chuckles softly)
Ready to roll?
Just about.
Just like old times, right?
(laughs)
Very old times.
Heard you, uh,
married your boss.
What's his name again?
Gil.
Right. Grissom. Bug guy.
You still married
to what's-her-name?
Candy?
Candy, right.
Yoga instructor.
No, no, we...crashed
and burned years ago.
Yeah, I didn't see that coming.
Yeah, you did.
Just like old times.
Hey, Doc.
How's it going?
Hey.
What do you
got for me?
On the left gurney
are the remains
from the cockpit.
In front of me
and on the right,
remains recovered
from the passenger cabin area.
PHILLIPS:
And we ran DNA
on a small sample
of those remains.
Turns out
we have one Jane
and two John Does.
So in addition
to what I assume
is our pilot,
we have three
unidentified passengers.
(whirring)
PHILLIPS:
Looks like I've got
something here.
Take a look.
ROBBINS:
Looks like a T-10
or T-11 vertebra.
What's that?
Part of the fuselage?
David, hand me
that, would you?
Yeah.
Hmm, looks like shrapnel.
Surrounding tissue appears
deteriorated--
this guy was in pain.
And over a long period of time.
Just a second.
(beeping)
Radioactive?
As I suspected.
I think
I know how we
can identify
at least this victim.
(jet engines whining)
Dalton Burk?
Not a good time
right now.
We're from
the crime lab.
We're here investigating
the crash.
Crime lab?
I don't understand.
What happened was
an accident, right?
STOKES:
Well, that's
why we're here.
There was no passenger manifest
filed for the flight, so...
'Cause Keith was
flying solo--VFR.
He doesn't need to;
there were no passengers.
FINLAY:
Well, we found three
other bodies in the wreckage.
That's impossible--
Keith was alone.
Told me he was
flying home
to visit his folks
for a few days in Chicago.
I'm sorry, man.
I think he told you wrong.
FINLAY:
Can you explain how
three other people might get
on your plane
without you knowing?
Keith and I are
business partners.
We each focus on different
aspects of the company.
Normally, I do
the booking,
but obviously he must've booked
some passengers on his own.
Why are you asking me
all these questions?
Is there something
you're not telling me?
When you say Keith
was your business partner,
how well did you know him?
Well, it's not any
of your business,
but we were a couple.
We were together
for the last 15 years.
So if it seems
like I'm not in the mood
to talk right now, you're right.
We're really sorry
for your loss.
We do need to confirm
that one of the bodies
that we found
was indeed Keith's.
STOKES: So, if you could
get us a toothbrush,
a hairbrush, anything that
might have Keith's DNA on it,
that'd be great, okay?
Yeah, I'll get that to you.
SANDERS:
Yeah, you're gonna love Donna.
She's awesome.
She totally got me hooked
on genealogy.
She seems cool.
I found this mixed
with the personal effects.
Take a look.
Looks like a section
of airplane carpeting.
Yup. Melted around something.
Whoa, I got a gun.
It could be our hijacker's.
Can you hold this
open for me?
(camera shutter clicks)
Nine-millimeter Beretta,
receiver's torqued.
Damage from the fire.
Three rounds left
in the magazine.
Someone could have fired it.
And I think
we might know who.
Shrapnel in one
of the victims
turned out to contain
depleted uranium.
You mean, like from
a battlefield?
So the guy's a vet?
Right, and the V.A.
had X-rays on file
matched to a Charles Harrigan.
Made headlines last year,
when he got into a fight
and got tossed out
of the Mediterranean.
Yeah, he, uh, gambled away
his home, his car,
his wife--
he blamed the casino.
Camped out in front
to keep people from going in.
Maybe commandeering an airplane
and trying to crash it
into the casino
was his form of revenge.
That's what I'm thinking,
so let's run the gun,
see if it traces
back to Harrigan.
All right.
Flight data recorder's intact.
Wish we had the cockpit
voice recorder too.
Yeah, join the club.
They're not required
for smaller charters.
Hey, did you hear
that the Rusty Nickel closed?
(laughs)
Well, that's about time.
That bar gave dives
a bad name.
What are you talking about?
You loved that place.
Well, yeah, you're right,
I did love it, right up until
the moment that they
kicked me out for life.
(clears throat)
They did do that.
Yup.
Okay, moving on.
So, we have
the primary flight display up.
SIDLE:
It should show us everything
on the instrument panel.
17 minutes into the flight,
airspeed is 250 knots,
altitude is 29,800 feet
and climbing,
heading is 50 degrees--
all normal.
Looks like there's a slight
decrease in cabin pressure.
Pilot's turning around,
making a descent, looks
like he's putting in vectors
to return to the airport.
(alarm blares)
What the hell just happened?
WILSON:
Massive depressurization.
30,000 feet,
virtually no oxygen,
temperature is 34 below.
They were dead before
they even hit the ground.
The plane just
kept going.
Vector entries
kept it on course
all the way to the ground.
Barely missing
the Mediterranean Tower.
Mm-hmm.
Why the depressurization?
Gunshot, maybe.
We know there was
a gun on board.
A bullet hole alone wouldn't
trigger that kind of event.
This was instantaneous,
catastrophic.
Like a bomb?
Bomb would've taken out
the avionics and hydraulics.
Plane wouldn't have
stayed on course.
All right,
what's left, then?
Uh, maybe a window
blew out, or a door.
Whatever it is, it had
to fall to earth, right?
Extrapolating
from their position
at the time of depressurization
and factoring in their
altitude and their velocity,
I mean, I can zero in
on their location.
Always the physics major.
I tell you what,
I'm going to take my physics
and I'm going to find whatever
fell out of your airplane.
And what about me?
What do I do?
Well, you're going
to build me a plane.
WILSON:
Well, you found the door.
Still don't know
what happened.
Let's go with
our gunshot theory.
We're traveling
at 30,000 feet.
I'm Harrigan.
I am going to take
over the plane
and I'm going to fly it
into the Mediterranean.
Payback for
bankrupting you
in one night
at the tables.
I pull my nine-mil
and I start for
the cockpit.
But one of the other
passengers sees you.
Jane or John Doe.
Tries to overpower you.
And we struggle
for the gun.
(mutters):
We're struggling.
In that struggle,
the gun goes off,
hitting the cabin door.
Would explain the initial
slow loss of cabin pressure.
And then Harrigan breaks free...
(clears throat)
commandeers the plane.
Pilot only has time
to radio once
and turns the plane around.
It was what Harrigan
wanted anyway:
to return to Vegas
on a suicide mission.
Yeah, and what he
doesn't realize
is that the cabin door
is already compromised.
Bullet must've hit
the door somewhere.
I'm not seeing anything.
No holes, no marks.
Must be missing something.
Just saying.
Maybe the bullet hit
a cabin door seal
and compromised it.
I got something.
Bullet hole?
No, but I think our inside job
just turned into
an outside job.
Tool marks
on the outside edge.
This door was
tampered with
before the plane
even took off.
Sabotage.
We've been looking
at this the wrong way.
Maybe the motive
wasn't hijacking.
Maybe it was
straight-up murder.
So the plane was doomed
before it even took off.
WILSON: Yeah, somebody
on the ground
made sure of that.
Tampered with
the cabin door seal.
The seal couldn't handle
the increasing pressure,
and finally the
door blew out.
We're talking murder now,
not hijacking.
Somebody on that plane
was targeted.
WILSON:
We've got our pilot,
Keith Mannheim,
and our other three
remaining passengers,
but so far we've only
identified one:
Charles Harrigan, the man
we thought was our hijacker.
You know, if he got into a
squabble with the Mediterranean,
maybe he got into a fight
with someone else,
somebody he shouldn't have.
Yeah, it could have put
a target on his back,
or maybe the target's
just one of the
other passengers,
our John or Jane Doe.
There is one
other possibility.
What's that?
Maybe the plane was the target.
HODGES:
Didn't see this
on the outside of the door.
Must have gotten wedged
in the seal.
Got paint trace
from what I hope is our
outil de sabotage.
It's all yours.
So this, uh,
NTSB guy, Wilson.
Seems like
a good sort.
He is.
When you guys worked
together in Frisco,
were you, uh...close?
Well, it was a pretty
lengthy investigation.
We spent a lot
of time together.
Yeah, there's spending time
together, and there's...
spending time together.
What are you getting at,
Hodges?
I--I'm not getting
at anything.
How's it going in here?
Well, the
Mikrosil's ready.
Good.
Good cast.
No bubbles.
You can see
the tool marks.
Helps if you get in close,
doesn't it?
Is that...is that
paint transfer?
Indeed.
Don't you have, like,
a machine to go put that in?
Say no more.
Three's a crowd.
Come and knock on my door.
(crashes)
What's his problem?
Don't even get me started.
These marks are paired.
I'm thinking that the tool
might have been two-pronged.
You can tell what kind
of tool it was?
No,
but between the Mikrosil cast
and the paint chips,
if we find it,
we should get a match.
You know, whoever tampered
with this cabin door
knew exactly what
they were doing.
Too much damage
and the plane wouldn't
have pressurized at all...
Setting off a warning
light in the cabin.
The pilot would've turned
the plane around immediately.
Too little damage would've
had no effect at all.
Saboteur had to
get it just right.
Suggests an intimate
knowledge of the plane.
STOKES:
Hello!
Are you Hal?
Yeah, I'm Hal.
Yeah, the same Hal that,
uh, did the maintenance
on that charter jet
that went down last night?
I--I already gave
the logs to NTSB.
Look, I'm good
at what I do.
I checked and double-checked
every system on that plane.
Well, we're not saying that an
oversight caused it to crash.
No, we're saying
somebody brought it down.
FINLAY:
Can you tell us
about your relationship
with LVN Charter.
Yeah, my relationship is fine.
Been taking care
of their plane
ever since I left Beaufort.
FINLAY:
When was the last time
they paid you?
Yeah, it's been a while.
Been a while? It's been,
like, four months, hasn't it?
They owe you over six grand.
Hey, look, I'm not going
to sabotage a plane
over a lousy six grand.
These are your tools, right?
Yeah, they're my tools.
Well, you certainly have
an interesting way
of marking them.
Helps me keep track of them.
Green color is the same that
we found on the cabin door.
What? You're saying
somebody
messed with the plane
using my tools?
No, we're wondering
if maybe you messed with it.
I didn't mess with it,
all right?
I been in Laughlin
the last couple of days.
I got back this morning.
Yeah, well, I'm packing
up your tools.
They're coming with me now.
These tools are my livelihood.
Hey, you maintain a jet
that took a nose dive
into the ground last night,
I don't think your phone's
ringing off the hook.
Is it?
Sorry.
Quick question.
I'm having a little trouble
searching your
father's surname.
Did you ever see it
spelled E-K-L-I?
Actually, yes.
I think my grandfather--
I've seen him spell it that way.
Brilliant. I knew it.
Uh, I have
a question for you.
In your genealogy work,
have you heard of ITS Labs?
Indeed I have.
ITS is a DNA lab in Dallas.
Their business
specializes
in do-it-yourself
DNA analysis
in paternity suits.
Paternity suits?
Mm-hmm.
The lab mails you a DNA kit,
you do your own swabbing.
Wrap it up
and mail it back.
Answer comes
in a couple of weeks.
There's no name
on the return label.
Well, for confidentiality,
they use serial numbers
to identify the client.
Look at the shipping label.
Great. With a warrant,
I might have Jane Doe's I.D.
You may also have motive.
I'm sorry. I couldn't
help but overhear
about the plane
being sabotaged.
You know
that paternity suits
are particularly contentious.
Contentious enough
to make Jane Doe our target?
I remember hearing about
a fast-food franchise mogul
who fathered a child
with his secretary,
and when she tried
to prove paternity
and get child support,
he, uh, dunked her
in the fryer.
I'm just throwing it
out there.
I'm just going to give
this to Henry.
(cell phone buzzes)
You can take that.
I'll come back.
No, that's all right.
I--I'll call him
back later.
If you ever feel like talking...
You ever tried
the long-distance thing?
No, but I think it
would have helped
my relationship
with husband number two.
Ah, the Seattle ex?
Yeah.
What was that like,
seeing him again?
It was weird.
And then it wasn't.
You know, I wondered why
you took a later flight.
What about your NTSB guy?
Is that weird?
Very weird.
(both chuckling)
Gonna stay that way?
It has to, right?
This looks promising.
Similar tool marks
as the sabotage
that we found
on the cabin door.
Can you pass me those, uh,
paint chips that Hodges found?
Sure.
Thanks.
Got a physical match.
Got a murder weapon.
But not a murder suspect.
Hal the mechanic's alibi
checked out.
Eye in the sky
at the Lucky Stakes Casino
in Laughlin
had him at the tables
three nights in a row.
So Hal's off the hook.
But somebody helped
themselves to his tools.
Yeah, someone who had access
to the airport.
Surveillance hasn't
come in yet,
but maybe we'll get lucky
and find our killer on it.
Well, in the meantime,
we have a lead
on our other
John Doe.
The gun's not
registered to Harrigan
like we thought.
It's actually registered
to a Jeffrey Forsythe.
He's a partner
in a law firm downtown.
Brass called the office.
Apparently, Forsythe
wasn't on the plane.
Maybe he knows who was.
Mr. Forsythe, we matched
the serial numbers on this gun
found at the crash site
to you.
It's your gun.
I leant it to my colleague,
my friend Grant Abbott.
He was on that plane.
Our firm uses
LVN Charters exclusively.
Grant told me he was flying
to Chicago last week.
He used to live there,
still has a place.
He'd decided to take
a little time off.
Why?
Same reason he was
carrying my gun.
Grant is the go-to
criminal attorney at our firm.
He represents
numerous clients
with, uh, proclivities
to violence.
Did Mr. Abbott have any concerns
about any of these clients
in particular?
I can tell you
that Grant
had a misunderstanding
with one client,
who subsequently
fired our firm
and made veiled threats.
I'm going to need that name.
RUSSELL:
Donna, I've heard
so much about you.
It's a pleasure to meet you.
The pleasure is mine.
Donna was helping me
with my family tree,
but now she is helping
us with a case.
We found a DNA kit
in our Jane Doe's luggage.
Thanks to Donna, we were
able to trace it back
to a private lab.
They gave us a name.
Jordan Lowell,
Chicago address.
Requested a kit
two weeks ago from ITS Labs.
What's that about?
Well, we think she may
have been looking
for proof of paternity in
a potential child support case.
Jordan Lowell may
have had a baby
with the wrong kind of guy.
Okay, do we know if
she used the, uh, DNA kit?
BRODY:
It looks that way.
Henry's running the swabs now.
If the victim was
able to obtain
an exemplar from the father,
you could have
the DNA of the killer.
We could. You're right.
Then again, I just
got a call from Brass.
Turns out that the passenger
with the gun
was a criminal attorney who may
have disappointed a client.
Hey.
Yeah?
You're not going
to believe this.
A lady in Henderson returned
home from a business trip,
found some dude
floating in her pool.
So?
He came from the plane.
There was another
passenger on board?
No.
According to the
driver's license,
he was the pilot,
Keith Mannheim.
So if he's our pilot,
who's the dead guy
in the cockpit?
Doc, I thought we
already found our pilot.
Please, make sense
of this for me.
I'll try.
Prints and DNA
both confirm this body--
the one pulled out
of a pool in Henderson--
is our pilot.
Keith Mannheim.
Victim has a distinctive,
crescent-shaped head wound.
Looks like some sort
of blunt-force trauma
unrelated to the rest
of his injuries.
The skin tearing and fractures
are both consistent
with a high-altitude fall.
RUSSELL:
All right, what about
the other remains that
we found in the cockpit?
Well, now that we know
it's someone else,
Henry's running the DNA.
So we have a mystery man
that we found in the cockpit
who's not the pilot.
How the hell does that work?
SIDLE:
So, we got five people
on the plane.
If our pilot,
Keith Mannheim,
is at the controls,
then our mystery man
from the cockpit wreckage
must have been sitting
in the copilot's seat.
Two in front,
three passengers in back.
17-minute mark, we have
the slow loss of cabin pressure.
Mannheim radios
he's turning around.
Maybe the pilot wants
to check something out.
Maybe that's why he
gets out of his seat.
Yeah, but not before
Mannheim enters in
the vector coordinates
for a return.
Making a slow descent.
A few seconds later,
door blows.
And Mannheim gets
sucked out the plane door.
Doc Robbins said
that he had
a crescent-shaped
head wound.
Looks like he hit his head
on the way out, huh?
Uh-huh.
One mystery solved.
One step at a time.
SANDERS:
Hey, guys.
Uh, Henry ran the DNA
from our mystery man
through CODIS,
and he got a hit.
A parolee named
Thurston Mayfield,
aka Thor.
Thor?
Specialized in writing
phony checks,
and recently was a dancer
in an all-male revue.
Now, the club is just two blocks
from the executive airport.
Brass talked to the owner.
It turns out that
Thor quit last week.
He said he was moving in
with his new boyfriend,
Keith Mannheim.
WILSON:
That would explain why Thor
was sitting up front
in the cockpit.
Keith was flying his new
boyfriend home to Chicago
to meet the folks.
And if Keith's partner
Dalton found out about it,
might be reason enough
to want them both dead.
STOKES:
You know that guy?
No.
Classic case of
"I didn't recognize him
with his clothes on."
How about now?
The place where he dances
is right out by your airport.
Yeah, I guess.
I--I've been there
a few times times with Keith.
Yeah, old Keith, he went there
a lot on his own, didn't he?
What does that mean?
FINLAY:
It means that we
talked to some
people at the club,
and it, uh, turns out
that Thor and Keith
were having a thing.
It was kind of
hot and heavy.
Well, if that's true,
I didn't know about it.
STOKES:
Suppose you didn't know
that Thor was on that
plane, neither, huh?
With Keith?
Cockpit, right by
Keith's side.
He was flying home
to meet Keith's parents.
FINLAY:
Yeah, it must suck
having your partner
cheat on you
with someone like this.
That would really
piss me off.
You know, maybe just enough
to actually do
something about it.
(scoffs)
You think I brought down
my own plane
with the most important person
in the world to me on board?
Well, the way I see it,
the plane's insured, right?
I mean, with Keith
out of the way,
you can start
the business over,
and this time without
having to share the profits
with some cheating
boyfriend.
Fuel log says
that you refueled
and performed
the last safety check
on that plane 12 hours
before it crashed.
I didn't sabotage
my own plane!
In the heat of anger.
I get it.
No. No, you people
don't get it.
I lost everything
in that crash.
Everything.
Looks like you got
the airport surveillance.
Yeah.
Sugar, no cream?
Thanks.
Mm-hmm.
WILSON:
Anything?
Nothing yet, but I did confirm
Burk refilling the plane
and doing a safety check
12 hours before takeoff.
He never touched
the plane door,
and so far, nobody else
has touched the plane.
WILSON: Listen, Sara,
I was just wondering
if I could buy you
and Grissom dinner tonight.
You guys pick the place,
NTSB picks up the tab.
I'm a hell
of a third wheel.
Actually, Gil's out of town.
Okay, just the two
of us, then?
Don't.
Don't what?
Do this.
Okay.
I mean, if everything's
good between you two--
and I know you, Sara,
so I'm getting the feeling
that maybe it isn't--
then, I understand.
Everything's great.
Okay.
Fuel truck--stopping
in front of the plane.
Right in front of
the cabin door.
What's he doing?
They already refueled.
One guy's getting
out of the truck.
(taps key, video blipping)
He was only there
for two minutes.
Is that enough time
to sabotage a plane?
Yes, it is.
Can you get a better
look at the driver?
I can't bring up
a face.
But look at this.
WILSON:
Beaufort Aero Club patch.
Those are Hal's overalls.
And we know that
Hal was out of town.
We know that somebody
borrowed his tools.
Borrowed his clothes,
as well.
(whirring)
ANDREWS:
I got your results.
DNA on the coveralls did not
match Dalton Burk, so...
goodbye prime suspect.
Sorry. It's a dead end.
Were you able to run
the ITS DNA kit
that Morgan found
in Jordan Lowell's luggage?
Yeah. Jordan used
two of the swabs,
but both were degraded,
probably from the crash
and the fire,
so I couldn't get DNA.
The weird thing is,
Morgan said she thought
this all had to do with
a paternity suit.
Right.
But to do a paternity test,
you need to use three swabs.
Yeah, you're
absolutely right.
One for each of the parents,
and one for the child.
So what was Jordan Lowell
testing for, then?
Most people use ITS
to verify the baby's father,
but a lot of people use it
to find their own father.
Do you think that's
what Jordan Lowell was doing?
I know that's what
she was doing.
Just got off the phone
with her roommate in Chicago.
Turns out Jordan was raised
by a single mother.
After her mother died,
she started looking
for her father that
she'd never met.
Her roommate said
she got a lead in Vegas.
Donna, you think this
is something you can
help us with?
Give me a birthplace
and a birth date.
Right there.
DONNA: Well, we'll start
looking for the father
by searching for
Jordan's birth certificate.
RUSSELL:
No name for the father.
But that makes sense.
That's who she was
looking for, right?
DONNA:
Look at the mother's age.
Fifteen.
DONNA:
Back in 1968.
There were a lot of strict rules
about what unwed mothers
could put on
the birth certificate.
They could only give the baby
their own surname.
But the rules only applied
to the baby's last name,
so sometimes the girls took
the father's surname
and made it the baby's
first name.
You mean like "Jordan."
Mm-hmm.
Sounds like
we should be looking for
a Mr. Jordan in Las Vegas.
Morgan, did Jordan's
roommate ever mention
if she used
a genealogy Web site?
Yeah, actually, uh, she said
she used ancestry.com.
Great!
Ancestry not only helps people
find their relatives,
but if it finds two people
who are searching
for the same relative,
it connects them.
So if we input the same
information that Jordan did,
the we'll be able to find
what she found.
DONNA: Let me just link
into Jordan's family tree.
And there he is--
Jordan's father.
"Joseph Donovan Jordan."
Looks like she found him,
but a little too late.
Died December 12, 2005.
Yeah, but look
below his name.
He had a daughter--
Helen, born in 1962.
RUSSELL:
Half-sister.
So maybe Helen is the lead
that Jordan found in Vegas.
Mm-hmm. And that's why
Jordan used the DNA kit.
She swabbed herself, so she
could compare her DNA
with that of her sister's.
I'm looking up
Helen Jordan right now.
And I'm getting nothing.
Not a driver's license?
Not even a Social
Security number.
How is that possible?
Okay, well, hold on.
There's a link under
Helen's name.
Looks like we just
found Helen Jordan.
MAN: Are you feeling
all right today?
BRODY:
We didn't realize Helen Jordan
wasn't living on her own.
Yeah, how long has she been
under your care, Dr. O'Keefe?
Helen's been at our facility
for almost 40 years now.
Since she was 12.
Helen?
These nice people
have come to visit.
BRODY:
Uh...
I don't understand.
Helen was in a car accident
when she was ten.
Her mother was killed
and she was left, well,
as you see her.
Her father tried several
special hospitals
before bringing
her here.
Helen?
Did a woman named Jordan Lowell
visit Helen recently?
Yes. Several times over
the past few months.
She was wonderful.
Read to her for hours.
She told me she thought
Helen was her half-sister.
Even took a DNA sample.
(sighs heavily)
We're gonna have
to do the same.
Is there some reason the police
are interested in Helen?
Actually, we're interested
in the woman
who came to visit her--
Jordan Lowell.
Please don't tell me she's
some sort of scam artist.
No, ma'am.
She's dead.
She died in a plane
crash yesterday.
Oh, my Lord.
She was just here.
Helen's father never visited.
I understand he died
a few years ago.
I had hoped that,
after all these years,
that Helen had someone
who wasn't a stranger
to hold her hand.
BRODY:
Talk about a tragic story.
And an unlucky family.
Well, someone in that family
had good fortune.
I mean, you saw that place;
it's pretty high-end.
40 years of constant care.
It would cost a pretty penny.
The kind of money
Joseph Jordan
would amass over a lifetime.
I looked into
Jordan's father.
His family's owned
property in Nevada
for over a century.
He made a fortune
in ranching,
mining,
and real estate.
And when Joe Jordan died,
he left over $100 million
in a trust to Helen.
Does it say who
controls the trust now?
No. Those terms
are confidential.
But it looks like
the trust donates
several million dollars
to a nonprofit
home for the
disabled every year.
Let me take a wild guess--
Tranquil Hours?
Correct.
So Tranquil Hours
is getting millions
from Helen Jordan's estate.
And then, one day,
Jordan Lowell shows up
and takes a DNA sample
from Helen.
Hoping to prove
she's part of the family
and perhaps entitled
to a big share
of her newfound inheritance.
You thinking what I'm thinking?
(cell phone chimes)
Tranquil Hours
saw Jordan as a threat.
Just one problem
with our theory.
You know the DNA sample
we took from Helen?
Well, Henry just compared it
to Jordan Lowell's DNA.
Helen and Jordan aren't sisters.
(laughs)
That's impossible,
Hojem-Sanders.
I'm sorry, Donna,
but it's science.
Your science, not mine.
Mr. Russell,
my research is meticulous,
my methods precise.
I fact-check and verify
my information
at every turn.
I'd like to say I make mistakes,
but I don't make mistakes.
Jordan Lowell's half-sister
was at Tranquil Hours.
Donna, I'm sorry,
but science is science,
and the DNA results show
conclusively that Helen Jordan
and Jordan Lowell
are not half-sisters.
They're not even
related.
A little help here?
Well, maybe you're both right.
I mean, who's to say
that microfiche
and microcentrifuges
don't mix?
I don't know
what you're talking about.
Finally, we agree.
Jordan Lowell
found her sister,
Helen Jordan,
through genealogy.
Right.
But DNA proves that the woman
she found at Tranquil Hours
was not her sister.
Right.
So...
what happened
to Jordan's sister?
And who's the woman
pretending to be her
at Tranquil Hours?
Obviously, something happened
to the real Helen.
Maybe she died.
And maybe another patient was
substituted in Helen's place.
Because the woman
that I met
was definitely not pretending.
All of which suggests
a much wider conspiracy.
Why the conspiracy?
Who benefits?
Well, Tranquil Hours does get
several million dollars a year
from Helen's trust.
And if she dies,
the money dries up.
It's a Social
Security scam.
Until Jordan Lowell shows up
and threatens
to expose all of that.
But Jordan
showed up months ago.
Why did someone wait
till yesterday
to kill her
in a plane crash?
Ah.
The DNA kit.
Right.
Jordan swabs
the fake Helen,
and that is when somebody
at Tranquil Hours got spooked--
'cause they realized
they were about to be found out.
So the question is: How wide
is this wider conspiracy?
RUSSELL:
Don't know.
But if I were you,
I would start
with Helen's doctor.
Excuse me.
Can I help you?
Yeah, we're here
to see Dr. O'Keefe.
She called in sick this morning.
Big surprise.
Uh, in that case,
we'd like to see Helen Jordan.
We have a warrant
for her fingerprints.
I'm sorry.
Helen was transferred
to a critical care facility
a few hours ago.
Really? Where?
You'd have to ask Dr. O'Keefe.
Okay. Well, if her room
hasn't been transferred,
we're going to need to see it.
You smell that?
Bleach.
Mm-hmm.
Not a speck of dust.
No DNA, no trace,
and probably
no fingerprints.
SANDERS:
Hold that thought.
Maybe we do have
Helen's fingerprint.
They always miss something.
Nick.
Yeah?
Get this.
Henry found a sibling match
between our killer
and the impostor
in the wheelchair.
What do you mean?
The swab we got
off our impostor
has multiple alleles
in common with the DNA
we pulled from the coveralls
of our saboteur.
Mmm. So what? We still
don't have a name.
We do.
Print we got from the room
at Tranquil Hours comes back
to a Marcia Forsythe.
As in Jeffrey Forsythe?
Well, he's the guy
who loaned his gun
to the lawyer who
died in the crash.
She's his sister.
She had a skiing accident--
brain damage.
He put her
in Tranquil Hours.
He's the trustee
in charge
of Helen Jordan's millions.
Mmm. I'll call Brass.
I already called
Forsythe's law firm.
He's on his way out of town
for a business trip.
Flying his own plane.
(sirens wailing)
(sirens stop, car doors opening)
Are you going somewhere,
Mr. Forsythe?
Is there a problem,
officers?
I don't know.
Have you checked
your cabin door seals lately?
STOKES:
We know about your scam,
siphoning millions
from Helen Jordan,
enriching yourself
at her expense.
And putting your sister
in her place
whenever anyone came to visit.
Oh, and by the way,
we found her
stashed away
in another hospital.
These are absurd
allegations.
I don't think so.
We've arrested the good doctor,
and she's confessed.
So, perhaps there was
a little creative accounting.
A victimless crime.
That plane crash
wasn't victimless.
You can't possibly think I had
anything to do with that.
I already told you
my associate, Grant Abbott,
had enemies--the type
that were capable
of doing such heinous acts.
Just stop, okay?
We already know
that you persuaded Dr. O'Keefe
to offer Jordan a free
charter flight to Chicago.
Plus you had access.
Got your plane
at the airport.
You know, people
wouldn't think twice
seeing you walk in
and out of the hangar.
That's wildly speculative.
DNA evidence isn't.
What DNA?
Yours.
Found on the coveralls
you were wearing
when you sabotaged
the plane's cabin door.
You're bluffing.
You don't have a sample
of my DNA for comparison.
We have your sister's.
That's good enough.
You killed five people
on that plane.
It's just dumb luck you
didn't kill more on the ground.
I hope you saved some
of the money you stole,
because you're
going to need it
to hire a lawyer
a lot smarter than you.
Get him out of here.
Okay.
(handcuffs clicking)
I heard you got your man.
Yeah.
Thanks to you.
Little help from DNA.
You don't see genealogy
as a pure science,
do you, Mr. Russell?
I wouldn't say that.
It is, after all,
a systematic pursuit
of knowledge, right?
Seeking an understanding
of who we are
and where we
came from.
I mean, that sounds
like science to me.
Maybe not pure, but...
(laughs)
Well, if you ever need
a little systematic
pursuit of knowledge,
you know where
to find me.
Bye-bye.
DONNA:
What do you think?
Donna, this is awesome.
My dad is going to love it.
I just love
that your family crest
has an evergreen
and reindeer on it.
It's perfect
for Christmas.
Perfect for Christmas.
Anyone ever tell you two
that you're really
very cute together?
But, of course,
you'd want be careful.
Because Ekli and Hojem-Sanders
are both Norwegian names.
They could branch off
of the same family tree.
Which would make you
kissing cousins.
But...probably not.
All right,
I'll see you in a bit.
Cargo plane, San Jose.
All hands on deck.
No rest for the NTSB.
Nope.
So, I guess this is it.
Yeah.
Listen, about my, uh,
dinner offer...
Oh.
It's just that...
...seeing you again
brought back a lot
of good memories, Sara.
Honestly, it's kind of
annoying how great you look.
(both laugh)
Thanks.
I'm glad things
worked out for you.
You deserve it.
Give my regards to the Bay.
Will do.