(playing "Chopsticks")
I didn't know you played, Jim.
I dabble.
That doesn't sound good.
No, it's not.
I got a call, a couple
hikers wandered into
what may be the piano
show from hell.
A little out of the way
for a concert.
RUSSELL:
Shall we?
Oh, boy.
Not your usual body dump.
BRASS: I'm guessing mid-30s,
no wallet, no purse.
Early stages of rigor.
Got to be dead at least
eight to ten hours.
Blood pool inside the piano.
No accompanying
blood on the ground.
She wasn't killed here.
You're awful quiet over there.
I know her.
Alison Bailey.
A music journalist
from New York.
She helped me with my Vegas
book a couple years ago.
Vegas book?
Yeah, about the history
of the Mob in Las Vegas.
So, did you know her well?
Uh, a couple meetings.
She wrote a couple
books herself.
About the music scene
in Vegas in the '60s.
So, a piano expert
ends up dead in a piano.
RUSSELL:
Got to be connected.
Whoever killed her
wasn't a stranger in the night.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
PHILLIPS :
I hate pianos.
BRODY:
Really?
Six years
of piano lessons--
my mother's idea.
Best day of my life?
My piano teacher backs her car
into my mom's new Cadillac.
Never saw Mrs. Liebowitz again.
Lucky you.
Mm-hmm.
(sighs)
Not so much
for Greg, though.
Russell says he knew the victim.
PHILLIPS: Well, I hope
he didn't know her well.
She was cut to ribbons.
BRODY:
Triangular dolly.
Rules out out any,
uh, drunk pranks.
"Hey, let's steal
the bar piano."
Whoever did this could have
been a professional mover.
(sighs)
At least this one's intact.
Most pianos suffer a worse fate.
I didn't realize
pianos had fates.
Generally, a junkyard.
Thousands of moving parts.
Repairs are expensive.
Cheaper to buy a new one.
Yeah, or some
digital keyboard.
It's a shame.
Old pianos are
a thing of beauty.
Look at the end of
the dolly tracks here.
Rectangular impression.
Maybe from a truck tailgate?
BRODY: Piano's dropped here,
little push.
SANDERS:
Could have been a one-man job.
Something is wedged
between the keys.
Edges are jagged,
and it's opaque.
Maybe some kind of latex?
Did you see this?
Black trace?
Yeah, it's all over the keys.
It's also all over the inside
of the piano case.
Let's collect it,
get this piano
back to the lab.
Whole right side's lit up.
So, the victim
was definitely slashed
in proximity to the piano.
With extreme force.
Blood says killer
had to have
sliced her carotid.
Metal plate:
"Haggenmiller and Sons."
Looks like somebody's
obliterated the serial number.
Do you know since 1896,
all Haggenmiller pianos
were manufactured
at the same
factory in St. Paul?
With the serial number,
you can track a piano
to the exact date it left
the factory floor.
I take it this is not
your first body in a piano.
First ones with
the limbs intact.
Well, I always knew
Seattle was a music town.
I'll see what I can
do about bringing
that serial number back to life.
If we can find out where
the piano came from,
maybe we'll find the killer.
(whirring)
(sizzling)
Hey.
I, uh...
found
a hotel key card.
She was, uh, staying
at the Palermo.
What was she like?
A small-town
girl from Iowa.
Smart.
Funny.
Huge Sinatra fan.
(sighs)
Come on, Greg.
You guys were doing more
than write a book, right?
It was a...
a week of fun.
Why didn't you guys
stay in touch?
It was just a fling.
For you or for her?
If it meant that much to her,
I think she would
have looked me up.
Can we...
...keep this from Russell?
Sure.
I'll process her room.
Little advice, though:
I would stay out of
autopsy.
C.O.D. is exsanguination due
to multiple incised wounds.
27 to be exact.
Overkill.
But no sexual assault.
Defensive wounds on
the fingers and wrist.
She put up a fight.
Any idea what the weapon was?
Hilt bruises
on the wounds.
Depth and width
suggest a box cutter.
Something that a piano mover
might carry around with him?
I found these inorganics in a
couple of the larger wounds.
This looks like the trace
that Greg pulled out
of the piano keys.
Hodges is already
working on it.
So?
Hover much?
Results?
Shouldn't we wait
for Russell first?
I'll stop the
questions if you do.
Trace found in the piano
and in the girl's wounds.
Carbon black and
polyvinylchloride.
These other fragments
that you found in the piano:
Hide glue, straight from the
horse's... fibrous tissues.
You see how these edges line up?
I'm thinking that our shards
des Monsieur Ed are from
one sheet of dried glue.
There are striations
on one side.
Looks like a wood grain imprint.
So you're thinking
a piano repairman
got into it with our victim?
Well, who else would be
using glue on a piano?
That's a brilliant theory, Greg.
There's just one problem.
See, I tested all the glue
that held our piano together
and it's not a match to any
of the fragments that you found.
Oh, and the carbon black
and polyvinylchloride--
it's sheet vinyl,
commonly used
in floor tile covering.
My theory is that you're looking
for somebody in construction.
My pleasure.
What's all this?
It's evidence
from Alison's hotel room
at the Palermo?
She checked in five days ago.
It's definitely
not our primary though.
Place was clean.
Well, was she moving in?
She set up a work station.
Lots of books and files.
Think she was
researching a new book.
I also found this.
An appointment book.
Last entry was yesterday.
Some kind of
number/letter sequence
Doesn't look like a VIN number.
I was just about to run it.
I'll take these.
RUSSELL: Sin City Secrets
by Greg Sanders.
Nice photo.
Hm.
So I guess you were, uh,
a big part of her research?
You didn't even know it, huh?
SIDLE:
Hey, there you are.
Wow, those are a lot of boxes.
Uh, I ran the serial
number on the piano.
It was built in 1966,
and the original owner
was a guy named Ledo Wright.
Wait-- the Ledo Wright?
I didn't know there
was a "the" involved.
(wry laugh)
Well, who is he?
Only a legend.
That both of us
have never heard of.
What is so legendary?
How he played the piano.
And...
how he was murdered.
1966.
The Golden Age of Vegas.
The Rat Pack roamed the casinos
and the Mob ran 'em.
Now, Ledo Wright was a hotshot
young piano player from L.A.,
playing a week with
Sinatra at the Sands.
The story goes:
Ledo was hitting on
one of Sinatra's
dames after the show.
Grazetti was an aspiring
thumb-breaker for Sam Giancana.
The new kid in town was also
from Hoboken, so, of course,
he and Sinatra hit it off.
Grazetti would have done
anything to impress Frank.
Grazetti was a real hothead.
Ledo: no wallflower.
Both up-and-coming stars
in their own worlds.
Things went south-- fast.
(woman screams)
Ledo Wright's body
was never found.
No body, no evidence.
No charges could be filed.
What happened to Grazetti?
Disappeared.
Until he popped up in
Jersey, 20 years later.
But, by then, Ledo was
just a distant memory.
Well, his piano isn't.
It's been going to same repair
shop in Los Angeles for years.
Place was scheduled
to receive it two days ago.
Moving company's called
"Play On Movers."
The night that Alison died,
their truck gassed up
five miles from the crime scene.
Who was the driver?
RUSSELL:
Lenny Vanders, it says here.
Former musician.
I guess all he's playing lately
is "Jailhouse Rock."
He did two tours at Ely.
Paroled last year.
Besides the piano-moving gig,
he works at a store called
"Back When Music."
(playing bluesy riff)
'56 Strat.
Plug you in, bro?
Maybe next time.
Are you Lenny Vanders?
I go by Moondog.
What can I do you for?
Do you know an Alison Bailey?
Nope.
The bells do not ring.
Are they ringing now?
Did you move this piano?
I move a lot of pianos.
Yo, Clapton,
we have proof
that you moved this piano
in your truck.
Dude, look...
I was supposed to deliver it
to L.A. for repairs.
The dead girl was definitely not
on the shipping manifesto.
So how'd she get in the piano?
No clue.
Look, I stopped to get gas.
I checked the piano,
went to tighten the straps.
Next thing I know, I got a dead
girl staring at me.
BRASS:
And you did the right thing.
You called the cops, right?
Look, I panicked.
I dumped it in the desert.
Who owns the piano?
I got it at this old theater.
That wasn't the question.
You know that
Witness Protection thing?
Can I get in on that?
How does that work?
Who owns the piano, Moondog?
Tommy Grazetti.
Yeah.
I thought he was hanging out
in Jersey somewhere.
Since when did he
come back to Las Vegas?
How am I supposed to know?
All I know is he runs this
Rat Pack show at that theater
and he used to kill people
for a living.
Yeah, people
like Ledo Wright.
I think Greg's
onto something.
If Alison was looking into
one of Grazetti's
old murders...
Maybe she's a new one.
ANNOUNCER:
Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome to the Copa Room
at the Sands!
Here they are,
straight from the bar--
Dean, Sammy,
and the Chairman of
the Board, Frank Sinatra!
Whoa!
Hey, how are you this evening,
ladies and gentlemen?
Ho-ho!
How'd all these people
get in my room?
I got this one, boys;
I got this one.
♪ Without a song ♪
♪ The day would never end ♪
♪ The road would never bend ♪
♪ When things go wrong ♪
♪ A man ain't got a friend ♪
♪ Without a song ♪
♪ I've got my trouble and woe,
but sure as I know ♪
♪ That Jordan will roll... ♪
What a time.
Oh, please.
You weren't even born.
♪ As long as a song
is strong in my soul... ♪
♪ I'll never know... ho! ♪
♪ What makes the rain to fall ♪
Hey, check it out.
There's Ledo Wright.
And look at the date on
the poster-- October 23, 1966.
Two days before
Ledo was murdered
by Tommy Grazetti
to get in good with Frank.
Looks like Mr. Grazetti's
still leading the good life.
♪ There's no love at all,
without a song. ♪
(song ends)
Can I help you?
Yeah, as a
matter of fact.
CSI Russell, CSI Sanders,
Vegas Crime Lab.
We'd like to talk
to a Tommy Grazetti.
Yeah, he's out of town.
So unless you got a
ticket, you got to leave.
How's this for a ticket?
SINGER: Hey, ladies and
gentlemen, thank you so much.
(applause)
I don't know
what to tell you.
Piano was taken out
yesterday.
Guy took it out through
the loading dock.
Okay. But it was
right here, right?
More or less.
Do me a favor.
On the way out the door,
turn the lights off,
will you?
Thank you.
(sighs)
I think we found our primary.
Three voids, identical.
What are you thinking,
piano legs?
This is where
Alison was attacked.
(screams)
SANDERS:
Missed a spot.
Blood...
with a strand of fiber in it.
Maybe trace from our killer?
We need some backup.
I'm gonna text Sara.
(light switch clicks,
then footsteps approach)
Oh, look who's here.
You charge extra
for the cleaning?
Mr. Grazetti, uh,
heard you were out of town.
Heard you wanted to talk.
Yeah, yeah, we do.
You know a lady
named Alison Bailey.
Is that right?
Don't recognize
the name.
How about the face?
Oh, yeah-- her.
She's a nutjob.
A few days ago, I'm at
the sports book at Caesar's.
I got a fresh cigar,
a fresh racing form-- paradise.
She saddles up next to me,
asks me questions
about the old days.
I gave her the shine.
Yeah, and then you
shined the floor
with her blood.
Yeah, excuse-- excuse me.
Um, where were you
Monday night?
At home by myself.
Show's dark on Mondays.
She found out, didn't she?
She had proof that you're the
one who killed Ledo Wright.
(chuckles)
You're out of line, kid.
Yeah? And you're a killer.
All right, you know what?
Time... time-out.
Can I talk to you
for a second, please?
And don't go anywhere.
We'll be right back.
What-What are you doing?
The guy did it!
No, actually, Greg,
he's a suspect.
There's blood
all over that place!
All right,
All the more reason
to rein it in,
so we can nail him.
Rein it in?
Oh, I get it.
When it's people
that you care about,
the rule book goes out
the window.
But when it's someone who
meant something to me...
Yeah, I should've
told you.
Yeah, you're right,
you should have.
And yeah, you're right.
When Katie was taken, I...
I led with my heart.
I didn't know
what to do.
But I was wrong.
It wasn't until
I stopped doing that
that we were able
to find her.
Easier said than done.
Yeah, tell me about it.
Well, I guess this is
when you take
me off the case.
Off the case, no.
Off the front lines, yeah.
You think that whatever Alison
found got her killed, right?
So... take a deep breath
and go out and find it.
For her.
Okay?
(music playing in distance)
(Frank Sinatra song playing)
♪ ♪
Hey, I don't go on
for another 20.
Sinatra needs his rest.
(needle scrapes, song stops)
Show's over, Frank.
BRASS: You know, I don't know
why the DMV gets this so wrong.
They got you down here
as some schmuck named
Jeff Lummet.
Someone gonna tell me
why I'm here?
Oh, my God.
I take it you know her, Jeff?
That's Alison Bailey.
I met her a couple
years ago.
I helped her with her
Sinatra biography.
Oh...
I'm a, I'm a
memorabilia collector.
There were some items
that she wanted to see.
Have you seen her more recently
than that?
Maybe in the
little love nest
they have under
the theater there.
It's not a love nest,
all right?
It's a listening room.
And it's not mine,
it's Tommy's.
So you and Tommy have
a little listening room.
Someplace where
nobody listens.
You were partying down there,
and maybe things got out
of hand.
Hey, hey, hey, wait a minute.
Whatever happened
to Alison,
I had nothing
to do about it.
Oh, man.
It is my fault.
I told her where
to find Tommy.
At Caesars.
Oh! I warned her.
Told her not to talk to
Tommy about his past.
It's a bad idea.
Laying around in blood and
fibers at a crime scene--
that is a bad idea.
Where were you Monday night?
I was working at the Avalon.
That's a hip-hop club, Jeff.
I mean, they're
not Sinatra fans there.
I wasn't singing.
I was spotting.
Here.
Note Seek.
That's an app
that identifies songs.
Charlie actually just
showed me how to use this.
It's really cool.
Note Seek has this
database of songs
that are catalogued by
artist, year and title.
Then you take your app
and you digitally listen
to a snippet of music...
(Sinatra song playing)
And then it tells
you exactly what
you're listening to.
How cool is that?
I thought you were more of
a Grateful Dead kind of guy.
No, I am, I am.
This is just research.
Barbara's the Sinatra fan.
This one, we actually
learned how to dance
to that song
at an Arthur Murray studio.
Barbara wanted us
to learn how to dance
for Maya's wedding.
It was fun, too.
How are you guys doing?
We're good. We're good.
Thank you. Yeah.
She's still flying up
to Seattle every
weekend, but...
Well, that must be really
good for Maya and Katie.
Yeah, I hope so.
So, how does Note Seek
alibi Lummet?
I had to look
that one up, actually.
Um... the company has
these music spotters
that they send out to clubs
to listen and record
new songs and remixes
for the database.
And Lummet did say that
he was music spotting
on Monday night at the club.
And an exec from Note Seek
confirmed his story.
Lummet turned in his playlist.
So I guess we no longer
have a suspect.
Guess not.
(record skipping)
Oh, Lord.
You don't get that
with MP3s, do you?
FINLAY:
What?
I have a... I have a box cutter
in that left-hand drawer.
Can I have it, please?
Sure.
Forgive me, Barbara,
but it's for a good cause.
Does that look familiar?
Vinyl trace
Greg found in the piano.
Same as Doc found
in the victim's wounds.
Vinyl tracings,
box cutters...
Maybe a record played
a part in Alison's death.
Wow.
You have done a lot of
work in here, Greg.
None of this makes any sense.
I thought that Alison
was researching
Tommy Grazetti's involvement
in the Ledo Wright murder,
but there is nothing
in here about Ledo Wright.
So what was
she researching?
Well, she was definitely
interested in Grazetti,
but most of these files are
about the Mob moving
into drug dealing,
or making inroads
with the hippie crowd.
Tell me you got something.
Yeah.
I've got Alison's car.
The rental car company
turned over the GPS files
for the vehicle.
As you can see,
most of her trips
were right around the Strip,
but on the day
she was murdered,
she takes a ride to an
abandoned house in Henderson.
"850 Timber Lane."
Yeah, does that mean something?
Here it is.
October 26, 1966.
Tommy Grazetti walks
into 850 Timber Lane.
What is this,
FBI surveillance?
No.
That's Sam Braun surveillance.
Braun had a P.I.
tailing Grazetti.
Well, why would
Sam be following him?
850 Timber Lane.
The house was owned
by a Linda Overton.
She was a trust-fund kid
turned violent radical.
Robbed Braun's
Rampart Casino
in '66, killed two guards.
Died of cancer in '95.
The cops never found any of
her co-conspirators.
Maybe Alison did.
Tommy Grazetti.
Yeah, this whole time
I have been thinking
that the Ledo Wright murder
got Alison killed.
Maybe Tommy Grazetti was
helping radicals rob a casino.
I've been looking
at the wrong '60s.
You should've stayed
in Jersey, Tommy.
But I guess everyone's past
has a way of catching up
to all of us, huh?
I don't even know
what I'm looking at.
You're looking at a crook.
And a murderer.
Sam Braun knew it.
That's why he had his P.I.
take that photo of you
paying Linda Overton
a little vist.
Take a look at
the date stamp, there.
October 26, 1966.
That's three days before
the Rampart casino was robbed
and two guards were killed.
Tragic.
Historic.
I had nothing
to do with it.
STOKES: Just like you had
nothing to do with
Alison Bailey's murder.
Now, forget about
the piano player--
Ledo Wright.
It was easy to
make him disappear.
But this... ooh.
Well, that's a different
story, isn't it?
I think that you hightailed it
out of Vegas in '66
because you stole from Sam Braun
and killed two of his boys.
40 years later,
Alison dug up the truth,
and you killed her for it.
I was also the guy
on the grassy knoll.
Did you find that
in her research?
No, but I can tell you
what I think I'm gonna find.
The name of a co-conspirator
who was in on the heist
with you and Overton.
You like the word "allegedly"?
It's a favorite of mine.
Now, you just told me
a little story
about Vegas in '66.
I'll tell you one.
In '66, we're running
the casinos.
Skimming, loan-sharking...
you know, allegedly.
Life is good.
And then Howard Hughes
buys the Sands.
Makes it all legit.
Not even Sinatra
could get comp'd.
Yeah, sure, we still
hit the Sands every day.
But not like
players, kings-- no.
All we could do was
play the nickel slots like
a bunch of old ladies.
We had to come up with a
different revenue source--
drugs.
Allegedly.
You're telling me
you're a drug dealer,
not a murderer.
I'm not telling you anything.
Except for Linda Overton was
one hot hippie piece of ass.
(laughs)
(hip-hop music playing)
(scratching)
Do you play weddings, too?
I'm not playing, dawg.
I'm cleaning.
(laughing)
What are you
talking about?
Well, as much as it pains me
to admit, I was wrong
about the glue that
he found in the piano.
I think our killer used it
to clean a record.
Wouldn't that mess
the record up?
Not if you follow
this simple recipe:
You take one LP album,
add four ounces
of store-bought hide glue.
Spread evenly
across the vinyl.
In time, dust and particles
affix to the glue.
After the glue dries,
you take a handy box cutter,
and use it to pry the glue
off of the record.
And...
voilà,
a perfectly clean record.
RUSSELL:
You also got a perfect negative
of the record's grooves,
just like these.
We got the grooves,
why don't we just play
the damn thing?
"Name That Tune,"
name that killer.
(beep)
SIDLE:
I was able to assemble
and reconstruct
four separate audio segments
from the glue.
This is what I got.
Track One.
(applause)
Live album, maybe?
Track Two.
(snippet of music plays)
Jazz, maybe?
There were vocals, too.
Track Three.
(male voice sings one note)
I got the most
out of this track.
(slow, jazzy instrumental
plays briefly)
That's all I got.
I mean,
if it were a Radiohead song,
I could help you, but...
No, wait a minute,
wait a minute, I...
let me use my app here.
God, I love this thing.
(imitating Bogart):
Play it again, Sara.
(instrumental plays)
(beep)
Ah!
Sinatra at the Sands.
Classic album.
Seems whenever this case
takes a turn,
it's always back to 1966.
Taking a music break?
Listen to this.
GRAZETTI:
Yeah, sure, we still
hit the Sands every day.
But not like
players, kings-- no.
Grazetti's interrogation?
Yeah. I've been listening to it
for the last couple hours.
The guy's lying.
You didn't expect him
to admit to killing Alison.
No, I'm not talking
about Alison.
I'm talking about
the Sands in '66.
Grazetti said that he was
"hanging with the boys"
in the casino.
That's impossible.
Why?
The Vegas Black Book.
It's a list of
all the people banned
by the Gaming Commission.
In 1965, Tommy Grazetti
was busted for counting cards.
He was banned from
the Sands after that.
So there's no way
he was hanging with the boys
in the casino.
But why would he lie about that?
Maybe... he forgot.
Trust me, guys like Grazetti
don't forget
about their Vegas glory days.
In fact, they
spend more time
living in the past
than in the present.
Kind of... sounds like
you're talking about yourself
more than Grazetti.
What's that supposed to mean?
Greg...
your... passion
for Vegas history is awesome.
It makes you a
better CSI, right?
And... I'm...
the last person
who should be giving
relationship advice, but...
I mean, look at
you, you're...
you're a hot guy;
you're smart, you're funny,
you're... a total catch.
What I'm saying is...
with Alison,
with your obsession
with the past, maybe...
...you should stop looking back,
you know? Try...
moving forward.
You're right.
You are the last person
who should be giving
relationship advice.
(chuckles softly)
All I'm saying is,
with my parents' divorce,
I couldn't get past it;
I-I thought of my father
as this one guy,
and...
I came to realize he was
a completely different person.
You know, maybe...
Wait.
What you just said.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
(spritzing)
I think you're gonna be
a little late for that show.
Yeah, well, not for
Ledo Wright's thumbprint.
RUSSELL:
You're kidding me.
A 46-year-old print?
You're gonna make
the Journal of Forensic Science.
I'm gonna make more
than that, bubby.
Look at that photo
of Ledo Wright.
See the ring on
his finger?
Yeah.
Ledo always wore an
Irish Claddagh ring.
Now, I blew up this photo
of Tommy Grazetti
in front of Linda
Overton's house.
What's on his hand?
An Irish Claddagh ring.
What is Grazetti doing
with an Irish ring?
He's Italian as pasta.
Because it's the same guy.
So maybe it's the other
way around--
maybe Ledo Wright
killed Grazetti.
And assumed his identity.
It's a good story.
One I am going to prove.
Now, Nick already got
Grazetti's print
when he brought him in,
and now we have
Ledo Wright's print
from the poster.
RUSSELL:
Wow.
Hey, that's
great work, Greg.
For 46 years,
Ledo's been hiding.
Alison found him,
and that got her killed.
The guy putting on
the fake Rat Pack show is
the biggest fake of 'em all.
(piano playing gentle melody)
That's a Ledo Wright flourish
if I ever heard one.
Same build,
same looks,
a few nips and tucks.
But you couldn't change
your fingerprints.
It all made sense.
The legend.
"Gangster kills piano player."
(chuckles)
But Alison...
discovered the truth.
I didn't kill Allison.
I didn't kill anyone.
Not wanting to kill is how this
whole damn thing got started.
1966 was a...
a very good year for an
up-and-coming piano player,
but a very bad year if you drew
the wrong number in the draft.
I thought my only choice
was to go to Canada.
And then... (chuckles)
fate stepped in.
It was just another night
in paradise,
hanging out with the boys.
Yeah, Tommy and I,
we had our differences,
but we made up.
We always told Tommy,
"Swallow first,
then flap your gums."
(choking)
It all happened so fast.
Tommy, get up, man.
What are you doing?
We tried to revive Tommy,
but it was no use.
He was gone.
And I was supposed to
report for basic training
in two days.
And the boys, they come up
with this crazy idea.
And the more I thought
about it,
the less crazy it got.
Tommy was the same height,
same build.
I dyed my hair,
(lowers voice):
made a few adjustments.
Showtime.
Why'd you come back to town?
Vegas.
At least the Vegas I remember.
Frank and the boys,
the songs... the attitude.
(chuckles)
Man, it was magic.
And now... I get to bring
that back to life
every night... right here.
SANDERS:
Ledo Wright's story
checked out.
He put me onto
a 1966 John Doe.
C.O.D.: asphyxiation
due to...
...chicken bone.
And you believe this guy?
Well, I believe Ledo Wright
isn't a killer.
Well, hell,
somebody cut up
that girl and put her in
the piano.
Hey, guys, I've been doing
some research on our album,
Sinatra at the Sands.
Turns out it is
a very rare pressing.
RUSSELL:
Go on.
Every vinyl record is imprinted
with a stamped I.D.
on the lead-out groove.
And that I.D. can be used
to trace it to the manufacturer
or the label.
You remember the number sequence
that we found
in Alison's
appointment book?
It's the same number.
It says here they only pressed
a thousand copies.
And only one store
in town sells it.
What's up, Moondog?
Came back for the Strat?
Sweet.
Actually, I'm looking
for a record.
A very rare pressing
of Sinatra at the Sands.
BRASS:
I know.
You move a lot of records.
You got that
right, dude.
But I did move that,
couple days ago.
I got it right here.
Yep.
"Jeff Lummet."
Jeff Lummet?
The Sinatra impersonator.
That's the guy.
He said it was a gift for--
his words-- "a hot dame."
What a tool.
And you would know.
So what?
I bought a Sinatra record.
A guy like you's got
every Sinatra record ever made.
No, no, no, not this one.
This is 180-gram vinyl.
It's like he's whispering
in your ear.
Must be great to impress a girl.
STOKES: Yeah, Moondog
already told us
that you gave it
to "a hot dame."
You want to tell us
where you really were
Monday night?
(scoffs)
I already told you.
That's right. You were recording
some songs using Note Seek?
They gave us a copy, I think,
of the playlist.
BRASS:
And the D.J. gave us
his playlist from Monday night,
so, let's play
the music and dance.
♪ ♪
Does not compute.
"Unknown song."
How about that?
Ah.
That one single song
the DJ played
is in Note Seek's database.
You weren't there, Jeff.
BRASS: I mean,
why would a beautiful,
smart girl like Alison
go out with a
guy like you?
You're a two-bit impersonator,
working a nostalgia act
worse than a cruise ship.
Hey, I beat out hundreds of
Broadway stars to be Frank.
You want to
know how?!
I'm dying to know.
He thinks he's as good
as Frank Sinatra.
Better.
As good. As good.
You know, chicks hear me,
and I feel sorry for them.
Their seats puddle when they
hear what Jeff Lummet's got.
BRASS:
You're an impersonator.
You're Jeff Lummet.
You're not
Francis Albert Sinatra.
You're not even
in the same area code.
STOKES:
Let's get back to the girl.
So, you say you met her
a couple years ago,
and you were helping her
with a book, right?
I had my hands full with
a redhead at the time.
I must have
broken her heart.
So, what, she forgets about you,
and she doesn't call you
when she comes to town?
Is that it?
She called me plenty.
She needed help finding
one of Frank's records.
Sinatra at the Sands,
and you're the go-to guy
on all things Frank, right?
I told her to meet me backstage
after the show.
BRASS:
Yeah?
To give her the record.
Right.
Get it all nice
and cleaned up.
Uh-huh.
And she says
it's not even for her.
A surprise gift
for some guy named Greg.
Turns out she hooked up
with him a couple years ago,
still has feelings for him.
Or some... I mean, what
the... what the hell, right?
The Chairman of the Board
got played.
The guy who's
better than Frank, right?
You're damn right.
I did her a favor,
and she spits in my face.
She spits in my face!
Yeah. Did she not
know how things are done?
How we do things here?
Right. How are things
done... Frank?
They're done my way.
Well, it's a surprise...
just for you.
It's not for me.
It's for my friend Greg.
What? What?
(grunts)
(gasps, screams)
(cries and yelps)
(yells)
(crying)
(thud, notes play)
How's this sound?
Huh? How's this sound?!
You okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
About earlier, I'm
sorry for what I said...
No.
I'm the one who should
be sorry. I...
The last night
we spent together,
I told Alison that I'd
meet her in New York.
Even though I knew it
would never happen.
Why not?
Why spoil a perfect memory?
She wanted to see you.
That's something to hold on to.
Just bought this.
You know what
Sinatra always said?
"That's life"?
(quiet chuckle) No.
"The best is yet to come."
(Frank Sinatra music playing)
♪ ♪