MAN:
How does an eagle fly?
With wings?
I don't know. Ask the chicken
how that's working out.
An eagle flies
because it is fearless.
Using its force of mind,
the eagle is the lord
of the sky.
My name is Alan Quinn
and I believe
that you are all eagles.
Thank you, friends.
Thank you for visiting
this sacred paradise.
If you join my week-long
"Force Of Mind" seminar,
you... will... conquer... fire.
Your fears will vanish.
Your work, your relationship,
everything in your life
will be enriched.
Now who wants
to come fly with me?
Come on! I don't see
every hand up.
Who wants to come fly with me?!
Come on! Let's go, people!
Let's go!
Come on in the back there!
Ciao, David.
Oh... (chuckles)
I wish you were here.
HODGES:
Ciao bella, Elisabetta,
il mia amore.
I wish I were there, too.
You do? You're not avoiding me?
Of course not. Work beckons.
(chuckles)
It's so beautiful here.
So empowering.
Empowering?
Sounds like you've been sipping
the Alan Quinn Kool-Aid.
I'm about to enter
the sacred mud spring.
Ugh, if I can't see
the bottom, I don't go in.
If you were with me,
you'd see something else.
It's all natural here.
I assume that this is
a private mud spring?
Just me and nature.
Ciao, David.
Ciao... (speaks Italian)
Is that your fiancé
on the phone?
You're such a tease, huh?
Have you told him about me?
It's not the right time.
Santo? Non é buffo.
Not funny!
(yells, laughs)
Mi hai fatto paura!
You scare me!
(speaks Italian)
Stop kicking!
I'm not kicking you!
You, stop rubbing me.
I'm not.
(screaming)
Welcome to your
hot springs nightmare.
Floater in a
natural mud bath.
Why does this place
look so familiar?
Because Alan Quinn shoots
his infomercials here.
This is his resort.
Right.
The "Force of Mind" guy.
All over late-night TV.
I don't think this'll make
his next ad.
Watch your step.
What do we got?
It's a unknown male.
There's no I.D.
Liver temp's ambient
with the mud.
Body's bloated, but there's
no sloughing of the skin.
I'd say he's been dead
at least 24 hours,
but probably no more than 36.
Heard a couple of bathers
found him.
It floated up between them
while they were messing around.
Yeah.
And we know one of the bathers.
RUSSELL:
That's Elisabetta.
Hodges' girlfriend?
Yep. She was taking a dip
with Fabio over there.
They're sharing a room.
She and Hodges are still
engaged, right?
Far as I know.
Hey, what is that right there?
Looks like bruising.
Maybe handprints?
Could be he was held down.
So, not an accidental drowning.
Murder in paradise.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
You conquer fire...
...you can conquer anything.
It is all within you.
Here you go.
Force of mind.
You got it-- yeah!
(laughs)
There you go.
Feels good to be an eagle,
doesn't it?
Doesn't it?
Alan Quinn?
Captain Jim Brass,
Las Vegas Police.
Excuse me, birdman,
do me a favor--
fly back to your room.
I need to speak
to your spirit guide.
Hey, what's going on, Alan?
Aren't you concerned
that a murder victim was found
in your mud springs?
Of course I'm concerned.
It's a tragedy.
Mr. Quinn, we're kind of hoping
you could help us identify
the victim.
As far as I know,
every employee, every guest
has been accounted for.
And I handed over our registry
to one of your guys.
Well, somebody got stuck
in the mud.
All I can think is, uh,
probably a hiker.
Sadly some people can't
afford the entrance fee.
So what do you think,
they sneak down
from the hillside?
If they're not a bother,
I look the other way.
In the end, these springs
are for everyone, right?
That's a beautiful
sentiment, Alan.
But let me tell you
what's happening.
Right now, these springs
and every inch of this ground
belongs to us.
You got it?
BRODY: You know, I kind of miss
playing in the mud.
Sacred bubbly mud.
Even better.
Heard you might need
some extra on-site testing.
I'm here to help.
She's over by
the reception area.
Elisabetta, Elisabetta,
mi amore.
It was horrible, David.
Oh, it's okay, it's okay.
I'm here.
Now, I heard you were
with someone?
Si. Santo.
He's my brother, David.
He's visiting from Tuscany.
But I checked
the hotel register,
and he has
a different last name.
And you two were staying
in the same room.
You don't trust me, David?
I do, it's just
I want to,
but I don't understand.
Santo and I have different
last name because...
I was married before.
I keep my husband
last name.
David, I was very young.
Why didn't you tell me
you were married before?
I tried.
You've been so busy.
You never have time for me.
How much time does
it take for someone
to just say, "By the way,
I'm divorced, Italian-style"?
It was just one week.
Not helping.
I'll explain everything.
Era niente.
It was nothing.
Please.
♪ ♪
Ready?
Let's get dirty.
This looks like the last of it.
Hold on--
there's something's wedged
between the rocks right here.
Leather bracelet?
It looks clean.
That means it wasn't
in here for very long.
Maybe it belonged
to someone who was in here
with our vic.
Maybe even our killer.
SIDLE:
Doc, what do we have?
Confirmation our
victim drowned.
Stomach contents are muddy.
Also confirmation
we're dealing with a homicide.
In addition to the
apparent bruising
to our victim's chest,
I also found this abrasion
on his forehead.
Think he was hit
before he went in?
Possibly.
These were embedded
inside the wound track.
Looks like wooden splinters.
Maybe from a weapon.
Beaten and then drowned?
I'll send this off
to Hodges.
John Doe had a maxillary
partial denture.
Four numbers are engraved on
the metal framework.
Most dentists I.D.
their patients
using the last four digits
of their Social.
Should give us a name.
SIDLE:
Mrs. Wade.
Hi.
I'm, um, I'm sorry
for your loss.
I thought Justin was still
at the spa.
I can't believe this.
You weren't with him
at the spa?
No, he was on
a corporate retreat
with his sales team.
Justin's a... a rep at Bixton.
Bixton--
the pharmaceutical company?
That's right.
The company uses Alan Quinn's
team-building techniques.
Do you know, um,
if Justin had problems
with any of his co-workers?
No. He loved his job...
our life together...
We were just getting started.
When was the last time
that you spoke with him?
Uh...
two days ago.
This is so stupid.
He didn't even want to go.
I convinced him.
Why didn't he want to go?
He thought it was New Agey
and-and silly.
I had stayed at the spa before,
so I thought
it would be good for him.
RUSSELL: Wow, look at that.
What wasn't in this mud bath?
FINLAY:
Yeah, it looks like the day
after a frat party.
STOKES:
Complete with the muddy
walk-of-shame evidence.
The condoms are swabbed for DNA.
Henry got no results.
As well as the bottles
and cigarette butts.
And that pigeon feather
is disgusting.
Really, all of
this stuff looks
like it's been down there
a couple of weeks
except for this thing
right here.
Doesn't even have
any mud on it.
Can I see that thing?
Mm-hmm.
What are you doing?
This is a...
eagle feather, maybe?
You know,
you put this little tassel
thing on the end
of the feather, you got yourself
a smudge feather.
(chuckles): A what?
Smudge feather.
Native American Indians
use it sometimes
to waft incense around.
My mom used to use
a smudge feather to cleanse
the negativity from our house.
I thought you said
your house was a van?
Believe me,
that van needed
a lot of smudging.
Wait a sec.
Smudge feather.
Where have I seen that?
Alan Quinn sent over a list
of everyone on the retreat.
Opening day itinerary.
He divided everyone
into teams of three.
Each team was named
after a type of eagle.
So, this is a
white-tailed eagle.
And the feather symbol
that Alan Quinn gave
to you and your
Bixton team--
which consisted of you,
Heather, and Jessica Lowell
and Justin Weed.
First, let me say,
as a citizen and as
a representative of Bixton,
I want to cooperate fully
in this investigation.
I very much
appreciate that.
So, Justin's feather
was found in his room.
And this feather
was found where he died.
So, whose feather is it?
Is it your feather or
is it Jessica's feather?
(quiet, indistinct conversation)
You and Jessica
need some time
to get your
story straight?
I have nothing to hide.
We were both with Justin.
Heather wanted
a team strategy meeting.
Having it at
Club Mud was my idea.
What time did you meet
at the mud bath?
Around 10:00.
And what was
the mood in the mud?
Was everything
cool with Justin?
Justin was over
the whole Alan Quinn
team-building-
eagle-flying-thing.
He just wanted
to go home.
Sure.
And what about you
and Heather?
Who doesn't like
a free mud bath?
Heather, on the
other hand,
spent that last day
looking like she
was gonna pop a button
on her pant suit.
Why's that?
She wasn't happy
with the team.
HEATHER:
I don't want
to speak ill
of the deceased,
but Justin
let the team down.
How so?
He wouldn't do the firewalk.
And why would that
concern your team?
Alan Quinn sends
an assessment report
back to Bixton.
Your team fails
mission objectives,
you get a bad score.
So you were
upset with Justin?
Maybe even got into
a shoving match.
Not liking your
insinuation here.
They were both alive
and well when I left.
So, you're saying
that Jessica and Justin
stayed in the
mud bath together.
Don't know what
happened after that.
JESSICA:
We just...
talked.
He was distracted.
I was half-naked and
he didn't even blink.
All he could talk
about was his wife.
Why are the good ones
always so boring?
So, how'd the night end?
We got out at
the same time.
Now wait a minute...
(sighs) Justin got out
of the mud bath?
Yeah.
We walked back together.
I saw him go
into his room.
What time was that?
Around 11:00.
Okay.
Thank you, Jessica.
You can call me Jess.
Any time.
You text me?
Indeed, I did.
I understand our
women in the mud bath
claim that Justin Wade
exited the mud?
Yeah, yeah, before he
returned to it to drown.
I sense your frustration
and I may have something
to assuage it.
The bruising on the
victim's chest, right?
Mm-hmm.
Histology results of the
tissue reveal fluid loss
from damaged blood vessels.
Swelling and blistering
that was obfuscated
from the bloating.
Blistering. So you're
saying that he was burned
before he was drowned?
According to Doc Robbins,
an inhaled substance
caused urticaria and angioedema
along the interior of
the primary bronchi.
I think the cause-- smoke.
Okay.
And, you recall that Justin Wade
had splinters in his forehead?
Yeah, he was hit by some kind
of weapon, right?
I think not.
The splinters are wood from
the Northwestern Red Cedar.
It's a tree that's sacred
to Native Americans
used in rituals and
rites of passage.
Like Alan Quinn's firewalks.
Wood in his head,
smoke in his lungs.
I think between dips in the mud,
Justin Wade played with fire.
And, I can prove it.
If... you'll firewalk this way.
First of all,
walking across hot coals
doesn't take force of mind,
it takes force of physics.
Coal's lightweight
carbon structure
is a poor conductor of heat.
The layer of ash further
insulates the heat.
Firewalks are
conducted at night
so you see the
red, burning coals,
and not the layer of
ash that coats them.
Phew, whoa!
You sure about this?
That's hot enough
to cook meat.
But your feet only make contact
for two-tenths of a second.
The key is to walk
softly and steadily.
Ecco, amico mio.
I am an eagle!
All right, what
about the victim?
He didn't receive his wings.
While we know
that Justin Wade
was a reluctant
spiritual warrior,
Heather, his teammate,
was unhappy
with his unwillingness
to walk the fire.
So you think that
after Heather berated
him in the mud bath,
he went back to his room,
and he warriored up,
and he gave it a shot.
Bad shot.
I think he panicked
halfway across,
tripped and fell.
Forehead hitting an
unburned piece of cedar.
Discoloration on the chest that
we thought was bruising...
was really burns.
You know, the firewalk
was fenced off
from the rest of the spa.
Even if Justin Wade
warriored up,
there's only one person
who conducts the firewalk.
Alan Quinn.
Bad for business
if a client ends up
with third-degree burns
and in the hospital.
Better if he ends up
accidentally drowned
in the mud bath.
Letting the healing waters
cover up all the sins.
Justin Wade...
the floater in your mud.
He wasn't a hiker,
he was your client.
We have evidence
that ties Justin
to the kind of cedar
wood that you use
in your firewalk.
BRASS: He wanted to make a
firewalk to help his team.
He needed your
guidance, maybe?
BRASS:
Didn't turn out
so good, huh?
Come on, Alan.
You lied to us.
You were with
Justin that night.
Force of mind.
Be brave.
Tell us
what happened.
I had no idea
it was Justin.
Uh, he called me
to his room,
wanted to do a firewalk.
So, you took him up there?
No.
Uh, I sensed
he wasn't ready.
You know, I'd rather have
someone not do the walk
than try and fail.
Told him to go to bed.
What time was this?
Around 11:30.
Went home after that.
Back to your room.
No, home.
Santa Barbara.
Flew back Friday, midnight.
You fly like an eagle?
Or fly commercial?
Private jet.
Call my co-pilot,
he'll confirm it.
Hey, Doc.
Hey.
What do we got?
I am looking
at a sample from Justin Wade's
bronchial tissue.
I don't think the smoke
from the firewalk
caused this inflammation.
Take a look.
ROBBINS:
He had an acute mast cell
degranulation
resulting in a massive release
of histamines,
tryptases and chymases.
The guy suffered
anaphylactic shock.
Caused by what?
Unknown. I only see
effect, not cause.
That's weird.
We thought that Justin Wade
fell in the fire because
he had an anxiety attack.
No, what he really had
was an allergy attack.
Okay, well, I'll send
this tissue up to Hodges,
have him run a Rast test
and find out what caused it.
♪ ♪
Ciao, Morgan.
Hi.
Thanks for meeting me.
Yeah. I was actually surprised
you wanted to meet up with me.
I don't have so
many amici here.
Friends. So,
I was thinking
maybe we could talk.
David's speaking
about you so much.
I think you two guys...
are very close.
We're very good friends.
Friends?
To a certain degree.
What are we talking?
I just feel that there is a
weird distance between us.
I feel there is
something wrong.
Or, maybe...
someone else.
(chuckles):
Trust me, honey,
there is absolutely
nobody else.
When I look
at the two of you,
you are so great together.
And-and he is
smitten with you.
But why he seem
so unhappy lately?
He doesn't speak
about marriage anymore.
I think...
you need to talk to David.
You need to have
this conversation...
with him.
I'm not gonna ask.
Really?
How disappointing.
Mm, I'm not doing it.
I wore it for you.
Fine. What?
Common household items:
swim cap,
hot water bottle, balloons,
cleaning gloves,
bath mat, shower curtain--
they're all
made of latex.
And, uh, thanks
to my assiduous testing,
I've determined are the cause
of our victim's
allergic reaction.
He had a reaction
to latex?
Aren't you missing
the obvious,
the condom that we found
in the mud bath...?
We're not talking
about the pedestrian
skin contact here.
Justin Wade's
bronchial constriction
says he inhaled the latex.
SIDLE:
How's that happen?
HODGES:
Well, you know what they say:
where there's latex vapor
there's fire.
(Justin gasping)
So you're saying there
was latex in the burning
coals of the firewalk.
Greg's at the primary now,
looking for the culprit.
Interesting theory.
You know, latex allergy's
kind of a personal thing.
Yeah, something only
a spouse might know of.
Justin Wade's wife,
Mary, told me
that she'd been
to Alan Quinn's spa before.
So she knows
all about the firewalk.
Man alone in the mud bath
with two women,
one of whom admits
to hitting on him.
Workplace romance?
I wouldn't know anything
about that.
Just sayin'.
Could be a cause for murder.
I'm assuming you're aware your
husband had a latex allergy,
Mrs. Wade?
Yes, why?
We discovered that he had
an extreme allergic reaction
before he died.
But he was always so careful.
You said it was all
good between you two?
That's right.
Well, not according
to his phone records.
About three weeks ago,
Jessica Lowell
started calling Justin.
A lot.
Work calls, I'd imagine.
Most of the calls here
are after work,
after midnight, in fact.
What does this have to do...
with Justin's death?
Mary, you told me that you were
home the night that Justin died.
But that isn't true, is it?
You got a speeding ticket
ten miles from the spa
at, uh, let's see...
8:30 p.m.
Okay, I...
realize how this must look.
Looks bad.
Okay, yes.
I was on my way to the spa.
I had a feeling
about Jessica Lowell.
So you went
to confront them.
Yes.
But I didn't.
Okay, I filled up
my car, and I...
and I turned around,
and I went home.
Look, I told you...
I loved my husband.
And in the end...
that meant trusting him.
Just got back
from Alan Quinn's fire walk.
Knee-deep in coal ash,
found these.
Drug implant pellets.
Used for maintaining
hormone levels.
(laughs)
What are they made of?
Latex.
Looks to me like one of them
isn't fully burned.
Logo says...
"Made by Bixton."
The same company
Justin Wade worked for.
That can't be
a coincidence.
Nope.
Here, maybe I can get
a partial.
♪ ♪
RUSSELL:
Jessica Lowell
is not returning
Brass's phone calls.
She's also a
no-show at work.
Sounds like she's on the run.
Bixton sent over
her employee file.
Three years ago,
she was suspended
from work for six months.
She and two other employees
were under suspicion
of selling company secrets.
But she wasn't fired.
No.
They didn't have
enough on her.
Okay, so what
are we thinking?
That Jessica Lowell
was up to her
old tricks again,
stealing from the company?
Justin Wade finds out,
she kills him.
If that's the case, there's
still one more member
of "Team White-Tailed Eagle."
Heather Conner.
Right, and if
she found out
what Justin Wade found out,
we need to find her now.
Thank you.
All right, Heather, thank you
very much for coming in.
I don't know
what happened to Justin.
I swear.
Can I please have some water?
It's right there
in front of you.
Sorry, of course.
Heather,
you need to relax, okay?
You are not a suspect.
What we need right now
is to find Jessica.
Jessica's not
who she says she is.
Who is she?
A thief.
She steals company secrets.
And Justin found out.
Is that why he's dead?
Yes.
I think Jessica kills anyone
who gets in her way.
Oh, this water's terrible.
The Jessica Lowells
are destroying Bixton.
Consider a new typical drug.
After an average
development cost
of 900 million,
a successful launch depends
on sales reps delivering
complex information.
I put every fiber
of my soul into this company.
Into America!
Heather, slow down.
It's okay.
I try...
to do the right thing.
(wheezing): I try...
so hard to be good.
Are you okay?
(wheezing)
I need a medic! Oh, my God.
...2-3, we need
a medic in here.
I need a medic now!
Finn... hey, listen to me,
listen to me.
You did everything you could.
Now just-just get
the body to Doc
as soon as you can.
Whew! Finlay's at E.R.
Conner girl didn't make it.
I mean, it's crazy.
A seemingly healthy woman just
drops during an interrogation?
Kind of like Justin
taking a header
in the middle
of his firewalk.
Doesn't make any sense.
Well, the only
common denominator
is Jessica Lowell--
maybe she poisoned them both.
Do we know where she is yet?
Still in the wind.
ROBBINS: Haven't had a chance
to open up Heather Conner yet,
to determine C.O.D.--
but, in the washroom,
David found this.
White powder under
her fingernails.
Hodges says it's
magnesium sulfate.
Common dietary supplement.
Yeah, David found a
receipt in her purse.
She'd been stocking up on all
sorts of nutrients and powders.
Maybe Jessica Lowell spiked
her vitamin shake.
Could explain her death.
Now for the unexplainable.
David also found...
strands of animal hair.
Hodges I.D.'d it
as capra aegagrus hircus.
Goat?
Yeah.
She had goat hair
all over her.
I didn't say it made sense.
Mm, something better
start making sense.
You here on business or
to make another girl date
with my fiancée?
She told you we met.
No, uh, she texted
me by mistake.
"Morgan, thank you
for listening.
My new amica."
She just wanted to talk.
Look, I'm on your
side, Hodges.
She's a great girl.
Who feels that I'm backing away.
Are you?
Ah, saved by the tox report.
Whoa.
Heather Conner
was higher than Elvis
at the Vegas Hilton.
So she wasn't poisoned.
She O.D.'d.
Makes sense.
You said you found
magnesium sulfate
underneath
her fingernails, right?
Yeah, I thought that was
from a vitamin drink.
But it's also used
to manufacture meth.
Drug sales rep
becomes drug cook,
becomes drug addict.
Deadly career path.
So, she's tweaking on meth,
she's called in by PD.
She's worried that we figured
it all out-- the illegal drugs.
She takes some downers
to calm down.
And she downs herself forever,
right in front of us.
I hear you get very
thirsty on meth.
Check out the
stomach contents.
"Lacteal secretions high in
potassium, niacin and copper."
Milk.
Goat milk.
The udder milk.
Come on, it's too easy.
No, it's too much goat.
We found goat hair
on Heather's clothes.
(cell phone dings)
Text from Nick.
Our prime suspect,
Jessica Lowell,
just turned herself in.
STOKES:
Thought you were on the run.
Business trip.
I came back as
soon as possible.
I want to cooperate.
Well, that's good.
You knew the murder victim
Justin Wade.
The guy who was drowned
in a mud bath?
STOKES:
We found your prints
on the latex pellets
that were tossed
into the firewalk
to knock Justin out.
Those pellets were samples.
We all had them
at the retreat.
Captain Brass, I believe
you know Colin Garrett
with the FBI field office here.
Mm-hmm.
We're working together.
I'm not a sales rep.
I handle corporate
security at Bixton.
I'm teamed up with
the FBI right now.
Justin Wade and Heather Conner
were under investigation
for stealing research and drugs
to manufacture designer meth.
Just slip your mind
to mention that to me before?
And the last time I checked,
big pharmaceuticals
don't sell street meth.
No.
But we have all
the chemicals at hand,
and cutting-edge lab technology.
We believe they set up
a lab somewhere.
BRASS:
Well, that still doesn't explain
how Justin ended up dead.
Are you familiar
with Rolan Zahl?
Drug distributor-- bad news.
JESSICA:
Worse news for Justin.
Zahl was his street connect.
Feds think that once he
finished with the lab,
he became expendable.
So you're saying
that Justin Wade's murder
was a drug hit?
You have a better theory?
Did you follow up on the
Rolan Zahl drug angle?
Yup, I tested
some meth pulled off
a Mad-10 dealer two days ago.
Same trace contaminants we
found in Heather Conner?
To a tee.
Okay, well, I did a little
follow-up of my own
on the magnesium sulfate
from, uh, Heather's
fingernails.
Uh-huh.
According to her credit cards,
she bought about
200 pounds of the stuff
last month,
from a medical
supply company.
And it was shipped
to Greenlore Scientific.
AKA our secret meth lab.
That's right.
Looks like it's time
to pay a visit
to 93644 Dagwood Street.
(sirens wailing)
LVPD! Open up!
Go, Stokes.
Go.
(bleating)
What the...?
(glass breaks nearby,
goat bleats)
(door creaking)
Looks like they cleared out.
Think we found our lab.
Yeah, what's left of it.
Hold on, Nick.
Check this out.
Well, somebody
trashed the place.
This is too elaborate just
to manufacture meth.
Industrial fridge.
Don't usually see that
in a meth lab.
Nope.
Got milk?
Right-- goat's milk,
I'm guessing.
SIDLE: Distillation condenser--
this is some very
complex chemistry.
STOKES:
Microporous membranes?
You don't use that to make meth.
I got to say
a lot of the stuff
in here just doesn't fit
with making street drugs.
(distant thump)
Mrs. Wade?!
Please don't hurt me.
SANDERS: Nick's still
collecting evidence,
but he sent over some trace
from the farmhouse lab.
It's definitely meth.
So, what do you think?
Husband and wife
cooking team?
Looks like it.
"Looks like it"?
The goat milk
doesn't make sense.
Well, maybe it's
some kind of
cutting agent for the meth.
Ah, it's more than that.
There was...
a lot of sophisticated
equipment in that lab;
stuff you don't
need to make meth.
Something else was cooking
in that kitchen.
(coughs)
(door opens)
I know you think Justin,
Heather and I are all
meth dealers.
Yeah, I do.
And I know why:
you need the money
because you're sick.
I... have a chronic deficiency
of the antithrombin.
It's an anti-coagulant.
And without it, I'm...
in constant danger
of blood clots.
Which can cause a
pulmonary embolism.
So, Justin was using a Bixton
drug formula to help you.
It uses goat milk to make
the antithrombin protein.
It's why Justin took the job
with Bixton in the first place.
To steal the recipe?
Yes.
The drug's called "Btryn."
It was canceled during
clinical trials three years ago.
Company deemed it
too expensive.
My disease
is extremely rare,
so there wouldn't
have been enough customers.
Yeah, those pharmaceutical
giants have their bills to pay.
So, Justin started
making the drug himself.
But he needed
the money to do it.
That's where Heather came in.
It was her crazy idea
to set up the lab.
Was the Btryn working?
I've been on it
for about a month now.
Justin was right.
It's-it's actually helped
stabilize me.
I never knew
that he was making meth.
I only found out about it
a couple days ago.
You know, I don't get why
you destroyed the lab.
I mean, it was your one
chance to get the medicine.
I... I didn't destroy it.
I went to get my last dose.
If Mary Wade's
telling the truth...
and she isn't the one
that trashed this place...
Then who did?
All this...
destruction, this rage.
This is personal.
Yeah, I think
I got something here.
In the sink. Check it out.
STOKES: Maybe in the middle
of going Hulk,
our suspect cut
himself on some glass.
BRODY:
Rinsed it off in the sink.
And left behind some blood.
♪ ♪
Russell?
I got DNA on the blood
from the meth lab sink.
You are not gonna believe
who broke into the place.
QUINN (inhaling, exhaling):
Come on, Sheila.
Exhale the weakness.
Release the toxins.
(exhaling)
Feels strong, right?
Just have faith in me.
(inhaling):
No fear.
Mary Wade have
faith in you, Alan?
I'm sorry?
Can you give us a second?
I wanted to talk to Alan
about the blood he left
in the meth lab.
Because you did.
When you broke in.
Force of entry more
than force of mind.
I have no idea
what you're talking about.
Did you teach Mary your
breathing exercises?
And... did you know
she was sick?
I wouldn't--
Because we checked
your credit cards.
You've been shipping her
cases of that Spirit Force
drink of yours.
You do that
for all your clients, Alan?
I'm trying to help Mary.
Well, of course
you are.
I mean, good heavens, you're
in love with her, right?
Mary's a very special...
very brave woman.
Yeah, she is.
But you didn't
answer my question.
You know,
I came from nothing.
Built an empire.
Truth is, I never found
anyone who interested me.
Until Mary.
When you find
your other half,
that...
is what it's
really like to fly.
Have you found
your other half?
Wow.
That's so romantic.
The truth is, she
didn't want to fly
with you, did she?
I mean, she didn't
want to have anything
to do with you, Alan.
And you know why?
Because her husband
already found a cure for her.
Something that actually worked.
Is that what happened?
Hmm?
You found out that
his worked, yours didn't?
Is that why you
destroyed his lab?
Well, come on, man.
Usually you have
all the answers.
You know something?
I've seen people
like you before.
And you
make me sick.
You sell snake oil
to the weak.
So you think Justin Wade
was so good?
He was poisoning her.
I wasn't gonna
watch her die.
(scoffs)
Modern medicine?
That's the real snake oil here.
They spend millions
conning people into
buying chemicals and pills,
so they can make billions.
(scoffs) The weak?
I...
I make people strong.
Justin Wade, he didn't
understand that.
And he didn't
understand Mary.
I do.
You killed him, didn't you?
You're damn right I did.
Whatever it took
to save Mary's life.
To heal her; to make her fly.
And I'd do it again.
Thank you.
(clears throat)
ELISABETTA:
David,
everything is okay?
Are you still upset
because I didn't tell
you about my past?
No, no, it has nothing
to do with that.
I don't care that you
were married for a week.
Because...
I want to marry you.
For...forever.
Then why are you
running from me?
'Cause I'm an idiot.
And I'm afraid.
Of what?
Me?
My family?
No, no. Um...
Having a family.
My father...
wasn't around very
much when I grew up
and when he was around,
he-he really wasn't.
He was a scientist.
He was always holed up
in the basement.
You're afraid
you will turn into him?
Terrified.
David...
you fear things
that have never happened.
Don't you think
it's a waste of time?
Not if I'm wasting
it with you.
Hey.
I, uh, have your
husband's wedding ring.
Thanks.
Blood test confirmed
your illness.
I hope someday there's a
drug that will help you.
Have you ever...
flown in your dreams?
Ever since Justin died
I'm so numb all day,
but when I sleep...
I'm healthy, I'm free and...
...I fly.
And he's with me somehow.
And then I wake and...
I'm alone
but I'm...
I'm not as sad.
Because I can
still feel his presence.
You two must've loved
each other very much.
I'm sorry.
Maybe someday, there'll be
a drug that can save me.
Maybe not.
All I know is when I remember
all the good that we had...
I'm fearless.