♪ ♪
(indistinct police radio
transmission)
You need anything else, hon?
No. Thank you.
WOMAN:
He loves his little sister.
(laughing):
Look at...
I love 'em.
Here you go, Miss Connie.
Oh, thank you.
You're welcome.
Edie, did I show
you these yet?
Aw.
Look how precious.
I can't believe how big
those grandbabies are getting.
I know.
Hey, guys.
Whenever you're ready, okay?
Thanks.
Thanks, Edie.
MAN:
Sheila, it's 4:00
in the morning.
Do we really have to
fight about this now?
Looking good.
Not for you, young lady.
We've been married
for three years.
You know me
better than that.
Strawberries.
I don't know
what your secret is,
but one of these days,
you're gonna have to share it
with my brother.
Babe,
why do we keep having
the same conversation?
It's not going to
change anything.
But it's not up to you.
This time it's up to me.
I don't know how
you keep that figure
drinking one of these
every night.
Work it off on stage, honey.
Trust me.
You should come see
the show sometime.
Yeah.
I thought
you were off at 4:00.
I'm-I'm staying
a while longer.
OFFICER:
Is that guy still bothering you?
Can't you two
make him disappear?
Hey, I'll tell you what,
we'll have a little
talk with him
on the way out.
Thanks.
Looks like your problem
disappeared, Edie.
MAN (over radio):
3-David-11, respond to 308...
Control,
3-David-11, copy.
Bye, guys.
All right, see
you, fellas.
I got to get more
hash browns.
Okay.
(glass shatters in distance)
STOKES:
Hey, you know what I'm
talking about, though.
I'm talking about the dish
with the tortillas and the...
(laughing):
Yeah, I know what you mean.
(sighs) I can't believe
we've been coming here
for the past 12 years
and you've never had
the chilaquiles.
I don't like chilaquiles.
Seriously? Have
you had Vincent's?
No.
Sara.
Huh?
Help me out here.
You know, I'm not a fan either.
Really?
Yeah...
Hi.
Vincent call you guys, too?
No, we're just
coming here to grab
something to eat. Why?
Not sure. Vincent said
he's stuck in the fridge.
Can't get his brother
to answer his cell.
Maybe he's enjoying
some "chilly-killies."
STOKES:
No, no, its "cheelay-keelays."
Oh, my God.
OFFICER:
Control, 3-David-10.
Multiple 419s at Frank's Diner.
Owen's dead.
Yeah, so is Dahlia.
SIDLE:
It's Edie.
We just left her.
She's dead, too.
STOKES:
Let's take the back.
Come on, let's go.
Clear.
(quietly):
Freezer.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
J-Just me, guys.
Hey, Vincent,
let's go out back.
Why? Wh-What's happening?
Let's just go out back.
OFFICER:
Go in there. Come on, come on.
Vincent, stop, Vincent, no.
VINCENT (quietly):
No.
Vincent...
Come on, man.
There's blood on
the floor here.
This can't be!
I just...
VINCENT (panting):
Nick...
They're all dead.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
(siren wails, tires screech)
What the hell happened?
You were here?
We'd just left.
Captain, it was only
a couple minutes.
Register's cleaned out.
It looks like a robbery, maybe.
Maybe?
Edie was having trouble
with some guy, a stalker.
He was hanging
around out front.
Well, did you do
anything about it?
Wish we had.
We were gonna go talk
to him, but he was gone
before we even got outside.
We know this guy, right?
Yeah.
Yes.
So put a broadcast on!
Get him here!
Yes, sir.
(bell tinkles)
(groans):
Oh, man.
You know, I-I been coming here
probably 20 years.
Even had Thanksgiving
dinner here when I
first came to Vegas.
Shooter must've come in
the front door.
I mean, the trouble started
right there with Owen.
And you know Dahlia always
sits at the counter.
Must've tried
to jump in.
Once a marine, always a marine.
(heavy sigh)
I always used to notice them
when they came in here.
The way they looked
at each other.
They seemed so... content.
Seemed to have marriage
all figured out.
Look at that.
I know most of the faces
in here.
Ever see these two guys before?
No, I haven't.
But Connie was always happy
to see a fresh face
so she could show off
her grandkids.
All this carnage, you know.
I don't buy robbery.
Akers is putting a broadcast out
on the stalker.
Ronald Basderic.
Been terrorizing Edie
for six months.
Wasn't enough to kill her.
He wanted to destroy
her whole world.
Gunshot to the head,
up close and personal.
I tried to help her
get a restraining order,
but the judge denied it.
Basderic has been very careful.
He'd push right up to the line
and never cross it.
Until now.
Shoe impression.
They don't match
any of the shoes in here.
(phone ringing)
I got to take this.
(beep)
Yeah, go ahead.
(door opens)
(bell tinkles)
♪ ♪
FINLAY:
Whoa.
You step on my finger,
I'll kill you.
Ten inches in front
of your left foot.
Could you mark it?
Thanks.
Hey, guys, could I just have
an hour to be alone
so I can work the blood?
SANDERS: I was just going
to check the walk-in.
Is there blood?
No.
Okay.
♪ ♪
Hello?
(sighs)
(exhales)
(beep)
(sighs)
(phone chimes)
Ah.
Hey, Finn.
I found something.
(laughs)
Well, I'd... I'd love to,
but, uh... you're
gonna have to come to me.
VINCENT:
This is so horrible.
OFFICER:
I know it's been a
long night, Vincent,
but they still need
to talk to you.
It's okay, Charlie,
I'll take care of him.
Yeah.
Hey, Vincent.
Nick.
How could this happen?
I don't know yet, man.
We're just getting started.
Now, do you have
any other clothes?
'Cause the minute
you stepped in blood,
you became evidence,
you know that, right?
No, I-I understand.
How many times have
I heard you guys talk
about crime scenes?
No, no, that's okay,
I'll get it.
Just relax.
Okay, turn around for me.
Vincent?
Oh, God.
That's Sheila,
Owen's wife.
Vincent, they called me,
but they're wrong.
It's not true, right?
He's okay!
Please!
(sobbing):
Tell me he's okay!
(crying):
I'm so sorry.
(sobbing):
No!
Sheila.
No, no, Vincent.
Now, get back.
I can't let
you do that.
Not until I've processed
your clothes, okay?
VINCENT:
Okay.
What's all the fuss?
You look okay to me.
And here I thought you weren't
gonna come visit me.
You got in just under
the wire, mister.
Yeah, I know.
I'm sorry.
No, that's...
Barbara and I had to take Maya
and Katie back up to Seattle.
I took a little time off.
How you feeling?
You know...
Honestly, it hurts.
I wouldn't recommend
getting shot.
Although it did get my daughter
to tell me she loves me, so...
Can't be bad.
Yeah.
How is your family?
Better.
Thank you.
Barbara's gonna
stay there for a while.
Help them get settled in.
(sighs)
Damn it.
Oh, come on.
There it is.
Thanks.
Yeah.
(sighs)
Good, you're dressed.
We got to go.
Hi.
Honey, look, if you
don't have the time...
No, I-I want
to take you home.
I just can't stick around.
Got a call.
All hands on deck.
That's the diner?
Mm-hmm.
Finn told me that
she had that handled.
Well, I got "all hands."
All right.
I better take off.
I'm happy to see you.
Really, thanks for stopping by.
Yeah.
See you there.
Hey.
You're not supposed
to be working, remember?
No, you're right.
Hmm.
I'm gonna get a nurse.
Get you out of here.
Yeah, it's Ecklie.
Get me the sheriff.
You know, I appreciate you
having my back,
but I think you might
have misrepresented
the situation
just a little bit.
Yeah, in what way?
Pretty sure that I said
that it was something
that I could handle.
I think your exact words were,
"It's nothing to worry about."
Oh, and are you worried?
Yeah, a little bit.
You look stumped.
I'm not stumped.
I'm thinking.
I've released
the other bodies,
but there's something odd
about these three.
I'm going with stumped.
Thinking.
Look at the blood
on this guy's chin.
Unless gravity's been altered,
it's going the wrong way.
RUSSELL:
Yeah, you're right.
This guy's lying down now,
but he had to be upright
when he was shot.
Mm-hmm.
And over here,
on this guy...
There's no exit wound,
and yet,
his back is all bloody.
Which means he was
laying down, not sitting.
Where's her wound?
(sighs)
On the right.
How was she shot on the right
while she was sitting here?
She wasn't.
Someone moved all three of these
bodies after they were shot.
Hey.
Hi.
BRODY:
Whoa.
They had a camera
in the walk-in?
Yeah, Vincent said
someone was pilfering steak
and lobster a while back.
How long was
Vincent in there?
Well, the camera's
motion-activated,
and there's no time code,
so I checked cell records
from the first time
he dialed his brother
until the cops let him out.
Under seven minutes.
You buy he got
locked in there?
It happens easier
than you'd think.
Not interrupting.
I just, uh... I wanted
to find out about,
uh, your father.
Uh, he's getting out
of the hospital today,
and I wanted to see
how that all went.
It was... fine.
Thank you for asking, though.
Yeah, it's, uh,
no trouble at all.
Uh, to ask,
I mean.
Uh, yeah, I'm-I'm...
I'm gonna go.
(Sanders scoffs)
Did he seem weird to you?
I mean, weirder than usual.
No, not at all.
I got three more in the hallway.
Well, I can always
use the overtime.
Why don't you, uh, prep
this young lady?
I'm almost done
with Dahlia.
Yeah.
Can I help you?
I'm looking for a loved
one who was brought in.
Edie Graham.
Reception let you
come back here?
I might have given them
the impression
I worked for the mortuary.
ROBBINS:
So, you're
the next of kin?
I'm the closest
thing Edie's got.
We were gonna be married.
I see, Mr...
Basderic.
David,
call Sara.
Tell her to bring down
Edie's paperwork right away
for Mr. Basderic.
Right.
(chuckles)
We met at the diner
where she worked.
I went in there a lot.
She was always so good to me.
So warm.
I just knew.
And I could see in her
eyes... she felt it, too.
I'm sorry for your loss.
Right there.
I can't allow you to touch her.
I'd like to put the
ring on her finger.
No, I'm sorry.
That's him.
That's Basderic.
Hello, Ronald.
It's a match.
You're done,
you son of a bitch.
Where are my clothes?
I want my clothes.
That prison
jumpsuit
is the only clothes
you need to worry about now.
When you return them,
I expect them to be
in the condition
in which you received them.
I'm very particular.
SIDLE:
We have you
in the diner, Ronald.
You stepped in Edie's blood.
I went in to check on her.
Cops saw you stalking
her from outside
right before the shooting.
I wasn't stalking;
I was observing.
You were there.
Yes.
But I knew the officers
would harass me,
so I took a walk
around the block.
When I got back,
I could tell
something was wrong.
That's when I went inside.
She was already dead.
Why didn't you call 911?
Because she was already dead.
BRASS:
Okay, you didn't do it,
so you must have seen who did.
I told you, I went for
a walk around the block.
If I knew who killed Edie,
I would tell you.
They took her from me.
She was mine.
Do you own a gun, Ronald?
I would never.
I hate guns.
Open your mouth.
No.
You can't make me.
Not without my consent.
I can get a court order.
Good luck with that.
I can't imagine too many judges
being receptive
to your requests.
What with your
corruption scandal and all.
Three bodies all
moved after the fact.
Why were they moved,
and who moved them?
Do we know who they are?
STOKES:
Yeah, this is Connie.
She was a regular
at the diner.
A bus driver who drove
the 5:00 a.m. shift
so that she
could be at home
with her grandkids
in the afternoon.
Their mom's a
blackjack dealer.
This one I don't know.
Who is this, Super Dave?
Oh, I found an Arizona
driver's license.
Robert Rios.
I ran him through
mobile AFIS.
There's no criminal history.
And this guy,
Alex Brenner.
Local address.
Look at that,
brand-new license.
Mint condition.
PHILLIPS:
I'm running his prints now.
Access blocked.
I have a feeling our
friend Alex Brenner here
isn't Alex Brenner.
BRASS: Sheriff, I'm aware
of the pressure
that you're getting
from the press on this case.
No, I know, I get it, I get it.
No, I don't disagree.
No, especially in light
of what's going on
in the department.
But I have a feeling that
the answer you're looking for
is staring at me
right now in my office.
I'll get back to you.
Captain.
Karen Taylor,
Deputy U.S. Marshal.
Your department
ran fingerprints
on someone we have
an interest in.
Let me guess: Alex Brenner.
That's what you Feds
are calling him, right?
And since it's
U.S. Marshals in my office
and not FBI, I'm guessing he
was in Witness Protection.
So, who is he really?
Obviously, I can't
tell you that.
Who are you protecting him from?
I can't tell you
that, either.
Miss Taylor,
you dropped this guy
in my jurisdiction
without even bothering
to call the department.
Now he's one of eight victims
in a multiple homicide that
just so happened to have killed
several of my friends.
Now, you got about two
seconds to tell me something
or I'll have you
thrown out of here.
Alex Brenner testified
against some really bad people
about four months ago.
We dropped him
in Las Vegas just last week.
As for our failure
to notify LVPD, frankly,
we didn't know
if you could be trusted.
(sighs)
Okay.
So, these "bad people,"
are they the kind that would
sacrifice seven innocent lives
just to get the
one they want?
I believe so.
Yes.
Pretty intense look
you have
going on there.
What are you
searching for?
Edie's stalker, Basderic.
He knows the law.
Up until last night, he
has known exactly how far
he could go without
crossing the line.
Okay.
But the guy is sick.
Edie couldn't
have been his first.
He-he must've screwed up
somewhere before.
I just haven't been
able to find it.
Well, have you tried
searching court records
for other TROs
or denied apps?
Yeah, I did that.
I'm on criminal records now.
Ok, well, how about I take
civil court.
Basderic's not a common name.
Well, you never know.
Oh, here's something.
Apparently,
Basderic was involved
in a lawsuit.
Who sued him?
Actually, he was the plaintiff.
He sued for damages
after some guy assaulted him.
Well, what do
you want to bet
that the guy was the boyfriend
or the husband
of some poor woman
that Basderic was stalking?
Well, the judge sided
with Basderic
and awarded him
almost $200,000.
I hate this guy.
I hate the way he works the law.
Well, this probably won't ease
your blood pressure any,
but during the assault,
Basderic actually
shot the guy.
He shot his attacker?
Legally, it was
self-defense.
Point is...
he had a gun.
Hey, Doc.
Hey.
We need to take a long,
hard look at Alex Brenner.
You care to elaborate?
Well, he was in the
Witness Protection Program.
We're thinking maybe that's
what got him killed.
Along with everybody
else in the diner.
What can you tell us
about where he's been?
Well, there are some things
that suggest his history.
Dental work, certainly.
I don't think it
was done in the U.S.
Mexico, maybe.
Hmm.
What else?
He was suffering from talcosis.
I found talc granulomas
in his lungs.
Talc?
Yeah, it's a condition
usually associated
with drug use.
People inject talc-diluted
heroin or cocaine.
But there's no evidence
that he was a drug user.
So how did the talc get
into his body?
Probably inhaled.
I'm thinking that he
spent a lot of time
in an environment where talc
was used, breathed it in.
Yeah, drug environment.
If he was cutting heroin
and cocaine with talc.
It's not an
unreasonable inference.
Stomach content was waffles.
Is that significant?
If he ate waffles,
that puts him
in the corner booth
where we found Rios.
What did Rios eat?
Hmm.
His stomach
was filled with pizza.
Frank's Diner
doesn't serve pizza.
Maybe he wasn't there to eat.
Okay, what more can you tell us
about Rios?
I found fibers in his
upper trachea and esophagus
as well as his mouth.
I gave them to Hodges,
but he hasn't
tested them yet.
Until a minute ago,
Mr. Rios here was on
the back burner.
He's on the front burner now.
HODGES: The pizza would
have raised a red flag
had I known that the
diner didn't serve pizza,
but I didn't know
that the diner
didn't serve pizza.
You care to guess why?
Because no one ever includes me
whenever they go to the diner.
Positive for lead.
What about the fiber?
It's a microfiber.
Polyethylene terephthalate
to be more precise.
More commonly known
as polar fleece.
Like a jacket.
Or, considering
that he inhaled it,
I think Rios
was wearing a ski mask.
The belt tested positive
for lead.
Tells me he had a gun.
And a mask.
Robert Rios was not a victim.
He was the shooter.
STOKES: Robert Rios
had an Arizona license.
PD's there checking
into him now.
I guess the
bigger question is,
if Rios is our shooter,
who shot Rios?
Probably whoever
hired him.
Could be the cartel if they
were after Alex Brenner.
You know, once the
dirty work's done,
you bring somebody in;
a cleaner.
Kill Rios, take his gun,
move the bodies.
Okay, you know what?
Let's not wait
for the cops in Arizona.
Dig into Rios.
Get whatever you can, okay?
All right, I'm on it.
All right, I'm here.
What's the issue?
I ran ballistics on all
15 rounds that were fired.
Turns out five of them
were from a second gun.
Well, that's consistent
with the idea
of a cleaner, right?
We know
at least two of the shots
were the ones that killed Rios.
And we've got
the point-blank
on the waitress, Edie.
Then I've got two misses.
Misses?
Wouldn't have thought
a cleaner would be sloppy.
That's not all. Check this out.
The red laser is a miss
from Rios's gun.
The green is the cleaner's.
Two different guns,
both fired
from the same place.
Doesn't make any sense.
Yeah.
Is that can where it was
when you found it?
No, it was on the floor.
I replaced it.
But there was oil residue
on the counter,
so I knew where
to put it.
Let me try something here.
Excuse me a sec.
Square peg in a square hole.
Shots came from there.
Alex Brenner had the second gun.
It fits with everything
we know about him.
He was in
Witness Protection.
He was fearing for his life,
so he was carrying.
Call Finn. Get her down here.
I want to run this thing.
Okay, I'm Rios.
I'm the shooter.
Where do we start?
Okay, first event
happens here.
Owen and the shooter
struggle,
and fight for control
of the gun.
The gun discharges,
severing Owen's finger.
FINLAY: Okay,
and then at some point
during the struggle,
Dahlia gets up off of her stool,
and comes over
and tries to help.
First shot misses,
hits the chocolate milk shake,
and the next two
take Dahlia down.
Now, I just shot two people
pretty quickly.
If I'm robbing the place,
why don't I just
turn around and leave?
Why do I keep killing?
Well, we know that you
were wearing a mask.
Maybe it came off
during the struggle.
So I'm eliminating witnesses.
Or you haven't hit
your target yet.
So the waitress is next?
FINLAY:
Shot goes through the coffee
pot, and then into her chest.
What about the coup de grâce?
Well, given that Edie crawled,
that actually comes later.
The old couple comes next.
They are sitting targets,
literally.
He tries to shield her,
he gets the first shot,
and she gets the second.
That leaves
just two more targets:
Alex and the bus driver Connie.
Yeah, she goes first,
running towards the restrooms,
probably trying to escape.
Shot catches her in the side,
just below her armpit.
That leaves Alex,
and he just saw me
shoot six people.
And we now know
he has a gun.
And he knows
that I'm coming for him.
So he tries to defend himself.
Both shots miss
and hit the olive oil can.
And I put two into him.
SIDLE:
As far as Rios goes,
that's the end
of the shooting.
Time for the cleaner.
Say that's me.
Vincent said that they kept the
back door open to let air in,
so I could have come
from back here.
And I, Rios, know you,
so I don't shoot.
But I do something
that you are
definitely not expecting.
I pick up Alex's gun,
and I shoot you.
Which leaves one final shot:
the coup de grâce
to Edie's head.
So Edie crawls out
from behind the counter.
I realize she's alive.
She's just seen me shoot Rios.
I go up to her and...
final shot.
So the theory is
Alex was the target.
Wait a minute.
It still doesn't explain
Edie's stalker, Basderic.
We know he
was here.
He left shoe impressions
right there.
So are you thinking
that Basderic put the kill shot
into Edie?
He felt rebuffed by her.
We know he's gone off before.
He lied about
never having had a gun.
(phone rings)
Hold on a sec.
Hey, Nick.
Yeah, just got access to
Robert Rios's banking records.
Somebody we know
has been writing him
some big checks.
Who?
His ex-girlfriend.
BRASS:
You know, Mrs. DeMarcus,
this must be a
complicated time.
I mean, who
do you mourn?
Your dead husband
or the other guy
you were involved with?
There was nothing going on
between me and Robert.
Well, not anymore.
So you didn't pay him
to kill your husband?
Why would you think that?
You gave him $6,000
last month.
$5,000 the month before.
$10,000 the month
before that.
I help Robert out.
I have for a long time.
He had a gambling problem.
He owed people money.
I didn't want
to see him hurt.
Mmm.
Why on earth
would I want Owen dead?
I don't know.
Maybe your marriage
was in trouble.
Our marriage wasn't in trouble.
Owen and I were fine.
Owen didn't love the fact
that she kept bailing out Rios,
but it was her money.
That's what you get
for marrying a rich girl.
STOKES:
Did you ever hear them
fight about it?
Sure, but they fought
all the time.
That was part of the attraction.
That kind of passion
can turn bad.
Believe me,
I've seen it happen.
Not them.
I-I-I'm telling you,
things were going well.
Even the money thing.
What do you mean by that?
Owen and I were working a deal
with the Mediterranean.
They want to put
a Frank's Diner in the casino.
Owen was about to have
plenty of money of his own.
Both of us.
Trust me, Nick.
There's no way Sheila is the
one who's behind what happened.
(over radio): All units,
possible 413, shots fired.
Corner of Dermott and Westfall.
Repeat...
That's the diner.
What's going on?
Uh, not sure.
Shots fired at the diner.
No, stay here, Vincent.
We'll handle it.
Coming through.
What's up?
OFFICER MITCHELL:
Nick, relax, man.
What's up?
Code four.
Accidental discharge.
Newspaper guy.
STOKES:
What's he doing out of bed?
Hey, Ecklie.
Didn't you get shot?
Come on, man,
you know the drill.
You got to give yourself
some time to heal here.
Thanks for the advice, Nick.
Here's the gun.
Nine-millimeter?
That's the same caliber
as the diner.
Yep.
Guy was refilling
the newspaper machines.
He took the day-old papers out,
was stacking them
in his truck for recycling
when the gun fell out.
He picked it up.
It discharged.
Where's the second one?
We know there
were two guns.
(sighs)
Here we go.
This one's a little bit thicker
than the others.
There she is.
The second gun.
Both of these guns
have been wiped clean.
Same with the shells.
There's nothing on them.
SIDLE:
But the ninhydrins brought up
some useful prints on the paper.
Okay.
It sounds to me
like after the shooting,
our guy leaves the diner looking
to dump the guns somewhere
and sees the newspaper machine.
For a buck in quarters,
he's found
a pretty good place
to hide them.
It's already Monday--
it's unlikely
that anybody's going to
buy the Sunday paper,
so the guns stay put until the
delivery guy hauls them away.
Mm-hmm.
We got a match.
Ronald Basderic.
BRASS:
How'd you meet Rios?
Gamblers Anonymous?
Some twisted chat room?
I don't know
what you're talking about.
I don't know any Rios.
Listen, Ronald, we're
just trying to give you
a chance to
explain yourself.
Your fingerprints
are on the paper.
The gun was inside.
Your footprints
are in the diner.
You are never
going to see
the light of
day again.
BRASS:
Hey.
Don't touch the evidence.
Can you just fix that?
That newspaper machine
is on public property.
I can legally be there.
I can watch Edie from there.
Hey.
You know how, when you
make a sandwich,
you don't like
to use the heel?
Right, so when
you open up
the package of bread,
what do you do?
I, uh... well, I move
the heel out of the way,
reach past it
and I grab a slice
from the middle
of the loaf.
Yeah, me, too.
What's your point?
The point is,
it's the same thing with
a newspaper machine.
You don't take
the top copy,
right, that has
a fold in it?
You lift it up, and you
take the one underneath.
Especially if you're
as OCD as this guy is.
So he lifts it up and takes
a clean copy from the middle.
He bought a paper
the day before--
this one was on top--
and that's how
his prints got on it?
You think Basderic's prints
were already there
when the cleaner
hid the guns there?
Hey.
Find anything?
Do you have any idea
how many people touch this thing
on a given day, week, month?
You check the inside?
Door won't open.
You need a quarter?
Oh, that's funny.
But the coin slot's jammed.
My guess: it's
not by accident.
Whoever stashed those guns
probably didn't want
anyone to find them.
What is it?
It's a foreign coin.
Chinese.
Is that bad?
Nick, you know me.
I thought I did.
Till I found that.
You keep a bowl
below the register
for all the foreign coins
that end up at the diner.
You showed it
to me once, remember?
Come on, it's a coin. So what?
So I don't miss details,
Vincent.
I want you to take a look
at a couple of photos.
That's the apron you had on
when you went into the fridge.
And that's the one you had on
when we let you out.
Take a look at the strands.
This one's white,
and this one's blue.
You switched the aprons.
Wh-What?
Why would I do that?
To hide the evidence.
It's the same reason
you moved the bodies
and dumped the mop bucket.
Here's the apron
you started with.
I had to tear
the back room apart,
but I found it.
You've been working
in that restaurant
since you were ten years old.
I've never even known you
to take a vacation.
I mean, I've seen
the car that you drive.
You've sacrificed
everything
to keep that
family business going.
But your brother--
he's a different story,
isn't he?
He married a rich girl,
he buys nice things,
he travels.
And then, finally,
one day, your ship comes in.
The Mediterranean wants to put
a Frank's Diner in the casino.
That's got to be
a big payday, Vincent.
How much was that worth?
I don't know.
Sure, you do.
You know exactly
how much.
But your brother, he vetoed it.
Didn't he?
He said no.
Hmm?
That was my payoff.
My reward for 40 years
of giving everything.
And he said no, just like that.
And now eight people are dead.
I never wanted that to happen.
Rios was supposed to
do a fake robbery.
I knew Owen would fight back.
Rios was just supposed
to shoot him and get out.
That's it.
What the hell did you do?
What'd you do?
He pulled off my mask.
They saw my face.
I had no choice.
STOKES:
And at that point, you knew
there was no turning back,
so you shot him.
You were afraid
that we'd eventually
connect Rios back to you,
so you tried to make him look
like a customer.
And moved the bodies.
VINCENT:
The apron.
The mop bucket.
Like you said, I...
I learned a few things.
Not enough.
Nick, please.
Don't look at
me like that.
I was just desperate.
Just pushed too far.
I'm not a monster.
No?
What about Edie?
She was still alive, wasn't she?
And she witnessed
everything that you did.
So you put a gun to her head...
(sobbing)
...and you pulled the trigger.
BASDERIC:
You see?
You were wrong
about me.
I didn't hurt her.
I couldn't. I loved her.
You loved her?
Are you kidding me?
You terrorized her.
You kept her
awake at night.
You made her afraid to
walk down the street.
And you want to know what
else your twisted love did?
It killed her, Ronald.
Edie was supposed to
be off work at 4:00.
She should have been gone
when the shooting happened,
but she was afraid
to walk home
because she was afraid
that you were out there.
It's because of you
that she stayed,
and now she's dead.
RUSSELL:
I know, Barbara.
I-I know that.
But this is our home now.
I'm here. Charlie's here.
Uh, sweetheart,
I'm going to have to call
you back, all right?
I got to go.
I love you.
Hey.
Is Barbara okay?
Yeah.
When's she coming back?
Uh, she's going to stay
up in Seattle
for a little while longer.
Maya needs her.
Do you need me to stay
for anything?
No. Go home.
Thank you.
And good work on this one.
Thanks.