(coyotes howling)
(indistinct radio communication,
siren whoops)
I saw a movie that
started like this.
It did not end well.
Alien invasion.
Sheriff Anderson, Davis County.
Thanks for coming.
CSI Russell,
CSI Finlay.
What's with all the men
in black?
ANDERSON:
Nellis Air Force Base
is down the road.
Apparently they just broke
a very expensive toy.
You said something
about a grave over the phone?
A couple hikers called
in about a light show.
I was first
on the scene.
I noticed some disturbed earth.
Want to follow me?
Three tours in Iraq,
saw my share of mass graves.
They looked
just like this.
RUSSELL:
Roughly three
meters square.
Vegetation has
barely grown back.
FINLAY:
Desert varnish is on the
ground side of the rock,
should be on the side
facing the sun.
This area's definitely
been worked.
There's only one reason
to dig a hole this far out
in the middle of nowhere.
Oh, here you go.
Bracelet says that it's female.
RUSSELL:
Right.
WOMAN:
Excuse me.
This is a Federal
investigation.
You're in a
restricted area.
Well, ma'am, we just found
a buried body,
so this is now
an LVPD crime scene.
You're gonna have
to leave the area.
You know,
if you keep insisting,
you're gonna be in violation
of NRS197-point-190.
Interfering with
public officers
in the discharge
of their official duties.
FINLAY:
In other words, our body
trumps your X-Files convention.
Right.
Let them have their grave,
keep them out of my hair.
That's the first time
that ever worked.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
PHILLIPS:
Tissue on the extremities
and skull is largely gone.
Remaining tissue is desiccated.
What's it smell like?
(sniffs)
Smells like dirt.
It means the body's been buried
for more than five years.
David, hold the camera
steady, please.
Yeah.
Well, the body's
strangely preserved.
Much lighter than what
we're accustomed to seeing.
How many bodies so far?
Three.
They all appear
to be female.
Another desiccated
fern leaf.
Unless these bodies were buried
in the Jurassic age,
they're not from around here.
RUSSELL: And neither's
this dark, rich soil.
Could be that the bodies were
buried somewhere else,
and then moved here.
Look at that-- military sure
took off in a hell of a hurry.
I think you scared them, Finn.
(laughs)
Oh, Lord...
Got number four over here.
This one's...
different from the others.
Completely mummified.
Yeah, tissue's black.
Look at the facial features.
Distorted from bloating,
and the color change is
from bacterial activity.
Which means that she was
exposed to the elements
shortly after death.
So maybe she wasn't buried
for very long
before she
was moved here.
The question is
where were they
all buried first?
Rich, dark soil, fern leaves?
My money's
on northern climes.
more north than Northern Nevada.
(gasps)
David...
removing a necklace.
What you got?
One of a kind, vintage pendant,
one carat small diamonds.
flowery design,
16-inch silver
Coreana chain.
Two years and 1,200 miles--
we found her.
I haven't heard
from Janet.
Something is wrong--
Janet and I talk every day.
She's a good girl.
Dr. Warren,
We're doing everything
we can to find Janet.
Were you able
to find me
a recent photo of her?
Please find my daughter.
I would like to be the one
to notify
Janet Warren's mother.
As soon as we have
positive I.D., we notify.
(watch alarm beeps)
Do me a favor.
Greg's down at Autopsy,
working the bodies.
Go help him out, will you?
I can't believe that
Dr. Warren has had to wait
two years for this moment.
The last thing
you should do
right now is
give that woman
bad information.
Come on.
What are the chances
that it is not Janet?
Okay, the necklace.
The condition
of her body, the soil.
It all points north
Yeah.
to Seattle,
to Tom Cooley's ranch.
Finn, you're getting ahead
of the evidence. Again.
He moved her body when
we turned up the heat.
But you know what we didn't know
back then, that we know now?
Janet Warren was
not the only victim.
This guy is a serial killer.
Who sued the crap out of you.
And the Seattle PD,
last time around.
And that was with one body,
we got eight now, Finn.
You know I'm right.
And for the record, I am not
getting ahead of the evidence.
Just go help Greg, please?
Where's Janet Warren?
She's in there.
She should move
to the head of the line.
That's not your call.
Well, can you make it yours?
(laughs)
Why are you working on her?
We really need to confirm
Janet Warren's I.D.
Well, isn't that why Russell
sent us both down here?
(sighs)
Have you ever had a case
that kept you up at night?
I have been awake for two years.
(sighs)
Hey, we all know about you
and your case with
Janet Warren, and we're a team.
So if you're in,
we're in.
Let's get this Cooley guy.
Thank you, Greg.
Okay.
Get her printed,
and, uh, when you run DNA,
can you do her first?
You do know that
I'm not the DNA tech anymore.
I promise you I'll
make it up to you.
(sighs)
Another finger bone for you.
Speaking of giving
someone the finger,
Finn compromised
a case in Seattle
by illegally obtaining
DNA evidence.
They had hair,
carpet fibers and semen
from Janet Warren's car.
Finn went after
the suspect's exemplars.
Why didn't she
just get a warrant?
Guy was juiced.
Son of Seattle,
lots of money, lots of friends.
And from what I heard,
he had a snake for a lawyer.
Well, snake or not, if this guy
Cooley's good for one,
he's good for all eight.
Hey, look what I found.
It's a ring.
Looks like a man's.
So far, all the bodies
have been female.
Maybe our killer left
something behind?
So, I found a lot of interesting
insects at the gravesite.
A lot of them are
not locally abundant.
Yeah, I recognize
the rain beetle, there.
Pleocoma australis--
How do you know that one?
Aw, I had them on a case once.
Found a body
in a shipping container--
the rain beetle
told us that she'd been buried
on land first.
Any idea of
post-mortem interval?
No, but I think
I can give you a location.
This beetle,
and the western thatching ant,
tell me that the bodies were
originally buried
in the Pacific Northwest.
This is the pink millipede,
found in
the agricultural areas
of Washington state.
Okay, well that narrows
it down considerably.
Yeah, but this last one
is the reason
you should probably
give me a pay raise.
The horntail,
Xeris tarsalis, game changer.
narrows it down even further,
puts the bodies
just outside the Seattle
metropolitan area.
Okay.
Well, next question is
why were eight bodies already
buried just outside of Seattle,
dug up and moved
to who-knows-where, Nevada?
Yeah, a place so remote,
you'd have to know
where it was to find it.
That's a good question.
Hey.
Greg.
Have you seen Finn?
Yeah.
I just got off
the phone with her.
Gave her the good news.
Well, now you'll give it to me.
Prints confirmed--
it's Janet Warren.
(phone beeps)
(keypad beeping)
Hi, this is Finn,
leave a message.
Oh, come on, Finn.
I just talked to her.
Are you keeping tabs
on all of us?
Thought you needed
my permission
before you can...
track me.
Exigent circumstances.
Hey, Mike, it's D.B. Russell.
How you been?
Got a little problem.
(siren whoops)
Step out of the vehicle, ma'am.
(sighs)
I see they busted you
back to working traffic.
This how you getting
your dates these days, Mike?
You know, I'm kind of hurt
you're back in Seattle,
and didn't give me a call.
Well, I'm only here for a day.
Yeah, that's what
D.B. figured.
Of course he called you.
Hmph.
I thought once I signed
the divorce papers
I'd never have to see you again.
Here, get in my car.
We're going for a ride.
Are you arresting me?
Because if you actually
talked to D.B.,
you would know why I'm here.
With or without cuffs,
it's your call.
Where the hell are we?
Trying to help you out,
here, Jules.
Uh, could you please
not call me Jules?
That brings back a lot
of bad memories.
Yeah, I've heard your
version of our marriage.
You found Janet Warren's body,
and some evidence that
she was buried in Seattle.
Now you think that you
have all that you need
to get that warrant
to dig up Cooley's ranch.
Well... you're too late.
That son of a bitch.
After he moved the bodies,
he covered his tracks.
There's no evidence
that the bodies
were ever even buried here.
Well, you been gone
for two years.
A lot of things have changed.
You can't go tearing down
these people's homes.
All right?
If Janet and the other girls
were buried down there,
we'll never know now.
You know Cooley did it.
Jules...
you got a new job,
a new life.
Don't screw it up this time.
Look, I'll drive you
back to the airport.
You could drop me at my car.
I'm not leaving until
I see Janet Warren's mother.
She deserves to know.
(laughs)
The press already
took care of that.
She's already on
her way to Vegas.
ROBBINS:
Dr. Warren,
you're not going in there.
I am not just any
grieving mother,
I am a doctor,
I'm a pediatrician,
I've seen it all.
But you've never seen your own
daughter dead on a slab.
I appreciate your concern.
I need to say good-bye.
Janet was identified based on
fingerprints and DNA.
Her physical features,
as you remember them, are gone.
You don't want this to be
your last memory of her.
Are you so desensitized to death
you can't even
understand how I feel
after two years of searching?
Monica...
(sighs)
Doctor, I believe
you know CSI Russell.
I'm so sorry.
I'm sorry we weren't able
to give you the answers
you were looking for in Seattle.
Well, you're giving
them to me now.
And for that,
I'm grateful.
Now, I'd like to
see my daughter.
ROBBINS:
Dr. Warren...
please take some
friendly advice.
Remember your daughter
in happier times.
This is the only way
that I can be sure.
Sit with me,
just for a second.
You remember CSI Finlay?
Yes.
Well... she found this
on her body.
(sobs)
(crying):
Oh...
You've given me Janet back.
Now go get that son of a bitch.
(buzzes)
Uh, your cell phone
is blowing up.
Yeah.
That's why I
left it over there.
(laughs sarcastically)
Finn is under
the impression that I am
her personal assistant.
If she's gonna get fired again,
I am not gonna go down with her.
Nobody is getting fired.
Haven't you ever been
passionate about a case before?
I am passionate about
a lot of things.
Okay, so....
Take a look at this.
Been working on
that ring I found.
Hardison High School,
Class of 1987.
Hardison High.
15 miles outside Seattle.
Any photos of the class of '87?
Huh. She was limber.
Bet you can't do that.
(clears throat)
Look who was
Senior Class President.
Tom Cooley.
Voted "Most Likely to
Become a Serial Killer."
(cell phone buzzing)
Time to answer your phone.
DNA hits on two of
your Jane Does.
Stephanie Hollinger...
and Sunshine Vanletti.
Now, Stephanie
went missing in 1999.
She was a 21-year-old
coed from UCLA
in Seattle for a Walk-and-Run.
Last seen at a place
called Endless Lounge.
Trendy bar in Capitol District.
What about the other girl?
Went missing in '02.
23-year-old fitness instructor,
worked nights as
a cocktail waitress at Zobo.
Also in the Capitol District.
You know, that's the same area
that Janet Warren went missing.
This could be
Tom Cooley's hunting ground.
He had an office
right around the corner.
Well, he didn't have
to work that hard.
Tox results showed high levels
of flunitrazepam.
Date rape drug.
Early 20's, athletic, blond...
Most of the bodies showed
signs of strangulation,
broken hyoids...
M.O. is up close and personal.
He likes to look in
their eyes as they die.
Guy's a sadist.
Lures them in,
sexually assaults them,
and then strangles them.
Take a look at this.
A couple weeks after
Janet disappeared,
a witness came forward
with this cell phone video.
Last time Janet was seen alive.
HENRY:
With Tom Cooley.
Mm-hmm.
Her hand's on his thigh.
Giving him permission
to take her home.
Hi, this is Captain Robinson
with the, uh,
Seattle Police Department.
Um, we're conducting
a murder investigation,
and we're searching for
a list of students who purchased
a 1987 Hardison High School
class ring.
Yeah, I'll hold.
Hmm...
What did the poor
thing wear home?
A smile.
Yeah, I'm here.
Oh, great.
Could you e-mail me that list?
Thanks.
Excuse me, "Captain."
Remember, our guy
lost his ring.
Was there anybody on that list
that ordered a replacement ring?
Yeah, a second ring.
There is one.
What's the name?
Eric Louie.
L-O-U-I-E.
Is there anybody else?
Okay. Thanks.
What, you think
it'd be that easy?
She'd say "Cooley,"
and you'd say "Get in jail?"
Let's go.
Any good Seattle cop
knows Eric Louie.
CHILD:
Love you, Daddy!
ERIC:
Bye, guys.
Hey, Mikey.
What the hell you doing
in this neck of the woods?
Well, we're following a lead
in the Janet Warren case.
Oh, yeah.
Heard about that
in morning briefing.
I know you.
You're a CSI.
Fired a couple
years ago, yeah?
Uh, resigned in lieu of.
FINLAY:
Officer Louie, we would
like to ask you
some questions about your
1987 Hardison High class ring.
The one you lost?
Thought you were working
the Janet Warren case.
Oh, we are.
CSI Finlay here's with
the Vegas lab these days.
We found your ring
in our mass grave.
That sounds like
an accusation.
Do I need my guild rep, Mikey?
No. Just tell us
how you lost the ring.
(indistinct radio communication)
Well, I didn't lose it.
I gave it to my
high school sweetheart.
She told me she lost it,
right after she dumped me
for the quarterback.
Well, I figured
she tossed it.
Marla always was a bitch.
Have you seen
this "bitch" lately?
Yeah. In the kitchen.
I married her.
Marla!
These guys want to
ask you some questions.
They're okay, yeah?
I gotta get back to work.
If you're done with me.
Yeah. Thank you.
All right.
Coffee?
Sure.
Fresh pot.
Thank you.
Sure.
Yeah, I know Eric
doesn't believe me,
but I did lose
his class ring.
Wore it on a chain.
It could've fallen off anywhere.
I was kind of wild back then.
Do you know where
you might have lost it,
or what you might
have been doing?
Dating most of
the football team?
Eric went through
the cheerleaders.
We were young, then.
Did you ever date
a guy named Tom Cooley?
No way.
I-I did date his best friend,
for a week or two.
Max Liston?
Quarterback.
Really got Eric
thinking about me.
You think...
Tom is responsible
for all those girls?
Did he kill them?
Well, that's what
we're investigating.
Did you and Max ever
hang out with Tom?
Once.
Max took me to a party
at Tom Cooley's ranch.
High-class booze,
beer in bottles...
kind of a step up for me.
Was that around the time
that you lost the ring?
Maybe.
I don't know.
If I knew
where it went,
it wouldn't be lost.
Like I said, I only went out
with Max a couple of times.
Anyone besides me
need a refill
on the coffee?
No, no, I'm good,
thanks.
She's hiding something.
Yeah.
Look, her husband's a cop,
you know?
If Marla Louie
is hiding something,
it could simply be something
she doesn't want
her husband to know.
And that would make you
zero-for-two up there.
Is that your nice way
of telling me
that I shouldn't have
come up here
without getting your permission?
You shouldn't have
gone up, period.
I mean, come on,
what are you doing, Jules?
Are you trying
to kill your career?
Marla Louie dated
Tom Cooley's best friend
in high school,
this guy named Max Liston,
all right?
I'm gonna send you a link.
"Max Liston, small-time Seattle
contractor,
"gets big break.
Cooley hired Liston to
develop the family ranch."
Not just to develop,
but to pave over eight graves.
If I wanted to dig up
eight bodies in Seattle
and rebury them in Nevada,
I'd would definitely negotiate
with my contractor best buddy.
Can we prove any of this?
Well, here's where I go 1-for-3.
Max Liston became
an instant millionaire,
and he retired
to the Virgin Islands.
Hey, don't even think about
taking an island cruise.
Well, you don't have to worry.
Even I couldn't get
this guy to talk.
BRASS:
So Max Liston gets
a truckload of money
and dies three weeks later.
I'd be interested to know what
Tom Cooley was doing
while Max was flunking
scuba diving.
Boss, you might want
to turn on the TV.
Really? Okay.
Today I've come to Las Vegas to
offer a reward
of $100,000
for information
leading to the arrest
and conviction
of the killer of Janet Warren.
In the last 24 hours,
Las Vegas PD has confirmed
the bodies of Janet Warren
and seven other young women were
recovered from a mass grave
200 miles from here.
Two years ago,
a chance meeting with Janet
at a public restaurant on
the last night of her life,
turned my life
into a nightmare.
RUSSELL:
Look at that.
He's making this about himself.
Now he's the victim.
(over TV):
...my reputation destroyed.
I have been pursued
with a vengeance
by an overzealous CSI who has
had no regard whatsoever
for the evidence.
(scoffs)
Jules, you mind
putting down the coffee mug?
Can you believe this?!
...cost her her job...
but it cost me everything.
The killer of Janet Warren is
still out there.
Let's all of us work together
to get him.
Scumbag!
He's playing games with us.
He thinks we're too stupid
to catch him.
No! Not the TV!
It's my TV. I paid for it.
What you got?
Hey.
Okay, well, this is where
we found the bodies.
It's federal land that
was taken from a private party
by eminent domain.
It was part of a big government
land grab in the '90s.
A "Covenant of Appurtenant."
What the hell's that?
It's a lawyer's
way of saying
that land can never
be developed.
Good place to bury a body.
No one's ever digging it up.
Who was
the previous owner?
It was buried under layers
of straw corporations,
but the law firm that
handled the deal was
Denton, Rutman
and Schmidt.
Whoa. Now, they are
the biggest
real estate firm
in Seattle.
Really?
Tom Cooley's family made all
their money in real estate.
So that could've been
Cooley land.
It it was, that would be enough
to compel his DNA.
Yes, sir, it would.
My client will not be
offering up his DNA.
We both know that particular
glass is off the table.
How is CSI Finlay?
She's terrific.
Mr. Pearson, if your client
wants to be so helpful,
what the hell's he doing
hanging out in the hall?
He's just waiting for me
to make sure his rights
will be protected.
This isn't Guantanamo.
(chuckles)
Okay.
Tom?
Captain Jim Brass,
Tom Cooley.
Pleasure to meet
you, Captain.
Sit down.
Now, Seattle PD was
investigating you
as a suspect in the
murder of Janet Warren.
Here in Las Vegas, I'm making
you the prime suspect
in the murder
of Stephanie Hollinger.
Sunshine Vanletti, five
Jane Does and Janet Warren.
Well, this is no way to
start a relationship, Jim.
Captain Brass,
we came here...
I've had a crash course
in the legal system
in the last couple years.
You can't arrest me just because
you don't like me.
If I could arrest you, you'd
already be in a holding cell.
Now, the victims
we've identified so far
were all last seen a few blocks
from your office.
Heart of downtown Seattle.
Population
half a million.
And the evidence suggests that
the bodies were buried
in Seattle,
then reburied here in Nevada.
Now, that requires logistics.
I mean like a dump truck
and a backhoe.
It's a shame
about your friend Max Liston.
We understand he did a lot
of construction work for you.
Max was a dear friend
and a good man.
If you're suggesting...
I'm not suggesting anything.
But what I don't get is,
why did you rebury them
1,200 miles from home?
What happened in Seattle?
CSI Finlay put your feet
too close to the fire?
You had to get out
of state?
Okay, that's it.
Captain,
we're done here.
These unsubstantiated
accusations,
they're bordering on slander.
And I was just getting started.
PEARSON:
We're staying at
the Mediterranean,
if there's anything
else we can do.
Mr. Cooley, thank you
for coming in,
but don't leave Las Vegas.
(pounding on door)
What the hell...?
Ah, single malt.
One bottle down,
one to go. Nice.
(scotch pouring)
Hey, could you give me
your glass when you're done?
I was hoping I'd see you.
How about a drink?
Yeah, that's how
it all starts, huh?
Some blonde
catches your eye.
Young, athletic,
looking for a good time.
And you buy her a drink.
Hell, maybe three.
And you add a little sweetener;
a little flunitrazepam.
Must be hard for a guy
like you to sleep at night.
You spend a lot of time
thinking about me.
I'm flattered.
I'm just
getting started.
Just like you, I don't want
the party to end.
So what happens next, huh?
You say say something
like, uh...
"Hey, baby,
just a short drive
to my big fancy ranch."
And then, in her car,
you get the sex part
out of the way
because you can't wait
to get home
and get your hands around
their necks.
I am your type, aren't I?
Five-foot four, blonde...
I'm looking for
a good time.
But I don't expect much
from you in bed...
'cause you're inadequate.
Is that your trigger?
How do you know
I'm not gonna kill you, hmm?
That's what makes it
so exciting.
(phone rings)
Hey, Jim.
Uh, she should be here
in a few minutes.
Landed about an hour ago.
Why? What's up?
Oh.
Okay, I'll be right there.
Hey.
Hi.
I just got a 419
at the Mediterranean.
Sounds like Tom Cooley just
committed suicide,
sometime in
the last couple hours.
Try in the last 30 minutes.
Look, I know you're angry.
I know you think
I let you down.
But I'm not the same person
I was two years ago.
So you weren't in
Cooley's suite?
I can explain.
Look, come here...
But Dad, the soda machine
stole my dollar.
It's Vegas, kiddo.
Stick to the
table games.
Internal Affairs is gonna
ask me questions.
So you be very careful
what you say.
I'm not gonna lie for you.
Let's go.
Mr. Pearson, this officer's
gonna accompany you
to the police station,
take your statement.
Yeah, of course.
I can't even begin
to understand this.
What do we got?
Gavin Pearson,
Tom Cooley's lawyer.
Supposed to meet Cooley
at the bar.
Cooley was a no-show.
He came up here
looking for him.
Banging the door,
there was no response,
so he called hotel security,
and they cut their way in.
Can I get
a little help here?
Yeah. Charles,
keep your eye on him.
You mind?
No, go ahead.
No, no, hold on.
So a room service waiter gave
a statement on the record
that said he saw
an angry blonde woman with
police credentials
and a service pistol
banging on the door
of Cooley's suite
a half an hour before
Security arrived.
Now tell me that isn't you.
Stay here--I'm gonna need
to take your statement.
You know, this isn't
just your job on the line.
Wow.
Unusual way to hang yourself.
Usually, you find them hanging
from the sprinkler head
or a curtain rod.
As long as the hang point's
longer than your torso...
that's all it takes.
Are we gonna find
your fingerprints
on one of these glasses?
RUSSELL: Flunitrazepam.
This is the drug
that Henry's finding
in all his victims.
BRASS: Both of the doors were
locked from the inside.
That works in your favor.
A narcissist does not hold
a press conference
and then, a few hours later,
kill himself.
Are you sure that's the argument
you want to make?
Yeah.
It's a homicide.
And we need to find out
who did it.
Well, whatever happened here,
you're finally gonna get
your DNA sample.
If I were Janet Warren's
mother, I'd feel cheated.
I'd want to face
this guy down in court,
tell the world
what he did,
and watch him be punished
for his crimes.
Well, not in this lifetime.
So what are you
thinking for C.O.D.?
Asphyxiation due
to ligature strangulation.
Suicide versus homicide,
still undetermined.
Henry found flunitrazepam,
50 micrograms per milliliter.
BAC was point two-one.
Alcohol three times
the legal level,
plus a heavy sedative.
Finn said he was wasted.
And tying a knot
requires a certain dexterity.
Think he could
accomplish that?
Eh, maybe, maybe not.
Mr. Cooley here
had a fatty liver.
He was a boozer.
And most likely,
he built up a tolerance.
Okay, until
we're certain,
we're treating this
as a homicide.
I got Cooley's DNA results.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Out of my autopsy
until you've been cleared
as a suspect, okay?
Did you give
your statement to Brass yet?
I'm waiting
for his call.
Cooley's DNA
matches the semen we found
in Janet Warren's car
two years ago.
Okay, it's official.
He killed Janet.
That solves
one murder.
Yeah, how about all eight.
This guy has been
murdering women
for the last
20 years.
I don't think
he suddenly
grew a conscience
and committed suicide.
So what's the motive
for murdering him, then?
Cooley's not the type
to get his hands dirty.
We believe that he had help
moving the bodies.
Max Liston.
But he drowned.
He's out.
Cooley's got
another best friend.
So, Cooley goes down,
his best friend would go down.
Cooley's dead, case closed.
So, who is it?
I don't know.
But I think I know
someone who might.
You call me.
Look, I'm sorry
that you wasted a trip,
but I already told you
everything I remember.
Well, you must know by now
that Tom Cooley is dead.
He can't hurt you anymore.
Who said he ever hurt me?
FINLAY:
Marla, listen to me.
Okay, I was kind of a wild
girl in high school, too.
Girl with a
reputation--
she gets invited
to a lot of parties.
And sometimes, those parties
would just be me and
a couple other guys.
You know what
I'm saying?
Expectations of my
boyfriend of the weekend
and those other guys.
There are eight
girls dead.
You are so lucky
to be alive.
ROBINSON: Marla,
you've got three kids.
What if something
happened to one of them?
Wouldn't you want the person who
knew the truth to come forward?
The bastard's dead.
What difference
does it make now, anyway?
FINLAY: Somebody helped
him cover it all up.
Probably the same guy
who killed him.
And that guy deserves
to be punished.
Eric doesn't know
about that night.
I didn't want
to lose him.
I don't want to lose him.
This is just the
three of us talking.
FINLAY: Marla,
you're the only one
who can speak for
those eight girls.
You were right,
about the party.
It was just me
and three horny boys.
Max, Gavin...
Gavin?
Gavin Pearson?
Yeah, the tagalong.
And Tom Cooley.
(laughter)
Cheers.
MARLA:
Back then, I didn't know
how to say no.
You know, I could usually
hold my booze,
but that night, I blacked out,
and I woke up
in the bottom of a hole.
COOLEY:
She's moving.
Bastards were burying me.
I didn't tell you to stop!
What are you doing?
(gasping)
Town whore!
No one's gonna
believe you, anyway!
He was right.
The Cooleys owned the town.
No one would've
believed me.
And even if they did,
Tom was untouchable.
What about
Max and Gavin?
They never spoke to me again.
Marla, you should know
that you probably
did not pass out
just from booze.
Cooley liked to
roofie his victims.
Did he rape you?
SANDERS: We know Cooley was
still alive at 9:40.
That's when room service
delivered his second bottle
of scotch.
Waiter passed Finn in
the hallway as he was leaving,
and we picked her up
on hotel surveillance
as she got back down
the elevator at 9:47.
Presumably, Cooley was
still breathing.
What about Pearson?
He was down at the bar
until 10:18.
Surveillance picked him up
in the casino,
clocked him getting
into the elevator at 10:20.
Pearson then entered
his room at 10:21.
He called Cooley--
no answer.
Called him again at 10:24,
at which point
he called hotel security.
So Pearson had a window
of three minutes to kill Cooley.
Takes at least 20 minutes
for drugs to be absorbed
from the stomach.
Pearson admitted
he had drinks with Cooley
up in the room earlier.
So that gave him access
to the man's scotch
and his drugs.
Plenty of time
for them to kick in.
Cooley would've been
passed out
by the time
Pearson came back upstairs.
So all Pearson had to
do was string him up
and let gravity do the rest.
(gasping)
I'm with you, Sherlock,
but there's only one problem.
Both doors to the room
were locked.
From the inside.
So how did the killer
get out of the room?
Same way he got in.
After Cooley's death,
Pearson's key card
stopped working.
(door beeps)
Need a little help here.
SANDERS:
Is that significant?
I mean, aren't those things
always getting demagnetized?
Yeah, you're absolutely right.
But, Dad,
the soda machine
stole my dollar.
That's Vegas, kiddo.
Stick to the table games.
"Out of order."
I'm sure you can get a
soda on another floor.
It's a magnet.
How'd you know...?
Pearson's key card
got demagnetized, right?
Kid lost his money
in the soda machine.
Okay, so how does that
help Pearson kill Cooley?
Pearson got into the room
using this magnet.
Got out the same way.
Then he probably
pocketed the magnet.
That's when he wiped out
his key card.
He's a lawyer, so he knows
he can't get caught with it.
So he sticks it to the
back of the soda machine
and fries the circuit board.
Guess we're lucky
he didn't stick it
behind the ice machine.
We would never have known.
BRASS:
You killed your best friend.
And your
biggest client.
Well, you know
how this works.
If you cooperate,
things can go easier.
Now, I have
eight victims.
Four Jane Does.
I need names.
Sarah Jones.
Tiffany Alcott.
Jennifer Sutterman.
Kinley Summer.
I have met a lot of
people searching for
missing loved ones over
these past two years.
Parents who are
willing to do anything
to bring their
babies home,
searching
for answers.
But I was lucky.
I had you.
And you wanted to find
Janet as badly as I did.
I only wish that I could have
brought her home to you.
You did.
You should feel
good right now.
Yeah.
Two years, two jobs,
one marriage.
But I got him.
Yeah, most people
would've given up.
I'm sorry that
I sometimes go too far.
I'm really working on
that side of my personality.
(laughs)
Thanks for sticking by me.
You're welcome.
You miss me, don't you?
Sometimes.
Sometimes I miss you.
All right, you ready
to get to the airport?
There's a flight
in the morning.