(panting)
Leave me alone!
Stay away!
(grunts)
(filtered breathing)
(twig snaps)
(loud crunch)
(screaming)
(scream fading, echoing)
(siren wailing in distance,
indistinct radio chatter)
Homeless couple
was camped there with the group
under the overpass,
spotted the body
and flagged down a patrol unit.
David.
Hey.
Well, looks like
somebody beat you
to the burrito
wrap here.
I would've done
a better job, though.
BRODY:
Camouflage.
Says, maybe, military.
Yeah, or army surplus--
you know, camping stuff.
STOKES: It reminds me
of when I used to go hunting
with my old man.
I never pegged you as a hunter.
Of course I was a hunter.
Just never got
into the killing part.
Apparently, someone doesn't
have the same reverence
for life as you do.
Massive bruising on the face.
He took
a real beating.
Yeah, and that looks like some
kind of animal bite on his leg.
Vital response
in the tissue
means it happened
while he was still alive.
A wolf or...
a coyote,
some kind of dog.
But I think dogs were the least
of this guy's worries.
Somebody took his hands.
Well, a dog didn't do that.
No wallet, no I.D.
No hands, no fingerprints.
Well, then again,
if we're talking about hunting,
maybe the killer took the hands
as a trophy.
BRODY:
Either way,
we have no I.D.,
and we have no idea
where this guy
came from.
We're stumped.
Sorry. I'm just saying,
this is gonna be a tough one.
They always are,
Super Dave.
They always are.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
RUSSELL:
This a traffic camera?
On Sunrise Boulevard.
Got a detail of the
drainage basin, blew it up.
Picked up an image
of this guy dumping our victim.
RUSSELL:
Time code--
3:36 a.m.
It's about five
hours ago.
Well, maybe our killer
will show his face.
Freeze that,
right there.
I can enhance it.
(beeping)
Night vision goggles?
That's some serious hardware.
Nick thought that our guy
was a hunter.
Who's hunting humans?
Man is the most dangerous game.
He has a knee brace.
Must have had an old injury.
SANDERS:
Vonner Sports Motocross.
You know, a lot of this gear
is custom-made.
Might be able to get an
I.D. from the manufacturer.
There's something
in his little pocket.
Looks like
a wad of paper.
Maybe it's something more.
Huh.
Paper crane.
You think our victim
was into origami?
Or our killer was trying
to leave us a clue.
How about you
chase the crane,
and I'll get our John Doe
to Doc Robbins.
C.O.D.'s exsanguination
due to bisection
of the right wrist,
rupturing the radial
and ulnar arteries.
The right hand was severed
peri-mortem?
That's correct.
Well, we assumed both hands
were removed postmortem
to prevent identification
or possibly taken as trophies.
Well, that's the case
with the left hand.
The injury here is
definitely postmortem.
In both instances,
the method was crude.
I can't tell you
what tool was used,
but I sent swabs from the wounds
over to Hodges.
What about the animal
bite on his leg?
It was no animal.
It was man-made.
Come on over here.
Perfect symmetry
of the punctures was the tell.
GREG:
A bear trap?
Well, it's consistent
with our theory
that the killer
may be a hunter.
I also found this
in the postmortem wound.
Appears to be some
kind of synthetic.
Could help us
find our primary.
I'll get it to Hodges.
Thanks, Doc.
♪ ♪
(beeping)
Mm.
Hey.
(groans)
I see your artist
remains anonymous.
(sighs):
Yeah.
I didn't fare
much better myself.
The green sliver
Doc found on the body
is a polypropylene blend
with green dye.
Artificial turf.
Indeed.
And I didn't find
any trace that put us
closer to the primary.
(sighs) So we
both struck out.
Mm.
You know,
I dated a Japanese girl
in college.
Washi is the paper
traditionally used
by the masters.
Tougher than
ordinary pulped paper,
it's often made
from the bark
of the gampi tree,
or sometimes
from the mitsumata shrub...
Hodges.
All I'm saying is
in origami, sometimes
the medium is the message.
As in, that is not
proper origami paper.
Our crane may not
be speaking to us,
but the paper might.
Okay, thanks
for the info.
Hey.
Hey. Get up there
and lay down, boy.
Is it
"bring your dog to work" day?
We were just coming home
from the vet.
I thought I'd bring him up here
to see some friends,
maybe cheer him up a little bit.
(Sam whines)
I bet you Sam's bored.
Are you kidding me?
This dog's living the life.
I treat him like a king.
(chuckles): Nick,
he used to be a cop;
now he's retired.
He probably misses the field.
Is she right, Sam?
You bored? You want to do
some work? Travaillez?
(barking)
Told you.
Speaking of getting to work,
that custom knee brace
that Greg found on our
victim-- manufacturer said
it was ordered by a Dylan Trigg.
Summerlin address.
Sounds like we just I.D.'d
our John Doe.
I'm heading out there now
with Crawford
to give notification.
We don't envy you that,
do we, Sam?
(whines)
Mm.
(dogs barking in distance)
Yeah, excuse me, sir.
I'm Detective Crawford,
this is CSI Brody, LVPD.
My crazy neighbor
call you guys again?
I'm sorry, I
don't understand.
My pickup.
Guy keeps complaining
that I park it on the street.
So I park in front
of his house--
what's the big deal?
It's a public street.
Nobody called
about your truck, sir.
Um, does a Dylan Trigg
live here?
Yeah. Dylan's my son.
What's this about?
Mr. Trigg, when's
the last time
you saw your son?
Five minutes ago.
Hey, Dylan,
can you come out here?
You say your friend's
name is Carl Abrams?
Yeah, I loaned Carl
some of my motocross gear
a couple days ago.
Uh, this is us
at the freestyle competition
in Laughlin last year.
That's where he dinged
his knee.
You said somebody...
killed Carl.
(sighs) I mean, I-I don't
understand. What happened?
That's what we're trying
to figure out.
Did it go down
up near Koval Ridge?
Why do you ask that?
We were supposed to go camping
there this weekend.
But I bailed at the last minute.
And why didn't you go?
There's something
about that place, man.
Creeps me out.
What about it?
There's this whole
Hunger Games, Road Warrior
vibe up there.
All these people waiting
for the world to end--
it's kind of scary.
Carl loved the place.
He camped there
by himself.
Loved exploring
around the old mines.
He told me he'd
strike it rich one day.
Do you know any spots
maybe your buddy
liked to camp in?
If I was gonna go
looking for him,
I'd probably look in the areas
around those old mines.
Sorry, I-I wish
I knew more.
Maybe if... if I had
been up there with him,
this wouldn't have happened.
Hey, Crawford, you there?
CRAWFORD:
Copy.
All right, listen,
we're about a mile
from Pielstick mine.
We're gonna
start our search
with the dog
over here, okay?
Copy that. We're on
the south side of the ridge.
Haven't found anything yet.
Venez.
Let me know.
Roger that.
Yeah, let's go, troops.
Restez ici.
Très bien.
All right, we're gonna
find out where
Carl Abrams came from.
This is a swatch from
the victim's shirt.
Got it?
Trouvez.
(barks)
(whimpers)
There he is.
Hang on, I think
he's got something.
Hang on.
What is it, boy?
(barking)
(whimpering)
Huh? Sam?
Arrêtez.
Good boy.
(barks)
It's got a handle.
BRODY:
What is this, Lost?
We got some blood right here.
(Sam barking)
Sam, allez là-bas.
Restez là.
(groans)
(metal door creaks)
BRODY:
More blood inside.
Yeah, yeah,
here we go.
All this blood--
tells me this could be
our primary.
Ready?
BRODY:
Restez ici, Sam.
♪ ♪
(lights buzzing)
(gasps)
They're just empty suits.
(sighs)
Motion sensor lights.
Fatigues...
night vision goggles.
Well, I've seen this before.
I'm gonna call for backup.
Crawford,
it's Morgan.
We've got something.
Crawford?
You might want to go topside;
I don't think
you're gonna get
a signal down here.
I'll be back.
'Kay.
Crawford.
Come in.
It's Morgan.
Crawford, do you copy?
(creaking)
(grunts)
(door creaks)
Hey, Morgan?
How we doing on that backup?
You don't belong here.
I'm with the LVPD.
I don't care
who the hell you are.
You're trespassing.
And you're making a big mistake.
There's a whole lot
of cops up there.
Gonna be coming
through that door any second.
You think I'm stupid, pal?
You think I was born yesterday?
Nope.
But I think you may die today
if you don't put the gun down.
(barking)
Why the hell are
you people here? Why?!
Put that shotgun down,
and we'll talk about it.
Otherwise,
they're gonna be
scraping us both
up off the ground.
Is that what
you want?
You're here to arrest me?
We want to talk to you.
(Sam barking)
Guess I should have had them
scrape us up off the floor.
Better than sitting here
like a common criminal.
Well, that part's still
to be determined, actually.
Who are you?
I'm CSI Russell.
Care to tell us who you are?
A lot of people are living
off the grid nowadays,
but y-you've taken it
to a whole new level.
You-you have no identification.
So far, we've found nothing
in your little bunker.
No bank statement,
no utility bills,
nothing with your name on it.
It's almost like
you worked
very hard to disappear,
haven't you?
Is that a crime?
Well, I'm just wondering why.
Why?
You had no right to
drag me out of my home.
Without as
much as a word
as to why.
You know why.
I've seen the way
you treat trespassers.
You're not very hospitable.
Is that what happened
with Carl Abrams?
He trespass?
I don't know Carl Abrams.
Okay.
That's fine if you
don't want to cooperate.
We'll let your little
hole in the ground
do the talking.
Who does this?
(sighs)
Someone prepping for doomsday.
Re-creating a world they believe
will disappear with
the coming Armageddon.
Tried to make
something disappear.
Blood.
Lots of it.
Astroturf is porous,
just like carpet.
That's a significant blood pool.
The killer severed
Carl Abrams' right hand.
He bled out.
Could've been right here.
Doc Robbins found
something like this
in the victim's
wound track.
Positive for blood.
Carl Abrams died here.
Place is lacking a certain
survivalist touch.
Yeah, it doesn't really fit
our man with no name, does it?
How long do you
think the guy's
been living down
here like this?
Well, he's got
a well-stocked pantry,
he's got water, electricity.
I'd say for a while.
You know, I'd say
we're done in this room.
There's no blood,
there's no sign of disturbance,
there's nothing probative
in here.
All right, let's check
the rest of the house.
Hey, Fin?
I think I found
the master's master bedroom.
This decor is more like it.
I found his toys.
FINLAY: Sara, you
got to see this.
This is not good.
Mm-mm.
Man keeps a room
for a little girl
in his hunting cave.
Yeah, it gets worse.
I don't think
he uses the room
just for little girls.
Women's clothes.
Yeah, and different sizes.
Could mean a number
of different women.
Some of these labels
are old.
Sutters?
That department store's been
out of business for years.
Origami paper crane.
Just like the one I pulled
out of Carl Abrams' pocket.
Do you think he makes
one for each victim?
You recognize that?
We have your prints all over it.
I'll give you a hint:
it's not one of
the origami animals
we just found in your house,
but it looks just like it.
This was in
Carl Abrams' pocket
when we found his body
and his blood
in your bunker.
I told you,
I don't know the guy.
You're setting me up.
You need a suspect.
And for whatever reason,
you've chosen me.
Yeah, actually, you know what?
Y-You reached out to us.
Here, take a look at that video.
See, you made the first move,
didn't you?
Look, I know how this works.
Yeah, I'll bet you do.
That's it.
I've had enough
of this pervert.
Why don't you tell us about
the little girl's room
you have set
up down there.
And all the clothes
from all those women.
I mean,
how many were there?
You want me to admit
to something that I didn't do.
Something that I have
no knowledge of.
Well, I'm not playing your game!
All I want
is to be left
in peace.
Is that what
you told Carl Abrams
before you killed him?
I don't know Carl.
He was camping
in your area.
What happened?
Did he stumble
upon your little piece
of hell down there?
Got signs of sexual activity.
Not that
I'm surprised.
Well, I'm surprised.
There is no blood here.
Well, a sex room isn't
the same as a kill room.
He takes them somewhere else.
(thumping)
Did you hear that?
Yeah.
Sounds like it's coming
from behind the wall.
Looks like an air vent.
(thumping continues)
There's no air coming out.
Whatever it is,
it's inside the walls.
It's moving.
It's headed towards the yard.
It's trying to get away.
Stop. Hold on.
Stop right there!
Wait, wait!
(panting)
Stop.
It's okay.
Stop. We're the police.
No one's gonna
hurt you.
We're here to
help you, okay?
What's your name?
We're gonna get
you out of here.
You're safe now.
You're okay.
You're safe.
♪ ♪
We may not know your
name, but we're starting
to get a pretty good
picture of your crimes.
We found the girl.
One you've been
holding captive.
The one you kidnapped.
And raped.
And probably
would've murdered,
just like all the others.
Remember how we asked you
how many women there were?
Well, we've already found one.
Rebecca Barnes.
Recognize her?
Or have there just been so many,
you can't even remember
at this point?
Found her dress
in your bunker.
The DNA on it traces
to an unsolved murder
in Carson City 11 years ago.
Was she your first?
Is that why you
kept the dress?
As a trophy?
You people have no idea
what you're talking about.
Then you tell us!
What drives a man
to kidnap, to rape,
and to murder?
I wouldn't know.
This woman that you said that
I murdered, Rebecca Barnes--
she was my wife.
And the girl that you found--
the one you accused me of...
Her name...
it's Miranda.
And that's my little girl.
She's all I have left
in this world.
Just got the file on
the Rebecca Barnes
homicide from
Carson City.
Bunker Boy's name
is Tommy Barnes.
He was the husband
and primary suspect
in his wife's murder until
Carson City cleared him.
That explains the attitude.
He thought the cops were
coming after him again.
Says here they never
caught the killer?
Yeah, still
an open case.
Barnes's daughter Miranda was
seven years old at the time.
After he was cleared,
he told police
he was taking his daughter
and leaving town.
Then went underground,
literally.
DNA confirms the
only contributors
on the women's clothes are
his wife and his daughter.
Different sizes.
He kept his wife's dresses,
then he bought his kid new
clothes as she was growing up.
Sad story,
but none of that
clears him on the
murder of Carl Abrams.
No. No, it doesn't.
Where's my daughter?
I want to see her.
She's fine.
She's in the hospital,
getting checked out.
It's just a...
It's a formality.
I'm gonna, uh, take
your cuffs off here.
Mr. Barnes...
...why don't you and I
start over again.
With an apology.
I was just told
about Carson City.
I can't even begin
to know what that was like.
Losing your wife,
having the police
suspect you like that.
For months.
While that animal
who killed Rebecca
is still out there, free.
I, um...
read the case file.
Your daughter Miranda was there
when-when your wife was abducted
from the mall parking lot.
It could have been both of them
taken away from me.
Mr. Barnes, I'm so sorry.
Thanks.
You know, Rebecca was my
high school sweetheart.
We had a perfect life.
Nice house, good friends,
part of a church.
You never expect
to wake up one morning,
leave your home,
you go to work,
the wife does some shopping--
just a normal day.
When you get back home...
it's all gone.
And-and that's when
you-you went underground?
Well, in the '50s,
before my grandfather donated
the land to the state, he built
a fallout shelter
to protect his family.
And you decided
that's how you were gonna
protect your family, too.
What was left of it.
So I built a home
in the bunker.
I'd take odd jobs
in the area.
I provided Miranda with
everything she needed.
Food, shelter.
I even homeschooled her.
Well, that's a great plan
when she's seven.
What about now
when she's 17?
Miranda has everything
that she needs.
You and I both know
that's not true.
We found evidence
of sexual activity
in your daughter's bed.
Two DNA contributions.
Two men-- one unknown,
the other one,
our victim, Carl Abrams.
You're lying.
I know my daughter.
You just told me
that you took odd jobs.
That gets you out of the house.
Your daughter--
she's lonely,
she's curious, she ventures out.
No, she would never leave
on her own, not without me.
Mr. Barnes, Carl Abrams' semen
in your daughter's bed,
his blood in your house.
Now, come on.
Look, I know
you'd do anything
to protect your daughter.
I just told you,
I'm not a murderer.
Did he break in?
Did he threaten Miranda?
You guys are all the
same, aren't you?
Here, Carson City--
it's the same.
I'm done talking to you.
(door opens)
I need to ask you
some questions.
Miranda.
Yes, I-I do know your name.
And I know how you and your dad
ended up in that bunker.
But what I don't know
is what happened
to Carl Abrams
two nights ago.
And I need you to tell me.
I can't help you.
Yes, you can.
This is a DNA report
which tells me that there were
two boys in your bed.
One of whom was Carl.
No, that's a lie.
I've never been with any boys.
What happened?
Was the other boy
jealous of Carl?
Did they fight?
I know Carl was hurt.
He went down into the bunker
to you for help.
Leave me alone.
Miranda,
I remember being so scared
of disappointing my dad.
And yet, I was
so desperate for other people's
attention, I would do anything.
You started sneaking out
when your dad was away,
and you met Carl.
And I'm sure the two of you
had a really good time.
And then, you met another boy.
And he was a bad boy,
and it was really exciting.
And you didn't realize
just how dangerous that boy was
until it was too late.
I know you know
what happened to Carl.
And I know that you're scared,
and you don't know
who you're more scared of--
your-your dad
or the other boy.
But you don't have to be.
You just have
to tell me the truth.
(sighs)
I had her.
She was this close
to talking, and then
I lost her;
she just went right back
into being
that scared little girl.
Where's this leave us?
What about that other kid--
the one you think
that killed Carl Abrams--
how do we find him?
I think Miranda's
still the key.
She's a teenage girl
who is sneaking out at night,
and she's trying
to hook up with boys.
So if we find out
where she's sneaking off to,
we find the kid.
Exactly.
So we have to go back
into the bunker,
and we have to search it again.
We have to look for something,
like a diary
or-or some clue
to her secret life.
(cell phone chimes)
Like the way you're thinking.
Thank you.
Oh, boy.
What?
I think Dad just grounded us.
CSI Russell, CSI Finlay,
Jill McDermott.
Tommy Barnes' attorney.
Pleasure.
CRAWFORD:
Ms. McDermott is alleging
that we violated her client's
Fourth Amendment rights.
Illegal search and seizure?
You're saying we needed
a warrant to get in the bunker?
Last time
I read the Constitution.
CRAWFORD: I was
explaining to counsel
the exigent circumstances.
Your CSIs found blood
at the entrance of the bunker.
Yes, not to mention that
the bunker is on public land.
A little preview of how this is
gonna play in court.
One, I don't buy
exigent circumstances.
And two,
while the Barnes estate
generously donated much of its
land to the Koval Ridge Reserve,
the estate maintains
all mineral rights.
So everything under the surface
is still private property.
And any evidence you collected
in Mr. Barnes' home
gets thrown out.
Fruit of the poisonous tree.
I think a judge would be
reluctant to let you go digging
around those roots again.
Of course, if you were
to release my client now,
I'd take that
as a good faith gesture.
Might discourage me from
filing any civil action
against the department.
I'm sure you all have a lot
to discuss.
Have a nice night.
I know you wanted to get
back in that bunker.
Yeah. We need a lead
to find out where Miranda goes
when she meets the mystery kid.
Maybe we don't have
to go back in there.
I'm gonna call Hodges.
(scanner humming)
Hey. That crane
speaking to you yet?
Whispering. I ran the
paper through the VSC,
managed to get some detail.
Looks like an MRE
packaging label.
"Meals-Ready-to-Eat,"
as in military fare.
Consistent with the
Barnes family lifestyle.
You know, along the bottom,
that looks like
a barcode.
You know, these days, they
encode the shipping destination.
(beeping)
"Koval Ridge Supply Store."
Well, it's not much, but
if you live out here,
it's your one and only
stop shop.
And it's the only civilization
a girl could find for miles.
Good a place
as any to meet a guy.
What? I've done worse.
(laughs)
(doorbells jingle)
STOKES:
Whoa.
I'm getting a serious feeling
of déjà vu here.
Yup.
Guess now we know
where Tommy Barnes got his gear.
Yeah, and maybe
where our killer did, too.
(door closes)
Excuse me.
You work here?
No, stocking shelves
is my hobby.
Well, we're, uh,
we're with the crime lab.
We need to talk to you
for a second.
What's your name?
Luke.
Luke. Luke what?
LUKE:
Holland.
You ever seen that guy?
His friend says
he comes in here.
No. A lot of people
come in here.
STOKES:
Yeah. I can see that.
How about this little girl
right here?
You ever seen her?
No. I've never seen her either.
BRODY: Nick.
Remember what you said
about déjà vu?
Is that your stuff, man?
Call for backup!
(engine sputtering)
Going somewhere, Luke?
I didn't do nothing.
Innocent people don't run
from the police.
That's Carl Abrams' bike.
Yeah, and I think
we just found his killer.
STOKES:
We got you, Luke.
The blood on the outside
of the fatigues was a match
to Carl Abrams.
And the DNA on the inside
is gonna be
a match to you.
You killed Carl,
and you dumped the body.
You're wrong.
Yeah, I got rid
of Carl's body,
but I didn't kill him.
Then who did? Miranda?
I don't know who did it.
STOKES: You're gonna
have to do a lot
better than that, Luke.
Seriously, a lot better.
I'm telling you
the truth. I swear.
I was with Miranda
saying good night,
and that's
when we heard him.
Help me.
Carl was hurt. Real bad.
It was like
out of a horror movie.
His hand was gone,
he was bleeding.
There was nothing
we could do; he died
right there in front of us.
I told her
I'd take care of it,
so I cleaned up.
I cut off Carl's
other hand, so no one
could identify him.
I dumped his body
on the edge of town
and cleared away his campsite.
Well, that's a pretty
good story, I guess.
But think I got a better one.
It's not really a...
a horror movie.
It's... more
of a tragic romance.
See, I think
you killed Carl Abrams
because the girl you loved
started showering her attention
on him, not you.
You think I killed Carl
over Miranda?
STOKES:
Come on.
We know about the love triangle.
We got
Carl's DNA in Miranda's bed
and an unknown male.
We're not only gonna
match the fatigues to you,
we're gonna
match the sheets.
I'm not the one on those sheets.
And there's no way...
Miranda was with Carl.
What are you saying?
Miranda's not that kind of girl?
No, Carl's not that kind of guy.
The dude's got a boyfriend.
We all used
to hang out together
in the bunker when her dad
was away. Guess now I know
what those boys were up to
when they ran off to her room.
You're looking
at the wrong
jealous boyfriend.
Carl Abrams' boyfriend
got a name?
Dylan Trigg.
He and Carl were
into motocross and camping.
That's how Miranda
and I first met them--
camping up
on Horizon Peak.
Yeah.
Carl was my boyfriend.
Why didn't you say anything
about this before?
(sighs)
I'm not exactly out.
Was he out?
Carl didn't
give a damn about
what anybody thought.
STOKES:
That include you?
Pretty much.
Was that a problem?
Yeah, it was a problem.
Carl didn't get it.
It was so easy for him.
He said that...
if I had any guts,
I'd tell people the truth.
Is that what you two
fought about that night?
Do I need a lawyer?
I don't know, Dylan.
Do you?
Hey, I found motorcycle tracks
back up on the ridge.
They match the tires
on Carl's bike.
So far, Luke Holland's
story's holding up.
Let's hope it gets us
to the crime scene.
I got two sets
of shoe impressions.
One looks like work boots,
and the other has a tread
like the shoes
we found on Carl Abrams.
It's long strides.
Carl was running.
Looks like...
he slowed down
around here,
stopped,
backed up.
SANDERS:
Right into a bear trap.
(screaming)
It's got blood
on it, just like
Doc Robbins suspected.
Mechanism's rusted.
Must've broken when it
snapped on Carl's leg.
That's why he was
able to get away.
SIDLE:
He didn't get very far.
I just found
Carl's right hand.
Buckshot in the wound.
Confirms it was a shotgun.
Still...
there's blood and tissue
under his fingernails.
We lucked out. Carl got
a piece of his killer.
DYLAN:
You guys don't understand.
I loved Carl.
I would never hurt him.
BRODY: I'm sure
you didn't mean to.
You were the one who told us
where Carl was camping.
You sent us to Koval Ridge.
Clearly, you wanted us
to discover the truth.
I'm sure you feel terrible
about what happened.
You know there's only one way
to make this right.
What the hell is going on here?
I think I want
that lawyer now.
RUSSELL: Mr. Trigg, this is
your son Dylan's confession.
He told us that you
admitted to assaulting
and hunting down
Carl Abrams,
shooting him
and leaving him for dead.
My son is lying;
I never told him any such thing.
Dylan's head is
so filled with lies
because that...
kid, Carl Abrams,
messed with him.
Screwed him up
so he doesn't know who he is
or what the truth is anymore.
You're right,
your son is confused--
because he's had to live a lie.
Thanks to you.
Think you just made
my case in court.
This confession isn't worth
the paper it's written on.
Well, that's why
we depend on evidence.
This is a tire track
found on an access road
near the scene
of the crime.
Matches your truck.
Lead trace found in
Carl Abrams' wound
and pellet size
matches the shotgun
and the ammunition
we found in your home.
Don't tell me
I'm the only one
who uses that ammo.
No, but you're the only one
that was up on the ridge
that night with Carl Abrams.
Maybe you recognize...
Carl's hand.
We found your DNA
underneath his
fingernails.
I guess he must
have scratched you.
In death, Carl has given
us more than enough
to convict you.
My son is not what
that kid tried to make him.
I had to protect Dylan.
By killing the boy?
I told him to stay away;
he laughed in my face!
He said my son
didn't belong to me anymore.
That he belonged to him.
That Dylan
was born to...
(panting)
...to love him.
My son was born to be a man.
He was.
And he proved that
when he signed this confession.
Dad.
I'm so sorry, Dad.
(crying):
It's all my fault.
No, no, no, no.
I'm just glad
you're okay.
I knew that
the first time I sneaked out.
I just-- I saw the campfires
and I heard the other kids'
voices in the night.
I just wanted to be
a part of it.
It's okay, honey.
Every kid wants to
explore the world, okay?
But that's just it, Dad--
I had a world.
You loved me enough
to make one for me,
and I destroyed it.
I've let all the bad in.
Because you're right, Dad,
that's all there is out there.
And when you open the door,
that's all that comes in.
No, no, no, no,
sweetheart, no.
(sighs)
I was wrong.
See, when I was your age...
nothing could hold me back.
Everything was possible.
And I robbed that from you.
When we lost Mom, I kept
you from everything
and everyone
that you knew.
Well, the important thing now
is where you go from here.
Not underground,
that's for sure.
Dad, are you sure?
Yeah, I'm sure.
Remember when you asked
me if I had any plans
for Miranda when
she turned 17?
Yeah.
Well, there's a town up in
Oregon where your mom's from.
It's this perfect
little place--
it's got this quaint
little Main Street,
everyone knows
each other.
Sounds like
a really, really good idea.
It is.
Honey, you got
family there.
I think that's a pretty good
place for you to start all over.
What do you say?
(laughs)
I love you, sweetheart.
(sighs)
I love you, too, Dad.