(crowd applauding)
(woman grunts and screams;
sharp impacts echoing)
CHRIS EVERT:
What an incredible
turn of events
in this women's
semi-final match.
Second seed Tara Janssen is
struggling to stay alive
in this match against
18th seed Claudia Weber.
LINDSAY DAVENPORT:
Well, Weber's not
just any opponent.
These two, very close
friends off the court.
I know what it's like
to play
against a friend,
and it's not easy.
It's a difficult proposition
for both these players.
Weber to serve.
A huge Janssen forehand.
Weber's getting to every ball.
(crowd cheers, applauds)
CHAIR UMPIRE:
40-15.
DAVENPORT:
Incredible rally ends
with the easy unforced error
from Janssen.
Weber, now with her
first match point.
You know, Lindsay, Weber
has never beaten Janssen.
And this would be an
incredible win for her.
Oh, biggest match
of her career.
Claudia's husband
and coach, Ivan,
looks as nervous as
she does right now.
And her father, also,
who's cheering her on.
You know, he's never
missed a match
since she's been
12 years old.
CHAIR UMPIRE:
Let.
DAVENPORT:
Uh-oh.
A little tight there
on that first serve.
Nerves, maybe?
CHAIR UMPIRE:
Game, match, Weber.
(crowd cheers, applauds)
DAVENPORT:
What a way to end it.
120-mile-per-hour
ace to seal it.
EVERT:
Wow, and Claudia
Weber now advances
to her first-ever
premiere final.
Claudia, congratulations
on an incredible win
in front of
your hometown crowd.
Is it even more
challenging playing against
one of your best friends
and doubles partners?
She's an incredible
competitor.
That's what makes her
a great doubles partner.
Oh, and I want to thank
my husband and my Dad
for believing in me.
And to all of you,
who cheered me on.
Thank you.
Mm, gosh, what a shame.
Did you ever
see Claudia Weber play?
No, I never did.
More of a
basketball fan, really.
Mm, she was such
a great player.
And a really good
person off the court.
You sound like a real fan.
AKERS:
CSIs Russell and Finlay,
meet Justin Gimelstob.
He's the one who found
the body this morning.
Want to tell us
how you found her, please?
Just going through
my normal routine,
trying to get
a light workout in,
hit some balls against
the ball machine.
And I called the police.
We're going to need
your clothes for evidence.
I'll escort you
to the locker room.
RUSSELL:
Thank you.
FINLAY:
Clay's been disturbed.
Medium force spatter.
Claudia was
definitely killed here.
Who says tennis
isn't a blood sport?
♪ Who are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
Here goes the last of the rigor.
Ready?
Mm-hmm.
(groans, sighs)
Wow, her right arm
is quite a bit
bigger than her left.
Well, that's typical
of tennis players.
Their hitting arm's
often more muscular.
You a tennis fan?
Yeah, my, uh, doubles
partner and I are the top-ranked
wheelchair team
at our club.
Liver temp. is 89.5.
Puts TOD at less than six hours.
Shouldn't it be 12 hours?
She's in full rigor.
Physical activity
so close to death
sometimes causes
the body to go into rigor
a little faster than normal.
Got a spatter
pattern on her shoe.
Clay mixed in,
so I can't really
tell if it's blood.
Serious blunt-force
trauma to the head.
She may have
won the match,
but she took a beating
on the court.
Ms. Weber
was not only beaten,
she was stabbed in
the throat, too.
Wasn't there
another tennis player
who got stabbed on
the court years ago?
Yeah, Monica Seles.
By an obsessed
Steffi Graff fan.
Right.
Sports fans can be
extremely passionate.
Maybe someone was not happy
that Claudia won
that match yesterday.
Why are you treating
me like a suspect?
My wife just died.
I understand that.
But if anything, we're
doing everything we can
to eliminate you
as a suspect.
When's the last time
you saw Claudia?
Uh, right after her match.
I stayed for her
press conference,
then I went home.
You know, her car was
still in the parking lot.
Were you worried
when she didn't
come home last night?
She booked a room in a
hotel across the street.
My snoring, uh, keeps
her up at night.
And she wanted to get a good
night's rest before the final.
She was on that court
really late last night.
Does she normally stay
after hours like that?
She liked to hit balls
after a big match at night.
It would clear her head.
So anybody in
the tennis world
would understand that's...
that's part of her routine?
Athletes, they're--
they're creatures of habit.
Do you know of anyone who
would want to hurt your wife?
Everyone loved Claudia.
Okay, man.
The hardest part
is telling her dad.
He just lost his
wife last year.
Claudia's... she was
all he had left.
I'm going to do
everything I can
to find out who did
this, all right?
Check out these scuff marks.
Ms. Weber struggled
with her killer.
(grunting)
FINLAY:
Got more blood drops.
Some grass,
little pieces of gravel.
Could've come
from the killer's shoes.
All right, I'll collect
this section of the clay,
and then I'll bring
it back to the lab.
SANDERS: I got more blood drops,
leading to the garbage can.
Killer could've tried to
dispose of the weapon.
It's empty;
the bag's been changed.
Well, looks like
I'm going Dumpster diving.
AGENT: Excuse me,
are you CSI Supervisor
Diebekorn Russell?
Judging by the suit,
I'm guessing you're
a government agent.
And, if you're DEA,
the mushrooms behind
me are medicinal.
I've been through this
before with you guys.
I'm not here about
your mushrooms, sir.
Agent Smith, USCIS.
Immigration.
All right.
What's that about?
One of your employees,
David Hodges.
David? He's an
American citizen.
He's got family in Canada,
yeah, but, I mean, who doesn't?
How would you describe
Mr. Hodges' character?
A little odd,
but nice, hardworking.
To the best of
your knowledge,
has he ever
been dishonest?
No.
Never falsified
reports?
Tampered with evidence?
No, no, absolutely not.
Does he travel
internationally a lot?
Not that you'd
notice, no.
Well, wait, no, he took
his mom to Italy last year.
Is Hodges in some
kind of trouble?
You recognize
that woman?
No, should I?
David Hodges claims
she's his fiancée.
HODGES:
Her name is Elisabetta.
We met at her family's
vineyard in Tuscany.
She educated me about
the acidic properties
of the Sangiovese grape.
Sounds romantic.
It was amore.
I knew then that
we were destined
to spend our
lives together.
Well, I-I certainly hope that
Immigration agrees with you.
Did the agent happen to seem
overly suspicious?
Raised a red flag, yeah,
when I-I didn't
recognize Eli-Eli...
Elisabetta.
Why-why didn't
you tell anyone?
Um, what can I say?
I'm a man of mystery.
Yeah, okay.
Um, hey,
very happy for you.
Congratulations.
Well, thank you.
I'm going to let you
get back to your clay.
You know, technically,
it's not clay.
American courts
use crushed basalt.
Ah, see, I didn't know that.
That's fascinating.
Okay, good, um...
ROBBINS:
As you can see,
being a professional athlete
takes its toll on the body.
Broken wrist, stress
fractures in the feet.
Come look at this.
Brown discoloration of
the cerebral cortex
adjacent to brown
discoloration of the subdura--
indicative of previous
head trauma, likely a contusion.
How long ago?
No way to
know for sure.
What about her
current injuries?
Three depressed skull fractures
that left rectangular
impressions
approximately one inch wide.
Is that the
cause of death?
No, actually this was:
this vertical fracture bisected
the thyroid prominence
and fractured
both superior horns,
causing a
soft tissue hemorrhage.
She choked on her own blood.
Essentially, yes.
Any idea what the
murder weapon is yet?
Well, the margins of
the wound are jagged
and the puncture's
less than an inch deep.
Doesn't appear to be a knife,
but at this point,
I can't say for
certain what it was.
So, Ernest, what
time did you
change the trash
bags on that court?
Uh, start of my shift,
around 6:00 a.m.
You, uh, see anything
unusual in there?
I don't look in the bags,
not since a player on the court
had food poisoning.
Bags were full of puke.
Oh, well, that's great.
You don't mind going
first, do you, Greg?
So, this is, uh, everything
from yesterday and this morning.
Okay.
Thank you, Ernest.
♪ ♪
(groans)
Here we go.
Broken tennis racket.
This could be
our murder weapon
right here.
Looks like there's
some blood on it.
Well, Claudia had blunt-force
trauma to the head.
Killer must have hit her
with that racket
and broke the frame.
(grunting)
STOKES: Yeah, and then
used this sharp edge
to stab her in the throat.
You know, I know
tape on the handle
absorbs sweat.
SANDERS:
Well, that means DNA.
♪ ♪
(machine whirs)
Got some results for you.
Hey, Henry...
you're friends
with Hodges, right?
Uh, depends on the day.
Did you know
that he was engaged?
You know, I heard it
from Rick, in QD,
who heard it from
Arlene in Reception.
Word travels fast
around here.
Yeah, well...
ever since Hodges accused me
of trying to steal Wendy...
Wait, who's Wendy?
Our old DNA analyst.
Sorry. Uh, anyway,
since then,
he doesn't really
confide in me anymore.
Okay, you have
some results for me.
I do.
Blood on the frame
of the tennis racket
was a match to our
victim Claudia Weber.
So, it's definitely
the murder weapon.
She was also
the major contributor
of DNA on the handle.
Killed by her own racket.
But there was
a minor contributor
of touch DNA
on the handle, as well.
And get this:
It came back to Tara Janssen,
the player that
Weber just beat
in the semifinals.
I guess Tara was
a sore loser, after all.
Ms. Janssen,
would you mind?
Oh, not at all.
Of course.
Hey, break it up.
Ms. Janssen, I hate to drag you
away from your adoring fans,
but we have to talk.
Please, come with me.
Claudia was like
a little sister to me.
I've known her
since she was 14.
How could you
possibly think
that I'd do anything
to hurt her?
Because your DNA
was on her tennis racket,
which just so happens
to be the murder weapon.
Let me show you.
Claudia and I both used
the Ace-Trak 528 racket.
A couple of times,
when we were
playing doubles, we grabbed
each other's by mistake.
Okay.
Ms. Janssen,
let me ask you something.
What's the prize money
on these kind of tournaments?
Half a million.
That's a good
chunk of change.
So when Claudia knocked you
out of the tournament,
you obviously lost
your shot at the cash.
I'm not interested
in the prize money.
I made $11 million in
endorsement deals last year.
So you do it for the glory;
for the love of the game.
I'm chasing history.
17 more wins,
and I'll break the record
for most career
singles titles.
But, you know, let's face it,
I mean, you're pushing 30.
I mean, that's not old,
but in tennis, that's old.
And young up-and-comers like
Claudia could get in the way
of you chasing
your legacy, right?
Listen, no one likes to lose,
but... she deserved to win.
She played a
great match.
And I was happy for her.
You weren't always
such a gracious loser.
Let me show you something.
This was taken
about a month ago.
TARA:
That ball was out?
That ball that landed
right there, that was out?
(muttering)
Wow.
Yeah.
Where were you between
11:00 and 1:00 last night?
I had a late dinner
with Chris Evert,
and then I went home
and I went to bed.
Ms. Evert?
I'm CSI Finlay.
I need to ask you
some questions
about Tara Janssen.
Sure, but can it wait?
I'm right in the middle
of a workout.
Can I borrow your racket
for a moment?
Thank you.
You play?
A little.
When I was a kid.
But enough to keep the ball
going, so we can talk.
Let's see what you got.
So what was your
relationship with Tara?
Well, she's been getting
some code violations lately,
and I'm really trying to help
her with her anger issues.
When was the last
time you saw her?
Last night,
after her match.
We were just chatting
about her game.
Grabbed a bite, and then I just
dropped her off at her condo.
What time was that?
A little before midnight.
Did Claudia Weber have any
issues with anybody on the tour?
No, not the players.
But she hasn't been too happy
about her coach lately.
Is that her husband Ivan?
Yeah. She actually has been
thinking about firing him.
Really?
She asked me if I'd be
interested in coaching her.
Whoa!
(laughs)
Where'd that
come from?
You holding out on me?
I learned it
from watching you.
(both laugh)
Thank you.
(speaking Italian)
Uh...
(continues speaking Italian)
What is the problem, baby?
Are you ashamed
with me?
Elisabetta, mio amore,
please calm down.
Calmati.
Calmati. No.
Potresti avere
all spoiled.
(continues speaking Italian)
Do you understand me?
Si. Si. Si.
Who is that?
Hodges' fiancée.
Fiancée?!
Yeah. Shh.
I'm trying to figure out
what she's saying.
If my translate app
is correct,
it's something about
a green card.
HODGES:
Don't worry.
Everything will be okay.
(scoffs)
Okay?
Si. Bene.
Non okay.
(speaking Italian)
Like I'm invisible,
or what?
Mm-mm. Ti amo.
No, it's--I didn't want to
tell anybody about you yet.
Non soon pronto.
(speaking Italian)
Cold toes?
Oh, she means
cold feet.
Hey, shh.
No. No cold feet.
(speaking Italian)
There is another
woman in your life?
Qualche bionda
bimbo Americana?
No, wait...
Oh, she thinks
there's another woman.
Yeah, I got that.
Elisabetta...
there is only you.
Sei l'unica donna...
...che amo.
(speaks Italian)
You drive me crazy,
David, you know that?
I love you.
I have never been jealous
of Hodges until this moment.
Mm-hmm, yeah.
Wha...?
(camera clicks)
Now everybody knows
who I am.
(man)
Way to go, Hodges!
You have something
for me, right?
Yes...
Uh, Hodges found traces of
chewing tobacco in the clay.
It's the same trace that Finn
pulled off the victim's shoes.
Guess who the DNA
comes back to.
Why'd you lie to me, Ivan?
What do you mean?
You know as well as I do
you were on that practice court
with Claudia last night.
BRODY: Chewing tobacco
is a dirty habit.
When you spit, you got some
on your wife's shoes.
We have DNA to prove
it's yours.
We know Claudia was shopping
around for a new coach.
You were about to be fired
by your wife.
That's got to be
a serious blow
to the ego, man.
You couldn't
handle it,
so you killed her.
No! No.
I went there
to talk to her.
You just had the best game
of your career,
and you want to fire me?
I can't take orders
from you on the court
and then come home
to you at night.
It's too hard.
So, that's it?
You're just gonna
get rid of me, huh? I'm gone.
If we want to try
and make this marriage work,
you can't be my
husband and my coach.
I agreed to do whatever it
took to save our marriage.
And how long had you two
been having trouble?
About a year.
The last month had been
the worst. Uh...
She hadn't been herself.
What do you mean?
She'd been having
nightmares.
She was calling out
some guy's name.
Brent.
Is that somebody on tour?
Not that I know of.
When I asked her about it,
she wouldn't tell me.
She'd been kind of
secretive lately.
Is it possible that your wife
was having an affair?
I don't think so.
Claudia was the most honest,
decent person that I ever met.
Hey. This is the last
of what was collected
from Claudia
Weber's locker.
Cat treats...
three different kinds
of hand lotion.
Learn a lot about a woman from
what she keeps in her purse.
Same goes for
her tennis bag.
Oh, what's this
thing called?
A Blossom Ballerina?
Oh, yeah.
My daughter had one of those.
Took it everywhere.
Athletes tend to
be superstitious.
Maybe it was a
good luck charm.
Receipts from Tasty Time
and Choozies Chicken.
Well, players burn
a lot of calories,
and fast food is an easy
way to replace them.
Their dirty little secret.
She might have
another secret, too.
This looks like LSD.
(laughs)
Man, that takes me back.
Wait, you took LSD?
No.
No, my folks did.
Hey, wasn't illegal
until 1966.
Okay.
But Claudia Weber's
tox was clean.
And as you know, or your
folks, should know...
(chuckles)
LSD doesn't
stay in your system
for more than a half an hour.
You know, her husband thought
that she was keeping
a secret from him.
This would be quite a doozy.
But LSD isn't a
performance enhancer.
It's recreational.
So, pressures of the game,
maybe it was Claudia's
way of coping.
He also said that
she was having nightmares
about a guy named Brent.
Didn't think he was part
of the tennis world.
Maybe he's part of this world.
We got a print here.
(computer blipping, trilling)
RUSSELL:
"Darcy Shaw."
"Felony drug distribution."
SHAW:
I'm not a drug dealer.
I'm a doctor.
Well, Ms. Shaw, says here
you, uh, took an online course
in hypnotherapy.
That doesn't really
qualify you as a physician.
Or give you the right to
dispense illegal drugs.
Mind-altering drugs
like LSD have been used
for thousands of years
to help open the mind
and connect the body
with the soul.
Along with hypnotherapy,
this can be
a valuable tool in healing both
mental and physical ailments.
And what ailment were you
treating Claudia Weber for?
Claudia had been having
violent dreams,
and I believe that they
were repressed memories
of a traumatic experience
that happened when she was four.
What kind
of a traumatic experience?
I think that someone viciously
attacked Claudia and her mother.
She actually remembered
this happening?
Well, recovered memories--
it's not like a movie
with a beginning,
middle and an end.
It-It comes in flashes.
And the brain doesn't
want to remember. It's...
It's too painful.
Mm. So how's that work?
What, do you interpret
those flashes, do you?
I wasn't influencing
Claudia's memories,
if that's what
you're implying.
I was just there
to guide her
safely through
the process.
I recorded the sessions
if you'd like to see them.
SHAW:
As I continue
to talk, you feel a heavy,
relaxed feeling come over you.
With every word that I say,
it's putting you
faster and deeper into
a peaceful state of hypnosis.
How old are you, Claudia?
Four.
Look at that.
She's already
under the influence.
The LSD is making her
prone to suggestion.
Maybe it's just
making it easier
for her to tap
into her subconscious.
SHAW:
Where are you?
(Claudia panting)
I'm in the woods.
Who is with you?
CLAUDIA:
I'm in a tent.
By myself.
I'm scared.
No one can hurt you.
You're safe.
(clanking, banging,
woman screaming)
Mommy?!
They're hurting her.
SHAW:
Who's hurting her?
I don't know.
(man grunts)
(Claudia gasps)
(gasps)
I need you to
stay in the tent.
All right, everything's
going to be okay.
I won't let anything
happen.
Stay here.
(zipping door)
Brent!
SHAW:
Who's Brent?
(grunting)
Brent?
Okay, so that was
her last session.
What are you thinking?
She talks about this guy
Brent, from her past,
who tried to save her.
If any of this
even happened.
Why would you say that?
Because it's a memory from
when she was four years old.
Tr-trust me, kids' memories
are not the most reliable.
They have vivid imaginations.
Charlie--he swears
that he fell off a horse
when he was
five years old.
Never happened.
But look at Claudia's
autopsy report.
Doc found evidence
of an old brain injury
right where she said she
got hit by the shovel.
I mean, don't you think
it's strange
that Claudia starts
having childhood memories
of someone trying
to kill her,
and then, one month later,
she's dead?
I mean, that cannot
be a coincidence.
Timing is interesting.
I'm thinking that
whoever tried to kill her
when she was a kid came
back to finish the job.
Mr. Weber, I am so sorry
for your loss.
Your daughter was
such a talented athlete.
Thank you.
You-you said you had some
questions you wanted to ask me.
I do. Did you
and your family ever go
on a camping trip
when Claudia was little?
No.
My wife wasn't really the, uh...
the roughing-it type.
Why?
Well, about month ago,
Claudia started having memories
from when she was four.
A-a camping trip where both
she and her mother
were violently attacked.
We always wondered
what happened.
What do you mean?
I'm not Claudia's
biological father.
When she was
four years old,
I found her
lying unconscious
by the side of the road,
up in Mount Charleston.
She was bleeding,
she was near death.
I picked her up
and I took her to the hospital.
Did you report it
to the police?
Well, of course.
I told them.
They searched the area
where I found her, but they...
they never found her family.
Did Claudia ever tell anyone
what happened to her?
She didn't
remember anything.
The only way we figured
her name was Claudia
is because it was, uh...
it was written
on her jacket.
Did anyone ever
come looking for her?
Were there any
missing persons reports?
Nothing. I mean, we just
assumed she was abandoned.
Social Services let
my wife and I become
foster parents,
and then, um...
well, eventually,
we adopted her.
Did you tell Claudia
any of this?
We just wanted her to
feel like she was ours.
And she was.
She was ours.
We thought it
was a blessing
she didn't remember
what happened to her.
FINLAY:
So, these were taken
at the hospital
the day Claudia was found.
She suffered
severe head trauma,
dehydration
and multiple cuts and abrasions.
You know, a head injury
would explain
why she couldn't
remember anything.
Yeah, not to mention
the emotional trauma
from the attack.
You know, in all
her sessions, Claudia never
mentioned a daddy, just Brent.
Could be a brother,
stepfather,
mother's boyfriend.
Hey, look at that--
Blossom Ballerina.
Just like the one you found
in Claudia's tennis bag.
It looked like it hadn't
been cleaned in years.
If she had that toy when
she was attacked,
there still could be
evidence on it.
I'll get it to Hodges.
Hmm.
You decapitated
Blossom Ballerina.
Well, I assure you,
she didn't feel a thing.
So, I talked
to Simon Weber.
His wife passed away
a year ago.
He was cleaning out his house,
going through boxes.
He came across a box
of Claudia's old toys.
Hmm.
Sent them to her
last month.
Could be seeing this toy is
what triggered her memories.
And if we can figure out who
tried to kill her back then,
we might be able to
find out who killed her now.
Exactly.
Hm.
Was there something else?
Yeah.
Elisabetta.
That's... Wow.
She's something, isn't she?
Oh, yeah. Firecracker.
She is Italian.
I'm just surprised
you got engaged so quickly.
Well, when you know,
you know, right?
But...
you guys haven't known
each other that long,
and... marriage is not
something you rush into.
I-I would just hate
to see you get hurt.
Yeah. Uh, don't
worry about me.
What if this woman is using
you to get a green card?
Yeah.
Why would a beautiful,
amazing woman
want to marry me, right?
That is not
what I meant at all.
You know I think you are
a great guy; you know that.
It took me
ten months to choose
a new cell phone last year.
I analyzed
consumer reports,
data rates,
battery longevity.
For once,
I'm following my heart,
not analyzing everything.
And that's great,
but you don't have to go
from one extreme
to the other.
Can't you just
be happy for me?
I don't trust this woman.
There's no other way
to say it.
And deep down in your heart,
I don't think you do, either.
If you thought
this was a real relationship,
you'd be shouting it
from the rooftops, right?
This is exactly why I didn't
say anything to anyone.
Because I knew
this is how you'd all react.
I just didn't
expect it from you.
I love Elisabetta.
Unless Immigration
gets in the way,
I'm going to marry her.
Hey, what do you got?
Well, Hodges found traces
of Claudia's blood
on that Blossom Ballerina.
Lack of solubility suggested
it was a very old blood sample.
So she did have it
during the attack.
Well, you know, even though
Claudia was rescued,
her mom never came
looking for her.
Yeah, well, maybe
Mom and Brent
never made it out
of those woods.
Exactly.
Hodges found something else
mixed in with the blood.
Sulfur. So, I've pulled up
a map of Mount Charleston.
There are several
sulfur springs in the area.
Well, according
to the police report,
Simon Weber found Claudia
on a service road
just South of Echo Cliff.
There's a sulfur spring
less than five
miles from there.
Yeah, let's get some
ground-penetrating equipment
out there,
see what we can find.
♪ ♪
WOMAN:
Clear!
(oscillating tone)
MAN:
Clear!
Well, I have a hit.
(sighs)
Looks animal.
Maybe coyote.
MAN:
Clear.
Hey, I got something.
That's too big
to be an animal.
♪ ♪
(sighs)
One male, one female.
Yeah.
Yeah, I think we just
found Mom and Brent.
Based on the dimensions
of the injuries
and the extent
of the trauma,
weapon used could have been
some sort of wide-based tool.
Like a shovel?
Yeah, injuries are
consistent with a shovel.
Just like Claudia remembered.
Take a look at the extent
of the injuries to the male.
Multiple depressed
skull fractures...
ring fracture
at the base of the skull.
He was nearly decapitated.
So he took the brunt
of the killer's rage.
Hey, got DNA results,
and we've restored
the I.D.s found
at the grave site.
These are actually both
Claudia's biological parents.
Both?
Meet Karen...
and Martin Abbott.
Martin.
Who the hell's Brent?
FINLAY:
Brent was their son.
Karen and Martin Abbott
were from Montana.
Brent was their oldest child,
and when he was 12,
they had Claudia.
All-American family.
Well, not exactly.
Martin Abbott
had a record.
For what?
Assault
and credit card fraud.
When the family
disappeared,
he had several
outstanding warrants.
Maybe that's why nobody
reported the family missing.
Thought they
just skipped town.
Okay, Abbott family gets
the hell out of Dodge.
They go camping
up in Nevada.
Parents end up dead,
Claudia barely escapes
with her life,
and Brent--
nowhere to be found.
FINLAY:
So Brent is either
our killer
or he is still buried
out in those woods.
Claudia thought
her brother was still alive.
I-I went through
her phone records.
For the past few weeks
she's been calling Brent Abbotts
across the country.
She was calling
Brent Abbotts
up until the day
she was killed.
I-I contacted
a few of them.
Claudia asked them
all the exact same question:
were they on a camping trip
18 years ago?
What if one of
these Brent Abbotts
really was her brother?
And he got nervous
that she was remembering
what happened
in those woods.
That he killed their parents,
tried to kill her.
So he returns to Vegas
to shut her up for good.
Got away with
murder once,
probably thought he
could do it again.
Only problem is, Claudia called
at least 50 Brent Abbotts.
How do we figure out
which one's our killer?
Hey, Finn.
Hi.
I've done some more checking
into Martin Abbott.
Now, according
to his rap sheet,
he's used
several aliases.
One of them--
Ernest Prestwich.
Why does that sound
familiar?
Well, Ernest Prestwich is a
janitor at the tennis center,
but that's not
his real name.
According to his
contact information,
he has an L.A. cell
registered to Brent Abbott.
So Brent used one
of his dad's aliases
but forgot to change
his cell phone number.
I cross-referenced
Claudia's phone records.
She called him a week ago.
That's great.
Let's bring him in.
Patrol just picked him up
at a service station.
Looks like the past finally
caught up to you, Brent.
We found your parents' bodies
on Mount Charleston,
right where you buried 'em.
After you beat them to
death with a shovel.
We get it.
Your old man
was bad news.
I did some digging
into your history.
I know you made a lot
of trips to the ER.
I know that that son of a
bitch beat the crap out of you
since you were
eight years old.
We understand.
Yeah, the cops even came
to your house a few times,
and your mother never
pressed charges.
She always
covered for him.
She would always say
that the bruises were
from fights at school
and the broken bones
were from football.
And on this family
camping trip
you decided to end the
abuse once and for all.
Am I right?
We were in the middle
of the woods.
So I waited for everyone to fall
asleep and I took out Dad first.
Your dad abused you and your
mom did not protect you.
But why would
you try to kill
your four-year-old
little sister?
I didn't mean
to hurt Claudia.
I told her to wait in
the tent; she didn't listen.
(grunting)
Claudia!
I thought she was dead.
I went to dig the grave.
When I turned around,
she was gone.
But she saw what you did.
Is that why you showed up
18 years later and killed her?
I-I didn't kill her.
I-I-I looked her up and saw
that she was playing in Vegas.
I didn't come here
to kill her.
I came here to, to talk to her,
explain my side of the story.
Okay. What'd she say?
I didn't get a chance
to talk to her.
I went to the courts that night,
and she wasn't there...
so I left.
I didn't kill my sister.
G-give me a-a-a polygraph
or take my DNA--
whatever it is you people do--
but I didn't kill Claudia.
What time did you
leave the court?
It, it was, like, 1:00.
Can anyone verify that?
It was pretty deserted.
N-No, there was the other,
uh, tennis player, though,
um, Janssen,
Tara Janssen.
She was there.
What was she doing?
I don't know,
practicing, I guess.
She had a basket
full of tennis balls.
♪ ♪
We found your prints
in Claudia Weber's blood.
BRASS:
Game. Set. Murder.
RUSSELL:
You know,
I always thought
that you just killed Claudia
'cause you were
a sore loser, but...
murder over an off day
seemed a bit extreme,
so... we took
a closer look.
You know, I always
wondered what players said
to each other
after a match,
so we isolated
and boosted the audio.
Good match.
By the way, I'm sleeping
with your husband.
Ooh, that's cold.
I probably would have just
stuck with a handshake.
Out of curiosity,
how long have you been
involved with Ivan?
Almost a year.
He and Claudia were
having problems
long before I came
into the picture.
So, instead of
helping your friend,
you helped yourself
to her husband.
I loved him.
He was going to ask
Claudia for a divorce.
That's why he went
over there that night.
I'm sorry, I know,
she doesn't...
JANSSEN:
But instead he told her
that he still loved her
and that he wanted
to work on their marriage.
Claudia agreed
to give him
a second chance.
She didn't even love him.
She just didn't want
me to have him.
That's enough
to set anybody off,
especially someone
with a temper like yours.
She took everything
from me that night.
She took the match
and she took Ivan.
I hated her for that.
(both grunting)
(yells)
(sobs)
I killed her and I stuffed
her body in the ball machine.
Me and Ivan--
we were good together.
We were.
She just should
have walked away.
Yeah, but she didn't, so you
eliminated your competition
on and off the court.
So, instead of
serving aces,
all you'll be
serving is time.
Hey, glad I
caught you.
Oh, hi, I was just going
to get dinner with my dad.
Oh, tell him I said hi.
I just wanted to thank you.
My lawyer called
and told me
that you talked
to Immigration;
gave me a glowing
character reference.
Seemed like it couldn't
hurt, right?
Mm-hmm.
Yeah, but you weren't
exactly supportive
of my relationship
with Elisabetta.
(sighs)
You're my friend, and I just
want what's best for you,
so, if she makes you happy,
then it's good enough for me.
Thank you.
I should go.
Okay.
(sighs)
FINLAY:
So, I guess Tara Janssen
will go down in the
history books after all.
Yeah, just not the way
she wanted, I'm guessing.
Mm.
So now you can take
her spot on the tour.
(laughs)
That's funny.
Now, don't be so modest.
I heard that Chris Evert said
you had some real talent.
Well, I did play a lot
when I was a kid.
You ever think
about turning pro?
Oh, when I was 15,
yeah, for a second.
What happened?
Life--life happened.
Well, I'm glad it did.
Yeah, me, too.