(wolf howls)
(eerie moaning)
(evil laughter)
MAN:
What's up, man?
Shut your mouth and act like
you got some sense, girl!
Are you sure you have
the right address?
It's 1027 Washington Street.
(cackling in distance)
I don't even
see any numbers.
Well, it's got
to be just...
up there.
You better shut
your mouth!
That guy
has a gun.
It's...
probably just part
of his costume.
MAN:
Yo.
Cheerleader.
Yeah, you.
Okay.
Forget the party.
Let's get a cab
and go home.
MAN:
Want to party with us?
(man laughing)
(gasps)
What is that?
(growling, slobbering)
(snarling)
(barking)
(screaming)
MAN:
Come!
STOKES:
Hey.
What's going on?
Well, the dog's
freaking out.
Won't let us near the body.
It's like he's...
guarding his kill.
STOKES:
Who called it in?
BRASS: Tinker Bell
and the cheerleader.
They got lost on the way
to a party. At first,
they thought
the body was a fake.
Happy Halloween.
STOKES:
Looks like the dog went
for his throat.
Yeah.
BRASS:
Animal instinct.
Well, his throat is
completely ripped open.
Must've bled out.
STOKES:
Any I.D.?
Yeah.
Smith &amp; Wesson.
Okay, well...
Gun hasn't been fired.
And a wallet.
(dog barking)
STOKES:
He's a cop.
K-9 Unit,
Officer Mike Nelson.
So you think
that's his dog?
So much for man's best friend.
Found something else.
Want to give me
some light there?
Okay.
Oh, man.
Well, it looks like
methamphetamines, Jim.
So we got a cop out of uniform
in a skanky part of town
with a bag of ice.
Something stinks here
and I don't think it's the dog.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
(barking, snarling)
STOKES:
CSI Russell,
Sergeant Varanski,
chief trainer
with the K-9 unit.
Sorry about Officer Nelson.
Is that dog
always that aggressive?
Sam? No.
He and Mike were partners
for eight years.
Best team in the department.
STOKES: Officer Nelson
was out of uniform.
Was he working undercover?
No.
He was off duty last night.
If he was off duty,
what was he doing
in the alphabets
with a bag full of meth?
Mike was a good cop.
They both were.
These dogs are trained
to attack, am I right?
They only bite to hold a suspect
or to defend themselves.
We're talking about
more than just a bite here,
Sergeant.
Nelson's throat was ripped open.
Can you think of
anything that would set
that dog off?
He could be sick.
That would make
any dog lash out.
And he could've gotten
into Nelson's stash. I mean,
look at him.
(growls)
I'll take him into custody,
get him checked out by the vet.
No, no.
No, we have
to process him first.
He's got evidence
all over him.
STOKES:
Yeah, when we're done
I'll make sure
he gets to you, okay?
Thank you very much.
Appreciate that.
(barking, snarling)
STOKES:
Hey.
Brass found
Nelson's truck
about a block from
the crime scene.
Had it towed in.
Find anything?
Yeah.
A piece of the dog's nail,
and some dried blood
on the window.
Dog clawed
his way out.
(barking)
So, if Nelson was off duty,
buying drugs,
why bring the dog?
Sergeant told me that the dog
lived with Nelson.
Went everywhere with him.
So... for protection?
Well, if that's the case,
why would you
leave the dog in the truck?
Maybe that's what
he was trying to protect.
In a neighborhood like that,
you leave your truck,
you never know
if it's gonna be there
when you get back,
especially on Halloween.
Department-issued envelope...
...full of cash.
Huh.
Must be at least
five grand here.
Could've been stolen
from Evidence.
Could be this dog wasn't just
going after his partner,
he was going after a dirty cop.
Meet Barry Sloan.
Big-shot lawyer.
Lived alone.
But I bet
he wasn't lonely.
This place
reeks of money.
Professionally decorated,
impeccably clean...
all to impress the ladies.
Yeah, I've spent some time
in bedrooms like this.
(chuckles)
Thought you were into cops.
I do marry cops, but...
I've dated some lawyers.
They're fun to argue with.
Hm.
Boy, they can be sleazy
sometimes, though.
Apparently, you're not
the only one
who thinks so.
Police responded
to a 911 call, shots fired.
When they got here,
the shower was still running,
but Mr. Sloan
is bone-dry.
GSW to the chest.
Blood is confined
to this area, which means
he must've been on the bed
or nearby when he was shot.
Shooter missed at least once.
Found a bullet hole
in the wall there.
Based on the trajectory,
looks like it came
from that direction.
(camera shutter clicking)
Radial cracks indicate
that the force
must've originated
from the outside.
(gunshot)
Means our shooter was
on the outside of the window.
Who called it in?
(indistinct police radio
communication)
(indistinct chatter)
Mrs. Young?
Ms.
I got tired
of being a housewife.
Dumped the husband,
kept the last name.
And his Jag.
Oh, lucky you.
I had to pay
mine alimony.
FINLAY: So, what exactly
did you hear?
Well, I get up early every
morning to do my meditation.
I had just reached an elevated
state of consciousness
when I heard: bang, bang!
So two gunshots in all.
Yeah.
And what time was that?
I looked at the clock.
It was 6:05.
And did you see anything?
Anyone?
Nothing.
But then I had
this really bad feeling
it had something
to do with Barry.
Why do you think it had
something to do with Barry?
Mm. A lot of people hated him.
He was a real shark.
Divorce lawyer.
I've known quite
a few of those.
One time
a brick came flying through
my window with a note attached.
It said, "Burn in hell,
you scumbag lawyer."
Meant for
Barry but...
they got my house by mistake.
So, I guess
Mr. Sloan was not very popular
in the neighborhood.
Listen, I feel bad about what
happened to Barry, but...
you ask me, our property values
just went up.
That's a horrible
thing to say.
The poor man just died.
And how exactly
do you know Mr. Sloan?
Oh, um, we've been neighbors
for 13 years.
Oh, uh, Marjorie Randall.
Look, when I had
my hip replacement,
Barry brought
in my mail every day.
So you two were good friends?
Oh, yes.
Did he ever discuss
his work with you?
Oh, he talked about it
all the time.
He loved his job.
Especially when he won a case.
Do you know
if he was in the middle
of a particularly messy one?
Barry just always said
that all divorces were messy.
Do you think that
that could've had
something to do with his death?
We will do everything
we can to find out.
(barking)
How you doing with Cujo?
I don't know.
He's still pretty riled up.
Well, why don't you wait
for Varanski?
He's on his way back.
He'll help you muzzle the dog.
Then you can get your evidence.
By the time
he gets here, all the evidence
is gonna be gone. Look at him.
Look at him.
He's licking it all away.
Hey, if you're thinking about
opening up that cage,
we're gonna have
another crime scene.
(sighs) Maybe he's just
threatened by me, you know?
I mean, he's in there,
he's cornered,
I'm coming at him
with sticks.
Open the gate,
maybe he'll calm down.
Nick...
Hey, come on.
Don't worry.
I had a bunch of dogs growing
up-- know what I'm doing.
(phone rings)
All right, look,
I got Doc Robbins.
Nick, that dog killed somebody.
Wait for Varanski. Please.
(dog growling)
(growling)
(barking)
Well, boy...
(sighs)
(barks, growls)
I'm not gonna let you
destroy all my evidence.
(growls)
I'm gonna process you,
just like any other suspect,
whether you like it or not.
So...
here's how it's gonna go down.
I'm gonna let you
out of this crate,
and when I do,
you're gonna be cool...
and I'm gonna be cool.
(low bark)
Okay?
(low growl)
Easy.
Easy...
Easy, now.
(low groan)
(low growl)
(growls, barks)
(grunts, snarls)
(barking)
(growling)
How about one of these?
Huh?
Want a little treat?
Cooperate, now, okay?
(barks)
Right in here.
Cooperate.
Right in here, bud.
Easy.
(whines)
You got something
in your teeth there.
Easy.
I'm not gonna hurt you.
(low growl)
Well, it looks like you got
your pound of flesh, eh?
ROBBINS:
When the kids were little,
I bought them a dog.
A mutt from the shelter.
He slept on my daughter's bed
every night--
part of the family.
Yeah, it's easy to forget
they're still animals.
ROBBINS: It's hard to
make out the teeth marks.
May have to call in
an odontologist.
Well, maybe the saliva
will give us
the dog's DNA.
You said our victim
had drugs on him--
I don't see
any needle marks.
Could be
a new user.
Maybe the drugs haven't
taken their toll yet.
I'll send blood and hair
over to Tox.
Multiple cuts and bruises,
defensive wounds.
Boy, this guy
put up quite a fight.
Why didn't he pull his gun?
I think I know why.
When the dog attacked Nelson,
he must have knocked him over.
(barking)
(bone cracks)
The angle of the fall
broke Nelson's arm
in two places,
rendering the arm useless.
Well, that explains
why he didn't shoot the dog.
One mystery solved.
♪ ♪
Hey.
Hit the jackpot.
Yeah?
.38 Special.
Just like the slug
we took out of the wall.
That's not all I found:
fingerprints on the windowsill.
Killer saw
quite a show.
I found semen stains.
No way a guy
like Sloan wouldn't
wash his sheets,
so they're fresh.
And he wasn't alone.
Lipstick?
Mm-hmm.
Maybe Mr. Sloan was sleeping
with someone's wife.
Or girlfriend.
Yeah.
His job didn't
get him killed,
his penis did.
You're back
from the vet?
Yeah. Yeah, they did
a full workup.
The dog's healthy
as an ox.
And his tox came back
clean, too.
But if there's behavioral
issues, there's not
much they can do.
Well, I guess that makes
him a dead dog walking.
Yeah, unfortunately.
Well, his tox wasn't the only
one that came back clean.
No drugs in Officer
Nelson's system, either.
Hair analysis proves
that he wasn't
a regular user.
If he wasn't buying drugs
in that part of town,
then what was he doing
with all that cash
in his truck?
I don't know.
But I can tell you
that he didn't steal
it from evidence.
Money came from his
personal bank account.
He made a series
of large withdrawals
within the last
six months.
Well, he was into something.
ANDREWS:
Where's the dog?
Animal Control.
ANDREWS:
What?
No, they're gonna put him down--
you have to stop them.
Why? What's going on?
The dog is innocent.
He didn't kill his partner.
The saliva on Nelson's throat,
it isn't canine; it was human.
(dog snarling)
BRASS:
Start of the zombie apocalypse.
You know, we had a case where
a cheerleader, high on PCP,
ate another
cheerleader's stomach.
Nelson's killer
was high on something.
Why was Nelson
in a Cracktown, anyway?
He could've been setting
someone up, you know,
planting evidence to
catch a bigger fish,
things go south,
he gets killed, I don't know.
But not before his partner
took a piece out of the killer.
That flesh from the dog's teeth
came back to...
an unknown male.
(panting)
(Sam whines)
I guess Nick sprung him
from Animal Control.
Ah, there he is. Sam.
Hey, wha...?
Sorry, he just got away from me.
I can't have him
walking around CSI.
I know. Come on.
STOKES:
Sam, come on. Come. Hey.
S...
Boy, you have a way
with dogs, Stokes.
Hey, this pain in the ass may
help us find Nelson's killer.
I mean, he is our only witness.
Aw, no, hey, come on,
that's my anniversary gift!
Drop it, Sam.
RUSSELL:
That is hand-carved.
One of a kind.
(whispers):
Drop it!
(low growl)
BRASS: I know he's a highly
trained police dog,
but how the hell is he
gonna help with the case?
He won't even
drop an anniversary gift.
(Sam whines)
(barking)
(growling)
(gunfire)
Sergeant Varanski.
(dogs barking)
Hey, Nick.
Hey, man, how's it going?
Good to see you.
Thanks for clearing his name;
you really saved his life.
(Sam whining)
What you got there?
Huh? What
you got, boy?
(low growl)
Say, if it's all right with you,
we'd like to hang on
to him for a while,
see if he can help us
track down Officer
Nelson's killer.
Sure. If anyone
can, it's Sam.
Best nose in
the department.
There is one problem, though.
I can't get him to do anything.
He won't even drop
that stupid totem pole.
Maybe you're not
speaking his language.
No?
What's that, "dog"? I could
try barking or something.
French. Sammy was born
just outside of Paris.
All the dogs come to us
fully trained.
Laisser tomber!
(whines)
There you go.
Go ahead, take
his leash off.
Okay.
(barks)
Venez!
♪ ♪
Asseyez-vous.
Fini.
Guess I better brush up
on my French.
Well, that and, uh...
earn his respect.
(quietly):
Right.
Hey.
So you know those...
fingerprints I collected
outside the vic's
windowsill?
Yeah.
Got a hit in AFIS.
Brent Walsh.
A casino worker
in the middle of a divorce.
And Mr. Sloan
was his lawyer.
MAN:
That arrogant,
despicable piece of crap.
I take it
you weren't satisfied
with his services.
I'll say.
He was too busy
satisfying my wife.
They were sleeping together?
Sloan is supposed
to protect my assets,
not hand everything over
to that bitch.
That's when I got suspicious.
So you went to Sloan's
house last night.
Yeah. I snuck in the side yard
and I peeked in
the bedroom window.
That's when I saw that scumbag
sleeping with the enemy.
(moaning)
BRODY:
And then you waited
for your ex-wife
to leave, and you shot Sloan.
WALSH:
No. I don't even own a gun.
I didn't want Sloan... dead.
I wanted him... disbarred,
unemployed, homeless.
But you were there.
You had motive.
I peeked in the window,
and then I left.
Where'd you go?
I went to work.
I'm a blackjack dealer at
the Tangiers, graveyard shift.
I checked in at midnight
and finished my shift at 8:00.
You can check surveillance.
I will.
Where can I find Mrs. Walsh?
At my house.
With my cat.
And all my stuff.
You got something
on Officer Nelson?
Yeah. I checked
his phone records.
Couple of hours before he died,
Nelson got a call
from a pay phone around
the corner from the crime scene.
Liquor store cam
caught a glimpse
of our mystery caller.
Judging by the outfit, I'd say
she's a working girl.
What's that
in her pocket?
RUSSELL:
Yellow bandana.
Just like the one
we found on Nelson.
I'm thinking he
got the drugs from her.
DNA proved
that a man killed Nelson,
but if she was there,
she could be involved, right?
Or, at the very least,
a witness.
Okay.
I'll have Brass round up
all the hookers in Cracktown
that look anything like her;
maybe our police dog
can pick her out of a lineup.
(quietly):
Oh, boy.
Ladies...
can I have your attention
for a second?
Hi. First of all,
thank you for coming in.
Did we have a choice?
No, not really.
But I'll get you out of here
as soon as I can.
Okay, open up your jars there.
Go ahead, open 'em up.
Yeah, reach in
and pull out the pipe,
and hold it in your hand.
I'd rather hold on to your pipe.
Uh, thank you,
I appreciate that,
but my wife frowns
on that kind of thing.
Where do you want me
to put this?
Just hold on to it.
By doing that,
you're transferring your scent
onto the pipe.
If I rub it,
will it get bigger?
Young lady,
as long as you're holding it,
I'm happy.
All right,
put 'em back in.
Thank you.
Put the lids on.
There you go. Come on.
Look, Sam, I know we got
off to a bad start, and
I know you miss your partner.
You guys were together
a long time.
(whimpers)
But I want the
same thing you do--
to catch his killer.
I can't do that
without your help.
You understand?
So... want to
go to work?
Hey, Sam. How you doing, boy?
(whines)
Okay. Trouvez.
(sniffing)
(barks)
Recognize this?
Officer Nelson's partner did.
He identified you
as the working girl
who gave Nelson
this bandana,
which was full of
methamphetamine, by the way.
Hey.
RUSSELL:
Carly,
we know
you called Officer Nelson
from a pay phone last night.
We know you met up with him
and gave him the drugs.
And then you killed him.
Gave him the drugs, that was it.
Well, why would you do that?
He wasn't a user.
Ms. Green,
we know all about you.
We know that Officer Nelson
arrested you
for possession
and prostitution,
and sent you to prison
for nine months.
Must have hated
him for that.
BRASS: So, last night,
you lured him downtown
and got one of your
junkie friends to kill him.
No, that's bull.
Mike was the only person
who gave a damn about me.
He even visited me in prison.
Okay, so why did
you call him then?
Mike used to pay me for info.
When something new
hit the streets,
I'd turn it
over to him.
Help him go after the dealers.
Are you telling me,
you're a C.I.?
You were Officer Nelson's
confidential informant?
Yeah.
It was Mike's way
of giving me a second chance.
Look, I gave him the drugs, told
him what I knew and beat it.
When I left, he was still alive.
What are you doing?
The GCMS is broken,
and the repairman's
on vacation.
So you're fixing
it yourself?
Are you even
qualified to do that?
I am a man of many talents.
I'm just saying,
defense attorneys
love to challenge
our findings in court,
and if this is not fixed
exactly to code,
you are gonna be in...
Okay, can... can we just
forget the GCMS for a moment?
Can you and I talk about...
you know?
No.
So, we're just gonna pretend
like it never happened?
Yes.
Now, when you are
up and running,
I need results
on the red smudge
on my victim's shirt, please.
Okay.
(laughs softly)
Thanks for stopping in.
Yeah.
So, you and
Hodges doing it?
What? No.
I think it's
great really.
He's funny, he's
charming, smart.
He's like an awkward
Jimmy Stewart.
Okay, you know what?
I kissed him.
Once.
Really?
I was at the hospital.
My dad had been shot.
It just happened.
And now things are all awkward
between us.
(sighs)
Did you get anything
off the gun?
Uh, did not get any prints,
but it is definitely
our murder weapon.
Striations matched the slug
we pulled out of the wall.
And this is where
it really gets good.
The gun was registered
to Barry Sloan himself.
Shot by his own gun?
Mm.
So, Brent Walsh's
alibi checked out.
But he claims that his ex
was sleeping with the vic.
(moaning)
Which would give her access
to Sloan's house and his gun.
Let's bring her in.
Hey, Doc, got your 911.
What's up?
Body was just brought in.
Fingerprints matched a person of
interest in your dead cop case.
Okay, let's take a look.
That's Carly Green.
I interviewed her
earlier today.
What--what happened to her?
Found her at the Blue Siren
Motel with a needle in her arm.
Apparent overdose.
Yeah.
Heard Hooker
Number Four OD'd.
Carly Green.
Detective just logged in the
evidence from her motel room.
Lots of condoms, needles.
Live hard, die hard...
so to speak.
Bloody bandage.
Did Russell say anything
about Carly having
other injuries?
No.
Doc's doing her
autopsy right now.
But I did find
this LVPD envelope.
It looks just like the one
we found in Nelson's truck.
There's 800 bucks in there.
Carly said Nelson
was paying her as a C.I.,
so I checked with
Sergeant Varanski.
Said Nelson hadn't worked
Narcotics in over a year.
Well, Nelson must have been
paying her from his own pocket.
Unless he was paying her
for something else.
I mean, she was a hooker.
She wasn't a thousand
dollar a night hooker.
Something was going on
between them.
ROBBINS: Carly Green
didn't commit suicide.
D.B., take a look.
Needle didn't hit a vein.
RUSSELL:
She has track marks.
She was a regular user.
You'd think she'd know
how to find a vein.
That's what
kept me looking.
Found this.
It's a needle mark
right in the middle of her back.
She couldn't do that herself.
So Carly Green was murdered.
Well, there's more.
Ms. Green was also pregnant.
Based on the thickening
of the uterus
and the size of the fetus,
I'd say about ten weeks.
You know, she told me
that Officer Nelson
was the only person
in her life
who ever cared for her.
You think he was the father?
Well, he spent a lot of time
visiting her in prison,
and he was giving her money.
All right.
Let's take a sample
of the fetus's DNA.
Have Henry run it.
Absolutely.
All this time,
I thought he was a dirty cop.
Well, maybe he just got involved
with the wrong woman,
trying to make things right.
I didn't have sex
with Barry Sloan.
Yeah, you did...
the night he died.
We pulled your DNA
off of his... penis.
Mrs. Walsh?
All right, I did.
I know it was wrong to sleep
with my husband's attorney,
but sex with Barry was...
He just kept you
coming back for more.
We have evidence that you were
not the only woman
who came back for
more last night.
(chuckles)
Your DNA had company
on his penis.
You know, the thing
about a three-way is,
someone usually ends up
being the third wheel.
It wasn't like that.
I had wild sex
with Barry.
When I was looking
for my clothes,
I found lace panties in his bed.
Not mine.
Then whose?
Barry said he couldn't
remember her name.
Some neighbor
he was screwing.
And how'd that make you feel?
Not angry enough to kill him,
if that's where you're going.
But you were angry.
Ooh, you bet your ass I was.
We got into a big fight.
Then I went home.
What time was that?
Around 5:30, 6:00.
Hm. That's right around
the time he was killed.
(sniffs)
If you're really hungry, I'll
share half my sandwich with you.
(laughs)
No. It's for the dog.
He's not eating for some reason.
Well, he lost his partner,
you know?
He's probably still grieving.
Yeah.
Okay, here's
where we are.
Henry matched the DNA
from the fetus
to that piece of flesh that you
pulled from your dog's teeth.
So Carly's baby daddy
isn't Nelson.
It's the guy who killed him?
That's right. Yeah.
He killed Carly, too.
That bloodied bandage
we found in her motel room?
Yup.
Also the killer's DNA.
And that's not all
Henry found in the bandage.
Bacteria and leucocytes.
The killer's wound is infected.
From the dog taking
a bite out of him.
He's going
to need medical attention.
Robbins already checked
all the local hospitals
and free clinics in the area.
No dog bites reported
in the last 24 hours.
Well, there are
some back alley clinics
near the Blue Siren motel.
What are you gonna do?
You don't have a name.
You don't know
who you're looking for.
No... but Sam does.
Hey, Sam?
I got a little something
for you... here.
(phone chirps)
(phone beeps on)
Thank God. Hey, I don't
know how he got in here,
but you got to
get him out.
I know, David.
I'm sorry.
Hey, boy.
Hey.
(sighs)
I should have known
I'd find you in here.
You really loved him, huh?
It's hard when
you lose a friend.
You know, I lost a friend once.
Partner in the line of duty.
I think it'll always hurt,
'cause...
well, I know
I'll never see him again.
But you know what
you can do for Mike?
Together, you and me...
we'll get a little justice.
Sound good?
(Sam whines)
(quiet whirring)
Did you know that,
in a lifetime,
the average woman eats
four pounds of lipstick?
And that helps our case how?
I confirmed the red smudge on
Barry Sloan's shirt as lipstick.
We knew that.
Yes, but did you also know
that lipstick,
like food, can go bad?
And to preserve
its shelf life,
cosmetic companies
used to use formaldehyde.
There's formaldehyde
in my lipstick?
Formaldehyde is
a carcinogen,
so cosmetic companies
these days use metheneamine,
which is a different
type of preservative.
Okay, so what about
the lipstick in our case?
Well, the lipstick
in our case contains
straight formaldehyde,
and was manufactured
by a company that went
out of business in 1972.
Are you sure the GCMS
is working properly?
I fixed it myself.
Oh, whatever
you say.
But who wears
40-year-old lipstick?
FINLAY:
Mrs. Randall...
Oh, call me Marjorie.
Marjorie, you told me
that you and Barry Sloan
were good friends.
That's right.
Good enough to have left
lipstick on his shirt?
CSI's are searching
your house right now,
and when they compare
your lipstick
to the smudge on
Barry's shirt,
I'm... betting
it's gonna match.
Lots of women
wear lipstick.
This sample was
much older than
all of the women that
Barry was sleeping with.
Were the two of you
intimately involved?
My husband left me ten years
ago, for a younger woman.
I never thought
I'd fall in love again.
(laughs quietly)
Till I met Barry.
For years,
I never told him how I felt.
He always had some
beautiful woman on his arm.
But the other morning,
I heard him arguing
with one of them.
Look, I never said
we were exclusive.
You made me think we were.
Come on, okay?
We've been having fun.
You really are a
scumbag, you know that?
Go to hell.
She was so mean to him.
So you saw an opportunity
to make your move.
Well, I wanted him
to know that he was...
appreciated.
That he was loved.
Marjorie.
Everything all right?
I heard you arguing
with that woman.
I'm sorry. I didn't
mean to wake you.
Oh, no, no, you didn't.
I just wanted to make
sure that you're okay.
You are so sweet.
I don't deserve you.
Mmm...
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
What the hell
are you doing!
I thought that...
You're kidding, right?
Hey, come on,
you're old enough
to be my mother. (scoffs)
He humiliated me.
(crying):
Just like my husband.
And you've been
carrying that anger
and that pain
for all those years
since your husband left.
So when Barry
rejected you...
you snapped.
(thump)
(body thuds)
Marjorie, we know that
the gun was Barry's.
How did you get it?
He gave it to me.
There'd been some break-ins
in the neighborhood,
and he wanted me to be safe.
I just wanted to be loved.
Is that so bad?
(siren wailing in distance)
The clinics down here
fly under the radar.
If you can call them that--
no licensed doctors,
no nurses, no questions asked.
BRASS: Well, whatever
you want to call it,
we're down to our last two.
Only could be the dog's
lost his mojo.
Well, he can do this.
(Sam panting)
That's it.
Trouvez.
Go on.
(Sam whines)
(barks)
He's got something.
(Sam barks)
BRASS (sighs):
Great, he wants a burrito.
No, no.
Hang on a second.
(Sam sniffing)
(Sam whines, growls softly)
(curious groan)
(growls)
(barks)
That's him!
Police! Stop!
(gunshots)
STOKES:
Move! Move!
BRASS (over radio): Shots fired!
Officer in pursuit! Send backup!
(panting)
(Sam barks, snarls)
(barking)
STOKES:
Hey!
(panting)
(gunshot,
gun clatters to ground)
(barks, growls)
(yelling)
Get him off me!
I didn't do nothin'!
I don't know, I'm kind of new
at this whole dog thing.
Let me see, uh,
hmm--release him.
(yelling)
Get him off me!
STOKES: No, no-- drop him?
No, uh, it's...
STOKES:
Hmm...
(yelling continues)
Laisser tomber.
(Sam barks)
(pants)
You see, the dog over there
thinks that you
killed his partner,
Officer Nelson.
(siren approaching)
You know what I think?
I think he's right.
(Sam growls)
You're under arrest for murder.
Take this scumbag
to the hospital,
then book him.
Good job, Fido.
STOKES:
Hey, Sammy.
(chuckles)
(Sam whining)
Oui. Tres bien.
(chuckles)
Good boy.
Good...
(panting)
(Sam whining)
I need a little help here, boys!
(Brass speaking indistinctly)
Okay, sign it.
Sign it.
(sighs)
Did you get a confession?
Vinnie was a regular songbird.
He wanted Carly
to get rid of the baby,
so she went
to Nelson for help.
Well, Vinnie followed her.
He sees them.
He's loaded on methamphetamine,
he's tweaking out of his mind,
he kills Nelson
right in front of her.
Poor Carly.
Too scared to talk to us.
Vinnie couldn't take the
chance, so he kills her.
And her baby.
STOKES: I don't know;
I'm still waiting.
He's been in there
for a couple hours.
Nah, nah, I'm okay.
Hey, listen, I got to go.
I'll call you back, okay?
All right.
So?
How's he doing?
Sam made it through surgery.
And?
Vet said he's going to be okay.
(laughs quietly)
Wow.
Well, that's--that's good.
I didn't even know Sam
had been shot.
He just kept going.
Mm. That's Sam for you.
Ah, here he is.
Hey, how you doing, boy?
Huh?
You did it, Sam.
You caught Mike's killer.
He's going to prison
for a very long time.
And we got some justice.
But don't you ever scare me
like that again,
you hear me?
You know, uh...
Sam was going to retire
at the end of the year,
spend the rest of his days
with Nelson, just being a dog.
Nelson didn't
have any family, so, uh,
Sam's going to
need a new home.
Well, I guess he could
come live with me.
That'd be nice.
What do you say, Sam?
I'll take
good care of you.
Now, there's gonna be
a few rules, okay?
No drinking out of
the toilet,
and, uh, we watch
football on Sundays,
and we root for the Cowboys.
(whimpers)
Okay?
And when
my girlfriend's over,
you got to sleep
on the floor.
All right? Is that a deal?
(laughing)
Okay, boy.
Ah, geez!