(water splashing)
(knocking on door)
I'm gonna be out in a second.
(phone rings)
Is that a girlfriend?
Not right now.
Can I see?
Ah! Whoa!
She wouldn't like that.
I'm gonna go to the bathroom.
Gonna be here when I get back?
If you're lucky.
(phone chirps)
RUSSELL:
Yeah.
Yeah, it's me.
I just heard about Ecklie.
I'm at, uh...
Where am I? I'm at, uh...
Bar 483.
I'm with
Moreno's partner Crenshaw.
Jules...
Something's definitely
not right.
they got Katie.
FINLAY:
What?!
McKeen. His-his people,
they took Katie for payback
for his son or something.
Crenshaw's one of 'em.
How do you know that?
FINLAY:
I just know.
I'm gonna stick with him
and see where he takes me.
You get your ass out of there
and come back
right now--
I've lost enough tonight.
I'll be in touch.
BARBARA: Your father
will not let anything
happen to Kaitlyn.
MAYA (sobbing):
No, no, no, no...
I want to see her room!
You can't come in here.
Listen, we have
to process the scene.
The scene?!
What are you talk...
Listen to me,
will you, please?
Listen to me.
I promise you
I will bring her home.
I promise.
(Maya sobbing)
OFFICER (over radio):
Go with the vitals
on Undersheriff Ecklie.
Tachycardia
in the 120.
BP: 82/40 and dropping.
O2 sats
in the 80s with
assisted ventilation.
Preparing to transport.
One, two, three.
What's his condition?
Stable but critical.
I'm going with him.
Russell's granddaughter's
been kidnapped.
What?!
It sounds like
it's McKeen.
Uh, I've tried
Nick three times.
He's not picking up.
Okay, I'll...
I'll handle things here.
You should go to Russell's.
Be careful.
CRENSHAW:
Where's your car?
(laughing):
I can't drive.
We'll take mine.
Where are we going?
Relax.
Enjoy the ride.
(car alarm chirps)
(books clattering)
(safe dial clicking)
How's Maya?
I gave her something
to calm her.
I never thought I would see
that in your hand again.
Neither did I.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
SIDLE:
Russell...
we found some
shoe impressions.
Some standard work boots.
I'm not sure
we're gonna get anything.
And this didn't come
from your house,
right?
Uh...
Could be transfer
from the kidnapper.
I'm gonna get
it to Hodges.
Uh, listen, th-there's something
else that you need to know.
"Property of LVPD."
Found it under the window.
We're looking at a cop.
You call Brass, and you
tell him I don't want
to see anyone here who's
not one of his guys.
SIDLE:
So, what do you want to do?
Just work-work the case, please.
Dad.
Hey, buddy.
BRASS:
Officer Tracey.
You're relieved
of your duty.
Officer Mitchell
will take over.
Now.
(door unlocks)
You don't look
like my bus driver.
You know, I've been
stuck in this cell
sucking my thumb
for three hours, waiting
for my transport back to Ely.
On your feet.
(sighs)
I'm traveling light
these days, Jim.
Goes with the uniform.
(grunts)
I don't know how
you've been communicating with
your people on the outside,
but however you've been
doing it, it's over.
You don't talk to anyone,
you don't see anyone.
Not even my lawyer?
Man's got his rights.
Not anymore.
Is D.B. on board with this?
'Cause I think he's really
gonna want to talk to me.
Anything happens to
that little girl...
...I got people, too.
So this is where you take
all your girls?
This is where I'm taking you.
(metal detector beeping)
(low chuckle)
Moreno?
Yeah.
Mmm.
He had his chance.
Hey, maybe this is a bad idea.
That's what makes it so good.
(siren wailing in distance)
You asked for a good time,
here it is.
(Finlay laughs wryly)
FINLAY: Yeah.
Nick? Where are you?
I have been calling and calling.
And McKeen unleashed hell...
tonight on Russell and Ecklie,
and his guys may be after you,
and I know that you said
that you quit,
but could you call me, please?
I, uh... I need your help.
I need to know
that you're all right.
(phone chimes)
(siren whoops)
Hey, don't worry,
we're safe, everybody.
The police are here.
CSI Stokes.
Lot of people looking
for you tonight.
Well, thank you for the
information, Mr. Clean.
Well, I'm just minding
my own business.
Ruining business, according
to the liquor store owner.
We can take you in
for drunk and disorderly.
You're right--
I am a little drunk.
But if you two chuckleheads
don't beat it...
...it's gonna get disorderly.
Man's got a gun, Hank.
Oh, this?
Yes, he does.
(laughing):
Whoa...
You're a little slow
on the draw there, Hank.
I don't even need this.
There's one beer left.
I'll fight you for it.
Could shoot you for it.
You do think she was
just kidnapped, right?
I don't know what to think.
Well, I know one thing:
you shouldn't be doing this.
It's a conflict of interest,
and the evidence
will be challenged in court.
Yeah, I'm not really thinking
about court right now, Sara.
You want to open up that kit,
or you gonna just stand there?
He's still in surgery.
I'll be
all right, David.
Y-You should get
back to work.
Are you sure?
Yeah.
Okay, but if-if you
need anything, call me.
Yeah.
I, uh...
found this change of
clothes in your locker.
I remember a car...
the sound of a gun...
...my-my father lying there,
but... I didn't see
anything, anyone.
I'm useless!
Still no word from Finn?
No.
But Brass talked
to Moreno,
and evidently, Moreno got
a text from Finn and...
he's worried.
Moreno?
You think we can trust him?
Well, he's gonna be here
in a few minutes.
You can ask him yourself.
More transfer.
Same as I found outside.
This comes with a bonus.
Hair.
ECKLIE:
Karma, Jeffrey.
Your son paid for your sins.
One phone call from me,
and your family's
living out of a car.
You leave my family
out of this, D.B.
Karma-- what's it mean?
Ecklie's words.
McKeen's sending me
the same message.
KATIE (distant, echoing):
No...!
(phone rings)
I guess I, uh, I should get
all this back to the lab.
I've been calling you.
But I think
you know that.
(Stokes grunts quietly)
Yeah, I'm done talking.
I didn't come
here to talk, Nick.
I'm came to drag
your ass back to work.
So, how many beers
have you had exactly?
Mm... not enough.
Look, I already
told you, Sara-- I quit.
Not tonight.
Tomorrow, you can
do whatever you want.
This is usually the kind
of place we shut down.
(Finlay laughs)
Oh, I'm-I'm good.
You're not on duty.
No.
Or are you?
(both suddenly laugh)
I'm bored.
Thought you wanted to see
how far this was going to go.
Yeah, where's it going to go?
Where is it going to go?
Let's go, guys.
Door at the end
of the hall.
You gonna tell me
what's behind the door?
Come on.
This is what
you came for.
Isn't it?
If you were going to kill me,
you would have done it already.
We could've had so much fun.
We still can.
Open the door.
Katie.
(Katie cries)
You're late.
ROBBINS: Are you sure
you want to do this?
I have to.
I am going to kill him.
You said they would call.
D.B.?
You said they'd call.
They will.
I like that.
Is that a new painting?
I-I've been working
on it for a few weeks.
I hadn't noticed.
I guess that's been
happening a lot lately.
I'm sorry.
That's the view from our bedroom
up in Seattle, right?
You miss it?
That's not a very good
question to ask me right now.
I'm sorry,
I don't know what...
(sighs)
The only thing worse than
the thought of losing Katie
is the thought of
losing both of you.
That is not
going to happen.
D.B.?
You hear from Finn?
BRASS: No.
MORENO: As you know,
I got a text message
from her a couple hours ago.
She was with Crenshaw,
said she was onto something.
And she wanted me to follow
her on the GPS.
We were tracking her toward
downtown.
The signal went dead somewhere
around Maryland Parkway.
Wait, what do you
mean it "went dead"?
Crenshaw's got a jammer.
Why-Why would you do that?
Why would you leave her alone
with some guy you know is dirty?
She wanted to be alone.
And there's no way that
I could have seen this coming.
You know something --
you ought to...
Listen, look, look.
I think McKean has blindsided
all of us on this one.
Radio call, sir.
Detective Crenshaw--
he's asking for CSI Russell.
Well, so much for
a tracing a call.
This is Russell.
CRENSHAW: I got someone who
wants to say hello.
Hey, it's me.
RUSSELL:
Where are you?
Uh, can't say,
but I'm with Katie.
and she's okay.
Grandpa!
KATIE:
I'm scared.
Hey, Katie.
That was proof of life.
They said that if you want
to see her again...
...you have to talk to McKeen.
Tell those sons of bitches
if they lay a hand on...
(radio static crackles)
This is okay.
Where's McKeen?
He's in holding.
Now, this isn't just
about McKeen's dead son.
His empire is crumbling.
He's burning the house down.
He's trying to take
us all with it.
I'm sorry.
Did Sara give you
some hairs to run?
Geez, what happened
to your face?
The hairs, please.
Right.
Well, there were no tags,
but DNA wouldn't help anyway.
'Cause I can tell
you right now,
they didn't come
from any kidnapper.
I pulled
exemplars for comparison.
Uh, hair's not human.
It's bovine.
Could still be transfer,
brought in on this guy.
Maybe we're looking for some
sort of dairy farm, or ranch.
Lots of those
in the Central Valley.
Maybe Hodges can help
you narrow it down.
I wish I had
better news for you.
The white trace you found
in the shoe impression
and in Katie's bedroom
is a composite
of calcium hydroxide,
gypsum and quartz.
Plaster.
Generic, at that.
Not exactly
a game-changer.
Patrol found a car
matching the description
of one fleeing the scene
where Ecklie was shot.
This was in the backseat.
Where's the car now?
It's in the garage.
Mandy's on it.
I'm going to process the gun
and someone needs to go back
to the hospital
to pick up the pellets
that were removed from Ecklie.
I'll go.
DOCTOR: That's about
all we can do for now.
Okay.
He's going to be okay.
That's good news.
I thought I lost him.
The whole time in the...
in the waiting room,
I kept thinking to myself,
if he dies, it's my fault.
There's nothing
you could've done.
That's not what I mean.
When I was a kid...
I was so angry at him.
Do you know how
many times I prayed...
that he would get shot?
That's not your fault, either.
I'm sorry.
Where's your buddy Brass?
This is what you want,
isn't it?
Maybe it's what you want.
I'm in no mood for games.
So there is a real cop
in there somewhere.
That's good to know.
'Cause maybe then we can
have an understanding.
What is it that you want?
You want to trade my
granddaughter for your freedom?
Is that it?
Don't insult me, D.B.
That'll never be on the table.
You know, you CSIs,
you're all the same.
You're-you're so busy
with your black-lights
and your little tweezers
and your spray bottles.
(mimicking hiss
of a spray bottle)
Who do you think you're
kidding with that thing?
What do you want?
What do I want?
You know, you were so
obsessed with the "how,"
that you never asked
yourself the "why"--
Why Donny Price got popped.
Why Veronica Gilmore
was beaten to death.
Why Jack Gilmore was
"innocently" framed?
You're saying Jack Gilmore
wasn't innocent?
I'm saying Jack Gilmore used
his whore of a wife
to steal $2 million in drug
money from Donny Price.
From me.
Collateral for his stadium.
I want what's mine.
For my family.
You want me to get $2 million?
From Jack Gilmore?
You get me my money back and
you get your granddaughter back.
You got 12 hours.
Now I got people
waiting by a phone,
and if they don't
hear from me, well, eh...
(mimicking the hiss
of a spray bottle)
I take care of your family,
you take care of mine.
Is that it?
Karma.
Where's Grandpa?
Will he find us?
Aw, honey.
Don't worry.
I am going to bring you home
to see him, okay?
And Grandma.
Mommy, too?
Of course you're going
to see your mommy.
Okay, but until then,
I really need you to be brave.
Okay.
(traffic driving by outside)
I'm scared.
Hey. I am going to go up
there and look at that.
And you go sit down.
Okay.
How are you supposed to get Jack
Gilmore to give you $2 million?
I have no idea.
Brass said the guy's
dropped out of sight.
Vanished.
Probably hiding
from McKeen, right?
Card's clean,
no prints.
Tear it apart--
ink, card stock, paper,
maybe it'll tell us
where it came from.
And who put it together.
(phone rings)
Yeah?
Maya just talked to Ryan.
His flight was canceled.
He's catching
the next plane, but...
Well, she's hysterical.
She's asking for you.
All right,
I-I'm on my way.
If you get anything,
call me right away.
We're down to ten hours
and counting.
STOKES:
McKeen's number one guy.
Kimball is definitely
our kidnapper.
Well, the text and images
on these letters
looks like some
sort of escort rag.
Like magazines you see on the
streets downtown, right?
Advertisements for strip
joints, sex clubs, brothels.
STOKES: Yeah, but they
all look the same.
Well, luckily, not
to the micro-FTIR.
I ran the paper stock.
It's Zurvan Photo Select M-1.
Discontinued in '08.
Pretty specific.
According to the manufacturer,
only one printing company
in Vegas used it.
Place went out of business
a couple months ago.
Who's using the old paper
to print ads for hookers?
Maybe the new tenants.
A sex club called PD7.
Okay, honey, keep going.
I'm scared.
I know.
It's okay.
You can do it.
(loud banging)
What's that?
CRENSHAW:
Hey!
What the hell?
Open this damn door!
Katie, I need you to go now
and I need you to go fast.
Go, sweetie, fast.
I'll find you.
(Crenshaw slamming into door)
Kick it in.
What the hell?
I got the back,
you take the front.
(grunts)
(screams)
(Finlay yells)
(Finlay grunts, screams)
(handcuffs ratcheting)
(whimpers, gasps)
I told you we were going
to have so much fun.
(gunshot)
You okay?
Yeah, we've have to find Katie.
Oh! She's not in there.
(siren approaching)
Where the hell is she?
Katie!
(siren blaring)
FINLAY:
I am sorry.
I just thought that
if I could get her out--
RUSSELL:
I don't need you to think.
I need you to be smart, Finn.
Wh-Why would you let yourself
get separated like that?
She's a child, for God's sake.
And now she's out
there all by herself.
All right, all right, look.
There-There's four hours
left on McKeen's deadline.
Get to the hospital.
Check yourself out.
And then go
back to the lab.
I'm fine.
(phone beeps off)
We will find her.
Please calm down and go
and talk to your daughter.
MORENO: We searched the building
and the surrounding area.
No Katie.
Brass put a BOLO out
on Kimball's car.
And your team's
processing the club.
That's it.
Don't beat yourself up.
You found Katie.
I was supposed
to bring her home.
You did what you could.
Thanks for saving my life.
You knew I would.
I was... (inhales)
so happy to have
a moment to myself.
To let you read to her.
Put her to bed.
(sighs)
And now...
Please don't do this
to yourself.
Please don't.
When I was little,
I always felt so safe.
You always made
me feel so safe.
You said that no harm
could come to us.
To our home.
This isn't our home.
What is this place?
I-I hate it.
Hey, hey, come on.
We can't give
up hope, all right?
(sighs)
I know what happened.
When we were in Seattle.
The murders on campus.
You lied to me back then.
(Russell sighs)
And now...
stop lying.
I was trying to protect us...
Stop lying.
(monitor beeping quietly)
Hey.
You're okay.
Ah, thank God.
You're going to be okay, too.
Yeah?
It was McKeen, wasn't it?
Mm-hm.
He go after anybody else?
He, uh, got
Russell's granddaughter.
They're looking for her now.
You can't worry about that.
You ha...
You have to get your rest
and you have to get strong.
I'm glad you're here.
I love you, M.
I love you too, Dad.
(door unlocks)
So you followed the evidence...
but you didn't
get her back.
Where is she?
It's not going
to be that easy, D.B.
Where?
You didn't really think
I was going to give her
back to you alive, did you?
Ah, that's what I thought.
Just like Stokes.
(Russell screams,
gunshot pops, body thuds)
STOKES:
That's a good kill.
Don't worry,
I got your back.
Russell?
Hey, Russell.
Where are we?
Uh, Sara found more plaster and
bovine hair in Crenshaw's car.
Well, what good is that?
I mean, we're already
speculating that these guys
are spending time at a ranch
or a farm somewhere.
Not just somewhere.
Right there.
ROBBINS: Found a fungus
in Crenshaw's lungs.
Coccidioides Immitis.
Causes Valley Fever.
There's been a cluster of cases
reported in that area.
This is like 40
square miles of desert.
I mean, how the hell
are we supposed to...
We have one hour left
on McKeen's deadline.
One hour.
That is, if-if Finn's botched
attempt to rescue Katie
hasn't gotten
her killed already.
So, if she's alive, cow hair
and Valley Fever are
not going to bring her home.
Bring me something that can,
will you, please?
Go!
(phone ringing)
Hey. How's Maya?
(sighs)
I'm gonna have
to call you back.
Are you deaf?
Or is this
you quitting again?
You got something
you want to say?
After Jack Gilmore's
wife was murdered,
Finlay got a warrant
from Brass for his phone.
It's still active.
And he's still
making phone calls.
Everybody is looking
for Jack Gilmore.
I know where to find him.
(remote chirps)
(tires screech)
Hey, Jack.
Hey, you want to tell me what
the hell this is about?
McKeen told me about
the $2 million in drug money
that you had your wife
steal from Donny Price.
That's why
McKeen had them killed
and you kept your mouth shut,
even when he tried to frame you.
He wants his money back.
I-I-I don't know what
you're talking about.
I don't have much time.
(scoffs)
Come on, man.
Who you kidding?
You're not going
to shoot me.
You're the good cop.
I'm not.
I quit last night.
All right, guys, look...
you're a little late, okay?
What does that mean-- "late"?
That means that I already
gave McKeen the money.
Hey, I swear to God.
My lawyer made the drop.
Ask him.
You didn't think two million
bucks was going to get
your granddaughter back
from a guy like McKeen, did ya?
(scoffs)
She's dead.
(horn honking)
OFFICER (over radio):
David-64, secured rooftop
of adjacent building.
What the hell were you thinking?
You lied to me.
I didn't lie to you.
You told me that Gilmore
was nowhere to be found.
We found him
with your warrant,
so you knew where he was
the whole time, right?
Stokes, shut up.
Yeah, that's right.
Gilmore was a material witness
in an ongoing police
corruption investigation.
Which, by the way, you
completely screwed up
by going going full
cowboy on some scheme
to extort drug
money for ransom.
No, no, listen to me.
We're talking
about my granddaughter.
What, you think
don't understand that?
No, I don't.
You're not behaving that way.
Hey, you know what?
Look, when you processed
your own house,
I didn't say anything.
When you walked into McKeen's
cell by yourself,
I didn't stop you.
You want to know why I didn't
tell you where Gilmore was?
Because I knew it would
end up exactly like this.
Look, don't you get it?
McKeen knew he was going
to get his money.
The only thing
he couldn't get was Gilmore.
He needed you
to find him.
So...
(sighing heavily):
D.B., go home.
Be with your family.
BRASS:
Get some CSIs here.
Hey.
Barbara called you, huh?
Yeah, I can see why.
You're lying in Katie's
bed in case files.
She's really worried about you.
I can't believe
how wrong I've been.
I mean, this whole time,
willing myself to believe
that she's still alive
when the facts say so clearly
that she is.
I'm, I'm not losing it.
Just... listen to this.
Yes, Katie
should be dead,
but so should you.
After proof of life,
they didn't need you,
but they kept you both alive.
Why?
In your case, 'cause Crenshaw
is a scumbag and he wanted
something more
than just your life,
but, but Katie-- Kimball didn't
just see a hostage.
He saw a child.
I mean, look at this,
the guy is divorced, right?
He's got three kids.
Th-The youngest one is like
this 7√-year-old little girl,
same age as Katie.
Okay, so, going with that,
why would Kimball
still be in town?
Out of loyalty, right?
He wanted to do
one last job for McKeen.
Deliver the $2 million
to the family.
Right.
But with the heat on,
how does he do that?
I don't know, I don't--
that's the part
I don't know,
but I don't think
he does either.
You know, maybe he's,
maybe he's laying low
until he can
figure out what to do,
but I do know he's out there
and so's Katie.
We have 40 square miles
of desert and all we have
is cow hair and plaster.
I know, I know.
Oh, my God,
I can't believe it.
What?
I didn't even see that.
Damn it!
D.B.!
Look at that. See that?
It's not, it's not
hair and plaster,
it's hair in plaster.
Before World War II,
they used to use
animal hair in plaster
as, as a binding agent
or something.
There can't be
that many houses out there
from that era still standing
in the desert.
SIDLE:
You're right,
I've got the county assessor
records in front of me now.
Nine properties
fit the description.
Any of them have
a connection to McKeen?
SIDLE:
I'm going through the deeds--
nothing so far.
I found a cartridge case
on the rooftop across
from where Gilmore was shot.
It's a .223.
Matches the bullet
that killed him.
Tell me you got a print.
I did, and a hit--
an ex-cop named Earl Whitson.
He, uh, grew up with McKeen.
SANDERS: Actually, McKeen is
the godfather to his daughter.
I checked cell phone records.
He was in the vicinity
last night,
when Ecklie was shot.
That can't be a coincidence.
SIDLE: It's not-- because
Mm-mm.
I have a Mary Whitson at 21525
Sage Willow Road,
off Highway 26.
RUSSELL:
Call Brass.
We have a deal.
Let's go.
Earl Whitson.
Yeah, retired cop.
Dave Beck... Dennis Melky.
Both worked Vice
with Kimball.
Hmm, probably worked
for McKeen, too.
BRASS:
Kimball is obviously
tying up loose ends.
OFFICER:
It's all clear.
Didn't find the girl.
(tires screeching)
OFFICER (over radio): Suspect
sighted-- rear of the house.
Vehicle on the move.
(siren chirps, tires screech)
(cars crash)
Hold it right there.
Drop the gun now.
Give it up, Paul.
Gave up everything
a long time ago,
when I got in
bed with McKeen.
Come on,
there's still time
to make some of it right.
(chuckles)
I'm a lot of things.
But not a rat.
(Kimball panting)
Where is she?
Should have let me die.
Where's the girl?
She's here.
Oh, God.
(gasps)
The man told me
to hide.
I cut my hand.
♪ ♪
It's time to go home, boys.
Actually, McKeen,
your bus isn't
going back to Ely.
See, I made a humanitarian
phone call to the governor,
reminding him how hard
it is for a cop to,
to survive in
general population.
Where?
Federal facility, Indiana,
and for your
own safety
you will be in isolation
for the rest of your life.
Oh, yeah, and the,
um, that $2 million--
that was donated
to the crime lab
in your family's name.
You have a nice trip.
TV NEWS ANCHOR:
A promising development tonight
in the corruption investigation
of the LVPD.
Detective Paul Kimball
is cooperating
with the D.A.'s Office
and arrests were made today
of more officers
linked to the former
Undersheriff Jeffrey McKeen.
The commission report
is due out--
Sounds like the LVPD
is making a comeback.
How about you, Nick?
What about me?
I don't know;
I haven't talked to Russell yet.
This isn't
about Russell.
Words have consequences,
you know.
I mean, if you
say you quit,
you need to mean it.
You quit.
Well, yeah, but I
didn't say it out loud.
I left a note
at Reception for Grissom
and I walked
right on out of here.
And you're still here, so don't
preach to me about integrity.
Okay?
Wait a minute.
I am not preaching
to you about integrity.
Kind of are a little bit,
don't you think?
I went away for a while
and I got
my head together.
You got a lot of nerve
to talk to me about quitting,
you really do.
All right, all right,
all right, all right.
This is not how family
treats each other.
Actually it is,
but we are also
a team,
and that means
that we have
to trust that we have each
other's back, no matter what.
So are you in
or are you out?
You shouldn't be looking
at those.
Why?
This is our life,
isn't it?
That's not fair.
I can't live like
this anymore.
What do you mean?
Oh, Barbara,
don't do this, please.
FINLAY:
I'm gonna head out.
D.B., D.B.--
Are you okay?
Yeah, yeah.
Sorry.
No, it's all good.
Jules, are you gonna
stay for dinner?
Oh, I'd love to.
Great.
Thank you.
Honey, will you come
help me in the kitchen?
I can help.
No, no, I got it.
Hey, come here,
come here.