PRODUCER:
Ready 11.
DIRECTOR:
25 seconds to air.
PRODUCER: T.O.C., we should
have Ella up on the strip.
Signal looks good.
20 seconds.
Tell Rainy that we're gonna
stick with Theresa
for the first segment,
so no Storm Center
till after the bump.
(crew chattering)
Ten seconds to air.
Put Denny on standby
to warm up her green
screen lights.
Okay.
Five seconds.
Why don't I see Theresa?
Because "my boy Friday"
doesn't understand
the difference
between lipstick and lip liner.
ANNOUNCER:
Tonight, on KVKC News
DIRECTOR: We're live.
with Theresa Shea...
Ready one.
That's not fair.
You specifically said
you wanted...
PRODUCER:
Chad, get Theresa some coffee.
(snaps fingers)
Light cream.
Truvia, specifically.
Chad, now.
Move two to apple six.
ANNOUNCER:
...Las Vegas.
go one.
Welcome to
the KVKC Local News at 11:00.
I'm Theresa Shea.
Our top story is a torrential
rain hitting the city.
Ready two.
Open up Ella, REM 17.
On the scene
in the eye of the storm
is our own fearless
Ella St. James.
Go REM 17.
THERESA:
Ella, how's it look out there?
Uh, Theresa,
I'm having trouble hearing you,
so let me just report
what I know.
The storm has picked up
and is getting worse,
Come on, come on.
(static crackling):
with wind speeds increasing
up to 80 miles per hour.
THERESA:
Ella?
Can't hear you, so if you...
Theresa, pull it back.
Go three.
Thanks, Ella.
We'll try to get
that sound sorted out.
We'd like to remind everyone
that it's best to stay indoors
for the next few hours.
(crew murmuring)
(scoffs)
It's like amateur hour tonight.
Theresa, just bear
with us a second.
Can someone tell me
what the hell is going on?
House lights are out,
overheads as well.
No monitors,
camera servers are down.
We're blacked out.
Denny, tell me you're
on it, brother.
I am. Hopefully the generator
out back will kick in soon.
(crew chattering)
Theresa, you still
okay in there?
Theresa, you still there?
MAN:
I think we're back.
Theresa, you okay?
(crew gasping)
Go to a commercial.
Go to a commercial!
(crew chattering)
RUSSELL:
Looks a lot bigger on TV.
This your newscast
of choice?
I like watching them all.
Like a little mini documentary
on the city every night.
Hey.
Detective Vartann,
what's our top story tonight?
Theresa Shea,
the most trusted name in news.
Alive when the power went out.
20 seconds later,
the lights come back on,
and she falls dead
onto the news desk.
Well, somebody in here
must have seen something.
Sound person, camera guy?
Cameramen don't exist anymore.
Cameras are all robots,
operated from the
control rooms.
Sound and
lighting, too.
Newsrooms have gone
the way of gas stations.
Great, got a locked
room mystery,
with a million viewers.
VARTANN:
Come on over here.
This is Denny Jones; he's
the studio lighting tech.
I didn't know if you wanted
the house lights up or not.
Denny, can you get the lights
back to these exact settings?
Push of a button.
Turn up the sun.
Let's go.
What's the rest of
the team doing tonight?
Finn is finishing
a fire investigation.
Life coach
or something like that.
Walking on coals gone
horribly wrong?
Probably.
Greg and Morgan
are pushing paper,
and Nick's on a B and E.
(lights clank)
Okay, call him and tell him
to lock in chain of custody.
I want all
hands on deck.
Crime lab has the same rule
as the local news:
if it bleeds,
it leads.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
Looks like there's only
the one injury.
Single puncture wound
to the back of the neck.
The shape suggests a knife.
Killer was either lucky
or good.
He hit the perfect spot
to kill her.
When we dissected frogs
in high school biology,
you'd pith it
by sticking a pin
right here.
The frog would get all...
None of the
girls in class
wanted to do it, so
they asked me to.
I became known
as the designated pither.
I would have gone
with relief pither.
That's better.
David, can you, um,
sit her up for me one more time?
I want to get some context.
Yeah.
(grunts)
Spatter
suggests the killer came
from the left.
Plunged the knife in the back
of her neck.
Directional blood drops
tell me
he took off to the right
in a hurry.
If this was a pithing,
this was a drive-by pithing.
I know where I'm watching
the next Seahawks game.
VARTANN:
CSI Russell?
Yeah?
Fred Paulsen,
executive producer.
Hey.
Hey, how are you?
22 years of covering crime,
I never figured it would hit
this close to home.
Can you give us a sense
of what happened?
Um, we were cutting back
from our field reporter,
and the lights went out.
You mean the power.
No, the power here
is compartmentalized.
There's battery backup
for all the electronics.
The lights reroute
through a generator out back.
And it took 20 seconds
for the backup generator
to kick in, right?
During which time,
we were all in the dark.
No light means no eyewitnesses.
Makes a murder case
a little tougher to crack.
Right, but every murder
needs three things, right?
Means, motive, opportunity.
We have a low threshold
on means.
Victim sustained
a sharp-force injury.
Anyone can get their hands
on something sharp.
Okay, let's talk
about motive.
You have any idea who would
want to see Theresa Shea dead?
Sure.
You could start
right there.
What's this?
Our crew list.
Theresa was not
the easiest person to work with.
Well, that leaves
opportunity.
Which would narrow down
this list.
So, lights were out
for 20 seconds, right?
Who would have been close enough
to kill her
in that window of time?
Plausibly, three of my people
would've been in that vicinity.
Okay, well, I've
got three people.
Let's go
with man-to-man coverage.
Paulsen told me they wouldn't
need me until the next segment,
so I stayed here,
monitoring the Doppler.
For the monsoon?
Monsoons only happen
between May and August.
Technically,
this was a training.
A training?
Two storms hitting
at the same time,
upping the volume
of precipitation,
creating a flash flood.
That's very impressive.
Masters in meteorology
and atmospheric sciences,
and I've got the student loans
to prove it.
Rainy, do they
make you wear that?
I mean,
wouldn't you want to dress
a little bit
more conservatively?
Well, if I did, I'd be at home
watching the girl who didn't.
And my real
name's not Rainy.
It's a cutthroat business.
Well, any idea
who may have wanted
to cut Theresa's throat?
Or neck?
Top of my list
would be Ella.
Ella.
Mm-hmm.
Is she the
field reporter?
Well, Paulsen was grooming Ella
to take over the anchor desk.
But the most trusted bitch
in news was not going
to go quietly into that night.
So Ella had the
most to gain
if Theresa was
out of the way.
Where was she
at the time of the murder?
Giving a report
clear across town.
Well, that's
a pretty good alibi.
But in all honesty,
it could be anyone.
Theresa could be brutal.
MAKEUP ARTIST:
So she's really dead?
Did you get her broomstick
as proof?
You don't seem very
broken up about it.
That woman made
everyone's life a living hell,
but my life
was her favorite target.
So, Chad, where were you
when the lights went out?
I was getting her her coffee,
light cream, Truvia.
I was at the vending machine,
right there.
How'd you pay for it?
Credit card.
Why?
Might have a
time-date stamp.
I'll need the
number to verify.
I'd also like
to check out
the sharp objects
that you carry around for work.
Take your pick.
BRODY:
You've got a lot
of sharp tools here,
Denny.
My job involves a fair
amount of cutting.
Wire, cable, carpet, tape.
Each requires a
different blade.
I'm gonna need to take
a swab of your hands.
What does a swab do?
We use it to find blood.
You think I might
have stabbed Theresa.
You're on the list.
I guess that makes sense.
No blood.
So...
if you were to stab somebody,
what would you use?
Nothing here.
Something with a heftier handle
so that you can...
Sorry, I didn't mean to...
What do you do here, Denny?
Lighting, simple I.T. work,
and, um...
Listen, you gonna need
anything else from me?
No, I'm good.
Thank you.
Theresa.
Was she in pain
when it happened, when...
when the knife went in?
I don't know.
(thunder rumbling)
(sniffs)
Hey, uh, I think some of the
power's still out there, bud.
No, only in
the main circuit.
Garage runs on a feed
that's divorced from
the rest of the station.
Say, you sure do seem
to know a lot about
the electrical workings
of the building.
What's your name?
Robbie. It's kind
of my job to.
Uh, who are you?
I'm Nick Stokes
with the crime lab.
Hi. Um, is it true
about Theresa?
Murder?
Yes, ma'am, it is.
We drove back
as soon as we heard
what happened.
News vans from
our competition are
already gathered in front
of the station. Vultures.
And how well
did you two know Ms. Shea?
I'm not sure anyone
really knew her.
She kept the world
at arm's length.
Saw everyone
as a threat.
Would you mind giving us
a quick interview
about this investigation?
If you could do that
"yes, ma'am" thing again,
that would be great.
Robbie, could you get out
the camera...
No. Actually, I would mind.
Sorry.
I know it seems callous,
but it is my job.
Well, it is my job to process
the crime scene... ma'am.
But if we need
anything else,
we'll be sure to be
in touch, okay?
Okay.
Right.
(phone ringing)
(phone beeps)
Cheek implants?
This poor woman was fighting
the war against aging
one cosmetic procedure
at a time.
Scarring and thread
from multiple facelifts.
Forehead presents
immobile musculature
suggesting Botox.
Lip and wrinkle fillers,
you name it.
When your looks are
married to your career,
it's job security,
I suppose.
(chuckles softly)
C.O.D.?
Severed brain stem.
Knife wound hit right between
the occipital bone of
the skull and atlas, C1.
Spinal cord was transected
at the level
of the medulla oblongata,
effectively disconnecting
the transmission of signals
between the brain and the body.
So not just
lucky, good.
Yeah.
Any idea of the
murder weapon?
We did find bruising at
the entrance of the wound.
You know, it kind of looks
like one of those guards
that you see on
folding utility knives.
It's a single-edged blade
and a sharp one at that.
Some sort of
viscous green paste
in the wound track?
Any idea what that is?
Well, it is not biological.
Looks like a job
for David Hodges.
(phone ringing)
Hello, Russell.
Hey. I've been following
the dedicated power line
that goes between
Nevada Flats Power and KVKC,
trying to figure out
why the power went out.
Oh. You finding anything
interesting?
It's more about
what I didn't find.
Transformer about a quarter mile
from the station got blown
to bits.
Well, those transformers
can be volatile,
particularly in wet weather.
Maybe it was some sort
of a malfunction.
Yeah, well, that's what
I thought at first, too,
but then I found remains
of explosive material
in the debris.
Hold on a second, will ya?
Oh, yeah, I just found
parts of a cell phone.
This is definitely
not an accident.
So this murder wasn't
a crime of opportunity.
No, no, no.
This was patient.
This was planned.
What kind of device
are we looking at?
Well, I got some nitroglycerine
and some wax paper.
Figuring the former
was wrapped in the latter.
You got to know an awful lot
about explosives
to mess with dynamite.
So we're looking for someone in
construction, demolition,
ex-military.
Cell phone.
Cheap-looking components.
Could be a burner.
Remote detonator?
Welcome to the hurt locker.
As long as the phone
has enough juice,
the device can sit and wait.
SIDLE: Until it gets
a call to action.
(phone rings)
Well, why don't
I take the phone.
Maybe I'll get lucky
and be able
to pull a print or two.
I'll see if I can salvage
some date/shift code
from the remnants of
the dynamite paper.
♪ ♪
(chuckles softly)
Hey, Hodges, got anything
on the coffee cup
Nick found
in the garage?
I do.
Aside from a bold
French roast,
I found trace of
water, salt and urea.
Someone peed in
Theresa's cup?
Or they're test-marketing
a horrible new
nondairy sweetener.
I think I know
who's behind this.
Theresa's assistant Chad.
I thought he might have
hated her enough to kill her,
but I guess he had
a smaller-scale
revenge plan in mind.
Still. Ew.
What about the green paste
Sara found in
the victim's wound?
Ah. Chromium oxide.
Used to sharpen
knives and razors
on pieces of leather.
The piece of leather
is called a "strop."
And the method of sharpening
is called "stropping."
You'd take a razor with
an imperfect edge,
and begin stropping.
The leather hugs the blade's
edge as the grit from
the chromium oxide tears away
any imperfections and burrs,
leaving our slasher
of Seville with
a sharper-than-
sharp blade.
Something Theresa Shea knew
all too well.
I'm sorry to bother
you with this.
FINLAY:
Oh, it's no bother.
You said that it might be
important to our investigation.
And it might be nothing, but I
wanted to make sure you saw it.
Should be good to go.
Thank you.
This is tape of the newscast
from right before
the murder.
Ella was giving
her remote report
just after
11:00 p.m. Pacific.
And this is our Doppler radar
from the same time.
Two storm fronts crashing
into one another.
A training.
Mm-hmm.
Our satellite shows
two dense storms covering
the sky comprehensively.
No light breaking
through anywhere.
But if you look behind Ella
in the shot...
You can see the moon.
Which wouldn't
be possible
if the clouds were as dense
as your Doppler suggests
at the time
of broadcast.
Exactly.
I think this tape
was made before
the two fronts trained into one.
So you're saying Ella wasn't
broadcasting live?
But she was having
a conversation with Theresa.
No, she didn't,
remember?
Rainy, can you play the tape?
Mm-hmm.
Uh, Theresa, I'm having trouble
hearing you,
so let me just report
what I know.
How long before the murder
do you think this was recorded?
Ballpark?
Maybe a couple of hours.
Is there any way
to confirm this?
I don't know of any.
I know who we
can talk to.
(footsteps approaching)
Hi, Denny.
Uh, hope I'm not
interrupting.
I have a technical
question.
Well, you've come
to the right place.
Okay.
So, is it possible
to prerecord
a report in one of
your remote vans,
and then send it to newsroom
as if it were live?
I suppose so.
You'd have to fool the internal
clocks on the van side.
And what about
on this end?
Is there any
way of telling
if a van is not where
a reporter might say it is?
Yes.
Yes, there is.
Here, ma'am.
(chuckles softly)
This is from
last night.
What am I looking at?
Oh, T.O.C.
Transmission Operations Control.
It's like an air
traffic controller
for all our
microwave signals.
And how many signals
do you have?
Four remote vans
times 11 towers
all over Clark county.
A lot of signal
permutations.
Wow, I had no idea
how complex this all was.
FCC rules are a bitch.
The guy in the van finds
the strongest signal path
and beams the microwaves
to the signal tower
where it is amplified
and rerouted back here
to our broadcast center.
And when the signal comes back,
it lets us know
where it's been.
So when Theresa was killed,
were Ella and her cameraman
where they said
they were?
Actually... no.
If the van was here,
the tower
they transmitted to
is at an
impossible angle.
There's a whole mountain
in the way.
Why would they lie?
It's a good question.
Um, where's Robbie?
I thought you were
talking to him, too.
My friend Nick is talking to him
in the next room.
Just there behind
the mirror.
ANNOUNCER:
Tonight, on KVKC News
with Theresa Shea.
What's this?
That is the opening
of your newscast two weeks ago.
THERESA: Welcome to the KVKC
Local News at 11:00.
I'm Theresa Shea.
And I'm Ella St. James.
Our top story tonight,
Bobby Reed, son of Dennis Reed,
pleads guilty
to drug charges and...
Congratulations. Co-anchor.
Don't congratulate me;
it didn't last.
No, it didn't, did it?
Just last week,
you were back out in the field
and it was the Theresa show
all over again.
What changed?
Honestly, I don't know.
It felt like Paulsen was
grooming me to take over.
I know Theresa felt the same.
I still have the claw marks.
So he demoted you
back into the field?
Mm.
I was actually fired once.
Really drove me crazy.
I think if I was demoted,
I don't know what
I would have done.
STOKES: Don't worry about
what's going on in there.
Worry about what's
going on in here.
This is your T.O.C. report
from the news station.
Okay.
It tells me you weren't
where you said you were
when you were
broadcasting.
Do I need a lawyer?
It doesn't
matter to me.
I'll just ask your boss
if it's possible to prerecord
a live news segment.
I think we both know
what he's gonna say.
Of course I fantasized
about killing Theresa.
But I wouldn't.
It's not who I am.
Not why I got into news.
So, it was an ethical thing?
For starters.
And, uh, falsifying
a news report?
It was a weather
stand up.
Soaking-wet fluff-- they
should've sent Rainy.
But they sent you.
Why?
Not "they"-- Theresa.
She felt threatened,
so she alpha-femaled me.
It was a big "screw you"
to Ella.
Nobody challenged Theresa.
Not even Paulsen.
So, you faked your news report,
fabricated an alibi,
snuck into the station...
No.
I mean, yes.
We were sneaking,
but... for a very
different reason.
ELLA:
Robby and I,
we worked closely together.
We got closer.
Physical.
Don't get me wrong,
I'm married...
And she loves her husband.
I get that.
But when we found the time,
we would try to...
Step away, every
once in a while.
So when the rain
gig came up,
we played hooky.
Went to our usual spot.
To the King's Bridge Motel...
on D Street.
That's fairly close to the tower
you broadcast from.
(chuckles):
Well,
I'd ask you for a
receipt, but, uh...
It's not exactly
a receipt hotel.
So, Ella, if you didn't do it,
maybe you could help us
with who did.
I don't know who.
But maybe I know why.
Theresa was working
on something.
A story, a big
one, I think.
How do you know?
I started noticing that
she would take her journal
and her bag with her,
even to the restroom.
Maybe she was just paranoid.
She was on a story.
Despite our differences, Theresa
and I were birds of a feather.
And back in her day,
she was a hell of
an investigative reporter.
She was kind of my idol.
Well, I did look all through
her work computer,
and I really didn't find
anything out of the ordinary.
If it were me, I'd
keep it all at home.
Nice digs.
Boy, I'll say.
Guess it pays a lot better
to report crime
than it does to solve it.
(laughs)
Well, you could say
that about any job.
Except crime--
I heard it doesn't pay.
(chuckles)
Warrant served.
Okay, so...
Theresa's working on some
big secret story, right?
Where does she keep it?
Not in the living room,
seems untouched.
Theresa Shea lived alone.
Right?
Divorced, three times.
Well, I know
when I take work home,
sometimes it'll
make its way into the bedroom.
Yeah, but you're not single,
you're married.
Yeah, but, um...
my place often looks
a lot like this.
Okay, maybe not exactly
like this.
Russell?
I think I just found
what we're looking for.
Oh, my.
Theresa was certainly
into something.
Like she was obsessed.
Good chance this obsession is
what got her killed.
Theresa Shea earned her stripes
as an investigative reporter.
Looks like she's still got it.
Or had it.
News clippings,
Internet articles.
I got copies
of police reports all marked up
and lots of arson reports.
All these clippings are about
a series of unsolved warehouse
and store fires on the east side
17 years ago.
Why is a superficial
nip-tuck diva
digging into cold cases
about a firebug?
She wasn't digging,
she was excavating.
Yeah, but why was
she so invested?
She didn't need the story
to advance her career.
Right?
Yet, she spent
all her time here.
She ate all her meals
in here, too.
Hmm.
Living alone can drive you
a little crazy.
Yeah, well,
there's crazy and then
there's Colonel Kurtz crazy.
Mm.
Maybe she wasn't
always alone.
One of these wine glasses
is wearing lipstick
and the other isn't.
Wonder who our mystery date is.
I'll get them to Henry.
Reporter's notebook.
Maybe this can
help us make
sense out of all this
organized chaos.
What is that writing,
some kind of
shorthand maybe?
Gregg style, to be specific.
Haven't seen that for years.
Our victim's
very old school.
I suppose some of our answers
might be here.
You must be running
on fumes.
You should go home.
Home is where the
coded notebook is.
(cell phone ringing)
(ringing stops)
Have you talked to him
since the NTSB guy?
Nothing happened
with NTSB.
How come you can't
pick up the phone?
Because I feel
like when I do,
I'm gonna be very
sad when I hang up.
How do you know?
'Cause he wants
to talk.
Want some help?
Oh, that's...
that's really nice.
You should go home,
have some fun.
This is fun.
I'm really good
at crosswords.
Yeah, okay.
Uh, so Gregg style shorthand
is written phonetically.
"Cat" is "k-a-t,"
knee is "n-e."
Soft consonants
like "ch"
and "sh" are
written horizontally.
And hard consonants like
"t" and "d"
are written downward.
Like this.
And vowel sounds are
curves and circles.
Okay, let's crack the code.
All right.
♪ ♪
17 years ago, a series
of warehouse arsons
in the furniture district
baffled investigators.
Cases were unsolved
and put on ice.
But Theresa dug up
lab reports,
which pointed to dynamite
and wax paper,
and that looks an awful lot like
a 17-year-old version
of what blew
that power transformer.
Do we have a clue as to who
would've made either device?
No, but Theresa did.
She referenced
in her journal
someone named "G.H."
He was a demolitions expert,
uh, storied career
in the military.
He's now working as...
A motivational speaker.
Didn't you just
investigate a fire?
Yes, I did--
Garrett Howard.
He was a retired military
munitions expert.
So, where's he now?
He's downstairs.
SIDLE: Anything of note
with Mr. Howard?
Well, most people
die in fires
from smoke inhalation,
not burns.
But take a look
at this lung.
Very clean.
He didn't die from the fire.
Nope.
Did you, by chance,
find anything
on the back of his neck?
Your instincts are
good as always.
Come on around here.
(grunts)
There, we got it.
Knife wound right between
the occipital bone of the skull
and atlas, C1.
Consistent with the murder
of Theresa Shea.
Yeah, right down
to the green paste.
Mm-hmm.
THERESA:
In related news,
there has been
a rash of vandalism
across Las Vegas landmarks.
With the latest hijinks taking
place at the Palermo fountain...
Yesterday's news?
And the day before
and the day before that.
Trying to make sense
out of this whole
dysfunctional family
of a news team.
Theresa sucked up
a lot of oxygen.
I just want to see
if any of her siblings
look a little short of breath.
Any luck?
No.
You?
A little bit.
Theresa was investigating
a cold case.
It was serial arson.
Those famous fires
in the furniture district
were started
by an explosive device
that lead us to a current case.
Which one's that?
Finlay's dead
motivational speaker.
Turns out, he was
a demolitions expert.
And he specialized
in the type of devices
that were all found
at those old arson sites--
dynamite with a remote trigger.
Rings a bell.
And...
best that I can tell,
the device was a precursor
to the explosive device that
you found at the transformer.
Okay, so the guy 17 years ago
builds incendiary devices
to start fires,
then nothing.
Then he blows up
a transformer.
Why'd he start up again now?
The similarities
don't end there.
Guy's wound track has
the same green paste
as we found
in Theresa's pithing.
So we're looking at
a locked-room mystery,
tucked into an enigma,
wrapped in dynamite paper.
You can say that again.
(laughs)
Hey, Sara.
Let me ask
you something.
How you doing?
You all right?
I'm fine.
Well, you just seemed
a little bit down
when we were at Theresa's place.
Um, I don't know, uh,
woman married to her career
without much to show for it.
It's a little depressing.
Yeah, uh...
I don't mean to pry, but...
Pause right there.
I know, I know.
I'm supposed to be your boss.
Separation of church and state.
No, no, no, hit,
uh, pause with the remote,
and-and back it up
a little bit.
Oh.
There, you see it?
Map's not only behind her,
it's on her dress.
I see London, I see France.
There's only one reason
that we'd be able
to see that on her dress.
She's got a green stain on her.
Well, that's embarrassing.
VARTANN: Worse than that.
It's incriminating.
What are you talking about?
We found a green paste
on the body of Theresa
and also on
a second victim.
It's a compound used
for sharpening knives.
It was used
by our killer.
PAULSEN:
Wait a minute,
you don't think...
I mean,
why would Rainy have
a knife-sharpening paste
on her dress?
Why don't we let Rainy
answer that question.
Well, let's see.
Um, clear skies,
red dress, Wednesday.
The Doppler network was
funky, so I spent most of
my time looking over Denny's
shoulder in his cage while
he was trying to
fix the connection.
(phone ringing)
Excuse me.
Greg, what's going on?
Hey, you're not gonna
believe this.
I was just sorting through the
storied career of Garrett Howard
and came across a familiar name:
Denny Jones.
In what context?
He was in the military, too,
briefly.
He got in trouble
for stealing supplies.
In and out of the stockade.
Short fuse.
Was deemed unfit for duty.
Received a less-than-honorable
discharge.
So, Denny and Garrett Howard...
Were brothers in arms.
Where's Morgan?
Denny?
Wait.
Denny!
(reporters clamoring)
We've just seen a man emerge.
We don't know if he
works for the station.
Denny.
Denny, hey.
(clamoring continues)
I didn't do anything wrong!
Okay, okay,
nobody said you did.
Is that the murder weapon?
This is my knife, yes,
but it didn't...
I didn't kill Theresa!
Hey, drop that knife!
Stay away!
Everybody move back, move back,
move back.
Move your camera. Move!
I didn't kill Theresa,
because she loved me.
And I loved her, too!
I loved her!
I... Get away!
Hey, get the cameras
out of here! I'm serious!
I believe you.
Let us talk about this.
No! I will not
go back to jail!
I cannot go back to jail!
All we want to do is
take you in.
Just gonna go have
a conversation.
Stop!
You drop that knife right now!
No, this is just, this is all
just too much.
Denny, listen to me, calm down.
You don't want to do this.
Now come on. Denny...
(voices overlapping, fading)
(echoing):
Denny. Denny.
No!
(crowd gasping)
Wait!
Why'd you do that?!
Denny, okay...
Can you see this?
(reporters clamoring)
Move back, will ya, please?
Look at me.
I'm here.
I got you.
Move!
(siren wailing)
(talking quietly)
Denny. Denny.
(clamoring continues)
Unlike lightning, tragedy
tragedy strikes twice at KVKC.
I'm at the site of yet a second
violent death in as many days,
as the news station is rocked
to its foundation
by the suicide of a man
suspected in the murder
of Theresa Shea.
Embroiled in a mystery
that keeps on unraveling,
authorities have kept quiet
thus far,
but the man who killed himself
has been identified
as Denny Jones.
So what motivated these events?
Psychotic break?
Crime of passion?
Until the facts come in,
one can only speculate.
(mutters):
Stupid.
Okay, okay, okay.
Boss?
Yeah?
I have an update
on the wine glass
we found at Theresa Shea's.
Thought you didn't
find a match.
No, we didn't until
the knife came in.
But sweat around the handle
matched the DNA on the glass.
Denny was sharing wine
with Theresa.
And sharing a bed.
I found evidence
of sexual activity
in her sheets.
Strange bedfellows.
Everybody needs somebody.
But if he was in love,
why kill her?
I don't know.
Love makes you do
all sorts of stupid things.
You don't think he did it,
do you?
Sorry.
Okay, this is gonna be fun.
Now, when we came into this,
we had three suspects
and no evidence, right?
Now we got some
evidence,
I want to play a little game.
Capture the flag.
Bear with me.
Okay, this particular flag
is gonna represent
Theresa Shea's life.
We're gonna stick it right here.
Sara, you're gonna be
playing Theresa.
Three of you are each gonna be
playing one of our suspects.
Now you'll start from wherever
our evidence placed them.
We'll turn off the lights.
Whoever can get in,
take Theresa's life and get out
in 20 seconds is our killer.
20 seconds to airtime.
Are you good?
I'm gonna be playing
Mr. Paulsen.
Sara, you're my
anchor, right?
Alive and well.
Okay, Greg,
where are you at?
All right,
I am at the coffee machine,
about to go to the garage
and make a deposit.
I'm at my Doppler station.
I'm monitoring the storm
as instructed.
Computer puts Rainy here
until the lights go out.
RUSSELL:
Thank you, Rainy.
Denny?
I'm in my cage.
Internet activity locks me here
until we lose power.
As soon as the
lights go out,
I want everyone
to try to kill Sara.
Ready, set,
go.
(lights clank)
VARTANN:
19, 18, 17,
16, 15, 14,
13, 12, 11,
ten, nine,
eight, seven,
six, five,
four, three,
two, one. Lights up.
(lights clank)
Well, Chad was too far away.
And Denny was, too.
Rainy couldn't get to Theresa.
None of us made it in time.
Yeah, but...
the flag is gone.
Well, who took it then?
(knocking)
You were all
too far away,
because you were sent
too far away by me.
Detective, did you see me
leave this room?
No, I did not.
And as far as everyone
in here knew,
Paulsen never left either.
Theresa, pull it back.
Go three.
THERESA:
Thanks, Ella.
(phone beeps, dials)
We'll try to get
that sound sorted out.
RUSSELL: Blew up the power,
stepped outside,
took care of Theresa,
got back in the room
before the generator kicked on.
Theresa, are you okay?
SIDLE:
Do these... articles
look familiar to you?
Yeah, let me give you
a hint-- the A.P.
credits the photographs
to a younger you.
Yeah.
I took pictures of
the furniture district fires.
You know, they never
caught that guy.
Never say never.
What's that
supposed to mean?
RUSSELL: You know what?
Let's talk about
your old pal, Garrett Howard.
The one who liked to play
with dynamite.
I don't know a Garrett Howard.
Really?
And yet, you did
a whole profile on him
on one of your news shows.
What was it called?
Uh...
"Army demolition expert
turns motivational speaker."
That's a hell of a favor to do
for somebody you don't know.
SIDLE:
And not the only favor.
You also hired his hapless
army buddy, Denny Jones.
So he gave you the job
as a favor to a friend?
How does that work?
Um, Garrett said Paulsen
owes him his life.
Any idea why?
Denny and Theresa together. Wow.
I didn't see that coming.
Did you see
that coming?
No.
No, that must have come
as a surprise to you, too.
And now...
Theresa knew
that you had a secret.
She figured if she could
uncover it, then she could
keep her job. You wanted
to have her replaced
with a younger anchorwoman.
So she became
a one-woman news team.
And she connected you
to these fires 17 years ago.
First one on the scene
because you lit the match.
That must've given Theresa
a lot of leverage.
Leverage?
She was a
washed-up talent.
Her best years were behind her.
Why'd you keep her
on the anchor desk then?
See, to me,
that sounds like a...
deal with the devil.
SIDLE: Yeah, one
you couldn't live with.
So you made a plan
to kill Theresa.
RUSSELL:
Asked Garrett Howard
for another explosive device--
just one more job.
But then, like Theresa,
he knew your secret.
So you had
to dispose of him, too.
SIDLE:
And that left poor Denny.
So you borrowed his knife,
and you set him up.
(chuckles):
I'm a reporter.
I'm not a murderer.
I wouldn't even know
how to wield a knife.
Hate to fact-check you
on that, pal, but...
You know, actually,
I'm loving this.
We found
an old news story
that you ran years ago
about a killer who stabbed his
victim right in the sweet spot,
right under the skull.
SIDLE:
When you take notes,
you really take notes.
You know, in my business,
before making
outrageous accusations,
on or off the air,
you need a little thing
called evidence.
In our business, too.
This is a partial print
from the transformer explosions.
It's also
your left index finger.
Oops.
RAINY:
Welcome to the KVKC
local news at 11:00.
I'm Jennifer Thomas.
Breaking news tonight--
which sadly hits close to home--
long-time news producer
Fred Paulsen has been charged
with first-degree murder
in the death of Theresa Shea.
(cell phone ringing)
(turns off TV)
Hello.
GRISSOM: You've been hard
to get a hold of.
Yeah. Um, I'm so sorry.
How are you?
I'm okay.
Is now a good time?