(sultry, urgent
Afro-Cuban music playing)
(singing in Spanish)
(screaming)
(horns blasting, woman screams)
(music blaring,
woman screaming)
(woman wails)
(song ends)
(light applause)
Bravo, Silvana, save some
of that for opening night.
Silvana's on fire.
We're gonna make
some money, bro.
Good for you...
and for your club.
Well, good for
all of us, right?
This is not about the money
for me, bro.
It's about the soul
of Cuba.
The music.
(Silvana speaking Spanish)
Venga.
Cuidado, Vegas,
Silvana has arrived.
Vegas is just
the beginning.
Sure, sure, sure.
Necesitamos hablar press.
We do the local news,
and after the first show,
CNN, Fox, MSNBC.
The sky's the limit.
Come on.
(conversing in Spanish)
Marta!
(sobbing):
Marta...!
No!
Oh, Marta...!
(camera clicking)
(indistinct radio communication,
sirens wailing in distance)
Thank you.
Hey, fellas,
what do we got?
Marta Cuerto,
32, Cuban national.
Sister to
Silvana Cuerto,
Cuban pop star.
Who found the body?
Silvana and her manager.
So, no signs of
a disturbance.
No blood, no cleanup,
which means
this isn't the primary.
The body was staged,
just like that,
and one of Silvana's costumes
was taken
off the rack
and put
on the victim's body.
That explains the lack
of blood on the dress.
What do we got
going here, bud?
Blunt force trauma-- the face
and most of her upper torso.
Semicircular impressions
all over the body.
(thermometer beeps)
Liver temp is 90.4.
She died about six hours ago.
I'll get the gurney.
So our killer brings her here,
stages the body...
nobody even notices?
She was rehearsing
for a couple of hours onstage.
The music's loud,
people are distracted.
How many ways in and out
of here?
Only two.
Door from the stage,
and there's a back door
down that hallway
leading to the alley.
Well, that's the how;
I'd like to know the why.
Silvana's sister...
...in her dress,
sitting at her vanity...
...staring into her mirror.
You got something?
Yeah.
"Silvana, eres
la proxima"?
"Silvana, you're next."
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
(protesters chanting
in Spanish)
SANDERS:
Silvana Cuerto is
the hottest ticket in Vegas.
Next to...
rum and cigars, Silvana is
Cuba's biggest export.
So, how come
I've never heard of her, then?
I don't know, I mean,
she's been touring Europe,
now she's finally
coming to the States.
Didn't know you were
such a big Cuban music fan.
You know, Sex Pistols,
Sinatra, Silvana--
I'm equal opportunity
like that.
If she's so popular,
why are all these
people here protesting?
I'm very sorry
for your loss, Ms. Cuerto.
It's like...
part of me is dead.
I do have to ask you
some questions.
I'm sorry.
I understand.
I know that you
and your manager
found your sister
Marta.
Right?
Was there anyone else
backstage, anyone
who didn't belong?
No, just us.
When was the last time
you saw Marta?
Yesterday.
We had lunch, then
she went shopping.
Shopping?
Marta does wardrobe
for the show.
She made all of my costumes.
My whole life,
she's taken care of me.
And coming here,
I was so scared.
But Marta gave
me the strength.
She was so happy for me,
like it was her
up in that stage...
and I felt her with me.
Did your sister mention
receiving threats?
Everyone loved Marta.
Okay, how about you?
Have you received
any threats?
MANAGER: Silvana received
threats every day,
ever since we arrive
in this country.
Threats from whom,
Mr. Ficha?
Los Gusanos--
the so-called Cuban exiles
who want Silvana
to go home or die.
You're talking about
the people outside.
That's right.
It's a long way from carrying
a sign to killing someone.
I don't expect you
to understand.
Politics in your country
is entertainment.
In Cuba, it's passion;
it's blood.
These threats
against Silvana--
were they anonymous?
The threats, yes...
the source... no.
What do you mean by that?
The leader of the exile
community-- Eddie Santos--
he's been following us
ever since we landed--
outside the hotel, outside
the restaurant where we eat,
outside this club.
Why didn't you report him?
I did-- to your
State Department.
Obviously,
your government is deaf
to the concerns
of the loyal Cuban citizens.
Some more loyal than others.
Hmm.
Couldn't help but
notice on your passport
there's an entry--
"Gobierno Cubano."
My Spanish is a
little rusty, but I'm
pretty sure that means
"Cuban government."
You're not just Silvana's
manager, are you?
I was assigned to accompany
Silvana on her tour--
Marta, too.
You're a handler.
Yeah, that makes sense.
I mean, a talent
like Silvana--
you're the guy
assigned to make sure
that she, uh...
finds her way back home.
Perhaps if I had been
more vigilant...
Marta would still be alive.
Got black streaks
on the floor here.
Looks like some kind
of oil residue.
I've got a fiber here.
Could help us find our primary.
More fibers
at the base of the chair.
There's a trail heading
right out of the room.
And down the hallway
to the door
to the alley.
You thinking what I'm thinking?
When fibers get snagged
on the floor like that, it means
material was dragged.
SANDERS: Weighed down like
a body in some kind of sack.
Body dump.
But where did the
killer stash the sack?
What are the odds?
(sighs)
SIDLE: So much for security
at your club, Mr. Mejia.
In fact,
the only functioning camera
in this entire club
that's working is aimed
at the cash register
behind the bar.
Kind of sums up your
priorities, don't you think?
You're out of line.
I don't think so.
Given what I saw
outside,
you have no excuse for not
providing adequate security.
I tried.
I installed these
cameras this month.
I've had to fix 'em four
times already. Ever since
I announced that Silvana
was performing at the club,
I've had acts of
vandalism every night.
You're pointing
a finger at the exiles?
All I'm saying is,
I don't get how people
who are otherwise
calm and law-abiding
can go crazy over
ancient history,
wounds that are
over 50 years old.
Aren't you Cuban?
Cuban-American.
My parents and I came here
20 years ago, when I was 11.
This is my country, not Cuba.
My generation-- here.
Marta's and Silvana's--
over there.
We just want to be free
to live our lives,
follow our dreams.
Yeah, well, somebody ended
that for Marta Cuerto,
and Silvana
may be next,
so, if this show must go on,
then you have
to fix these cameras.
(mellow, upbeat
Cuban music playing)
Beautiful music, Doc.
(player beeps off)
Oh, brings back memories.
Have you been to Cuba?
15 years ago.
I was invited to a symposium
on forensic pathology
in Havana.
Hmm, you must have
some good stories.
Actually, that's why
I called you here.
But this story is
far from good.
This pattern of injuries
is quite specific
and not new to me.
What do you mean?
Injuries on the wrists
indicate the victim
was forcibly restrained.
Ligature marks.
Width suggests rope.
Same ligature marks
on her ankles.
Slight bruising
on her shoulders
from a hyperextension
of the muscles.
And this bruising on her abdomen
says the victim was subjected
to an extended period
of intense pressure.
Which all adds up to what?
She was hog-tied.
(moaning, screaming)
So you're saying
systematic torture?
I met a journalist
in Cuba who claimed
to have been arrested
by the authorities.
He described
an account of torture
referred to as "la silla."
Which means
"the chair."
According to him,
it was a technique commonly
employed by the Cuban police.
After a few hours,
they lifted him off the floor,
tied him to a chair,
and beat him into submission
with a pipe.
The pipe would
be consistent
with the semicircular gashes
all over her body.
Do you have anything else?
Well, no obvious signs
of sexual assault.
I sent the SAE kit to DNA.
But I did find this...
partially embedded
in the skin of her left heel.
FINLAY:
Hmm.
Looks like some kind of metal.
Whoa. Lurk much?
You know, if you weren't my
boss and dating my mother,
I'd say I hate that.
Well, I'm not too happy
myself, Depardieu.
Or I guess you're really
Andie MacDowell, aren't you?
What are you
talking about?
Green Card, the movie.
Saw it with
Morgan's mother.
At least the first
15 minutes, before I got
paged to an even worse crime.
Right. This is about the
immigration investigation?
Yes, it is.
What the hell
were you thinking?
What do you mean?
You meet a woman
in Italy
and a week later,
you're engaged?
You don't even speak
the same damn language.
Which has its
advantages.
All right,
you think this is funny?
This is Morgan's deposition...
supporting your story.
I know; I didn't
ask her to do that.
I'm your supervisor, David;
we're family here.
You should've told me.
And you sure
as hell should've
told your mother--
she's beside herself.
Default position.
That's not funny.
My daughter went
to bat for you here.
You better not
be making her a liar.
(sighs)
♪ ♪
You have good news for me;
I can always tell.
Well, at least someone
still has faith in me.
Oh, Lord.
Family?
Yes. Um, never mind.
Good news item
number one: the residue
Morgan and Greg found
in Silvana's
dressing room...
Was motor oil.
Mm-hmm.
Which was also found
on the burlap sack used
to transport the body,
along with flecks of dried
blood matching our victim.
What else you got?
Item number two:
the chip found embedded
in our victim's heel
is not just one metal,
but four.
A metallic layer cake,
if you will.
"Trivalent chromium,
nickel, copper,
flat carbon steel."
Steel for the body,
copper for the surface,
nickel for the shine,
and tri-chromium
for the polish.
Auto body shop.
Actually, it's
a chrome-plating facility.
There's only three
in Vegas, one of which
is only two blocks
from the club.
Check out the name
of the owner.
Eddie Santos--
face of the Cuban exiles.
Good work.
I'll call Brass.
(tires screech)
Doesn't look like
they're open for business.
Well, it looks like
somebody's home.
Hey, Jim...
(whispers):
Yeah?
STOKES:
Metal chips look just like
the trace Doc pulled
out of the victim.
Yeah.
(whispers):
Nick.
Yeah?
BRASS:
I got blood.
Looks like we
found our primary.
(vehicle approaching)
(tires screech)
(turns off engine)
BRASS:
Eddie Santos, LVPD.
You going somewhere, Eddie?
STOKES:
We found all that stuff
in your shop, Eddie,
but it was matched
to Marta Cuerto.
BRASS: So let me guess, uh,
you were headed
back there to clean up
when we arrested you, right?
I had nothing
to do with that
or killing anyone--
I was going to my office
to get paperwork.
Paperwork?
Mm.
Your last customer
picked up his car
at 11:30 yesterday morning,
right before you
closed up the shop
at noon, right?
And we know that
Marta Cuerto
was killed between
1:00 p.m. and 6:00 p.m.
and then delivered to her
sister's dressing room,
which is a block
away from your shop.
Guilty until
proven innocent!
I feel I'm back in Cuba!
Is that were you
got those scars?
In Cuba?
30 years ago,
I was in a room like this,
with police like you.
They beat me
and threw me in la gaveta.
La gaveta.
They threw you in a drawer?
Ten guys in a six-by-eight
prison cell filled with rats,
roaches, feces,
(speaking Spanish)
Eddie, save the history lesson.
This isn't Havana, Cuba.
This is Las Vegas,
Nevada, USA,
and here we go on evidence,
and we found a lot of it
in your shop.
I have no reason
to kill anyone.
STOKES: We checked you out,
Eddie-- the way you
were following around
Silvana, Marta, her manager--
everywhere they went,
there you were.
(speaks Spanish)
It's a free country.
BRASS: Right,
where Silvana Cuerto
can cash in.
"Bringing the Benjamins
back to her
repressive government."
Those are your words.
(speaking Spanish)
Last I checked,
I have the right
to speak my mind.
Yeah, but you don't have
the right to commit murder...
to exact revenge on traitors
who aren't loyal to your cause.
And you damn sure
don't have the right
to torture people
the way that you were tortured.
I didn't kill anyone!
Oh, right-- you're one of those
romantic revolutionaries.
We ran a rape kid on Marta.
We found semen.
We found contributions
on a sofa in your shop!
If you want us to compel
your DNA and match it to the DNA
we found,
we're happy to do that.
You want evidence?
You don't need to
compel anything.
Go ahead, take my DNA.
♪ ♪
(whirring)
RUSSELL:
You sure DNA's not a match?
I ran it twice,
then called Greg.
Which is when
I noticed
that the result
wasn't a total bust.
Eddie Santos's
DNA profile
showed a second-order
relative match
to the profile of our suspect.
Second-order,
as in a half sibling?
Or a grandson, maybe a nephew.
ANDREWS:
Either way, our suspect
is definitely a member
of Eddie Santos's family.
Well, sounds like
you need to shake
the Santos family tree,
right?
Or, you know, we could call
our friend Donna Hoppe.
Well, at this point,
I may not be a genealogy Jedi,
but Padewan,
at least, I am.
I got this one.
Hey, Doc. You said
you had some news?
An unexpected detour on
the road to determining
cause of death.
Take a look at these
internal organs.
FINLAY:
Wow. The heart and brain
look really swollen.
30% more than normal.
Lungs are lined
with this cherry red mucosa.
So Marta was poisoned.
What about the beating?
While poisoning appears
to be the ultimate C.O.D.,
vital response in the wounds
suggests they were
simultaneous events.
So the killer poisoned her
and beat her.
You were talking
about Cuban police torture.
Did you ever come across
anything like this?
Never.
FINLAY:
And the cherry red color
is indicative
of cyanide, isn't it?
Well, the short
answer's yes.
I can't tell you how
it would have gotten
into her system.
Didn't find any injection marks,
no inhaled residue
in her nasal passages.
What about her stomach contents?
Already sent that off to Hodges.
Silvana's manager, Antonio,
provided everybody in the band
with prepaid cell phones;
I pulled up every call
that Marta made the
day that she died.
Made calls to her
sister, Antonio,
couple of calls
to the Rumbason Club,
also some fabric stores
and fashion outlets.
RUSSELL:
Well, that makes sense.
Silvana said that
Marta went shopping
for wardrobe for the show.
Rehearsal wasn't until 8:00.
SIDLE:
Here are the last calls
she ever made--
three in a row
right around 2:30 p.m.
Couple hours before she died.
No caller I.D.'s.
702 number's
another prepaid cell.
RUSSELL:
202.
Well, that's Washington, DC.
Yeah.
Let's do a reverse
directory search on that.
Read my mind.
(blipping)
SIDLE:
Access denied.
Put that together
with Cuba and Washington, DC.
The plot thickens.
You know,
I don't want to go
to that CIA place, but...
I'm kind of going
to that CIA place.
(Sam whining)
Want a bite?
Here you go, bud.
Easy, easy.
Dog walker on vacation?
Yeah, stomach flu.
Huh.
Speaking of,
is that
the report on Marta Cuerto's
stomach contents?
This? Uh, no.
This is personal.
Okay. No problem.
If you must know,
uh, it's Morgan's
character reference
to Immigration in support of
my engagement to Elisabetta.
Wow. Well, you know,
I would've been happy
to write you a character
reference-- I mean,
I would've left out
the part about
your criminal record but...
Well, clearly, I should've
talked to you first.
Congratulations, buddy.
I look forward to
meeting her sometime.
An oversight I plan to correct.
Hear that, Sam?
He's getting married.
(barks)
(laughs)
So, stomach contents.
Yeah, in my office.
All right.
Sammy, I got some work
to do now, boy.
Stay here,
I'll be right back.
Based on my analysis of Marta
Cuerto's stomach contents,
I know how the cyanide got
into her system.
GCMS picked up linamarin,
lotaustralin...
cyanogenic glucosides.
Well, how the hell
did they get in there?
Page two.
Lovely illustration.
Behold the cassava leaf,
which has been known to produce
medicinal properties,
only if processed carefully.
And if not?
Uh, nasty business.
Especially in the hands
of our killer,
who, it seems,
force-fed them to Marta,
knowing that the glucosides
from the unprocessed leaves
would react
with stomach enzymes
to produce hydrogen cyanide.
Which is then absorbed
through the stomach lining
into the bloodstream.
Once in the blood,
cyanide binds to hemoglobin
more strongly than oxygen,
preventing the oxygen
from getting to the cells.
The result-- asphyxiation.
Suffocation.
And death.
Heard our suspect's DNA shows
he's related to Eddie Santos.
Russell said you were doing
a little genealogy?
Yeah.
And this family tree has
some seriously poisoned roots
back in Cuba.
I accessed
the Clark County Museum
of Hispanic Heritage database.
I found this.
BRODY:
Cuban Army photo.
Guy on the left--
Colonel Carlos Cuerto.
Cuerto? Related to
the Cuerto sisters?
Grandfather, and the guy
next to him--
25-year-old Sergeant
Eduardo Santos.
Young Eddie Santos.
A year after this,
Eddie and two comrades
made a crack about
Colonel Cuerto's ties
to the black market.
They were arrested
and thrown in jail.
Where they were tortured.
For six years
at the hands of
Colonel Cuerto himself.
This may have nothing to
do with politics at all.
It's a feud between the
Cuerto and Santos family.
Yeah, simmering for 40 years.
And I think I know which
family member exacted revenge.
Hilda Santos, sister
of Eddie Santos,
emigrated from
Cuba in '92,
married Oscar Mejia.
They had one son together.
Estefan Mejia, owner
of the Rumbason.
Also...
Eddie Santos' nephew.
(Silvana singing in Spanish)
What do you guys want?
We just want to talk
to you about your uncle,
Eddie Santos.
MORGAN:
And the vendetta your family
has against the Cuertos family.
Vendetta? I have no
part in any vendetta.
SANDERS:
Really?
Then why don't you explain to us
how we found your DNA
on Marta Cuerto's body
in your uncle's auto shop?
The DNA you left behind
when you raped and killed her.
(Silvana gasping,
mic feedback whining)
(muttering)
Mitch, call an ambulance!
(distant, echoing
singing in Spanish)
(indistinct chatter)
I'm going with her.
Sir, I'm sorry.
I can't let you
in there right now.
Get your hands off me. I demand
to be inside with Silvana.
Mitch, I've got this.
Mr. Ficha, I'm so sorry.
Let me talk to you
just for a second.
Silvana's exhibiting the same
signs of poisoning as Marta--
cyanide-- now,
I've told the doctors,
so they know what to do.
You saw the message scrawled
in Silvana's dressing room.
Those animals
said she was next.
Where were you?
We do have a suspect
in custody, sir.
A little late, don't you think?
Why won't you tell me
what's happening with Silvana?
Why? You trying
to figure out
if you're on the hook
for one murder or two?
What?!
Your club is getting
a bad rep, Estefan.
First Marta.
Now your star attraction,
Silvana, collapses on stage.
STOKES:
Yeah, at first we
thought you just
had lousy security, given
the angry crowd outside,
but now we know
that the real threat
was coming from inside.
Coming from you.
I told you,
I don't share the same beliefs
as the exile community.
Maybe not them,
but what about your uncle?
That's a different story.
Blood is thicker
than politics, right?
I don't know
what you're talking about.
STOKES:
You know exactly what
we're talking about.
Let me show
you something.
I think you referred to this
as "ancient history."
Let me show you a
little recent history.
I think you recognize
that, don't you?
Look familiar?
CRAWFORD:
How'd it go down?
Did your uncle watch
while you raped her?
And then, you two guys,
what, you tied her up,
then you beat her.
STOKES:
And then forced
cassava leaves
down her throat and
watched her suffocate.
No.
DNA doesn't lie, man!
We know it was you!
I didn't. I couldn't hurt her.
So? It was your uncle then.
No! I mean, I don't know.
You don't know?
No, I wasn't there...
when this happened.
Look, my uncle tried to turn me
against the Cuertos,
but Silvana, Marta
and I were friends.
I lived with them
when I was a kid.
Even when I came to this
country, we stayed in touch.
When Silvana's
career took off,
I saw it as a chance
to bring them here.
STOKES:
No, you saw it
as an opportunity to
lure the Cuerto sisters
and settle an old score.
My uncle's fight
is not my fight!
I couldn't hurt her!
I couldn't hurt Marta!
Her and I were in love.
Is that why you took her
to your uncle's body shop?
That's not my
idea of romance.
It was the only place
near the Rumbason
where we could meet...
in secret.
Marta called me,
and I went to her.
(moaning)
We made love.
I got to go.
I'll see you tonight.
Marta was still alive
when I left.
I swear.
What about your uncle?
Where was he at?
I can't tell you.
You can't... or you won't?
HODGES:
Si, si, si.
Sono contento.
No, Elisabetta,
I'm-I'm very happy.
It-It's just
that it's-it's hard.
Um... difficile,
uh, for me to express it...
in Italian.
It's, uh... it's the
language barrier and...
Elisabetta. Hello?
Hello?
(sighs)
(phone beeps off)
Sorry to interrupt.
Hi.
(laughs)
I brought you Silvana Cuerto's
stomach contents for analysis.
Aw, you shouldn't have.
(laughs)
So, everything okay
with Elisabetta?
Yeah, uh, great.
Yeah, in-in fact, uh,
she just heard from Immigration.
Uh, they processed
our application,
and, uh, because
of your help,
uh, we've been approved.
Wow. (laughs)
Yeah.
So, what...
what does that mean?
Well, uh, it means that
we have 90 days to get married,
or she gets put back
on a plane home.
Well, it's a good thing
you live in Vegas.
You can just get hitched
at a drive-thru.
(laughs)
Well, don't take your foot
off the gas.
(laughs)
Thanks.
Look who's back.
CSI... Russell, right?
Yeah, that's right.
How are you feeling?
I don't know.
What happened?
Well, we're gonna
find that out.
Seems somebody tried
to poison you.
Like they did to Marta?
Antonio told me.
Well, the person who poisoned
your sister forced her
to ingest cassava leaves.
Now, clearly, that was
not the case with you, but
do you remember if anyone
offered you any food,
or something to drink
before your rehearsal?
No.
But I-I can't remember much.
Okay.
What I do remember,
I wish I could forget.
I was so happy
to come here.
To be a star...
in this country.
Now, Marta...
Marta's dead.
(voice breaking):
I should never have...
Please...
find who did this.
Please tell me
that you have something.
You know we had
to let Eddie Santos go.
Well, we just sprung
his nephew Estefan, as well.
So I am hoping
that we can tie at
least one of them
to Silvana's poisoning.
Well, I can tell you this much.
Silvana Cuerto was poisoned
with cyanide
by way
of unprocessed cassava leaves.
So at least
our killer is consistent.
Not entirely,
because in Silvana's case,
he changed the method
of delivery.
In addition
to the cassava leaves,
I found gelatin
and plant polysaccharides.
Which is from soluble capsules?
Yes.
So, Silvana ingested pills
filled with poison.
Yes, again,
but I don't think she knew
that they were
filled with poison.
I suspect that she thought
they were filled with
justicia pectoralis,
which I also found in the mix.
It's an herbal remedy,
primarily used for relaxation.
Cubans call it tilo.
Tilo.
You know it?
Yeah, I just saw it
on the evidence list.
Greg found a bottle of it
in Silvana's dressing room.
Maybe somebody who had access--
perhaps Estefan--
spiked Silvana's calm pills,
tried to kill her buzz.
I'll get Greg to run the tilo.
Thank you.
Pleasure.
♪ ♪
(trilling, beeping)
RUSSELL:
So, Hodges confirmed
that the tilo capsules
we found in Silvana's
dressing room
contained ground-up
cassava leaves.
Source of the cyanide.
Right. Lucky for Silvana,
that when you put the
poison in a capsule,
it reduces
the-the potency.
All right.
And we know the print
Greg assembled
came back to Antonio Ficha.
So much for him
being her handler.
Looks like he's our killer,
but I-I don't... I don't get it.
Well, I may have
something for you.
Just got off the phone
with the State Department--
Cuerto sisters
were seeking asylum.
That explains
the phone call to... to DC.
Sisters defecting,
bad news for Antonio.
All right.
So what are we thinking?
That he killed Marta and then...
left the warning for Silvana,
"You're next"?
Obviously,
she didn't get the message.
Right.
I'm on my way.
You got something?
Yeah, Antonio Ficha
checked Silvana out of the
hospital about a half hour ago.
Where were they going?
Patrol spotted them
returning to their hotel.
(phone ringing)
I'm meeting Brass
over at the Palermo.
Crawford.
Okay, I'm on my way.
CRAWFORD:
Guy at the front desk says
Antonio and Silvana
arrived about 20 minutes ago.
Went straight up to the room.
Were they alone?
They were.
What do you mean
"they were"?
A few minutes after that,
another guy showed up.
His description
matches Estefan Mejia.
What the hell is he doing here?
(shouting,
clattering)
Uh-oh...
MAN: No!
(gunshot)
BRASS:
LVPD!
Drop the gun!
Drop the gun, Antonio!
CRAWFORD:
Drop the gun!
Show me your hands!
Against the wall!
Come on!
It's Estefan. He's dead.
Silvana?
(woman crying)
It's okay.
Everything's okay.
Antonio's crazy.
He was going to kill me.
It's all right. It's all right.
You're safe now. You're safe.
It's all over.
All right, what do
you got for me, David?
Broken nose, bruises.
Took a few shots
to the face before
a single GSW to the forehead.
And there's no exit wound.
It's a large caliber,
consistent with a .45.
Check this out.
(groans)
It's a compound
fracture of the
right index finger.
That's the trigger finger.
Antonio must've wrenched
the gun out of his hand.
Hey, Morgan...
...take a look at this.
Seen that before.
In Silvana's dressing room.
Yeah. Killer used
the burlap sack
to transport Marta's body with.
But what's it doing here?
(ventilation whirrs, whooshes)
Hey, guys, look what I found.
BRODY:
Antonio's bag.
Yeah.
With blood on it.
It's like a regular murder kit.
What do we have here?
I'm guessing
those are cassava leaves.
It happened so fast.
Estefan pushed his way
into the room.
Then he and Antonio
started to argue.
What were they arguing about?
He said Antonio
had murdered Marta,
tried to poison me
and that he wouldn't let
Antonio hurt me again.
What made Estefan think
that Antonio was the one
behind it all?
He said his uncle told him.
When Estefan
pulled out a gun,
I ran into the bathroom to hide.
Then I heard a shot.
And I was sure
he'd killed Antonio.
Then the police arrived,
and I saw Estefan
lying on the floor.
He was just trying
to protect me.
You're gonna be all right.
I think we should get you to
the hospital, just to make sure.
No, I don't want to go
to the hospital.
I just want to go home.
Silvana's returning to Cuba.
And so am I.
You have no right
to hold me here.
I've done nothing wrong.
Antonio, we walked in on you
standing over Estefan Mejia
with a gun in your hand.
Yeah, man, I think the
gun was still smoking.
That was in self-defense.
Mm.
Silvana and I were packing
our bags when...
Estefan showed up.
I tried to reason with him,
but his head was filled with...
lies.
You son of a bitch!
I know what you've done!
Oye, tranquilo!
Tranquilo! Cálmate!
You killed Marta!
You poisoned Silvana!
What are you talking about?!
That was your crazy uncle.
Not me! I am the one
protecting Silvana,
and I'm taking her home.
No, you're not going anywhere!
No, no, no! Ooh!
(speaks Spanish)
(grunting)
(shouts, grunts)
Now you get the
hell out of here.
No!
Estefan gave me no choice.
STOKES: Let's say I buy
self-defense.
We still found your fingerprints
on Silvana's tilo capsules.
They were filled with cyanide.
So you think I poisoned Silvana?
Why would I do
such a thing?
She's Cuba's gift to the world.
Gift to the U.S.,
you mean.
She and Marta
wanted to defect.
But you weren't
gonna let that happen.
(over speaker): I don't know
what you're talking about.
He's lying.
Maybe.
(over speaker):
And I don't know anything
about any poisoned pills.
I gave Silvana my tilo to calm
her down after Marta's death.
I guess you don't know anything
about this bag.
Same one with your name on it.
CRAWFORD: It also has
Marta's blood on it.
And that's the same kind
of rope you used
to tie her up with.
STOKES:
And the fiber
is a match to the same
burlap sack used
to transport her
to the Rumbason
from Eddie Santos's
auto body shop.
CRAWFORD:
You've been trying
to frame
Eddie Santos from day one.
No. I am the one
being framed here.
Don't you see?
I thought justice
in your country
wasn't about what you believe.
It's about what you can prove.
No?
What can we prove?
We're running everything
right now.
State Department's
all over this.
We can't afford any mistakes.
Well, neither can he.
HODGES:
Hey, boss.
I've got confirmation of
our preliminary results.
Blood on Antonio Ficha's duffel
bag matches Marta Cuerto.
That's good.
And the fibers
that we found from the burlap
sack match the burlap sack
that the killer used
to move the body.
Also good.
The rope, the cassava leaves
are all consistent.
But?
But Henry couldn't recover
any DNA from the gloves.
And I found this little mystery
in the duffel.
What's this?
Mouton.
Lambskin. With a particular
acrylic dye recipe
commonly used in the restoration
of classic American cars.
Which you're thinking the killer
used to transport the body.
HODGES:
Yes. And according to the fiber,
we should be looking
in the trunk
of a 1956 Chevrolet Bel Air.
Oh. Now, that's the same car
that Eddie Santos drives.
I went there, too.
There's just one problem.
I processed Eddie's Chevy
while he was in custody,
and his car hasn't seen
a carpet upgrade since 1956.
Oh. Well, that's not good.
HODGES:
Of course, Eddie has a stable
of classic cars.
Could be one of them.
Or the car, like our killer,
could've been staring us
in the face
the whole time.
I checked with Sunstar
Auto Rental.
They said they wrote a two-day
contract on this '56 Chevy
for Antonio
for-for your photo shoot.
But the kid behind the desk said
that he was such a big fan,
that when you came back
to rent it for an extra day,
he gave it
to you for free.
Off the books.
I guess...
like me, he was won over
by your-your beautiful voice,
your warm heart,
your... trusting face.
Anyway...
he said something else
that was very interesting.
He said that he wasn't used to
having people return vehicles
cleaner than when they drove
them off the lot.
Silvana...
I know you did it.
I know you killed your sister.
I loved my sister.
I don't doubt that.
Because, in my experience,
a brutal murder like Marta's
can only come
from deep emotions.
Love turned to hate
through betrayal.
You don't even know
what you're talking about.
Actually, I do.
Let me back up a second.
Estefan brought you
and your sister here,
but it was Marta who contacted
the State Department.
So that you
could have a career
in this country.
But more importantly,
so she could be near Estefan.
But you wanted Estefan
for yourself, didn't you?
You loved him.
Ever since you were kids.
And the more you loved him,
the more you hated your sister.
You're forgetting I'm the victim
of Antonio's betrayal.
Well, it does
look like that.
Because you made it
Antonio's bag, incriminating.
Antonio's tilo pills, poisoned
just enough to make you sick
but not enough
to kill you.
These are lies.
These are all lies!
Why can't you see the truth?
You know, actually,
I-I heard the truth, Silvana.
Because you've already given us
your confession, haven't you?
(Silvana's melancholy
love ballad plays)
All this time,
listening to these lyrics
but not really hearing them.
These words of-of love,
loss, revenge...
redemption.
No matter what she's done,
she still believes
that her lover will forgive her.
Come to rescue her.
Just like you believed
when you called Estefan,
and begged him to come
to the hotel to rescue you.
But Antonio was trying
to kill me.
No, you murdered your sister,
and you told Estefan
that Antonio did it.
You do realize, don't you, that
your lies got Estefan killed?
Marta knew how much
I loved Estefan.
Since we were children.
Every song I wrote
was about him.
She should have never
come between us!
Forced me to punish her
for what she took from me.
I beat her. I killed her!
And I would do it again if that
would bring Estefan back!
You tried to tell me
that you should never
have come to this country.
You're right.
Unlike your song, Silvana,
you'll find no redemption here.