(cheering, chatter)
(horn toots)
Boy, there's a lot
of live ones tonight, huh?
I know. You're used
to the dead ones.
Yeah, they're a lot
easier to work with.
Thanks for coming out,
helping us grunts
in the Mobile
Crime Unit.
You're welcome.
All the problems in
the department lately--
it's, uh, been hard making
cases stick, you know?
Uh-huh.
Well, that's
why I'm here.
You deal with
the whack-jobs,
and I'll do
the evidence collecting.
I'd like to think I'm going
to miss all this, but I ain't.
What do you mean? You're not
quitting, are you, Crawford?
No, I'm, uh, looking
at a promotion.
Really?
Yeah. Detective.
A lot of
opportunities now,
so I'm gonna trade in
my uniform for a suit.
Well, congratulations,
Detective.
Thank you.
Yeah, it's, uh... it's
got a nice ring to it.
Yeah, it does.
Excuse me, miss.
Can we talk to you, please?
I ain't doing nothing
wrong, Officer.
Well, you're not doing
anything right, either.
CRAWFORD:
What's your name?
Chastity.
Can I see some I.D., please?
Lost it.
But you didn't lose your purse.
Mind if I take a look inside?
You got some cash, a wallet
and some condoms.
Well, safety first.
No I.D. Debit card.
Wait a minute. You don't look
like Keith Dobson.
Yeah, it's not mine.
Then what are you
doing with it?
Have you been
arrested before?
No. Never.
Here's the deal.
You start telling me the truth,
and maybe you get to go home.
But if you keep lying to me,
you're going to jail.
SIDLE:
I've never had
to patrol the
streets like this.
I mean, not even
when I was a CSI-1.
It is a little crazy.
Full moon tonight.
You know, not
to discount the crazy,
but no lunar effect
on human behavior has
ever been established.
What about horses?
(groaning)
Hey, Trigger.
Wake up.
Hello.
(groans)
Well, this grass ain't hay.
Trigger just bought himself
a night in the barn.
Control, 3-0-5-Charlie.
Sergeant Weiss requesting
transport van to our location.
(groaning)
(indistinct chatter)
Hey, boys.
(laughing):
What?
Adrian. Hey, man.
Hey.
How are sales?
What did I say,
last time, huh?
One more swing and miss--
that is strike three.
That's life.
What's your name, kid?
I know you're scared, all right?
Okay, here's the deal--
you work with me,
maybe you
go home tonight.
Just going to need you
to come downtown
and make a statement, okay?
We got a deal?
(siren wails)
MAN (over radio):
All units, 415-C.
Olympia Casino.
Suspect possibly armed.
What are you all afraid of?
Hey, hey, I want you all
to meet my dad.
We got in a little fight.
But, you know,
it's all good now.
What's going on?
Casino security called it in.
A guy just showed up
swinging a head.
Right, Pops?
Doesn't look like he's armed.
What are you
looking at?
No, just dangerous. Officer, we
need to move these people back.
LVPD. I'm going to have to ask
everyone to move back.
Hey, sir, calm down.
Put the head on the ground.
Step away.
Keep your hands
where I can see them.
The blood is on your
hands, not mine!
I'm not doing
anything wrong.
SIDLE:
Hey, hey, sir! Hey, sir,
there's another casino
across the street.
Hey, hey.
Dad, come back.
Call for paramedics.
SIDLE:
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Oh.
Hey, uh, guys,
the head is fake.
Please tell me you're
getting this. This is awesome!
Hey. It's a stunt.
Yeah, that girl
in the blue hoodie!
Grab her!
Hey, get back here!
You, stop!
Vegas PD.
Get over here!
Running was bad,
but, dude, that hurts.
Hurt's just beginning.
Joke's over, kid.
I think you're going
to jail, dude.
Only adds to my fame
when my video goes viral.
I'm gonna have more hits
than that chick singing...
All right, you know what?
That's enough of that.
Shut up.
Come on, man.
It's not like anybody died.
CRAWFORD:
Get over here.
You got something?
Looks like someone else
got punked tonight.
But this is no joke.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
Everybody out.
RUSSELL:
You got an I.D.
on our gunshot victim?
No. No, not yet.
Wallet was missing.
What about vehicle
registration?
Well, it's a rental, but the
guy won't give up the name till
he clears it with corporate,
so we're getting a warrant.
Sara is processing
the car right now.
Evidence says the shooter
was in the backseat.
Sounds like a pop-and-rob.
Well, unfortunately,
traffic cam footage was a bust,
so in the meantime,
I'll check in with the doc,
see what he's
got to say.
Good Lord.
MAN:
Dude,
I need my head back.
I rented it
for the weekend.
This guy
does special effects for TV.
Very good, but very expensive.
Sir, I need to confirm--
is this your vehicle?
BRODY:
Feel like I'm back
at the Hollywood Division.
Where exactly
do you need me?
Booking. Ask for Chastity.
You'll know
when you see her.
I'm on it.
(garbled radio transmission)
Hey, hey, hey, Crawford,
when do I get my phone call?!
Hey!
Here's my statement.
About buying drugs
off that dealer.
Can I go now, Officer?
You need to sign it.
Ah.
Here you go.
Bobby Reed.
Is your dad Dennis Reed?
City attorney?
Yeah. He's not going
to be too happy.
Well, it could be worse.
Next time,
I won't let you off so easy.
You understand?
WEISS:
Josh McClure,
Florida license.
It's Joslyn.
Joslyn. You understand
why you're here?
No.
No, I... I do not.
You took a swing
at a cab driver.
He started it, and I wasn't
just protecting myself.
I was protecting the life
of my unborn child.
Have you been drinking tonight?
Have you taken anything?
I take offense. I'd never
endanger the health of my baby.
How dare you!
Oh, hey.
(overlapping chatter)
Hey, I need
some help here!
Somebody get the chair!
Get your hands off of me!
Calm down!
MAN:
Ma'am? Sir?
Sit down!
Sit back.
Joslyn, calm down.
What the hell is this thing?!
WEISS:
Joslyn, sit down.
This is a violation!
I've been violated!
If my water breaks,
it'll be on your head!
Oh, you hear me?!
JOSLYN:
Your head! Oh, no!
WEISS:
Take it easy.
Joslyn, take it easy.
$2,300 in cash,
and a stolen debit card.
Pretty good night, huh?
I'm gonna need you
to take off your clothes
and all of your
personal belongings.
Jewelry, everything.
I'm gonna need the ring, too.
You'll get it back.
(sighs)
Mayans were right. World's
coming to an end next month.
BRASS:
We should all be so lucky.
Has Sheriff Liston
talked to you?
Hmm? No. Why?
Well, I wanted
to give you a heads-up.
When I got shot,
the department gave me a medal.
Uh-oh. What does the sheriff
want to give me?
Her job.
What? What are you
talking about?
She's thinking of resigning,
appointing you
as her replacement.
Resigning? No, no, no.
That's the worst thing
she could do right now.
And-and I'm the last person
who should replace her.
You should consider it.
Seriously.
For the sake of the department.
Look, Conrad,
not everyone likes you,
but everyone respects you.
And maybe more importantly,
they trust you.
I'll admit, there was a time
I would have jumped at
the opportunity, but now...
I don't even know if I want to
be doing this job anymore, Jim.
BRODY:
Captain,
we need to talk.
(camera shutter clicks
and beeps)
How's your
head, Mr. Pak?
It hurts.
Oh, but you should see
the other guy.
Well, the other head.
Nice to see you still have
a sense of humor.
Are you here
on vacation?
Electronics convention.
Hospital wasn't
on the itinerary.
Those are some nasty-looking
hives on your hands.
Oh, I'm sure it's nothing.
Shellfish, allergy
to cigarette smoke, maybe.
Surprised it's still legal
to smoke in casinos.
You can get away with
a lot in this town.
Yeah, like assault
with a fake bloody head.
Head was fake.
Blood's another story.
The blood was... real?
Could you give me a minute?
(touch tones sounding)
Hey, Greg, are you still talking
to our prankster?
Yeah, I'm sitting right
across from him. Why?
Hematrace on the blood
from his fake head says that
it's real, nonhuman.
I need to know what it is.
Hold on. Blood from your prop
head's positive for nonhuman.
Nonhuman?
You make it sound like
I used alien blood.
It's pig's blood.
Old-school horror movie, dude.
Like any zombie movie.
Tarantino here says
it's pig's blood.
Ugh. That's what
I was afraid of.
The guy he clocked
is having a reaction.
Could be viral.
Maybe a blood-born pathogen.
Oh, great.
FINLAY:
Yeah, we need to know
exactly where he went
on the Strip
and how many people
he came in contact with.
Got it.
Well, it looks like your
wish might have come true.
You went viral.
Awesome!
(whoops)
As in outbreak.
Your pig's blood may
have been tainted.
What are you
talking about, dude?
I'm feeling fine.
All right, dude, you are
going to draw me a map.
Everywhere you went.
And you had better find
your girlfriend with the camera.
I'm gonna go find you
another shirt so you don't
contaminate anyone else.
You stay here,
don't touch anything.
SIDLE:
Your gunshot victim's stippling
indicates close range.
Dead center, back of the head.
Victim never even
turned around.
Tells me the shooter was quick
and efficient, a professional.
Or the shooter was someone
that the victim knew.
Or thought
he knew.
Doc pulled a .22-caliber
slug out of his head.
Come take a look
at this.
There's no rifling.
Hmm, weird, right?
Yeah, usually see this
when someone drills out
the barrel of a gun to
make it harder to identify.
Yeah, but that kind
of modification
would still leaves marks
on the bullet
as it rattled
down the barrel.
Yeah, there's
no sign of that
on this bullet.
No.
So...I'm thinking
the shooter used
a sub-caliber device.
Adapting a larger
caliber weapon
to fire a smaller
caliber bullet,
like using a .44 to fire a .22.
I'll get it to Hodges,
see if he can identify trace
from a sub-caliber device.
Maybe we'll be able to tie
the bullet to the murder weapon.
Got to find the gun first.
Stop pushing me, I said.
Sit down.
I ran your
prints, Chastity.
Your real name is
Heather Tile, you're 19.
You're from Butler,
Pennsylvania.
You have prior arrests
in Los Angeles and Nevada
for prostitution and larceny.
Look, I can explain
that debit card.
I asked a friend...
Forget about
the debit card.
We'll talk about
that later.
Now, here's what
I want to ask you.
Where'd you
get this ring?
What do you mean,
where I got that ring?
That's mine.
No, it's not yours.
It is mine.
No, it's not.
You know how I know?
The inscription.
See, I had
that ring made
for my ex-wife.
That's her
engagement ring.
So I'm going to
ask you again,
where'd you get the ring?
I already told you,
I bought it for,
like, 200 bucks.
From who?
This girl--
we worked the streets together.
What's her name?
I don't know.
We call her Jersey
on the street.
Let me show
you something.
Tell me...
...does that look like her?
Mm-hmm, yeah.
That's the girl.
Oh, man. That's my daughter.
JOSLYN:
It's coming.
It's coming,
it's coming.
My baby is coming.
Oh, my water broke.
Oh,
I'm out of time.
Joslyn,
remember, we agreed,
if I let you out of the
chair, you were going
to cooperate
and be calm.
Please,
I'm bursting.
Joslyn, please, we are
trying to help you.
The paramedics are here.
They just want to take you
to the hospital,
make sure you're okay.
Yeah, to make sure
your baby
is okay.
My baby is coming.
I'm not going to any hospital.
I'm having my baby here!
I'm having my baby now.
Joslyn, just calm down.
(screaming)
Get her down.
Get her down!
(shouting indistinctly)
Help me, help me with my baby.
Looks like a war zone.
Yeah, war at home.
One casualty.
Hospital said
our pregnant
transvestite was DOA.
Internal Affairs
is going to be all over that.
Sergeant Weiss
follow procedure?
As far as I know.
Doesn't mean they won't be
looking for a scapegoat.
Quite a busy night
on the Strip, Marko.
So where did you go
after the Fashion Arcade?
Uh, I went to
the Olympia.
Oh, hey, Lydia, it's me.
So, I'm here
with the cops.
They think maybe our
pig's blood spread
some, like, Ebola
or flu or something.
Anyway, I need the camera
'cause they want to see
who we messed with,
so call me back.
Like, right away.
(phone rings)
Hey, Finn, if you're still
at the hospital,
I hope you're in quarantine
because you do not want
to be here.
I'm actually not in quarantine.
The hospital tested
the pig's blood, and there is
no sign of any virus
or pathogen,
and Mr. Pak's responded
well to treatment,
so he's on
his way home.
So outbreak averted.
Yes.
I am headed back to the lab.
Yeah.
I'll see you soon.
All right, bye.
Told you everything
was cool.
Everything is not cool.
What is this?
This is a map
of our prankster's trip
down the Strip.
Passing right by
our John Doe homicide.
Dude, I didn't
see anything.
What about your girlfriend
with the camera?
She was too busy shooting.
Video.
So maybe the camera
is our witness.
Yeah, where is it?
Lydia has it.
She's not calling me back.
Well, you'd better
make up with her soon
because that camera is evidence
in a homicide investigation now.
Hey.
So I ran
the stolen debit card that
we got off of Chastity,
and guess what.
It was used to
rent the car
that Nick found our
gunshot victim in.
Did you get
the driver's license?
Yep.
Keith Dobson.
Name matches the one
on the debit card,
and the photo matches
our dead guy.
So Keith Dobson
is our John Doe...
and Chastity is upgraded
from trick roll
to murder.
Sara says
the prankster
may have footage
of the crime.
Now we may have
a suspect,
although I'm not so sure
she did it all on her own.
Maybe she had a partner.
Hey.
Um,
what you said before about not
wanting to do this anymore--
did you mean that?
I'm sorry you
overheard that.
I don't know what I'm
thinking right now,
and right now is not a
good time to discuss it.
Okay?
Okay, but, you know,
whenever you're ready,
you know where
you can find me.
Okay.
CHASTITY:
I really did buy that ring,
you know,
and I'm willing
to return it
as long as you cut me
a deal
on that debit card.
So you want
to negotiate?
Okay, let's
negotiate.
You know who this is, right?
That's good.
Now, I want you
to take your time
because the next answer
you give is going to decide
whether you spend 25
years to life in prison.
I don't know nothing
about that, man.
Okay, what do you know?
I met him at the pool
at the Tangiers.
Him and his buddy--
they...they wanted company.
And you--who did you go with?
No one--it was just me.
They didn't seem to mind.
What?
Don't give me that look.
I'm telling you
the truth, all right?
We'll see.
How'd you get
that debit card?
I spent the day
with them
at their suite,
showed them a good time,
you know.
The debit card guy
was clueless.
The other guy
was more of a player.
Seemed like a local.
Kind of like that cartoon,
you know,
like the Country Mouse,
the City Mouse, I don't know.
Except, in this cartoon,
the Country Mouse gets
a bullet in the
back of his head.
Look, I-I stole
the card from the guy
while he was in the shower.
Then he and his buddy--
they wanted to hit the Strip,
so I left them
at the valet stand.
I'm telling you
the truth, I swear.
The dead guy's friend--
what did he look like?
Not much different--
just another college boy
getting off on the Strip.
ROBBINS:
Subject is
a male Caucasian, 27.
Cause of death is exsanguination
due to multiple
sharp force injuries
severing
the external iliac artery.
Greg, you okay?
Yeah, I...I just thought
he was high.
I never imagined he would do
anything like this.
We all have our own demons.
Drugs only weaken our ability
to confront them.
Whatever delusions
he was suffering from,
clearly they got
the best of him.
He may not have been
as delusional as you think.
What do you mean?
According to the abdominal
X-rays, Joslyn was pregnant--
not with a baby,
but, uh, definitely
with bundles of joy.
SANDERS:
He was smuggling drugs.
And like him,
not all the product survived.
No wonder he had
a psychotic break.
Wanted to cut
the baby out.
There must be
at least 20 balloons
left inside his stomach.
SANDERS:
I'll get them to Tox.
If we can identify this drug,
maybe we can figure out
who he was
muling for.
They did this to him.
HODGES:
I put our bullet
under electron microscope
magnification.
STOKES:
Well, whatever it is,
it looks like it's scorched
right onto the bullet.
It is, and if you
take a closer look,
you can see
the face of Jesus.
Come on, man, it's been
a long night, dude.
Fine, be a
secular humanist.
What you're
looking at is
a composite material--
unpolymerized resin
and calcium carbide.
Trace left
by a sub-caliber device?
Could be, except that
sub-caliber devices
are made of brass or
steel, not polymer.
Well, maybe the killer
is using plastics.
Maybe even an
entirely plastic gun.
Think about it.
Virtually
undetectable, perfect
for a robber
working the Strip.
John Malkovich--
In the Line of Fire--
made a gun entirely
out of polymer.
Good movie, bad science.
A polymer gun
can't stand up
to the pressure
of firing a bullet.
It would break down.
Okay, what if you only
needed to fire it once?
One shot, one kill.
Is that another movie?
It will be,
starring my theory,
coming to a
lab near you.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I have some work to do.
Who would play you?
Hmm.
Hey, Greg, I ran those
balloons Doc pulled
off your pregnant
transvestite.
Yeah.
Drugs were a cocktail
of oxycodone,
fentanyl and meperidine.
That's prescription, not
your typical drug-mule fare.
No, but already on
the menu tonight.
What do you mean?
A few hours ago, Nick
and Officer Crawford
busted a dealer
on the Strip--
Adrian Dinan.
They took a baggie
of powder off him.
The drugs the dealer
was selling have
a chemical
composition identical
to the drugs in your
victim's stomach.
Same drugs.
Means Joslyn
was smuggling
for the same scumbag
who has Dinan
out there selling
on the street.
Looks like it.
Thanks, Henry.
You found the connection
I was looking for.
ADRIAN (whistles):
These are some nasty photos.
SANDERS:
Nasty business,
smuggling drugs
for you and your boss.
We know who you work for,
Adrian--
Rolan Zahl, Mad-10's set leader.
He runs girls
and drugs
along the Strip.
Sorry, I'm an
independent contractor.
You want to stick
to that story?
'Cause the drugs
you're selling
tie you to this.
Felony homicide.
Forget about three strikes.
I mean, we go
for "special circs,"
you get the needle.
I know you like
to "make deals," Crawford,
but it's my turn.
What the hell
are you talking about?
Crawford here collared
the wrong drug dealer.
That's BS. Adrian,
I caught you selling.
Not selling; sampling.
The white boy
that he let go...
His name is Bobby Reed.
He's a rich kid.
His daddy's some big shot
lawyer for the city.
He's been moving drugs in clubs
on the Strip.
Good business
plan because
he and his friends
don't look like drug dealers.
But there's only...one problem.
Zahl.
And I imagine
he doesn't like people...
cutting into his profits.
Which is where the
sampling comes in.
Bobby approached me
with his product.
Wanted to set up
a meeting with Zahl.
Thought that going
into business together
was preferable
to the alternative.
Let's say we believe you.
Where do we find Bobby Reed?
You want me to help you
with your case,
you need to help me with mine.
Hey, babe. Finally.
I've been leaving messages
for you all night.
I thought we agreed,
when you freeze me out
like this,
it's not healthy
for our relationship...
Marko, Marko,
that's not helpful.
Right.
Listen, I need
to put you on speaker.
Do not put me on speaker.
Too late.
Sorry. Listen, I'm here
with Detective Siegel.
The cops really
need the camera, okay?
Marko, I'm going to hang up.
BOTH: Don't hang up!
Uh, Ms. Kasper...
It's-it's Lydia, right?
Who's this?
Uh, I'm Sara Sidle.
Uh, I'm with the crime lab,
and I'm sure that you don't want
anything to do with this,
but in all honesty,
a man was murdered tonight,
and your camera may be the key
to finding out who did it.
We really need your help.
You're right. I don't want
anything to do with this.
Okay, w-well, you don't have to.
Uh, all I need you to do is
drop the camera someplace
where I could find it.
Could you... do that
for me, please?
Where?
Okay,
uh, behind the Olympia Casino,
there's an alley with a Dumpster
for newspaper recycling.
You can dump it in there.
Okay. Marko, you still there?
Yeah, babe, I'm here.
I'm dumping you, too.
(beep)
MAN:
All right, ladies,
I'm going to ask you
to step over here.
Hey. You find anything yet?
No, nothing.
I swear, why do I trust people?
This job should've
beat it out of us
by now.
Wait.
Sometimes life
does offer up a surprise.
"M.P." Marko Palmisano.
All right.
Got blood drops.
What?
And some drag marks.
Looks like a struggle.
SIDLE:
Blue hoodie.
Oh, my God, it's Lydia.
Killer must've been looking
for this camera, too.
Instead of finding it,
found her.
This is my fault.
Whoever did this to Lydia
did this because of me.
Marko, this is not
your fault. It's not.
It's because of the camera.
I'm so sorry this happened,
and I promise you that
we'll find the person
that did this.
I'm sorry.
(sighs)
Got to feel for the guy.
Hope he can forgive himself.
I recovered this
from your victim.
(sighs)
SIDLE:
Looks like a .22.
Same caliber as the bullet
that killed our gunshot vic
in the car, Keith Dobson.
Identical wound--
single round perfectly placed
at the base of the skull.
Same caliber, same M.O.,
same killer.
Hey! I want you all
to meet my dad!
So, did you find anything
on the video?
I did. I found
our crime scene.
Keith Dobson's
rental car,
and he has company.
Yeah, hold it
right there.
Chastity.
It's a hooker we busted
on the Strip,
had Keith Dobson's debit card.
Well, she told Brass that
she left Dobson and a buddy
at the valet stand
at the Tangiers.
Hard to believe
that a hooker would lie.
Yeah. So what about
this "buddy"?
Caught him on tape.
Ah, there he is--
in the backseat,
right behind
Keith Dobson.
Bobby Reed.
That's the kid
we let go--we thought
he was buying drugs,
dealer said
he was selling.
Well, I think he may be
guilty of more than that.
Sadly, we don't have
the smoking gun on tape.
Thanks to Mini-Me
in the Mini.
There's a bit
of a jumble here.
There... it is.
Bobby Reed and Chastity
high-tailing it away
from the car.
Leaving Keith
at the wheel.
Yeah, not moving.
Just like you found him.
CHASTITY:
It's not what it looks like.
BRASS:
Well, what is it, then?
You know, I'm trying
to be a good guy,
you know,
but all I get
from you is lies.
You're gonna
tell me the truth,
or I'm throwing you
to the wolves,
so you got
about five seconds to tell me.
I am telling you
the truth, okay?
I had nothing to do
with that murder.
I met them for the first time
at the Tangiers.
Okay, we're done here.
On orders from Rolan Zahl.
Rolan Zahl?
The Mad-10's
set leader?
Huh?
Yeah. I work for him.
You mean he's your pimp.
He asked me to pick up
on Bobby Reed, so I did.
His buddy just came along
for the ride.
He told me to...
hang out with Bobby
and text him,
let him know
where we were.
So Rolan Zahl had you
keeping tabs on Bobby Reed?
He said he just wanted
to talk to the guy.
"Talk"?
Yeah, talk,
like, with a gun
to his head. Look,
what I don't understand is...
So, Bobby Reed
is in Rolan's sights,
but Bobby's friend ends up dead,
and you and Bobby Reed
are seen walking away.
No, no,
it's not what it looks like.
Look, Bobby said he saw
some friend of his
on the Strip and...
he wanted to go say hi to him,
so he just took off.
And me, I mean, I just wanted
to get the hell out of there,
you know? I couldn't tell
any... When we walked away from
that car, his friend was alive.
And they looked
a lot alike.
Maybe if Rolan
really wanted to...
Come on.
What are you saying?
You're saying that Rolan
popped the wrong guy?
Forget it. I already
said too much.
Number one rule
for survival:
always know when to walk away.
Jersey taught me that.
You better not be lying to me.
I'm not.
And I didn't lie
about that ring, either.
She really did sell it to me.
Wait a minute.
The two of you met in L.A.?
No, I didn't meet her in L.A.
I met her in Vegas.
Vegas?
When?
Couple months ago.
Didn't know she was here, huh?
HODGES:
The two bullets
we pulled from our victims
exhibited not just
the same trace,
but, as you will notice,
identical residue patterns
singed onto
their surfaces.
So what? Fired
from the same gun, right?
Yes and no.
Heraclitus said, "You never step
into the same river twice."
Well, truthfully, you
never fire the same gun
twice, because each time
you fire a weapon,
you ever so slightly alter
its characteristics.
Heraclitus, huh?
Mmm.
Go on.
All right.
Polymer trace
got me thinking.
Maybe we're looking
for a plastic gun.
Identical markings got
me thinking further.
What if you were able
to duplicate a gun?
One you could use once
and then simply dispose of.
John Malkovich,
In the Line of Fire.
I love you. Uh,
I mean...respect.
Go on.
Okay, I want to
show you something.
(lilting music plays)
3-D printer?
The future is here.
They have scanners now
that can scan an object
to generate a perfect
3-D computer model,
which is then fed into
a 3-D printer, which then
prints the object
in three dimensions
using layers of polymer.
Now, that's cool.
Mm-hmm.
Primarily, 3-D
printers are used
to manufacture parts
for antique cars
and design prototypes.
And you think our killer...
printed a gun.
Multiple guns.
Identical,
disposable, untraceable.
Fits the M.O. of a pro.
How much do these cost?
They're not cheap--
around 150 K.
Okay, so they're not completely
untraceable. Get on the phone,
call the manufacturer,
let's get a list going.
Okay.
BRASS:
Mr. Reed, thank you
for coming in.
I know, as city attorney,
you're very busy and...
I can't believe this.
Do you recognize any
of these faces with your son?
This young man is, um, Keith.
He's Bobby's college roommate.
This is Bobby's cousin,
Josh, though I've...
never seen him dressed
like that.
You say they're both dead?
Yes. Along with a young woman,
a witness.
Bobby's mom and I split up
when he was four.
She took him to live back east.
After college, he came
to live out here.
He wanted to make
it on his own.
"Hospitality management."
Mostly it just seemed
like he went to clubs. I...
I figured he's young.
So you...
you really didn't know, uh,
what he was into?
Do you have kids?
This isn't really about me,
Mr. Reed. You know,
Bobby has been playing
drug lord, and he's pissed off
the real one.
A vicious bastard
named Rolan Zahl.
Now, we don't
have enough evidence
to bring Zahl in.
But with three people dead,
and maybe Bobby next,
we need your help.
What can I do?
Reach out to your son.
Tell him to come in
and talk to us.
Help us bring a killer
to justice.
And if I can't talk him into it?
Then he's looking
at street justice.
And very soon.
I ran Chastity's phone records.
She was definitely texting
with someone
about where she and Bobby
Reed were all night.
Texting Rolan Zahl?
I don't know.
It was a burner cell.
10:20 p.m.,
"Leaving the hotel with Bobby."
FINLAY:
Burner cell responds,
"Stay with him."
SIDLE:
10:32, "In car,
heading for the Strip."
FINLAY:
"Tell me
where you end up."
10:50, "Pulled over,
Price and Boulevard."
"Keep him there,
don't let him leave."
It sounds to me like someone
was closing in for the kill.
That's when Chastity
got out of there.
And Bobby sees a guy on
the Strip he wants to talk to.
Our dealer, Adrian Dinan.
And Bobby and Chastity
take off,
leaving Bobby's friend
Keith behind.
SIDLE: Shooter slips
into the backseat,
pops the wrong guy.
You know, Bobby and Keith
do look a lot alike.
SANDERS:
That's a good theory.
But how do we prove it?
Anybody order
a break in the case?
I hate it when you do that.
You're gonna like this.
Trace from our bullets--
unpolymerized resin
and calcium carbide--
turns out to
be a match
to a 3-D printer model.
One that I believe
printed our guns.
Could I see that trace report?
So you proved your
plastic gun theory.
Congratulations.
How does that
break our case?
Purchase of said printer
tracks to
a car restoration shop
on Madison Street
in Northtown.
The owner:
one Rolan Zahl.
Oh, looks like
we're closer to putting
the murder weapon
in Zahl's hand.
Not exactly Zahl's hand.
Unpolymerized resin
and calcium carbide.
That is not the first time
I've seen this trace.
What do you mean?
Same results came back
from Desert Palm last night.
They were looking
for biologicals.
A blood-borne pathogen.
The cause of
an allergic reaction
experienced by Mr. Anthony Pak.
SIDLE:
Wait a minute.
Isn't that our tourist
who was clocked by
Mark Palmisano's latex head?
Yeah.
FINLAY:
Who also had
an allergic reaction,
apparently, to his own gun.
Plastic guns
aren't for everyone.
Context is everything,
and everything is making
a lot more sense right now.
Check it out.
Lydia's video footage.
He must have thought
she recorded the murder.
It was no accident
Pak was there.
No, man, he was going
for the camera.
Our tourist is our killer.
So Dennis Reed convinced
his son to turn himself in.
Well, the guy's
the city attorney.
His whole life
is about negotiation.
You know, unions,
developers.
This was a negotiation I didn't
think he could pull off.
I guess you can't
underestimate
the bond between
a father and a child.
Hasn't been
my experience.
Yeah, sorry.
I heard about the ring.
Well, you know,
that might have been
one of the best
days of my life.
I surprised Nancy,
my ex-wife.
I gave her the ring,
took her to dinner, the ballet.
Yeah, yeah, ballet.
I like ballet.
No, I can see that.
Yeah, there was a lot of good
memories in the early years.
But I guess that's what you
hang onto, the good times.
Even with my
daughter Ellie.
I'm sorry.
That's got to be hard.
You know, when Nancy
and I split up,
she wanted to give
the ring back.
I said, no, give
it to Ellie.
She should have it.
And then she sells it to
that girl for 200 bucks.
That only means that
she's in trouble,
and she's not
reaching out to me.
You know that guy?
Never seen him before.
Well, he knows you.
Lucky for you,
he doesn't know you that well.
That's why he popped
your buddy Keith
instead of you.
STOKES: You really
pissed off Rolan Zahl.
He hired a hit man
to put you out of business.
I know that.
That's why I'm here, right?
I don't get it.
You have everything:
education, money, opportunity.
Why the hell would you want
to be a drug dealer?
You sound like my dad.
These men are trying
to help you, Bobby.
You should listen
to your father.
I've listened plenty.
I don't want to be a lawyer
or a doctor or a banker.
Might as well be dead.
(chuckles)
I don't expect
you people to understand.
What it's like
to be a player.
Prince of the city.
You do realize that
three people are dead
because of you, right?
That's not on me.
Do you have any idea
what you've done?
What the hell is
wrong with you?
I know exactly
what I've done, Dad.
And I know where I'm going.
Just like old times.
You get weekend visits.
And, hey,
maybe if you show up
more often this time,
you'll figure me out.
Got something for me
to sign, don't you?
We do.
Okay.
So the college boy's in;
what about you?
Do I really
have a choice?
Right now, you're just
looking at solicitation.
I'd rather have your help
trying to bring Rolan Zahl in
than bumping up the charges
to accessory to murder.
When this is all over...
then what?
It's not like you guys are
gonna protect me or anything.
Hey.
Heather.
Listen to me.
When this is over...
I'm gonna give you money
and a bus ticket
back to Butler, PA.
I want you to go back home,
I want you to call your dad,
I want you to try
to build a life there.
And don't come back
to the Strip.
SIDLE:
Chastity's made contact
with Pak.
I hope she keeps him
on the hook.
Looks like it's going down
at the Fashion Arcade.
Fashion Arcade.
You got that, Nick?
STOKES:
Yeah, copy that.
We got eyes
on Bobby and Chastity.
CRAWFORD:
Backup's en route.
Taking up positions.
I'm pulling up
CCTV cams
on the Strip.
I got Bobby Reed and Chastity.
There's Nick and Crawford.
Any sign of our shooter?
Not yet.
Oh, wait a minute.
Got him.
Hello, Mr. Pak.
Nick, we have
a visual
on Pak.
Where?
To the right of you at 2:00.
Yeah, yeah, it... it looks
like he's texting.
Yeah, he's telling them
to go to the food court.
All units,
converge on the food court.
All units, converge
on the food court.
Pak's on the move.
That's all right,
we got him.
He's taking a shortcut.
Where the hell did he go?
Nick, we lost him.
Yeah, so did we.
CRAWFORD:
Where'd he go?
I don't know.
I can't find him anywhere.
He knows where the cameras are.
LVPD.
Drop the gun.
Drop it or we drop you.
CRAWFORD:
Looking good, Weiss.
Pak's not talking.
Not even to ask
for a lawyer?
I'm sure Rolan Zahl
has that all taken care of.
By the way, we searched
Rolan Zahl's
auto restoration shop.
No sign of a 3-D printer.
Got rid of it.
Okay, so what
do we got?
We got a gun and a phone
with text messages,
both in Pak's hands.
And Rolan Zahl's
hands stay clean.
We do have
Chastity's testimony.
Uh, the word of
a prostitute?
Good luck.
Okay, so Zahl walks,
everybody else goes to jail.
And Chastity?
No, she's got a deal
that stays in place.
She's getting a
second chance.
She's a smart girl.
I think she'll take it.
Little help from the right
person, I'm sure she will.
(indistinct chatter)
Waitress was busy.
Thought I'd give her a hand.
Man, you are
a tough guy to find.
I practically had
to bribe
your duty officer
just to get your 20.
I just needed a little
peace and quiet
to finish up these
reports for I.A.
Probably having a field day
with the bloodbath in the PD
and cops letting
suspects walk.
Anybody getting
the ax?
Not if I can help it.
Chicken soup?
You don't like
that stuff.
Last time I saw you
with a bowl of that,
it was in the hospital.
Well, I'm developing a
taste for it, I guess.
What's wrong, Dad?
Is this about
the sheriff's offer?
I don't know, M.
I-I guess
I'm just not feeling
myself lately.
These days,
everywhere I look,
everything in my life
just seems so complicated.
(chuckles)
Everything, huh?
Really?
No, no, I d--I don't
mean everything, no.
Listen to me,
I'm confused
about a lot of
things right now,
but you and me,
our relationship--
that is the only thing in
my life that makes sense.
Well, my shift is over.
Mind if I join you?
I'd be happy to have
your company--always.
Would it drive you crazy
if I ordered a bacon
double chili cheeseburger?
Not if we order two.
BRASS:
Hey.
I just got back
from holding.
Where's Heather?
Who?
Heather Tile.
Chastity the prostitute.
Oh, yeah, somebody
made bail for her.
Bail--who?
I don't know.
You know, actually, she
left something for you.
Oh.