(neon sign buzzing)
(siren wailing in distance)
(bell chimes)
(slot machines dinging)
Money plays.
$100.
Eleven.
Doubling down.
21.
Yes!
Two or 12.
Splitting aces.
21.
Oh!
Yes!
♪ ♪
Blackjack.
Yes!
(cheers, drums on table)
Blackjack.
Eyes on BJ-13.
MAN:
I'm already on him, Bobby.
I don't know what to tell you.
I can't figure out
how he's doing it.
Blackjack.
Yeah!
Whoo!
$100,000.
Twenty-one.
Yeah!
21.
Blackjack.
$200,000.
Shuffle.
21.
Yes!
Okay, I think
you're done.
Okay.
Good luck.
Thank you.
I think I'm done.
Cash me out.
That's a hell
of a run there, uh, Mr....
That's about $350,000.
Your lucky day.
I have a proposition
for you.
Why don't you
stick around?
We're gonna put you
upstairs in a suite on us.
You can eat up,
clean up,
and then come back down here
in a few hours
and take us
for everything we got.
How does that sound?
No, I'd like
to cash out...
now.
(indistinct radio transmission)
Excuse me.
Who are you?
Do you know
what time it is?
I'm sorry?
It's 8:00 a.m.,
as in the graveyard shift
ended two hours ago.
You realize that, right?
This body
is, is mine.
I'm not going to get into
a turf war with you right now.
Because you'll lose.
Look, don't make me
call your supervisor.
Oh, too late.
And you are...?
Sean Yeager, day shift.
RUSSELL:
Oh, Yeager.
Yeah, your supervisor
speaks very highly of you.
You're a CSI-2, right?
Yeah, one solve away
from a promotion?
Yes, sir.
You know, I-I never
cared much for this
day shift
versus night shift crap.
I mean, we're all
one crime lab, right?
All for one, one for all.
Okay, look, cards
on the table here.
I really do need this
solve to be a solo.
I hate to break it to you,
Yeager, but I don't think
this is the game-changer
that you're looking for.
Homeless guy assaulted
in an alley.
(phone chirping)
Looks like a trash run.
Yeah?
I'm not so sure
about that.
Yeah, I think I'm with you.
Why, do you got something?
Uh, my wife Barbara
is stranded at
the airport,
needs a lift.
So you should go
pick her up.
We'll take care
of this.
RUSSELL:
The two of you work
together?
I think that's a great idea.
Don't you think?
Like you said,
all for one and one for all.
(chuckles)
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
Whew, this guy is ripe,
and I don't think
it's decomp.
I think he just
may have really
needed a shower.
BRODY:
He's got dirty clothes,
got weathered skin.
He's been living on the streets
for quite a while, you can tell.
You get a wallet, David?
No wallet--
I checked.
PHILLIPS:
Yeager,
come on, man,
you know the protocol.
You can't touch my body
without my authorization.
I didn't touch your body.
I saw a wear pattern
on the back pocket with no lump.
No lump,
no wallet.
I figure the guy gets mugged,
the attacker rifles
through the wallet and tosses it
in the nearest
trash receptacle.
Hey, I'm not in
here for my health.
You've been in there
for a while.
You found a wallet yet?
I'm working on it.
PHILLIPS:
Hey, uh,
liver temp was 91.1,
which puts time of death at
around 3:00 this morning.
I count 12 sharp-force injuries
with a two-inch blade.
Stabbed in the back.
I know how he feels.
You know what?
When we close this case,
you can have the solve.
Thanks,
but I don't need your charity.
Case...
in point.
Blood says it's related.
Empty.
What is homeless
guy doing with
the Mission: Impossible
briefcase?
So much for your trash run.
Got blood drops.
Looks like the assault
started right here.
Our victim is heading
down the alley,
he gets attacked from behind.
The assailant grabs
the briefcase,
steals what's inside.
But these blood smears
and drag marks say
that it didn't end there.
The killer sees his victim
still alive,
trying to crawl away,
so he drags him out of sight,
finishes him off.
You know,
you see that blood on his finger
and under his hand?
Weird, right?
D.E.
What do you suppose
that means?
Well, maybe it's a,
a message, you know,
last words to
a loved one.
Or, if it were me,
my dying breath,
I'd try to identify
my killer.
I see you're not the
sentimental type.
Okay, I like that.
RUSSELL:
Oh, boy, honey, I'm so sorry.
Problem solved.
Conrad wanted me to
reschedule a hearing.
It's okay, I get it, I know
you're a very busy person.
That's why I said I would take
a taxi from the airport.
No, no, I told you I wanted
to take you home.
I'm gonna, I'm gonna
take you home.
Sit first.
Have something to eat.
These pastries are good.
Pastry?
No, I-- ah, I'm sorry, I
can't-- couldn't possibly...
I will-- let me have a hit
of that coffee, though.
Thanks.
Hey.
I'm sorry, really, I...
How are you?
How was Seattle?
Maya and Katie
are both doing very well,
and Ryan talked
with his company
and worked it out
so he can stay home more.
That's good.
(phone beeps)
Have you talked
to Charlie?
It's been crazy around here.
I-I know I got
a couple of
messages from him.
Is there something
I should know?
Well, there's something
he would like
to tell you himself.
Oh, come on, come on,
that's not fair.
I promise I'll
act surprised.
What? What?
He's gotten an offer
from Eastern Indiana--
full scholarship,
starting point guard.
Is he gonna take it?
Well, I think so.
Well, that is news.
It's great, it-it's just
that, you know...
one of the reasons why we took
this job was so we could be,
you know, near Charlie,
watch him play his games.
I think getting away
could be good for him.
I know.
I just didn't expect it,
that's all.
Things change,
plans change.
That sounds like another
discussion we need to have.
Yeah, but at another time.
I can tell you're busy,
sweetheart,
and I can take a taxi.
Hey, Doc, got
your message.
You have something for me?
Yeah, still working
on our alley John Doe,
but I found this
in one of the wound tracks.
Maybe a piece
of the murder weapon.
Tip of the blade--
maybe it broke off.
I'll get it to Hodges.
Tell me something--
these wound patterns...
I admit sometimes cases
start to blur together,
but I could swear I have seen
this somewhere before.
Well, the two wounds
in the center,
closest to the
spine, appear
deeper and wider.
Almost like the killer
twisted the blade.
Yeah, but the rest of the
wounds are clean, sharp.
That could be overkill, rage.
Or something else--
a signature.
I'll pull some case files,
see what I can find.
Thanks.
♪ ♪
(bell chimes)
WOMAN: Well, don't you look
like a lovely couple.
Let me guess.
You're in the market for a ring?
(chuckles)
Uh, information,
actually.
I am CSI Brody,
and this is CSI Yeager.
I take it you're Ruby.
Yes, but...
if this is police business,
I must confess,
I'm just the name on the door.
My boys
run the store now.
I just come in occasionally
to help out.
Keeps me out of trouble.
Kyle!
Zeke!
Little help up front.
KYLE:
Coming, Ma.
What's up?
Well, these very nice,
uh, police folks
would like to talk
to you about something.
I'll be in the back
if you need me.
Oh, and, honey,
don't let him get away.
Uh, okay. Um...
we recovered
this pawn ticket.
Looks like it's from one
of your customers last night.
We just need a name.
Hey, what's this about?
Well, that wasn't the question.
This is
time-stamped 11:49.
Why don't you look that up?
Uh, our computers
are down right now,
so...
Mmm.
Uh, 11:49?
Plaid shirt,
T-shirt, jeans, smelled bad.
Farami watch.
14 karat pinky ring
with the inscription
worn off
at 90 days at 23%. $200,
uh, cash on the barrel.
Wow.
You remembered all that?
Can you remember his name?
Jeremy Sikes.
1139 Cornell Road, St. George,
Utah, 84780.
I made a copy
of his driver's license, too.
200 bucks for a Farami watch
and a gold ring?
I can see
you're, uh,
real generous.
It's a secured loan.
Guy doesn't come back for it,
that's on him.
You sure it's just on him?
Here you go.
Thank you.
You mind if I hold on to this?
Uh, yeah, sure.
I always make a duplicate.
You never know.
Oh, and the watch and the ring.
You guys still have those,
right?
Yeah. We got 'em.
Great. We'll take those to go.
RUSSELL:
Wow, somebody had a good night.
FINLAY
Yep, that's Jeremy Sikes
from last night
from the eye-in-the-sky
from Pike's Gambling Hall.
This was distributed to security
at all the casinos in town
with a warning to keep
a lookout for this guy.
RUSSELL:
Why?
Was he causing trouble?
Oh, the worst kind.
At least in Vegas.
Our friend here
took his $200
from Ruby's Pawn Shop,
walked into Pike's
and 37 hands,
45 minutes later,
he had $350,000.
Wow.
Well, at least we know
why he had
that briefcase.
$200 turning into 350 grand--
come on, what are
the odds of that?
I'd say somewhere in the range
of being eaten by a shark
while being struck
by lightning.
(chuckles):
Yeah...
The casino, obviously,
thought that he was cheating.
Card counting?
No, the betting pattern
was off.
They suspected collusion
with his dealer, Kristi Holt,
who, by the way, did not show up
for work this morning.
RUSSELL: You're thinking
that Sikes and Holt
were scamming the casino.
And then Holt stabbed Sikes
in the back-- literally--
and ran off with the money.
Interesting theory, but...
(tapping keys)
RUSSELL:
Look at that--
Sikes drew quite the crowd.
Any one of them could've
followed him back
into the alley, right?
FINLAY: My money's
still on the dealer.
That's because you're assuming
that they were cheating.
Of course they cheated.
No, and Sikes even tried
to I.D. his killer
in his own blood:
"D-E" spells "Dealer" to me.
Look, for all we know,
this is just one of those
great Vegas stories:
Guy pawns
his last possessions,
nets it all and wins.
The two of them
are total strangers
and it's just a case
of dumb luck.
I don't believe in luck.
Me, neither.
Why? What do you got?
A connection...
between Jeremy Sikes
and our dealer Kristi Holt.
The watch that Sikes
pawned for stake money
turned out to belong
to Kristi's husband.
And here's the kicker:
Her husband was
murdered two months ago.
Dumb luck, huh?
I'm thinking that maybe
this casino heist
isn't the first time that
Kristi enlisted Sikes
to engage in
a little dirty work.
Two months ago, she has
him murder her husband.
And, last night, after
they both scammed the casino,
Kristi kills Sikes.
So it looks like
we have this Kristi Holt
dealing the death card--
not just once,
but twice.
Yeager and I pulled
the cold case file
on the murder of Simon Holt,
our blackjack dealer's husband.
You and Yeager.
Nice to see you kids
getting along.
Yeah, well,
let's just be clear:
I'm Rizzoli
and she's Isles.
(laughing):
Yeah.
Anyway, the case is
still open.
And maybe open because
day shift was investigating.
Don't look at me, okay?
I was on the swing shift then.
The night of the murder,
Kristi Holt was questioned.
She said she finished up
her shift at Pike's
then left the casino to meet up
with her husband Simon.
They met for dinner,
then got home around midnight.
She was really tired.
Immediately went
upstairs to bed,
and he went to the living room
to watch the news.
YEAGER: And that's when
she heard two shots ring out.
She ran downstairs
and found her husband dead
and the place was ransacked.
So Kristi Holt's story is that
her husband walked in on
some guy robbing the place.
Now, in defense of day shift,
it was a good story.
There was no reason
to doubt it.
Until last night...
when Jeremy Sikes
turned up dead.
After pawning Kristi Holt's
husband's watch,
and going on
one hell of a run
at her blackjack table.
They say there are
no coincidences.
Yeah, but...
sometimes there are.
Yeah. Right.
Dumb luck.
I thought we agreed that
luck wasn't a player in this.
All right, well, then,
call it destiny.
Or fate.
BRODY: Of all of the
blackjack tables
in all of the world--
is that where
you're going with this?
No, where I'm going with this
is there's one person
still alive
who can answer these questions.
(phone chimes)
BRODY: Mm.
What, is that your wife again?
No, someone else's.
A widow, as a matter of fact.
Brass just
picked up Kristi Holt.
If this is about what
happened last night,
I'll tell you what
I told Bobby, my pit boss:
It was a straight-up run.
There was no cheat.
If we're just talking about
cheating here,
then this is your lucky night.
Now it's my turn
to deal.
Your pal Jeremy Sikes.
Oh, my God, wha...
that's... the guy.
I... Is he...?
Dead? Yeah.
But I think you know that.
How about I hit you again?
Your husband Simon.
This is the time
in this gambling session,
when you go bust.
Or you play your ace in the hole
and tell me the truth.
The truth?
The truth is
my husband was murdered
when he walked in on a burglary.
You sure you want
to stick with that story?
It's not a story.
Yes, it is. And you
really ought to hang out
with a better class
of co-conspirator--
or at least a smarter one--
because your pal Jeremy
pawned your husband's watch
for $200 and brought
the money to the table--
that's what staked him
in the game.
This guy...
had Simon's watch?
Yes.
If he had his watch,
it must be because he stole it
because he's the one
who broke in our house.
Or there could be
another explanation:
You could've given it
to him as a little
thank-you gift
for killing your husband.
That's sick!
I gave that watch to Simon
for our anniversary!
Yeah.
We checked with Farami.
It's a special order.
Around $2,000.
So I--I looked
at the insurance records,
the claims and
the police statements,
and... nowhere is there
mention of a $2,000 watch.
My husband was murdered,
Detective.
I forgot about
the damn watch!
You didn't forget about
the insurance money.
Which went to pay off
Simon's debts!
Which is why
you and Jeremy doubled down
at Pike's Gambling Hall,
to the tune of $350,000.
Kristi, you know,
you didn't show up for work.
You end up at a motel,
hiding under the bed...
this doesn't look good.
If you worked
for old-school guys
at an old-school
casino like Pike's,
and they thought
you cheated them...
you'd be laying low
in a motel, too.
And if this is the guy
who broke in my house
and killed my husband,
then he deserved to die.
But I didn't kill him, and I
didn't have anything to do
with cheating the
casino last night,
and if you don't believe me,
check the damn tape,
the cards, the shuffler--
I didn't cheat!
♪ ♪
(cards fluttering)
(computer blipping)
♪ ♪
(tapping on glass)
ANDREWS: Hey, hey.
What do you got?
It looks like
our dealer didn't cheat.
Says you.
I'm still not convinced.
This guy went on
an insane run.
We saw the tape.
He's hitting when he shouldn't,
holding when he shouldn't--
the odds of
that happening are...
183,120 to one.
I have an app.
Okay.
What about the evidence?
I did examine all 416 cards
in play-- they weren't marked.
And the shoe checked out.
And I looked
at the shuffler.
There's no sign that
either one of them
was tampered with.
And you didn't get anything
on the eye in the sky?
No. If she was palming cards or
pulling some sleight of hand,
she was doing it between
the video frames.
Okay, so she's a magician.
That doesn't mean
she's not a killer.
I like what she said.
(scoffs)
Looks like you're the only one.
FINLAY:
So we weren't the first
to toss Kristi Holt
into the box.
She was detained
by casino security
right after she left
the blackjack table,
and then was interrogated
by her pit boss Bobby Esposito.
That's them in the holding room.
Check out the time code.
BRODY:
2:58 a.m.
Sikes' time of
death was 3:00.
So Holt's inquisition
lasted over four hours.
There is no way
that she killed Sikes.
So who did?
Well, I hate to admit it,
but Russell may be right.
Sikes' run at the table
did draw a crowd.
Meaning there are several people
who could've followed him
out that night.
Did you get a chance
to look through
the rest of the casino's
floor footage?
Did you see anybody
that looked like
they were shadowing him
at all?
Well, I didn't see anybody
who was obviously following him.
Wait a minute.
Freeze it for a second?
FINLAY:
What do you see?
BRODY: Take it back
just a little bit.
Right there.
That guy,
talking to the pit boss.
I've seen him before.
You've seen him before?
Where?
BRODY: On someone else's
security video.
(doorbell chimes)
Where's your friend?
Busy.
Just get me this time.
You know, cops keep
showing up around here,
people are gonna get
the wrong idea about
my establishment.
You gonna return that watch
and ring you took or...?
No, they're still
in evidence.
Actually, I am here to look
at a few other items.
You gotta be kidding me.
Nope.
The surveillance video
that you gave us
shows this guy
coming into
your establishment
sometime after 3:00 a.m.
He works for
Pike's Gambling Hall.
His name's Alonzo Pierce.
Pierce: uh, 1453-- 1456
uh, Silver Ridge Road,
Seven Hills, 89052.
I got his phone number,
if you need it.
Thanks.
Actually, what I need is to look
at the items that he pawned.
Looked like an old turntable
and some speakers.
Right, and I would love to help
you out with that, it's just...
it's such a mess back there
right now, it's kind of...
I know where it is.
(chuckles)
Of course you do, little bro.
Yeah, Rain Man here
will take care of you.
Oh.
Okay, uh, turntable,
not valuable.
Uh...
The speakers, they're Cadillacs.
Frequency response 30 kilohertz,
impedance four ohms...
You tried them out,
and they didn't work, right?
Yeah, the-the left one's out.
How'd you know that?
Do you mind, uh,
letting me borrow
that little drill over there?
Sure.
Thanks.
(drill whirring)
Uh, I'm pretty good
with electronics.
I'm sure you are.
These speakers, it's usually
just a, like, a wiring issue.
Well, in this case,
I think it might be something
just a little bit different.
(gasps)
Whoa. Uh,
okay, that's a lot of money.
I'm guessing about $350,000.
I don't understand that.
If I had that kind of money,
I'd put it in, like, a bank.
Unless you couldn't.
Place like this,
people drop off an item,
you keep it for 60 days,
then they come back to collect.
Beats a bank
if you're trying to beat
a murder charge.
Pike's casino said Alonzo Pierce
didn't show up for
his shift today.
Getting to be a habit
with their workforce.
Yeah, a real brain drain
at Pike's.
We buzzed Alonzo's apartment,
no answer.
His manager said he was going
on a trip; he took a small bag.
When was this?
A few minutes ago.
We got the exits covered;
he's not going anywhere.
(whispering):
That's him.
(gun clicking)
BRASS:
Alonzo Pierce!
Las Vegas Police.
You're under arrest.
Hey!
Sorry, pal,
but you're gonna
be disappointed.
It's the pit boss.
Told you.
What the hell
are you doing here?
Use your freaking imagination.
Get him out of here.
Pop the trunk.
Oh.
Alonzo Pierce.
That was a short trip.
Yeah, well, nobody steals
from Pike's Gambling Hall.
Well, at least somebody
at Pike's
is dedicated to their job.
Tell you something, Bobby,
you make detective
work look simple.
I mean, there you are, standing
there, gun in your hand,
Alonzo's Pierce's
body in the trunk.
I mean, all I had to do
was call a tow truck.
I'm gonna make it
even easier for you.
I'm gonna tell you exactly
what that little bitch,
Alonzo, did.
Tell me.
You know I seen
a lot of cheats in my time.
But last night, (sighs)
that was different.
I don't know exactly
what this guy
and my dealer had going on,
but I knew the grift was on.
It had to be,
'cause nobody's that lucky.
See, in the old days, Vegas,
when guys like Sam Braun used
to run the town,
we would've put this guy
in a car,
done a little carpentry on him.
He would've given it up.
Town's changed.
Not for the better.
Right, more civilized now.
You whack guys in the alley.
I didn't tell him
to whack the guy.
I just told him
to get the cash back
and put a little healthy fear
of God in him
before he put him
on the Trailways bus.
So Alonzo killed Sikes
on his own initiative?
And he stole the cash.
Believe that?
I don't know what
to believe anymore, Bobby.
I mentored him,
and he turns around,
this little bitch,
and he doesn't have the cojones
to look me in the eye
and tell me the truth?
He has to make up some BS story
about he didn't kill him.
He just roughed him up,
and he put the cash away
for safekeeping.
I'm not gonna lie to you,
I-I would've whacked him anyway,
Alonzo,
but that's because he stole
from the house.
That's a matter of honor.
Old Vegas.
Damn straight.
See, you and me, we're
on opposite sides of the table,
but I know
that right here,
we're on the same page.
I'm gonna ask you a favor.
What's that?
Put in a good word for me
at sentencing.
I'd like to get sent up
to Carson City...
with the old boys.
Men of honor.
Done.
Heard you caught a case
with day shift.
(chuckles)
Yeah, lucky me.
Seems to be
case closed.
Right.
Homicide, guy's luck
ran out in the alley.
Yeah, the casino pit boss
sent one of his goons
after the guy.
The goon kills him,
takes the money, and
then he stashes it
in a stereo speaker
and then pawns it.
Now, why am I doing this?
This day shift guy, Yeager,
really wants this solve,
he should be the one
finishing up the paperwork.
Your victim was stabbed
multiple times, wasn't he?
Yeah, why?
I don't know, I'm just looking
at the timestamps
on these photos.
So, the security goon
gets his orders
from the pit boss
at 2:48 a.m.?
Yeah, and then the goon
follows him to the alley
and kills him around 3:00.
What are you seeing?
You know,
what about the clothes?
Doesn't this look like
the same suit, same shirt,
same tie?
Oh, my God, you're right.
Guy stabs him 12 times,
and he doesn't have
a single drop of blood
on his clothes.
Yeager still hasn't
gotten his solve.
SANDERS:
Hey, Morgan,
I've been looking for you.
So your security guard
didn't kill Sikes.
Yeah, I know.
What, Hodges told
you about the bullet?
What bullet?
The metal fragment we found
in Sikes' wound track.
We thought it was
the tip of the knife,
but it turns out
it's from a bullet.
I thought he was stabbed.
Now you're saying he was shot?
Yeah, twice.
(two gunshots)
And then the killer
used the knife
to dig out the bullets,
and then proceeded to stab him
ten more times.
To throw us off track.
Well, that's where he made
his mistake.
Doc thought he recognized
the wound pattern,
so I did some checking,
found an open case
from two years ago,
same pattern.
Drug informant was murdered.
Person of interest
was a Luis Delgado.
Had ties to the Mala Noche
drug cartel in Miami.
The letters in blood.
"D.E."
He was trying to spell
"Delgado."
I-I just... I don't get it.
Why is a big-time gangster
wasting time with a nobody
like Jeremy Sikes?
I have an idea about that.
Turns out, a month ago,
Delgado walked in
on a robbery
at his house.
He got shot,
and his girlfriend called it in.
You think Sikes was the robber.
I do,
and the DEA has had Delgado
under surveillance.
Check out this photo.
He's wearing the same ring
that Sikes pawned at Ruby's.
Where is Delgado now?
Owns a strip club
off of Flamingo.
♪ ♪
Luis Delgado?
I hope these gentlemen
are up to date with
their carry permits.
What do you want, Detective?
I'm the bearer of good news.
You recognize him?
His name is Jeremy Sikes.
No. Should I?
The guy died
two nights ago.
Two shots in the back,
bullets dug out.
Sound familiar?
This is the guy
who robbed your house.
I didn't file any police report.
Yeah, well, we
recovered this item,
pawned by Sikes.
That's my ring.
Yeah, well, no police report,
I can't return it to you.
Even in prison.
I think you have me mistaken
for somebody else, Detective.
You say he was killed
two nights ago?
You see, my mother,
she's very sick.
Two nights ago,
I was staying with her.
I can prove it.
I mean, you can prove it.
So the jury's in;
Luis Delgado is a beautiful son.
DEA surveillance
just alibied him out.
Okay, but that doesn't mean
that he didn't get
one of his own guys
to do it for him.
That's true, but
the rep on Delgado
is that he's very hands-on.
So where does this leave us?
I think we have
the right motive,
but the wrong person.
So, Kristi Holt
and Luis Delgado
both talked about Sikes
breaking into their houses,
and in both cases,
they walked in on him.
What if they weren't
the only ones?
Maybe another homeowner
walks in on Sikes,
gets a good look at him
when he's in their house,
two nights ago sees him again
in the alley,
after he was rolled
by Alonzo Pierce.
I think we have to pull
more case files.
Yeah, I agree.
Go back to the pawnshop.
See what else
Jeremy Sikes pawned for cash.
♪ ♪
Okay, what do we got?
22 items from Ruby's Pawn Shop,
all pawned by Jeremy Sikes
in the last six months.
And all of them
can be traced forensically back
to five B-and-Es,
including the break-ins
at Kristi Holt's
and Luis Delgado's.
BRODY: These aren't
your ordinary B-and-Es.
In all five cases,
the homeowners walked in
on the robbery.
According to this,
walked into a bullet.
Yeah, well, five
B-and-Es, four murders
and one attempted.
Only Delgado escaped death.
So what are we supposed
to believe?
This Jeremy Sikes is just
one unlucky burglar?
I thought we agreed that luck
wasn't a player here.
No, the shootings weren't
an accident,
and the robberies
were cover stories.
Remember how Kristi Holt
left her husband's watch
off of the insurance claim?
Well, the same goes
for all of these homeowners.
YEAGER:
22 items stolen,
and not one of them reported
by the victims' survivors?
I mean, personally,
I... we think that
it's payment
for services rendered.
I agree.
We had a case like this
up in Seattle.
Low-rent hit man for hire ring.
Advertised in the personals.
Called themselves
"problem solvers."
They're pretty good, too.
Flew under the radar
for a long time.
So how'd you bust them?
Caught a break.
Turned out one of the hit men
was a coke addict.
Burned through his money,
started shooting off his mouth,
I guess he became
a liability.
'Cause the head guy decided
to hit the hit man.
So Jeremy Sikes
became a liability.
Only instead of blow,
it was blackjack.
BRODY: All this loot,
he should've been flush,
but instead,
he was living on the streets
with his last $200.
Sounds like a liability to me.
One that the broker
decided to eliminate
by framing Delgado.
The only question is:
Who's the broker?
Kristi, in addition
to your husband's watch,
we also recovered these
other items that were stolen
by Jeremy Sikes.
The... the man who broke
into my house.
And murdered
your husband, Simon.
RUSSELL:
That's roughly,
we figure,
about $5,000 worth
right there.
That's an awful lot
of valuable stuff
to forget to report,
don't you think?
(sighs)
Listen, we know that you...
you bought this watch
for Simon for your...
your anniversary, right?
But you did not buy
this bracelet for him.
Someone else did.
Another woman.
BRODY:
We traced the purchase
back to a...
Tiana Lee.
Oh, come on, Kristi,
we understand.
I mean...
you're working
two jobs, right?
And you're
still in debt
because Simon spends the money
as fast as you can make it.
What happened?
You came back
from work one night,
he wasn't there.
He was out again.
Then he shows up.
Maybe he's drunk.
And you ask him,
"Where were you?
What were you doing?"
Maybe he hits you.
Maybe he does that a lot.
And then, one day,
someone, a friend,
suggests a solution.
And all you can think
about is getting rid
of that pain, all that sadness.
Look, Kristi...
We know that, in your heart,
you are not a killer.
And that you... you feel
guilty about all of this.
But this is your chance
to get rid of some
of that guilt.
By telling us the
truth right now.
KRISTI:
But you're right.
About Simon.
About the friend.
That person gave me
an e-mail address of a broker.
I was told
to follow instructions.
They were going to make it
look like a robbery,
and I was told to leave
certain items off the report.
To pay the hit man.
I wasn't lying
when I said
that I never met the guy.
Him just... sitting at my table
and going on that
insane run was just...
Dumb luck?
What about the broker?
I paid $5,000 up front,
and they set up a meet.
You remember where?
At a pawnshop.
Oh.
Is this the guy that you paid?
No. I think
he runs the place.
The broker's a woman.
Older.
She said she
hangs out there.
(cell phone ringing)
Russell.
When?
What now?
Somebody just went
into Ruby's Pawn Shop,
shot the place up.
BRODY:
Akers, what the hell happened?
According to Ms. Banks,
two armed men entered.
They were looking for something.
She doesn't know what.
They shot her son, Kyle.
Took her other son, Zeke.
Okay. Thanks.
(crying)
Who would do
something like this?
I don't know.
But I think you do.
Excuse me?
Kristi Holt gave you up.
We know Jeremy Sikes worked
for you as a hit man,
and we have a pretty good idea
how you terminated
his employment.
What is wrong with you people?
My son is lying there dead,
and now they've got
my other boy, Zeke.
Ruby, it's over.
I didn't kill Sikes.
But I know who did--
it was Delgado.
I mean, the word on the street
is it's his signature.
Two shots to the back,
bullets dug out.
Sikes even tried
to write Delgado's name.
That is one hell of a story.
But word on my street is
that you're a sociopath.
You're the one who
killed Jeremy Sikes...
(two gunshots)
...and framed Delgado.
BRODY:
And you know exactly
who came here
and why.
If you don't come clean,
you're going to
lose another son.
Come on, Ruby.
We know how much
you love your boy.
Okay, you're right.
I killed Sikes, but...
my boys didn't know anything
about the side business.
Sikes stole this cigar box
from Delgado,
and it wasn't even
worth anything--
it was a few hundred bucks--
but what was inside
was worth a lot more.
It was 100 grand in heroin.
Where are the drugs?
I sold them.
But Delgado's guys
don't know this.
Zeke, he wanted to protect me,
so he lied to them.
He said he knew
what they wanted
and he would
take them to it.
When Delgado finds out
that he lied,
he's going to kill him.
(indistinct chatter)
Back again so soon?
Where's the kid, Delgado?
What kid?
I know you got him
in some basement,
beating the hell out of him,
but he doesn't know anything.
You're not going to
get your drugs back
because his mother has
already sold them.
They're gone.
Are you going to make
me ask you again?
Where is he?!
Hey. I think you need to start
showing me
a little more respect.
This is my house.
Yeah, right.
Look, your lapdog is
going to mess on the rug.
If he doesn't get
his hand off his gun...
Or... what are you
going to do about it?
(patrons screaming)
(man groaning)
Now that I have
your attention...
You tell me where
the kid is,
and we all go home.
Or we all got to
die sometime.
You're new in town,
so here's your play.
Here's what the guys
in Vegas used to say--
in the old Vegas:
It's your house,
it's your rules.
You got that right.
I think you got yourself a fan.
(chuckles) No, he just likes
the way I handle power tools.
No, I wasn't talking about him.
Oh.
Well, congratulations.
You got your solve.
No. You take it.
I mean, you earned it.
I'll catch the next one.
Maybe I'll catch it with you.
I'll see you around.
Yeah.
This is nice.
I'm glad you could
finally get a night off.
You should thank Finn.
She's covering for me.
You have a... a great
group of people here, D.B.
They work so well together,
and they're like a family.
You should feel good about that.
I do.
Charlie--
has he made
any decisions yet?
No. Not yet.
And what about you?
What's going on?
This last trip to Seattle,
I made a pilgrimage
to that neighborhood
that we used to love
to drive through,
with the house on the
hill, with the view.
I remember.
We used to fantasize
walking up to the front door,
knocking and asking
if they would sell it to us.
I did that.
And they're an
older couple,
and they're very
open to the idea.
Okay, don't look
at me like that.
Well... you're serious?
We have a house--
here.
We've talked about
this before.
You can't do this
job forever.
And I don't want to wait
forever for this house.
Where's this coming from?
I'm worried about you.
I think... I think this
job is getting to you.
It's not. I'm fine.
I don't believe that.
Well, I'm fine.
I'm sorry. Come here.
My work here isn't done yet,
but when it is,
when that day comes, you and I
will go back up
to Seattle, and we'll...
we'll both knock
on that door together.
I promise.
I accept.