RUSSELL:
Previously on CSI:
Our serial killer
got all of his inspiration
from one place:
the Nine Circles of Hell.
Your daughter, Ellie,
is one of the girls
who may be missing.
LARSON:
The pictures I sent online?
A client who reached out
to my ministry.
Oliver Tate.
Works for a biotech company.
BRODY:
Without an undercover
operation,
we are all just sitting around
waiting for
another body to drop.
I need to do this, Dad.
RUSSELL:
Stop the SUV.
Killer's got Morgan.
And Ellie.
He's got them both.
PRIEST:
The Book of Job tells the story
of a man who loved God
and renounced evil.
Until one day,
Satan posed a challenge to God.
Test this man.
Test his faith.
When we mourn,
we're all tempted to curse God.
To give voice to our anger,
our confusion.
Our sense of powerlessness
against evil.
We're tempted to ask:
Are we being punished
for our own sins?
We're tempted to ask:
Is there something
we could have done?
TATE:
You are the angry girl.
(siren whoops)
Get out of the car!
Now!
Get out!
Nick! She's not here.
Russell, Morgan's gone.
(sighs)
Oliver Tate, LVPD!
Go, go!
Go left!
Yep. Clear.
Clear!
Sheriff, it's clear.
No sign of...
Find Tate.
RUSSELL:
Nick, traffic cams
showed two SUVs.
We're tracking
the other one now.
I got it.
RUSSELL:
The SUV with Morgan
is parked outside
a storage facility
off of Hill
and Decatur.
Greg.
Greg!
Drop back!
Greg?
RUSSELL:
Nick, Greg, talk to me.
What's going on?
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
STOKES (on radio):
Stand by, Russell.
SANDERS:
It's not Morgan.
It sure looks like her, though.
Her hair, her dress.
STOKES:
I think it's one of
the missing girls
from Larson's church.
The crime scene's
staged like the
Fifth Circle of Hell.
We'll start to process.
Uh, get us some help
out here, will you?
If I may conjecture...
RUSSELL:
John, not now.
Your press badge only gets you
so much access.
No, I understand.
This has nothing to do
with my being a reporter
doing some story
right now.
If neither Ellie Brass
nor CSI Brody
were intended to be
the killer's next
victim, then...
then there is still
hope, isn't there?
There are four circles
of Hell left,
so... more circles
means more time.
We are gonna find them.
Alive?
Or like all the others?
ECKLIE:
We know you're working
with Oliver Tate.
Oliver Tate.
(chuckles)
No way.
Where are the girls?
I already told your
guys who stopped me.
Now I'm telling you--
I don't know.
ECKLIE:
And we're telling you
we don't buy it.
Two SUVs, two drivers--
you playing decoy,
and whoever was
driving the girl.
And not just any girl.
I know your daughter Ellie
from Brother Larson's church.
She told me all about you.
(whispers):
I'm not your little girl.
You're gonna talk to us.
Kiss my ass.
BRASS: All right,
all right, no, no, no, no.
ECKLIE:
The kid knows
where Morgan is, Jim.
You want to know why
I was driving that SUV?
I work for Brother Larson.
Talk to him.
You set us up,
you son of a bitch.
I don't know what kind of...
intimidation
Jake was subjected to,
but I know the boy's
flesh is weak.
Righteousness and a good lawyer,
cast out that confession
faster than Jesus cast out the
moneychangers from the temple.
I--I don't way what
game you're...
you think you're
playing here.
You--you and Tate
are on the hook
for four murders, and
now two kidnappings.
I'm being set up, pal.
I'm telling you,
Oliver Tate is setting me up.
Why would Tate go after you?
Obviously, a man of Tate's...
dark desires is vulnerable.
I tried
to blackmail him, but...
man wouldn't pay
my price, so...
I called his bluff.
I shared his secrets
with his...
friends, his employer.
(chuckles softly)
Much to his chagrin,
I imagine.
You don't believe me, do you?
No.
Admittedly, I've
not earned your faith.
But... I know someone who has.
Someone who was once
Tate's favorite forbidden fruit.
Someone who once
saved your life.
Angela?
The very same.
I should warn you, Mr. Russell,
if Oliver Tate is
the master of this game,
he will never stop
until he sees to it...
we all burn.
ELLIE:
Can you hear me?
Are you okay?
Ellie?
You're the cop.
He said you'd be coming.
Who? Who said that?
I don't know.
I haven't seen his face.
All I know
is that I was with him
at his condo,
and then I woke up here.
You were
with him, too?
Yeah.
Where are we?
What is this place?
It's hell.
ROBBINS:
Hyoid bone's broken.
Denise Tyler was strangled.
Thoracic injuries
appear postmortem
from being impaled
on that spear.
Staged.
Just like the others.
We've seen this
latent bruising before.
Our last victim.
(beep)
"Barb...
"the...
thorns."
What does that mean?
I don't know.
This guy's dropping bodies,
he's staging crime scenes
and leaving nothing behind
to tie him to the murders.
ROBBINS:
Maybe this time he did.
This looks like
a dried secretion.
Perhaps a bead of sweat
from the attack.
PHILLIPS:
Could be our killer's DNA.
Who's the mannequin
supposed to be,
the Grim Reaper or something?
Phlegyas, the boatman.
In Dante's Inferno,
Virgil escorts Dante
down through
the Nine Circles of Hell,
and Phlegyas here
is the one who
gets him across the River Styx,
the River of Death.
I always liked engineering.
How wide
do you think that door is?
I don't know,
maybe four feet.
And the beam
of this boat?
At least six.
Somebody put this thing
together in here.
Let's see if we can take
it apart real quick.
I think there's a
seam right here.
Ready?
Yeah.
Balliol's bones--
just like the ones our guy's
been leaving behind for us
in the Bibles.
STOKES:
Yeah, but those dowels
had zeros on them;
these have zeros
and numbers in repeating order
from stem to stern.
Maybe it's some kind
of, uh, sequence, like a code.
RUSSELL:
Tate's leaving us messages.
He must've left us something
somewhere in that condo.
I mean, he know we were
gonna tear the place apart.
I'm telling you,
I haven't found anything,
and I mean anything.
There is no blood,
there are no signs of violence.
There is nothing here
to even suggest
a secondary location.
All right. Keep looking.
You know, there's got to be
a message there someplace.
Hi.
Did you find any trace
from the crime scene?
Boat, SUV, dowel?
I did find trace on the spear
and the planks of the dory.
Halide deposits.
That's rock salt, right?
We're 300 miles
from the nearest ocean,
but there are any number
of mineral deposits
in southern Nevada.
Doesn't exactly narrow
it down, does it?
No, it doesn't.
She's a CSI.
What the hell
was she doing undercover?
Call me if you find
anything, David.
Doc said he may have found
some DNA from the killer
on Denise Tyler's body.
Is that right?
Yeah, I've got
a dried secretion.
I ran it--there seems
to be a problem.
The profile seems incomplete;
there's no amelogenin.
RUSSELL:
No sex gene?
How is that even possible?
You know, run it again,
and get Greg to help you.
(sighs)
Hey.
When did you get back
from San Francisco?
A few hours ago.
You were in PD.
Uh, Ecklie asked me
to check on Larson's story.
According to police records,
Angela, aka Miss Kitty,
was arrested last year
for solicitation.
Vice made a notation that she
was with an Oliver Tate.
Cops busted her;
they let Tate go.
So Larson's telling the truth
about Tate knowing Angela.
And maybe the blackmail.
I spoke to his
old boss at PhiloDyne, the
biotech company where he worked.
Tate was fired
for personal indiscretion.
After that,
he was angry
at the company, he was angry
at the cops, at the world.
He became a recluse.
We need to talk to Angela.
She's disappeared.
♪ ♪
(floor creaks)
How the hell
did you get in here?
Officer downstairs let me up.
You don't want
to shoot the messenger.
Someone left their Bible
and a dowel
outside my hotel door
with that inside.
Instructions to come here.
FINLAY:
Quote from Dante's Inferno.
Inscribed on the Gates of Hell.
The King said,
"Bring me a sword.
"Divide the child in two.
"Give half to one
and half to the other."
By this wisdom...
Solomon discerned
the worthiness of the one that
would lay claim to the child.
You can only have
one daughter back.
You have a decision to make.
Or the decision
will be made for you.
You have six hours.
You can only have
one daughter back.
You have a decision to make.
Or the decision
will be made for you.
You have six hours.
(click, beep)
Has Brass seen this?
Yeah.
What I don't understand
is why Tate
is now sending messages
through you.
Is there anything
you want to tell us?
Maybe he knows who I am,
what I'm doing here.
FINLAY:
Wouldn't be
the first time
that a killer reached out
to the press.
He's screwing with us.
He's using my daughter to do it.
He doesn't even say
how we're supposed
to communicate with him.
FINLAY: My guess is
we're gonna get
another flash drive.
Well, when you do,
why not give Tate
an answer?
Excuse me?
It is the last
thing he'd expect.
Maybe throw him off his game.
No, this isn't a game.
And as I recall, the
last time you were here,
you two convinced me
to send my daughter
into the arms
of a killer.
I don't think that's quite fair.
No, no. You're right.
'Cause I'm the one
who made that call.
But you two don't have
to live with it.
I know you said
we got nothing,
but we better find
something soon.
Or the decision
will be made for you.
She keeps looking up.
Here, watch this.
You have six hours.
RUSSELL:
She keeps looking up.
Why is she doing that?
Well, she's struggling,
she's under duress.
No, she's stronger
than that.
And she's smart.
Like you.
Why would you be looking up?
I would look up
to send a message.
NANCY:
Did you see
Ellie on the video?
No, just Morgan,
but we have to believe
that Ellie's still alive.
If you had to choose...
We don't have to choose.
There's no choosing.
This isn't real, Nancy.
I know. I'm just saying.
Ellie is my daughter.
She's my little girl.
But she's not
a little girl.
She's--she's not...
six years old.
(sighs)
Look, I understand.
The first six years
we were all together,
you were a great father.
You were a great husband.
You were a better man.
Until I screwed it up.
We screwed it up.
So what chance
did Ellie have
but to do the same thing?
Gun to your head,
you'd choose
the other girl, right?
If we get her back,
you have to love her
not for who she was
but for who she is.
All this time, all these years,
I've been searching for Ellie
when she didn't
want to be found.
I thought, by my sacrifice,
I could prove to myself
that I still loved her.
But you're right.
I'd choose the other girl.
STOKES:
You know, maybe she's trying
to draw our attention
to something else
in the room.
You know, that's what
I thought at first.
But check this out.
Every single time
Morgan looks up, there's
a spike on the audio track.
BRODY:
You have six hours.
Maybe if I can isolate it.
(beep, whirring)
(beep, low rumbling)
Low frequency.
Power lines?
Yeah, but it surges.
Then it dissipates.
(rumbling continues)
Doppler effect.
It's moving.
Could be an engine.
NICK:
It sounds like a jet.
And it's close
to the ground.
Taking off or landing?
If we can I.D.
this audio,
we might be able
to I.D. the plane.
There are several airports
around the Vegas area,
including Nellis
Air Force Base.
Yeah, and if we run it
against FAA flight logs
from the time of the recording,
we could have our flight path.
And we can narrow down
the search area.
I processed the dowels
in the boat.
They were clean,
just like the ones
that you guys have been
finding in the Bibles.
If that's a sequence, I'm
not sure where to begin.
It's ternary code.
Like binary code
but instead of just having
zeros and ones,
you have zeros, ones
and twos.
You're talking
about digital encryption?
I'm also talking about DNA.
In this case.
Finn found this
in Tate's condo.
Synthetic DNA
in saline solution.
An exact match
to the DNA
we thought was sweat
from our killer.
Engineered for
data storage.
That sounds
pretty sci-fi.
But Tate did work
at a biotech company.
Forget about flash drives--
this is the future.
So let's say that we
wanted to store this
digitally on
synthetic DNA. First,
we would have to translate
the pixels
into the zeros, ones and twos
of ternary code.
Then we'd transfer
those numbers
into the nucleic acids of DNA.
The information
can be retrieved
as long as you have
the right decryption key.
Tate must have been storing
something important,
something he wanted to protect.
Well, if the dowels
are a decryption key,
we should be able
to read it, right?
We'd need the biometric scanners
from Tate's company.
And a warrant.
So let's get a warrant.
(grunts softly)
(quietly):
We shouldn't
be doing this.
What if he hears us?
Just keep listening.
I almost got this.
(groans)
It's not gonna
work anyway.
We're not giving up.
Just like the people who are
looking for us aren't giving up.
Yeah, right.
Keep on dreaming.
(sighs)
Ellie, I know it seems
like the world has turned
its back on you,
but it's not the case.
You don't know anything
about me.
I know a lot more
than you think.
I know how much
your dad cares about you.
And how much he misses you
and how he would do anything
to help you.
He's not doing this for me.
You know that
he's not
even my father?
Yeah, my real dad
is some cop
that my mom hooked
up with at the bar
trying to get back at him
for all the bitches he banged.
The only thing they
ever agreed upon
was to lie to me about
it, but I found out.
From some vice cop in Jersey
who busted me
after he screwed me.
(sighs)
I used to hate my dad, too,
you know?
Please.
Just spare me the speech about
how you let go of your past
and learned to accept your dad
for who he was.
All I'm saying
is I've seen your parents.
It isn't what
you think it is.
What are you talking
about, my parents?
Your mom's here.
My mom?
Your dad called her.
They may disagree
about most everything, but...
they both love you.
Well, it doesn't matter
because there's no way
we're gonna make it
out of here alive.
(beeping)
(phone chimes)
Russell.
It's me. Angela.
Angela, where have you been?
We've been looking for you.
There's something
I should have told you
about these murders,
about Oliver Tate.
I'm scared, Mr. Russell.
Tell me where you are right now.
At the Fellowship.
All right, Angela,
I'm gonna send a team over
to you right now.
No. No, please, Mr. Russell.
I don't trust anyone but you.
(sighs)
All right.
All right, okay, I'm on my way.
Angela?
Oh...
Put the phone down.
Phone. On the floor.
Now.
Kick it over here.
Whatever Angela
did to you, Tate,
she did not deserve this.
Easy for you to say.
She didn't betray you.
What do you want? You want...
you want me to beg? Is that it?
You want me to
choose which girl
gets to live, you sick...
You really have no idea what
is happening here, do you?
Look, it's just... it's
just you and me right now.
Tell--tell me
what it is you want,
and I... and I'll
get it for you.
I just want the girls back.
For a pair of whores,
you would cast your own soul
into the fire?
I would make a deal
with the devil himself
to get those girls back.
Whatever you think of me,
I am not the devil.
However, I do believe
the devil is within your midst.
Are you talking about Larson?
That's kind of funny,
'cause he said
the same thing about you.
Except he's been in
custody for two days.
Kind of hard to kill somebody
when you're behind
bars, isn't it?
Oh, God.
I see.
Those girls are going to die,
and I will be held accountable.
You can't stop it.
And neither can I.
Control, this is
Charlie-Zero-One, Russell.
I need backup at Fellowship
of the Fallen Angels.
I'm in pursuit of Oliver Tate.
Suspect's driving
a silver Taurus.
Thomas-David-Henry,
Ocean-Three-Four-Seven.
(Russell grunts)
(glass clinking,
debris thudding and clinking)
ECKLIE:
Oh, God. What the
hell is going on?
I thought we
had our guy.
BRASS:
Who says we didn't?
All the signs
still point to Tate.
They'll be picking up pieces
of him till tomorrow morning.
I think we're looking
for an accomplice
who decided to end
the partnership.
I'm not so sure.
Violence.
ECKLIE:
What?
Violence.
The scattered remains look
exactly like the engraving.
The Seventh Circle of Hell.
I think that Tate
was just the next victim.
ECKLIE:
Which means
there are now
only two circles left.
FINLAY:
I processed
the Bible and the dowel.
They're both clean.
But there was a SIM card
inside the dowel and...
a message... for you.
The killer wants me
to make a call.
We're set to run
a cell tower trace,
for what it's worth.
(line ringing)
ELLIE:
Dad?
Ellie.
It's time.
You have to give me your choice.
Ellie...
Sweetheart...
I can't do that.
I know.
(phone beeps)
JOHN:
I was told
I'd find you here.
I assume this is where
you come for answers.
Given your reputation,
it must work.
Well, it's not working now.
I know it took you 11 months
to find the Gig Harbor Killer...
but you did find him.
After he had already
killed six women.
And here I am now
with seven dead,
and I'm waiting for
another body to drop.
Maybe a member
of my own team.
Or at least the daughter of
someone very close to me, so...
We're trained to
follow the evidence,
but some--sometimes
that's not enough.
There... there are times
when you need to hear that...
that voice in your head
that says, "Look here."
Trouble is, when you...
when you've done this job
long enough...
one day,
you stop hearing that voice.
And that day has come?
SIDLE:
Russell.
Hey.
You have anything?
Two things.
Doc found skin
under Angela's nails.
She got a piece of her attacker.
Henry ran the DNA,
it came back
unknown male,
so Tate is not our killer.
Okay. What--what about
the synthetic DNA?
I got the warrant.
I got Tate's company
to decrypt the files.
You need to see this.
Tate's been using all his DNA
gigabytes for one thing--
porn.
Guy certainly had a fixation
on the Nine Circles of Hell.
All of our female victims
are here.
Yes, but he wasn't
killing them.
It was sheer fantasy.
Pretty clear, also,
that Tate was a watcher,
not a participant.
He was using teenage boys
as sexual surrogates.
Some of them were pretty young.
Our killer, whoever it is,
left us evidence
of Tate's perversions, right?
He's been talking
to us in puzzles, in--in code.
Like the-the message...
the message on the body.
"Barb... thee... thorns."
It's an anagram.
That's from Dante's Inferno.
"Who is in yon fire, that comes
so parted at the summit,
"as it seem'd, ascending
"from that funeral pile
where lay the Theban brothers."
"Barb... thee... thorns."
Theban Brothers.
Sons of Oedipus.
Cursed for life because
of the sins of their father.
See, I think we're looking
for brothers that Tate used.
Hey, Henry!
Come here.
The skin you got
under Angela's nails--
run it against Jake.
Hey, D.B.
Hi.
So it turns out your
hunch was right.
DNA confirmed it.
Angela's killer was a
familial match to Jake.
Meet his brother--
Matthew Tarland.
I pulled a print off
the trigger remote
that was used in the
bomb to kill Tate.
Got a hit in AFIS.
It turns out that his
brother there, Matthew,
was busted a couple of years ago
for solicitation.
There's no way this
dude's gonna roll over
on his own
flesh and blood.
All we have him on right now
is driving around the block,
and he knows it.
I just... I just don't see
he and his brother going
to all this trouble
without wanting the world
to know what Tate did to them,
why Tate had to be punished.
Why we all had to be punished,
for that matter.
Mm-hmm.
No, he wants to confess.
Just not to us.
LARSON:
When they came to me,
I proclaimed your innocence.
Even though you'd just planted
a big, fat, red Judas smack
on my cheek,
I said, "No.
"He could never have committed
these heinous crimes
"because only one man lives
in such dark places.
Oliver Tate."
Well, you would know.
You pimped to him.
Yes, I did.
Is that why
you bore false witness
against me?
I don't know
what you're talking about.
Yeah, you do, Jake.
You know what you've done--
you and your brother.
It seems to me,
your brother's kind of left you
holding the bag.
And the Lord
said unto Cain,
"Where is Abel thy brother?"
And he said, "I know not.
Am I my brother's keeper?"
Am I my brother's keeper?
A boy came to me once.
A little boy.
He'd been cast out onto
the street with his brother
by a man who, father-like,
promised them everything...
(panting)
...but instead...
used them.
Twisted their souls.
Do you remember that boy?
Yes, I do.
But he's... dead.
I think
there is still love
in your heart.
Not for me,
but for someone...
someone who gave that life
to you unconditionally,
who's been repaid in blood.
I think you need
to look at this.
Recognize
your brother's work?
You're lying.
This is a trick.
No, Matthew would never...
He--he knows how much
I care about Angela. No.
Jake, your brother killed her.
He posed her just like
all the other girls.
No!
You are your
brother's keeper.
You are responsible
for what he's done
and what he will do
to two more girls
that have nothing to do
with what happened to you.
We know he's in that area
right there.
LARSON:
We are all sinners.
We all need redemption.
This is your chance.
(footsteps, Ellie
whimpering and groaning)
So what's the deal
with the mask anyway?
Why are you so scared
to show your face?
You're just going
to kill us.
Or is that it?
You don't have the guts
to look us in the eye
when you do it.
This what you wanted?
Take a good look.
It's the last thing
you're going to see.
I'm going
to make you feel everything.
(groaning)
Lock him up.
Wait.
What?
I think there might be
another girl.
What do you mean?
When he had me on the phone,
I think I heard
another girl.
Are you sure? Where?
I don't know.
Maybe in another room.
Run! I'll catch up.
Hello?
Anybody in here?
(gun cocks)
Come down here.
Get down on your knees.
Told you I was gonna
make you feel everything.
(Brody grunts)
(groans)
(grunts)
(both grunting, blows landing)
No!
(gagging, grunting)
Let her go.
(Brody grunts, gasps)
(low grunt)
(body falls)
(panting)
Thank you
for coming back for me.
Come on, let's
get out of here.
(gunshot)
(body thuds)
(sirens wailing)
(sirens stop)
♪ ♪
What do you got?
He's dead, Jim.
BRASS:
Ellie.
ELLIE: Dad.
He shot her. I tried to
get the gun from him,
but I couldn't-- he was
too strong, and he...
It's okay. It's okay.
Her pulse is weak,
but she's alive.
Control, this is
Captain Brass.
Officer down.
Need medevac.
My location. Code Three.
(siren wailing)
Ellie said Morgan
got the girls out of there,
but Matthew just...
chased 'em down,
shot Morgan right in the back.
STOKES:
Then he tackles her,
there's a struggle,
the gun drops, she shoots him.
What about Morgan?
In surgery.
Doctors say anything?
Nothing yet.
Finished the trace reports.
Morgan's in surgery,
so I thought I'd...
Go.
Thanks.
It's a good thing the
kid was a bad shot.
Ellie was lucky, too.
You know, she only got off
the one round, the kill shot.
I found, um...
debris...
in the firing mechanism.
Maybe from the struggle.
Kid on top of her,
wrestling in the dirt.
On top of her?
Don't think so--
at least not
when Ellie
fired the gun.
There was no GSR
on his shirt.
She had to be at least
four feet away from him.
Traumatic event.
People remember things
differently, I guess.
Not that differently.
Call me from the hospital, okay?
With an update.
Nick found Matthew Tarland's
cell phone at the scene, right?
Yeah. I'm going over
his e-mails now.
Okay, forget
the e-mails for now.
I need to see the photos
right away.
What are you
looking for?
I'll know when I see it.
Whoa. That's Ellie Brass
with our killer.
Uh, metadata says the photos
were taken a year ago
in Jersey City.
Nancy told Brass
that Ellie
brought a guy home
with her last year,
said that he was her fiancé.
Wait, so Brass's daughter
knew Matthew Tarland?
She's been lying to us.
D.B., we have a situation.
Is Brass still at the hospital?
When did he leave?
Hey. It's me.
Got some moo goo gai pan.
Your guys' favorite, right?
Nancy?
Ellie?
Right here, Dad.
(phone ringing)
You gonna get that?
(phone continues ringing)
You shouldn't have dragged Mom
out here.
She saw me with Matthew.
I had no choice.
You should have
just kept this
between you and me.
Why?
Matthew and Jake
had their daddy issues,
and, thanks to you... so do I.
You--you and the
boys--you did...?
You did this?
When I had you on the phone,
I asked you to make a choice.
Oh, my God.
You tried saving me
my entire life, and you could
have saved me then, but, oh, no.
Like always...
(phone ringing)
...you had to be the cop.
Sounds like someone wants to get
your attention pretty bad.
I know what that's like.
(phone continues ringing)
You killed the only
person I ever loved.
The only person
who ever loved you.
Ellie,
you want to shoot me...
...go ahead.
(voice breaking):
Because...
I'm dead already.
What happened?
(knocking)
MAN:
LVPD!
Give me the gun.
(gun thuds onto floor)
(rhythmic beeping)
Hey. Hey, hey.
Dad.
Uh, uh, El--Ellie...
Yeah. We know.
She's in custody.
Don't worry.
You are gonna be okay.
(sighs)
But you know what?
You and I really need
to steer clear of hospitals
from now on.
Thought you'd already left.
Not without
saying good-bye.
Did you get your story?
Yes. Yes, I did.
Although it's not really the
story I came here to write.
Should the mayor be worried?
It's not a hatchet job, if
that's what you're thinking.
Doesn't all just go
into the box, does it?
No.
There is one question
I never got to ask you.
That voice inside
your head--
the day that it
does go quiet...
do you think that that
will bring you peace?
Or will it be a loss
too great to bear?
MAN:
And so we gather together today
to mourn the loss
of our sister Nancy...
taken from this life
all too soon.
In grief,
we throw our arms
around our brother Jim,
and we pray
that his journey with Nancy
to her final
resting place
will bring them both peace.
The lesson of
Job is clear.
Even in a moment of
immeasurable sorrow
like this one,
we're given a choice.
A choice between the
hopelessness of despair,
and the everlasting
promise of faith.
Faith...
that there is a plan.
And that in times of doubt,
God will speak to us
in a voice that is clear
and true.