(woman speaking Spanish)
The sweetest little
girl you've ever seen.
BOY:
Ana is the only girl
I ever asked out.
She said no,
but still...
(voices murmuring)
Kid was a force of nature.
She'd come into
my class laughing,
and just...
light up the room.
She will not
be forgotten.
Al...
Thank you for coming.
Can we have a word?
Of course.
ROBBINS:
I am so sorry for your loss,
Gabriel.
And I apologize;
I still haven't heard
quite what happened.
I didn't want to keep
the news of Ana's death
from her friends and family,
but there are certain details
of it which...
remain unclear.
Three days ago,
Ana was discovered dead
in the border city
of Arquero, Mexico.
The local coroner
found her license on her,
notified LVPD...
calling her death
"drug-related."
They sent these photos
and prints to confirm
it was Ana.
But he's been
otherwise uncooperative
and refused to arrange transport
of the body to Las Vegas.
Has he performed
an autopsy?
I demanded that he
not proceed with one.
He's wrong about
Ana doing drugs,
and I don't want him
getting anything else wrong.
Al...
I want you to go to Arquero.
Determine how my daughter died.
Gabriel...
that... that's not
something that I can do.
No, no, no, you must!
As my friend.
Please.
Since Carmen's passing,
Ana was all I had.
I need you to make sense
of what has happened to her.
She was a good girl.
I've been to Arquero, Mexico.
For business.
There's no reason Ana
should have been down there.
In that wretched place.
Please, Al.
Tell me what
happened to my Ana.
Okay.
I'll see what she
can tell us.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
All right, well...
thanks for your help.
Yeah, yeah,
not a problem.
Hey, Greg.
Hey.
Landlord came over
to collect the month's rent
from the couple
who lives here.
Came across this
when he looked through
the garage window.
Wow.
That's one hell
of a body dump.
Like they were dumped
by a cement truck.
Got this picture
from inside.
I'm pretty sure
this is the couple.
Brett and Claire Marsh.
Someone's been doing
a lot of work in here.
SANDERS:
Landlord says
that Brett had repaired
the sewer line
and was in the middle
of replacing the floor.
Yeah, but concrete's
not quicksand.
They couldn't have just
gotten stuck in it.
No, I'm thinking
that someone was trying
to bury these two.
PHILLIPS:
And the ground just
vomited them
up, huh?
Yeah, because someone
messed up the recipe.
A couple of
these empty bags
are expansive mortar.
It looks like concrete,
but it's actually designed
to bust up concrete.
You pour it
into drilled holes
and it'll grow
to such a volume
that it can crack solid rock.
The stuff is mistakenly
mixed with the concrete,
gets poured on the couple,
and then the dead shall rise.
Beyond bizarre.
David, I can help you
chip them out
for transport back
to the morgue.
That would be
great. Thanks.
All right, I'll get started
processing inside the house.
OFFICER: Sir, hold up.
MAN: I live here.
This is a crime scene.
I live here, all right?
This is my house,
all right?!
Whoa, hey.
I live here!
Hold on a second.
What the hell is going on?
Brett Marsh?
Yeah.
I'm CSI Sanders.
I'm with
the crime lab.
Claire?
Oh, my God.
She's dead?
I'm so sorry.
BRETT:
Is that Jeff?
My wife and my brother Jeff.
I was only away
in Bakersfield for a night.
What the hell
happened to them?
You said that your brother
was doing your cement work?
He needed a
place to stay.
So I let him crash.
And I knew he'd screw it up,
the kind of guy Jeff is...
but I was expecting
sloppy edgework,
not...
that.
Do you know anyone who'd
want to hurt your brother?
Or your wife?
All right. We're gonna
figure out who did this.
RUSSELL:
Oh, there he is.
Hola, amigo.
You ready for this?
Took a little convincing
with my wife,
but, uh, I'm clear.
RUSSELL:
Good. You're clear
internationally, too.
Mexican Federal Police
are gonna have an agent
meet you at the airport
and then escort you
throughout the entire trip.
Yeah, it's this agent
right here.
His name's, uh,
Javier Silva.
He'll be like
our own personal
Federale, right?
And Nick's gonna liaise
any evidence you find
during the autopsy.
And act as my
translator, por favor?
Well, it's been a while,
but I'll do my best.
Oh, boy.
RUSSELL:
All right, look,
I know I don't have
to tell you guys this,
but that part of the border...
it's like the Wild West.
So you do your
thing and then
come right back.
Sounds good.
Besides,
what could go wrong?
♪ ♪
Ahh!
I don't suppose
they're too strict about
speed limits here, Agent Silva?
The way cops work in Arquero,
be lucky if it's a radar gun
they are pointing at you.
Yeah, I've been reading
up on the situation
down here.
The war between
the drug cartels
is really
heating up.
And from what
I understand,
local police are in
the cartel's pocket.
Am I right?
And one thing
all sides agree on:
they despise
outside law enforcement.
Americans
or Federales.
Great.
♪ ♪
That's the place?
Dr. Blanco?
Sí.
(speaking Spanish)
I'm Dr. Al Robbins,
pathologist
from the Las
Vegas coroner.
Las Vegas?
STOKES:
Sí. Yo soy
Nick Stokes,
con Las Vegas PD.
This is about that girl?
Yes, sir. Ana Ortiz.
What kind of budget
do you have to work with
out there
in Las Vegas?
I'm sorry?
You can travel
the world,
just to be told
in person, go away?
I told you, amigo.
ROBBINS:
Dr. Blanco. Dr. Blanco.
We're not trying
to invade your
territory, sir.
Dr. Blanco...
if you'll just
allow me
to examine the
body-- please.
I've already told her father
what happened to her.
I will autopsy her
once I'm finished
with those that have
been waiting longer.
SILVA: Dr. Blanco,
federal agencies are prepared
to intervene if necessary,
so I suggest...
(speaks Spanish)
The body's in cold storage.
Drains are backed up.
There's the bucket.
Thank you.
Are there other
staff here?
Just me.
STOKES:
Wait a minute,
you handle
over a thousand murders
a year by yourself?
In a good year, yes.
That's insane.
There's only one body
that you're worried about.
She wasn't murdered.
Anonymous caller, uh, saw her
by the side of the road
in the middle of nowhere.
I picked her up.
I found cocaine
inside her nostrils,
all over her hair,
her dress-- overdose.
She has no history
of drug use.
Says who?
Says me.
(chuckles)
You know, I'm starting
to get the feeling
he doesn't want us around.
♪ ♪
Hey.
So, I had Dr. Blanco
give me Ana's clothes.
There was no
butcher paper.
So local news is going
to have to do here.
Everything all right?
Ana's father wanted
some answers.
He's not gonna like them.
Her hair is thinning, she
has sores on her mouth.
The signs of sustained drug use.
The degree of damage
to the liver and kidneys
is further evidence
consistent with her being
a serious long-term drug user.
And her father had no idea?
I don't think so.
We'll express-ship a sample
of her heart blood to Vegas.
Lab can run a drug panel.
Blanco also gave me a sample
of the cocaine trace
he found in her nose and hair.
So we'll check that out.
What's going on
with her feet?
Are you seeing this?
Well, it sounds kind of strange,
but the tissue damage
is consistent with frostbite.
Frostbite?
In a town where the morgue
doesn't drop below 50 degrees?
You got me.
Whoa, there's traces of cornhusk
all over this dress.
Don't worry, Doc, we'll find out
exactly what happened to her.
I hope so.
Okay?
Hey.
This is definitely Claire Marsh
and her husband's brother Jeff.
Single GSWs
to their heads?
Through and through on his,
no exit wound on hers.
Expansive mortar did
the rest of this damage.
Well, Finn is X-raying
the rest of the concrete now.
She thought she saw
an embedded bullet,
which means they were shot
in the garage.
Right beside
their shallow grave.
But the concrete
expanded and shifted,
so we won't be able
to determine anything
about the bullet's trajectory.
(Sidle grunts)
Greg.
Look at this.
A gun.
Possible murder weapon?
You know, I found
some antidepressants
among Jeff's stuff at the house.
Guy has emotional problems,
ends up with a gun in his hand?
You're thinking murder-suicide.
Wouldn't be
the first guy to covet
his brother's wife.
He wants to off himself.
Decides to take her with him.
So, he shoots her,
pours the concrete,
and then snuggles up beside her
in the concrete.
Bam.
It's a possibility.
Actually it's not.
I found high-velocity
blood spatter
on Claire's clothing.
Wrong side to be from her GSW.
So it was his, which means she
was standing out of the concrete
next to him when he was shot.
My theory--double murder,
killer plants the gun,
buries them.
Occam's razor is so dull.
Okay.
Doc's gathering his notes,
writing his report.
We'll be out of here
first thing tomorrow.
Cool. Secured some tacos
from down the street.
Weapons-grade hot sauce.
Thanks.
So, did you read about
this cartel massacre last week?
Four gunned down,
one of them beheaded.
I've got them
in the cooler right now.
The news treats it like
it's something to celebrate.
But look at these guys.
Murder sells papers, amigo.
Yeah, but it's
different down here.
I mean, these cartel guys are
worshipped like celebrities.
There's songs written
about their crimes.
Sure, but wasn't Vegas
founded by criminals?
You guys put your
mobsters in a museum.
That's history, not news.
Okay, so who do you think
buys all the drugs?
Place like Sin City.
Come do whatever you want.
No cartels without customers.
I think you hurt his feelings.
Don't get me wrong, Stokes.
You hook me up with a deal
at Caesars, I'm there.
Something wrong, Nick?
These men were all slaughtered
in a cartel hit last week.
That paper shows
cornhusks on the ground.
It's all over them.
That's the same trace that
was found on Ana Ortiz.
Dr. Blanco?
I think there's been
a cross-contamination of
trace between the bodies.
Bull.
This place might
not be pretty,
but I do my job right.
I don't make mistakes like that.
If that's true,
then Ana Ortiz
was at the same place where
those four men were murdered.
We found traces of cornhusk
on her body,
the same way they had it.
Dr. Blanco, there's more
to her story, isn't there?
I recovered those men
from the site of the massacre.
Cartel property.
Used to be a
cornfield.
Next day, an anonymous caller
said that I left a body behind.
Went back out there,
little bit away from
where the other bodies fell.
There was a girl.
So, you lied to us.
You're here
for the girl.
Not the cartel
killings.
And she wasn't shot
like the other...
men, so why-why keep
digging into it?
I want to see the investigative
file on that shooting right now.
She died of an overdose.
An overdose of cocaine.
All right?
So, let it be.
I need to see that file.
There isn't one.
Oh, come on.
He's not lying to you, Stokes.
Cartel-on-cartel crime,
nobody's looking into that.
Then we will.
What?
We came here
to determine what happened
to Ana Ortiz.
And by God,
that's what we're gonna do.
Now, her body was found
at the scene
of that massacre,
we're gonna go
back out there,
and we're gonna process it.
Nick, I'm not so sure...
You want to go stand in a field
that's still bloody
from the last guys
who stood there.
We'd be target practice.
Well, if you think
it's too dangerous...
I'll go alone.
(speaking in Spanish)
You trust these guys?
Local PD was the best protection
my office could coordinate.
These guys are safer
than nothing.
That's debatable.
So, Dr. Blanco
said he found Ana's body
right around here.
And look at this.
Same cocaine trace
that was found in Ana's nose.
(speaking Spanish)
Tire treads.
Looks like they came to a stop
right here.
SILVA:
18-wheeler.
Javier, there's flakes of blood
in these treads.
The truck drove through
the blood from the massacre.
(gunfire)
That's what I'm thinking.
(policemen speaking Spanish)
Who the hell is that?
¿Quien es ese, señor?
Be ready.
(gun clicks)
(speaking Spanish)
What was that?
Said he heard
we were investigating
an overdosed American girl,
so why the hell are we poking
around the blood of the cartel?
Right.
You know,
the way the blood
is flaked in these treads
tells me this blood pool
was dry when the truck drove
through it,
and that was at least
a couple hours
after the massacre.
It stopped right there,
and it dumped Ana's body
right over there.
Fascinating.
Can we get the hell out of here?
Yeah, let's go.
♪ ♪
Hey.
Just finished processing
the concrete couple's
clothes.
That was kind of a sexy little
dress she had on there.
Nice shoes, too,
although the, uh, soles had
speckles of paint on them.
Well, I have
a bullet and I have a gun,
but I have no way
to fire it
to make a comparison,
because the gun barrel
is split like a banana peel.
The expansive mortar got in it.
Yeah.
So I've tried
something different.
I've Microsiled
the inside
of the barrel.
That works?
Yes, it does.
It's a match.
We've got our murder weapon.
The killer left it
in the vic's hand.
Oh, I also found
an errant hair
in the cement.
Henry ran DNA on it.
Did not match either one
of our victims, so...
hopefully could
be the killer's.
I can smell the health code
violations in that place
from here, Doc.
ROBBINS:
Hodges...
Promise me I can't get a staph
infection through the Internet.
Hodges, the tox reports, please.
Right. I ran a full drug screen
on the sample of heart blood
you sent.
Ana Ortiz was completely clean.
ROBBINS:
Well, that makes
no sense.
Cocaine was collected
from inside her nostrils.
Well, then she
must have exercised
remarkable nasal restraint.
Don't know what else
I can tell you.
Oh, yeah...
Hmm.
Definitely see some mold spores
up in that corner
of the ceiling over there.
Hodges, uh, we're
starting to lose connection.
Thank you, Hodges.
Whoa, wait a...
(sighs) Uh, Dr. Blanco, may I
use one of your microscopes?
Should I check it for
health code violations?
That man is a hypochondriac
and a lunatic, and I apologize.
Thank you.
So what are
you thinking?
Now, with a drug overdose
eliminated,
other explanation
for Ana's symptoms is poisoning.
Look at that.
BLANCO:
Alternating dark bands
near the root.
Heavy metal poisoning?
Certainly appears
that way.
Seen my share of that.
As a young coroner, this area
was full
of industrial pollution.
Factories were no better
than the cartels.
They left babies
on my table.
Oh, yeah. Mees' lines.
Consistent with
heavy metal poisoning.
It could also explain
the frostbite on her feet.
Toxic metals can cause
peripheral neuropathy,
Yeah.
make one's feet feel
like they're burning.
She may have been icing them.
So the question is,
how was she poisoned
and why did she end up
at that massacre site?
She was dumped there
by a semi truck,
hours after the shooting.
Well, Nick, I'll match
and raise your discovery.
Ana Ortiz didn't have
any drugs in her system.
Not an overdose.
Heavy metal poisoning.
Wait a minute, now.
Then what is this stuff?
I was hoping you'd
figure that out.
Okay.
Is that your water, Doctor?
Doesn't dissolve in water.
Not cocaine.
This is pulverized plastic.
They melt it
down and use it
to make milk jugs,
stuff like that.
So how did it
get on Ana Ortiz?
Any, uh, plastics production
around here?
There's a plant outside of town.
ROBBINS:
Well, the fact that Ana
had it in her nose
and her hair suggests
she was around a lot of it.
Maybe buried in it.
Semi could've come
from that plant.
I got to get out there,
check out those
trucking records.
That plant-- like much
around here-- is infected.
Ties to cartel trafficking
and money laundering.
They're not gonna be happy
to see you there, my friend.
I don't care.
What did I miss?
Hey, grab your stuff.
We're going on
another field trip.
¿Otra vez?
Yippie ki-yay.
SANDERS:
The concrete the killer
poured all over
your wife
and brother's bodies...
we crushed it all up.
Found this hair.
It's yours.
It's my equipment.
The hair must have been
in the mixer from before.
Do you, uh, have
receipts from your trip,
to show that you were
in Bakersfield all night?
You mean for an alibi.
Why the hell would I kill
my own wife and brother?
Your wife was wearing a pretty
revealing outfit when she died.
So?
So... your brother, alone
in the house with your wife.
You head out of town,
come home early,
catch them in the middle
of something.
What kind of slapstick porno
are you living in, pal?
My wife, with Jeff?
My wife had the
house fumigated
after Jeff visited for
Christmas last year.
She looked at him
like he was an ape.
Claire with Jeff?
Not in a million lifetimes.
I'll get you those
receipts from my trip.
But tell me you guys are working
on some real leads, too, right?
That's the plastic company's
trucking records
for the last two weeks.
How'd you
get that?
Slipped some cash
to an office clerk.
I mean, you were
right, Dr. B.
They're into a lot more
than just plastic over there.
A lot of firepower.
I mean, who needs
an M-16 to guard milk jugs,
you know what I mean?
ROBBINS:
So, let's see
who was trucking
pulverized plastics
when Ana Ortiz was dumped.
On the ground.
En el piso.
Get back, get
back, guys.
Somos policía.
¿Qué pasó?
NICK:
What's going on?
(officers yelling in Spanish)
Whoa!
Oh!
Javier Silva.
You're under arrest
for the murder of Ana Ortiz.
¿Qué?
What?
That's crazy, man.
Who-Who sent you guys
down here, huh?
Who told you to come do this?
Hey!
Hey.
It's gonna be
all right, Javier.
STOKES:
Oh, we're all right.
I mean, we're under house ar...
well, morgue arrest.
But we're fine.
BRASS:
Well, I'm here with
representatives
of the State Department.
We're going to extricate you
and the doc ASAP.
But there's a snag.
The Arquero police department
has the two of you
as persons of interest
in the death Ana Ortiz.
You got to be
kidding me. Really?
The investigation obviously
stepped on the wrong
snakeskin boots.
Well, I'm worried about
how they're taking it
out on Agent Silva.
There's no word from
him yet, is there?
Nada. That's a negative.
But hang tight, Nicky.
We'll get you out of there.
Okay.
(phone clicks off)
Well...
How you guys feeling?
Splendid.
I love visitors.
ROBBINS:
Listen, the best way
we can help
Agent Silva...
is to find out exactly
what happened to Ana Ortiz.
The trucking
records.
I'll entertain the company.
You think Ana
came down here,
crossed paths
with the cartel somehow,
and they had one of their
truckers dispose of her body?
Hey, Doc, I'm not so sure that
trouble found her down here.
I think that trouble
found her in Las Vegas.
Take a look at this
trucker, right here.
Now, he's from Arquero,
but he has a regular route
between here and Las Vegas.
He was in Las Vegas
eight days ago.
When Ana went missing.
That's right.
Hey, Jim,
it's Nick again. Listen,
I think I have someone
you guys should look into.
How we doing with
Nick's trucker suspect?
Well, the Vegas plastics
company's been cooperative.
Given us some good information
on Mateo Garcia's truck
and his schedule.
He is on his way
to Las Vegas right now
to pick up his
regular shipment.
Should be in Las
Vegas by breakfast.
And Brass will pick him up.
Okay, thanks.
I really appreciate your
concern, David, but we're fine.
Are you sure?
I-I'll call my dad's
Air Force buddies.
Some of those guys
are crazy enough
to come get you.
I'll take a rain check, okay?
Hey, I, uh... I heard about
the concrete couple.
How did their autopsies go?
You're checking up on my work?
Of course not.
I'm just killing some time.
Oh. Okay, well,
let's take a look.
Nothing surprising on him.
C.O.D. is a gunshot wound
to the temple.
Big exit wound, though.
But with her, things are
a bit more complicated.
That hole in her head
would be my guess.
Thank you, Dr. Blanco.
And you are right.
C.O.D. is the gunshot wound.
But...
there are other factors.
Extensive damage to the liver
and the kidneys.
And, Doc,
I took a look at her hair
and I saw alternating
dark bands.
Check her fingernails, David.
Gotcha.
False nails.
One's missing.
I'll see if I can
scrape off the glue.
Good.
Mees' lines.
Heavy metal poisoning?
(exhales)
Go to the scope.
Get measurements
on the dark bands
in her hair.
Absolutely.
Two bands,
half a millimeter wide.
And a half a millimeter apart.
Poisoned on
alternating days.
Same pattern
as Ana Ortiz.
David, two women
from Vegas
poisoned the same way--
that can't be coincidence.
Doc, you went all
the way down to Mexico
and we're working
on the same case.
BRASS:
So you got her
in your truck,
and you took
her for a ride,
isn't that right, Mateo?
I have no idea
what happened to her.
Well, let me jog
your memory, okay?
You're on a long haul,
you're a lonely guy.
You see a beautiful
girl in Vegas.
You pick her up.
Maybe she'll accompany
you on your trip
to Arquero, right?
No.
We know that you
drove her down there.
But I didn't know.
All right? I loaded
my truck at the Vegas plant.
20 drums of pulverized plastic.
Mm-hmm.
Drove it down
to Arquero.
Okay.
Straight through,
no stops.
When I got there,
I started unloading.
One of the drums felt...
too heavy.
She was inside.
Muerta.
And how did she
end up like that?
Yo no sé.
But I called
the Arquero police.
They wanted nothing to do
with a dead American girl.
So you dumped this
poor girl's body
like a piece of
road trip trash
in a field?
Señor,
I could have made it so that
nobody ever saw her again.
But I wanted the girl,
y su familia,
to get a chance
to get some answers.
So I hear about
the cartel massacre,
and I took the girl
to that field.
And then you told the
coroner he missed one.
Whatever happened
to that poor girl,
it happened up here.
BRODY:
So Brass thinks
that the truck driver
was just an unwitting
transporter of Ana Ortiz's body?
Well, tox says
both Ana and Claire
were poisoned by thallium.
Same pattern of dosing.
So it has to be the
same poison suspect.
Whoever that is must have dumped
Ana Ortiz's body in the barrel
at the Las Vegas
plastics facility.
And then moved on
to their next victim.
All right, so hair analysis
shows that Claire's poisoning
began four days after
Ana's body was dumped.
But before the poison had
the chance to kill Claire,
she was gunned down
along with her Jeff Marsh.
Yeah, I feel like
the killer panicked,
like he couldn't wait
for the poison to do its job.
Ana's disappearance was
getting a lot of attention.
It might have put
pressure on him.
You know, Ana and Claire
have the same killer.
So what else do they
have in common?
Any overlap
in their life could be
where they crossed paths
with their assailant.
Well, Ana's 18,
child of privilege.
Claire is 15 years older,
scraping by
on temp receptionist
jobs around town.
And they lived
in different neighborhoods.
No apparent
family connection.
You guys, tip just
came in from PD.
A friend of Claire's
heard about her murder,
and thought this
could be a lead.
Claire texted her
this photo three days ago.
"Ready for a visit
with my artiste."
Seeing someone
on the side?
Friend said Claire didn't
give her any details,
but, Morgan, you found trace of
paint on Claire's shoes, right?
It could be that Claire
had contact with this artiste
around the time of her death.
Anything that can help solve
Claire's case
can help solve Ana's.
Where was
the photo taken?
Henry just analyzed
the metadata.
Picture was snapped at a house
in Henderson.
Want to check it out?
LVPD!
Elderly homeowner leases out
the guesthouse to a guy.
Uses it as his
studio, pays cash.
All clear.
You got a name?
No, she swears she
wrote it down somewhere.
♪ ♪
Ana Ortiz.
Claire Marsh.
Lifelike.
For the last time.
It's a shame the artist
didn't sign his work.
Didn't leave
any indication of who he is.
You know, Claire was wearing
that dress when she was shot.
Maybe she was here
shortly before, posing.
Whoa.
Got some broken glass.
Red wine with trace
of something in it.
Got some personal letters here.
Green flame.
It's thallium.
He hid the poison in the wine.
SANDERS:
Tastelsess, odorless.
The victims had no idea.
Greg, one of these
is from Ana Ortiz.
"My love,
I can't be yours forever.
"You're capturing me
in your work,
and that will have
to be enough for now."
She was pulling away from him.
But he wasn't going
to let that happen.
He poisoned her to weaken her,
make her sick,
dependent on him so
she couldn't leave,
but he pushed
it too far.
When a sadist kills a plaything,
he needs a replacement.
A new victim to control.
Claire.
Hey.
Claire was missing
an acrylic fingernail.
Here it is.
You know, Ana was
all over the news.
Claire might have
recognized her.
SIDLE:
She was holding
a portrait of Ana...
She looks familiar.
Then the artist yanked it away
from her.
SANDERS:
She realized he was bad news.
SIDLE:
He follows her home
to silence her.
Brother-in-law had the bad luck
of being there.
Claire was gonna be an artist
before we met.
Still had some friends
from back then.
One of the guys--
she used to model for him.
I told her I didn't
want to hear about it.
Well, I want to hear about it.
So, this dude's the killer,
you're saying?
It's just someone
we want to talk to.
What's his name?
I don't remember.
You don't remember?
No!
I wasn't interested
in hearing about some guy,
sat there staring at my wife
with his brush in his hand.
If I knew his name,
I'd tell you.
RUSSELL:
We found some letters
that Ana wrote
that lead us to believe
that the artist who painted this
was in a relationship
with your daughter.
Why would Ana keep
that from me?
Well, I don't know.
I don't know.
Maybe he was an older man.
Somebody who could manipulate
her into keeping a secret.
This is the person
who hurt her.
Yeah, look, there's one
other thing, sir.
My... my CSIs found
a trucking manifest.
Ana's body was found
in a barrel
that belonged to a company
here in Las Vegas.
A Partell Manufacturing.
What?
We checked
the employment records,
and the other victim,
Claire Marsh, worked for Partell
recently for a few days
as a temporary receptionist.
We've also discovered that...
you're on the board
of... of that company.
I hope you're not implying that
I had something to do with it.
Absolutely not.
But the fact that your daughter
and another woman
who was employed by a company
that at least you're involved
with, were both victims...
You know, I was just hoping
you could help us
connect the dots.
That's all.
You know anyone like that?
I mean, who... who would be
capable of such a thing?
Nobody.
So, if we're done...
I think I need
to go rest now.
You can see yourself out.
SIDLE:
Russell?
I checked with Partell
Manufacturing HR,
any chance they have an employee
who also is a known artist.
Turns out they just
commissioned a mural
in their cafeteria.
Artist's name is
Keith Garner.
He worked on it
late at night,
because he's also
got a day job.
Garner's day job is an
art teacher,
Ana Ortiz's high school.
Guess where he taught
15 years ago.
Claire Marsh's high school.
He knew both our victims
as young students.
He also attended Ana's wake.
She will not be forgotten.
He must have bumped into
Claire again at the factory,
and invited her back to
his studio as a kind of--
I don't know--
replacement for Ana.
Brass is on his way
to Garner's residence.
I requested a ping
on his cell
and a broadcast
on his vehicle.
Hey, look at that.
Ping came back on
Garner's cell phone.
Look where he is.
(grunting)
GABRIEL:
I never should have let Ana
convince me to hire you!
(coughing)
I'm so sorry.
That I didn't
protect you, Ana.
(wheezes, coughs)
That I didn't see...
what this son of a bitch
was doing to you!
No! You don't look at her!
She was mine.
I loved her.
I just wanted to keep her.
I just wanted her to need me.
Shut up!
She loved me.
(grunting)
LVPD!
Put the gun down!
Gabriel. All right,
all right, hey.
Just relax. Everybody
just take a second here.
You don't want to do this.
Just put...
put the weapon
down, all right?
He killed her.
He killed my baby girl.
All right, now, hey, hey,
don't do that. No, no.
Don't you dare.
(gun chamber cocking)
All right, everybody relax
just for a second.
He took her from me!
I know, all right, all right.
Just-just listen to me
for one second.
You can still hear
Ana's voice, can't you?
What is she telling you
to do right now?
(crying)
(sobbing)
(groans)
(crying)
He took her.
All right.
Just give me a minute
here, will you?
My daughter.
You did the
right thing.
You did the right thing.
Your daughter would be
proud of you, Gabriel.
(sniffing)
(laughs)
I thought you and Stokes took
the first flight out
this morning.
Oh, we decided to
take a later one.
I went to the police
chief's office,
and I told him how sorry we were
for invading his lovely city
when the real killer was
a homegrown American monster.
(laughs)
You told him that?
Yeah, and
I asked him to release Agent
Silva from jail, and it worked.
Silva's a free man.
Gracias.
Thank you for
everything, Nick.
You, too, Agent Silva.
And, listen, if you're ever
headed Vegas way,
you got to look me up,
all right?
Will do.
Okay.
But keep your crazy gambles to
the casinos for a while, hey?
I'll try.
Vamos.
STOKES:
Hasta luego.
You took a big risk...
sticking around,
going to meet
that police chief. (laughs)
He's a dangerous man.
It was the right thing to do.
Which is something you don't
see too much of around here.
I want you to have these tools.
I realize you have a horrible
amount of use for them.
Gracias.
I really wish
I could do more to help,
but I know
wishing's pretty useless.
It's not useless.
It's faith.
La fe.
(laughs)
We all need faith.
Vaya con dios, amigo.
(laughs)