(intercom chimes)
WOMAN:
Ladies and gentlemen,
as we start
our final descent
into Las Vegas,
please make sure
your tray tables
and seat backs and are in
their full, upright position.
Make sure your seat belts
are securely fastened,
and all carry-on luggage
is stowed underneath the seat
in front of you
or in the overhead bins.
(intercom chimes)
You have a good flight?
You have any idea
how gorgeous you are?
Not interested,
but thanks.
You smell good, too.
You know, I dreamt about
you the whole flight.
X-rated.
Is that your best line?
I thought chicks flying
to Vegas were ready to party.
Sir, I'm gonna need you
to take your seat.
Yeah, I'm gonna
need another one
of those
free drinks, though.
Sorry, sweetie.
Bar's closed.
Oh, wow, it's really
not my night.
(scoffs)
Psst!
Maybe you're not coming on
strong enough.
(laughter)
(intercom dings)
MAN:
This is your captain speaking.
We've just been cleared
to land in Las Vegas,
where the local time is 10:42
and the temperature is
a pleasant 84 degrees.
Cabin crew, please take
your seats for landing.
WOMAN:
On behalf of Pan Transit
and the entire flight crew,
I'd like to thank you
for joining us
and we look forward to seeing
you again in the future.
Have a great night.
A little help?
And good luck!
Which bag is yours?
The yellow one. Thank you.
Hey, look, I-I didn't mean
to come off like a creep before.
I was just trying
to have a good time.
Buy you a drink to apologize?
I don't think so.
Bottle of champagne?
Cut me some slack, baby! Damn!
Hey, what the hell?
Hey, my watch--
where the hell's my watch?
It was in my bag.
Hey, hey! Hold on!
Hold on, all right?
Ain't nobody leaving this plane.
I've been robbed.
Stewardess!
Don't let anybody
off this plane!
Hey, wait, hold on a second.
You-you probably left it in
the bar at the, uh, airport...
Ain't nobody got no time
for your jokes, man, okay?
I'm gonna need some help
finding my watch.
Somebody stole my watch!
MAN: Hey, hey, hey!
What?
My wallet's gone, okay?
Somebody stole my wallet.
(passengers clamoring)
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Somebody definitely
went through my bag!
Who went through my bag?
They stealing on this plane!
Hey!
Come on!
(passengers clamoring)
I got to get off!
Come on, damn it!
Hey, hey! Get back, man!
What the hell's
wrong with you, man?
(passengers clamoring)
You know...
there's something about
being at the airport,
that makes me just want to jump
on the next plane out of here.
Doesn't matter where.
Excitement of the unknown.
No, Sara, I got big plans.
Really?
Yeah, Morocco.
You gonna open a bar
in Casablanca, Nick?
Call me Rick.
(laughs)
I think that was
his name, wasn't it?
(Sidle laughs)
PHILLIPS: Caucasian female,
early 30s.
Blunt force trauma
to the head.
(camera shutter clicking)
STOKES: Well, looks like
she started out on the road.
Skidded through the dirt and...
she came to rest right here.
Long way to roll.
She hit the road
with significant velocity.
It would explain
the road rash...
...and the broken neck.
She's dressed for a good time.
I don't think she found it.
Sara?
"Janet Riggins,
Pan Transit flight 111."
Originated in Newark.
Layover in Atlanta.
Landed here at 10:45 tonight.
Well, that's got
to be some kind of record.
Dead in under an hour.
Welcome to Las Vegas.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
(clamoring)
Everyone, please,
everyone, listen up.
Please, everyone.
Excuse me.
Look, my credit cards
are in my wallet.
My driver's license.
How am I supposed to check
into my hotel, huh?
I understand, sir.
WOMAN:
That pendant was irreplaceable.
Irreplaceable!
My mother gave it to me.
My dead mother.
Now, we want to help you.
But we need your cooperation.
Okay? Police officers are gonna
be taking your statements.
And after that,
you're free to go.
It's a family heirloom.
Do you understand that?
Where am I supposed
to sleep tonight, huh?
Yeah!
All right, look, the airlines,
the airlines are gonna
help those of you
who have to make connections.
And when they can't,
they're gonna
offer you hotel vouchers.
At the cheapest hotel
you can find.
But first,
CSI Finlay and I
need your help to do our job.
Do you remember
a woman who was seated
in row three, seat D.
3D.
Ooh, let me conjure up
the seating plan in my head,
and do your job for you.
Anybody here sit in row two,
three or four?
Okay, some of you men
might've remembered her.
She had long blonde hair,
a white dress, heels.
Yeah, yeah, the blonde with the
ass in the tight, white dress.
Why? Did she steal
my wallet, huh?
I was sitting right behind her.
She was acting very suspicious.
(all clamoring)
The woman
that we are talking about
was just found dead.
(all clamoring)
So that makes this
a homicide investigation.
And you...
are the last people
to see her alive.
Him!
He was harassing her.
She wanted nothing
to do with him.
I was just talking to the lady.
Hater.
Excuse me, sir?
Could you tell me
how you got the black eye?
Yeah, yeah.
He-he didn't have that
on the plane, man.
Hey, you need to mind
your damn business.
Yeah, right.
My watch was in my carry-on
in the overhead bin.
When I realized
it had been stolen...
No one is leaving this plane!
I want to get by here...
Relax, okay?
Somebody stole my watch!
Let me get by!
I hit my head when I fell.
Old guy, he fights dirty.
When I looked up, I saw
the blonde pushing her way out.
And that was
the last time I saw her.
Can anyone else confirm
that story?
Yeah, the old guy had
some fight left in him.
I don't know
about all that,
all I know is the blonde
wanted off the plane.
Am I right? Right?
We all saw that.
(passengers clamoring)
The airline confirms
Janet Riggins' flight
landed on time.
Gate F24.
F Gate means she had to take
the tram to baggage claim,
pick up her checked bags.
Well, she ended up here.
She had to have
left the airport.
Road leads
directly there.
Yeah, but there's
a big convention in town.
Long lines for taxis,
rental cars,
shuttle buses.
She'd still be waiting in line.
She could've walked.
Right, maybe in your shoes.
But not in those heels.
(chuckles)
So... somebody
picked her up
and gave her one hell of a ride.
(screams)
(car tires screeching)
I think she left
the vehicle at this swerve mark.
Right here.
SIDLE:
Distance from there
to where she came to rest
is 75 feet, so...
30 is the constant,
multiplied
by 75 feet,
times the coefficient
of friction
for sliding...
On this terrain,
I'd give it a...
a one.
One? Lucky guess.
2,250 feet.
Square root of that.
Vehicle was traveling
about 45 miles an hour.
You physics majors, you're...
you're show-offs.
So the driver
never hit the brakes.
This was no accident.
And either she jumped out
or was thrown out.
Her luggage could
still be in the car.
If we're lucky, maybe the driver
threw it out with her.
Nick, down!
Laser...
pointed right at your chest.
You see anything?
There. Right there.
Hey! Las Vegas Police.
No, no, no!
No, no, no, no, no, no.
I got him, I got him,
get this other guy!
Stay down! Keep your hands where
I can see them! Don't move!
What are you doing?
(laughing)
(grunts)
What the hell are you doing?!
Watching some planes, man.
Huh?
Don't point that thing at me!
Chill! All right?
We're just having a little fun.
Hey, I got the other one!
You know
that flashing pilots
with your little laser's
a felony?
You're interfering
with federal air operations.
There was a murder
out here tonight.
Did you and your buddy
see anything?
(scoffs)
We'll find out.
(camera shutter clicks)
I hear you and Nick collared
a couple of would-be
terrorists tonight.
Yeah.
Yeah, Nick threatened to bring
the FBI down on them
unless they turn over
their laser pointers.
And then he called
their parents.
Who, I'm sure,
were very proud.
So, where are we
with our victim?
Well, Mr. Scare 'Em
Straight and I found
the victim's carry-on bag down
the road from the crime scene.
There's not much to go on,
but she is a local.
Found a Nevada license.
"Janet Riggins.
1432 Desert Vista."
I'll have Brass look at this.
Can I see your license
for a second?
Sure.
Look at your photo.
Uh-huh, when it's backlit,
you can see the perforated
outline of Nevada.
Right.
Janet's...
...not so much.
So...
why does Ms. Riggins
need a fake I.D.?
BRASS: Here's some
video surveillance
from outside
the baggage claim.
That's the victim, right?
Janet Riggins?
If that's even
her real name, yeah.
Sure is looking over
her shoulder a lot.
And what's she doing
leaving baggage claim
with no checked bags?
She didn't stick around
to claim 'em.
And the reason she didn't
stick around is...
...Kenny Greene.
He was a passenger
on her flight.
He had his
watch stolen.
He told me
the last time
he saw our victim
was on the plane.
That's a lie.
Yeah, and not
only that,
when I met him,
he had a fresh black eye.
He told me
that he got it
when a fellow passenger
banged his head on an armrest.
Well, if he got it on the plane,
then we should
see it right here.
You think she gave it to him?
I like to keep things simple
in the beginning.
He ended up
with a shiner;
she ended up dead.
(exhales)
My man!
Any luck with that watch?
Wow, the party never stops
for you, does it?
Have you slept since the
last time I talked to you?
You ever been to
Combustion Junction?
(chuckles)
My lap is still achin'.
It's open 24/7.
You want to tell me again
about that black eye?
Okay. Busted.
I didn't get it
on the plane.
No, you got it when
you beat up Janet Riggins.
No, no, no,
no, no, no, no.
Then how'd she
end up dead?
I ran into the blonde
at baggage claim.
Look, I just figured
it was the Vegas gods
giving me another
crack at it.
I bet you're
really tight with all
the Vegas deities.
You know, me?
I'm tight with Father Time.
You know,
like time code.
See, the time this
picture was taken
and the time you
showed up at the gate...
that was two hours
of free time.
She was hot, man!
I was looking to score.
You can't arrest
a guy for trying.
But when she saw me,
she ran.
And that's when I knew
she stole my watch.
Only the guilty run.
Hey, babe?
Yeah.
You got something
that belongs to me.
You want your phone,
give me back my watch.
Hey, that's assault!
Look, I didn't
see that coming.
All right?
But that was the last
time I saw her.
I spent the rest
of my "free time"
at the airport bar,
waiting on you guys
to show up.
Hey, if you don't believe me,
just ask the bartender.
She gave me her number.
Let's say
I believe you, okay?
Do you still have Janet
Riggins' cell phone?
Oh...
You stole her phone?
Oh, no, no, no.
No, no.
I was bargaining.
I'm bargaining, too.
So what do I get
if I charge you
with robbery and
strong-arm assault?
I can't catch a break.
STOKES:
Hey.
Any luck
I.D.'ing my victim?
Well, she's got
a burner phone.
You can get
one of those
at any corner store
or gas station.
Yeah.
Burner phone,
fake I.D....
She sure is going to a lot
of trouble to stay anonymous.
Well, if I were to pull
a mid-air caper,
I'd fly under
an alias, too.
She's got
a Vegas number.
Chances are
she bought it local.
(chuckles)
Disregarding all the calls
her drunken assailant made
to various call girls
and phone sex
operators last night...
Nice.
HODGES:
...got one text,
outgoing
at 10:48 p.m.
to a local number.
"Landed."
No registered owner.
Another burner.
I'll get an AG Waiver
for the detail records.
Maybe she texted
her ride.
Or getaway driver.
Mmm.
Also, she made
one phone call,
13 minutes later,
at 11:01,
to a different
local number.
Nalley Janitorial
Services.
North
Las Vegas.
Maybe she needed someone
to clean up her mess.
Jefferson Nalley?
Yeah, uh... you must be
the guys that called.
Yeah, I'm
Nick Stokes.
This is
Sara Sidle.
We're with
the crime scene unit.
Need you to take
a look at a photo,
if you don't mind.
That's all?
Yeah. Sure.
Know this woman?
No, no, never seen
her before.
SARA: Then why'd she
call you last night,
right before
she was murdered?
Want to take
another look?
It kind of looks like
Helen Morrison.
Helen Morrison?
Yeah.
God, I haven't seen her
since high school.
She went blonde.
What high school?
Uh, Hardison High.
Back in Hoboken.
Yeah, Helen and I
grew up together.
Wait, did you just say
that she was murdered?
You moved out here together?
No, no, I...
I-I came out here
for college.
The last I heard from Helen,
she was living in...
Saddle River.
So you have
kept in touch?
Well, no.
I mean, not really.
We-we reconnected online
about six months ago.
Did you know
she was in Vegas?
I knew that she was
planning a trip out west,
and maybe swinging
through Vegas...
And you two were gonna hook up,
is that the deal?
Look, I can button
up that van,
tow it downtown,
and we can talk down there.
I don't care.
After Helen found
me online, okay,
she-she never mentioned
that she was married.
And then a couple
months later,
she let it slip.
Look, I don't
mess around
with married chicks anymore.
There's too many
complications.
You know what I mean.
I cut it off.
Then why was she calling you?
I don't know.
Look, I-I'd love
to help you guys out,
but I've got my
hands full right now.
Half my crew just
quit on me, so...
You know what?
Las night, I sent her call
through to voicemail.
So... I mean,
knock yourself out.
HELEN (on voicemail):
Jeff, I know I'm not supposed
to contact you,
but I need help.
I don't know who else to ask.
Just call me back.
(phone beeps)
Some friend.
Like I said, I cut it off.
Well, it's not
my problem.
You know what?
I bet you guys need some cleanup
every once in a while.
I sure would love
the opportunity.
Yeah, I'd love to help,
but my hands are full.
♪ ♪
FINLAY: According to
the flight manifest,
Helen Morrison was
the last passenger
to board Flight 111.
She sat here,
in 3-D.
Flight attendant said
that her carry-on
did not fit underneath
the seat in front of her,
the overhead bin
was full...
I'm going to have
to take your bag, sweetie.
I'd really prefer
to keep it down here.
I got it, I got it.
I prefer to have
it here.
Thanks. I'll put it here.
She stowed it here,
two rows back.
The open bins are
the ones that were robbed?
Yes, there were
12 passengers
who filed
police reports.
These are the four
targeted bins.
And in each one
of these bins
there was at least one bag
that was at some
distance from its owner.
Well, that makes sense, because
it's pretty risky to be rifling
through someone's bag
when the owner is sitting
right beneath it.
Rule number one of
the professional thief:
board the plane early.
Find a seat with a view.
And I don't mean
a view outside.
Our crook,
in order to get a view
of the targeted bins,
had to have sat
aft of row eight.
And he didn't want
to sit so far back
in the plane
that he was on
the flight attendant's lap.
And we have to presume
that our suspect
boarded in
the first wave.
So that definitely rules out
Helen Morrison as our thief.
She boarded last,
sat forward of
the targeted bins,
so she wouldn't have
been able to have eyes on.
To get eyes on
and good visibility,
an aisle seat
is the best seat.
So that leaves
us with...
...eight suspects.
Who boarded early?
9-C.
Hank Kasserman boarded
with the first group.
"Families with children
and those needing assistance."
You think a senior citizen
would qualify for that?
Because I spoke with
another passenger...
his name is Kenny Greene.
He had his watch stolen.
Now, he told me
he had an altercation
with, quote,
"an elderly gentleman"
who was in a real hurry
to get off the plane.
Hank Kasserman,
you've been upgraded
to our number one suspect.
Hey, Hank,
sit down, please.
Wow, you know, Hank,
you know, you got
almost enough
frequent flyer miles
for a free room at
the Grey Bar Motel.
That's the minimum security
prison in Indian Springs.
I was thinking of,
um, saving my miles
for a trip to Algeria.
That's good.
There's no extradition.
You know, more than a few
of your recent trips
have coincided with
in-flight thefts.
That's why I got
a brand-new bag.
Tamper-proof zipper
and an extra lock.
You know,
these days you can't
trust anyone, right?
They're awful.
And, by the way,
I like watches.
That's a nice watch
you're wearing.
Oh. Well, you see, it's new.
Now, if I flipped
it over,
I wouldn't see an engraving,
"Cristal Kenny"
on the back, would I?
Oh, yeah.
Kenny is my father.
Big drinker.
Yeah, you're very quick
for an old guy, I gotta tell ya.
You're pretty slow
for a young guy.
All right, let me show you
something.
Here's a list of
the things
that were stolen
from Flight 111.
And this is a list
of the items that were recovered
from your hotel suite.
Mm-hmm.
It's an exact match.
No!
I hear you had a big night
at the casino last night.
I was up, then I was down,
and I was up.
Yeah, well,
now you're down again, Hank,
'cause you're with me;
you're in the police station.
I've got you on
12 counts of grand larceny.
So how far are you gonna fall?
What do you want to know?
You walked in the Mediterranean
casino last night
with a very big wedge of cash--
tell me about it.
It's a score of a lifetime.
There was a woman
on the plane.
Blonde and in 3-D.
Clocked her the moment
she walked on the plane.
Very well-dressed.
And she was wearing expensive
shoes, expensive clothes.
She had a designer carry-on.
She was very reluctant
to let the flight attendant
put it in the bin
a few rows back.
Please... please,
just this once, please...
Can you just...?
Okay. Right there.
So she put it two rows back
right over Cristal Kenny's seat.
He was three sheets to the wind.
And I sent him the fourth.
I'd like to buy my friend
in 5-D a drink.
I needed him passed out.
Passengers who are sleeping
or, uh, reading
or, uh, watching a movie,
they're easy marks.
Oh, you're a real student
of human nature, Hank.
When I'm working, I don't leave
anything to chance.
When I'm playing...
I'm all on black.
What did you steal
from the blonde?
Chick like that, I expected
you know, diamonds,
uh, jewelry.
But.. I hit the mother lode.
30 G's.
Is this the blonde?
Well, I had nothing
to do with that.
Hank, it's time
to go all in now.
All on the black.
Okay.
Let me tell you what I saw.
A woman of means
traveling alone.
She knew how to handle
that drunk.
Never closed her eyes.
And kept,
kept putting makeup on.
Especially over here.
She was trying
to hide a, a bruise.
Now she's dead?
You should be looking
for that guy
that used her as a punching bag.
Not some senior citizen
on a fixed income.
SANDERS:
Hey, Doc.
Heard you got a C.O.D.
I do.
Atlanto-occipital dislocation
due to being thrown
from a moving vehicle.
But that's the least
troubling thing I found.
Ms. Morrison was married.
Yeah. Brass is tracking down
her husband.
She has multiple perimortem
fractures consistent with
falling from a moving vehicle,
but these bony calluses
indicate healed fractures.
This ulna fracture here
is typically the result
of a direct blow while
the arm's in self-defense.
No... No!
Ms. Morrison has also has
several broken ribs.
Two ribs, two separate events.
Left number five, judging
by the size of the callus,
is about six months old.
Break to left number six,
Callus is larger,
but not fully formed.
That's a recent injury,
only a few weeks.
It looks like he gave her
a black eye, too.
Yeah, it was hidden
under her makeup.
That's only a few days old.
Well, the old man
on the plane was right.
She's been physically abused.
Yeah. Given the number
of healed fractures,
it's been going on for years.
Yeah, I heard the airline
finally located
Helen Morrison's
checked luggage.
And not what you
usually pack
for a weekend
in Vegas:
childhood photos,
teddy bear...
her bronzed baby shoes.
No, that's what you pack when
you're never going home again.
She was definitely leaving
her husband.
New identity,
new cell phone.
$30,000 in cash.
She had a plan.
Saddle River PD
just called.
Helen Morrison's
husband was not home.
Evidently,
he caught a flight to Vegas.
So, the woman he's been using
as a punching bag
finally left him,
and he followed her.
Do we know what time
his flight got in?
Yeah.
Morrison caught a nonstop.
Helen's flight had a layover.
So that put him in about
15 minutes before her.
Well, that give him motive
and opportunity.
(phone ringing)
Yep. Hold on a sec.
Doc Robbins says that
out concerned husband
is in Autopsy as we speak.
What the hell's he doing
down there?
No idea.
MAN:
Look, Doctor, I know
you've got your rules,
but we're talking about my wife!
The cops just told me
that she was dead.
I have a right to say good-bye.
Look, her body's already
been identified.
There's no reason
for you to be here.
No reason?
A mortuary can
provide the final viewing.
The final view...?
Hey!
What are you talking about?
I'm not your wife!
Hey, hey, hey! Mr. Morrison,
what are you doing?
Sorry. I just got
a little worked up.
All right,
I'm Nick Stokes.
I'm the one handling
your wife's murder, okay?
Did you catch the bastard
who did it yet?
I will.
Well, what's that
supposed to mean?
That the, that the husband
is always the first suspect?
There's a good reason for that.
Listen, my wife and I had
a very physical relationship.
Oh, we know. Bodies don't lie.
What's this say?!
She liked to test me.
She liked to make me
feel jealous.
She would leave little bread
crumbs all over the place.
Like a few months ago when
she left her e-mail open
so that I could read
a little exchange
between her
and an old flame.
That's why
you broke her arm.
Would you shut up?
There were pictures,
explicit pictures.
So when I confronted her,
she denied it.
Which is another game
she likes to play.
But yesterday,
Helen crossed the line.
I get a call from my bank
which says that she withdrew
all of our money.
All of my money.
So I go home,
and she's gone.
And you took
the next flight out.
So you'd be here
when she landed.
Yes, that's right, Sherlock.
I figured she would run
to her boyfriend.
But my plane was delayed.
A mechanical error.
And I didn't get in
until after midnight.
Which is probably better.
Saved me a life sentence.
Oh, we'll check
with the airlines.
Okay, fine, do that, Doctor!
Check the airlines!
But I'm not leaving here until
I see my wife's dead body.
And I want my money back.
Now, tell me about
this boyfriend.
Does he have a name?
He has this little
housecleaning business,
the little schmuck.
His name is Jefferson.
When that psychotic husband
of hers found out
that we'd been chatting online,
he put her in the hospital.
If you're looking
for who killed her,
you should look at him.
That guy is dangerous.
He's a control freak.
He monitored all
of her phone calls,
all of her e-mails.
He kept track of every nickel
that she spent.
Now, look, I-I know you think
that I am a real S.O.B., but...
Maybe if you'd
helped her,
answered her call,
she'd still be alive.
I did help her.
When I found out
that Allen had been
hitting her,
how many times he put her
in the hospital,
I begged her
to leave him.
I set her up with this guy.
I-I met him in a bar
a while back.
And for a price,
he could make anybody disappear.
This guy have a name?
He went by "The Wolf."
The Wolf?
He was like
a private witness
relocation program.
And I, I arranged
the-the introduction.
Did he pick her up
at the airport?
See, that's just the thing.
I don't know. I-I'm not sure.
See, he had these rules,
nonnegotiable rules.
And Helen and I, we were to cut
off all communication
with each other for at least
six months, maybe more.
And we weren't supposed
to trust calls
or e-mails from each other
because they could've
been a trap.
And we could have ended up hurt
or... or dead.
Helen was beaten
last night, and then she was
pushed from a moving vehicle.
Do you think that
The Wolf killed her?
How do I get a hold of him?
Well, I, uh... I have
a cell phone number for him.
I-I don't know
if it's still good.
SIDLE:
It's the phone number that
Helen texted when she landed.
According to the boyfriend,
it was payment on arrival.
The Wolf had paid
for her plane ticket,
her fake I.D.,
her cell phone,
and any other arrangements that
he'd made for her future.
But after she was robbed,
she had no money to pay him.
Probably why she ignored
The Wolf's instructions
and called the boyfriend.
But he didn't answer.
She really had no choice.
She had to stick to the plan.
Well, he left a trail, so...
let's track down this wolf.
♪ ♪
SANDERS:
Brass and I checked out the bar
where the vic's boyfriend
says he met The Wolf.
No one there knew him.
Although the sun was still up.
So we'll go back later
and talk to the night crowd.
But I did meet a guy
named "The Goat,"
who says he'll eat
anything for a dollar.
Beard, pierced ear?
Yeah.
I had to get evidence
out of him once.
Gross.
Helen's cell was purchased
at the Silver Wagon
Convenience Store on Flamingo.
No functioning cameras.
Buyer paid all cash.
Her plane ticket was bought
on Boulder Highway
at Truxton Travel.
Let me guess--
cash, no cameras.
You got it.
Thank you.
Any luck?
Uh, Wolf's phone
has gone silent.
No activity since last
night around midnight.
Time of the murder.
Yeah, and his call detail
records have come in.
The phone was activated
ten weeks ago.
Since then, it's been used
around the Greater Vegas area.
90% of all the activity occurred
between 10:00 p.m.
and 6:00 a.m.
Sounds like
our werewolf works nights.
And he definitely has a routine.
Every Monday night,
his phone pings off
of the tower in Henderson.
On Tuesdays he's
in Spring Valley.
Helen's plane ticket
was purchased
in Henderson on a Monday.
And the phone
in Spring Valley on a Tuesday.
Where was The Wolf last night?
On Wednesday he was
just off the Strip
near the airport.
When I was 15,
I tried to make
a fake I.D. using pencil,
chalk and hair spray.
If I had had one that
was this good,
I could've gotten
into any bar I wanted.
When you were 15, you probably
looked more like you were 12.
And not even a letter from your
dad would've gotten you in.
Well, Helen Morrison's
fake license
isn't even a license.
Official DMV licenses
aren't chipped.
And I found
an RFID chip in hers.
Common in security badges
like ours.
So where do you get
one of those?
The county prints ours.
For casinos and large companies,
they make their own.
And there are
a couple dozen businesses
around town that print them.
So the Wolf had access to blank
security cards and a printer.
Not just any printer.
This is a quality print job
from a top-of-the-line
digital printer.
Which narrows it down
to only a dozen facilities.
"Slots of Luck Industries,
Varlos Boulevard."
We have his phone pinging
off the tower
in North Las Vegas.
North Las Vegas means
he was there on Friday.
We were the first company
in Vegas to get the Lazgan.
Better printer means
I can charge more for jobs.
We don't print
driver's licenses.
Yeah, but could you
if you wanted to?
It's against the law.
It's not a trick question.
Is your machine capable
of printing this?
Technically, yes.
I print all our
employee I.D. badges.
So, to make
a driver's license,
it's just a matter
of downloading the template
and uploading a photo.
But it's against the law.
We have reason to believe
that someone printed
this license on that machine.
If it was one of my employees,
that's cause for termination.
How about outside
normal business hours?
Only my security guard
has access.
But George has been
with us forever.
Does he work Friday nights?
Yes.
And the cleaning crew.
They're here every Friday.
Hey, Stokes.
Hooked you up with
some rougher customers.
Oh, yeah.
Scoot over
for me, will you, boys?
Thanks.
What's up?
I'm in a lot of trouble
because of you.
Because of me?
I'm not the one that made
you smoke dope,
get all dumb and endanger
planeloads of people.
My dad took my car away.
Oh.
And that guy said
that I'm looking
at 4,000 hours of
community service.
Could be staring at a felony.
Or you could be sharing
a cell with this fella
right here.
You'd like that,
wouldn't you?
See there? you're
already making friends.
No...
(clears throat)
Now, I can't
really do anything
about your old man,
but I might be able to shave
a few thousand hours
of community service off.
What do I have to do?
Last night,
air traffic control reported
laser hits on inbound
flights at 11:25.
That puts you at the
end of the runway
when my victim was thrown
out of a moving car.
What'd you see?
(laughs)
I don't know.
There was lots of planes.
Uh, a f... a few cars.
Then a-a lot of cops.
You...
were there.
4,000 hours
of community service.
That's like being
busy every weekend
for the next ten years, so...
Come-come on, man,
listen... (groans)
I was really stoned, man.
I mean, help me out, guys--
even when you're really stoned,
you notice if a car's
going too fast.
Or if it's swerving.
A woman's dead.
You realize that, right?
Yeah.
Okay, so think.
If it wasn't a car,
maybe it was something else.
Maybe it was something bigger.
Oh, there-there was this guy.
Um...
a farmer with a pitchfork.
Farmer with a pitchfork
at the end of the tarmac?
Well, no, like, not...
He wasn't a... Why?
You can have a seat right here.
Well, I was...
Why don't you two guys
get to know each other?
Well...
He says there's a farmer
with a pitchfork
at the end of the tarmac?
No... (laughs)
Not a... He's not a real guy.
It was... He was a cartoon.
Okay.
No!
No, it was on...
it was on a side of a van!
It looked like a farmer
with a pitchfork.
Only it was, uh,
it was some moron with a mop.
Moron with a mop?
Yeah.
Was it that moron?
That's him.
BRASS: So, a witness places
your van at the crime scene
at the time
of Helen's murder.
And Truxton Travel
I.D.'d you from a photo.
That's the travel agency
where you bought
a plane ticket for Helen.
And we know that you printed
Helen's fake license
at Slots of Luck
where you used to work
every Friday night.
Yeah, well, I-I was...
I was trying to help her.
I loved Helen.
So you made up some
fake hero named The Wolf?
She was terrified
that her husband
was gonna kill us both.
So, she didn't want me involved.
But I wasn't gonna
turn my back...
You weren't gonna turn
your back on her money.
It wasn't her money.
It was Allen's money.
Yeah, $30,000, right?
Now, was that the amount
that The Wolf told
Helen it would cost
to start her new life?
Or was 30K the number
that Helen said
that she could get her hands on?
It wasn't like that.
She was getting a fresh start.
And, yeah...
I was getting the money,
but I was also getting my girl.
Hey!
What are you doing here?
How did you know I'd be here?
I'm meeting The Wolf.
You can't be here!
Change of plans. Get in.
No, you heard what he said.
We can't be seen together.
It's all right.
He called me. Come on.
Everything is going wrong.
No, Helen, everything's
gonna be fine, all right?
Just get in.
I'm gonna take you
to the motel.
And then I'm gonna bring
The Wolf his money.
I don't have it.
Someone stole it.
Stole it?
In my carry-on, on the plane.
Someone stole it!
No, you don't understand.
The Wolf needs his money.
He can't help you
without the money.
Where is The Wolf?
I need to talk to The Wolf.
BRASS:
So, there was no Wolf.
There was no happy ending.
It was all about the money.
You killed her.
You're as bad as her husband.
Look, you're right.
I-I-I-I was upset
about the money,
and I-I lost my cool.
But I loved Helen.
I-I was planning
a life with her.
And when I told her
that there was no Wolf,
she freaked out.
HELEN:
I trusted you!
How could you do this to me?!
You just wanted the money.
What?
You were never gonna help me.
No, Helen, that is not true.
You told me
to leave my husband.
You told me I would be safe!
Allen's gonna kill me.
Allen's gonna find me
and he's gonna kill me.
No, Helen...
Pull over, stop the car.
No, no!
Stop the car!
No, oh, my God!
Just stop the car!
God! Helen!
Helen!, no!
Stop the car!
No! Oh, my God!
Stop the car and pull over!
Aah!
No, no, stop it!
Get down!
Stop the car!
My God, you're
gonna kill us both!
Let me out! Just let me out!
I need to get out!
Helen! Oh, my God, no!
I need to get...
No!
Let go of me!
Stop it!
(tires screech)
I am done with that.
(both grunting)
No one hits me!
No!
(screams)
Sit down!
(screaming)
Helen!
(Helen screams)
(van tires screeching)
I didn't mean to hurt her.
So you pushed her
out of a van
going 45 miles an hour.
And kept on driving.
I loved her.
SIDLE:
No, you didn't.
If you did, Jefferson,
you would've pulled over.
Call a cab?
Thanks for getting
my money back.
Or what was left of it.
Either way it was
the cheapest divorce I ever had.
(laughs)
You know, you can convince
yourself all day long
that you came down here
chasing after that money.
But we both know the
truth, don't we?
Look, the-the truth is...
is that Helen got
what she deserved.
Really? Okay, um, you know what?
You can take off, bro.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, that's my cab.
No, no, that was your cab.
Hey, what the hell's
going on here?
Get your hands off of me!
I am placing you
under arrest
for felony assault.
And in Nevada, that carries,
what, three to 13?
I never touched her in Nevada.
No, no, I'm not talking
about your ex-wife.
I'm talking
about my medical examiner,
Doc Robbins.
The guy on crutches
that you pushed.
Oh, come on, man!
That's like hitting a cop.
Are you joking?
The judge is gonna
laugh you out of court.
Maybe he will,
maybe he won't,
but it's, like,
4:00 on a Friday afternoon.
Nothing's gonna happen
till Monday morning.
Have a good weekend.