Where's Russell?
He's in layout.
Okay.
What's going on?
Russell?
Russell.
It's Sara.
There's been a shooting.
How bad is it?
I-I don't know.
Her cell phone cut out.
What about Finn?
I can't reach her either.
Listen to me,
I want you to call
the Sheriff's Office
in Larkston.
Find out if they know
anything about the shooting.
(phone keypad blipping)
Go.
Jim, it's DB.
I need a chopper.
[chopper engine roars]
Deputy's dead.
Sheriff's still alive.
STOKES:
Sara.
It's been a rough 48 hours.
You all right?
I'm okay.
Bullet just grazed me.
What about Finn--
do you know where she is?
No, I don't know.
She's not picking up her cell.
What if he went after her?
Well...
we gotta find her.
(panting)
Hey!
Hey! Come on! Stop!
(tires screech)
(engine revving,
tires screeching)
(grunts)
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
Paramedics said
you're good to go.
So, Brass is gonna take
your statement
down in the Sheriff's
Office in Larkston.
Yeah, yeah, I'll go over there
as soon as we find Finn.
No, no, listen
to me, please--
there are gonna be
a lot of questions
about what happened
the last couple of days.
Sara, I need you to talk
to Brass now--please.
Nick and I are
gonna stay here
until we find Finn,
I promise you that.
All right?
Mm-hmm.
Come here.
I'm so glad you're okay.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Uh, who's in charge
here, please?
I...I-I guess
that would be me.
Yeah.
Uh, Maxine Lennox.
Deputy Lennox, I'm CSI
Supervisor Russell.
One of my CSIs is missing.
She was investigating
a case up here.
Her name's
Julie Finlay.
Yes.
I saw her a few hours ago
at the motel.
Lent her my car.
She said she was
following up on a lead.
Did she say where
she was going?
No.
I need you to
put a broadcast out
on your car, right now.
Yes, sir.
Have a seat.
We'll be right with you.
BRASS: I got you this;
I thought you could use it.
Thank you.
How you holding up?
It's been a long couple of days.
Well, uh, I know things might
be a little cloudy for you
right now, but, uh...
You know, we have
to officially
get a statement to know
what happened up here.
I know the drill.
(recorder beeps)
Let's start from
the beginning.
What were you and
CSIs Finlay and Brody
doing here in Larkston?
Larkston was never
part of the plan.
We just wanted to have
a little fun, I mean...
how often do we all
have the weekend off?
Whew! I am gonna go home,
open a bottle of wine
and watch Hepburn
and Tracy movies.
Oh, wish
I could do that.
I've got about a month's
worth of laundry to do.
Ugh.
What are you
up to, Morgan?
Uh, actually,
I am driving to Reno.
My mom got me this gift
certificate for a spa there.
It has all mineral-based
treatments,
so I am getting
the amethyst massage.
It's supposed to calm the nerves
and absorb negative energy.
I could probably use that.
Yeah, me, too.
You guys should join me.
I got a suite.
Got plenty of room.
Oh, I...I mean,
we don't want
to crash your weekend.
Are you kidding?
I would love it.
I hate drinking alone.
Massages, alcohol...
I'm in.
(Finn laughs)
Awesome! Okay...um,
let's go home, change,
and I'll meet you
back here in an hour.
Okay.
BRASS:
But you never made it to Reno.
Why not?
Finn said that
if we took her car,
we could make it there
in half the time.
That turned out to be a mistake.
♪ ♪
♪ You're living in the past ♪
♪ It's a new generation ♪
♪ And I only feel good
when I got no pain ♪
♪ And that's how
I'm gonna stay ♪
♪ And I don't give a damn
'bout my bad reputation ♪
♪ Oh, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no ♪
♪ ♪
MAN:
Yeah, she's a beauty.
You got the 440 in there?
Yeah.
And the four
barrel carb.
(chuckles)
That's a lot of power.
Oh, I think I can handle it.
(wry laugh)
So, Darryl, uh,
what's the bottom line?
Can you fix it?
Uh, yeah, it's just
a broken water pump.
I can replace it
in about an hour.
Now, if, uh...I order
the part tonight,
I should have it
by noon tomorrow.
(groans)
So much for our moonlit
salt scrubs.
I can give you ladies
a lift into Larkston.
We don't have a spa,
but we do have a nice motel.
Plus it's karaoke night
at the Cactus.
Awesome.
(Finn laughs)
BRODY:
Come on.
Have a drink,
some food, it'll be fun.
Try not to look
so happy about it, please.
♪ I want you to come on,
come on ♪
♪ Come on, come on and ♪
♪ Take it, take another little
piece of my heart now, baby ♪
♪ Oh, oh, break it ♪
♪ Break another little piece
of my heart, you know you will ♪
♪ Have another little piece
of my heart now, baby ♪
♪ You know you got it ♪
♪ If it makes you feel good ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, oh ♪
♪ It makes you feel good ♪
(applause, whooping)
Oh, my gosh,
couple shots of tequila
and you turn into
Janis Joplin.
Yeah, I think you
missed your calling.
Like, awesome! Wow!
Thanks.
Yeah, uh, well,
I was a double major
in college.
Chemistry and voice.
Chose chemistry.
But I was the front woman for
a band at The Roxy for a year.
I can't believe we didn't
know this about you.
Speaking of secrets,
I didn't know you were
into mechanics.
Yeah, you and,
um, Darryl...
seem to be enjoying
each other's company tonight
He's very nice.
He's, uh, he's actually smart.
BRODY:
Oh.
(laughs)
He's, uh, he's funny.
Knows a lot about cars.
Oh. It's too bad
he's so unattractive.
(laughs)
This round's on Darryl.
Thank you.
Oh, thank you.
BRODY:
Thank you.
All right, here's
to our girls' weekend.
Yes.
(whooping)
(laughs)
Oh, God. Aah.
Whee.
(Finn laughs)
BRODY: Whoo!
All right, so I'm gonna,
um, go back to the motel.
No, I-I put in
a Beyoncé song,
I want us all to
sing it together.
I'll come with you.
Hey.
No, stay.
Stay, have fun.
Darryl's gonna walk me home.
We need to finish
the conversation.
Uh-huh.
Of course you do.
(Finn laughs)
See you guys later.
Okay. Have fun.
BRODY:
Yeah, right.
Who's Beyoncé?
The stars are really
beautiful out here.
There's so many lights
in Vegas, you know,
you never
get to see them.
Yeah, I guess I don't
really notice them anymore.
Born and raised here.
I guess I kind of
take them for granted.
Was it great growing up here?
Yeah, it was great.
Was it?
It was real great.
Must have been.
Mm-hmm.
(Finlay laughs)
Oh...yeah.
Oops. (chuckles)
You have something
in your pocket.
You mean, um...
You mean this.
Mm-hmm.
You got me.
I'm not really
into married men.
Or liars.
I'm not lying anymore.
You're still married.
Not happily.
Good night.
(grunts quietly)
Night?
You're a little tease,
you know that?
Darryl, don't do this.
Oh, you're not going anywhere.
You think you can
just lead me on
all night and then
just walk away?
Don't do this.
(grunts)
(gasps)
I don't want to hurt you.
But I will.
(grunting)
(panting)
You're dead.
(Sara speaks quietly)
What happened?
Oh, my God,
you're bleeding.
I stabbed him.
BRODY: What are you
talking about?
FINN: He attacked me.
What?
I think he's dead.
Darlene, call the sheriff.
Finn, what happened?
I don't know.
Okay, we got to get you to
a hospital--you need stitches.
I don't want to go
to the hospital.
Where's Darryl?
He's-he's over here.
Show us.
(panting)
His body was right here.
Where'd it go?
How many times
did you stab him?
I stabbed him twice.
What did you do
with the knife?
Uh, I-I-I dropped it
beside the body.
Maybe you didn't kill him, Finn.
Maybe he's not dead.
Did you take
his pulse?
No, no, I wanted to get away.
I-I'm sure he was not moving.
It's okay. All right?
It's gonna be all right.
All right.
They're not flags,
but they'll have to do.
Really hard to tell
how much blood he lost.
It seeped into
the dirt.
There are blood drops moving
away from the blood pool.
Hey, Finn, was Darryl
wearing cowboy boots?
Yeah.
SIDLE:
I got a boot print.
(siren wailing in distance)
and corresponding
blood drops.
He was on his feet
and bleeding.
Ah, I didn't kill him.
He walked away.
SIDLE: There's a second set
of prints, so...
not by himself.
Somebody helped him.
BRODY:
Into a car.
Blood drops end...
where these tire tracks begin.
(siren stops)
What the hell
you girls think
you're doing?
It's all right.
Sheriff, we're law enforcement--
Las Vegas CSIs
Sidle, Finlay and Brody.
Las Vegas Crime Lab?
I didn't call you
to work this scene.
Uh, we're not
working the scene.
Our friend here
was attacked.
I got a phone call
saying you killed him.
Well, the evidence shows
that Darryl is still alive.
Evidence?
Thought you said you weren't
working the scene.
We're not working
the scene.
We just made a couple
of observations.
Uh-huh.
Yeah.
Yeah, I'm making a few
of those myself.
Three girls; been drinking...
one bleeding...
messing around
in a crime scene
you got no business being in.
We're not
messing around.
How do I know
you didn't kill him?
Dumped his body
somewhere.
Now you're tampering
with the evidence.
Mm-hmm.
So he just released you?
No.
No. His deputies
separated Morgan and I,
and, uh, they interrogated us
inside the bar.
What about Finn?
Sheriff put her
under house arrest in the motel.
Finn said that he grilled her
while the local doctor
stitched her up.
So you're saying
the knife...
was Darryl's?
Yes.
How'd it end up
in your hands?
I told you:
He pulled the knife,
he tried to rape me,
I grabbed the knife
and I fought back.
Oh.
Look at these bruises,
Sheriff.
Consistent with
a struggle.
Hmm.
So you stabbed him
in self-defense
and in that few minutes,
while you were inside the bar
telling your friends,
someone took Darryl
and the knife.
Yes.
And he is out there,
and I-I think
you should be out there
looking for him.
Oh, I got deputies
going to his house
and his auto shop.
But, frankly...
(grunts)
you could save us
all a lot of time.
Just tell us the truth.
I am telling you the truth.
I am a CSI, and I deserve
the benefit of the doubt.
I've known Darryl Walsh
for 15 years.
I play poker with him
every other Thursday.
It just doesn't seem
like something he'd do.
Ms. Finlay didn't inflict
these wounds herself.
Come on, Owen,
she's been through enough.
Do you really have to keep her
locked up here like a prisoner?
Until I figure out what
happened to Darryl...
she's not going anywhere.
You do your job, Marty;
I'll do mine.
MARTY:
All done.
You're gonna be just fine.
(voice breaking):
Thanks.
(phone ringing)
Any sign of Finn?
No.
Russell just texted.
They're still following up
on leads.
So, CSI Brody took
photographs of the crime scene
which you believe prove that
Darryl Walsh was still alive.
Now, did you share those
photos with the deputies
who questioned you?
Yes. Of course.
I mean, it wasn't our scene.
We were legally obligated
to turn 'em over.
But Morgan didn't delete them
from her cell phone, did she?
(computer blipping)
(computer beeping)
(auto-dial beeping)
(line ringing)
Hey, Greg.
Hey. That, uh, tire track photo
that you guys sent me from the
crime scene, I ran it through
Treadfind--
tire was manufactured
by Bridgman Wheels in 2008.
What kind of car?
A truck, actually.
Primarily the Ford Ranger
and F-150.
I pulled DMV records.
Sending you a list
of everyone in Larkston
who owns that vehicle.
Pulling it up now. Thank you.
Hey, Sheriff?
Yeah.
According to DMV records,
there's over 30 vehicles
in this town with tires
that match the tracks that
we found at the crime scene.
Well, the last I checked,
you weren't part of
this investigation.
BRODY: Sheriff,
evidence shows
that somebody helped
Darryl Walsh into a truck.
We find the truck,
maybe we find Darryl.
It exonerates CSI Finlay.
You really think
he's still alive?
There were
no drag marks.
Boot prints
and blood drops show
that he was upright and moving
when he got into the truck.
BRODY: You've searched his home,
you've searched his work.
You haven't found him.
This list is the closest thing
we have to a lead.
All we're asking is
that you take a look at it.
Is there anyone
on here that might
put themselves on the line
for Darryl?
(sighs)
All right.
Valerie Irvin, Darryl's wife.
Great. Let's go talk to her.
We can't.
She left for Vegas
this morning.
BRODY:
I'll call Greg right away.
Have him bring her in
for questioning.
You don't seem
too worried
about your husband,
Mrs. Irvin.
I mean, Darryl was stabbed.
Now he's missing.
And you're playing slots
in Vegas.
Oh, he'll turn up.
He always does.
So he's gone missing before?
(wry laugh)
We don't really keep tabs
on each other.
Darryl does his thing.
I do mine.
Uh, last night, after Darryl
was stabbed, back in Larkston,
somebody picked him up
from the motel.
Wasn't me.
I was working all night
at the diner, 6:00 to 6:00.
I drove straight here
after my shift.
Uh, we searched your truck.
Found this...
stuck to the floor mat.
What is that?
SIDLE:
It was a high resin leaf,
along with expanded
clay pebbles.
Marijuana.
I get it--so Darryl was
running a hydroponic
pot-growing operation
under the radar.
Thing about hydroponics--
it requires a lot of energy.
HODGES: I pulled up
the electrical grid
of the town of Larkston.
The blue dots
represent average
household electrical use
per month, about 900 kilowatts.
Well, they're all blue dots.
A grow house would use at least
five times that much power.
Now, step back in time with me
as we follow the "current"
back to the past.
This is a time lapse reversal
of the town's
electrical use
over the past year.
There's your red dot--indicates
usage of over 5,000 kilowatts
a month for
four months.
Goes back to normal for a month
and then spikes again
for another four months.
SANDERS: Typical growth
and harvest cycle
for marijuana.
Four months to grow,
one month to dry.
And only minutes to enjoy it.
So I've heard.
So what is that,
a house?
Well, according to
the satellite image,
it's a dilapidated barn,
registered
to Edith Skinner.
She's 85.
DEPUTY: Think old lady Skinner
has any idea
what Darryl and Val are doing
in her barn?
SHERIFF:
I just talked to her.
Darryl told her he was
storing some cars here.
Put that thing away.
Darryl could be hiding
in here somewhere.
I'm not taking any chances.
Willis, pop the trunk.
He's not the monster
you're making him out to be.
No offense, Sheriff,
but I'm not sure you know Darryl
the way you think you do.
Plates are all
from out of state.
SHERIFF: Well, Darryl could've
bought 'em for spare parts.
Or, in addition
to growing pot,
he's running a chop shop.
No sign of him.
(groans)
Sheriff, Deputy,
take a look at this.
Oh, my God.
You still think
your friend's not a monster?
(camera shutter clicking)
All right. Let's do it.
All right.
Blunt force trauma
to the head and face.
Compound fracture
to the right forearm.
It looks like
she was beaten to death.
When I have to put
on my coroner's hat,
death is usually natural causes
or car accidents.
Don't see violence
like this very often.
Wish we could say
the same.
Yeah.
No identification.
There's a green residue
on the shoes here--hmm.
Didn't come from the car.
Do you mind
if I collect it?
Not at all.
There's no fresh blood.
There's no evidence
that Darryl was here last night.
Wife's alibi checked out.
Val wasn't the one
that picked him up.
Maybe one of his buddies
gave him a ride,
and he's hiding
him somewhere.
Val said that she had no idea
what Darryl was doing up here.
Said that he borrows
her truck all the time.
It could explain
the pebbles and the cannabis.
I'll run the license and
registration on these vehicles.
See if we can figure out
who they belong to.
Thanks.
Uh, Sheriff...
I would really like CSI Finlay
to help us out on the case.
There's no reason
to keep her locked up
in that motel room.
She still stabbed Darryl.
In self defense.
But she had nothing to do
with this crime scene,
and frankly...
we could really use her help.
Fine.
I'll lift the house arrest,
but she's not leaving town.
One more thing...
Anyone ever tell
you you're pushy?
(wry laugh)
I just need DNA samples
from everyone here,
for elimination purposes.
What, you think one of us had
something to do with this?
Just procedure.
BRASS:
Then what happened?
SIDLE:
Morgan took those samples
back to the lab.
What about the body--did
Dr. Kinney do the autopsy?
No. No.
Because of his limited
experience in forensic
pathology,
Morgan took the body
back to Vegas as well.
She handed it off
to David Phillips.
So, let me get
this straight.
Finn, Morgan and Sara go away
for a nice fun weekend,
Finn is then attacked,
accused of murder
and Sara finds a body?
Yeah.
Not the relaxing weekend
they were hoping for.
Hey, David, there's a 419
at the Mediterranean.
I'm on it.
SANDERS:
Pumpkins painted on her nails.
Must've liked Halloween.
That could be
when she went missing.
I'll rehydrate
her fingertip,
see if we can get an I.D.
Based on the temperature
of the building
and the condition
of the body,
I'd say she's been dead
less than a month.
SANDERS:
These look like ligature marks.
Narrow.
Killer must've used
a string to tie her up.
Maybe wire.
Restrained and beaten.
Circular size and
shape tell me
she was hit repeatedly
with a hammer.
Any idea how old she was?
Wisdom teeth are present,
so she's over 18.
And there's something
in her teeth.
Could you hold that?
Looks like a pubic hair.
Suggests sexual activity
close to the time of death.
ROBBINS: Considering that
she was restrained,
I'm betting the sex
wasn't consensual.
I'll collect an SAE kit.
Follicle is still attached.
Should be able to get DNA.
Might help us
identify her killer.
RUSSELL (over phone):
What did you find out?
FINLAY: Victim's name
is Brenda Whittaker.
She is a 23-year-old
from San Diego.
Disappeared four months ago.
Cross-referenced her driver's
license and registration
and prints confirmed it was her.
Held against her will and raped.
Spermatozoa was found in the
oral, anal and vaginal samples
collected from the victim.
Still waiting on the DNA.
Which will prove
Darryl's a murderer.
Can't believe
he's still out there.
Which is why you better
watch your back.
Tell me about the other cars
in the barn.
They belong to two other
missing women.
A 19-year-old college student
from Sedona
and a 28-year-old waitress
from Salt Lake City--
both missing for over a year
and both traveling alone.
Darryl's a mechanic, right?
Yeah, he operates a gas station
and a garage.
So maybe these women had
car trouble, stopped for gas.
Just happened
to be Darryl's type.
He seduced them, abducted them,
raped them,
and probably killed them.
Brenda Whittaker
was the only one found.
Darryl must've dumped the other
bodies someplace else.
(phone buzzing)
Oh, hey. This is Hodges.
I have to go.
Oh, go ahead.
What have you got?
Trace Morgan collected
from the victim's shoes--
Pediastrum boryanum.
Algae?
Specifically green algae
found in fresh water.
I did some checking,
and the nearest large body
of fresh water
is over 150 miles away.
That doesn't make any sense.
RUSSELL:
Finn was here when we spoke
on the phone last night,
so this is the last place
she was seen.
And that was...
a few hours ago.
Well, we know she borrowed
the deputy's car.
Where was she going?
RUSSELL:
She shouldn't have been
going anywhere.
Her laptop's locked.
Any idea what
the password might be?
Um... bloodgirl.
Nope.
Bloodgirl528?
No, sir.
No.
Oh, I know, I know--uh...
Try "Agnes."
Agnes? Who's that?
Crazy aunt she loved.
(Stokes laughs)
Worked. All right.
So, according
to her Web history,
she was looking for fresh
bodies of water in the area.
Did she find any?
No, not according to this.
She wrote the name "Gary"
next to an ad
for the Diamond Cactus
Bar &amp; Grill.
That's the bar they were at
Friday night.
Give them
a little call here.
Uh, hey, there.
Um... is Gary around?
He's on his break?
Okay. Thank you.
He's the bartender.
If I was looking
for information around town,
that'd be the first place
I'd start.
Yeah, let's go talk to him.
Did CSI Finlay ask you anything
about bodies of water?
GARY:
Yeah.
She wanted to know if there were
any lakes or streams nearby
that weren't on a map.
Only thing I could think of
was Stone Rock Lake.
Is that a
man-made lake?
Just a hole
in the ground now.
It dried up years ago.
You know,
the algae would still be there.
How far away is this place?
About 30 miles from here in the
old Stone Rock Lake campground.
Just off Stevenson Highway.
Thanks, Gary.
(sighs)
What do you think?
I'd hate to go running off
in the wrong direction.
Well, I think that
an abandoned campground
would be a great place for
Darryl to hold women hostage.
Be a good place for him
to hide out, too.
Finn's got a two-hour
head start on us.
Let's go find her
before she finds him.
So how'd you end up
in a nasty gunfight?
Deputy Willis said
that he got a tip
that Darryl's car
had been spotted
on the side of the road,
just off the interstate.
So... I went with the sheriff
to check it out.
(sirens wailing)
(sirens stop)
Darryl!
It's Owen!
Get out of the vehicle!
We're armed, Darryl!
Come on, show us your hands!
He's not here.
Is that bus stop still active?
Yes, it is.
SIDLE:
Where does it go?
Reno. But from there,
he could've hopped a plane.
(phone ringing)
He could be
anywhere by now.
Get on the radio
and find out
when the last
bus came through here.
Hey, Henry, what's up?
Are you sure?
Okay. Thanks.
I need a bus schedule from
Larkston to Reno, please.
What the hell are you doing?
Drop your weapons.
Sheriff, step away
from Deputy Willis.
Sheriff...
I'm not going anywhere
until you tell me what
the hell's going on.
Got DNA results
on semen recovered
from the woman's body
in the barn.
There were two male
contributors.
You telling me there
was two men involved
in that woman's death?
Darryl Walsh
and Deputy Simon Willis.
What? That's crazy.
Ms. Sidle, there's got to
be some kind of mistake.
My colleague compared
the samples of the DNA
that I got off of you and your
deputies at the crime scene.
No mistake.
Simon...
did you have anything to do
with that woman's death?
No. Owen, come on,
you know me.
Why don't you...
why don't you put
the gun down,
we'll talk about it.
Okay.
BRASS: You're lucky
it was just a graze.
Yeah.
I managed to get
a call through to Morgan
and...
shortly after that,
help arrived.
You know, you saved
Sheriff Gardner's life.
I got a message that
he's out of surgery.
His version of the
facts matches yours.
So, we're done?
I'll just file a
report with the IAB,
they'll make their
determination,
but I wouldn't sweat it.
Thank you for coming.
You're welcome.
Of course.
Oh, hey, Sara?
Yeah?
Let me know
when you hear about Finn.
I will.
(Stokes cocks gun)
RUSSELL:
Plate's a match.
That's Deputy Lennox's car,
so Finn's got to be
around here.
The keys are in it.
She must've had car trouble.
Hey...
coil wires have been cut.
Darryl wanted to make sure
she couldn't leave.
(closes hood)
Nick... I got blood in the car.
Okay.
Let's go.
(whispers):
Take the right.
Finn?
I got a body
over here, man.
It's Darryl Walsh.
Shot in the chest.
He's dead as a doornail.
All right, so...
Finn's not dead,
then where the hell is she?
Obviously,
this is where...
he kept the girls.
Yeah.
So what do we got here?
(exhales)
Got a fully loaded rape kit.
STOKES:
Three shells.
.380 casing--
same as Finn.
(beeps)
It's her cell phone.
All right, let-let's
figure this out.
STOKES:
Well, for starters,
we got an ax handle
with blood all over it.
RUSSELL:
Rape kit's open.
Her cell phone's
right next to it,
so maybe she was trying
to document the
crime scene, right?
Yeah, he disables her car,
he grabs the handle
on his way back inside,
and just... ambushes her.
And that would
have pissed her off.
Yeah, yeah.
She fought back, for sure.
(Finlay grunting, gasping)
(punch thuds)
(Finlay shouting)
(grunts)
And there's two bullets
in the wall right here.
So she gets off
three shots--
two miss, but that
third one, boy...
(groans)
RUSSELL:
Punched a hole in his chest.
Blood pool is still liquid
around the edges, so...
this couldn't have
happened too long ago.
Car's dead;
she's got to be on foot.
After she makes it
through this mess,
she probably made a beeline
for the road.
I need you to stay here
and process this scene.
Finn shot the guy.
We need to do this right.
I'll go look for her.
Okay.
♪ ♪
Finn?
Hey, hey...
(monitor beeping steadily)
SIDLE:
We're looking for Julie Finlay.
WOMAN: She's right around
the corner.
SIDLE: Russell...
how is she?
They were able
to stop the bleeding.
She has a ruptured spleen,
two broken ribs,
and a concussion.
She's gonna be
okay, though.
Thank God.
The doctors say
that her injuries
are consistent
with being hit by a car.
I was out on that road.
I didn't see
any skid marks.
This was intentional.
Darryl Walsh and Deputy Willis
are both dead.
Who else could be
behind this?
That's what we're
gonna find out.
Why don't you go ahead
and process her and her clothes.
See what we can find.
♪ ♪
SANDERS:
So, these bruise lines
were made by the grill
of the car.
So, this circle, is
that some sort of logo?
I don't know.
Let me see
if I can enhance it.
"MMC"?
What kind of car is that?
That's not a car.
That's a badge of honor.
I-I saw this guy on one of
those antique car shows.
He had this old car,
he drove it for years,
and when he hit
a million miles,
he got an emblem to put
on the grill of his car.
BRODY:
"Million Mile Club."
MMC.
It's very exclusive.
And the town of Larkston
has one member.
Hey, Doc.
(sighs)
Mind if I join you?
(nervous chuckle)
Wh-What's this about?
Well, I saw your car
parked out front.
Looks like it's...
been in an accident.
Now, that'd be a real shame--
you've been driving that car
for a long time.
You got over a million
miles on it.
You even have that
cool grill badge
to prove it.
Love that thing.
It also made quite an
impression on my friend...
when you hit her
with your car.
(engine revving,
tires screeching)
(thudding)
It was an accident.
No, it wasn't.
You tried to kill CSI Finlay
to protect your nasty secret.
What nasty secret?
That you're a part
of Deputy Willis
and Darryl Walsh's
little rape club.
That's not true.
I found evidence you were in
the cabin in Stone Rock Lake.
I was only there
to stitch up Darryl
after CSI Finlay stabbed him.
Deputy Willis forced me.
Did he also force you to
rape Brenda Whittaker?
Come on. I'm a CSI, man,
and a pretty good one.
You don't think I'm gonna find
your dirty, nasty used condoms
in the trash can out front?
DNA was all over them.
(laughs anxiously)
So, I had sex with her.
No. You raped her.
And tying a woman up
against her will, for months,
and raping her over and
over and over again,
and then, you bash her
head in with a hammer,
and you dump her body
in the hood of her car--
mm--I don't think I need
to tell you what that is.
I had nothing to do
with her death.
That was all Darryl
and-and Deputy Willis.
Well, they're gone.
You're the one left
holding the bag now.
So, I know there are at least
two other women missing.
Where are their bodies?
I don't know. I...
Darryl said
they took care of them.
All I did was have sex
with those girls.
I-I never did anything
to hurt them.
What do you think rape is?
Hmm?
You're a sick man, Dr. Kinney.
You need some help.
And now you're under arrest.
LENNOX:
You heard the man.
Come on, let's go.
(monitor beeping steadily)
Oh... (laughs)
RUSSELL:
How you doing?
You all right?
Want some more drugs?
I do like the ones I'm on.
(laughs)
Thought we almost lost you
there for a minute, Jules.
I already started
interviewing replacements.
Yeah? You think you can
get rid of me that easily?
We could always hope.
SIDLE:
Up for more visitors?
Hi.
RUSSELL:
I'll call you tomorrow.
Okay.
So, we never made it
to the spa.
Thought we'd bring it to you.
Thank you.
So what do you want
to do next weekend?