(sizzling)
♪ ♪
This week on Elite Chef,
we are down
to the final four competitors.
Only one of these chefs
will take home
half a million dollars.
Will it be...
Ray, the firefighter
turned chef?
Curtis, Mr. Cordon Bleu?
Or Cici, the private chef
to the stars?
Or Michelle, the talented
hash-slinging single mom?
Chefs, what would you say
is the most indispensable tool
in your kitchen?
That's easy, my knife.
Something even more essential.
My palate.
Very good, Michelle.
Today's advantage round
is a palate test.
Each one of you
gonna sample
one of these four dishes
and identify
the mystery protein.
First chef to do so
will win immunity
for the next round.
Chefs.
Give it a try.
Looks like
some herb-crusted meat.
It's not beef or pork.
It's too chewy.
Strong iron flavor.
Is this made
from liver? Maybe lamb?
That's incorrect.
Lots of Asian spices.
Reminds me of a fish eye soup
I had in Vietnam.
Definitely not a fish eye.
Could be... pig?
Oh, my God,
is that a contact lens?
It's human!
(camera clicking)
(indistinct radio chatter)
It looks human.
But, uh, I can't
say for sure.
You know, they're down
to the final four.
They must shoot this show,
like, six weeks ahead,
because I watched last night,
and there were still
ten contestants.
Can you believe Michelle
is still in the running?
After she served
that undercooked
chicken roulade
to the judges last week?
Didn't realize you guys were
such big fans of the show.
Good-looking people
making great-looking food?
We love this show.
RUSSELL: Well, you're gonna
have to find some other show
to watch until
we figure out
this mystery ingredient.
FINLAY:
It's not caviar.
Definitely human blood.
Oh, brother.
I got it right!
I guessed "human"!
You all heard me say it.
I win immunity.
Oh, come on. That's crap!
MICHELLE: We were
all thinking it.
You just said it first.
Nobody wins this round.
The mystery protein
was supposed to be kangaroo.
It doesn't matter.
I got it right. I win.
RUSSELL:
Ray?
Is that your name? Ray?
Yeah.
What made you think
it was human?
Last time I checked,
animals don't wear contacts.
(chuckles)
But didn't you think
it was a little bit odd
that a show would
cook and serve up
a human being?
Mm-mm. That wouldn't be
the weirdest thing to happen
on a reality show.
WOLFGANG PUCK:
This is an elite
culinary competition,
not Fear Factor.
Somebody must
have sabotaged
these dishes.
RUSSELL:
Maybe they swapped the meat
to give themselves an edge up.
What do you think, Ray?
They don't exactly sell
human body parts
at the grocery store.
No, no. There's only two
ways you get a body:
you steal it
or you kill it.
♪ Who are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
You know, it's gonna be hard
to I.D. our victim.
Once flesh has cooked,
the DNA becomes denatured.
Yeah. There's no way an
entire body was used to make
these four dishes.
So what happened to the
remains of the remains?
That's what I'd
like to know.
So, who's
in charge here?
Right here, sir.
Oh, there you go.
Uh, ma'am?
Sorry. Could we, uh,
talk to you for a second?
Hi. Executive producer,
Nadine Bradley.
Uh, how long is
this going to take?
Because we were right
in the middle of filming.
Ms. Bradley,
you-you called us when you found
human body parts in your food.
We're gonna need to find out
how that happened.
Yeah, well, we're the highest
rated culinary competition show
on air, so any of our rivals
could've pulled a stunt like
this to try and sabotage us.
Or an eliminated contestant.
The prize money is just
the beginning.
Your past winners have gone on
to open their own restaurants,
become celebrity chefs.
A win is worth millions.
I doubt any of them
are involved.
The eliminated contestants
are sequestered
at a nearby hotel--
we don't want viewers
knowing who's
been kicked off.
We're gonna also need to see
your footage from
the last 48 hours.
We have 13 cameras
on this stage,
seven in the house set where
the remaining contestants live.
Are they on all the time?
No.
The cameras on the house set
shut down about 10:00.
That's still over
500 hours of footage.
So, this was a palate test.
The contestants did not
cook the food. Who did?
We have a team
of prep chefs who use
the kitchen set
after-hours.
Clocked out about
9:00 last night.
Went and did an event
at the Palermo,
then came back
at 6:00 this morning.
We're still gonna need
to talk to 'em though.
Who had access
to the kitchen last night?
The contestants
and the entire crew.
(phone ringing)
That's legal.
Sorry.
I have to take this.
Cast and crew?
That is over 100 suspects.
Well...
body was cooked in the kitchen.
Can't believe I just said that.
Start in the kitchen.
♪ ♪
I just found human blood
down that drain.
Hmm. Could be the body
was dismembered here.
Can you hand me
that luminol, please?
Sure.
I'll get the lights.
Thanks.
That's a large volume of blood.
Lights, please.
Means we're not looking
at a stolen body.
We're looking at murder.
Well, the prep chefs left
at 9:00, so the murder must have
happened after that.
You know, these gel mats
can hold an impression
for up to 12 hours.
Very close to
the blood pool.
Maybe we can I.D. the
last person who stepped on it.
Might be our killer.
You've heard how Jesus
turned water into wine.
Now watch in amazement
as I turn blood
into caviar.
You're comparing yourself
to Jesus?
Wow.
First, I take the blood
and add it to a mixture of...
calcium glucocinate
and calcium lactate.
Next, I add xanthan,
a polysaccharide secreted
from the bacterium
Xanthomonas campestris.
Used as a thickening agent
in food and a stabilizing agent
in makeup.
I took chemistry, too.
HODGES: Blend until
thoroughly dissolved.
(chuckles)
I take my handy pipette,
extract some of
the blood mixture
and drop it into the alginate
one drop at a time.
I will pull the sphere
from the alginate,
plunge it into an ice-cold
water bath
and...
buon appetito.
(chuckles)
I'll pass, thanks.
As you can see, molecular
gastronomy requires great skill
and an aptitude for chemistry.
Something not all chefs possess.
RUSSELL:
So we still
don't have a suspect.
No.
But I have a very good idea
who the victim might be.
Graham Deveraux is missing.
Who's that?
One of the founding fathers
of molecular gastronomy.
He has
a Michelin-star restaurant
on the Strip.
He was the guest judge.
Taped an episode
of Elite Chef yesterday.
And then this morning,
did not show up for work.
You think he's the one
in the soup?
Well, he did have
a very big confrontation
with the contestant
who was just eliminated.
I wouldn't feed it to my dog.
And I hate my dog.
WOLFGANG:
This looks like
a big mess on a plate.
No sense of presentation.
The presentation
was flawed,
but I think that it was seasoned
very well.
But you seem to fail
to appreciate there are
other spices than pepper.
I would call you "Chef,"
but that would
demean the entire profession.
(scoffs)
That guy's just mean.
I think he's being honest.
WOLFGANG: Derek, I'm sorry,
but you are not
the Elite Chef.
I believe you have
some passion for food,
and maybe someday you'll have
your own restaurant.
Where he will probably
kill someone
with salmonella poisoning.
Your cooking is horrific,
Mr. Barlow.
Do restaurant patrons
a favor everywhere
and get out
of the food industry.
(bleep)
(grunting)
Call security!
Get him off me!
(bleeping)
(shouting)
You know what? You better
watch your back, Deveraux.
Watch your back.
RUSSELL:
Okay.
That was a threat.
Derek was such
a nice guy on the show,
but I guess even
nice guys have
their breaking point.
(beeping)
Back a bit more.
Keep it coming.
That's great. Perfect. Thanks.
Lucky you managed
to stop the garbage truck
before it made it to the dump.
All the trash collected from
Elite Chef this morning
is still inside.
(whirring)
You talk to the driver?
Yeah, didn't notice
anything suspicious.
With all
that rotting food inside,
hard to tell if there's a body.
This could take a while.
Well, we only
have to go through
the green bags,
'cause those are the ones
that the studio uses.
(gags)
Maggots.
I don't even
notice anymore.
(groans)
Got an arm.
Definitely male.
Mr. Deveraux, I presume.
Hard to say.
Henry wasn't able
to extract a DNA profile
from the blood found
in the kitchen.
Looks like some of the flesh
has been excised.
Probably used to make
that herb-crusted meat.
(groans)
Let's see if we can
find the rest of him.
FINLAY: Those look like
fried mac and cheese balls.
PHILLIPS:
Definitely not mac and cheese.
I think it's something else.
Rocky Mountain Oysters.
Aren't those fried
bull testicles?
Indeed, they are,
and quite delicious.
It's like a light
chicken nugget.
But they're about three
times bigger than this.
This is an orchidometer.
It measures testicle size.
And these are consistent
with that of an adult human.
Guess the killer didn't want
to waste anything.
Ugh. Gross.
Hey, did you ever hear
about that Japanese chef?
He removed his own genitals,
and then served them
at a dinner party
for $250 plate.
Lowballed.
(laughs)
Look at that.
Dark pigmentation
on the chicharone.
Maybe I can reconstitute it.
♪ ♪
(beeping)
That's a tattoo.
Where have I
seen that before?
I would call you chef,
but that would demean
the entire profession.
PHILLIPS:
That's the tattoo,
but that's not Graham Deveraux.
No, that's Derek Barlow.
Who was just eliminated
from the show?
And now eliminated for good.
So, Derek Barlow
is not our killer.
He's our victim.
DNA just confirmed it.
Okay, where's Deveraux?
Still unaccounted for.
Oh. A lot of
killers miss work
the day after
they commit murder.
Anyway, we know that
Deveraux had an altercation
with Barlow yesterday.
Maybe we have
the right players,
just in the wrong roles.
You ask me,
they're both scumbags.
Especially Derek.
I know, as a producer,
I'm supposed to be impartial,
but that guy was a piece
of work.
He did not appear
that way on the show.
He was a great chef,
and I wanted the audience
to root for him,
so I cut out a lot of the stuff
where he was being an ass.
I can show you
the raw footage.
Sure.
(sizzling)
(plate crashes)
What the hell?!
Why don't you pick up
your mess, sweetheart?
You're such an ass!
(laughs)
(sighs)
DEREK:
Mmm!
That is exactly how
I like seeing my ladies
in the kitchen--
on their hands and knees.
Ugh.
That's just the tip
of the iceberg.
He tried to sabotage
all the contestants.
Now this seems personal.
I mean, who would have hated him
enough to want to cook him?
To be honest, I wouldn't
put it past any of them.
Derek tried to sabotage me.
Well, screw him.
(laughing)
I always thought
his cooking was overrated.
He's gone,
and I'm in the final four.
With Derek out of the way,
I really think
I can win this thing.
BRODY:
Greg and I were able to recover
most of Derek Barlow.
ROBBINS:
At least the parts that didn't
make it to the dinner table.
You know, I read somewhere
that the Yanomamo
tribe in the Amazon
consume pieces
of their deceased loved ones
as an act of mourning.
A way of keeping them alive
within them.
Well, I don't think that was
the case with Mr. Barlow here.
Finlay said everyone hated him.
Yes, but at least
the killer was kind enough
to kill Mr. Barlow before
they dismembered and cooked him.
Look at the margins near
the disarticulations.
Skin is blanched.
Orange in color.
Blood wasn't circulating.
May I?
Go ahead.
Looks like he's
had a head injury.
Found that examining
underneath his hairline.
Based on the bruising,
at least 48 hours old.
It's unrelated to his death.
So, what's C.O.D.?
Exsanguination due to multiple
sharp force injuries.
Based on the width
and depth of the wounds,
I'd say the killer used
a single-edged knife
with approximately
a seven-inch blade.
Do you think the killer used
the same knife to dismember him?
No, I don't believe so.
Look at the radius
and ulna here--
not a mark on them.
The flesh was removed
with great skill
and with the proper knife.
A boning knife.
Yeah, something any
professional chef would have.
Now, the stabbing, however,
was less precise.
I noted tool marks on the ribs.
(heart beating)
BRODY: Well, if we can
microsil the tool marks,
we may be able to
indentify the knife
and our killer.
Rod Steward.
I love his music, but what's
he got to do with this?
No, that's Rod Stewart.
This is Rod Steward,
with a "D."
He's a designer of
high-end men's shoes.
Very expensive.
His size-ten loafer
matches an impression
on the gel mat that Finn
found at the crime scene.
Well, that's interesting,
'cause when I was on the set,
I noticed most of the crew
wearing running shoes.
So did a lot
of the contestants.
Well, up-and-coming chefs
don't make a lot of money.
But celebrity chefs do.
Graham Deveraux,
our missing judge.
Not missing anymore.
(groans)
You feeling better?
Oh, just dandy.
Lot of people have been
looking for you.
What can I say?
I'm a popular guy.
You're also the lead suspect
in a homicide investigation.
What are you
talking about?
Derek Barlow,
the contestant
who attacked you--
he was murdered last night.
Oh.
Barlow is dead. Huh.
He was stabbed to death
in the Elite Chef kitchen.
No.
Well, that counts me out.
Judges aren't allowed
in that kitchen.
It's against the rules.
If it's against the rules,
then how do you explain
the fact that we found
an impression of your size ten
Rod Steward loafer
in the kitchen of Elite Chef
right next to where
Derek Barlow was murdered?
(grunting)
Because I was there,
but not with Barlow.
That hot female
contestant--
what was her name?
Uh, Cici? Yeah.
She was showing me
her secret rub recipe.
What time?
I don't know.
Around 6:00, after we
finished filming.
And after
your little hookup,
you arranged for Derek
to meet you in the kitchen
so you could teach him
a little lesson.
Payback for attacking you
on the show.
Derek Barlow
wasn't just murdered.
He was carved up, cooked, and
his blood turned into caviar.
Molecular gastronomy--
which also
happens to be
your area of expertise.
Look,
any idiot can try their hand
at molecular gastronomy
for the bargain price of $59.99.
You just buy a kit online.
Where were you
after 9:00 last night?
Uh, I was in a limo downtown
doing body shots of tequila
off two lovely young ladies.
You can ask them if
you don't believe me.
Their names were
Candy and Brown Sugar.
So, you have something for me?
I found kratom in Derek Barlow's
stomach contents.
It's a leafy herb
from Thailand.
Makes the ingestor
irritable and on edge.
So, Barlow was drugged.
Might explain why he attacked
Graham Deveraux last night.
In high doses, that
herb can be fatal.
So, what if someone
tried to poison him,
but it didn't work,
so the killer had
to stab him instead?
Plausible theory.
Mm-hmm.
Oh, uh, where are you
and Elisabetta registered?
I wanted to make sure that
I got you something you need.
That's very kind of you.
But, honestly,
I have no idea.
Elisabetta is in charge
of all things nuptial.
Really?
All I got to do is get
to the church on time.
That's funny.
I always thought of you as
a detail-oriented kind of guy.
And yet, you're not
even interested
in planning the most
important day of your life?
Well, work keeps me very busy.
Can I give you some advice,
coming from somebody who's been
down the aisle a couple times?
You should, um...
you should get involved.
You should have an opinion.
You know, band, DJ.
Roses, lilies.
I know it may not
seem important,
but if the groom does not
really care about the wedding,
it makes the bride feel like
you don't really care about her.
It's... symbolic.
Analyzed the tool marks
on Barlow's rib cage.
Turns out, he was stabbed
by his own knife.
Guess the, uh, chefs
all have their own
distinct set of knives.
They're all kept
in the kitchen.
Where anyone in the cast
or crew has access.
Doesn't help us narrow down
our list of suspects at all.
But this might.
Curtis LeBlanc,
one of the contestants.
But according
to that, he used
to be Curtis Gant.
It looks like
Mr. Cordon Bleu has a record.
Back in 2001,
he served four years
for possession
with intent to sell.
Didn't the show
do a background check?
Well, according to the
producer, just cursory ones.
Mainly to validate
culinary history.
But if Curtis lied to the show
about his criminal past,
that would be cause
for elimination.
Maybe Barlow found out
about Curtis's secret,
threatened to expose him.
Now that would be
motive for murder.
I perfected my craft in kitchens
all over the world.
It's my time now.
No one's gonna stand in my way.
RUSSELL:
Well, congratulations,
Mr. LeBlanc.
Word on the street is
you're the odds-on favorite
to win Elite Chef.
Not bad for an ex-con
who honed his culinary skills
making vats
of mystery meat stew
in the federal pen.
Of course, you were
Curtis Gant back then.
Look, I-I was, um...
I was a new man
when I got out.
A better man, so...
so I changed my name.
RUSSELL: But you
didn't tell the show.
You actually lied
about your criminal past.
And if they had found out,
you would have been kicked off.
You would have lost your shot
at a half a million dollars.
Only one person on the
show knew your secret.
That was your buddy,
Derek Barlow.
As it turns out,
you guys go way back.
You were frat brothers at
Brassard University in Florida.
Friends ever since.
Even roommates
here on the show.
But, I mean, let's face it.
Half a million dollars--
that could turn even the best
of friends into enemies.
What happened?
Barlow threatened
to expose your secret?
Is that why you killed him?
We know that you tried to
poison him earlier in the day.
We found trace amounts
of the herb kratom
in his stomach contents.
You special-ordered it
from Thailand two weeks ago,
so give me a break.
But that didn't kill him,
so you lured him
into the kitchen
and you stabbed him to death.
CURTIS:
I didn't kill Derek.
I wasn't even in
the kitchen last night.
I didn't stab him and I
wasn't trying to poison him.
I just...
I gave him a little kratom
to-to make him sick,
to throw him
off his game.
Derek was always
better than me...
at everything.
Even on the show, he was
winning every challenge.
I... just needed an edge.
So, after you edged out Derek,
where did you go?
Back to our room.
How long did you stay there?
All night.
Drank till I passed out.
Look, I-I wasn't trying
to get Derek eliminated.
I just wanted to win.
Nice digs
for a reality show.
So Derek Barlow
was killed in the kitchen
sometime between
10:00 and 6:00,
which means Curtis LeBlanc
could have left
this room anytime
during that window
and the cameras
wouldn't have picked him up.
Barlow was stabbed
multiple times, dismembered.
Must have been a lot of blood.
Killer would have definitely
gotten some on him.
Let's see if LeBlanc
took some to go.
♪ ♪
Morgan, look at this.
A fingerprint in blood.
Looks like it might have
been used as a weapon.
Didn't Barlow have a blunt
force trauma to his head?
Two days before
he was killed.
Maybe that's when Barlow
threatened to go
to the executive producers
and tell them about
Curtis's prison time.
They got into a fight.
No, no, no...
Hey, hey.
FINLAY:
Then it got physical.
What are you
gonna do, huh?
BRODY:
After the fight,
Barlow promises
to keep his mouth shut,
but Curtis can't take
the chance,
so two nights later...
(choking)
LeBlanc may have cleaned up
the kitchen, but he left
a mess here.
Could send him right
back to prison.
The alarm clock that we found
under Curtis LeBlanc's bed?
Blood on it belonged to
the victim Derek Barlow.
Was the fingerprint
LeBlanc's?
No, but it did match another
one of the contestants.
Huh, Michelle Rowlands.
She's kind of the underdog
on the show.
She's tough.
Tough enough to
commit murder?
I miss my daughter so much.
Losing is not an option.
Michelle, I'm impressed.
You made it
to the final four
of an elite culinary
competition.
You're a diner chef
from Ohio.
And a woman.
I mean, I worked twice as hard
as the guys to get where I am.
BRODY:
Yeah, I hear
the culinary world can be
a bit of a boys club.
(chuckles)
That's an
understatement.
And Derek Barlow is
their poster boy.
We know that he sabotaged you
more than once.
You must have been
very happy
when Derek was kicked off
the show.
He got what he deserved.
In more ways than one.
We found this alarm clock
in Curtis and Derek's room.
That there is your fingerprint
in Derek's blood.
FINLAY:
What happened, Michelle?
Had you had enough
of his abuse?
Decide to get back at him
for how he treated you?
You obviously got
into an altercation with him
in his room,
and two days later he's dead.
I didn't kill him.
BRODY: You had
motive, opportunity,
and you certainly had
the skill set
to cut him up
and cook him.
It's premeditated murder.
A cou... a couple
nights ago,
Derek invited
me to his room.
Curtis wasn't there.
He said he wanted
to form an alliance.
He gave me a drink.
Tasted like licorice.
There must have been something
in it, because next thing
I knew, I woke up and...
Derek was on top of me.
His hand around my throat.
No, stop, please, stop!
Shut up.
MICHELLE:
I couldn't get him off of me,
so I grabbed the alarm clock
and...
(screams)
...then I got out of there.
Well, how come
you didn't contact
the police, Ms. Rowlands?
It was just the two
of us in there.
It would have been
my word against his.
Besides...
a female chef accusing
a male chef of rape?
I would have never
worked again.
You know, I gave up
everything to be here.
You know, quit my job,
used up my savings.
Weeks away from my daughter.
All of it would have
been for nothing.
(sniffles)
You know, I'm not sorry
Derek is dead.
But I didn't kill him.
SANDERS:
So, this was shot
two days before Derek Barlow
was murdered.
According to
Michelle Rowlands,
the rape happened
just before 10:00 p.m.
If she's telling
the truth.
Well, there she is.
She looks pretty upset.
I'd believe her.
But this does not clear her
of Barlow's murder.
If anything, it gives her
a stronger motive.
Well, she already
hated the guy.
This might have pushed her
over the edge.
Let's look for evidence,
see if we're right.
Whoa, hang on a sec.
Yeah.
That's Barlow's roommate
Curtis LeBlanc,
just minutes after
Michelle left the room.
But she said he wasn't
in the room that night.
Michelle was drugged.
Curtis could have raped her
while she was unconscious,
then been in the bathroom
while Derek had his turn.
These guys are worse
than we thought.
So, this one is called
Tropical Desire.
Yellow butter cake
with Meyer lemon curd
and key lime mouse--
mousse.
Hmm... it's tart.
I thought it was
light and refreshing,
not so sweet.
Well, I mean, if-if you
like it, then we should go
with that one.
We both need to like it.
The wedding cake is like
il simbolo del nostro amore.
In Italy, when the bride
and the groom
feed each other cake,
it tells the world that
they will take care
each other forever.
Can't we tell the
world with a flan?
'Cause I'm-I'm not
a big cake guy.
Wow, those look amazing.
You want to help
us sample some?
We're trying to
make a decision.
Oh, no, no, that's something
that only you two can choose.
So, Elisabetta, is your family
coming over for the wedding?
Of course.
My parents, brothers,
few of my cousins, la mia nonna.
She has a big family.
Oh, must be hard to be
so far away from them.
ELISABETTA:
Ah, yeah.
I miss them so much,
but no, living here--
it's not forever,
solo temporanea.
Temporary?
Uh, uh, what
do you mean?
Of course we will have babies
and we move back to Italy.
HODGES:
Honey, I-I thought
you liked it here.
Las Vegas is
an amazing city,
but it's no place
to raise a family.
Yeah, but listen.
I-I've built a career here.
It's just a job, David.
My father said you can work at
the vineyard with my brothers.
(scoffs)
I'm a highly
trained scientist.
I have helped put serial
killers behind bars,
and y-you want me
to go stomp grapes
for a living?
La Dolce Vita
is not about work.
I'm sorry, we shouldn't
argue in front of you.
It's okay,
a couple needs
to iron out these details
before they go down the aisle.
I wish I had done that
with my first husband.
When we first got together,
it was very romantic--
very much like you two.
Where did you guys meet?
We met
at a forensics seminar.
Ended up ditching,
spent the whole week together,
and then, a month later,
we got engaged.
And then, uh, we got
married and real life
set in, and...
as much as we loved each other,
we were still very,
very different people
with different goals
and different needs and...
Just wasn't meant to be.
(chuckles softly)
I'm thinking, uh, white
chocolate raspberry symphony.
Anybody else?
I'm sorry to have
to tell you that,
in light
of the ongoing investigation,
legal has decided
to shut us down
for the remainder
of the season.
I'm sorry,
you have been
an exceptional crew,
and you will all be paid
for the next
two weeks.
In the meantime, uh,
let's strike the sets
and get rid of
all the perishables.
(indistinct chatter)
I'm so sorry.
(woman screams in distance)
Excuse me.
Excuse me, excuse me.
What's going on?
WOMAN:
Who is it?
SANDERS:
Blunt force trauma to the head.
Makes Curtis LeBlanc the second
chef murdered this week.
Killer competition.
(sniffs)
Smells like soda.
There's some trace
in this wound.
Looks like paper.
Maybe from that label.
Blood, bits of flesh.
Yeah, this could be
our murder weapon.
You know,
Russell and I found evidence
that LeBlanc was in the room
when Michelle Rowlands
was raped.
Yeah, but she never
implicated him,
just Derek Barlow.
Maybe because she wanted
to take care of him herself.
(yells)
Two men involved
with the rape.
Now they're both dead.
Serving up her own justice.
FINLAY:
So, I checked VICAP.
You know, Michelle Rowlands'
rape was very well planned.
On a hunch, I entered some
of the details: two men,
date rape drug
and a trace of licorice.
And I got nothing.
Pretty unusual combination.
But then I thought
there has to be other things
that taste like licorice, right?
Like-like fennel.
Ouzo.
And anise.
And then... I got this hit.
Unsolved case from
over 15 years ago.
College freshman
named Sally Lennon
was raped and murdered
at a Brassard University
music festival.
Traces of GHB
and anise extract.
Barlow and LeBlanc went
to the very same college.
And when LeBlanc was arrested
for drug-dealing,
they found his GHB
in anise extract bottles.
Says here two unidentified
semen donors entered into CODIS.
Did you run that
against Barlow and LeBlanc?
I did.
And?
They matched.
So these two guys
have raped before.
C.O.D. was asphyxiation
due to manual strangulation.
And Sally's body was found
scavenged by animals.
Based on this old case,
Michelle Rowlands is very
lucky to be alive.
Hey, Doc.
Got a C.O.D.
on Mr. LeBlanc?
Not blunt force trauma.
Take a look at
the esophagus here.
You see this swelling?
It's laryngeal edema.
There's also evidence of
eosinophilia in the lungs.
Anaphylaxis.
According to his
medical records,
he had a severe
almond allergy.
Even trace amounts would've
caused his throat to swell shut,
resulting in asphyxiation.
But we know that he was
hit in the head with
a frozen leg of lamb.
Maybe, maybe not.
It's possible
that when Mr. LeBlanc started
losing consciousness
from the anaphylaxis,
he fell, hitting his head
on the leg of lamb.
He had to have known that he was
deathly allergic to almonds.
How did they get
in his system?
I didn't notice
any needle marks
or almonds in the
stomach contents.
Only soda.
Morgan collected a drinking
cup from the crime scene.
Hey-o.
So, uh, I found
trace amounts
of amygdalin and benzaldehyde
in the soda.
BRODY:
Almond extract.
Every single person on that show
knew about LeBlanc's allergy,
including
Michelle Rowlands.
Greg's analyzing
the cup now.
Maybe he can find out
who tampered with it.
Let's hope.
Yeah.
Thanks.
Mmm.
Hey, um...
do you have a second?
Of course.
(sighs)
Do you...
think that I'm making a huge
mistake by marrying Elisabetta?
Uh...
I can't tell you what to do.
But I can tell you that,
whatever you decide,
I'm gonna be here for you.
Uh, um...
I should get back to work.
So, um...
I went to this
wedding last year.
They wrote their own vows,
which was kind of funny.
But the groom...
he said something that just...
man, it stuck with me.
"Never marry the one
"that you think
you can live with.
Marry the one you know
you can't live without."
SANDERS:
I figured out the source
of the almond extract
that killed Curtis LeBlanc.
It wasn't his drink.
It was his straw.
Hidden inside was
a sugar straw laced
with almond extract,
made precisely to fit
inside Curtis LeBlanc's straw.
He would have never noticed it.
So when he took a sip
of the soda,
it passed
through the sugar straw,
picking up trace amounts
of almond extract,
which then entered
into his system.
His throat swelled up.
Good night, Curtis.
But here's the thing:
when rolling sugar,
no matter how careful you are,
it's hard not to leave
an impression.
Tell me you got a print.
Better than that,
I got a match.
Ms. Bradley,
as a producer, I assumed
you worked your way up the ranks
in television, but...
as it turns out, you're
a classically trained chef.
I took courses at the
Culinary Institute of America.
Ah, so you learned, uh,
all about cooking, you know,
from butchering to baking.
Yeah, I've always been
fascinated with how chefs
can make almost anything
out of sugar,
from a sculpture
of a fire-breathing dragon
to something as simple
as a straw
laced with
almond extract.
This is the straw
that killed
Curtis LeBlanc.
And that's your print.
We know you
murdered LeBlanc.
We're pretty sure you
murdered Derek Barlow, too.
What we didn't know was why
until we started digging
into your background and
found out that your maiden name
was Lennon.
Same last name
as a young girl who was raped
and murdered 15 years ago--
Sally Lennon,
your little sister.
And the case
was never solved.
When they found her, she was
wearing my favorite sweater.
She was always
taking my stuff.
It's the only thing
we ever fought about.
(laughs)
The case went cold.
My parents shut down.
They... they couldn't
even mention her name.
Must have helped
that your college buddies,
Derek and Curtis,
were there for you.
You've been friends
with them ever since.
When you found out what
they did to your sister,
you arranged
to get them on the show.
You wanted them
on your turf so that
you could kill them.
No.
I only found out
three days ago.
I was going through raw footage,
and saw Michelle coming out
of Derek and Curtis's room,
half naked, crying.
She told me about the rape.
She'd been drugged,
tasted anise.
Derek's hand was
around her throat.
Sounded just like
what happened to Sally.
So then you confronted Derek.
Oh...
You and Curtis
raped my sister,
strangled her, then dumped her
in the woods like
a piece of trash.
Nadine, Nadine.
You pretended
to be my friend. You...
You knew how hard it was for me
all these years.
I know, I know.
No, no, no. No!
And the whole time,
it was you!
(grunting)
(gasps)
CRAWFORD: I get why
you wanted Derek Barlow dead,
but you didn't just kill him.
You carved him up,
you cooked him.
You served him to people.
My sister was ripped apart
and eaten by animals.
My parents couldn't bring
themselves to identify the body,
so I had to do it.
I have had that image in my head
every day for 15 years.
Derek deserved
everything he got.
And you wanted
to do the same thing to Curtis,
but there were cops everywhere,
so you had to make his death
look like an accident.
I made them pay
for what they did.
And I finally got
justice for my sister.
(sniffles)
Funny thing about Italian ice.
Some scholars believe that
it wasn't invented in Italy.
That it was actually
created in China.
(chuckles)
David...
Elisabetta...
Uh...
Uh, sorry.
You go first.
No, no, you go first.
(sighs)
I've been wanting to talk
to you about something.
And I don't...
know how to say
this, but, um,
lately, I... I've
been feeling that...
David, it's okay.
I know.
I've been feeling the same.
You and I--
we're very different people.
We both like different things.
You're not happy here.
You'll not be happy
in Italy, either.
You'll miss your friends,
you'll miss your work.
(sighs) And if we were truly
meant to be together...
That wouldn't matter.
Unfortunately, it does.
I need to go now.
(sighs)
Yeah.
I will always love you.
Ti amo.
Ciao, David.
I'm sorry.