(dog barking in distance)
(loud, rhythmic swishing)
WOMAN:
We invite the Ritthamels for
wine and they don't show up?
I mean, really,
what's next?
MAN:
Honey...
what's that?
I don't think
that's the Ritthamels.
Mother of...
(squish)
(woman shrieks)
(siren wails)
BRASS:
Male, Caucasian, in his 30s.
And this
is how he rolls.
PHILLIPS:
Volume of blood loss,
lack of visible cardio activity.
He's definitely dead.
Couldn't have
traveled far.
These folks recognize him
as a neighbor?
Yes, Bryce and Bunny.
They never saw him before,
so police officers
are knocking on doors
asking the neighbors if anyone
witnessed his wild ride.
Well, what
do you think, David?
This doesn't look like
the kind of damage you'd get
from just being
tumbled around, does it?
I think you're right.
Severe blunt-force injuries,
primarily to the head and face.
So, obviously a murder.
Have you ever seen
anything like this?
Actually, I have.
It's a human hamster ball,
I believe.
Saw one of these
at the state fair
with Charlie once.
It's airtight, waterproof,
you can roll around in a pool
for five bucks until
you lose your corn dogs.
BRASS:
State fair corn dogs.
That sounds slightly more fun
than this guy's experience.
All right, so we have
to figure out who he is,
where he came from
and what in the spinning world
happened to him.
Our entire crime scene
is inside of this bubble, David,
so I want you to get this back
to the coroner's office, intact.
Seriously?
Y-You want me to put that...
in my van?
That'd be nice.
Have a ball.
(sighs)
♪ Who are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
♪ ♪
Brody.
Heard you guys have a big,
bloody ball of bad to work on.
(chuckles) Well, grave shift
always gets the good ones.
MAN: Glad us swing shift
guys are done.
Heard you got a sexual
assault call, too.
Gonna be a
busy night.
I'll drink my first one
for you, huh?
Mm-hmm.
(laughs)
Let him gloat.
I don't really like anybody
that goes to bed
before sunrise, anyways.
Agreed.
Hey, Morgan?
The sexual assault call.
It's got to be our guy.
Similar victim and location.
Oh.
Oh, sorry.
Dawn. Banks.
Swing shift.
Hi. Seen you around. Greg.
Hi.
Dawn and I worked separate
home invasion rapes last week,
realized we might be
dealing with a serial.
Yeah,
looks like
he might have struck again.
Do, uh, you mind
if I work this one with you?
I don't sleep anyway.
Oh, um, sure.
Great. I can head out
to the scene.
The victim's waiting at PD.
All right,
I'll talk to her.
Okay.
Good luck.
I didn't see him.
I-I didn't hear him.
I didn't know
anything happened
until I woke up.
Tell me what you can
about your night, Amy.
What do you remember
before you went to bed?
I got off work at 8:00.
I'm-I'm a cocktail waitress.
Fell asleep in bed watching TV.
When I woke up,
my head felt all cloudy.
And... I was...
...hurting.
I promise you, Amy,
we're not gonna stop until
we hunt this animal down.
I saw something on the news,
that a girl
got attacked last week
a mile from my place.
Was this the same guy?
BANKS:
I processed Amy's condo.
Point of entry
was the back door.
The intruder used a bump key
to bust open the lock.
Just like the other scenes.
Yeah, I found some rubble,
crushed shells,
just like the last scene.
Confirms it's the same guy.
Yeah. It's just,
this stuff is used to pave
so many driveways around town.
Could have picked
it up anywhere.
Found a few small pebbles
of a different rocky material.
Oh, and fibers from
a chloroform rag.
He knocked Amy out,
just like the others.
And then,
again with the TV.
The rapist turns it on
and leaves it on.
He actually didn't
turn it on at Amy's.
She said she likes to
fall asleep to the news,
so she left it on.
So this time,
there's one less thing
on his sick,
twisted to-do list.
You know them?
Yeah, I-I thought
it was my son, Tyler.
I bought him a jacket
like that last Christmas.
He's 19. He comes home
every couple of weeks.
I try to get him to stay,
but then he wants to use in the
house, and then he's gone and...
He's just out there.
You said you don't sleep.
You worry.
FINLAY:
No I.D. on our victim,
so we're hoping
that the trace
from the outside of the ball
will help us determine its path,
and where it came from
will help us
with who he is.
Well, however bumpy his path,
that's not what killed him.
Intracerebral hemorrhage
from blunt-force trauma
is what bounced him
from this mortal coil.
He was beaten with
some sort of hard implement.
Small striking surface,
semicircular lacerations.
Hmm.
There were marks in his
second skin, as well.
Second skin?
I think I missed
that anatomy class.
The thin vinyl
of the ball was caught
between the weapon
and the victim.
So the victim was
inside the ball,
the assailant
was outside of it.
And the weapon made
distinct tool marks
at the points of impact.
What's the brown trace?
Those are paint flecks.
So, shape of the marks
plus the brown color
could help us
identify the weapon.
Well, at least something good
rolled this victim's way.
Forensic nurse exam
was very helpful.
A swab of Amy Morse's neck
found male DNA
and amylase.
He kissed her.
Yeah. Unfortunately,
there wasn't a hit in CODIS.
But at least now
we have a profile on him.
So, gets us a little closer.
Just not close enough
to stop him.
(indistinct muttering)
You okay there,
Hodges?
You're familiar with
the snowball effect?
A sphere in motion
tumbles along,
picking up mass?
Yeah?
Well, the human
hamster ball effect is worse.
Because it affects me.
To the tune of 37
different plant trace
exemplars,
each of which
I am tasked with identifying.
That sucks.
I like you.
Now, before
this avalanche
came tumbling down on me,
I ran the very reasonable amount
of trace that
you two brought me.
Crushed shell, just like
at the previous scene.
What about the other rubble we
found at the point of entry?
A little more interesting.
"Concrete and
titanium oxide."
Otherwise known
as smog-eating concrete.
A new, unique material
that helps reduce pollution.
The chemical additive
is activated by sunlight
and turns smoggy toxins into
less-harmful compounds
upon contact.
So where in Vegas
can this stuff be found?
It might help us
find our assailant's
point of origin.
It's in limited use nationally.
Haven't had the chance
to determine
if or where
it might be present in Vegas.
I can look into it.
You're busy.
Did I mention
my fondness for you?
I like her.
RUSSELL:
All right, so where are we
on this rape case?
Victimology shows no links
between the three rape victims.
None of them knew each other.
No shared routines.
No overlaps in their lives.
Other than being
this guy's type--
early 20s,
single, brunette,
living alone
in a first-floor condo.
The M.O.'s consistent, right?
I mean, he waits until
they're asleep, uses a bump key
on the back door lock
to gain entry.
Except that
at the first scene,
he passes a wide-open window
he could've used for entry.
He goes into
the victim's bedroom.
Chloroforms her.
Turns on the TV,
leaving it on while
he assaults her.
Actually, Amy already
had her television on,
so he just
left it playing.
RUSSELL:
What if it wasn't a coincidence?
Maybe it's significant.
You get the feeling that
he was more prepared with Amy?
At the first scene,
he overlooked the open window.
Second scene, he woke up a dog
that got the neighbors
all excited.
No missteps at Amy's house, and
he picked the one night a week
that she gets out
of work early.
He might've been
casing her home,
known her habits.
It's more than that.
He knew he was gonna
have to use a bump key
to break into Amy's house.
He knew that she
fell asleep with the TV on.
He re-created those conditions
in the previous
two scenes, because...
the first two rapes
were rehearsals.
Practice runs.
I think Amy Morse was his
intended target the whole time.
BRODY:
It could be anyone, Amy, um...
A customer,
a coworker, a neighbor.
Has anyone given you
unwanted attention?
I thought this was some random
psycho attacking random women.
Why would
I have known him?
We now believe
the rapist
may have targeted
you specifically.
There is someone.
My ex-boyfriend,
Jared... Wallace.
When I broke up with him
a couple months ago,
he turned awful.
Started sending me
these e-mails.
(voice breaking):
When I woke up...
after, I...
I could almost
smell him in the room.
Jared?
But it...
it was so faint, I-I thought
I was imagining it, I...
We're gonna need to get
a DNA sample from Jared.
Do you have anything from
when you guys were dating?
Hairbrush, um,
article of clothing...
I just wanted
to forget him.
Are you even sure
her story's legit?
Amy's a cocktail waitress.
That's kind of how she makes
money--leading guys on.
She takes one home
and if she regrets it,
buff one of the hundred
notches out of the bedpost
but don't call the cops.
Enough, Jared.
He doesn't mean that.
This is just
a stressful situation.
Look, Jared,
we're just going to take
a swab of your DNA,
and then you're
free to go.
Yeah, I don't think so.
It'll only take
a second.
And last a lifetime
in your database.
I said no, and you can't force
me unless you have a warrant.
Mr. Wallace,
as your son's attorney,
perhaps you should advise...
I already told
him no, too.
Wait a minute.
As his attorney, I have
to support his decision.
Well, as his dad,
don't you think
you should tell him
to man the hell up?
Parent protects his kid
no matter what...
disgusting thing
the kid has done.
Dad can't see it.
Little boy who used
to sit on his lap
couldn't be capable
of something so awful.
And if you are
clear-eyed enough
to see what he has done,
what does that say about
how you raised him?
JARED:
Dad, come on,
let's get out of here.
BANKS:
Hey!
You thought
you got whatever you wanted,
including Amy,
and when you lost her,
well...
If we're wrong, prove it.
Are you kidding me?
You raped her, Jared.
(grunts)
MR. WALLACE:
Jared, no, no,
Jared, Jared, Jared.
Jared.
You don't know
who you're messing with.
You were hoping
he would spit at you, right?
Big loogie in the face
would have been nice,
but at least
a good look
in his eyes let me know
we're right about him.
Leave the prop alone.
You guys got something
to show me?
Yes.
(clears throat)
Now, you know
that a rolling stiff gathers
no moss, but it does gather
an exhaustive
assortment of flora.
That is the plant trace that
we took off of the big ball--
Hodges I.D.'d it--
and this is
a landscaping map
that we got
from the subdivision's gardener.
Each blade and bloom
meticulously plotted
and labeled.
RUSSELL:
So you're looking
for one route--
probably downhill--
that makes contact with each
of the plant varieties
until it ends up in our
unfortunate couple's front yard.
Took us 17 hours without a
bathroom break, but we did it.
So we tracked the ball
to its point of origin--
the backyard
of one Zack Fisk.
The human
hamster himself,
rest his cardboard-
chewing soul.
RUSSELL:
Back door's open.
Wide enough for the
hamster ball to roll out.
FINLAY:
Look at these fresh scuffs.
Right height for the ball.
So the ball knocks over
the vase,
spreads water over the carpet,
does a few donuts right here,
and out the door.
That is one hell of a ride
before he even got out
of the house.
He was trying to escape
from whoever was wielding this.
Same shape as the impressions
left in the hamster ball's skin.
Paint must have rubbed off
during the assault.
(grunting)
Texture's not
really conducive
to prints.
Hmm.
Killer might have left
this little bit
of trace behind.
Hey, Jules,
I think I just found
this guy's romper room.
Ugh,
all kinds of freaky fun.
RUSSELL:
Don't suppose
he'll mind us looking
at his computer,
do you?
"ConfinedBliss.com--
a claustrophilia oasis."
I guess
that's the opposite
of claustrophobia, right?
People who get off
on tight spaces.
Zack Fisk
is in every video.
Well, let's go
to the movies.
A ball like this,
with a two-way zipper,
is perfect for solo
or partner play.
When sealed up,
the ball contains
20 minutes' worth of oxygen, so,
in 15 minutes,
the air will be thinning
and my lovely playmate
will be...
in bliss.
Claustrophilia can bring you
to full
sensory nirvana.
The lack of space,
of oxygen makes you
deliciously aware
of every inch
and impulse
of your body.
With the strictest
of boundaries
comes the most exhilarating
liberation.
Speaking of oxygen,
I could use a little.
(sighs)
Since Zack was killed
inside of the ball,
his playmate's
a pretty good suspect, right?
I'll figure out who she is.
(doorbell rings)
I got it.
Hey, Jules.
Yeah?
Package delivered.
Huh, big package shows up
a day after he's murdered.
Could be connected.
What do you think?
Should we open it?
Yeah.
Oh, Lord.
Well, whatever new pervy toys
this guy just ordered,
I think he went
with solid steel.
(Finlay groans)
That is no toy.
No, that's his playmate.
(closes knife)
BRODY:
Dawn, it's Morgan again,
following up on the case.
Uh, I really need
to hear from you.
I'm just hoping
you're, you're okay.
Please call me back.
Bye.
Everything all right?
Oh, uh, Dawn Banks--
she didn't show up
for her shift today.
When's the last time
you talked to her?
Yesterday,
after she got
in the face
of our rape suspect
Jared Wallace.
Well, do you want
to do a welfare check,
swing by her house?
Yeah.
Door's unlocked.
Dawn?
Looks like she left
this place
in a hurry.
Yeah.
She was working.
She got a response
from a smog-eating
concrete company last night.
Rapist tracked
some of that stuff
into the crime scenes, right?
Yeah, and according
to this e-mail,
this stuff only exists on one
half-mile strip of Verdugo Road.
Good lead.
(clattering)
Dawn?
(grunts)
Aah! The hell are you guys
doing here, huh?!
Who are you guys?
We're CSIs.
It's her son.
Tyler?
We work with your mom.
So, when's the last time
you saw her?
Look, I don't know
where she is.
Okay, I haven't
been here in weeks.
I just came to get a bite.
Sure.
If she got fed up with
me, everything else,
ran off to the Bahamas or
something, good for her,
she deserves it.
Other than that, I don't
know what else to tell you.
I'm gonna get out of here,
crash somewhere else.
Uh, Tyler, wait.
I know you have your own life
and everything, but
I know your mom has been
really, really
worried about you.
I think you should stay.
Yeah, I'm sure
she'd be happy to see you.
Look, I'm sorry.
If I see her,
then I'll tell her someone
else is looking out for her.
Thanks.
YEAGER:
Hey, Brody, I heard
you're on the rape case.
Stealing
the glory again?
Day shift doesn't start
for another hour, Yeager.
Go get your
breakfast buffet on.
No.
No carbs
until I make CSI-3.
Bumped into Sidle.
She looped me in
on the rape investigation.
So, what do you have?
Uh, suspect tracked
two different materials
into the scene.
One was, uh, crushed shells
and the other was a
smog-eating concrete,
and I found one location
where both of these
materials exist--
this trailer park.
So you think
the rapist may have
originated from there?
Yeah, but it still
doesn't clear
our prime suspect--
victim's ex
Jared Wallace.
Now, I thought he
was some rich kid,
not some trailer type.
Well, this particular
trailer park has
a lot of drug activity,
and Wallace has an ecstasy
charge on his record.
Okay, so Wallace swings by
to score something
before the rapes.
There's something else.
I think Dawn figured
this out before I did
and now she's missing.
Yeah, I heard--
no-show today.
I've worked with her.
That's not like Dawn.
Case had her amped,
so I'm thinking maybe she
found the same location.
Could be she ran
into our suspect.
This e-mail was the last
thing up on her computer.
Maybe she went
to follow up.
Went to the
trailer park,
and then...
Oh, you think something
happened to her?
I don't know.
All right. I'll drive.
Okay, the manager
did not recognize Dawn
or Jared Wallace,
but he said people
are in and out all hours.
He give you a list
of the residents?
No, he refused.
Suggested we move along.
(laughs)
It's okay.
We can do it another way.
You trying Dawn again?
Yeah.
(distant cell phone ringing)
Morgan.
Try her again.
(distant cell phone ringing)
Nothing here.
This way.
(ringing stops)
Where the hell is she?
Time for the
"postal mortem"?
(Finlay and Robbins
groan quietly)
No I.D. from
prints or DNA.
Well, lividity's fixed.
It indicates her
orientation in the box.
She was upside down.
Hmm. So she was inverted
during transit.
Well, autopsy will
confirm, but I'd venture
positional asphyxia was likely
the cause of death.
Gravity causes the organs
to impede
the diaphragmatic movement.
No movement of the diaphragm,
no breathing, suffocation.
There aren't any wounds
evident on her.
It doesn't appear she
was forced into the box.
That's bizarre.
Well, yes and no.
This woman was
a claustrophiliac.
Which means that
she liked to get off
by getting into
tight spaces.
The babe in the box
is named Melody Davis.
The package was shipped
from her residence
across town 36 hours ago.
I also lifted some
prints from the label.
Match to Zack Fisk.
So Fisk sealed his playmate up
at her house,
mailed her to his house
to have a thrill?
There's a catch.
Melody is married to a
guy named Roy Davis.
Brass is breaking the news
and bringing him in.
Your wife's death
was accidental.
She got into that box
voluntarily--it's part of her...
claustrophilia pursuits
that she indulged in
with her friend Zack Fisk.
But I suspect you knew
all about this, right?
Yes, sir, I did.
I allowed it...
to save my marriage.
She said she
needed her space.
Or... lack of space.
She had met a man online,
but she said it wasn't sex,
it was just... play.
And a couple of hours after
your wife put herself in the box
and mailed herself,
I guess you
got online
and tracked the package
on your home computer?
She had told me
about her shipping
fantasy before.
But I forbid it.
It's far too
dangerous.
But apparently, she
hadn't heeded me.
You saw the package was
delivered to, uh, Zack Fisk,
so you went over there
and confronted
him, huh?
No, sir.
That is not true.
Roy, what, uh, what
line of work you in?
(laughs softly)
I... work on a ranch.
Horses.
Wide-open spaces.
Yeah,
see, that was
a trick question.
We found a kernel
of your special blend
of horse feed.
It was stuck
to the murder weapon.
I mean, you gave this guy
Fisk a lot of leeway
with your own wife,
but he had to push it,
right?
He thought he was safe
in that stupid bubble.
So damn smug.
I told you guys, that's
where I drew the line.
If she gets hurt...
She's on the ride
of her life.
More excitement than
you've ever given her.
And you just
wait until
she arrives,
and I get to tear into
that pretty little package.
(grunting)
(Zach gasping, grunting)
"It was just play,"
she told me.
I'm sorry about
your wife, Roy.
I really am.
Unfortunately,
you're gonna have to share
her love of enclosed spaces.
So, PD towed in Dawn's car.
Found it roadside
in the middle of nowhere.
Searched the immediate area--
nothing unusual,
and no viable prints
on the outside.
Get to the inside yet?
No, not yet.
All right,
I'll take the front.
I got a receipt...
from a truck stop.
1:00 a.m.,
the night she went missing.
30 bucks.
Does it say what she bought?
I've got an evidence bag.
That looks like
a T-shirt.
Dawn might have gone rogue.
You know, stealing a DNA
sample from Jared Wallace
or maybe a suspect
from the trailer park.
(sighs)
The guy could've caught up
with her and...
stopped her.
I think the threat
was closer to home.
Her suspect was her son.
BRASS:
Tyler, your mom's car
was found abandoned
on the highway.
She was working
a serial rape case.
She was transporting
collected evidence in her car.
Now, we think because
of the sequence of events
and the timing of everything
that she identified the suspect,
who tracked her
to the highway location
and confronted her.
Where's my mom?
We pulled your rap sheet.
You're a registered
sex offender.
Yeah, for taking a
leak in an alleyway.
You've been convicted
of burglary.
What does this have
to do with anything?
The rape victim, Amy Morse,
the one whose case
your mom was working on,
you knew her.
You went to Sagebrush
High with her.
Okay.
There's 2,000 kids
at that school!
I don't know her.
Your mom collected
a DNA sample from the rapist.
She also collected
a DNA sample from you.
Right now, the lab
is comparing them.
Look, you got
to get my mom.
Where is she, Tyler?
Where's your mom?
(knock at door)
Captain.
Not now, Officer.
A detective's come from Reno--
you've got to hear this.
Take him out
in the hallway.
How you doing?
Jim Brass.
Inspector Smith.
Reno PD.
I hear that you've been
looking for CSI Dawn Banks.
Yeah, that's right.
She was supposed to be coming
up our way--never showed.
What was she doing
with Reno PD?
She was coming up to identify
her deceased son, Tyler.
(exhales)
That's her son
right there in the hallway.
Okay, let's step back.
Tell me what you know.
Two nights ago, Reno officers
found a deceased male
in a warehouse where homeless
kids were known to squat.
Overdose.
Badly decomposed.
Had a driver's license
identifying him as Tyler Banks.
I called Ms. Banks
to break the news.
She was at a trailer park
working a case.
She was devastated.
(sobbing):
Tyler...
Oh...
Said that she had always feared
a call like this about her son.
She was gonna collect
a DNA exemplar from home
and drive it up,
confirm I.D.
She never showed.
So that's why Dawn Banks was
taking a DNA sample of Tyler.
He wasn't her suspect.
She thought he was dead.
RUSSELL:
Henry ran Tyler's DNA
against the rapist.
He's clear.
Apparently,
Tyler lent
his I.D. to a buddy of his,
a homeless guy
who was heading up to Reno.
So his buddy O.D.'s,
decomposes beyond recognition,
cops go off the I.D.
in his pocket.
All right.
So, let's run this.
You get the call
that your son is dead,
and you pick up
a piece of his laundry
for DNA so you
can I.D. him.
You start driving
up to Reno where the body is.
Right. Except...
the road that her car
ends up on is not
on the way to Reno.
I found a receipt
in Dawn's car from a truck stop,
and the truck stop...
is at the junction
of 95 and 373.
That's when she started
driving south, away from Reno.
So maybe the truck stop
is where she changed her mind,
and her route.
The question is:
Where was she going?
Tyler,
I need to ask you a question.
Is there, um,
any place off
of Highway 373 that
may have meant
something to your mom?
Why?
Your mom thought
you were dead.
Your I.D. was on a young
man who overdosed in Reno.
She was driving out
to identify your body,
and, for some reason,
she changed her mind.
She stopped at a
truck stop, and, uh...
We pulled
the surveillance footage.
It looks like she bought...
vodka and acetaminophen.
S-So she's...
No, no, listen.
W-We don't know that,
but we think that maybe,
if she was going to do
something to herself,
she might have chosen a place
that was significant.
She used to take me
camping out there.
But, I mean,
i-it was forever ago.
Okay, show me.
Show me where.
Good boy.
This favorite spot
Tyler told you about,
are you sure it's this way?
That's what he said.
But he and his mom haven't
been here in several years.
He was a little hazy.
Well, if Dawn's up here,
how many hours has it been?
(dog barking)
Over there. Come on.
(dog sniffing)
(gasps)
Dawn.
She's got a pulse.
Control, this is
Adam-Zero-Four Yeager.
We have CSI Banks. North trail,
about a half-mile in.
Send medics. Code three.
Dawn? Come on.
(sighs)
Dawn,
wake up, please.
Tyler is alive.
He's okay. Come on.
Stay with us, Dawn.
Dawn, help's on the way.
Hey, boss. Got your text.
How's CSI Banks?
Oh, she's in ICU.
Morgan's with her.
Good. Uh, what's up?
We still have
a serial rapist out there
with some kind of connection
to that trailer park.
Right.
Want you to grab
Henry, go out there
and go through all the
trash cans you can find.
If you come up with
any biologicals,
run them against
our rapist's DNA.
We need to find
out if he's still
in one of those
trailers.
All right, I'm on it.
Thank you.
Doing noble work here, ma'am.
Hodges?
Check this out.
So they got
top-of-the-line locks,
security cam. They're treating
a dinged-up trailer
like it's Fort Knox.
Paranoid,
or protecting something?
Couple of wadded-up tissues.
Ooh.
I know what I'm
running first.
DNA matches our rapist.
We've got him.
LVPD!
All clear.
Come on, Henry.
(camera shutter clicks)
Surveillance cam's
not hooked up.
It's just for show.
Young brunettes.
Just like Amy
and the other victims.
ANDREWS:
I got pics of Amy
with Jared Wallace, and, uh,
other mementos.
"Jared, I hope
what we have
will last forever. Amy."
Certainly lasted in his mind.
Guy rents this trailer
to obsess
and prepare
in private.
Becomes his base
when he starts to act out
on his obsession.
Did some acting here, too.
I'll swab.
Heart medication.
ANDREWS:
Swiped Daddy's prescription.
A gray hair.
It's not Jared.
It's Dad.
BRASS:
I guess I can
understand, Mr. Wallace.
This whole event started
innocently at first.
You know, son brings home
his girlfriend to meet Dad.
She's attractive.
Dad likes her.
He notices her.
He liked having Amy
around, so he invites her
to family picnics, outings,
but then things
get weird.
Dad gets kind of
jealous of son.
Right? You also
took from him, too.
You took his jacket,
his love letters.
And you took from Amy, too.
You know, we asked Amy
about you.
What did she say?
She said,
"Ken Wallace walked in on me
once or twice in the shower,
"but it was
innocent.
"He was sweet,
clumsy, older man.
Nothing sexual about him."
So you had to
change that, so,
when Amy broke up with Jared,
about a week later,
you know, and you're gonna
lose her, too, you decided
to do something
about it.
Get a funky old
trailer, hired some
brunette hookers.
Got their DNA from the sheets.
But you stepped
over the line.
You started to prowl
around condos just like Amy's.
Started to stalk young women,
brunettes, just like Amy.
You broke into their house.
You broke into
their bedroom
to act out your
sick rape fantasies,
all in preparation...
for Amy.
Amy was worth it.
The woman... is a miracle.
Jared had her, he messed it up.
When I had my chance with her...
I made it perfect.
(indistinct voice over P.A.)
Doctors say your mom's
gonna pull through.
I never wanted to hurt her.
I know.
Or make it easy
for her to believe
I'd end up dead that way.
You know, I-I just keep thinking
about how cold
she was out there.
You know,
I could've told her,
sleeping outside sucks.
She's going to need you,
Tyler, more than ever.
I swear to God,
I'm not leaving the house
for a second.
I'm done...
with everything,
everyone else.
Just let her be okay.
(crying)
Please let her be okay.