WOMAN:
It's to you, Mr. Gentry.
$65,000 to call.
You've been playing me
all night.
(sighs)
In fact, I think
you're playing me right now.
What about you, Audrey?
You think this kid's trying
to pull one over on me again?
AUDREY:
I couldn't say.
Well, what the hell.
It's only money, right?
I'm all in.
(murmuring)
I'll call.
Let's do it.
(murmuring)
Mr. Gentry shows a straight.
Two pair. Aces and kings.
(laughing):
Oh, I knew it.
I got you.
Three-to-one odds
in my favor.
This one's finally
gonna be mine.
$490,000
in the pot.
Oh, no. No damn way.
The ace makes a full house.
Tough luck, man.
Maybe next time.
Cash me out?
Congrats.
What are we looking at,
a little over $600,000?
(switch clacks,
power whirrs off)
Sorry, gentlemen.
Back-ups will
kick in any second.
In the meantime,
everybody keep your hands
away from the table, please.
This is Brantson.
We lost power
in the Rialto Room.
MAN (over radio):
That repair crew's on its way.
GAMBLER:
Hey, what's going on, man?
(explosion)
(people shouting)
(people screaming)
(high-pitched oscillating tone)
(gunshot)
(grunting)
(engine revving,
tires squealing)
(engine revving)
(tires squealing,
engine revving)
(people screaming, shouting)
(engine revving)
(siren whooping)
(tires screech)
(engine revs, tires screech)
(engine revving)
(tires screeching)
(siren wailing)
Everybody get back!
Out of the way!
(engine revving)
(glass clinking)
(crowd murmuring)
(filtered breathing)
This maniac hit the Four Kings,
made off
with over a million bucks.
Well, I wouldn't exactly
say he "made off."
No, you're right.
Even if you leave with it,
this town has a twisted way
of getting it back
from you, doesn't it?
Security guard's
pretty shaken up.
He never shot anyone before.
PHILLIPS:
Well, he still hasn't.
There's no wound,
there's no blood.
Nothing.
STOKES:
Why'd he go down?
SIDLE:
Ugh.
What the hell happened to him?
STOKES:
Whoa, he's swollen.
Aah...
AKERS:
Here you go.
We were able to collect
just about all
the scattered cash.
Are you sure the upstanding
citizens of Fremont didn't try
to stuff their pockets?
(scoffs) With this?
Why bother? It's counterfeit.
STOKES:
Yeah. Yeah, I'll say.
And bad counterfeit at that.
Chips are fake too.
They're plastic.
So this guy
leaves the casino
with over a million dollars.
(chips clinking)
Where did it go?
STOKES:
I don't know. I'd ask him,
but I don't think he's
gonna be much help.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
(camera shutter clicking)
(low, indistinct conversations)
Oh, his name is Paul Brantson.
He was only 25 years old.
Married his
high school sweetheart
just six months ago.
(camera shutter clicks)
This is your first one back.
You went through a lot.
I can handle this
if you need me to.
No. I'm fine.
You know, I gotta do it.
(laughs)
I'm Captain Jim Brass.
Tell me what you told
the other police officers.
I... It all happened so fast,
I, uh...
like it wasn't even real.
Like when you wake up,
and you can't
even remember
what you just dreamed.
Okay, I want you
to think real hard.
Before the lights went out,
did anything happen
that might have tipped you off
that something was up?
Uh... I don't know.
I just...I can't remember!
Um...I had a glass
or two of wine.
Just, I don't...
just trying to calm
my nerves. I...
Sorry.
Thank you. Excuse me.
I talked to about
ten witnesses.
Not one of them can be sure
of what they saw.
This whole thing looks
like it was
designed that way--
to confuse.
(phone ringing)
Oh.
Says 201 area code.
That's New Jersey.
You still settling
Nancy's estate?
Mundane little things
that are just never ending.
If you need to take that,
go ahead.
We can handle things.
Yeah, thanks.
Hey.
Everything okay?
(sighs) Help me focus.
What do we know?
Well, winner was cashing in
on over 600 grand.
His chips on the table,
cash to match,
more stolen from the cart.
Total take--
just over a million
and a half.
A million and a half
that's still missing.
Yeah, but the timing is
what's bothering me.
The suspect knew exactly
what time to hit--the pay-out.
So he had eyes in the room.
Anyone here stand out?
No, but there is a guy
who's still missing.
Robert Gentry.
He was the last player
out of the game.
Gone before
the first cops arrived.
You think
he's our guy in the room?
Couple witnesses said
that Gentry and our suspect
collided during the robbery.
What that an accident,
or was it a hand-off?
It would explain
where the money went.
RUSSELL:
Yeah.
Let's find Gentry.
(Robbins grunting with effort)
(Robbins groaning, grunting)
You three want
to be left alone?
Very funny, Finn.
I could use a hand
getting these
leathers off.
Sure.
Ah, it's tight.
Must have been
a size or two smaller
when he bought them.
Whoa.
I venture to say
he was a size
or two smaller when
he put them on.
He didn't start the day
like this.
Body's swollen;
significant edema.
Some sort
of allergic reaction, maybe.
FINLAY: Clint Tyree.
He worked at the Four Kings.
Yeah, he rode a motorcycle
in their stunt show.
Can't say I've ever seen it.
Judging by these X-rays,
must be
a hell of a show.
He's broken almost
every bone in his body.
Hmm...
Huh. Guy could have used
a new pair of boots.
So what do you think caused
his allergic reaction?
Well, I saw a raised mark
on his shoulder.
Could be as simple
as a bee sting or spider bite.
A guy robs a casino,
shoots a security guard,
and rides off on
a motorcycle,
and gets killed by an insect?
I only said it could be.
It's the left shoulder, right?
Look at that.
An injection mark.
Somebody did this
to him on purpose.
You need anything else
before I zip him up?
No, no, go ahead.
You can take him.
Oh.
Ma'am, please...
Is that him? Is that Paul?
I'm so sorry, ma'am,
but you can't be here.
That's my husband!
I have to see him!
Please?
Are you sure
you want to do this?
(quietly, weakly):
Please?
Okay.
(whimpers)
Ma'am.
(stifled crying)
All the while
he was on active duty,
four tours of Afghanistan,
he wouldn't marry me.
You know why?
He was afraid
of making me a widow.
He didn't want
to put me through that
if something happened
to him over there.
(sniffles, cries)
I'm so sorry.
(crying):
How does this happen?
How does he survive
four years of hell
over there,
just to come back home
and die where
he's supposed to be safe?
(sobbing):
Oh, God!
(footsteps approaching)
Talk to me, Hodges.
(speaking Chinese)
In English.
The writing on these
newspaper bits is Chinese.
That, combined
with traces of carbon,
potassium nitrate, and sulfur,
tells me the explosives
used in the heist
are essentially untraceable.
They're Chinese fireworks.
M-80s, most likely.
Available at most any fireworks
stand outside the city,
if you flash a little cash.
Which brings us
to our next potential dead end,
the strobe ball.
It's a visual effects device
used in the motorcycle
stunt show
of the Four Kings Casino.
The suspect could've stolen that
from his job...
What about the casino's
security video?
To complete
the dead-end trifecta?
Après moi.
STOKES:
Okay, there he is.
That's him, right there.
That's the guy
we're looking for.
What's going on?
It's the strobe.
The camera's aperture
couldn't keep up with it.
It doesn't get any better.
So fix it.
What do you propose I do?
I don't know.
We got to find out if this guy
Gentry was in on this heist.
You want me to do it?
No, no, n...
I got it.
The lights in the Rialto Room
work just the same
as the lights in
the rest of the casino.
They're all automated,
controlled by a central system.
So how's the system
controlled?
You have to be able to turn
the lights on and off
when you want to.
Well, it's... like
everything else these days,
it's, uh... (clears throat)
it's essentially...
an app.
You have to have
an access code.
But once you're in,
you can program whole floors,
you can control
individual fixtures,
whatever you need.
So whoever
killed the lights
should be in the system.
Pretty much, he'd have to be.
(chuckles)
That's a cute kid.
How old is he?
He's ten months old.
So the real question is,
who has the app?
Or the access codes?
Besides me?
Uh... security department,
hotel manager,
executive manager, I mean,
(phone ringing)
just a handful of
people, probably.
Well, we're gonna need a list.
I don't have
that list.
I mean, I set up the system,
but the hotel manager
controls the access.
SIDLE:
Morgan...
Our missing poker player,
Rob Gentry, just turned up.
He was at the Palermo Casino,
playing with Four Kings chips.
Hm.
STOKES:
Whoo! (chuckles)
You had quite a night
last night,
didn't you, Mr. Gentry?
First you go all in
at the Rialto Room, lose,
then you wind up
in this armed robbery.
Yeah, I tell you,
whole thing was pretty crazy.
I feel lucky just to be alive.
Lucky? Oh, yeah.
But you're also
a little stupid.
Come on, you didn't think
we'd have every casino in town
looking for these
Four Kings chips?
And your dumb ass rolls
into the Palermo today,
buys in with 75 grand worth.
Where'd you get it?
Well, you know,
I can't remember if I...
if I won 'em or bought 'em.
I've--I've had 'em
for quite a while.
You see that?
It's an RFID chip.
Each one of these chips
has its own digital
identification number.
It helps the casino keep up
with chip movement.
And these particular chips
were scanned last night
as they were being put
on a cart for the Rialto Room.
So the only way
that you could have them
is if you stole them.
Wait.
I had nothing to do
with that robbery.
Yes, you did, Robert.
You and your motorcycle buddy?
We've got you on video
texting him, giving him
the signal to strike.
You're on the hook
for murder, bud.
When that robbery went down,
I--I ended up on the floor.
Suddenly,
I'm face-to-face
with the chip cart.
So you just
helped yourself to a handful,
is that it?
I lost big
at the tables last night.
It was just a way
to recoup a little.
But I didn't
kill anybody.
Look, maybe I can help you.
Yeah? How's that?
Well, as...
as I was slipping
out of there, I...
I ducked into a service hallway
off the main casino.
And I saw him,
saw the guy in the motorcycle
gear running away.
You know that's
in the opposite direction.
Well, I--I'm just telling you
what I saw.
Hey, we got to run this.
New security footage from
the east side of the casino.
You don't know how happy
that makes me. Of course...
sets the stage
for greater disappointment.
Not batting a thousand today?
So far, no.
Swing and a miss.
Can I see that again?
It's just him running away.
It doesn't help tie Gentry
to the robbery.
Will you please replay it?
I was just in autopsy.
I saw Clint Tyree's X-rays.
He has multiple healed
fractures and titanium posts.
There is no way
that he could run like that.
This boot belongs
to Clint Tyree,
our stunt rider who died out
on Fremont Street.
Check out
the wear pattern.
Uneven on the outer heel, right?
Guy probably had a limp.
Mm-hmm.
From a lifetime
of motorcycle injuries.
Now, look at this.
Right after the robbery.
(grunts)
No limp.
Not even close.
Mm-hmm.
Now, enlarge the boot.
(beeping)
No wear pattern.
It's a different boot.
Two suspects,
identically dressed.
One of them pulls off
the robbery,
makes a run for it
down the hall...
To where the other one
must've been waiting.
Tyree knows he's playing
the part of a decoy.
But he doesn't know
he's also the patsy.
And right before he rides away,
he gets an unexpected
parting gift.
RUSSELL:
The deadly injection.
(motorcycle roaring)
The guy who hit
the Rialto Room
is not the same guy
who died out on the street.
Hey, Doc.
Hear you got a C.O.D. for me
on our motorcycle rider here.
Well, the C.O.D. was easy--
the allergic reaction.
The interesting part
is the cause.
I was able
to identify the toxin
that was injected
into Mr. Tyree's shoulder.
An extremely
aggressive coagulant.
This is an exemplar sample.
Watch what happens
when I add a single drop
into a beaker of blood.
RUSSELL:
Wow, look at that.
Massive clotting.
In just minutes,
all the blood's clotting ability
is exhausted.
And as a result, massive
internal bleeding occurs,
in some cases leading
to total exsanguination.
But, now,
we didn't see that
with Mr. Tyree here.
No, because his allergy
to the toxin killed him first.
Without the allergic reaction,
he would've been in
for a slow
and very painful death.
What was the toxin?
Snake venom.
A species called
Daboia russelii,
commonly the Russell's viper.
No relation, I'm assuming?
None that
I'm aware of.
You said, without the allergy,
it would've been a slow death.
But Mr. Tyree there was
a professional stunt rider.
He could've led the cops
on a wild chase
for who knows how long.
But the allergy caused him to
drop in the first few minutes.
Yeah, exactly.
So maybe our real robber had
to change his plans.
Right? Maybe he had
to do things a little faster.
Thank you. Thanks.
Well, you were right.
Within an hour of that robbery,
we had every casino in town
looking for those chips,
but we were too late--
he cashed 'em in immediately.
So by the time
we sounded the alarm,
chips were already
in a casino vault.
Try six different casino vaults,
all sister hotels
to the Four Kings.
The Mediterranean
got a shot of our guy.
There he is right there.
With that disguise,
it could be anybody.
Exactly.
Hey, so I've been doing some
checking on the Russell's viper.
Turns out this thing
is so dangerous
it requires a permit
for ownership.
Please tell me you found one.
Right here in Vegas.
Guy's name is Julian Reese.
He's a valet car parker
for the Four Kings Casino.
Another employee.
Didn't show up to work today.
Brass already put a BOLO out.
All right, I'll follow up.
See you later.
Okay.
Yeah, that works and I'll...
Akers.
Hey, Stokes.
So parking enforcement
spotted the car.
When the plates came back
to Julian Reese, they called us.
When we found this,
we called you.
Whew.
Yeah, that's our snake charmer,
all right.
Looks like he got it right here.
Single shot
to the head.
There's a small caliber casing
on the ground.
There's also some bruising
on his face.
Yeah, looks like
somebody beat him up
pretty good.
And grabbed his shirt.
There's a tear in it.
Looks like there's
some residue or trace.
We'll get it back to the lab.
So that makes two
casino employees,
the stunt rider
and the valet parker,
both involved in the robbery.
And both dead, which means
there's at least one player left
in the game.
Someone who I'm assuming
didn't want to share the money.
AKERS: So then what was
this guy's part?
Oh, I'd say he played
a starring role.
Oh, hey.
Uh, I'll start
with the good news.
This...
is definitely
your murder weapon.
Venom from
the Daboia russelii viper.
And I found DNA
consistent with Clint Tyree
in the hypodermic tip.
However, I've been
less successful getting DNA
from the leathers.
There was quite a bit
of perspiration inside,
so I had high hopes
initially, but no luck yet.
I'm taking
another crack at it,
but for now,
I can't confirm
that they were worn
by Julian Reese.
What's with the orange color?
Yeah, I'm not sure.
It might have something to do
with the leather-tanning
process.
Thought you might be
interested to know
that I have identified the trace
left in the snake charmer's
shirt lapels.
Your residue looks to be pumice.
Pumice?
Oh, uh,
volcanic rock.
Created when super-heated,
highly pressurized igneous rock
is propelled from a volcano.
Is there any reason
I couldn't have told her that?
Guys, I know where
pumice comes from.
Why would it be on his shirt?
Well, it has many common uses.
Such as lightweight concrete,
insulation,
it's an additive in plaster and
it's even found in toothpaste.
Hm. Is that it?
No? If the pH is alkali,
that could indicate
the presence of...
Soap.
Mechanic's soap.
Look, I can't be here.
I just can't.
Do you hear me?
I need you
to sit in that chair now.
But you don't understand
what you're doing.
You don't know
what's going on.
SIDLE: Ryan,
we found pumice
from your hand cleaner
on Julian Reese's shirt.
Do you want to tell us
how that got there?
Look, I can explain everything.
Okay? Just not now.
I can't be here, all right?
Please.
We got a warrant.
We checked your
phone, okay?
It was your access code
that shut down the lights
in the Rialto Room
for the robbery.
You were in on that heist.
And...
you shot Julian Reese
so that you could have
all the money to yourself.
Fine, okay, don't talk.
We're in your home right now,
turning it upside down,
and we're gonna find
the proof that we need.
Well, no sign of the money.
And there's no evidence
of a female living
in the house, either.
I think he divorced the wife.
No divorce. She died.
From cancer.
These are all
condolence cards.
These are all medical bills.
Poor kid just
loses his mother.
Now he's gonna lose
his father too.
Morgan...
you gotta check this out.
(phone auto-dialing)
(sighs)
Sara...
this whole thing
just went sideways.
(phone beeps off)
We know what happened.
They kidnapped your son.
Yeah, now thanks to you,
they're gonna kill him.
So what we're gonna do
is just keep you in here.
We figure the best thing
for you to do is
stay inside, in case
they try to contact you.
Now, all our boys
are gonna be here.
We're gonna have taps
on the phone...
No, no, no, no, no--this is
exactly what I didn't want.
Hey!
They said no police.
If whoever has Christopher
is watching,
who knows what
they'll do to him!
Hey, listen,
man, there's a lot of people
here working really hard
to help you find your boy,
and we're gonna do that,
but we can't do it
unless you cooperate.
Okay? Sit down,
tell me how you got
into all this mess.
Come on, let's sit down.
About, uh, two months ago,
Julian approached me
in the employee cafeteria.
Julian...Reese,
the valet dude?
He came to me
and said that there
was a couple other people who
had come up with a plan, a way
to get rich off the casino.
What other people?
He didn't name names.
And to be
really honest, I didn't
take him that seriously.
I mean, we see
so much money that
comes through here every day...
I mean, and everybody's
fantasizing about how
they can get some of it.
Right.
But I just told him no thanks,
that I wasn't interested,
not while I have Christopher
to worry about.
(watch alarm beeping)
What's with the alarm, man?
I--I...got to take a pill.
Yeah? Let me see that.
Rifampin?
What do you take these for?
Christopher's nanny, one of
the kids got meningitis,
so now we're all taking
it as a precaution.
Yeah, okay.
So what did Julian say
when you told him
you weren't interested
in his plan?
He just said
it was no big deal,
that that was cool...
and that was the end of it.
Until yesterday morning.
I went in...
to take a shower
while Christopher was sleeping.
I mean, it couldn't have been
more than two or three minutes
at the most.
And when I came back out,
he was gone.
And he wrote that note
on my laptop.
"Keep quiet,
do what we ask,
and you'll get your kid back."
And I went
and I confronted
him at work.
Did you get physical with him?
Yeah, yeah, I admit it,
I lost my temper.
I hit him,
but I didn't kill him!
All right?
He said he didn't know
where Christopher was,
and that I should just go along,
and that I should just shut off
the lights in the Rialto Room.
But I did everything they asked.
Where is he?
Where's my son?
We're gonna
get him back for you.
You know,
when I was taken...
when I was being held...
...at least I knew
you guys were looking for me.
This little baby...
what is he thinking?
He's in a weird
place with...
without his father.
Yeah...kid cases
are always tough.
Thing is...
whoever took him...
they already got
what they wanted.
They have no use
for him now.
Morgan, do you really
want to go there?
Why not?
They've already shown they
have no trouble killing.
What's one more?
Yeah, but this is a baby.
And you just have
to hope that
it's...somehow different.
(quietly):
Yeah.
(crying softly)
(sniffles, sobs)
(continues sobbing)
Sorry.
What's wrong with me?
Hey...
You're only human.
(quietly):
Thanks.
(sniffles)
Let's check outside.
Father said he was
only in the shower
for a few minutes;
maybe the kidnapper
was waiting there,
watching...
for the perfect
time to strike.
We got to find this kid.
SANDERS:
Oh, yeah.
Someone was definitely here,
in this spot.
You can see
his shoe impressions.
BRODY:
Perfect view of the hallway
towards the bathroom door.
Kidnapper could have seen Ryan
heading to the bathroom
to take a shower.
What's this?
Hey, get a shot of that.
(shutter clicks)
Some kind of coin.
It could have
fallen out of someone's pocket,
if they were crouched down here.
SANDERS: Well, it's definitely
not U.S. currency.
I don't know--
how's your Arabic?
My Arabic's crap.
But my Pashto's not bad.
Pashto?
Like Afghanistan?
Yeah.
Well, our first victim,
the security guard,
his wife said that he did
four tours in Afghanistan.
You're thinking
our innocent victim
wasn't so innocent after all.
So Paul Brantson
was far from an angel.
He left the military
with a bad-conduct discharge.
Apparently, he was
trying to smuggle
more than a coin
out of Afghanistan.
I checked the security
schedule at the casino.
Mm-hmm.
He wasn't even supposed
to be working last night.
Really?
He traded shifts
to be in the room.
So it was no accident
he was there.
I just processed
the security guard's car.
Fibers found in the backseat
are a match to the baby's crib.
There's also traces
of zinc oxide.
Diaper paste.
Why won't anybody tell me
what's going on?
My husband's dead,
I'm trying to plan a funeral,
and your people storm
into my house and start
tearing it apart without even
an explanation!
Ms. Brantson....
please...
take a seat.
(sighs)
Do you recognize this?
It's an Afghani coin.
Yeah. It's Paul's.
He always carried it
with him to remind him
of all the guys who
weren't as lucky as he was,
the guys who
didn't make it back.
The problem is, we found it
outside of the house
where a young baby
was kidnapped.
Well, then obviously
it's not Paul's.
It just looks like
the one he carried.
Except his fingerprint
was on it.
And when we
searched his car,
we found evidence that a baby
had recently been
in the backseat.
No, no, this is insane.
There's no way Paul
was part of a kidnapping.
Do you know where your husband
was at 7:30 yesterday morning?
You know what?
I'm not doing this with you.
I just lost my husband,
and I haven't even
been able to bury him yet.
I am very sorry for
your loss, but right now,
we are focused on
finding that baby.
So if you know
something,
or if there's anything
you want to tell us...
No, no.
I'm not talking to you anymore.
I'm not speaking
to anyone,
except maybe a lawyer.
RUSSELL:
Okay, we've got at least
four employees from the casino--
the stunt driver, valet parker,
security guard...
and the maintenance worker.
These three all presumably
part of the robbery crew,
all killed during
or after the heist.
Well, so much
for honor among thieves.
RUSSELL:
Let me ask you something.
Why not kill
the maintenance worker?
Why is Ryan still alive?
'Cause he doesn't pose a threat.
He didn't even know
who the main players were,
except for the valet guy.
And he wasn't in for
a share of the spoils.
Well, we know we have at least
one more player out there--
whoever shot Julian Reese
and took the money.
Good chance
it's another Four Kings
employee, but there are
over 400 of them,
so it's gonna take time
to run them down.
Which we don't have--
that baby's been out there
for more than 36 hours.
Hey, guys, just got
a call from Akers.
Ryan Archer is gone.
Officer Akers!
What the hell
happened here?
Captain, he was only out of
my sight for a couple of min--
Why was he out of
your sight at all?
H--he said he needed
to use the bathroom.
I went to check on him...
Damn it, Akers, you had one
job to do, just one job.
You were to sit on this guy,
and keep an eye on him.
That's it, one job!
Jim, come on,
man, chill out.
Shut up, Stokes.
Don't tell me what to do.
You, get out of here.
Captain...
they contacted him.
We've been monitoring
his phone.
This is an e-mail.
"This is your last chance.
Meet at the employee
parking lot, level four."
He's gonna get his kid.
No, he's gonna get
himself killed.
I don't see him.
I think we're too late.
I don't see him, either.
Nick!
Ryan?
What happened?
I've done it. I've lost him.
I'll never see him now.
All right, calm down.
Is this your blood?
Are you hurt?
It's not my blood.
It just went off.
I didn't mean to.
What went off?
I was just sitting
in the car, waiting.
Next thing you know, somebody
comes up to my blind spot.
Suddenly, a gun was
at my head.
And as I was trying
to get out, I mean,
I guess the gun went off.
BRODY:
Nick...I got a body.
It's the dealer
from the card room.
No pulse.
She's dead.
No, no. No.
She was the one person
who knew where Christopher was.
Charlie-05, I got a 187.
Send backup, code three.
You better start
talking to me, Ryan!
I got keys.
(car alarm beeping)
Over this way.
You stay with me!
Stay with me!
(alarm chirps off)
(crying)
I got the baby.
Christopher! Oh, my God.
Oh, no, no, no.
Stay back, Ryan.
There's no way
I'm gonna let you touch him,
and you're covered in blood.
It's my son.
Look, the important thing is
that he's okay, see?
He's okay.
There's Daddy.
Yeah, okay.
We'll get him to the hospital,
we'll get you
to the hospital, we'll
get him checked out.
It's gonna be okay.
You're okay, buddy.
Daddy's right here, okay?
Just get his Bun-Bun, all right?
Okay.
It's gonna make him feel better.
Yeah, we'll do that;
we'll get his Bun-Bun.
Come on, let's go over here.
Come on, now.
You're okay.
Our dead poker dealer, Audrey--
just came from her house.
She's got all kinds
of kids stuff.
She's got toys, food,
a makeshift crib.
Looks like she was gonna
keep that kid for the long haul.
Also found
this disposable phone.
In it was the text
signaling Ryan
to turn off the lights.
So she was the eyes
in the poker room.
Okay...
the gun we recovered
next to the dealer's dead body
belonged to her.
Greg just ran
ballistics.
It's the gun
that killed Reese in his car.
So what are we thinking,
that she's the mastermind,
the femme fatale,
the one who seduced
the other three into
executing her plan?
Oh, way she looked,
it wouldn't have been that hard.
Is this it?
Is this really
the whole team?
No...no, we can't.
Where's the money?
Hey.
Oh, that's not a late-night
snack, I'm guessing.
No, I just came
from the hospital.
They belong to the baby that
was kidnapped and his father.
We looking
for anything specific?
Well, let's start with
where the baby was and who he
might have had contact with.
Oh, try to preserve that
the best you can.
It's special
to the kid.
Oh.
Yeah, it's funny
how babies do that,
fixate on one particular toy.
When I was a baby, mine was
an elephant called "Stinky."
Guess I carried him around
in my mouth a lot.
He was always moist.
Moist means bacteria,
which leads to stinky.
Henry, look at this.
It looks like sweat stains,
the pattern, at least,
but the color...
It's orange.
Just like the tint that came
off the motorcycle leathers.
It wasn't
from the tanning process.
It's from the perspiration.
Chromhidrosis--
colored sweat.
It's a rare condition
on its own.
More often, it's a side effect
of something else.
Like copper miners
can sweat blue
from the minerals
in the mine.
What about this?
What about orange?
Could be a pharmaceutical
side effect.
Is this baby taking
any medication?
Oh, finally.
(laughs)
Doctor said
everything looks good.
There's nothing
to worry about.
Thought I might never get
to hold him again.
No one's happier than me
to see this reunion.
I've been so obsessed
with the loss of my wife,
I haven't focused enough on him.
You did the best you could.
How's your son,
Mr. Archer?
Seems to be doing fine.
Doctors said
he checked out okay.
I guess the kidnappers took
pretty good care of him then.
Fed him,
changed his diaper,
gave him his medication.
Your son is on rifampin,
right?
You both are?
What's going on, Sara?
Well, the hospital ran blood
tests on Christopher tonight,
and his rifampin
level suggested he had
a dose about ten hours ago.
Would you like
to explain to me
how the kidnappers knew
to give him his medication?
SIDLE:
Well done, Mr. Archer.
You played us, you played
the sympathy card with your son.
You had us all believing that
you were one of the victims.
Not bad.
Look, I don't
care what you say.
I didn't kidnap my own son.
It was that security guard,
just like you said.
They took Christopher to force
me to be part of their plan.
That's what you
wanted us to think.
But it was you
who planted the Afghani coin
in your garden,
and it was you who put the
diaper paste in his backseat.
My God, you make me out to be
like I'm this
criminal mastermind
with this crazy plan.
I just did what I had to do!
I turned off the lights.
That's all.
FINLAY:
That is not all.
Not even close.
This, uh, medication
you're on, rifampin,
has an interesting side effect.
It's called chromhidrosis.
Causes colored sweat.
Your baby's sweat is orange,
your sweat is orange.
Haven't you noticed?
We've only been taking it
a couple days.
Does it really matter?
Yeah.
Yeah, it matters.
That's you.
You were sweating
when you robbed the card room.
when you shot Paul Brantson.
Injecting Clint Tyree
with snake venom--
that made you
sweat too, right?
FINLAY:
And then, after the robbery,
you went
and you killed Julian Reese,
and then you stashed
the motorcycle leathers
and the syringe
in his car,
hoping that we'd think
that Reese was the gunman.
SIDLE:
There was only one problem.
Those motorcycle leathers
absorbed a lot of sweat--
orange sweat--
when I compared them
to the shirt that I took
from you tonight, guess what?
They were a perfect match,
right down
to identical traces
of rifampin.
FINLAY: So that puts you
in the leathers, Ryan.
You're our guy.
You robbed the Rialto Room,
and you killed four people.
I didn't do it for me.
SIDLE:
Oh, let me guess.
This is the part where you argue
for father of the year.
Chris was five months old
when my wife died.
Do you have any idea
the amount of medical bills
she left behind?
So you killed four people
to pay them?
So much money
goes through that place.
I mean, just a handful
of chips would have changed
everything for me and Chris.
I mean, just think how
I could have raised him.
Yeah, how are you going
to raise him now?
(crying)
(sighs)
Hey, man.
Hey, you got a second?
Yeah, sure. What's up?
(sighs)
I owe you an apology.
(chuckles)
For what?
For jumping on you
and jumping on Akers.
I talked to Akers, and now I'm
talking to you--I'm sorry.
Jim, I get it.
You got a lot going on
right now, okay?
Yeah, I got a lot
going on, yeah.
The D.A.'s calling me.
The prosecutor wants to talk
to me about testifying against
my daughter.
Yeah, I mean,
I'm on the phone
six or seven times
a day to New Jersey,
handling my
ex-wife's affairs.
Come on, everything will be back
to normal eventually.
You know that.
Back to normal--
I'd like that.
But I'll tell you, Nick, the way
my life's going right now,
I don't know what normal is.
(footsteps approaching)
Hey.
Just got
off the phone with Greg.
They found the money
in a maintenance locker
at the casino.
Good.
Sit down.
I just wish
we could take the money,
you know, put it in a trust
for that poor kid.
That'd be nice.
Well, kids are resilient.
Maybe he'll be all right.
What about you?
You gonna be all right?
Time heals all, right?
I guess we'll find out
if that's true.
Have a good night.
You too.