(crickets chirping)
(television playing
indistinctly)
(laughter, conversation on TV)
(TV playing indistinctly)
(dog whimpers)
(woman speaks quietly
to dog)
(laughter and conversation
continues on TV)
Mom, I'm tired.
Can we stop now?
Just one more house.
Then we'll go home
for dinner, okay?
They're not home.
Well, knock louder.
The Conners bought
ten candy bars
from you
last year.
(phone ringing)
(knocking)
Sharon.
How are you?
Yes.
Yeah, we got back
last weekend.
Sorry we missed
the party.
Was he surprised?
Oh!
Wonderful. Amazing.
Beautiful.
Really, you need
to go with Burt.
(groans weakly)
(girl screams,
fades into police siren wailing)
Was that our victim?
Well, yes and no.
His name is
Doug Adamson.
He's, uh, 30 days out
of county lockup, right?
Got a long rap sheet.
Mostly drug use.
Looks like he fell.
Knocked himself out.
RUSSELL:
I assume we're not here
'cause he hurt his head.
Oh, he didn't live here.
This house belongs
to the Conner family.
The neighbors said they haven't
seen them for almost a month.
Ah. Well, whole families
just don't vanish.
Well, we know it's
easier to find a
car than people,
so I've got
a broadcast out
on their vehicles.
What does Doug Adamson
have to say about all this?
Well, nothing yet,
but I'm going down
to the ER later.
All right, so we've
got a convicted felon
just out of jail
at the same time
that a family disappears
and we find him
inside their house--
that does not look good
for Mr. Adamson.
Looks even worse
for the Conner family.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
So a whole family is missing
and no one reports it
to the police.
Well, if I wasn't a CSI,
I would think
they just moved out.
No TV, no furniture,
no electronics.
Everything of value
is pretty much gone.
Not if you include
sentimental value.
Looks like they left behind
some of their family photos.
FINLAY: Hard to believe
they would leave those.
All right, so this is where
our intruder, Doug,
hit his head and fell.
I'll see if I can find
anything else here.
I'm gonna take the outside.
Carpet hasn't been
recently shampooed.
That's good
for us.
STOKES:
Yeah.
You know, each of these photos
is a family member alone.
Doing their own thing.
Except for this one.
Guess that's how families
are these days.
Huh. Well, that's strange.
This curtain's missing.
Tieback too.
2 millimeter
medium force spatter.
From Doug Adamson's fall?
Yeah, some of it.
Okay, so...
Doug fell here...
...causing spatter
to move upward,
close to the floor.
Further away, over here,
spatter is traveling downwards.
Indicates a separate event.
Exactly.
Yeah, okay.
Yeah, here we go.
There's some spatter
on the fireplace,
and on the wall as well.
Nick, look at
the ceiling.
Castoff.
STOKES:
Ooh, yeah.
All right, I'm gonna
luminol the place.
Okay.
Do you mind stepping out
so that we both don't
trample all over
the evidence?
Seriously?
Yeah.
She kick you out?
Yeah!
(both laughing)
Hey, check this out.
The caulk on
this window...
it's fresh.
STOKES: Yeah, and the other ones
are yellow and cracked.
That means that somebody
recently replaced that glass.
All right.
Hey, come take a look at this.
Does that look like
blood to you?
To the naked eye,
yes, it does.
Soaked all the way
through the mat.
It's hard to believe
someone would
drag a dead body
out the front door.
Even at night,
there's not much cover out here.
But I bet they did
some cleaning up.
Which means we're
getting dirty.
Time to Dumpster dive.
You're joining me, right?
Yeah, um...
WOMAN:
Excuse me.
Officer?
Hi, there.
What's your name?
I'm Madge.
I'm a neighbor.
I'm Nick Stokes.
I'm with the Crime Lab.
I was just wondering...
what happened to the Conners?
Well, it's an ongoing
investigation,
so I can't really
talk about it too much.
Oh, I understand.
Did you know them?
Well, Dwight, the husband,
he works 9:00 to 5:00,
a real go-getter.
And Claire, she's a
lovely stay-at-home mom.
Their son, I think
he graduated
high school last year.
I don't know much
about the daughter...
but I haven't seen any of them
in the last few weeks.
And in that time span,
did you see anybody
hanging around the house?
Just the man they took
away in the ambulance.
You know,
he was working
around the house
and living there.
I thought he
was a relative.
Hmm.
Did you notice
anything else?
Uh, yeah, there was
a great big truck,
and they were
loading in all kinds
of furniture.
I thought the Conners were
remodeling or something.
I'd be willing to bet
that you saw something on
that truck to give it away,
like a company name, logo,
anything like that?
Yes, I did.
It was, uh,
Las Vegas Consignment.
That's a big help.
I would love
to live next-door to you.
Oh, aren't you sweet?
Hey, hey, that's all
the clothes I got!
Sorry.
Gotta take them in for evidence.
BRASS:
It's okay, Doug.
Question and
answer time.
Do we have to?
My head still hurts.
You're fine.
How'd you know
the Conner family?
I was behind the mini-mart.
You know the one on 12th?
What day was this?
February 18.
Oh, and that's the day you
were released from County.
Yeah, same day.
Mm-hmm.
Dude drives up
and asks me
if I wanted to
earn some money.
Had you seen
him before?
No. Never.
What kind of work
did he ask you to do?
Just some odd jobs
around his house.
Mm-hmm. Is this the guy
you spoke with?
Not him.
Him... and-and
she was with him.
BRASS: Ethan Conner and
his mother Claire.
Yeah.
I went with them,
I cleaned their garage.
I didn't finish till late,
so they let me
spend the night.
Inside the house?
Yeah.
The guest room.
Sounds like nice people.
Can I see your hands, please?
Over.
They're pretty thrashed.
Hard work'll do that.
Okay, so you spent the night.
Then what happened?
Then, the next morning,
they asked me to dig
some trenches
for the sprinklers.
Some trenches?
Yeah.
What happened to
the Conners, Doug?
No one's seen
them lately.
In fact, you're
the last person
to see them at all.
I don't know.
Okay?
I was digging in the backyard,
saw them get
into their car.
What kind of car?
A blue SUV.
Mm-hmm.
They said they were
going to a movie,
and they never came back.
A movie.
Yeah.
So you just kept
digging, even though
you weren't
getting paid.
Yeah.
They told me I could stay
as long as I wanted.
SANDERS: For 30 days?
Didn't you ever get curious
as to where they were?
Yeah, but what was
I supposed to do?
Call the cops?
They'd take me back to jail.
So whatever happened
to their furniture?
The computers,
TVs...
Look, I-I waited
for them to come back.
Really.
Then after a week or two,
I ran out of food,
so I sold some of the stuff,
just enough to cover
what they owed me.
Then-then I sold
some more stuff.
So perfect strangers
invite you,
a convicted felon
and drug user,
to stay at their
house indefinitely.
And then they
mysteriously vanish,
leaving you to sell
off their property
piece by piece,
for cash.
Sounds hard to believe, right?
It's ridiculous.
When he gets discharged,
bring him to the
police station.
And beg somebody
to clean him up.
♪ ♪
Wow!
That is a lot
of blood!
What did you find outside?
More blood.
And five bags of
wet, stinky trash.
Okay.
So the predominance
of blood is in this
main living area.
I marked the voids
with chalk
to determine
the furniture placement.
Which was not very difficult
because this entire carpet
is covered in blood.
So I found
two interesting areas.
Right here's
the most concentrated stain,
About 2 feet in diameter.
So somebody
was laying there bleeding.
And the medium-force spatter
that I found
on the wall tells me
that the beating occurred
in this general area.
And the cast-off positions
the suspect here.
But without the furniture,
I really can't be
more specific.
STOKES:
Well, I think I can
help you out there.
The neighbor lady said she saw
Las Vegas Consignment
moving a bunch of furniture
out of here.
Whatever you could recover
would really help us.
I'll get on that right now.
I'll see you later.
Bye.
The most concerning evidence
I found is over here.
Well...
drag marks.
Mm-hmm.
Where's that lead to?
The end of the hall?
A garage and backyard.
Bloody drag marks mean
dead bodies to me.
And anyone left alive who got
in the car with a killer...
Probably dead too.
Okay, the couch
goes right over here.
Be really careful that you
don't step on the chalk, okay?
And the string.
Really careful of the string.
Thank you.
She's a very bossy lady.
Morning!
Morning.
Wow, we're so lucky
that we could track
all this down, huh?
Nick's still working on it.
Evidently,
Las Vegas Consignment
keeps some pretty
shoddy records.
And some of the folks didn't
want to give up their stuff.
How did he charm them
into it?
Showed them
the blood spatter.
Nice. Okay, the end table
goes right here.
The barstool
in the chalked circle.
♪ ♪
Ha!
The, uh, cast-off
pattern extends
all the way
across the room,
which means that
the weapon was long.
You know, earlier,
I noticed
that the poker from the fire set
is missing.
That could be it.
All right,
so based on the spatter
on each of these
barstools,
I was able to determine
where they were
at the time of the beating.
And this one
is the hero.
All right, well,
that makes sense, right?
You take out
the biggest threat first.
Okay...
so I'm dad.
All right.
So I am the suspect,
standing right about here.
Point of origin is at
the convergence of string,
right where your head is.
Wait a minute. You know what?
You said that the victim was
struck multiple times, right?
Yeah.
Why am I just sitting
here taking it?
Nick said that he noticed
that one of the curtain tiebacks
was missing.
Yeah, maybe the victim
was restrained.
Yeah.
Tie me up.
All right.
Ow.
Sorry.
All right, so you're tied up
and I'm hitting you.
You know what?
That would explain
the gravitational drips down
the side of the stool here.
All right, so this is
the main blood event,
but without
the DNA results,
I can't tell you how many
other members
of the family were injured.
This is a lot of blood.
RUSSELL:
Yeah, I know.
Hey.
you guys have got
to see this.
The ground-penetrating radar
found something.
It's the family dog.
It looks like
it's been here over a month.
FINLAY: Well, it was
carefully wrapped.
Conners must have
buried it.
It gets worse, guys.
The throat's been cut.
That's horrible.
Nobody would do that
to their own dog.
No, that was a threat;
a warning
to one of the Conners.
Whoever that was knows
who sent it and what it meant.
Someone in the Conner family
was in way over their head.
Probably what got them
all killed.
You submitted over 50 samples
to DNA from the Conner scene.
We have a family of four
who are missing.
I would rather collect
too much than too little.
Right.
Okay, so how
are we doing
with the family
DNA reference samples?
All the obvious sources
of DNA in the house--
like hairbrushes
and toothbrushes--
all that was thrown out.
Mm. What about the trash?
Morgan and Hodges
are going through it,
but anything they find
is likely contaminated.
Until I get verifiable
references,
all I can tell you is which
donor bled where and their sex.
I will take whatever you've got.
Okay. Uh, the stains at the bar:
JF-1 and 2 match
Doug Adamson.
FINLAY:
Just as we thought.
I was able to identify another
male bleeder in the house,
but he only matched
one sample, JF-13.
Okay, so that's either
the father,
Dwight Conner, or the son,
Ethan.
Uh, given the limited population
of the four Conner
family members.
I'll take that as a yes.
Uh, all the other blood sources
in the house
originated from
a single female donor.
Female?
So the blood spatter
and the drag marks?
That's right.
Okay, so that's gotta either be
the mother, Claire Conner
or the daughter, Heather.
Assuming the limited
population...
...of the Conner family.
Yes, I get it.
Thank you.
Thank you, Henry.
Okay.
RUSSELL:
I don't get it.
I mean, on the surface,
the Conners seem like
this typical family, right?
The mom is a housewife,
daughter Heather's
homeschooled.
Which is why the school
didn't report her missing.
Is the homeschooling
a recent thing?
No. No, no.
There was a bullying incident
about four years ago.
Mom pulled her
out of school.
Has been teaching ever since.
Okay.
What about you? Did you find
anything in her room?
Well, pretty routine stuff.
Nothing that raised
any red flags.
Okay, all right, that leaves
Ethan the son,
he's out of high school.
Some of the neighbors say
that he hangs around
some shady characters.
But when you look at his record,
two speeding tickets.
The search of his room
is a different story.
Found some stash boxes
with traces of methamphetamine
and THC.
Now, I think they're
Doug's, the homeless guy's.
But if they're not...
you know,
then maybe Ethan, maybe Ethan
got into some trouble
with his sketchy friends.
Enough trouble
to kill the whole family?
No.
(phone chirps)
Sorry. Brass.
(knocking on door)
Oh, yeah. Hey.
Got your, uh, text.
You have something for me
on Claire Conner?
On February 1, Claire Conner
filed a police report.
Uh, she claimed someone
was stalking her.
Mostly minor vandalism.
You know, they keyed her car,
slashed her tires, threw
a rock through her window.
That would explain the glass
being recently replaced.
Yeah, well, on the same day
that she called it in,
she left the house for an hour.
She came home, all the cabinets
were left wide open.
So somebody got in.
Police officers
were dispatched.
They offered
to send a CSI tech to print
the place, but she declined.
That's interesting because
Henry just confirmed
that the blood on their
front porch was canine.
Their dog was killed
and displayed as a threat.
She never reported that.
That's a little odd.
(phone rings)
Oh. Excuse me.
Brass.
Okay. Good work.
So Dwight Conner worked
for Marvin Braxton
of Braxton Imports.
Coffee bean guy?
Well, coffee and other
Colombian imports.
Braxton fired Conner
one day before
the family went missing.
I'm bringing
him in now.
Dwight Conner worked for me
for seven years.
In what capacity?
He was my CFO.
Oh. Why'd you fire him?
He stole from me--500 Gs.
That's a lot of money.
Found out during
a routine audit. Took the money
from the company account,
put it into
his personal account.
Didn't even try to hide it.
That's not very smart
for a financial guy.
He denies it, you know?
But you can check for yourself.
It's in the account.
Did you know
that the Conner family
are officially missing persons?
I've heard something about it.
And are you aware
that they went missing
one day after
you fired Dwight Conner?
I am not aware of any dates.
I just figured they ran off
with the money.
Funny thing is
it's still in his account.
My new guy checked.
You know, we both know
that Braxton Imports launders
more money than it earns.
Those charges were dropped.
This is a big money hit
for any business to absorb.
I'll get the money back.
I got my own way of doing it,
and they don't involve going
after a family.
We think the Conner family
met with foul play.
You're talking murder now.
(laughs)
Uh-huh.
I have no idea about that.
You can direct any other
questions to my lawyer.
So this is
the son's car, huh?
Yeah. Auto shop called
after the broadcast.
Driver's side is
pretty banged up.
Car's been in the shop
for a month.
Obviously hasn't been
repaired yet.
A month? You know,
we keep running into this
four-week wall.
It's like life just stopped
for that entire family
in an instant.
Yeah. The mechanic called
the Conners with the estimate.
Never heard back,
so he put the car on hold.
Hasn't touched it.
They know what happened?
According to the DMV,
Ethan Conner was involved
in an accident February 15.
Claimed it was due
to brake failure.
Take a look.
The steel brake lines
on this car have been
completely cut
intentionally, front and back.
Maybe it put him
in the hospital.
I found a medical bracelet
belonging to Ethan in the car.
It's from
Desert Palm Hospital.
Well, Brass is convinced
that the entire family
is paying for the father
stealing dirty money.
You know, maybe
they were trying
to threaten the father
by hurting the son,
you know what I mean?
All Mob style.
(sniffs)
Ugh, you know, we're
not gonna be able to pull
any definitive DNA references
from all of this trash.
It's a waste of time.
I disagree.
I find garbage fascinating.
Yeah, that doesn't surprise me.
What most people throw away
in trash bags is actually
biodegradable or recyclable.
Unnecessarily taking up
the precious space
in our rapidly
diminishing landfills.
Hey, don't look at me.
I recycle.
I've started
recording my garbage
in a trash journal.
So now I discard no more
than 3 pounds per week.
You have a trash journal?
Yeah.
This looks like a contract
for a storage unit.
"Maybrook Storage."
Rented to "Doug Adamson"?
February 19, 2014.
It's the morning after he had
a sleepover at the Conner house.
"Unit 353."
Why would Doug Adamson
need a storage unit?
"353."
Ugh...
Hard to mistake that smell.
FINLAY:
There's a lot of blood.
Inside is empty.
Keys are still in the ignition.
(car door shuts)
Finn.
Dwight Conner.
Where's the rest
of the Conner family?
(distant siren wailing)
I.D. confirms that
this is the dad--
Dwight Conner.
Large volume of blood
tells us that
he was killed here.
Based on the castoff,
he was struck multiple times.
No kidding.
Mr. Conner's skull is in,
like, a million pieces.
There are bone fragments
embedded in the wood.
Doug must've been really angry.
(grunts)
♪ ♪
Confirmed blood in the trunk.
Did you find any blood
in the rest of the car?
Not a drop.
Hmm.
DNA match.
Blood in the house,
female donor.
(sighs heavily)
Okay, so either Claire
or Heather Conner
is killed at the house,
then put into the trunk
of the car,
the body dumped somewhere.
Then Mr. Conner
was driven here
to this storage unit,
where he was killed.
That means that Dwight Conner
was with the killer
when he got rid
of the body in the trunk.
Dead weight is heavy.
Maybe the killer needed
Conner's help.
BRODY: Looks like there's tar on
the passenger side of the car.
They must've picked it up
around the time
Mr. Conner was killed.
Means the car was driven
over a freshly paved road.
Find the road, maybe we'll find
the rest of the Conner family.
How many times do
I have to tell you?
I never rented
any storage locker.
How else do you explain
these photos, Doug?
They were taken
at Maybrook Storage
at 9:35 a.m.
The same day the Conner family
went missing.
I was digging trenches
in the Conner's yard
that whole morning.
That is not me.
The shirt you're
wearing in the photo
is the same one I collected
from you at the hospital.
I can't be the only guy in
the world who likes plaid, man.
Dwight Conner was found dead
in a storage locker
that you rented.
With his head bashed in
by a baseball bat.
Conner's wife, Claire, and
their two children are missing.
Blood is spattered
all over their house,
the same house you
were squatting in.
Look, I told you, they
invited me to live with them.
(door opens)
BRASS:
Okay, Doug, so you're telling me
that you never saw any
of the Conner family before?
That's what I keep telling you.
You're lying, Doug.
You and Ethan Conner were
on a 72-hour psych hold
in the same facility
on the same day.
January 13.
He was there for an O.D.
You were for medical detox.
So?
So, there's only
ten people in the unit!
You're telling me
you never even saw the guy?
Nope.
So it's just a coincidence
that Ethan offered you
a job at their house
and his whole family
may be dead?
Look, I'm not saying
I'm a saint.
Okay? I've been an addict
since I was 13.
Alcohol, coke, meth,
you name it.
But I have never hurt anybody.
Admit it--you'll do anything
to feed your habit.
Even kill.
If we charge you
for this crime,
you're looking at murder.
You know what that means?
So do yourself a favor.
Tell us where the rest
of the Conner family is,
and maybe we can cut a deal.
I'm done talking.
I want a lawyer.
Okay, so I've got some
DNA results here for you.
The unknown male DNA
we found in the house
is a match to Mr. Conner here.
So he was injured there,
and then killed in the--
in the storage unit.
And then Henry compared
Mr. Conner's DNA
against the unknown
female blood.
There were no markers in common.
She they're definitely
not related in any way.
So it wasn't the daughter
that was killed in the house.
It was the wife,
which is interesting.
Conner here was fired
by his boss Braxton
for embezzling, right?
Brass confirmed that it was
a lump sum electronic deposit
of a half-million dollars.
So what if--
what if Braxton
or one of his goons
forced Dwight here
to watch his loved
ones being murdered
before he himself
was beaten to death?
Except we still haven't found
a link between Braxton and Doug.
We do know
that Doug knew Ethan.
They were both addicts.
Maybe this was some kind
of drug deal gone wrong.
And the family is just
collateral damage.
Boy, beautiful wife,
two kids, a dog.
I mean, I bet they seemed like
the perfect American family.
Nothing's ever
what it seems, is it?
No, it's not.
So did you, uh--
did you already make a note
on the trace on these pants?
The reddish dust?
I figured it was
soil or crushed brick.
It's embedded in the tread
of his shoe as well.
You know, if the killer used
Dwight to help dispose
of the other bodies,
he could've picked
that stuff up from
where they were buried.
Are you familiar
with the Mesozoic Era?
The Age of Reptiles?
Ah, I see
someone paid attention
during earth science class.
The Mesozoic Era was
250 million years ago,
during a time
in which Nevada's landscape
was developing formations
of salt and gypsum.
As the years passed,
oxidization gave
these formations
a beautiful crimson hue,
creating what we now know
as Red Rock Canyon.
The red powder that Nick found
on Mr. Conner's pants and shoes.
Secluded.
A perfect place for a killer
to bury the rest of the family.
Still, that's over
100,000 acres.
Actually, over 200,000.
Right.
You know, I did find some tar
on the passenger side
of the SUV.
Means the killer drove
over a freshly paved road.
So, we're looking
for an area of Red Rock
near a road that was paved
about a month ago.
Yeah.
Good.
Hey, it's Brody.
(quietly):
Thanks.
Can you get me the
Department of Transportation?
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Oh, ah ♪
♪ Oh-ho-ho ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ ♪
♪ The storm never came ♪
♪ Or it never was ♪
♪ Didn't know ♪
♪ Getting lost in the blue ♪
♪ It meant ♪
♪ I wound up ♪
♪ Losing you ♪
♪ ♪
♪ Welcome
to the inner workings ♪
♪ Of my mind ♪
♪ So dark and foul ♪
♪ I can't disguise ♪
I think I got something.
Could be a body.
Yeah, okay, let's start digging.
Okay, everybody,
let's bring it in!
Looks like
we got a body.
♪ Welcome
to the inner workings ♪
♪ Of my mind ♪
♪ So dark and foul ♪
♪ I can't disguise ♪
♪ Hurricane ♪
♪ ♪
(indistinct
police radio chatter)
Found some kind of fabric.
That's the missing curtain
from the Conner house.
Okay.
Definitely female.
STOKES:
Badly mummified.
You think it's Mrs. Conner?
Yeah, either that
or her daughter.
(sighs)
Hey.
Hey, Finn.
So Nick and Morgan
are still out there,
but they haven't found
any other bodies.
I'm just finishing up
with our victim here.
FINLAY:
Ligature marks on her wrist
confirms she was restrained.
Multiple contusions
to the head as well.
Was that the cause of death?
Subarachnoid hemorrhage
caused by blunt-force trauma.
The weapon cracked the skull,
but it didn't perforate it.
Suggests that the killer didn't
have much upper-body strength.
Were you able to narrow down
what the weapon was?
Something heavy.
An inch or less in diameter.
Could it have been
a fireplace poker?
That's consistent
with her injuries.
There was one missing
from the house.
(door opens, closes)
The victim's X-rays.
FINLAY:
Is that an IUD?
ROBBINS: I did remove
an intrauterine device
during autopsy.
According
to their medical records,
Claire Conner had a hysterectomy
five years ago.
That means
this is not Claire Conner.
And Heather was never
prescribed birth control.
So it's not the daughter
either.
Who is this woman?
Hey.
Hmm?
You know the great thing
about IUDs?
Besides the obvious?
They have serial numbers.
Meet Jessica Fenton,
our mystery woman
buried in Red Rock.
Her DNA matched
the female blood in the house.
Well, that's interesting.
So Ms. Fenton here was killed
at the Conner house,
then put in the back
of their SUV,
driven out to Red Rock,
and buried.
Do we know why?
I mean, what's the connection
to the family?
Well, I'm working on that.
She was an IT specialist,
worked from home.
Landlord reported her missing
when she didn't pay her rent.
Nick just recovered her laptop,
so he's going through it
right now.
(passionate breathing,
laughter)
(sighs)
Is that Dwight Conner
in a sex tape?
Oh, yeah, but not with his wife.
This was taken
three months ago.
Looks like
he and our victim
from the Red Rock were, uh,
having a little fun on the side.
She's totally playing it
to the camera.
Oh, yeah, but I
don't even think
he knows it's there.
And check this out.
Jessica Fenton's hard drive
was filled with hundreds
of these photos.
All of Conner and
his wife and kids.
Claire Conner was right--
someone was stalking
their family.
Yeah, but it all happened
pretty fast.
I mean, the affair
happened in December.
And then a few weeks later,
she goes
all Fatal Attraction on him,
breaks into his house,
and then kills the family pet
after treating it like that.
And that's cold-blooded.
Well, she also tried
to kill their son.
I found diagonal cutters
at her house.
Liquid on the hinge smells
and looks like brake fluid.
Okay, all this time,
we have been thinking
that this entire family is dead.
Maybe we're wrong.
The cheating husband,
the mistress--both dead--
but who's the most
obvious suspect right now?
Claire Conner. I mean,
if she found out
about the affair,
she could've killed them both.
STOKES:
Yeah, and then what?
Just grabs her kids and...
gets the hell out of Dodge?
BRASS:
I gotta say,
Dwight Conner picked the
wrong woman to mess with
with Jessica Fenton.
She used her computer skills
to hack
into the company server
and then transferred
half a million bucks
into his private bank account.
She got him fired.
Yeah.
Yeah, and as if
that wasn't enough,
Nick found evidence
that she contacted the wife
and gave her the sex tape.
RUSSELL:
Proving that Claire Conner
knew about the affair.
Yeah, and she also knew
who was threatening her family.
Nick also found an email
from Claire to Ms. Fenton
on February 18
saying, "We need to talk."
That was one day before
the family went missing.
Which explains
why Jessica Fenton
was at the Conner house
in the first place.
Okay, so...
Claire Conner confronts
her husband's mistress.
Mm-hmm.
Things escalate.
Claire hits her.
Jessica falls down.
(panting)
Do you like the tape I made
with your husband?
RUSSELL: Obviously,
the rest of the conversation
did not go very well.
Get off me!
(screaming)
And we also know
that Dwight Conner's blood
was found at the scene,
so at some point,
he came in there
to try to intervene.
What the hell are you doing?
Stop!
CLAIRE:
Give me it.
No!
(groans)
So now Claire and Dwight Conner
have a body
in their living room.
Okay, they have two options:
they can call the cops
or cover it up.
They chose the latter.
They wrapped her in a curtain,
put her in the back of a car,
and buried her out at Red Rock.
And they drove
to the storage place,
where Claire Conner
killed her husband.
Okay, that all
makes sense, right?
Except for the storage locker.
I mean, we know
that Doug Adamson rented it.
We got him on surveillance.
So how's he fit
into all of this?
Someone set him up.
It's a strong possibility
that the person on that tape
was not Doug but someone
that looked like him.
There's no physical evidence
that he was there.
Okay.
Any evidence of the wife?
No. No DNA from her either.
Well, so then what are you
so excited about, Henry?
Dwight Conner
fought his attacker.
I found tissue under his nails.
And you have the DNA results?
Y-STRs match Mr. Conner.
A male relative?
So Dwight Conner was killed
by his son
in the storage unit.
And I think I know why.
I found evidence
of sexual activity
on Jessica Fenton's underwear.
It was an admixture of her DNA
and that same male profile.
Uh, all right.
So the son,
Ethan,
was having an affair
with his father's mistress.
You said Jessica Fenton
was trying
to destroy Dwight Conner's
family--maybe, maybe
seducing the son
was part of that plan.
Right. Ethan finds out
that she's just using him,
maybe even tried to kill him.
He takes his rage out
on his father.
And now he and his mother
and his sister
are in the wind.
BRODY:
Russell?
Yeah.
You have a minute?
So I traced the
mistress's credit cards.
Around the time
she was murdered,
one of them was used
to buy three bus tickets
to Prescott, Arizona.
Claire Conner
and her two kids, right?
Right. Next day, same card
was used to book a room
at an extended stay hotel.
Hasn't been used since.
Are they still there?
Brass contacted Prescott PD,
but when they got to the room,
the only one there was Heather,
the daughter.
The daughter?
Yeah.
I haven't seen Mom or Ethan
in two weeks.
Why didn't you call the police?
I didn't want
to get them in trouble.
Well, I mean, they're
already in trouble.
Your mother killed
Jessica Fenton.
Your brother k-killed your...
My father.
I know.
Were you in the house when
Jessica Fenton was murdered?
No.
No, I just came home,
and I saw that...
she was lying there,
dead.
And there was blood
all over the floor.
ETHAN: What did you do?
(screams)
What were you thinking, Mom?
CLAIRE:
You don't understand.
She was never gonna stop.
Who is she?
Ask your father.
This is all his fault.
We have to call the police.
No, no, no, no.
No one's calling
the police, honey.
Dad, we have to!
Look, here's what
we're gonna do.
We're gonna clean this up,
and we're gonna disappear
as a family.
It's okay.
Nobody ever asks me what I want.
People just make decisions
in my life,
and I get no say.
And now,
because of my parents,
I don't ever get to see
my friends again.
What about your brother?
He was part of the plan.
And how did he track down
that vagrant, Doug?
Ethan remembered him
from the mini-mart.
(sniffles)
He said every morning
he would be there,
looking through
the Dumpsters for food.
We found him right away.
And your mother and brother
invited him to stay
at the house?
Dad thought it was better if...
people thought we were dead.
You find some weird homeless guy
living there,
and everybody would think
that he killed us.
(grunts)
Boy, your dad thought
he had it all figured out, huh?
My dad and Ethan went
to drop off the car,
but only Ethan came back
and met us at the bus station.
He had blood on him.
When you saw the blood,
did you ask him what happened?
No.
He just said we were better off
without Dad.
Honestly,
none of this would have happened
if he had just kept it
in his pants.
(sighs)
So your family decided to...
take matters
into their own hands?
Yes.
My family ruined my life.
Then why protect them?
I'm not.
Tell me where your mother
and brother are.
I said I don't know.
Come on, Heather.
You don't know where
your mother and brother are?
No!
I don't believe you.
People don't just vanish.
They said they were going
to see a movie,
and I haven't seen them since.