(thunder rumbling)
(phone ringing)
Hello.
SIDLE: I heard you cleared
your scene. Nice work.
Would you mind, um,
picking me up a veggie burger
from RJ's on your way back?
I guess. They do have
a drive-through.
BRODY:
Hey, it's Morgan.
Uh, mind picking up me
a veggie burger, too,
and Finn a grilled cheese?
All right, but you ladies
are gonna owe me.
MORGAN: Thanks.
WOMAN: The National
Weather Service has issued
a flash flood warning
for the city of Las Vegas
and outlying areas.
Winds are expected to reach
50 miles per hour.
The Clark County Regional Flood
Control Center is keeping
a close watch
on the storm basins...
(groans)
It is nasty out there.
Can't argue with that.
Maybe we shouldn't have sent
Greg to get our food.
No, he's a...
he's a great swimmer.
ANDREWS:
Wait, Greg's on a chow run?
I could really use some soup.
Ooh, or chili.
Yeah, actually you guys are
gonna have to fend for yourself
out of the
refrigerator tonight.
Uh, yeah.
Wouldn't be the first time.
I knew that was you.
All right, all
right, listen up...
Wow.
P.D. just pulled a man
out of a flood channel
with a suspicious head injury;
we need to process him.
Treat it like a crime
until we know otherwise.
Who's up next?
That'd be me.
(clears throat)
Sorry.
Thank you.
Got a male, early 30s, severe
hypothermia and head injuries.
Okay, take him
to room three.
This your guy
from the flood channel?
Yeah, he's lucky his bag
got stuck on a tree limb.
Kept him from washing
further downstream.
Doctor, we need you
in room three, stat!
Agonal respirations
on contact.
Weak brachial pulse,
unable to get a BP.
On three. One, two, three.
NURSE:
Glucose is 50 mg.
Any I.D. on him?
If there is, it'll be in there.
DOCTOR: Breathing is
shallow but regular.
Blood pressure is 85/50.
I'll get him on the monitor.
EMT: There wasn't any
obvious swelling to the head.
Laceration's deep.
DOCTOR: Make sure
we get a core temperature.
Let's start by warming him.
Then we'll address
the head wound.
G-Guys?
Back out of here slowly
and take him with you.
What is it?
Bomb!
And it's armed.
It's a bomb.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
♪ ♪
Control, EOD-one.
I have the
target in sight.
Can you, uh, confirm that
the building is all cleared?
CONTROL (over radio):
EOD-one, Control.
Building is clear except
EOD personnel and target.
How you holding up?
Just willed myself
not to sneeze.
Almost blew us both up.
Keep up the
sense of humor.
I wasn't kidding.
Okay. Here's what I'm gonna do.
I'm gonna slide my hands
underneath that satchel.
I'm taking the weight
off your arms.
Now, it's crucial
that you don't do anything
until I tell you, okay?
I'm not about
to make any sudden moves.
I'm Anthony.
Sara.
You're doing great, Sara.
Okay.
I'm sliding my hands
under the satchel.
Okay?
Now... slowly
drop your arms
six inches
straight down.
(thunder cracks)
(gasps)
It's okay. It's okay.
Come back to me.
It's okay.
Now...
with your arms
in that position,
slowly walk directly back
until you're clear.
♪ ♪
You sit tight while I
take this thing outside.
EOD-one, phase
one complete.
UXO's in the portable,
in the big
bucket in two.
I'm gonna need those bomb parts.
Copy that.
You'll get whatever's left.
(electricity humming,
computers beeping)
(muffled explosion in distance)
ANTHONY:
All clear!
(sighs)
(thunder rumbling)
You Greg Sanders?
Yeah.
You've been served.
Have a nice night.
Some guy just served me
with papers.
CSI Three Greg Sanders,
meet Defense Criminalist
Jennifer Rhodes.
Ms. Rhodes is here
to review the evidence
on People v. Gus Ellis, 2006.
Yeah, that, uh,
doesn't ring a bell.
Ms. Rhodes,
wh-why don't you give us
the Reader's Digest
version.
Gus Ellis served seven years
of a life sentence
for the rape/murder of
college student Claire Gibson.
Since his case
hinged on DNA,
it fit the Innocence Project's
protocol.
We extracted touch DNA from
her jeans and her underwear,
which matched that of serial
sex offender Clyde Maroni.
Testing wasn't sensitive enough
for touch DNA back in 2006.
Maroni confessed
and pled to a life sentence.
Now Gus Ellis is free
and wants answers.
I've been hired
by his civil attorney
to see the case through.
So, if science
proved his innocence
through new and
improved technology,
what's the basis
for the lawsuit?
Well, a week before her murder,
Claire Gibson called the police
complaining that a man
was looking at her
through her bedroom window.
Gus Ellis was identified
as the peeper.
I remember that.
He was also
the one who called 911
from the Gibson murder scene.
He said that he looked
through the victim's window,
saw her lying there,
and claimed
she was already dead.
He was arrested that same day,
which we call...
a rush to judgment.
He was the person
of interest
in an investigation
started by the victim.
A week later, he calls 911
from her murder scene.
No prints, no semen,
no evidence linked Mr. Ellis
to the inside of that...
I-I remember that
there was a crowbar
next to her with
his blood on it.
Mr. Ellis stated that he never
went inside that house
and he never touched
that crowbar.
RUSSELL:
He claims only way his blood
was on that crowbar
is if it were planted.
What?!
He's saying that I
planted his blood?
How?
A reference blood sample
was collected from Mr. Ellis,
a blood sample
that you received at the scene.
(knocking)
Come on in.
Finlay's gonna be working
with Ms. Rhodes
on the re-examination.
Until they're finished,
I need you on desk duty.
(thunder rumbling)
(monitor beeping steadily)
He's still out.
How you doing, Sara?
I'm a little shaky.
Nothing like staring into
the abyss for 20 minutes
to decide what's important
in life.
It's sad how it takes
something so...
intense to make us stop
and smell the coffee, huh?
Bomb guys disrupted the device
to render it safe.
I sent what was left
to Hodges.
Well, police officers are
walking the flood channel.
It would be good to know
how long he was in there.
It only takes ten minutes
in 50-degree water
to get hypothermia,
but he could've been
in there longer than that.
He got hung up on
a tree branch.
We need to quickly I.D. him
and find out
what he planned
to do with that bomb.
(computer beeps)
Oh. I have a match.
Uh...
Yeah. Uh, name is Warren Hackett
from Atlanta, Georgia.
It's not our guy.
(groans)
473 Snowdrift Lane?
Last time it snowed in
Atlanta, I had a fake I.D.
Somebody wants to keep
this guy's identity a secret.
Then we go old-school.
Police are asking the public's
help in identifying this man.
He was pulled
from a flood channel tonight
in serious condition.
If you have any information
about his identity,
please call
the Las Vegas Police Department.
Hey.
Oh, my God. I am so glad
to see you in one piece.
(chuckles)
You and me both.
I got you a veggie burger.
It's in the fridge if you want.
Thanks. Uh, as soon as I get
my appetite back, I'm...
Right. Well, you can
have it later, I guess.
Um, so, I thought in order to
find where our bomber went in,
we could apply some logic,
so I got us a map of all
flood channels in Vegas.
I'm thinking he fell in the
water somewhere near his target.
Okay, if I was a bomber,
I would look for someplace
with a lot of people.
Probably looking at a casino.
Guy got pulled
out of the water... here.
Backtrack upstream.
Closest likely targets are
the Tangiers, Queen Regent
and Mediterranean.
(phone chiming)
Oh. Our John Doe's awake.
I'm, uh, heading back
to the hospital.
See you later.
(coughing)
This dust
could be toxic!
Where's my particle mask?
(coughs)
You got to die
from something.
(groans, coughs)
Man, Sara held certain death
in her hands for 20 minutes
and never moved.
Do you think it's true
that your whole life flashes
before your eyes
in those situations?
Did for me.
I'm listening.
I was 18,
getting my wisdom teeth pulled.
When I got the anesthetic...
Malignant hyperthermia
from anesthetic can be fatal.
They need a crash cart?
Not exactly.
It was my first experience
with a mind-altering drug.
I thought I was dying,
began to hyperventilate,
hallucinate.
And?
In my addled state,
I fell madly in love
with the dental assistant.
For some reason,
I had to tell everyone,
including her.
Turns out, it was just an
adverse reaction to the drugs.
(singsong):
Awkward.
No. Humiliating.
I never went back.
I still have my wisdom teeth.
You?
Perhaps another time.
Why don't you take what's
left of the satchel,
and I'll concentrate
on the bomb frags.
MAN:
Margarit t'agavorakan.
BRASS:
That's not English.
Sounds Slavic or Russian
or something.
Keeps saying it the same
way over and over again.
Well, hold on,
I have a translator app.
Maybe we can figure out
what he's saying.
Margarit t'agavorakan.
(phone beeps)
He's speaking Armenian.
Margarit means "pearl."
App doesn't recognize the rest.
Guy with a bomb, speaking
a foreign language,
possibly in code,
hacked into AFIS
so we don't
identify him.
That's a guy with
a lot of expertise.
That's the profile
for a terrorist.
One thing I know
about terrorists:
they never work alone.
Hey, Finn, I'd really like
to take a look
at my case notes.
Greg, I can't talk to you.
I have to remain
completely objective
while I work
with the defense expert.
(sighs)
FINLAY: Greg Sanders
worked this case solo,
so all of the
photographs are his.
The left screen shows
the digital code--
shot sequence, date, time,
any edits or deletions.
So we can tell if any of the
photographs have been altered.
Greg started by
photographing the exterior
of the crime scene first,
which is protocol.
Shots were almost
two minutes apart.
Looks like he finished
the exteriors just after 0600.
Now he's moved on,
inside the house.
Starting with the
body in the bedroom.
When I was working
crime scenes back in Detroit,
I liked to save
the victim's room for last.
Hmm, I'm the opposite.
I like to work the
toughest room first.
The first shot of the
bedroom was an overall.
First shot with
the crowbar
was a perspective shot.
RHODES: Now Sanders is moving in
for the close-ups.
20 minutes later, he finishes
photographing the bedroom.
Moving on to do
the rest of the house.
Finishes photographing
the rest of the house
and returns to
the bedroom.
What? He took over
50 photographs of the room.
Why go back?
Shouldn't he start collection?
Newer CSIs tend to take
more photographs than they need.
I was taught that film
is cheap-- of course,
that was back when
we used film.
(chuckles)
Look at that.
Crowbar's been moved,
up and to the left.
According to the
Major Incident Log,
Greg was alone
in the crime scene
until almost... 0730.
When did the reference
blood arrive?
He signed for it at 0705.
So Sanders was
in the crime scene
with the reference blood
from Ellis and the crowbar,
completely alone.
(thunder rumbling)
Margarit t'agavorakan.
Aren't you taking "death
imminent" a little too far?
Not the first
time we've had
a live one
in here.
Brass called.
Wanted to know if I could narrow
down where the guy came from.
Hospitals are running
on generators,
not doing any elective tests,
so I brought him over.
What'd you find out?
No surgeries, no birthmarks,
scars or identifying features.
His teeth are coated
in fluoride,
and he has a
porcelain filling.
So if he is
from Armenia,
he came to America when
he was very young.
They don't do dental work
like that over there.
Margarit t'agavorakan.
Sounds like chanting to me.
Word repetition.
Reminds me of a
case where a man
fell into a frozen
lake in Milwaukee,
came out speaking
Portuguese.
David, fire up the
fluoroscope, please.
Yeah.
Margarit t'agavorakan.
Bleeding at his temporal lobe.
Could be a case
where head trauma causes
a person to speak
a foreign language.
It's a condition called TGA--
Transient Global Amnesia.
It only lasts
about 24 hours.
So, what he's saying
is coming from
his subconscious,
something important to him.
Margarit t'agavorakan.
Mr. Sanders.
You took these
photographs
at the Claire Gibson
crime scene.
34 minutes apart.
The crowbar's been moved.
Did you move it?
If...
I saw that the crowbar
had been moved,
it would be in my notes.
It's not noted.
During the time
between these two photographs,
you were the only person
inside the crime scene.
You know, I am so focused
on my own work, I...
barely notice
what anybody else
is doing at a scene.
My former supervisor,
Gil Grissom,
trained me to follow
a particular procedure
so I didn't have to
rely on my memory.
Now, I was so afraid of
making a mistake and being
sent back to the lab
that I followed that
training exactly.
FINLAY:
And yet, this evidence
was moved
after it was documented
and before it was collected.
RHODES:
That's not protocol
in any crime lab.
I would be more than
happy to answer
your specific questions if I
could just review my notes.
That's all we need right now.
Should I be worried?
Greg, a man served
seven years for a crime
he did not commit.
We all should be worried.
(thunder rumbling)
I just heard you're in
the middle of a defense review.
Yeah. Kind of rough.
It's hell.
It's the worst part of the job.
Only, I'm not being accused
of making a mistake;
I'm being accused
of planting evidence.
Well...
the evidence is gonna win out,
Greg, I know it.
(phone ringing)
Yeah.
Oh, shoot, I got to go.
Brass found
the bomber's hotel room.
I'll call you later, okay?
(siren whoops,
indistinct police radio chatter)
BRASS: So, the manager
of the motel
recognized our John Doe
from the TV news.
Said he checked in
yesterday.
After she called the hotline,
right, she checked his room,
saw some guy tossing it.
She get a description?
No, some guy-- white
guy, blue shirt.
You know, he saw her, he freaked
out, he jumped off the balcony.
Here's the manager here;
she has a heart condition.
She's on the oxygen
and a cigarette.
Thanks for your help.
I hope you feel better.
Got to love Vegas, huh?
SIDLE: Looks like our bomber's
friends got here before we did.
Got scared off.
Well, whatever they were after
must have been important.
Something that would
tell us who they are.
Or where their next target is.
His clothes are mostly
in a pile by his suitcase.
I'm not sure he ever unpacked.
(indistinct
police radio chatter)
Three pair of tightie-whities
means three days of travel.
No suits.
All his clothes are casual.
Maybe a little too casual.
BRODY:
I got two chargers.
No electronics.
No evidence the bomb
was assembled here.
(thunder rumbling)
I got an American passport.
It's our bomber.
Name's Arman Agakian.
Armenian surname.
SIDLE:
Huh.
I got a flash drive.
Guy hides a flash drive
and a passport.
We might be looking at a pro.
(beeps, buzzes)
Ah, Henry.
You're just in time
for my demonstration.
Wait, you seriously
built a bomb?
I'm going back to tox.
I chemically tested
the bomb frags,
pieced together what I could,
then used identical components
to precisely duplicate
Sara's bomb.
This is disturbing
in so many ways.
Why? It's just a magnetic
switch, circuit board delay,
military blasting cap,
and a couple of pipes.
'Kay, just to confirm,
your bomb doesn't actually
contain explosives?
No. It's identical to the
original complex pipe bomb,
except I substituted
lightbulbs for explosives.
Now, lifting this switch
will duplicate the
action that Sara took
when she opened up the
magnetized satchel flaps.
If it's all wired correctly,
then the lightbulb should go on.
For the boom, you'll just
have to use your imagination.
Uh... if this does blow up,
I will come back from
the dead and haunt you.
This is perfectly safe.
(gasps)
Well, that was fascinating.
I came by to give you
DNA results.
Uh, no DNA off the bomb parts.
Only John Doe's DNA
on the straps of the satchel.
So it's back to
the drawing board.
You want to help me?
No, thanks.
I'm testing something for Finn.
(sighs)
Ecklie wanted me to review
the-the Gibson case as well,
because the department
and the D.A.'s office
are named in the lawsuit.
Sit down for a second.
13 women reported seeing Ellis
outside their homes
over a two-month period.
He was caught on three
separate security cameras.
He had no criminal record, yet.
Although, escalation's
pretty common
for voyeurs.
At the trial,
a coworker testified
that Ellis threatened
to get even with Claire Gibson
because she had started
the whole thing
by calling the police.
So Ellis definitely had motive
to kill Claire Gibson.
I mean, if this
happened today,
Brass would be
all over him like that.
That all may be true,
but we've just found
uncontroverted evidence
that the crowbar was moved
at the scene.
Things get moved accidentally
at crime scenes all the time.
Greg was the only person
in the crime scene
when it happened.
(sighs)
All right, you know,
leaving aside the fact
that we know Greg,
what possible reason would
he have to frame Gus Ellis?
It doesn't make
any sense.
A new CSI trying
to impress his boss.
No, I'm not buying that.
You know, I may be the
newest CSI around here,
but it's a pretty rotten job
to have to comb through
all of Greg's work.
I didn't choose you
because you're new, Jules,
I chose you
because you've been there.
You know how this
has to go.
I hated you when
you investigated me.
I don't want Greg
to feel the same.
It's a search for the truth.
He'll get over it,
just like you did.
Now, tell me
about this crowbar.
Whose was it again?
Joe Gibson, Claire's brother,
came over to fix a broken gutter
the morning of the murder.
He left it outside,
so it's his.
D.A.'s theory
was that Ellis
used the crowbar
to break into the house,
broke a window,
cut himself in the process.
There was only one
small smear of blood found
in the entire crime scene.
Ellis's attorney
only has to show
access and opportunity
to implicate Greg.
I know.
Defense attorneys are gonna
bring up this allegation
every single time
he testifies.
He is going to be a liability
on every case he works.
His career will be over.
(phone chimes)
I got to go.
FINLAY:
What'd you get?
Can I just say this?
Greg is one of the most
honest guys I know,
and a great CSI.
He would never intentionally
compromise a case.
Uh... one microliter
per mil of EDTA
was detected in the blood
from the crowbar.
Blood preservative.
That would be consistent
with blood collected
in an EDTA tube.
Thanks, Henry.
But for your report,
you should add that there are
trace levels of EDTA
in our blood from hundreds
of everyday items--
soap, mayonnaise,
salad dressing, beer, milk...
I get it.
...soda, ointments,
detergents, breakfast...
Henry, I get it.
You know what? It's fine.
I'll just put it
in my report.
I will, too.
(thunder rumbling)
(sighs)
Sanders.
Right?
She looked at you like
you were guilty of something.
Excuse me?
Terri Royce,
the new chemist.
Oh.
What'd you do?
Uh, nothing.
I... it's...
Good heavens, spit it out.
I'm being sued
for planting evidence.
(laughs)
We've all been accused of that.
You didn't do it, did you?
No. Of course not.
Good. Come in here and help me
with this Armenian
bomber evidence.
GCMS identified
polyunsaturated oil
consistent with peanut oil
from the suspect's pants
in fragments of the satchel.
Take a look.
SANDERS: Looks like what ends up
at the bottom of a deep fryer.
I worked at a fast-food
joint in high school.
Ha! Me, too.
I'm from New Orleans.
I didn't want to I.D.
fried food on my first day.
What would y'all think?
A couple of days ago,
a barrel of frying oil
intended for
recycling got spilled
outside the Mediterranean
and caught fire.
Closed the loading
dock for hours.
That would explain this.
SANDERS:
Carbon ash?
From the fire.
Looks like the bomber
was hanging
at the loading dock
of the Mediterranean.
Which has direct access
to the flood channel.
I think you just found
the bomber's target.
(laughs)
All day long.
(sighs)
Thanks for saving
me and coming out.
Hey, any day
I can be outside
without my blast suit
is a good day.
(chuckles)
I wanted to get a
bomb expert's opinion
on our guy's activities.
Glad I could help.
So, Arman Agakian
gets pulled out
of this flood control channel
about three miles downstream,
holding a bomb.
We couldn't
get past here.
This is how he got in.
ANTHONY:
Yeah, but where was he headed?
SIDLE: Maybe he was trying
to take a shortcut upstream
to the other end
of the Mediterranean.
I mean, no terrorist would want
to walk through the casino
and be on a hundred cameras.
It's way more stealth
out here, but...
he didn't make it.
He slipped, fell in, and
was swept downstream.
Yeah, makes sense.
Trace evidence we found tells us
that he was
at this loading dock.
I was hoping you could help me
narrow down a logical target.
Yeah. Let's go take a look.
Thanks.
(people chattering)
This is where
that oil fire was.
For a bomb that size,
you'd need the perfect location.
In Iraq, they'd put bombs
in culverts under the road.
You know, out of sight,
maximum damage.
Kind of like a gas main
under a casino.
Thanks.
A hell of
a force multiplier.
Even a small charge would
kill a lot of people.
SIDLE: There's a disturbance
in the dirt under this meter.
Could be from a satchel.
And somebody left...
a little calling card
on this sharp edge.
(thunder rumbling)
Perfect time
for my new DNA instrument.
You have a mobile lab?
In the back of my car.
No extractions,
quick results.
You want to see it?
Wow.
(machine beeps)
(beeping)
(siren approaching)
Blood isn't Agakian's.
So someone else placed the bomb,
and Agakian removed it?
(car door opens)
Sara?
Thought you'd
want to know.
Agakian flatlined
an hour ago at
the hospital.
What?
He did not have
life-threatening injuries.
I just saw him
with Doc Robbins.
David Phillips
is picking him up.
(sighs)
Damn it!
Uh, hi. Uh...
Can I help you?
Yeah. I'm from the
coroner's office.
I'm here to pick up
a... Arman Agakian?
No can do, pal.
I have my orders.
Federal orders trump yours.
He's FBI property now.
I went to Tovin's in Pahrump.
Best baklava in Nevada.
I brought you
some pastry.
And I got Tovin to translate
that mystery Armenian phrase.
The guy is saying "pearl royal."
Sounds like the name
of a stripper.
(laughs): Yeah,
it does, doesn't it?
How you holding up?
Just eager for this whole thing
to be over with.
It's crazy, right?
Everything we do
every day is scrutinized,
but it's different
when it happens in front of you.
In your own lab.
I just wish that
I could remember more details.
Greg, you've worked hundreds
of cases since then.
You can't expect
to remember every detail.
Yeah, but the details that
they found don't look too good.
And if Finn and that
expert can't exonerate me--
and I mean completely--
I'm through as a CSI.
EDTA in the blood
from the crowbar
is consistent with
the hospital blood tube.
We need to nail down
Sanders' timeline.
Well, I tracked his movements
through the crime scene
based on the
photo data code.
0617 to 0637,
Greg took 57 shots
in the bedroom with the victim.
Then he moved through the house,
taking a total of 45
other shots encompassing
25 minutes.
FINLAY:
Exited the house to receive
Ellis's reference blood
at 0705,
factoring in a couple
of minutes to sign
and initial the paperwork.
He then returned to the house.
RHODES:
Four minutes later,
he took the photo
showing the moved crowbar.
If Sanders made a conscious
decision to frame Ellis,
four minutes is
enough time to do it.
All right, let's see.
He'd have to carefully
break the seal, open the tube,
smear the blood on the crowbar,
put the cap back on,
reseal the package
and take the photo.
All with no guarantee
that he wouldn't be seen.
It's possible.
Who received Ellis's
reference blood at the lab?
Did they note any
discrepancies in the seal?
FINLAY: Uh, Wendy Simms,
the DNA analyst at the time,
received the blood sealed
and initialed.
It's in her notes.
RHODES:
And then Sanders took
the final four shots
in the bedroom,
and then no more,
until the exterior shots
after the scene was broken down.
To document the condition
of the crime scene
after the police had left,
which is protocol.
Wait a second.
You see that?
There's blood
on the sidewalk
outside the scene.
There was no blood outside
the perimeter in any of
Greg's initial shots.
That means someone bled
outside the scene after
the perimeter was set.
Gravitational drops.
Where did that blood
come from?
Simms also tested
a handkerchief
that was in Ellis's pocket
when he was booked.
Blood on both
was Ellis's.
How did the blood get
on the handkerchief?
Doctor at the hospital noted
that Ellis had no injuries.
Added what looks like "Noble"
in all caps.
Does Ellis look like a
handkerchief kind of guy to you?
FINLAY: Amido black
reacts with the blood.
RHODES:
Look at ridge detail.
It's surprising Simms didn't
process the fingerprint
in the first place.
Well, there was
no context for it.
The only useful evidence
would have been
to find Claire Gibson's blood
on the handkerchief.
Otherwise, it's just
Ellis's blood
on Ellis's handkerchief
in Ellis's pants, so...
wouldn't have been
a big deal.
(beeping)
"Yancey Langer.
Restricted access."
State employee?
His name is on the
Major Incident Log.
Does this look
familiar to you?
Looks like the handkerchiefs
my mom always buys me
for Christmas.
Why?
Do you remember
Claire Gibson's murder
from March 21, 2006?
Sure.
I remember everything.
It was my first murder scene.
I was a Police Explorer
back then.
Your handkerchief was found
inside Gus Ellis's pocket.
He was the suspect at the time.
Can you explain that?
Yeah. I was waiting on a radio
car to take him to the hospital
to get a blood sample
or something.
Guy was sitting on the curb,
scared, got a nosebleed.
He was dripping blood
everywhere.
I tried to stop it,
then gave him my handkerchief.
Nosebleed. N-O-B-L.
That was the abbreviation
on the doctor's notes.
RHODES: According to the
Major Incident Log,
you stayed outside
the perimeter
of the crime scene
the whole time.
That's not true, is it?
When the officers left with the
suspect, I snuck into the scene.
I never saw
a dead body before.
Did you touch anything while
you were in there?
No.
Are you sure?
I tripped.
Kicked a crowbar on the floor,
but I put it right back
where it was.
Do you realize that you
transferred Ellis's blood
from your hand
to that crowbar?
That blood was the physical
evidence that convicted him.
RHODES: Gus Ellis spent
seven years in prison
because you went
into a crime scene unauthorized
to see a body
and contaminated the evidence.
I never followed up
on the case.
Didn't even know
the guy was convicted.
I'm so sorry.
I...
I didn't know.
I'm gonna make some calls.
ANDREWS:
Is it safe in here,
Crazy Harry?
Still can't figure out
how the bomb was activated.
I'm stumped. I've double-checked
all the connections
from the magnetic switch
to the circuit boards
to the blasting caps
to the pipes.
Still doesn't work.
Then the circuit
isn't the problem.
Let me see.
Blasting caps creep me out.
I remember a public service film
in grammar school taught
kids not to play with them.
Showed a kid who
bit down on one.
Ugh!
Yeah.
Made a big impression on him.
And me.
Just... (imitates explosion)
That blasting cap
completely fragmented.
Why is this one still intact?
There's white powder
still inside.
I mean, shouldn't
the explosive be brown?
RDX and PETN are both white.
But this should have been
completely consumed
in the controlled blast.
Yeah, we should test it.
By "we," you mean me?
Primary explosives are
friction-sensitive
and flammable;
it's more up your alley.
I'm a body fluid guy.
Not touching that.
Powder should burn
when exposed to flame.
ANDREWS:
Well, there's the problem.
That white stuff
isn't explosive.
That bomb was never intended
to go off.
How's it going?
God, I have tried
everything I can think of.
Anything that we found
in the hotel room,
anything that
he was hiding,
anything we know about Agakian--
none of it's working.
I just... I can't
figure out
the pass code
to this flash drive.
Have you tried the info
from that bogus AFIS hit?
Everything I can think of.
What about... the fake address?
What was it again?
473 Snowdrift Lane.
(computer trilling)
Look at the intersection
that's highlighted.
We cracked the password
on that flash drive.
But it looks like
I'm a little late.
CSI Sidle.
Sara, this is
Ben Parker,
special agent, FBI.
We'll need
to take that flash drive.
Cut your arm
on a gas meter cage?
You're here about Arman Agakian.
Although, I'm sure
that's not his real name.
He's probably
not dead, either.
Agakian's FBI, Sara.
He's been working
undercover
for the last couple years
to infiltrate the Armenian mob.
They've been extorting money
from The Mediterranean.
He posed
as an explosives specialist.
Last night was his big drop.
You gave him two dud bombs
that seemed very real
to plant at The Mediterranean.
(thunder rumbling)
He planted the first one.
When he went
to plant the second one...
...he slipped into the flood
channel and got washed away.
After that,
we had to abort the op.
We picked up the bomb
at the loading dock.
Scratching your agent's arm
in the process.
How does planting dud bombs
help your undercover op?
We planned to discover the bombs
very publicly first,
then release to the media
that they were very dangerous
and expertly made.
Fooling the Armenians and
establishing your agent
as an explosives expert.
What about the
intersection
of Pearl Street and
Royal Avenue in North Vegas?
What was that about?
That's where our undercover
met his Armenian contact.
Probably why Pearl-Royal stuck
in his mind.
And the extortion plot--
has that been aborted as well?
Our undercover
was able to identify
the individuals responsible.
We're arresting them
right now.
Good.
Parker's men are gonna need
to take custody
of all the evidence.
Of course.
If we're square here, I need
to speak to Captain Jim Brass.
Sounds like a good idea.
WOMAN:
Federal agents descended
on the Mediterranean Casino
today,
taking five Armenian nationals
into custody.
The individuals arrested
are suspected to be members
of an Armenian
organized crime ring.
Our lawyers scheduled
a deposition
with Langer
for next week.
Unsure how it's gonna turn out,
but Sanders is off the hook.
I'm glad.
Well, no offense, but I hope
the next time I see you
will be at an American
Academy meeting.
(laughs)
See you later.
Thank you.
Hey.
Talked to Greg.
How's he doing?
Look, I guess I get
why you thought you had to
treat him the way that you did,
but it's tough to be on
the receiving end of that.
Yeah, I know.
I had an I.A. investigation
in Seattle,
and Russell treated me
the exact same way.
Still not over it.
Greg's in the locker room.
Hey. Congratulations.
Thanks.
I know I was really hard on you.
I was trying to do my best
for someone
that I really do care about,
but I couldn't act like it.
I had to seem impartial,
or it really would have
hurt your case.
Hey, I understand.
Greg, I never thought
you did anything wrong.
How about that grilled cheese
at RJ's?
That sounds great.
My treat?
Okay.