(indistinct conversations)
Lieutenant Hughes?
You got a suspect
for me, I believe.
We are bringing him in now.
Felony auto theft, right?
Your lab sent
this file over.
Some kid totaled
Councilman Hawk's new BMW?
You got a political one.
Jacob Baker.
Jacob Baker?
Isn't he the guy that
CSI Stokes brought in for
pointing lasers
at airplanes?
I thought Nick had scared him
straight, but I guess not.
All right, tell the councilman
he can rest easy.
We will get justice
for his Beemer.
HUGHES:
Thanks for bringing
him in, Blake.
No problem.
Headed back out on patrol.
Change of plans.
I cleared it
with your sergeant.
I need you to cover Dolan
at the reception desk.
Okay...
You know how I love
taking orders from you.
Am I going to have to report you
for insubordination,
Officer Hughes?
Go ahead. I'll claim sexual
harassment, Lieutenant Hughes.
RUSSELL:
Guys, get a room.
Oh, that's right, you don't have
to, you're already married.
(chuckles)
So, tell me about the kid.
Give you any trouble?
No. Seemed like a mama's boy.
You should talk.
See what I have to
put up with?
Ooh.
Sir, I am connecting you to
Detective Crawford right now.
Cavalry's arrived.
What did you do to your wife
to deserve this?
Just taking one for the team.
Well, it's all yours.
I need you to
fill out your name
in the top box there,
and then
your home address
goes in the box
right below that.
Okay, who's next?
Please step up
to the counter.
Hey, kid, what do you
think you're doing?!
Son, you got to wait
your turn.
Hey! Did you hear me?
(people exclaiming)
Just relax, all right?
Just take it easy.
(gunshot echoes,
casing clatters to floor)
(distant screaming,
Blake sighs)
(sputters)
MAN:
Go, go!
(woman whimpers)
(whimpers)
(gunshot, casing clatters)
(panicked shouting)
(woman sobbing)
(casing clattering)
(officer grunts,
distant screaming)
(gunshot, casing clattering)
(panicked shouts)
MAN:
He's got another gun!
(woman sobs)
(rapid gunshots)
MAN:
Hold your fire!
Russell's in there!
(panting)
Okay.
Okay, easy.
(groans)
Just take it easy.
(panting)
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
PAULA FRANCIS (on TV):
...Desert Palm Hospital.
Our understanding is
the shooter has now
barricaded himself
inside an interrogation room
and is holding hostages.
No word yet on whether or not
What the hell's going on?
there are any casualties.
It looks really bad.
Guys, I just got off
the phone with Brass.
Russell is in the room
with the shooter.
What?!
They haven't been able
to make contact with him.
They're still
securing the building.
Okay.
Well, the best
thing we can do
for everyone right
now, is our jobs.
So, Greg, you want to head over
to PD with me right now,
see what's going on?
Yeah. Sure.
I'll go to the hospital,
collect evidence.
I'll run things
from here.
(man shouts orders)
...the generators
are good to go.
All men in position!
Weapons high!
(gun clicking)
BRASS: Mr. Mayor,
all I can tell you now,
is I have one officer dead
and four others wounded.
It seems like the shooter
was targeting police officers.
We're clearing the building now.
I'll call you back
when I know more.
Sir, you wanted to see me?
Lieutenant Hughes,
I saw the wounded list.
Your husband's on it.
(whispering):
Oh, my God.
He was at the front desk
when the shooter came in.
I know.
(trembling):
I'm the one who put him there.
How bad is he?
You should go to the hospital.
But...
No. Go. Go. Debbie, go.
Go. We got this covered. Go.
Where's that camera feed
from interrogation?!
It goes directly into
the observation room.
I'm trying to reroute it.
I need eyes on that room!
Yes, sir.
(phone ringing)
(Jacob yells)
Hey! Hey! Hey, you!
Back against the wall!
All right. All right. All right.
JACOB: What the hell, man?!
Why'd you shoot me?!
TEEN: I didn't shoot you,
I don't even know you.
Everyone just shut up!
(groans)
What happened,
did you get hit?
Man!
Cops are firing rounds
in this room, you probably
caught one the same time he did.
Probably cracked a rib.
(groans)
(phone continues ringing)
You're gonna have
to let me answer this.
I told you, no.
Let me, let me tell you
how this works.
If I don't answer this
pretty soon...
(phone continues ringing)
...cops are gonna think
I'm dead.
And they're gonna think
that he's dead.
And then it's not gonna just
be a couple of rounds.
They're gonna
light this place up.
Well, maybe that's what I want.
You think I didn't know
I was gonna die today?
(computer trilling)
Hey, did you talk to Russell?
No. He-He's not picking up.
Yeah. Well, radio silence
usually means one thing:
Guy's not giving up.
If your CSI's still alive,
best chance to save him...
tactical entry.
That is a negative.
We're not there yet, Dolan.
And when we are, it's
gonna be too late.
Yeah, and if we go in too early,
everybody gets killed,
so why don't you just...
be cool right now,
all right?
God, it's friggin' cold
in here, man.
He needs a doctor.
He's all right.
(struggling):
Oh, yeah... g-g-great.
I'm gonna take a look at him.
Hey! You don't move!
Hey.
Listen, you know, I don't
know what your deal is.
I don't know why you thought
you had to do this,
but it has nothing to
do with Jacob here.
You got the gun.
You're in charge.
Besides, you know something,
I don't, I don't think
you want to see him suffer
any more than he has.
Do you?
All right. Mm.
(panting)
Jacob, you're not
gonna like this.
(groans)
Ready? Here we go.
(screaming)
Okay. All right. All right.
(groaning)
That's good, buddy.
There you go.
Was that really necessary?
Lean forward here.
I'm going to...
(short rapid whimpering)
Come on. Okay.
(groaning)
Well, you know what?
You are a very...
very lucky boy.
How is getting shot
being "lucky"?
Well, uh, because... (grunts)
(groans)
the bullet went
straight through,
so all we have to do is
stop the bleeding here.
(Jacob groans)
Here we go.
(groans)
All right. All right.
(Jacob groans)
Give me your hand.
(groaning, whimpering)
You're doing great.
JACOB: Oh...!
What's your name, son?
What do you care?
(sighs) It makes for an easier
conversation, that's all.
You first.
My name's Russell.
D.B. Russell.
Your turn.
No uniform.
No suit.
No gun.
You're not a cop.
No. I'm a CSI.
Is that why
you didn't shoot me?
You got a beef just with cops?
(panting)
(laughs)
C-CSI, huh?
Mm-hmm.
Like a science guy?
Yeah.
Makes sense.
Looks like you know
what you're doing.
If you mean,
I know first aid,
yeah, but that doesn't take away
from the fact that
he needs a doctor.
BRASS: How are we doing on
that camera feed?
I think I'm only going to
be able to get your picture.
No sound.
I'll take anything you can get.
(phone ringing)
(phone beeps)
D.B.?
RUSSELL:
Yeah, Jim...
OFFICER:
Captain, I got it.
RUSSELL: We got you on
speakerphone here,
just so you know.
BRASS:
What's your status?
Uh, I think
we're okay...
for the moment.
I do have a young man...
Jacob here, who needs
medical attention.
But our, um,
our friend with
the gun here,
is not comfortable
bringing a doctor in.
BRASS: We can get you
anything you need.
Food, water... medical supplies.
All right.
Okay, I think
we've agreed on that.
So, I guess the young man with
the gun is listening on speaker?
Yeah. I'm here.
What do you want?
BRASS: Well, I was gonna ask you
the same thing.
What do I want?
BRASS:
Yeah. What do you want?
Nothing.
BRASS:
What's your name, son?
Yeah. We-we already
tried that, Jim.
(sighs)
What do you want?
Maybe one thing...
a laptop.
Any luck recovering
any of the bullets?
I'm working on it.
Any word yet on Russell?
He's okay.
He was able to contact Brass
and now they have a
direct line of communication
with the gunman.
I found a photo
in Officer Matsuda's wallet.
Four kids, all boys.
Has the family
been notified yet?
No. I guess they
want to keep a lid
on what goes out
to the public,
in case the gunman is watching.
Meanwhile, his poor family
has no idea
that he's not
coming home tonight.
Looks like a nine millimeter.
Consistent...
with the weapon
we found on the scene.
(metal clinks)
Hopefully,
with this bullet
and that weapon,
we'll be able to I.D.
the shooter.
♪ ♪
HUGHES:
Blake?!
Blake?
Debra?
Hey.
Sara.
Where is he?
Wh-Where's Blake?
They took him upstairs--
he's in surgery.
So-so he's not...?
No. No. No.
They're working on him
right now, uh...
I'm sure the doctors
will have some news soon.
Why did this happen?
Why now?
I-I was just starting
to think that things
were gonna be good again.
Blake and I,
we-we've had our struggles...
Both you being on the job...
I know that's not easy.
But that was behind us.
We were ourselves again,
making plans for the future.
And now...
Debbie, you can't believe that.
Not right now.
Okay, Blake is gonna
pull through this.
He's gonna come through this.
You have to believe that.
Okay?
(groaning, panting)
The pain's getting worse.
RUSSELL:
Meds will be here
in a second.
You know,
you just need one of us.
True... but
isn't he more valuable than you?
Being a civilian and all?
BRASS:
Okay... All right, well,
we've cleared the building.
(sighs)
And now we need to figure out
a plan to get Russell
and the injured kid
out of there.
Yeah, alive.
Sir,
you wanted sound,
I got it for you.
I put a mic inside this
epinephrine injector.
I figure we could
get it to Russell
with the rest
of the medical supplies.
Nice work, Dunn.
Now, we need to figure out
a way to let Russell know
that there's a microphone
implanted in this device.
I can take care of that.
OFFICER:
CSI Sanders is approaching
for transfer!
OFFICER:
He's got a laser on you.
No sudden moves!
TEEN:
Put down the bag
and the laptop.
Put your hands to the sides
and turn around.
Slowly!
I'm not armed.
Just the delivery guy.
What's your plan now?
You can take the delivery.
(panting)
(door closes)
Glad to see you're still
in one piece.
(sighs)
How bad is it?
It's pretty bad.
It's all here:
Food, water... meds.
Oh, uh,
I grabbed your epinephrine
from your desk.
I'll keep it close by.
Thank you.
TEEN:
Hey, what's the hold up?!
No hold up.
I'm coming back in.
Hey, Russell.
I'll be back in a while.
Coming in.
(footsteps approaching,
computer trills, beeps)
Hey. You texted me.
You got something?
So, the bullets
that we recovered from
Officer Matsuda didn't
provide us anything, but
the shooter dropped a gun
and that's another story.
Gun's been through
a lot of hands.
First, seller and then
seven other sales after that.
Ending up in Arizona.
Purchased last year
by Mr. Holland Walker.
Age 48.
Scottsdale address.
How does Mr. Walker's gun,
in Arizona,
end up in the hands of a kid
shooting up LVPD?
Call Walker.
See if he has an answer.
(keyboard clicking)
What are you doing?
Looking for yourself
on the news?
RUSSELL:
How you doing here, Jacob?
Feeling good, sir.
Actually, I'm not...
I'm not feeling much
of anything.
Well, that's 'cause
you're on some
pretty good
drugs there, buddy.
I'm just gonna
clean you up here
and you'll be good to go.
JACOB:
Well, you're the doctor.
Hey. Hey.
Hey. Do me a favor, will you?
Give me a hand here.
I'm-I'm not asking you
to put the gun down.
I just need,
I just need a hand.
Give me some water.
Please.
Oh, come on, will you?
You afraid to get your
hands bloody, or something?
Hand me the water.
Come on.
All right.
That was a close one.
Russell knows what he's doing.
What is that medal?
Is that Saint Christopher?
Yeah. So?
Well, it just looked like it was
important to you, that's all.
I used to have
one of those.
Good for you.
Easy. Easy. Easy.
(groans, panting)
My wife gave it to me.
She wanted to protect me
at work.
(chuckles)
Who gave you yours?
I told you this whole, "Let's
have a conversation" thing
isn't going to work.
It's gonna make for a
hell of a long evening.
Maybe.
Maybe not.
JACOB:
Come on, dude.
Don't be such a tool.
I'm ju... I'm just saying.
If this was supposed to be
a suicide mission,
then why aren't you dead?
You know something?
I think you're wondering
the same thing.
I think there's
someone out there
you don't want to hurt.
You know, someone who's
worried about you.
Maybe the same person
who gave you that medal.
I'm thinking you should shut up.
Oh, hell. Uh...
Hold onto this,
just for a second.
Easy, easy.
You all right?
Thank you.
DUNN:
Why's he looking
at us like that?
The water bottle.
What about it?
Get me a screen grab.
Isolate that bottle.
Yes, sir.
(computer whirring, beeping)
STOKES:
Son of a bitch,
he just got us
the guy's prints.
I told you he knew
what he was doing.
FINLAY:
Are they good enough to run?
In the right hands... yes.
This should do it.
We'll see what we got.
(computer whirring)
FINLAY:
Mark Powell. 16 years old.
16-year-old walks into PD
and starts killing cops.
How does that happen?
Well, his juvie
record's sealed.
Maybe there'll be some
answers in there.
Well, maybe there's
some answers here.
(computer beeps)
Got a home address.
STOKES:
That's the kid's mom
right there, Cynthia Powell.
Does she have any idea
why her son
might do something
like this?
No.
She talked to Brass.
She's still in shock.
Said she doesn't even
own a gun.
Has no clue how her son
would be able to get his hands
on an arsenal like this.
Who's processing their house?
Morgan.
And she also told Brass
that the kid used
the family van.
Patrol found it a
couple of blocks from here.
Impound's bringing it in
right now
if you want to
get on that.
Yeah. I will.
STOKES:
All right, good luck.
I'm so sorry.
So are we.
(sighs)
Okay, Mrs. Powell, come on,
I want you to have a seat...
(trembling):
Oh, my God! Mark.
BRASS:
Mrs. Powell,
come have a seat please.
Okay.
(crying)
I'm gonna ask you
to phone Mark.
Now, I know this
is tough, I do,
but I need you to try
to reach out to him.
I don't know what to say to him.
Just remind him
that he's your son,
you know, tell him
that you love him.
And that he has a future
if he will just...
let these people go
and come home with you.
(whispering):
Okay.
Can you do that?
(voice breaking):
I'll try.
(phone ringing)
(sighs)
Yeah... yeah,
go ahead, answer it.
Yeah, Jim.
BRASS:
Well, I assume
that the young man
is listening over the speaker?
Yes, he is.
I have someone
who wants to speak with him.
(crying):
Mark, sweetheart,
it's me.
M-M-M-Mom?
W-W-What are you doing here?!
The police found me.
What? How?!
It doesn't matter, sweetheart.
You need to let
those people go.
You've got to stop this.
Mark.
You son of a bitch.
You played me.
You think I'm an idiot...
No. I don't, Mark.
I just think you need help,
that's all.
"Mark"?!
All right.
You-you got my name,
you found my mother,
but you don't know who I am!
But the world's gonna know,
'cause you know why?!
'Cause it's over.
(gunshot)
OFFICER: Shots fired.
Mark!
I need you to leave.
It's for your own safety.
No!
Promise me
you won't hurt my son.
Officer Wincroft, escort
Mrs. Powell to an outer office.
What the hell's going on?
I heard a shot.
DUNN:
Still got ears in there,
Captain.
What's going on in there?!
RUSSELL:
Mark...
Hey, come on.
Don't do anything
that we're all gonna regret.
I think we're way past that!
Actually, no, we're not,
but we will be.
In about five seconds,
they're gonna come
busting through that room
and then we're all dead.
Unless you let me
call them off.
What's it gonna be?
Mark?
Jim, we're okay.
Do you copy me?
What the hell's going on
in there?
We just had a little family
disagreement, that's all.
Mark and I
are working it out here.
I'm gonna need a few minutes.
I will call you back.
You and I have nothing to say.
Now sit down.
Sit down, man!
DOLAN:
This kid's a time bomb.
Thermal imaging can give us
a heat signature
on anybody in that room.
We could put a .30 cal round
right through the wall.
End it right now.
And what assurance
do we have
that you're gonna target
the right signature?
I agree.
We're not gonna wait
this kid out.
He killed cops! He knows he's
not walking out of here alive!
That sounds like you've
already made the decision
that nobody's walking
out of there alive. You!
You're the one...
You better watch
who you're poking!
Calm down! Calm down!
The two of you calm down!
That's an order!
Calm down.
Dolan, my heart is with you...
...but my head is with Nick.
Now, Russell's in there,
and I'm gonna give him a chance
to talk this kid out of there.
But we also need to give CSI
a chance to work this case.
The better we know Powell,
the better the chances are
to get Russell and Baker
out of there alive.
You got it?
SANDERS:
Powell's mother said
she hadn't seen much of him
the past couple weeks.
Now we know why.
He's been living in here.
The usual smell of teen spirit.
Yeah, and teen angst.
Self-hatred, depression.
Looking at his journal,
I'd say
that he'd be more likely
to commit suicide than homicide.
(camera shutter clicking)
Looks like he found another
outlet for his feelings.
Did his homework, too.
Even downloaded blueprints of
the PD from county archives.
He's been planning this
for a while.
BRODY:
But not planning it alone.
Take a look at this.
There are hundreds of e-mails
and IMs going back and forth
between Powell and this
username LookingGlass419.
This e-mail exchange
is from six months ago.
"Saw another po-po shooting
on the news.
"Homeless guy shot 16 times.
Since when is sleeping
on a bench a crime?"
Powell responds:
"5-0 got no respect."
LookingGlass: "Maybe someone
needs to teach 'em some."
BRODY:
More e-mails like that.
LookingGlass talks about
how much he hates the cops,
Powell agrees.
Then LookingGlass
suggests a plan
to attack police stations.
Some kind of suicide pact.
Powell is suicidal,
but he wouldn't be able
to do this on his own.
He needs an alpha; someone
to give him
a sense of purpose
and meaning in his life
that he's missing.
I think you're right.
This last e-mail exchange
is from ten days ago.
LookingGlass: "It's on.
I selected targets. You in?"
Powell: "Bring the pain.
Let them never forget."
LookingGlass:
"I got guns, burner phones.
From now on,
total radio silence."
All right, so we know
Powell's part of the plan.
Now what about
LookingGlass,
what's his target?
Which police station?
And when's he gonna strike?
Listen to me now, Mrs. Powell.
I think that Mark had help
planning this attack
from somebody,
somebody who got in his head
and encouraged him
to do the things
that he's done.
I don't understand.
A partner.
There's somebody else out there
planning an attack.
Maybe an attack
on a police station.
If we can find him,
stop him,
then maybe he can help us
stop your son.
We found some e-mails.
This partner goes
by the screen name
"LookingGlass419."
Does that sound
familiar to you?
No. I'm sorry,
it doesn't.
Not somebody he hangs out with?
A friend of his
from high school?
Anything like that?
A friend?
Mark doesn't
have any friends.
Not since Elliot was killed.
Who's Elliot?
The neighbor's boy.
But he was more like
a brother to Mark.
He spent a lot of time
at our house...
before he got into drugs.
About a year ago,
Elliot robbed
a liquor store.
(voice breaks):
The police cornered him,
they thought he had a gun,
so they shot him.
After Elliot was killed,
Mark was inconsolable.
You know, that would explain
his e-mails expressing
his hatred
for the police.
Mark said
a lot of stupid things.
He's a teenager!
He's done a lot
of stupid things now, too,
hasn't he? I'm familiar
with that juvie record.
He's been arrested
multiple times for
vandalism, assault...
I know!
You know, and you didn't
do anything about it?
You didn't see the warning signs
that he was capable
of something like this?
I did. I got
him into therapy
and into after-school
programs.
I mean, even one of your
own Police Youth Sports Camps.
(voice breaks):
Mark started going
to church with me.
We prayed to
Saint Christopher.
I gave him a medal.
And I told him that every time
he got upset about Elliot,
sad or angry,
that he should pray
until the anger left him.
I love my son.
I swear, I tried.
Mitch, hi.
Sara.
How you doing?
I've been better.
I just want to get out of here.
Well, it's gonna be
a little while.
You were shot in the stomach.
Did we at least get
the damn shooter?
He's on lockdown.
Russell's on it.
You hang tough, okay?
(indistinct conversations,
phones ringing)
He's gone.
Blake, he's-he's...
he's dead. (sniffles)
I'm so sorry.
You know, it's crazy,
but I can't stop playing it over
and over in my head.
All the "if only's,"
all the dominoes
that line up and fall over,
and we have no idea where
they're gonna take us.
You know, Miller's kid's sick,
so she leaves early,
so I shift Dolan to patrol,
which means I put Blake
at the reception desk.
You couldn't have known
this was gonna happen.
It's not your fault.
That's my point.
All the little pieces...
...if it hadn't all gone
the way that it did, then...
...Blake would-would
still be here.
Alive.
(Jacob groaning)
(groans)
This sucks!
I think the pills
are starting to wear off.
I'm sorry. I wish
I could help, but I think
you've topped out
on the dosage there.
You're not looking
for yourself on the
news, are you?
You keep checking
your phone.
You're waiting for a text
or a news report or something.
Is there someone else
is out there, Mark?
Someone who's
gonna do
the same thing you just did?
Just shut up, man.
You don't know a damn thing.
You've changed.
Just shut up.
You said you wanted
to die today,
but something's
different.
I know a little something
about the will to survive,
and I think I'm seeing
that in you right now.
You want to survive,
don't you?
(Jacob coughing)
You all right, Jacob?
You having trouble breathing?
My chest feels kinda heavy.
(gasping)
Okay, all right, we're
gonna take care of you.
I think the bullet nicked
his lung.
It's starting to fill up
with blood.
So? Look...
do-do something.
Listen to me. I can't.
He needs a doctor.
He needs a hospital, Mark.
(Jacob coughs)
I can't do that, man!
Jacob is not a cop, man!
He's not one of those people
you declared war on!
You-You know this
bullet in here?
That's a police bullet.
You let him die now,
it's not gonna be on them.
It's gonna be on you.
Is that what you want?
Call ahead.
Let 'em know our ETA.
Watch your back.
Russell was able
to talk Mark Powell
into letting
the wounded kid go.
Maybe he's finally getting
through to him.
If not, where are we
on the partner?
Greg's got the warrant.
He's tracing the e-mails from
LookingGlass419 as we speak.
We should know something soon.
RUSSELL:
You're going be okay, Jacob.
Thanks.
I hope you get out of here.
Both of you.
All right,
let's move out.
Hold your fire.
He's coming out.
(door closes)
Hang in there.
We got you.
Make way for him.
(phone rings)
Yo, what do you got
for me, Finlay?
Greg's been running a trace
on LookingGlass.
Nick, what he's found
does not make any sense.
What do you mean? Tell me.
All of the the e-mails came
from one server.
Whoever is Powell's partner,
whoever he has been
communicating with...
is someone inside
the police department.
Officer Dunn,
give me a minute.
Take a break.
(door closes)
Are you sure about this?
Greg verified the server's IP.
At least half the e-mails
the shooter received
have been sent
from a computer
inside PD.
What the hell
is going on here?
Look, all this time
we thought LookingGlass419
was just some
other screwed-up kid
looking to shoot up
some other police station.
Like this was some kind
of suicide pact.
But I'm telling you, Jim,
LookingGlass is one
of us, it's a cop.
And there was never
some other target.
This has always been
the target, LVPD.
Yeah, but-but why?
Why would a cop do this?
STOKES:
Whatever the motive,
man, this is crazy.
Yeah.
Yeah, this is crazy.
I want this guy.
STOKES:
Whoever it is,
they knew Mark Powell very well.
They know he hates cops,
and they know
he's a ticking time bomb.
So you say that
all the messages
came from
our server?
Which computer?
I don't know.
Greg's running it right now.
(exhales)
Not happening, is it?
Whatever it is
you're waiting for.
Or... whoever it is
No, i-it will, okay?
We had...
we had a plan.
He won't let me down.
(sniffs)
I think he already has.
And I think
you know that.
Mark...
I know it seems like
there's no way out
for you right now.
But there is...
There isn't.
Yeah, I blew away
a bunch of cops!
They're just
gonna kill me!
Not if you walk out...
with me.
And then what?
(sniffles)
Do you think I'm crazy?
No, I don't.
That's too bad.
(sniffles)
It's looking like that's
all I got left, you know?
Some kind of insanity plea.
I just don't
want to spend
the rest of my
life in a cage.
It's not about what you want.
You gave that up
when you walked in here.
I'm-I'm not gonna lie to you.
There are gonna be consequences,
obviously,
but if you choose
to live, man, there's...
you can make something
out of that life.
What if I don't?
Don't you do that.
(sniffles)
(grunts)
(panting)
Okay, I won't.
Okay, then,
you're going
to do it.
Kill me...
or I will kill you.
No one else is gonna
die here today.
(gasping)
(sobbing)
BRODY:
How's the trace going?
Figure out which computer
at PD sent e-mails to Powell?
It's a bit more
complicated than I thought.
I'm comparing each terminal's
user history
with the server history.
It's a process of elimination,
until I find a match...
How many terminals are there?
Seventy-two.
How many have you done?
Eleven.
I'll help.
I just heard.
Is it true?
Is the kid gonna
give himself up?
Yeah, it seems that
Russell talked him out.
You think he's
on the level?
Well, we'll know
in a second.
RUSSELL:
Jim, we're coming out!
Wait for my call.
BRASS:
That's far enough.
D.B., I need you to step aside.
Sir.
No, no, you're fine.
You're fine. Just do
everything they say.
I'm right here.
BRASS:
All right, Mark.
I want you to do
exactly as I tell you,
and only
what I tell you.
Put your hands above your head
and interlock your fingers.
Get down on your knees.
Mark, do what they say.
I got him.
BRASS:
Now lay flat on your stomach.
BRODY:
Let's get this
info to Brass.
You heard him!
Get down! Now!
Gun!
RUSSELL:
Mark, no. Mark, no!
(gunfire)
(shell casings clattering)
Oh...
He was reaching for a gun.
He was reaching for this.
Officer Dolan.
Give me your weapon.
It was a good
shoot, Captain.
Put him into custody.
Captain, it was a good shoot.
What's going on?
This doesn't
make any sense.
WOMAN (over P.A.):
Lab tech to Radiology.
Lab tech
to Radiology.
We got the shooter.
I heard.
We also, uh, tracked down
the computer in PD
that Powell was
communicating with.
Who was it?
Dolan.
Oh, my God.
The marital troubles
that you talked about,
Dolan was the
other man?
He said that
after you
went back to Blake,
he couldn't handle it.
He said he couldn't
stop calling,
he wouldn't
leave you alone.
So-so Dolan was
behind all this?
I don't believe it.
Yeah, neither do I.
The e-mails came from
Dolan's computer,
but we checked
the duty roster.
He wasn't there
when they were sent.
So... he had nothing
to do with this.
S-So it was
someone else?
Somebody who had a
connection to Powell.
Somebody that he
crossed paths with
when he was trying to
straighten his life out.
We found this
photo from, uh...
last year's Police
Youth Sports Camp.
I don't believe this, Sara.
That kid killed
my husband.
He killed Blake.
Yeah.
He did, Debra.
Because you set the
dominoes in motion.
Like you said, "All
those little pieces..."
We searched your house,
we found your laptop.
You created
LookingGlass419.
We searched your locker and
we found the burner phone
that you used
to text Powell.
You gave him the "go"
two minutes after
you put your husband
on the reception desk.
You took advantage of
a mentally unstable
16-year-old boy,
you used him to
kill your husband
and you designed
it to look like
some random
explosion of violence.
You betrayed
your badge.
You didn't care who
else he wounded,
you didn't care who
else he killed.
Why did you do this?
Because Blake was never
going to let me go?
He beat me?
I-I did it for
the insurance?
I don't know, Sara,
come on.
Do you... do you
really think that
there's anything
that I could
say to you
to make you
understand?
Y...
Before I... I say
anything else,
I really think
that I sh...
I should speak
to my police reps.
You do that.
(handcuffs clicking)
♪ ♪
In the news, they're going
to make him into a monster.
(crying):
But he wasn't.
You were with him at the end?
Yes, ma'am.
What did you see?
Well, I saw...
(sniffles)
I saw a young man
who was confused
and in a lot of pain.
I saw what you saw.
And whatever
you hear
in the days to come...
only God can judge.
And God can forgive, too.
(sobbing)