MAN:
Welcome to the Premiere,
where every player's a star.
(slot machine tunes playing,
tokens clinking)
MAN: All right,
lucky number seven, here we go!
DEALER:
Player has blackjack!
(players cheer)
CROUPIER:
No more bets.
Roll seven.
MAN: Come on, red, big money.
Come on!
(applause and cheering)
(indistinct chatter
on police radio)
SANDERS:
What do you think, Dave?
Blunt force trauma
to the back of the skull.
And her liver temp tells me
she's been dead about two hours.
I.D.?
No purse, no cell phone.
Nothing.
That is an elaborate model.
Must be a story there, huh?
The Premiere?
Yeah.
It was Jack Witten's dream.
In Jack Witten's house.
I've never seen it before.
Well, that's because
it was never built.
I could write a book
about the Vegas that never was.
So many casinos were imagined
and never realized.
The most legendary of all,
The Premiere.
It was Jack Witten's vision
to build a casino
that resembled his father's
old Hollywood movie studio.
What happened?
Well, like in the movies,
the dream ended in scandal.
Jack Witten lost his investors
when he became the prime suspect
in the murder of a young woman.
And here we are again.
Nice house.
Who lives here?
BRASS: Jack Witten.
He's an odd duck.
He's a modern-day
Howard Hughes.
That's him,
right over there.
A former party boy
turned recluse.
Said he was downstairs
in the screening room,
fell asleep, came up,
found the girl.
Tried to revive her.
Called 911.
Any sign of a break-in?
No.
Just some wine bottles
and drug paraphernalia.
You know, it's weird.
14 years ago,
we had the guy
for the same crime.
It's déjà vu
all over again.
Why? What happened?
We didn't have enough
evidence to make an arrest.
Powerful guy? Connected?
Back then.
Not anymore. Now he's shuffling
around in his slippers.
Hey.
Hi.
It's, uh, pretty
ugly in there.
Have you seen Sara?
Thought she was with you.
I think we got
the son of a bitch.
This had to come from
Jack Witten's house.
It should be enough
for a warrant.
Guy like Witten--
might not be that easy.
What do you mean?
This is Vegas, Sara.
RUSSELL:
Sara? Sara.
Got something?
A piece of the past.
Yeah, I heard
about this Witten guy.
Are you thinking
that the strand has something
to do
with the crime scene downstairs?
Well, 14 years ago...
I think the crime
scene was right here.
Tell me about her.
Who--who was she?
Darcy Blaine. 18.
Jack Witten
picked her up at a bar.
Security cameras caught
them leaving together.
He had a thing
for younger girls.
Darcy was never seen again.
They never found her body.
You think she was murdered
in this room?
It was my first
high-profile case in Vegas.
Catherine was supervising
in Grissom's absence.
I got it.
Witten's the one who got away.
I've spent a lot of time
with Darcy's family.
She was a troubled, wild kid
who never had a chance
to find her way.
I've been there.
But we do have a girl that was
killed in this house tonight,
so, let's focus on that, okay?
Yeah, I am.
I--I have waited a long time
to get into this room.
And that girl downstairs
might still be alive,
if we put Witten
away 14 years ago.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
So this guy Jack Witten
was a movie fanatic.
Let's see what was
playing last night.
Okay. Fade in.
I'm Jack Witten.
Welcome to my sleazy sex pad.
Glass of wine?
Why not?
Glass of wine, little romance...
But I get too frisky.
You push me away...
and drop your wine glass.
Hmm.
Little bits
of cork in there.
Hmm.
Nice bottle of wine.
Did the cork break?
Nope. Still intact.
Weird.
Where'd that come from?
I don't know.
Okay, so...
date is over,
I'm out of here.
That's the problem.
I want you to stay.
FINLAY: So Witten
and the girl struggle,
girl breaks free...
Good night.
Blood on the lamp is consistent
with blunt force trauma.
No castoff,
which means
it was one blow.
Okay, so,
Witten kills the girl,
calls 911, and then,
plays it off
like an intruder came in
while he was sleeping
downstairs.
Yeah, and that is the worst
alibi ever, which,
in my experience,
sometimes means that it's true.
What do you mean?
Well, didn't you say
that this guy killed a girl
and made her body disappear?
Why didn't he just do it again?
Maybe now he thinks
he's untouchable.
Seems like old times.
Right, Conrad?
Some ways, yes,
some ways, no... Jack.
Uh, Mr. Witten, I'm--I'm not
so interested in the past
as I am in what happened
last night.
I already told you.
I was watching a film
in my basement screening room.
Fell asleep to Jane Russell,
woke up to a horror show.
And you didn't
hear anything upstairs?
Screening room's soundproofed.
And the girl?
Never saw her before.
ECKLIE:
I'm so sorry, sir.
I just need this to be clear.
You're saying that you never
even met Darcy?
Did I stutter?
You heard me.
And this time, you people
aren't going to find me
wasted on some B.S.
security video outside a club.
Well, we may not
have video on you, but...
we do have blood
on your hands, sir.
ECKLIE:
Yeah, the victim's blood.
How do you explain that?
I tried to help her.
I got her blood on my hands.
What do you want me to do?
I won't play the sap for you.
Humphrey Bogart...
Maltese Falcon, right?
You know it.
A kindred spirit.
RUSSELL:
He played Sam Spade,
a private eye
everybody was lying to.
ECKLIE: Yeah, that's me.
You've been lying
for 14 years.
You brought
this little girl home,
just like you did Darcy Blaine.
You know it,
and I know it.
You don't know anything.
You sure as hell
don't know me.
You never did.
Keep smiling, Jack.
We didn't get
you for Darcy,
but I promise you
we're gonna nail you
for this one.
SIDLE:
Hello, Conrad.
Sara.
Here to pull
the Darcy Blaine case files?
Looks like you
beat me to it.
Well,
great minds obsess alike.
Yeah, well, I got a hunch
we're obsessing
for different reasons.
Huh. You're right.
I'm really sorry.
I should never have taken
this case away from you guys.
You can't do this, Conrad.
Yes, I can.
Grissom is at a conference,
and you don't have
the authority,
so this case belongs
to day shift now.
To me.
So you just decided
to stop looking at Jack Witten.
At least let us get a warrant
for Witten's house.
No!
I'm not gonna waste
valuable time
and resources
on a witch hunt
of a prominent man
whose family has done so much
for this town.
God, you are so political.
Well, that's an understatement.
Look, Darcy Blaine
was a drug-addict rich girl
slumming in Northtown.
You've been looking
in the wrong place, Sidle,
and you let her--it's time
the real pros took over.
Feels like a lifetime ago.
I was looking in the wrong place
or not looking at all.
Security cam photos--
Witten and Darcy
leaving the club.
Later on,
in the parking garage.
SIDLE: They drove away
together in her car.
Next morning, it was found
on the edge of town.
Trace on her tires
said it was driven up
to Mount Charleston.
Notorious body-dump site.
There was a lot of blood.
Exemplar from Darcy's father
proved it was hers.
Yeah, and her blood
tested positive
for cocaine and GHB, so she was
definitely roofied.
So what do you think happened
that night?
Well...
Darcy Blaine was a drug addict.
I think that Witten lured her
to his place
with the promise of drugs,
and then he drugged her.
Witten brought her upstairs.
Darcy was out of it, but still
she had some fight left in her.
(Darcy grunts)
(grunts)
He kills her.
Witten takes Darcy's body out
in her car
and buries her somewhere
near Mount Charleston.
He made one mistake.
He left a carpet fiber
in the trunk.
Still bloody
after all these years.
And...
the carpet fiber
I took from Witten's bedroom.
You just get that?
Uh-huh.
That looks damn close.
Hopefully, Hodges can confirm.
Hey.
I got a hit
on the prints.
Jane Doe from
Jack Witten's house
is Gwenn Onetta.
18. High school dropout.
Three drug arrests
in the last year.
Jack Witten's specialty--
young, vulnerable addicts.
God, this guy's really gotten
under everybody's skin.
It's not so much the guy--
it's the loss.
Grissom assembled
an all-star team here.
But ask any pro athlete.
Most wins feel the same.
It's the tough losses
that haunt you.
So this is a rematch.
Yeah.
I like it.
Chip of glass in the head wound.
Greg said there was a broken
wine glass at the scene.
This doesn't look like
any wine glass.
The lamp, maybe? The...
The suspected murder weapon?
Yeah, that could be.
You know,
for the record, Morgan,
I think you're
an all-star too.
(laughs)
Thanks, Doc.
News on your fibers.
Good news?
I hope they match.
No, sorry.
I know you wanted
a better answer.
Who's that?
Walter Blaine,
Darcy's father.
He heard about Witten
and he wants to talk.
Calls me every October
on the anniversary.
Every year,
it's the same conversation.
Sara, thanks much
for your time.
Of course.
Please, have a seat.
So, is today the day
we've been waiting for?
Well, he's been brought in
for questioning.
He did it again.
That's all I can say, Walter.
Please tell me you're gonna
get him this time.
I promise that I will do
everything in my power
to get justice for Darcy.
She would've been 30 this year.
Imagine that.
(whispers):
She didn't deserve...
(sighs)
Aah...
closure's a myth.
Doesn't exist.
Look, I know
that bringing Witten down
isn't gonna bring her back.
But at least he'll never
be able to do it again.
What are you doing?
The fiber Sara pulled
from over there
wasn't a match
to the bloody fiber
from Darcy Blaine's trunk,
so I'm thinking it must have
come from someplace else.
Wow, you guys really
don't give up, do you?
No, we don't.
Especially since
we have a pretty good idea
about what happened here
14 years ago.
It's got to be somewhere.
You know, I, uh, get
that you want
to put this guy away.
But don't you think
the best way to do that
would be to
focus on last night?
Did you find
what you're looking for?
No.
But maybe something better.
It's desiccant gel--
like the kind
used in pill bottles
to keep the contents dry.
Uh-huh.
Removes excess moisture.
And more cork.
Maybe the cork downstairs
wasn't from a wine bottle.
You know, Jack Witten's father
was a huge art collector.
And he left everything
to Jack, but,
I mean, these are all
movie posters.
Where's the good stuff?
What are you getting at?
You know,
maybe what happened last night
didn't start in the bedroom.
Maybe it started
in a Preservation Room.
It's a sealed vault
where collectors keep
their art.
It's climate-controlled.
Gel and cork are used
in the construction.
Well, we've been
all over this place and, uh...
haven't found
a Preservation Room.
SANDERS:
Hey.
There's a break
in the baseboard.
(hollow thumping)
Whoa.
(muffled shouting)
There's someone
in there.
Need a password.
We have to cut
through that door.
Russell, it's Finn.
Send an emergency response team
to Witten's house and tell them
to bring a plasma torch.
We're in.
How?
10-22-02,
the day The Premiere
was supposed to open.
(muffled cries)
LVPD!
It's all right.
You're gonna be okay.
Please. He tried to kill us.
Me and my friend.
Is she here? Is Gwen okay?
(sighs)
Emily,
I'm CSI Russell.
And I'm CSI Sidle.
Doc says that you're doing
a little better.
Still feel a little dizzy.
We could come back,
if you'd like.
No. No, I want to help.
RUSSELL:
Good, good.
Do you think you can
take us through
what happened last night?
Me and Gwen, we met
this old guy at a club.
He bought us champagne.
I got drunk. Stupid.
It's okay.
We went back to his place.
I needed to use the restroom.
Said he'd show me.
He pushed me
into that weird room.
Tied me up, locked me in.
Then... I could hear him.
And I could hear her screaming,
telling him to stop.
I never should've
left Gwen alone.
It's not your fault, Emily.
So--so you were
in the Preservation Room
when Witten attacked
your friend,
is--is that right?
Yeah. That's right.
Okay.
Can you call the doctor?
I really feel awful.
Of course.
What was that about exactly?
Emily just told you
that Witten locked her
in the Preservation Room.
Yeah, she did.
You don't believe her.
No, I didn't say that.
But I do think
it's a little curious
that she could hear so much.
Locked in a vault,
far away from the scene
of the crime.
A--all I'm saying is
if you want him this time,
you're gonna need more
than her statement.
Yeah, and I'm gonna get
what I need.
Okay.
Hey, Sara, sometimes
you push too hard,
and you know it.
Just...don't.
BRODY:
So we got trace
on that piece of glass
that Doc pulled
from our victim, Gwen Onetta.
Did the glass come
from Witten's lamp?
No. Density and refractive index
don't match.
"Silica, sodium oxide,
with a broadband
anti-reflective coating."
Sounds like
a flashlight lens.
That's what I was thinking.
Now, I followed up
on Emily Bridwell,
our girl
in the hospital.
Turns out, she was questioned
in a string of burglaries
in Summerlin,
along with her roommates,
our girl in the morgue,
Gwen Onetta.
Flashlights, burglaries...
maybe these girls
weren't invited
to Witten's house.
Maybe they invited themselves.
Pair of "Bling Ringers,"
Vegas-style?
Wait a minute, just because
these girls were questioned
in break-ins doesn't mean
that Witten's not guilty.
The guy has a serious
security system,
so how would these so-called
"Bling Ringers" get in
in the first place,
let alone one of them end up
in a locked vault?
Those are all
good questions.
Questions we know how to answer.
Yeah, we need to get our hands
on that murder weapon.
Find the flashlight.
Haven't we turned that house
upside-down at this point?
There is one room
we haven't searched yet.
Hey, Sara...
I found the murder weapon.
Yeah, and it has
Emily Bridwell's prints on it.
I know you've already
talked to her,
but I think you might want
to have another conversation.
Yeah, well, that's gonna
be a little difficult.
She died in the hospital
two hours ago.
I got to call you back.
What the hell
happened?
No Smurf jokes, please.
Can you explain
this to me?
C.O.D. is paralysis of
the respiratory system.
My educated guess
is that it was caused
by the ingestion of silver.
Blue skin is the result
of a reaction called argyria.
Nanosilver's broken down
in the stomach,
absorbed into the bloodstream
as a salt
and then deposited in the skin,
where exposure to light
turns the salt back
into elemental silver,
creating the skin's bluish hue.
How would
she have ingested silver?
I was just about to find out.
Whoa.
What is that?
It looks like film.
ECKLIE: Okay, it's official.
I've seen everything.
This girl died from
swallowing a roll of film?
We know what's on it?
Hodges is working on it.
Patrol found
Emily Bridwell's car
a block away
from Witten's house.
And a Post-it
with his address
and security codes.
Even the password
to the Preservation Room.
So these girls,
they were targeting
Jack Witten's secret vault?
Yes.
Then,
for some reason,
the partnership went south.
FINLAY:
And I think I know why.
No honor among thieves.
Especially when you're banging
the same guy.
I checked Gwen's
cell phone records.
Turns out Emily's boyfriend
texted her
at a very inconvenient time.
(phone chimes)
EMILY (chuckling):
What the...
You bitch! You're screwing Ryan?
Emily, chill out.
It's Ryan. Come on.
He said you weren't
that into him.
Screw you!
(grunting)
GWEN:
Get off of me!
(groans)
I'm out of here.
EMILY: You're not
going anywhere.
(grunting)
(glass shatters)
What is wrong with you?!
(thud, Gwen screams)
So Emily kills Gwen
in a jealous rage.
At this point, you'd
think, you'd run.
But she has to get
what she came for.
FINLAY:
She finds the film...
WITTEN: Yeah, I've got
a dead girl in my living room.
...but she hears
Jack Witten downstairs.
Just get somebody
out here!
But she knows the house,
and she knows his reputation,
so she improvises.
Locks herself in the vault,
hides the flashlight...
swallows the film...
and ties herself up.
And then
she makes up her story.
But I guess that
clears Witten, huh?
Yeah, at least
for last night.
RUSSELL: What
I want to know is,
what's so important
on this piece of film
that that girl would
mule it out of there?
My God.
Is that who I think it is?
Was.
I forgot how
young she looked.
Darcy Blaine.
Ghost from the past.
Well, she's definitely
in Boulder City.
And I recognize these banners
from the Millennium.
So it's got to be 2000.
So this film
that was shot of Darcy,
clearly before she died,
has been in Witten's vault
this whole time?
It would seem so.
You see the way she's
looking in the camera?
She's flirting.
And Witten claims that
he never met Darcy before
the night they walked
out of the club together.
The look in her eyes
says that there
was a lot more
to the relationship than that.
This film proves that everything
he said about Darcy is a lie.
Not only did they know
each other, they were
probably having sex.
Well, Witten was released today.
I say we go over to his house,
shove those in his face and
force a confession out of him.
SIDLE:
Uh, wait a minute.
If we know he's guilty,
somebody else does too.
Whoever sent our thieves
in there to steal the film.
Well, it's got to be
someone who knows Witten.
They knew the house,
they knew the security codes,
and they knew
that he had the film.
But how would
they know about it?
Maybe because they're
the ones who shot it.
Did you test
the film itself?
I did.
I found exactly
300 frames
of nitrocellulose-based
film print,
manufactured
sometime before 1952.
Well, that makes sense.
When planning the premiere,
Witten hired a bunch
of photographers
to use vintage cameras
to shoot
on vintage film.
Maybe one of the cameramen
shot footage of Darcy
for Witten's personal use too.
Someone like that
would know more
intimate details about
their relationship.
They might even know the truth
of how Darcy died.
But why steal the film now,
14 years later?
I don't know, maybe the guy
fell on hard times.
It's never too late
to blackmail.
All right.
Okay, let's say
we're right.
How do we find
the cameraperson
that shot this?
"Shot" is
the operative word here.
A strip of film
is like a bullet.
Just like a gun creates unique
rifling impressions on a round,
the pressure plate in a camera
imprints unique scratches
on film.
These scratch patterns,
they can help us
find the camera
that shot this film.
So find the camera...
maybe find the cameraman.
HODGES:
And...
action.
No, no, no,
no, no, no.
It's a sexy walk.
And look into camera.
Give me a little smile.
What difference
does it make?
We're testing
the film stock, right?
Please don't tell me
how to direct.
All right.
And...
action.
Okay, not bad.
Got that one.
Go back to the one.
Little happier this time.
Action.
Okay, that's better.
In with a wink.
Stop, wink, and cut. Okay.
This feels weird.
You're a scared little lady.
Uh-huh. No, no,
just... Okay.
Cut. Never mind.
Silent film.
And cut. Great.
You're Marilyn Monroe.
Just the slinkiest,
sexiest lady
you've ever been.
Looks great.
Okay, okay, no, that's...
that's too sexy.
HODGES:
I located five vintage
35-millimeter cameras
in the Vegas area.
Two from WLVU's
film department
and three from
a seedy pawnshop.
Scratch pattern
is identical.
Which camera was it?
This little baby here.
Arriflex 2C.
Sold to the pawnshop two months
ago by a guy named Bob Geer.
He was a cameraman
employed by Jack Witten.
And PD is pulling
an address right now.
MAN:
Robert Geer.
(knocking on door)
Robert Geer. LVPD.
Mr. Geer?
Hello?
Been dead a while.
C.O.D. on our cameraman was
a single gunshot to the head.
.22--same caliber as a gun
registered to Jack Witten.
All right, but .22's
a pretty common gun.
Doesn't necessarily
point to Witten.
This does.
Geer's bank records
going back to 2000.
RUSSELL:
Wow. $750,000 transferred
into Geer's account from
Iris Corp? What's that?
That is an LLC
that Witten formed
to build his casino.
I think it's blackmail money.
Witten paid off Geer
because Geer knew
that he had killed
Darcy, is that right?
Yes, and then 14 years later,
he's run through the money.
He needs more.
But this time,
his word against Witten
isn't gonna be enough.
Right, this time he
needs concrete proof
of Witten's relationship
with Darcy.
Hence the film.
And the Post-it that we found
in Emily Bridwell's car
with Witten's address
and security codes on it?
It's in Bob Geer's
handwriting.
He hired our thieves.
So it looks like Geer,
after all this time,
decided to put the pinch
on Witten again. Okay.
So the guy worked for me.
Everybody knows that.
But Geer
knew about you and Darcy.
He came back
for more money,
so you killed him.
(chuckles)
Here we go again.
BRASS: But this time
it's gonna stick.
We pulled a .22-caliber bullet
out of Geer's head--
same caliber as your gun.
We're running it now.
I didn't do it.
Wha...
I haven't seen Geer in...
forever.
I barely knew the guy.
Just like I barely
knew Darcy.
When are you guys
gonna give up?
For someone you barely knew, you
sure had a serious obsession.
Your buddy Geer shot that
for you, didn't he?
You been keeping it
all these years.
I've never seen that before.
Oh, come on, Jack,
you're getting high
with a wild party girl
and 500-a-night...
No, no. No, no.
Darcy wasn't like that.
She had a problem, just like me.
What problem was that, Jack?
I met her at N.A.
She was a mixed-up girl.
She liked old movies.
We used to...
watch them in my
screening room together.
She got a kick out of
the old actresses, you know?
Bergman, Vivien Leigh,
Gene Tierney in Laura.
Darcy was a bright girl.
She had better things
ahead of her.
Yeah, I get it.
No, it wasn't like that.
She was like
a daughter to me.
(sighs)
But I was a broken man. I...
...couldn't control myself.
With drugs...
with women.
With Darcy.
Yeah, with Darcy.
And for years, I tried telling
myself it never happened.
We were together at the club.
Next thing I knew,
Darcy was lying there, dead.
And I forgot
Bob Geer was coming over
to the house that morning.
I have no idea
what happened.
GEER:
Stay cool, Jack.
Let me handle this, okay?
He said he could help me.
Help you get rid
of the body?
Yeah.
But the one thing he
didn't tell me was...
how much it was gonna cost me.
All this time,
you guys
have been trying to prove
I'm a killer.
I got your proof.
When I was cleaning up,
Geer took this picture of Darcy.
Sometimes I forget
what I did.
So I kept this.
So I never forget
the kind of person I really am.
I just heard--
Witten confessed.
(sighs):
Yeah.
Uh, thought
you'd be happier.
Ballistics just came back
on the bullet that killed Geer.
It wasn't a match
to Witten's gun.
Okay, so maybe Witten had
someone else do it for him.
We still have him for Darcy.
Yeah, I'm not so sure
about that, either, anymore.
Witten said that he'd never seen
that old film of Darcy before;
he was telling the truth.
What do you mean?
This film collection
in Witten's vault
was a recent
acquisition.
The film canisters
belonged to Bob Geer?
Up until a month ago.
At which time, he pawned
his vintage camera
and all his film,
including the can
that had 300 frames
of Darcy Blaine.
I spoke to
the pawnshop owner.
He said that a regular--
one of his collectors--
bought all the film--that
collector was Jack Witten.
We've been thinking that
Bob Geer wanted to get ahold
of that film of Darcy
so that he could prove
that Witten was lying
about their relationship--
but why go after
that film if he had
something even better?
SANDERS: Yeah, not just proof
of their relationship, but...
proof of murder.
This doesn't make any sense.
What am I looking at?
The tox panel
on Darcy Blaine's blood
that we found in the car trunk
definitely had high
levels of cocaine, but...
we're saying that
she was roofied, right?
Right.
Well, it's weird
because the GHB
was never fully metabolized
into her blood.
Meaning what?
It just doesn't
make sense.
Greg, you are a great tech.
And I know that you want
to be in the field.
In this job, sometimes you got
to go beyond numbers.
Beyond what's
on the face of things.
What are you thinking about?
Something Catherine once told me
about looking deeper.
The Tin Man's rivet.
Uh, for the most recent
reissue of The Wizard of Oz,
they used a new
restoration technique.
Details that had been lost
had suddenly now become vivid.
One of those being
that the Tin Man had a rivet
between his eyes that nobody
had seen in 50 years.
Maybe there's some detail in
this film that we're not seeing.
There's only one way
to find out.
I'll send this
to FotoKem, have them
do a wet print and rescan it.
January 2001.
The bank was torn
down in '05,
but I remembered
it had a news ticker.
That film was shot
two months after Darcy Blaine
was supposedly murdered.
She faked her death.
SANDERS:
And she's smiling at the camera
because she got
away with it.
Darcy.
I've been
looking for you.
Sorry, my name's Vivian.
Oh, right, uh,
"Vivian Sinclair."
We found that
in Bob Geer's cell phone.
"Vivian" as in "Vivien Leigh,"
your favorite movie star
and "Sinclair," as in
your mother's maiden name.
Hotel Blanc said
that Vivian Sinclair
was checking out tonight,
heading home to Chicago.
Sorry to delay
your flight.
You're making
a big mistake.
SIDLE:
You're the one who made
a big mistake.
Bob Geer's phone records shows
a "Vivian Sinclair" called him
20 minutes
before he was murdered.
Cell tower hit
puts you a block away
from his apartment,
it puts you there.
We found a gun
in your suitcase, a .22.
Ballistics confirms
that it's the murder weapon.
He... It was self-defense.
He attacked me.
All right.
14 years ago...
we put ourselves on the line
for an innocent girl
we thought had been murdered.
You manipulated the evidence,
you put
an innocent man through hell.
That night, you and Jack Witten
were at the club,
you did go home together.
But it wasn't you
who blacked out,
it was Witten,
like most nights.
Once he was out, you called
your friend, Bob Geer.
Bob? He's out.
Let's do this.
SIDLE: Witten woke up
in a drug haze, panicked.
Just like you planned, Bob Geer
showed up in the morning,
told Witten
he'd take care of things.
(camera shutter clicking)
And then, you two
took care of things.
(laughing)
(laughs)
SIDLE:
You drew your own blood.
You made it look like
you'd been roofied.
And then you planted it
in your car trunk.
You framed Jack Witten.
The man that was trying
to help you.
You think Witten was trying
to help me?
You don't know
Jack Witten.
He was like
every other man in my life--
just trying to use me.
Is that the story
that you're going with?
I got one. Bob Geer.
Seems like
he wasn't using you.
Seems to me he was
trying to help you.
Phone records show that he
reached out to you six weeks ago
when he realized
that his film collection
had fallen
into the hands of Jack Witten,
including 300 frames
that prove...
that this was a lie.
Dead girl.
Dead girl walking.
I did a terrible thing.
I was a mixed-up junkie.
I was desperate
and afraid.
Yeah.
Oh, yeah, yeah.
Geer and I framed Jack Witten.
But it was just a way
for me to escape.
Escape from what?
From my father,
who, I'm sure,
was devastated at my loss.
You know why?
Because with me gone,
he couldn't come into my bed
every night
when my mother was asleep.
I did what I had to do
to protect myself.
SIDLE:
Tell that to Bob Geer.
(laughs)
I'm not a cold-blooded killer.
I'm a mom!
I have two girls.
I have a husband
and a life that I cherish.
I am not...
I'm not this person anymore.
People can change.
Terrible...
unspeakable things happen
to all of us,
but...
that doesn't give anyone the
right to destroy someone's life.
Whatever happened to you,
whatever the truth is,
for 14 years,
you let an innocent man believe
that he killed the one thing
that he cared about.
The one person
in his screwed-up universe
that he genuinely loved
like a daughter.
You took his desire
to protect and save you,
and you perverted it.
You twisted it.
I know you.
I know who you are.
You haven't changed, Darcy.
You never will.
Thank you.
(sighs)
Walter Blaine has
hired counsel for Darcy.
He's wrapped his fatherly arms
around his daughter.
Do you believe her?
Her story about
him molesting her?
She's definitely screwed up.
Maybe it's from abuse.
Maybe...she's just a bad seed.
I don't know what
to believe anymore.
Oh, I know that feeling.
That thing I said to you
about pushing too hard...
Thank God you did.
You're a free man, Jack.
What's going to
happen to her?
ECKLIE:
I wouldn't think you'd care.
All these years,
and I thought I'd killed her.
Had to live with that.
Now, I just keep thinking
I could've done more
to save her.
Hey, it wasn't your fault.
She made her own choices.
Yeah.
Look, Jack, uh...
I'm sorry.
No apologies.
You guys did your job.
Thanks for giving me
my life back.
(sighs)
Well, it's lights out
for The Premiere.
Witten can
still build it.
Ah, it wouldn't work.
Too innocent for Vegas
these days.
Speaking of another time...
(laughs)
Please put that away.
(sighs)
All this evidence,
all these years.
You ever think
you've had enough?
Are you kidding?
I'm just getting started.
♪ ♪