♪ ♪
(beeping)
(gun clicks)
(gunshots)
I'm standing live in front
of the Berman estate,
where the casino mogul's wife
has been killed...
Mr. Berman, I've been told,
is nowhere to be found.
Hey, Anderson Cooper.
What?
Yeah, you.
Do a 180 and take a hike.
I don't care
about freedom of the press.
Move the perimeter back.
Move it back.
And somebody shut
that damn dog up.
Where is Lee Berman?!
Where's the husband?
Metcalf, Smith,
put out a broadcast!
I want to talk to him
in ten minutes.
(siren whooping)
AKERS:
Turn the car off.
Step out of the vehicle and
get your hands in the air.
Do you know who I am?
Lee Berman.
I own the Tangiers.
Ring a bell?
One call
to Sheriff Ecklie,
and I turn you all
into mall cops.
Looks like we got a gun
in the car, boys.
Nine-millimeter.
Don't cuff him yet, Akers.
This is a red flag case.
Spin him around here.
I'll process him on site.
Right hand. Palm down.
Okay, now you can hook him.
Mr. Berman, you are under arrest
for suspicion of murder.
Murder? Who died?
Your wife.
(mechanical whirring)
Hmm.
Ah.
Oh, there you go.
Hey.
Smart house, right?
You walk into the room,
lights go on.
You walk out,
they go off.
Yeah, I know.
Me and Umbrella Man
just lit up together.
I'm assuming
that one
of the 18 cameras outside
got a good look
at our killer.
Actually, someone
outsmarted the smart house.
Alarm system and surveillance
cameras were disabled
at 4:17 a.m.
for an hour.
Remotely.
The good news is,
the motion sensors still tracked
the path of entry:
from the garage, down the hall,
through the foyer,
into the master bedroom.
In and out in less
than six minutes.
No wrong turns.
Whoever killed Audrey Berman
was familiar with the house.
D.B.
First two shots were not
immediately fatal.
Third shot,
she wasn't so lucky.
(gunshot)
She gave it a valiant effort.
Almost made it
to those doors.
Nine-mil.
Same caliber as the gun
that Nick found
in Berman's car.
So busy killing
his wife, he forgot
to pick up the casings.
Crime of passion.
Could be trouble
in paradise.
His nightstand's
completely empty.
Look at hers.
She also took over both sides
of the closet.
So I'm thinking
that Mr. Berman moved out
of this room a while ago.
Well, hello there.
(camera clicks)
(whirring, beeping)
Where'd you go?
Hey, boss.
Thanks for getting back to me.
MAN:
Did you ask for a plane?
Yes, sir, I did request a plane.
That's out of the question.
Wait, hear me out.
You know the "Kitty" case
that I've been tracking?
Yeah.
Well, one of her targets,
Lee Berman--
his wife was murdered.
And?
Which tells me
our Node is there.
But for how long?
Ryan, we don't have
the resources
to send you out there
at this time.
Sir, with all due respect,
you know these cybercriminals--
they're like gophers.
If you don't grab 'em
when they pop their head out,
they're gone forever.
I'll see what I can do.
Clock's ticking.
Ryan...
I got to get to Vegas.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
♪ ♪
MAN:
Special Agent Ryan.
I had an up-and-back
to St. Thomas
until the deputy director
called.
Ordered me to detour
to Vegas.
With all due respect,
ma'am,
we're not running
a taxi service here.
So why don't you save Uncle Sam
a couple of bucks
and fly commercial?
Captain, I'm gonna tell you
three things about yourself,
none of which you're gonna like.
Number one, there's no
such thing as an up-and-back
to the Virgin Islands; you go
there, you're staying the night.
And your
returning there,
it's not for Mrs. Captain.
Ooh.
(men chuckle)
Number two, you and I
both know, morally...
Okay. Wheels up.
Let's get Agent Ryan
to Vegas.
Grab my bags.
Okay, gentlemen,
this is Las Vegas.
I'll deal.
When was the last time
you saw your wife?
Yesterday morning.
I got you beat.
We saw her last night.
I didn't kill my wife.
Here's a photo of the nine-mil
we found on the front seat
of your Aston Martin.
These are the shell casings
that you left behind
in your wife's bedroom.
Also nine-millimeter.
Now, that's the only evidence
we have of you in that room.
That's because you've been
living in the guest bedroom
with another piece of tail.
I want to know everything
about this girl.
Who is she, and where is she?
Okay.
Let me play it out for you.
Your marriage is a bust.
Nevada's a community property
state, right?
Your wife
is going south.
The new chick
is heading north.
It's a classic trade-up.
You kill your wife
to be with her.
Now, as the comics
in the lounge act
at the Tangiers
like to say,
how am I doing?
This Brass is good.
And he's asking
all the right questions,
just not my question.
Do you mind
if we change dealers?
Good morning, Mr. Berman.
FBI Special Agent Ryan.
Cyber Crimes Division.
I'm not gonna ask you
if you murdered your wife.
I'm more interested
in a relationship
you've been having
with a woman online.
Her name's Kitty, right?
The way your pupils
just dilated,
I'd say there was a little more
than chitchat going on
in that chat.
Ten-Stars-VIP.com.
That ring a bell?
An exclusive
VIP sex site
for affluent men willing to pay
for anonymity.
I could say more.
Everyone with a law degree,
take a hike.
MAN:
Mr. Berman,
I strong...
(door opens)
Want to know something funny?
You and I were both
seeing Kitty.
So, I log in
under an assumed name, Ralph,
a lonely rancher
from Montana.
After about a month,
Kitty sends me a virtual gift.
And when I refuse to open it,
she kicks me off the site.
So back
at Quantico,
I'm trying everything.
I get male agents to log in
under assumed names.
But even when we open
the gift,
still she kicks us off the site.
You want
to know why?
'Cause Kitty is only interested
in wealthy men
that she can verify.
Well-known men,
like you.
You opened the gift,
didn't you?
I didn't get any gift.
I'm a behavioral scientist.
Fancy for "human lie detector."
Okay.
I got a gift.
I opened it.
The chat box went away,
and I could talk to her.
No more typing.
Hands-free, so to speak.
How long
did this honeymoon last?
A week.
Ten days.
Then it ended.
I ended it.
You're lying again.
Here's my big question:
What did Kitty have on you?
Call my lawyers back in here.
Ran facial recognition
on our mystery woman.
No hits in the Nevada DMV.
You're not gonna find her
in any database.
It's okay; I can
help you with that.
Everybody, uh,
this is Special Agent Ryan.
She's a cyber psychologist
specializing in cyber forensics,
and I'm afraid
I don't know anything else.
May I?
(beeping)
Clikk, you there?
Yes, ma'am.
Get me into Kitty.
Logging into Ten-Stars-VIP.com.
White label user.
All I need is a name.
All right, CSI, give me a name.
Hodges. That's
a good name.
All right, stand up.
Are you a sex site guy?
No, ma'am.
RYAN:
You ever been
on Ten-Stars-VIP.com?
No, ma'am.
Mm, you sure
about that?
First name?
Uh, that would be David.
Clikk,
verify David Hodges.
STOKES (chuckles):
Oh, it's the FBI, man--
you're toast.
(Clikk whistles)
A little deceptive
on the sex sites.
But he's never been
to Ten-Stars-VIP.
HODGES:
Okay...
uh, I can explain that.
I had a fiancée...
At ease, stud.
Just... just fall back.
You are science cops.
RYAN:
I'm a cyber cop.
I work crimes
that start in the mind,
live online,
and play out in the real world.
You work dark alleys.
I work the dark Net.
You chase suspects.
I chase Nodes.
RYAN:
"Node," short for "bad guy."
Little childlike drawing.
This iceberg represents
the Internet.
And believe it or not,
the world only uses
this top four percent.
The tip.
The surface Web.
I work down here,
in the 96%,
in the deep Web,
where criminals
are anonymous,
where money is untraceable,
and where everything illegal's
for sale.
And what does this
have to do with Mr. Berman?
Well, Berman's having
a relationship
with your mystery woman,
a woman named Kitty--
and Kitty...
she's one of a kind.
What's your name?
Kitty.
Because the more you pet me,
the more I purr.
What's your name?
RYAN:
David. Kitty-- ooh, I like that.
KITTY:
What else do you like, David?
RYAN:
Oh, I like sex.
I like sex too.
RYAN:
What are you into?
Everything.
Name it.
How many legs on a bicycle?
So you're a leg man?
How many bicycles on a leg?
You want to ride me?
FINLAY:
Wow, she always brings it
right back to sex.
Sex is her business.
Now, we're gonna have
a little fun.
RYAN:
I'm gonna frustrate
the algorithm
with a nonresponsive response.
You want to ride me?
You want to ride me hard?
Chain. Yank. Sweat.
Wet. Bleed. Finger. Lick.
Tongue. Ass. Ride.
Ride. Ride. Ride. Ride.
(repeating rapidly):
Ri...
(distorted):
Ride. Ride. Ride. Ride.
Ride. Ride. Ride. Ride. Ride...
What the hell kind
of sex site is this?
RYAN:
My team has been tracking Kitty
for six weeks.
She is a computer-animated
avatar chatbot
with machine-learning
artificial intelligence.
Okay, good, we're all
caught up now.
So...
she's not real.
But the person
who created her is.
That's why I'm here.
What's with
the mushrooms?
It's in my nature to nurture.
I guess I threw you
a little curveball
with Kitty, didn't I?
You know, all this
cyber hocus-pocus
is fascinating, but...
now what?
I still have
a dead woman downstairs,
a casino mogul
with GSR on his hands,
a gun on the front seat.
Up until now,
I've been thinking that
Lee Berman killed
his wife for a...
a younger woman online.
You come along,
you tap a few keys,
and then you reduce our motive
to a bunch of digital bits.
So...
where's that leave me?
Can you cut me CSI Finlay?
I'm bucking time here.
I really need to get into
the husband's computer.
Why her?
Men. Sex sites.
They're time assassins.
Fine with me.
But Lee Berman's computer
wiped out right in my hands,
so...
Was a sledge hammer involved?
No.
Then... the data's still there.
♪ ♪
FINLAY:
Oh, look.
Virus detected.
Two-way camera enabled
on Berman's computer.
The gift from Kitty.
There are some gifts that
should never be opened.
Here's what I suspect
happened to Berman.
No more chat box.
No more typing.
You can see me.
I wish I could see you.
Now, let's put those hands
to good use.
KITTY:
Oh, yeah.
RYAN:
He was so happy
to be hands-free,
he had no idea
he was being recorded.
KITTY:
Yeah, you're doing great.
You're doing great.
So Berman made a sex tape
and didn't even know it.
People forget
the cameras
on their laptops, their tablets,
their cell phones--
they're cameras.
They record.
I figured
if rich guys
like Berman were being targeted,
money was the end game.
And the good news
about his two-way cam is that
it recorded every one
of their encounters,
everything from their first
hello to their last good-bye.
I imagine you pinning me down,
taking me against my will.
Wait.
I want you to dominate me.
She can't feel pain;
she's not real.
Then why is she
massaging her jaw?
It's usually the sign of an
underlying medical condition.
Don't you want to see
how it ends?
David.
Hey.
I was just
bringing this to you.
Saves me the trip.
What do we got?
Nine-mil, right?
Mm-hmm.
Thank you.
Hi, Doc.
D.B.
What a shame.
Audrey Berman
was a great lady.
Heart of gold when
it came to this town,
and a very good friend
of mine too.
Can't say the same
for her husband.
It's always the better half
that gets punished
for the other half's sins.
What do you got there?
Is that a bruise
on the ring finger?
Minute abrasions
along the knuckle.
They weren't apparent
at the scene.
Developed
since we brought her in.
Wedding ring wasn't in
her personal effects.
Wasn't in evidence either.
This is one of the biggest
diamonds I've ever seen.
Instant divorce.
(two gunshots)
♪ ♪
RUSSELL:
How we doing
on those bullets?
(sighs)
Bullets from the wife
don't match the gun
from the husband's car.
Nick processed on site.
Berman's hands were
positive for GSR.
I know, but the striae
don't match.
Berman have a
carry permit?
I checked.
He is a regular member of
the Gun Club off Blue Diamond.
Well, there you go.
GSR on guns is like paint--
it sticks around,
maybe long enough
to transfer to his hands
when he handled it last night.
If the gun wasn't
the murder weapon, though,
why did Berman have it
in the first place?
There's got to be a reason.
How's it going?
Hey, good, good.
Uh, I know that Greg was
jocking Berman's smart house,
(chuckles):
but I don't think he saw
this smart car, man.
It's amazing.
It's like a detective on wheels;
you just give it
a CSI badge and
a field kit.
I did run diagnostics.
According to CSI Aston,
from the Tangiers,
Berman manually entered
his GPS coordinates
at 4:15 a.m.,
arriving at his destination,
Industrial Park,
at 5:13 a.m.
And then, of course,
I handcuffed him at 5:37.
So he was
nowhere near the scene.
He couldn't
have killed his wife.
But that doesn't mean
he didn't pay for it.
That bag I found
in the trunk
could have been used
for a money drop.
Okay, so...
what do we think?
Berman hires some guy
to kill his wife,
meets him in the park
an hour later
for the payoff.
I mean...
that does fit the timeline.
I'm not sure it fits
the logic, though.
I mean, what's a guy
like Lee Berman doing
driving an Aston Martin
around Industrial Park
at 5:00 in the morning
with a gun on his seat?
Yeah...
we're missing something.
This may be
what you're missing.
You're gonna pay,
or you're gonna pay.
LEE:
A hundred thousand--
that was one thing. 250?
Now you want
a half a million dollars?
I'm done.
You're done when
I say you're done.
Now it's a million.
You don't want
to play ball with me,
I will kill your whole family.
Who do you want to see
in a casket first,
your wife or your kids?
(quietly):
You leave them
out of this.
Now it's $2 million.
You say another word,
and it's four.
Same drill-- wire the money,
convert it to bitcoins.
Forget bitcoins.
I want a face-to-face!
LEE:
I'm in charge now! My terms!
Industrial Park
off Blue Diamond!
Cash on delivery!
I am ending this tonight!
Aw.
You do love me.
FINLAY:
And that was the last time
that they spoke.
Classic extortion.
How does an avatar
programmed for sex
turn so sadistic?
RYAN:
Kitty's not a sadist.
Her creator is.
A psycho-sadist.
Most likely male.
He derives pleasure
from inflicting pain on others--
physical, emotional,
financial.
Berman didn't pay
to have his wife killed.
He paid the sadist to spare her.
But he didn't spare her.
She's dead.
The second that Berman
initiated this power struggle
with his "my terms" bravado,
the sadist got pissed.
So he killed Berman's wife
and he took his money.
Which means Berman's the only
person who's ever seen this guy.
First you tell me
this girl is fake,
and now you're
telling me the "guy"
who was shaking me down
killed my wife?
Hey, Mr. Berman,
we have you on tape
agreeing to pay
$2 million cash.
Question is, who'd
you give it to?
RYAN:
You can't pay $2 million
to a chatbot.
So who'd you pay the money to?
(indistinct whispering)
Oh, wait a minute,
wait a minute.
There never was any cash,
was there?
You went to the
Industrial Park
not to pay Kitty
but to kill her.
And when you got there,
I'm guessing
all you had was
your gun in your hand.
Gun in my hand?
That's a polite way to say it.
No one showed.
I didn't
say it before because...
because I was ashamed.
I'm fooling around
online, and...
it gets my wife killed.
That's the first
honest thing you've said.
I'd like to thank
both the FBI and the LVPD
for proving what
we knew all along.
Mr. Berman is innocent.
And we're out of here.
Kitty?
Kitty. Kitty.
It's you.
What the hell
is going on?
They said
she wasn't real!
LAWYER:
Calm down!
I'm looking for the person
who gave my picture
to the press.
My name is Susan McDowell.
I'm from San Diego.
I'm cooking dinner
for my little girls.
I look up, and I'm
all over the TV,
the other woman in
a love triangle.
Every story mentions the
Las Vegas Police Department.
I drove five hours.
I want answers.
I understand.
I want some myself.
(clears throat)
I put your photo out there.
The FBI is working a case,
and you're a person of interest.
Person of interest?
Are you kidding me?
Do you use social networks?
Are you even
listening to me?
I have a husband overseas
serving his country.
I am trying to hold
my family together.
That guy in the hall, he
is not the first person
to call me Kitty.
What about Facebook?
Instagram? Snapchat?
Vine?
Yes. I'm on Friend Agenda.
My husband's stationed
in Afghanistan.
It's the only way we
get to see each other.
How often are you on it?
Every day.
I send Bradley photos
and videos of the girls.
I post whatever I can to
bring our life to him.
Do you grind your teeth
at night?
How do you know that?
You're massaging your jaw.
You have an idiosyncratic
medical condition.
I'm guessing it's TMJ.
It started when my
husband deployed.
It's how I knew
you were out there.
And it's why
I released her photo.
Ms. McDowell,
someone took your face,
your body,
and your mannerisms,
and they made a virtual you.
They gave it a name, Kitty,
and they put it on a sex site.
The guy who did it is now
making millions of dollars.
How could he do that?
I think we need to assess
your social vulnerability.
RYAN:
This is your Friend Agenda page.
Do you recognize
any of these six people?
WittyGirl285 is a girl
I went to school with.
BarbaraSD is an
over-caffeinated mom
trying to set up a playdate.
I don't know
the other four.
Today, these
are the top six people
who viewed your site--
not your friends,
your wannabe friends.
Your top hit is Nebula1.
Who's he?
I have no clue.
Well, he visited your site
2,507 times
in the last six months.
That's 15 times a day.
Playdate mom?
She was there two times a week.
That guy hiding behind
the smiley face--
he's the one that
did this to me?
2,500 times? Really?
I have two little girls.
What if this guy comes after us?
I'll protect you.
I give you my word.
Mr. Berman?
Listen, until we catch
your wife's killer,
I think it would be
a good idea
for you to stay
at the hotel.
Little extra layer of security.
I don't know what you
want to do about your dog.
Dog?
I don't have a dog.
STOKES:
Where you going, bud?
Come here.
Hey.
Nice pooch, Nick.
Thank you.
Yeah, thanks.
Hey, so I finally
figured out
how the killer knew his way
around the Berman house.
Place was up for sale
a few years ago,
and the, uh,
360 virtual walk-through
is still online.
All the killer had to do
was take the tour,
and he knew every inch
of the place.
Scary.
Something that
is supposed to
help you sell your house
ends up being
a blueprint to kill your wife.
Yeah, he'd
still have to get past guard
shacks, armed security,
and electronic sensor gates.
It's like Shawshank
over there.
I worked a grand theft
horse case there a while back.
Community's zoned
for four-legged friends.
Residents ride their horses
in and out of there
all the time.
Well, that's how he did it.
Where there's a horse trail,
there's a dog trail.
Maybe security
thought this guy was
just walking his dog.
That's how he
got past them.
Yeah, and then once onto
the Berman property,
he didn't need
the dog anymore,
so he let her loose.
(whines)
That's okay,
sweetie.
Uncle Hodges is gonna adopt you
when all this is over.
No, he's not. Uncle Greg is.
But I am going
to scan you
with my "ARF"-ID Reader.
(beep)
Shelter dog.
Rescued into a life of crime.
Okay, get a shot of her
for me, will you?
Yeah.
Say cheese, sweetie.
Cheese, sweetie.
Got your text.
What do you got?
Well, this is a first.
Our killer adopted
a death-imminent mongrel dog.
You know, a mutt.
But he made a mistake.
He left a copy of his driver's
license at the dog pound.
The information
is bogus,
but the girl at the
counter I.D.'d the photo.
So I'm looking at our killer.
It gets better.
Nick saw a security camera
in the parking
lot of the animal shelter.
We ran the plate.
Rental?
Affirmative.
Time to LoJack this jackass.
Control, this is Two Zero
Three Charlie, Captain Brass.
We're at
the LoJack-identified site.
Eyes on a silver Ford.
Nevada plates Adam, King,
Sam, Henry, Four, One, Three.
STOKES:
Key's still
in the ignition, Jim.
Well, you have evidence
but no one to tie it to.
He knew that.
That's why
he left it all behind.
Ballistics confirmed
that's the murder weapon.
No prints. No DNA.
We tracked down
Berman's jeweler.
He's the one who
identified the ring.
Five-carat rock.
Worth over $2 million.
RUSSELL: Great
payday for a killer.
Untraceable.
I also processed
the disposable phone.
There were only
two numbers in memory:
one from an animal shelter
and one from
a rental car agency.
The only thing
probative, really,
is the video.
Wait, there's a video on
a disposable cell phone?
Oh, yeah.
Play it.
(gunshot)
(woman grunts)
(shrieks)
(gunshot)
(sighs)
You okay?
I missed it.
Hey, slow down,
will you?
What did you miss?
Something on that snuff film?
It's not a snuff film;
it's proof of kill
sent by the hit man
to the deep Web
to create a résumé
in cyberspace
so he gets hired
for future hits.
Wait... (exhales)
You're saying
that the guy who created Kitty
is a hit man?
No.
No, no, no.
The man who created Kitty
is a psycho-sadist.
He derives pleasure from
inflicting pain to others.
He would never tape himself
killing somebody.
He is the one I'm after.
Don't you see?
My psycho-sadist
hired your hit man.
So your Node...
Was never even in Vegas.
And that's what I missed.
So now we're
looking for two ghosts.
Mine is underground, and yours
is halfway around the world.
Brass called Interpol.
They put out a worldwide
broadcast on our hit man.
Hopefully they'll
get a bead on him
so they can drag
his ass back to Vegas.
When's the last time you
changed your profile picture?
I don't know, probably after
I shaved my beard off.
Good, you're controlling
your self-image.
So's he.
Before Nebula1
was a smiley face,
this is what he looked like.
(laughs)
Oh, yeah,
that rates really high
on the creepy meter.
Nebula1-- what's that all about?
Nebula means dark mist.
He thinks he's
beyond our reach.
Tell me, what do you see?
The obvious? Um...
Caucasian male, 20s,
button-up shirt,
books, family
photos, window,
blinds.
And from what I can tell,
it's nighttime.
Put it in context.
Barbells
on the floor.
Guy works out.
He's antisocial.
He doesn't like the gym.
Yeah, and he doesn't like
to take out the trash, either.
(short chuckle)
Cans are stuffed.
To-go cups,
food containers.
He orders in a lot.
He's agoraphobic.
He doesn't like to leave,
not even to eat.
Well, we need
to I.D. him, right?
Guy's got a lot of
family photos there.
If they were his family.
What do you mean?
Blood is thicker
than water, but it's not
thicker than
a watermark.
Back up the bus.
He downloaded
a fake family?
Everything you see
here is staged.
Family photos communicate
that he's a good person.
Books are supposed
to make us believe
that he's intelligent.
Blinds are closed
so we don't know
where he lives.
Hmm.
Why did you say
it was nighttime?
I don't know.
I mean, I can see
stars through the blinds.
What, he stage those too?
No. No. That's an oversight.
(computer chirping)
It's gestalt theory
of continuation.
Looks like an arch.
It's the Gateway Arch.
He's in St. Louis.
I'll triangulate
coordinates.
Clear!
Clear? What do you mean,
"clear"?
No suspect on the premises.
Ma'am, you need to see this.
We've got a whole
nerve center here.
Computers, hard drives,
the works.
STOKES:
Oh, looks like he's
still in business, but
if he never leaves the house,
then where is he?
Give me the ceiling.
All four corners.
He's got a Web cam!
He's watching us! It's a trap!
Get out! Extract! Extract!
Go! Go! Everybody out! Go!
(shouting, explosion)
(static)
(sighs)
Figured I'd find you out here.
Hey, you saved all
those men's lives today.
Unfortunately, the evidence
didn't fare so well.
We lost DNA, prints.
All the hardware
was incinerated.
Oh. Is that right, D.B.?
Well, yes, Avery, it is.
I found a photo
of Susan's house on her phone.
She never posted it
to Friend Agenda.
If I upload it,
he'll know where she lives.
You're thinking
of putting her in play?
I applied some pressure.
I got an agoraphobe
to leave his house.
We could lure him.
He is moveable.
And now you want
to move him again
and use Susan to do it.
(Ryan sighs)
But you're on the fence
about it?
The Internet
amplifies crime.
If my Node gets
away with this,
his cyber cred
will be immortalized.
He will spawn hundreds, if not
thousands, of copycatters.
So it's Susan
versus the greater good.
I looked that woman in the eye,
and I promised her
I would protect her.
We are talking about a woman
and two little girls.
Do you want my opinion?
Greater good.
Put her in play.
I've got you covered.
(camera shutters clicking)
My name is Susan McDowell.
My husband's a Marine
proudly serving in Afghanistan.
I am a mother of two girls.
I thought I was tough,
that I could handle anything.
Then someone hacked
into my life,
hijacked all my photos online,
used my likeness,
my face, my body,
put me on the Internet,
where I was virtually raped
by thousands of men.
There is no law against
what this man did to me.
But I was violated.
Virtual rape...
Is rape.
SUSAN:
...is rape.
And I refuse
to stand back and do nothing.
And I refuse to stand by
and do nothing.
Susan, you can do this.
The difference between
a victim and victory
is action.
Take back your life.
Provoke him,
expose him for what he is.
You see this?
This is what he turned me into.
A whore, a prostitute.
He's selling my body
to thousands of men
around the world 24/7.
As of today,
I'm shutting you down.
And so here's my message
to all you men out there.
Log off and check
into your families.
Don't let this coward win.
(Ryan laughs)
(whooping)
RYAN:
Well done, Susan.
CLIKK:
Agent Ryan, I've been tracking
Nebula1's activity
on Friend Agenda
since you announced
her press conference.
In the last hour, he's peeped
her page 900,000 times.
He D.O.S.'d her?
He's so angry,
he crashed her site.
You wanted obsession.
You got it.
We're going to San Diego.
♪ ♪
You're a cop.
You're a sadist.
Where's Kitty?
You mean Susan?
You're confused.
Susan is real; Kitty is not.
I created Kitty.
I made her.
I'm not gonna ask you again.
Is that a .45?
(sniffing)
I guarantee you
it's never been fired.
I've had bigger guns pointed
at my face.
Wait till you see my other gun.
I saw it.
The one your hit man used
to kill Audrey Berman?
I thought
I'd do this one myself.
I thought you'd be
more of a blade man.
She just got him to trade down.
How long are we gonna play
this waiting game?
We wait for
Agent Ryan's code word.
You going to cut me?
You like to watch me bleed?
Yeah.
You want me to cut you again?
Are you hearing that?
Yeah. She's adding
years to his sentence.
Tell me about the first time.
I was eight years old...
and I cut my sister's breasts
with a straight razor.
I got no problem
cutting you.
Well, I do.
I'm out of here.
You're not going anywhere!
Have you ever
been murdered before?
Mushroom.
(explosive rumbling)
(grunts)
Drop it!
Drop it! Drop it!
Stay down!
You're under arrest
for attempted murder
of a federal agent,
conspiracy to commit murder,
extortion, and a thousand counts
of being a creep.
Say bye-bye to your Wi-Fi.
(grunting)
You all right?
I'll feel a lot better when you
get our hit man behind bars.
You're something else.
(laughs)
Oh, my God.
SUSAN:
Thank you so much for
bringing us down here.
The girls are
so excited.
(laughing)
They want to be pilots
just like their dad.
Girls!
(gasps)
BOTH:
Daddy! Daddy!
You brought my husband home?
After all you've been through,
you both deserve
a hero's welcome.
Thank you.
(Ryan laughs)
(laughs)
That was nice.
So this is good-bye,
I guess, huh?
Well, for now.
Where you off to?
Oh, bank robbery, Pittsburgh.
How much?
Three cents.
Oh, give me a break.
Talk to me. How much?
Three copper pennies...
from 80 million
checking accounts.
$2.4 million a week.
Makes for one hell of a heist.
Check your bank statements.
No kidding.
And they say there's no
such thing as the perfect crime.
It's not the perfect crime.
It's cyber crime.
♪ I can see for miles
and miles and miles ♪
♪ And miles and miles ♪