(siren wailing)
So, which one
is your favorite?
Got to go with
Jailhouse Rock.
But Blue Hawaii's
right up there.
Yeah.
How about you?
Well, it's
a little obscure,
but I'd have to say that
my favorite Elvis movie
is definitely
Change of Habit.
There's just something
about Mary Tyler Moore
dressed as a nun.
Yeah, I can see that.
SIDLE:
Hey, guys.
Wow.
Viva Las Vegas.
Yeah, minus the "viva."
No encore for this guy.
Do we have a name?
George Tabin.
Business card says
he's an Elvis tribute artist.
Cash is still there.
Credit cards, too.
Rules out robbery.
Looks like multiple head wounds.
No blood on the bench.
No blood pool on the ground.
No, this was definitely
not the primary.
He was killed somewhere else,
brought here,
propped up on the bench,
and staged.
I've got
gravitational blood drops
over here heading
away from the body.
Maybe from the weapon?
Well, looks
like a trail.
Nice night
for a stroll.
End of the blood trail.
No murder weapon,
but looks like
we have another victim.
It's been stabbed.
There has to be a connection.
Maybe the killer
is making a reference
to Edgar Allan Poe.
Well, then he needs
to brush up on his birds.
This isn't a raven,
it's a rook.
You see the white skin
around its beak?
A rook?
Well, the weird thing
though is rooks are
indigenous to Central
Europe and Asia.
What's one doing
in Southern Nevada?
I think I made the connection.
Between a bird and an
Elvis impersonator?
No, between a rook...
and a king.
As in, they're both
chess pieces.
As in,
whoever our killer is
has a sick sense of humor.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
Lost or lost
in your thoughts?
Avenue D and 1st.
D1.
We found the king
at Avenue C and 1st.
C1.
Now I'm lost.
We're looking for
the primary, right?
Where are we going?
Uh, you want
to fill me in, or...?
The squares of a
chessboard are delineated
by letters and numbers.
Avenue E and
1st Street-- E1.
Now, there is a chess move
known as "castling."
The player moves
two pieces at the same time.
The rook from its
original position to D1,
and the king from E1 to C1.
From Avenue E and 1st Street
to Avenue C and 1st Street.
We are in the Alphabets.
Um, Greg,
I-I know you were captain
of your high school chess team,
and-and I respect your instincts
as a criminalist immensely...
But you think I'm reaching.
No.
Actually, I-I think
you're a genius.
Memphis or bust?
Graceland's in Memphis, right?
Yeah.
(groans)
There is a significant
amount of blood spatter
in the driver's seat.
I think we just found
our primary.
Maybe he wanted us to find
the king's carriage as well.
Even threw in the murder weapon.
So, Doc, word
on the street is...
If you say,
"The king is dead,"
I will kick you
right out of here.
I've already had my fill of
bad Elvis puns from David.
So hard to resist.
Yes, I'm sure.
Okay, C.O.D. is multiple
craniocerebral injuries
due to the blunt force
trauma to the head.
Consistent with
the tire iron we found.
Didn't have any prints on it.
Well, he was struck at
least a dozen times.
Suggests rage.
With a twist.
The tox screen flagged
diphenhydramine in his system.
Wow, at these levels,
even the real Elvis
would've been unconscious.
Yes. There, uh...
was no pill residue in
his gastric contents,
but I found this.
An injection site.
So, he was drugged
before he was beaten to death.
Premeditation,
careful planning.
Just like a chess player.
Well, that's very
astute of you.
(imitating Elvis):
Thank you very much.
Out. Get out.
I know you're a fan
of fungi,
but are you also a fan
of nonvascular plants?
Specifically bryophyta?
Should I be?
Well, if it helps us
catch a killer, yes.
I found
what I thought was a hair
on the king's jumpsuit.
Didn't match our vic,
so I ran it.
And you found out
that it was moss.
Yes.
In this case,
a small, but mighty variety
capable of consuming 20%
of its own weight in fluids.
Sounds like my college roommate.
(laughs)
I know that guy.
It's a little
strange, isn't it?
I mean, you can't grow moss
in Vegas; it's a desert.
You need moisture.
I found traces
of sodium lauryl sulfate
and shea butter on the stem.
Those are commonly found
in shampoos and bath oils.
I give up.
Where's this moss from?
Not to shill
for the Mediterranean Hotel,
but they recently installed
live-moss bath mats
in all of their rooms.
Part of an
"environmental chic" design.
Now, I checked.
Our Elvis impersonator is
persona non grata
at the Mediterranean,
but perhaps our killer isn't.
Bit of a long shot,
don't you think?
Not if I told you
that the Mediterranean
is currently hosting an
international chess tournament.
Ah.
WOMAN (over P.A.): Welcome to
the King's Crown Tournament.
All players, please show
your USCM I.D. cards
at the registration desk.
Hi.
MAN: Check.
MAN 2: Damn it.
(laughs)
Come on, man.
You really think
that one of these guys
took a tire iron
to the king?
SANDERS:
What?
Too nerdy to kill?
Well, yeah. I mean,
look at them.
I doubt if half of these guys
could even hold a tire iron
over their head,
much less swing it.
Chess is by definition
a sequence of captures,
ambushes, sacrifices
and attacks.
It's violence played out.
Uh, no, I think it's
just a board game.
LVPD?
Yes.
I'm Jenny Carroll, the
tournament director.
I believe I spoke with
one of you on the phone.
That would be me.
I'm CSI Sanders.
Hi.
CSI Stokes.
Thank you for your time.
We just want to ask you
a few questions, okay?
What about?
Well, actually,
it's about a homicide.
A homicide connected
to the festival?
You mentioned
on the phone
that this tournament is
part of a promotional tour?
Yes, we are trying to broaden
the appeal of the game.
Just make it sexier.
Oh, well, no offense.
You might want to try getting
a few more women in the joint.
(laughs)
Oh, I agree.
Chess has been
pretty much a man's game.
It would be nice to open it up.
Can't say I disagree
with that.
Uh, excuse me.
STOKES:
He, uh...
he played chess in high school;
he-he gets really excited.
Check.
Kid?
I should've known
that you would've been here.
Hey, do you mind?
Man's an old friend.
A player once, too.
Well, if that's the case,
then you should know enough
to show some respect
for the game.
People should show
respect period.
We're done.
He's, uh... intense.
From the looks of it,
he had already lost anyways.
I assume you're not here
for the tournament.
I'm sorry, I still
can't believe
anyone here would be
involved in murder.
Well, I've seen
stranger things.
So, how long is
the tournament in town?
Since Monday. We're on the
eighth stop of a 12-city tour.
STOKES: And how many
players do you have?
150 signed up in Vegas.
Well, if you don't mind,
I'm gonna need
a list of all their names.
Including a list
of all your vendors.
Quite frankly,
anything associated
with the chess tour, okay?
Okay, sure.
I-I still think you're looking
in the wrong place,
but whatever you need.
Who is this guy?
What's going on over here?
It's called a "simul."
Um, man in the middle is
former champion Karl Schrute.
He's playing against
everyone seated.
He's playing
everybody at once?
Yeah, he's our
star attraction.
Ah, that's
a pretty cool trick.
Amateurs come from all over
to play against him.
So, former champ.
Has anyone ever
beat him doing that?
Never.
What about you?
Looks like you could
beat him pretty easy.
Okay, I'll start working
on that list.
(laughs)
Okay.
MAN:
"Chess Freak Kills the King."
Would certainly make
for a great headline.
Maybe I can see it.
At first, the game
gets in your blood.
Then it gets in your head.
It can drive you to madness.
Any idea who you're looking for?
I've already told you
everything I can tell you, Max.
Heard that before.
Day you told me you were
turning your back on the game.
(sighs)
It's good to see you again, Max.
Good to be seen.
(timer ticking)
SIDLE: Nick got a list
of all the participants
and the vendors
at the King's Crown.
There are a lot of names
to go through.
Let's pull people
from day shift and swing.
More eyes, the better.
You know,
if you want to play by yourself,
there's, uh, computers for that.
Yeah. Actually, do me a favor.
Come here.
Sit down for a sec.
Take a look at the white pieces.
Tell me what you see.
Looks like you castled
your king.
On the queen's side,
just like the killer.
But what else?
SIDLE: You moved your pawns,
your knight,
the bishop and the queen.
If you want to castle,
you have to move those pieces.
Because castling
can't be an opening move.
Which means if the killer
is following the rules,
our Elvis impersonator
would not be his first kill.
And if that's true, then our job
just got a lot harder.
We're not just looking
for a suspect,
we're looking
for more victims.
Hey.
Oh, sorry.
It's okay, I'm on hold.
I've been looking at
all of our open cases
for the past year.
None of them seem to have
anything to do with chess.
What about outside Vegas?
You're thinking that
if our killer is connected
to the King's Crown Tour,
maybe our cases
that we're looking for
are in cities where
the tour has stopped.
Yeah. I'm on hold with
San Francisco PD right now.
Yeah. Oh, Detective Ettinger.
Yeah, I'm looking
for unsolved murders
the week of
February 17th.
Right, bodies found near
numbered streets or avenues.
Uh, there is
one other parameter.
It's gonna sound a little crazy,
but the crimes are gonna have
some sort of
association with chess.
Yeah, like, the victim
could be a bishop or a priest
or maybe some
kind of queen.
I know it sounds crazy.
Look, any help
that-that you could give
would be greatly appreciated.
Thank you.
(laughs)
I do not envy you.
Well, misery
loves company.
Mm.
We... have six more
cities to call.
SIDLE:
Russell, you were right.
Our Elvis impersonator was not
the killer's first victim.
Morgan and I found
six other murders
that look to be chess-related--
not in Vegas,
but in the last three cities
that the chess tour visited.
Portland, San Francisco
and Reno.
SIDLE: In Portland,
a woman on horseback
and a homeless man.
RUSSELL:
Knight and a pawn.
SIDLE: In San Francisco,
a drag queen and a priest.
SANDERS:
A queen and a bishop.
And in Reno, another
homeless person and a priest.
RUSSELL:
Another pawn and a bishop.
All the bodies were dumped
at intersections
of numbered
and lettered streets.
So we have seven victims.
Seven chess murders.
Mm-hmm.
But I don't believe that
the murders are capture-kills.
The killer is not
eliminating pieces.
I believe that these murders
are chess moves.
SANDERS: Like our dead Elvis--
king to C1.
He wasn't eliminating
the king...
just moving him.
So we have a serial killer
who's playing a game,
and every time he makes a move,
somebody dies.
Yeah. Well, based on
what I can see,
the game's
just beginning.
I knew you'd be back.
Same old Max.
How many games
have you played
just staring at
that board?
Why don't you sit down...
find out?
I told you.
I don't play anymore.
You play every day.
You just don't do it
on a chessboard.
The only game I'm
playing right now
is "catch a killer."
And I need your help.
This is a list
of chess moves.
I need to know what
move comes next.
You already know it.
In here.
I really don't.
I only have one
side of the board,
and I don't know any of
the opponent's moves.
Remember what I told you
all those years ago?
Don't play the board,
play the man.
Greg, the board is the
face of your opponent.
You can know a man just
by watching him play.
I knew you the minute you put
your money down to play me.
You don't know me.
You come here every
day after school.
You're not at
football practice,
you're not in the
parking lot getting high.
You're different
from the other kids.
You think differently,
feel differently.
You want different.
What do I want?
You want to be the best!
But to be the best,
you've got to go through me.
School's in.
SANDERS:
Come on, Max.
We're not back
in the park.
This isn't
a lesson here.
There are people's
lives at stake.
This game has already
been played.
16 years ago.
These are the opening moves
in the championship match
between Karl Schrute
and Troy Parker.
Karl Schrute-- that's the guy
doing the dog and pony show,
playing simuls in
this tournament here.
Man's got to make a living.
All right, what about, uh,
his opponent, Parker?
(chuckles)
Troy Parker was
the greatest American player
since Bobby Fischer.
Till he lost
that championship in '98.
After that,
he went off the rails.
Just disappeared.
Back in '98...
what was Parker's
next move?
Bishop to E3.
Mm, yes.
It was Parker's fatal move,
actually.
A mental mistake.
Uncharacteristic for
someone so gifted.
And it was that move
that gave you the game?
Yes, yes.
He had me on the
ropes until then.
Only a few moves
away from victory.
And it wasn't just
the end of the game. No.
It was the end of him.
The man became a ghost.
Do you think he might harbor
any resentment toward you
about the game
or even try to...
engineer some kind
of a rematch?
Troy Parker was not
a violent man.
Okay.
So can you think of
anyone else out there
who might have
an unhealthy interest
in your old match
with Parker?
I can think of
hundreds of people
that cannot stop talking
about that match.
And as far as
"unhealthy interest,"
I get a letter a week
from some crackpot.
Really?
Have you, uh, received
any recently?
You know, I did
receive an odd missive
when I first arrived
at the hotel.
I didn't think
twice about it.
What kind of missive?
It was a note wishing me well,
wrapped around a chess piece.
Um, it was sort of,
mm... handmade.
It was a bishop.
Do you still have it?
I believe so.
Unless they've
emptied the trash.
♪ ♪
I processed the hand-carved
bishop sent to Karl Schrute.
It wasn't hand-carved so much
as it was hand-sculpted.
Made from papier-mâché.
A curious stew of toilet
paper, laundry soap and water.
Okay. That sounds improvised.
By someone with a lot of time
on his hands.
Say, a prison inmate?
The laundry soap
in our bishop
is specifically formulated
to work with the hard water
at Ely State Prison.
Good work.
All right, so we need
to cross-reference the list
of people who attended
the chess tour with
the population at Ely, right?
Already done.
I have a face
and a name.
You are on fire.
"Lee Crosby."
So you're just
gonna sit there?
Not gonna ask
why you're here?
You'll tell me
when you want to.
Or maybe
you already know.
That's a photo
from the dash-cam
of a Number 7 Bus.
It shows you
two nights ago
on the corner
of Avenue C and 5th.
Four blocks away from here.
A bold opening.
It's aggressive.
I usually find
when an opponent leads
with a big move, they don't have
much of a game to back it up.
We're not playing
chess here, Mr. Crosby.
And the fact
of the matter is,
we have plenty.
I guess this is the part
where I call my lawyer.
Five bills an hour--
I say save the money,
indulge the cop.
STOKES: We know you
spent five years
at Ely for possession,
and that most of that time
was spent in a rehab program
that taught you
how to play chess.
Some inmates find God.
I found the Royal Game.
CRAWFORD: You know
what we keep finding?
You.
In Portland,
San Francisco, Reno.
All stops
on the chess tour.
Cities where bodies
have been dropping.
Like little chess moves
on a board.
Admittedly, I am
a bit insane...
about... chess.
(chuckles)
Yes, I have been
following the tour,
but, like, riding
buses at night.
That's all
I've been doing.
You know who
Troy Parker is, right?
Heard of him.
At Ely, you ordered
over a dozen books on him.
Including his book
on the game.
CRAWFORD: Sounds like
an obsession to me.
I bet you know every move
this guy's ever made.
I bet you even think
that you're better than him.
Parker was the best,
the top of his game,
but he made a mistake,
a single bad move,
and it was his undoing.
Won't catch me making
that same error.
Promise you that.
You've been following
the chess tour.
You've been dogging Schrute,
trying to get him
to play you one-on-one.
There's a lot of people that
want to play Schrute, okay?
STOKES:
Everyone is not obsessed
with his old adversary,
Troy Parker,
the way that you are.
So obsessed...
that you're replaying
their match from '98.
And you've taken it
to a whole nother level,
Mr. Crosby.
You're killing people.
In some sick,
twisted little fantasy.
You're right.
I would love to play Schrute.
God, I would love to replay
his famous match with Parker.
And you can forget about
"as good as Parker,"
because I am better.
I got something
that he never had.
CRAWFORD:
What's that?
Killer instinct.
Mm-hmm.
And this is just
between you and me.
I'm no killer.
What do you think?
Is he our guy?
Well, he's got
the arrogance.
Delusions of grandeur.
Greg said he's got
quite a temper, too.
All right, let's have
Crawford sit on him
while we get a warrant,
check out his place.
(phone ringing)
Yeah.
We're definitely gonna
need something more
to connect him to
one of the victims.
What is it?
(sighs)
Another move
has been played.
SANDERS:
Hey, Sara.
So what's going on?
I think we have
another chess killer victim.
The next body dump
was supposed to be
near Avenue E and 3rd.
Yeah, I know.
But, uh... you need to see this.
Victim's name
is Chris Shatlock.
I found his wallet
tossed on the floor.
Work card says that he does
a dinner show at the Four Kings.
Take a look.
Security guard
discovered him.
Run through from
back to front.
Found his uniform in the back.
Take a look.
He's a Knight of
the Round Table.
SANDERS:
A knight?
But next victim
should've been a bishop.
Bishop to E3.
That's what Schrute said;
it was Parker's next move.
Yes. But...
he has an injection mark
on his neck,
just like our dead Elvis.
And take a look at the wall.
Knight to A4--
that's a chess move.
Killer's changed
his pattern.
He's changed the game.
♪ ♪
RUSSELL: Troy Parker--
I thought he was a ghost.
Are you sure about this print?
Yep.
Which means
we are holding
the wrong guy for
these murders.
At least the, uh, Knight
of the Round Table.
T.O.D. says he was killed
at the same time
we had Lee Crosby
in the box.
So what are
we thinking?
That Troy Parker
is staging his comeback?
Replaying the game
he lost to Karl Schrute?
Only to him,
it's not a game.
He's making his moves
by killing people.
Okay, so the guy's
a grandmaster.
Right? He thinks he's
smarter than his opponent.
Right now,
his opponent is us,
so we need
to make the next move.
What do we know about him?
Anything?
Where is he?
Well, since '98, he's been
pretty much of a recluse,
and, uh, nobody has laid eyes
on him in the last five years.
Nick did pull some trace
from the dead knight's car.
Hopefully, Parker left
something behind.
We need to find this guy.
(knocking)
I think
Troy Parker just reached out.
CSI Russell,
Jenny Carroll.
Ms. Carroll is in charge
of the chess tour.
How do you do?
How can I help you,
Ms. Carroll?
We received this package at
our reception area an hour ago.
It was sent to our grandmaster-
in-residence, Karl Schrute.
Has anyone else touched this
besides you?
My assistant and I.
He's the one who opened it.
It's a knight.
Has Mr. Schrute seen this yet?
No, and truth is,
I can't find him.
No one can.
He's not in his room,
not answering his phone.
You don't think something's
happened to him, do you?
We're gonna need to keep this.
Thank you so much
for-for bringing it to us.
SANDERS:
He's changed the game, Max.
Why?
Why do you think?
He wants to correct the error,
the fatal mistake he made
the first time around,
the one that cost him
the championship.
Correct.
Knight to A4 was the move Troy
Parker should have made in '98.
So... the guy's
trying to win.
No.
He's going to win.
But it's more than that.
In '98, Troy Parker was
on the verge of doing something
no one had ever done before
in competition.
What are you talking about?
The Osterlitz endgame.
It's like...
the Holy Grail of chess.
Parker was three moves
away from making history
when he screwed up.
Bishop to E3.
The move that ruined his life.
You think Parker's killing
these people, don't you?
I didn't say that.
Let me tell you something.
Troy Parker was a genius.
And... he was a fool.
The man
you're looking for
is neither.
And it's definitely not...
Parker.
How can you
be so sure?
I mean, you're the
one who said it.
Chess can drive
a man to madness.
MAN:
You're Troy Parker?
Is it really you?
I often wonder that myself.
Do you mind?
I can't believe this.
This is awesome.
It really is you.
PARKER: Congratulations.
You want a prize?
MAN: Settle for an answer
to just one question.
Bishop to E3, right?
How could I have been so stupid?
Dude, I didn't say that.
No, but you thought it...
just like everyone thinks it.
But aren't we all entitled to
make one mistake in our lives?
Leave me alone.
MAN:
Bro, bro, come back.
All I wanted to ask was,
"Why did you quit?"
Why did you quit?
How long have you
been standing there?
Not long.
All these years, "captain
of the chess team."
That's all you
ever told us.
Didn't know you were
such a chess stud.
Yeah, well, there are a lot of
things you don't know about me.
(chuckles) You haven't
answered the question.
I don't know why I quit.
It's just, one day...
I couldn't do it anymore.
Like him.
You know what the problem is
with people like you,
with the world?
You can't understand
what it is to be an artist.
What it is to create beauty!
You only understand ugliness,
because you can only
understand yourself!
MAN: Dude, I was just
trying to ask...
Get that out of my face!
Ooh.
Man holds the
world in contempt.
Just the kind of guy who might
see people as chess pieces.
Hey, Nick.
Yeah?
Apparently,
there are no shortage
of people around
who have seen your little
friend, cimexlectularius.
Oh, yeah? Like who?
Got a list here
of motels and weeklies,
all with recent
infestations of bedbugs,
just like the one you found
when you processed the car.
Take a look at the
one in Boulder City.
Manager there says
he's got a resident
who matches the photo we
sent over of Troy Parker.
Really?
Yeah. A little
older and grayer,
but it's definitely him.
Good. Thanks, Morgan.
According to the manager,
Parker's been here
for about a year
under the name Jason Winston.
He always pays his rent
in advance, cash.
Keeps to himself.
Hmm. Sounds to me like a
guy who didn't want to draw
any attention
to himself.
Saving himself
for the big event?
Yeah, well, game over.
(knocking)
Troy Parker, LVPD.
Open up!
LVPD!
Parker!
(water running)
It's Lee Crosby.
What?
He's dead.
(sighs)
Damn it.
Didn't have
enough to hold him.
Had to let him go
this afternoon.
STOKES:
Well, for somebody
who studied
Parker's every move,
I don't think he saw
that one coming.
I found these vials
and-and syringes in the trash.
Probably from the drug
that was used
to paralyze the victims
before they were killed.
I'll send it off to Hodges.
Talk about
a dangerous mind, huh?
All these chessboards.
And it looks like they're
playing the exact same game.
They are.
Except this one.
It's further along.
My friend Max was right.
It's the
Osterlitz endgame.
And Parker's
playing it out.
Crosby's murder--
it's just another move.
And see the pawn
there tipped over?
Parker's saying
that he and Crosby
teamed up for the killings.
But this whole time,
Crosby was just his pawn.
And the move-- pawn to C6.
It's the part
of the Osterlitz endgame
where the pawn
puts the king in check,
only to be quickly sacrificed.
What does he do next?
Checkmate.
He takes down the king.
Karl Schrute is missing.
I think Parker has him.
And he's gonna kill him.
Not if we find him first.
♪ ♪
Morgan, you're not
gonna believe this.
Try me.
The drugs in the vials
recovered from Parker's place?
It's not the diphenhydramine
Doc found in our victims.
So what is it then?
It's an experimental medication,
available only
in Europe and Mexico.
Used to treat people
in the late stages
of vascular dementia.
You realize what this
means, don't you?
If the drugs are Parker's,
there's no way
that he would be mentally
or physically capable
of committing
any of those crimes.
(computer beeping)
Parker's not our guy.
Then who is?
Where's CSI Sanders?
That's not your
problem, Mr. Lomax.
Your problem is you've
been lying to us.
STOKES: You knew this whole
time where Parker was.
And you know he can
barely lift a fork,
much less commit murder.
RUSSELL: You should
know we're going
through your
place right now.
We're also going
through Lee Crosby's.
Yeah, we know you two
hooked up at Ely.
During that outreach program.
We know that you're the one who
taught him how to play chess.
RUSSELL: Is that where
you turned him on
to this legendary match
between Troy Parker
and Karl Schrute?
We got your prints.
We got you for conspiracy.
So the only thing keeping you
from the needle
is if you stop lying.
And you tell us where Parker
and Schrute are
right now.
I never lied.
The only thing
I'm guilty of
is caring for a great man.
Now sadly diminished.
My only crime is not
turning him over to you.
To protect his memory.
The world should remember him
for what he was.
(chuckles softly)
Not as he is.
RUSSELL:
Yeah, well,
all we're concerned about,
Mr. Lomax, is where he is.
And Karl Schrute.
Okay.
That's too bad.
But I'll tell
you something.
For your sake, you better hope
they're still alive.
Wherever they are.
Kid?
If I figured it out,
and I think I have,
you can, too.
But you've got to look
in the right place.
Just like I told you a long
time ago.
To see the endgame,
you have to see
the board through
your opponent's eyes.
LOMAX: Come on, kid,
moves are motivation.
I'm telling you what I'm
doing, I'm telling you what
I'm going to do. You got to
stop me, make it your game,
not mine.
That's it. Good.
Come on, come on.
There you go.
Take it, take it.
Don't be afraid. Take it,
take it, take it, take it.
Checkmate!
The endgame.
It's the queen.
Please be careful with those.
I'd like them to make
it at least until...
Phoenix.
So, the tour continues.
Even without its
star attraction.
CSI Sanders.
Still no word on
Mr. Schrute's whereabouts?
Still playing games?
Excuse me?
The list of vendors
you gave us--
I checked it out.
You closed out all
of the accounts.
Except one.
A storage facility downtown
in the Alphabets.
Don't worry
about it because
we closed it for you.
The same time that we rescued
Karl Schrute and Troy Parker.
I get it.
Men are weak, aren't they?
Just like the king
on the chessboard.
He hides while all the other
pieces fight to protect him.
Lee Crosby was weak, too.
Easily seduced
into killing
for you.
Am I right?
What do you think?
You neglected
to mention
to us that you have
chess in your blood.
Your father
was a grandmaster.
You must've learned
a lot from him.
I learned nothing from him.
Except that, unlike my brothers,
I was worthless.
Women are worthless.
My father used to say,
"Chess is a man's game
because it's about power,
intellect."
All things, he said,
I did not possess.
But your father was wrong.
Damn right he was wrong.
I was better than my brothers.
Better than him.
And every time I killed,
I was killing him.
So why Parker and Schrute?
They were just...
like him.
Cut from the same cloth.
So you were better
than them, too?
You know, there are 32 pieces
on a chessboard--
bishops, knights,
pawns, kings.
And yet which piece
is most powerful?
The queen.
♪ ♪
(footsteps approaching)
I was just
on my way out.
Want to grab a bite?
Uh, I should...
probably finish this.
Thanks though.
Okay.
Actually,
um, you asked
why I quit playing chess.
I used to think that it was
because I didn't think I had
what it took to be the best.
Well, that couldn't
have been it.
(both chuckle)
And then I realized
that chess...
requires a lot of sacrifice.
Too much
sacrifice.
And I just didn't think
it was worth it.
It stopped being fun.
It requires a totally
different way of thinking.
You have to retrain
your mind, and...
it starts to become
an obsession.
Kind of like this job.
If you know
what I mean.
I do.
I was not even
my grade school champion,
and this is kind of crazy,
but, you know,
Russell's got that chessboard
in his office. Maybe...
we should get something
to eat and play.
For fun?
Sure.
(chuckles)
You better
go easy on me.
I'll try.
(laughs)