(music plays in distance)
(static crackling over
indistinct voices)
(indistinct chatter;
static crackling)
MAN (staticky): Can I get a cup
of coffee from...
(man continues, voice garbled,
mixed with other voices)
WOMAN: Where do you want
to go tonight?
(staticky):
You want, to, like...
MAN: I'd like a tall latte
with, uh, two shots... (static)
Coming right up.
Thanks.
Would you like anything
to eat, sir?
No, thank you.
That'll be three
dollars, please.
Um, look, I don't suppose you
could, uh, break a 50?
For a three-dollar latte?
Well, it's all I have.
All right.
(clears throat)
Thank you;
thank you so much.
Mr. Merchiston?
Keep walking.
Who are you?
A friend of Suvari.
Where is Suvari?
Not here, but I am.
Right. And what
assurance do I have
that this man Suvari
is actually real?
How does Suvari really know
that you're a reporter?
And not an Agency asset?
Well, in the interest
of full disclosure,
I've yet to be mistaken
for James Bond.
(laughs)
Aw.
(surveillance camera whirring)
Suvari will be in touch.
(alarm chirps)
(engine growling)
(engine roars, tires screech)
(engine roars)
(siren starts up,
tires screech)
OFFICER (over radio):
Control, this is 3-David-34.
Reporting a possible 425-Baker.
In pursuit of a silver Camaro.
License Adam-King-Sam-Henry,
413.
Vehicle's traveling southbound
on Rialto Ridge
at high rate of speed.
(siren wailing)
Backup units, be advised.
Suspect vehicle has turned
onto Wilmington.
(tires screech, siren wails)
He's heading for the Strip.
OFFICER:
Control, this guy's not
stopping.
We need to bring him down
before he hurts somebody.
OFFICER:
He's crossing lanes!
Oh, my God!
CONTROL:
All units, fire and paramedics
are en route to your location.
Thank you.
Yeager?!
What are you doing here?
Oh, I'm pulling
double shifts this week.
Need the hours,
so you're stuck with me.
So, our driver raced
through the intersection,
lost control,
hit this lamp pole,
and spun out over there.
The vehicle's registered
to Zenith Car Rentals.
Office will be
open in a hour.
We'll get
the renter's name then.
Think I have an I.D.
Passport.
Finn...
check this out.
It's John Merchiston.
The reporter?
Yeah.
I don't understand.
Why would he run from the LVPD?
I don't know.
It doesn't make any sense.
Well, if this guy's a reporter,
maybe there's more to the story.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
MERCHISTON:
That voice inside your head.
The day that it does go quiet.
Do you think that that
that will bring you peace?
Or will it be a loss
too great to bear?
Merchiston and I spent
a lot of time together.
I suppose he got
to know me a little bit.
But I don't, I don't know
anything about him.
I don't know
if he had a family...
He doesn't have any family.
Well, hell.
All right.
What do we know?
On the face of it,
it looks like an accident.
What's that supposed to mean--
"on the face of it"?
Well, look at the vehicle.
There's nothing left of it.
I mean, the engine is
all the way over there.
Have you ever seen
a car accident like this?
Yeah, sadly, I have.
Alcohol, drugs, a lead foot.
I see it all the time.
Yeah, well, John didn't drink
and he didn't do drugs.
He had been sober
for over two years.
Is there something
you should be telling me?
John was working on a story.
Something to do
with the government
and domestic spying.
He told me
that he was being followed.
I, of course, thought
that he was paranoid.
Wait, wait a minute.
When did this happen?
Well, a couple of months ago.
I-I had, uh, you know...
We stayed in touch.
You'd stayed in touch.
Yes, we stayed in touch.
I'm listening.
The extent
of the damage to the car,
the behavior of a man who had no
reason to run from the police,
and yet, was obviously running
from something.
So you think this was murder?
That John was targeted?
I think he was being silenced
for something that he knew.
Somebody puts a bomb
in the car?
Detonates it during a
high-speed police chase?
Is that what you think?
Mm-hmm, mm-hmm.
That's way out there, Jules.
You don't believe
that there are
parts of government
that would go
to extreme measures
to silence someone?
What I believe in is evidence.
And so should you
if you're thinking
about accusing
somebody in authority.
BRODY:
Based on this video footage,
I can't tell
if Finn's theory is correct,
and the car exploded
before hitting the light pole.
Or if it happened on impact.
Here's the rest of the traffic
cam footage from the chase.
Merchiston ran the red light
at Sahara and Rialto Ridge
already doing 90.
Let's see where
This chase began.
(beeping)
Garage at the
Embarcadero?
Man, he came flying
out of there.
Hmm.
And that is
the best angle from the street
of the Embarcadero we have.
We might be able to track him
moving through the mall.
Let's see.
Hello.
Who's the mystery woman?
I don't know.
But it looks like
she handed him something.
And the way the
light's hitting it,
it looks metallic.
Maybe a key?
Merchiston was
a journalist.
I'm thinking
that that was a flash drive.
We didn't find a flash drive
at the scene.
Though I doubt it would have
survived that explosion.
BRODY: You know, she was
the last person to see
Merchiston alive.
We need to find her.
WOMAN:
So, Mr. Merchiston,
you go from rock journalist
to quixotic muckraker.
I'd have to say
I'm just a seeker of the truth.
And if that makes
certain people uncomfortable,
then maybe they need
to be uncomfortable.
'Cause I would say that
in our obsession with security,
we may be relinquishing
our freedom.
Surrendering
to the real enemy-- fear.
Finished my autopsy
on Mr. Merchiston.
"C.O.D.: massive
blunt force trauma
consistent with
high speed impact."
If it's any consolation, death
would've been mercifully quick--
long before
the fire consumed the vehicle.
Tox report shows
high levels of cocaine,
and a blood alcohol level
of .19.
And in that condition,
I'm not surprised
he didn't want
to get pulled over.
It says here you're going
to rule it an accident.
He should never
have been behind the wheel.
(lift whirring)
♪ ♪
(whirring)
(camera shutter clicking)
FINLAY:
I got your text.
You find something?
Yeah, something
I've never seen before.
At first, I thought
this was some kind
of triggering device.
It's a black box,
like on a plane.
It was installed after-market
by the rental car company.
It's Wi-Fi. They use it
to monitor all their vehicles--
location, speed...
All right, so, it's
not part of a bomb,
but it is a black box,
so, maybe
there's some information in it
that would suggest
that there was a bomb.
Possible. Here is the file
of the car's last trip.
Merchiston floored it
down Rialto Ridge.
He made a left turn,
then crashed.
These vitals and
the GPS indicate
a single catastrophic event
occurring at the coordinates
where the car hit the pole.
So, your explosion
happened upon contact.
Well, that doesn't
rule out a bomb.
Well, it doesn't
support it, either.
This might.
I found unusually
high levels
of aluminum, magnesium,
silicon and iron oxide
in the wreckage.
All are consistent with
a thermite explosion.
Well, that would explain
the intensity of the blast
that we saw on the tape.
And the condition
of the vehicle.
But... we are talking
about a car exploding
upon impact with a light pole.
And the metals present in
thermite are also found
in laptops,
cell phones, tablets.
I know that you're looking
for a different answer,
but I think that we need to find
something more definitive.
(phone rings)
John's attorney is here,
and she wants us
to release his body.
I don't understand.
I thought the circumstances
of John's accident
were pretty clear-cut.
Well, we still have a...
few questions,
Ms. McDermott, and we thought
maybe you could, uh...
you could help us.
Questions like what?
Uh, like, what was the story
that John was working on
which brought him here to Vegas
in the last few months?
John.
So it's you.
(exhales)
John always had
a weakness for blondes.
Your client is dead.
Any information you have
might help us close this case.
So do me a favor,
will you?
Do you, do you recognize
this woman?
No. Why?
FINLAY:
She was the last person
to see John alive.
We think that she
passed him some information.
I've never seen her before.
All I know is
John was working
on an investigative piece.
Something to do with
computer hacking
and domestic
intelligence gathering.
So, spying on U.S. citizens.
McDERMOTT:
Allegedly.
The point person
is an Air Force general,
Robert Lansdale,
out of Nellis.
Nellis.
That would help explain
all the trips to Vegas.
Yeah, and why his accident
may not have been an accident.
I know John had a gift
for telling a good tale.
Seducing his listener.
But the truth is,
his story was going nowhere.
He was frustrated.
So you think
it was an accident?
I do.
Well, you must
have known
that he had enemies.
Yes.
But, also, you must know
that John's own worst enemy
was always himself.
Yeager, it's Russell.
Where are we
on the security footage
from the Embarcadero?
Well-Well then,
go to another judge.
We need those tapes.
I want eyes on Merchiston
and this mystery woman,
wherever they went, okay?
Call me back.
(car engine starts)
(grunts)
Oh!
John?
What the hell are you doing?
We thought you were
...dead.
Dead.
Yeah, I know.
We don't have much time.
I can't stay here.
Where's your car?
Where is your car?
We need to get out of here, now.
What the hell is
going on, John?
I wish I knew.
I wish I bloody knew.
You know a lot more than I do.
Start... Come here.
Whose body is in our morgue?
Oh, it's Brian.
Brian Freeman,
he's my assistant.
He was driving my car.
I gave him my coat and my hat.
He took his place
behind the wheel of my car
and I slipped out the back,
and we both know
what happened after that.
No, no.
We identified the body using
your dental records.
How is that possible?
Same way you got a tox report
claiming that I was high.
And drunk.
Don't play games with me!
Talk to me!
I'm not playing games with you!
(whispers):
I'm covering a story.
I know.
About domestic spying, right?
So you know
it's of a sensitive nature,
involving powerful people.
People capable of hacking
into a crime lab computer,
fabricating
a toxicology report
labeling me
a drunk driver.
What about the dental records?
Well, they've got their hackers,
and I've got mine.
I-I need your help, DB.
John, I'm just
a local cop.
If what you're
saying is true,
you need to...
you need to talk to a
friend of mine at the FBI.
FBI? You're joking, are you?
That's the last place
I'm going is the FBI.
You are hardly a local cop.
In fact,
you and your team--
you're literally
the only ones who can help me.
Please, DB.
My life's in your hands.
The people who are trying
to kill me, the people who...
killed Brian.
When they find out
their mistake...
they will try again.
I just need to lay low
for a while.
Until I can figure out
what the hell's on this.
I heard you got your hands
on the security cam footage
from the Embarcadero mall.
Yeah, yeah, I'm going
through it right now.
Well, how the hell
did you pull that off?
'Cause I've been on the
phone for three hours
with four different judges,
and I couldn't even
get close to a warrant.
Yeager, sometimes you
have to know who to ask
and how to ask.
There was a very lovely,
nice young woman
working at
Embarcadero operations
who was more than happy
to give me a hand.
Well, I'm impressed.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Here she makes
the drop-off,
and then she just kind of
heads off through the crowd.
What's behind
the corner, there?
Look at the reflection.
Let's see if I can
get a taxi number.
I'm impressed again.
"T312X."
Call the company, see where
the cabbie dropped her off.
(knocking on door)
I can't believe it.
I'm sorry,
I-I had nowhere else to go.
All right, come on in.
Let's start at the beginning,
with, uh, the flash
drive and the woman
who gave it to you.
Like I told you, I'm working
on a story right now.
Uh, I have an inside man.
He's providing
me with information
on Project Jericho,
which is a domestic
spying program.
And he goes by
the name of Suvari.
So the woman was your contact?
I don't know who the woman is.
I've never met her before.
You see, in the past, Suvari
just arranged a dead drop.
He'd leave a flash drive
somewhere and I'd find it.
But not this time.
No, no.
This time I told him I actually
need to look him in the eye.
Before I publish my story,
I need to be assured
that the information
that he's providing
on Project Jericho is genuine.
Specifically, about the man
who's-who's running things.
Who's some Air Force general.
Robert Lansdale.
How did you...?
Oh, that's all
right, go on.
Right. Well, amongst
other things right now,
they're using drones
for domestic surveillance.
Question is:
who are they watching?
And who's watching the watchmen?
Precisely. Um...
I was told that the information
off this flash drive would make
Snowden's leaks look like
a minor blip on the radar.
I'm assuming that
the files are encrypted.
I had the decryption key
on my laptop.
That was in my car.
Which is where we come in.
Assuming that you
can crack it.
The safest place
for you right now
is to stay here.
First, we need
to find out what's
on this flash drive.
Then we can figure out
what our next move is.
Where are you going?
I'm gonna go
back to the lab.
The three of us
are the only people that know
that John's still alive.
Let-Let's keep it that way.
I'll call you when
I get something.
(thunder rumbling)
YEAGER: The cab company
said our mystery woman
was dropped off at the
Palermo last night at 11:15.
Hotel has her registered
under the name Emily Rey.
Security checked her room,
she wasn't there.
An hour ago, we get
a call out here-- 419.
She fits the description.
Super Dave, what's the word?
TOD's approximately
six hours ago.
And we got blunt force trauma
to the back of the head.
STOKES:
Yeah.
All this spatter,
cast-off, I'd be willing
to bet you she was hit
more than a couple
of times, yeah?
Definitely.
YEAGER: Hey, we got
more blood over here.
Gravitational drops...
could've come
off the weapon.
Nick...
(thunder rumbling)
STOKES: Oh, yeah.
Got a print and blood.
And a good one, at that.
Just sent the photo to the lab,
they're running
a check.
(phone chimes)
Just got a hit.
That was quick.
What the hell?
What's wrong?
Hey, Dave.
Yeah.
You say the time of death
was six hours ago, right?
That's right. Why?
Our killer's a dead man.
Greg...
I got something
I need you to do.
Well, I'm kind of
in the middle of something.
Well, this takes priority.
A flash drive?
(cell phone chimes)
Files on it are encrypted.
I need you to open
them up for me.
Oh, damn it.
Is everything all right?
Just-Just do it.
STOKES:
DB...
We got a problem. I need to talk
to you about that Merchiston
car wreck.
All right, come in,
come in.
Well, there's something
just not right about it.
(sighs)
Tell me what you know.
Yeager and I tracked down
the mystery woman, the one
that met Merchiston in the mall.
I'm pretty sure those two
hooked up again later.
Why do you say that?
'Cause she's dead.
Beaten to death with a crowbar,
and Merchiston's fingerprints
right there
on the murder weapon.
Now, she was killed
six hours ago.
His car crash was 36 hours ago.
I mean, you do the math.
Are you absolutely positive
about the fingerprint?
It's in the victim's blood.
Listen, Merchiston
is still alive,
and he's a stone-cold killer.
What's going on?
(phone buzzing, shower running)
(gasps)
(sighs)
You scared me.
That wasn't my intention.
John, I-I...
Something happened
since the last time
I saw you.
What?
I don't want to
talk about it.
Russell left me a message.
Really? What about?
I'm checking.
What's the matter?
Why are you looking
at me like that?
FBI! Drop the gun.
CSI Finlay,
gun on the floor.
Now!
Give me the gun, Julie.
We have to take you in.
Both of you.
(laptop blipping rapidly
as it downloads)
(blipping stops)
CSI Russell.
Special Agent
Sturgis, FBI.
I'm going to need to
read you your rights.
That's all right...
I think I know them.
CSI Russell.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Well, it's a long trip
from Nellis.
General Lansdale,
right?
No uniform--
I'm guessing this
conversation's
off the record.
John Merchiston...
man's a murderer.
But worse than that,
he's a threat to this country.
Can you prove either one
of those allegations?
FBI will.
At this moment,
they're securing
all the evidence
from your lab.
You need to know that my people
had no knowledge of this
whatsoever.
Does that include CSI Finlay?
Despite your
best efforts
to alert her, she and
Mr. Merchiston are in custody.
I know...
that you have a relationship
with John Merchiston.
Maybe you trust him--
but you shouldn't.
I'm not sure who I should be
trusting right now, General.
Well, you certainly
come by that honestly.
I know about
your parents.
About their activities
during the '60s.
But you, you...
you became a cop.
That says a lot about you,
about them.
Must feel sort of odd sitting
on that side of the table.
What do you want?
I want to know
what Merchiston told you
about a gentleman named Suvari.
He didn't tell
me anything.
I'm here as a courtesy,
Mr. Russell.
The FBI can continue
this conversation.
(clears throat softly)
What about my lab?
I don't think it'll look
very good for either
one of us, General,
if the wheels of justice
grind to a halt.
I'll give you
an opportunity
to make arrangements
with your team.
You're a lucky man.
You got a family,
good job,
so much to live for.
You should know
from personal experience
the cost of misplaced loyalty.
STURGIS:
We believe your friend
John Merchiston
has been receiving leaks
of classified information
vital to our
nation's security.
Leaks from
an inside source,
goes by the name Suvari.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Yeah?
Obviously, you
know one thing--
Merchiston faked
his own death.
When he realized
we were closing in on him,
he set up his assistant.
Murdered him.
Then he murdered this woman,
Emily Rey,
the only other person who could
connect him to this Suvari.
Looks like you got it
all figured out.
Why do you need me?
Well, maybe this Emily Rey
isn't the only connection
to Suvari.
Well, if that's the case,
why didn't John kill me?
I like to think
we saved your life.
Now it's your turn--
to help save the lives
of perhaps thousands, if these
security leaks
are allowed to go unchecked.
I don't buy it.
(scoffs)
That's... not the cooperative
attitude I was looking for.
I don't know if you're
protecting Merchiston
because you've fallen for him
or his politics,
or maybe he's just a great lay.
Honestly, I don't care.
Whatever pillow talk
you two shared,
you are gonna give it up.
At the risk of sounding
like your British boy toy...
we could go all night.
You know what, Agent?
Go screw yourself!
That's what you wanted
to say, right?
BRASS:
Finlay, I advise you
not to say another word.
You're here
as an observer, Captain.
This is my house;
these are my people.
And if you don't
start acting nice,
I'm gonna kick your FBI
ass right out of here.
Russell. Russell.
Hey, I got your message.
Looks like Finn
and I are gonna be here
for a little while.
Merchiston's being charged
with willful communication
of national defense
information.
And murder.
He's letting his lawyer
do the talking right now.
According to them,
we harbored
someone who stole secrets,
faked his own death,
and then murdered
two people.
Unless we can prove
that someone was setting
Merchiston up the whole time.
I mean, we have
his bloody fingerprint
on the murder weapon--
that makes for a pretty
good argument.
I know, but...
he once did a forensic field
training with Scotland Yard.
So he's not stupid enough
to leave his bloody
fingerprint behind.
Look, you're the
boss now, bud.
Get us out of here,
will you?
♪ ♪
FBI yanked all the files
on the Merchiston case,
but I still had a photo
of the bloody fingerprint
in my phone.
Check it out.
Tell me what you see
or what you don't see.
BRODY:
Ridge detail's all there.
But there are no pores.
How is that even possible?
We've seen this before,
haven't we, Greg?
The Millander case.
Mm-hmm.
A serial killer made
a mold of Grissom's
print in latex,
planted it at
a crime scene.
But unlike skin,
latex gives you
ridge detail but no pores.
Russell was right--
this whole thing's a setup,
from the Emily Rey murder
to the car crash-- all of it.
Sounds pretty sophisticated.
Do we think
the FBI's involved?
STOKES:
No... no, I think they're
just doing their job.
Well, then
who is it?
I don't know.
But I don't even know
where to start looking
now that they've walked off
with everything.
Maybe not everything.
Russell gave this to me
right after Merchiston
came back from the dead.
The guy's accused of stealing
classified information--
it might be on there.
It might also show
who's trying
to set Merchiston up.
Even help spring
Russell and Finn.
BRODY:
With all these eyes on us,
it's gonna be almost impossible
to do the job.
All eyes are on us,
but I can think
of somebody who
might be able to fly
under the radar.
Hey, Nick.
Hey.
This was left
at Reception.
What is it?
Nevada Wireless--
looks like a new phone.
I didn't order a phone.
(music playing in distance)
Hi.
I'll have a cup
of coffee, please.
Sure. What flavor?
Coffee-flavored.
BARISTA:
That'll be $1.35, sir.
Keep it.
Thank you.
You're Suvari?
I'm not, but...
he reached out to me,
(over radio):
said he could help my client
and your CSI friends.
Okay. Where is he?
I'm supposed to take you to him.
So, you, uh, decrypted the files
on the flash drive I gave you?
Files are classified
Department of Defense documents
relating to Project Jericho:
the use of drones
to listen in on
communications.
Now, this is all in
the development stages,
but definitely something DoD
would not want to go public.
All right,
but is it serious enough
that someone from the government
would be willing to stage
a fake car crash,
murder a woman, just to...
keep it a secret?
Just because
you're not paranoid
doesn't mean
they're not following you.
In this case, backseat driving.
What do you mean?
One of the files
references--
(footsteps approaching)
One of the files refers
to Wi-Fi technology,
which enables a user
to hack a car's onboard CPUs--
specifically, after-market
black boxes,
like the one that was installed
in Merchiston's
rental car.
So you're saying that
they've developed a software
that allows you
to take control of a car...
remotely.
And remotely crash it.
There's also references
to enhancing the effects
of the accident
with a thermite
cocktail-- ka-boom!
All right, well,
that still doesn't mean
that someone from the government
is behind all of this.
For all we know,
it could be this guy Suvari.
You're not gonna tell me
where we're going?
You want to meet
Suvari or don't you?
There's a rest stop
outside of Searchlight.
He said to wait
for him there.
(engine accelerating)
Hey, you mind slowing down?
I'd like to get there
in one piece.
It's not me--
my foot's off the pedal.
Turn off
the cruise control.
No, it's not on.
Try the brakes.
They're not working!
All right, all right, just-just
stay cool, we got this.
What the hell?!
(truck horn blaring)
(McDermott panting)
(engine roaring)
(engine roaring,
tires screeching)
(tires screeching)
(both panting)
What was that?
I don't know,
but I'm getting the feeling
we just took
the same kind of ride that...
that John's car took.
Wasn't that the... the
coffee guy from the mall?
Well...
either he just tried
to kill us, or he just saved us.
Either way, he left us this.
♪ ♪
(computer blipping)
(camera shutter clicking)
I told you the truth
would set us all free.
Like I told you...
we're on the same side.
Call 'em.
Hey.
(laughing):
Hey, welcome back.
Good to be back,
thank you very much.
We heard you and John's
attorney had a close call.
We did.
One that was
headed off
by your friend Suvari.
You actually met him?
So did you.
He served you coffee.
Okay, what have we got here?
Evidence-- proof of the attack
on Mr. Merchiston's life
using a tactic called
"Boston Brakes."
Boston Brakes?
So-called because that was
the first place it was used.
At least,
according to mythology.
And that's all
I thought it was
till I saw the files your
colleague Hodges decrypted.
Project Jericho
included a DoD program
that developed technology
to hack onboard
computers in cars,
and I think that
Suvari wants us to know
it's what happened to this
woman and her son, as well.
Cheryl Perez
worked for DoD
as a programmer
on Project Jericho.
Ms. Perez resigned amid rumors
of an affair
with a high-ranking officer.
General Lansdale?
Name never surfaced.
Yeah, but it makes sense.
Suvari told me
he was working
on a story that was going
to send the walls
of Project Jericho
tumbling down.
Clearly, he's suggesting
Lansdale's behind the murder
of this woman
to cover up the affair.
There's the chance
that the child found
in the back of the car
is his son.
FINLAY:
So now he's targeting anyone
who comes close
to the truth.
STURGIS:
Yes, I agree that's what
this all looks like, but there
are still missing pieces.
This Suvari is
a mystery man.
Coffee vendor said
he rented the stand
just a couple
of times, paid cash.
But we don't know
who he is or where he's from.
Without him, all we
really have are allegations
against a high-ranking
Air Force officer.
So we need to find this Suvari.
We're working on it.
We ran diagnostics
on this device.
Suvari definitely
used it to override
whoever was hacking the
car that we were in, but,
in trying to save us,
I think he left himself exposed.
He left behind
a cyber footprint.
Greg is working on
that ISP right now.
(engines revving)
You sure
you found the right place?
ISP traced here.
STOKES:
How? It's not on the grid.
You don't even get
cell phone service out here.
Well, maybe that's the point.
(muffled rock music playing)
STOKES:
Somebody's home.
(rock music blaring)
♪ ♪
STOKES (loudly over music):
Yeah.
Yeah, photos.
He's definitely been watching.
Bloody duffel bag.
Bloody gloves.
Emily Rey's wallet.
STOKES:
Yeah, yeah, that's him.
That's-that's Suvari,
or whoever he is.
(music stops, computer chirps)
"To whom it may concern..."
What is that, a suicide note?
Oh, it's more than that.
It's a confession...
to all the murders.
I don't buy it.
Oh, me, either.
This evidence, the note...
Somebody sure is giving us
the hard sell.
Sorry, General.
Guess it's my turn
to keep you waiting.
Well, I hope it's
for a good reason
'cause I'm a busy man.
Yes, you are.
You wanted information
on Suvari.
Well, we-we found him.
But then again,
I think you know that,
because you found him first,
didn't you?
His real name is Joseph Powers.
Former Army Intelligence.
More recently employed
by Ceressus Logistics.
He was a-a contractor assigned
to Project Jericho, wasn't he?
I don't recognize him.
But then again, I have a lot
of people working under me.
How about Cheryl Perez?
You recognize her?
I heard about her car accident.
Tragic.
Yes, it was.
We were all deeply saddened.
Especially,
evidentially, Joseph Powers.
I mean, he-he resigned
a week after the accident.
He just fell right off the grid,
until, of course,
he started reaching out
to John Merchiston.
You remember John, don't you?
Where's this going?
Did Cheryl Perez threaten
to go to your wife or your boss?
Or did she want money
to help support her child?
Your child?
A man with a good job
and a family has so much
to live for, right?
Or... kill for.
I would be very careful
about what you say.
Why? Am I about
to have a car accident?
See, I know what you've done.
You've used
the entire national security
apparatus,
all of their technology,
to cover up an affair.
You don't know what I've done.
And even if you did,
you wouldn't understand.
You're not a soldier, a patriot.
You are just another
child of the '60s
who cloaks himself in principle,
while our enemies plot
to bring chaos to our streets.
Well, I am not gonna
let that happen.
And I will stop anybody
who gets in my way.
You know, my-my hippie parents
might not have taught me a lot,
but they did teach me
about patience.
I may not be able
to prove anything today,
but you have involved way
too many people here, General.
And someday, there's gonna be
another Joseph Powers,
another person of conscience,
and when they step up,
oh, I'm going to be right there,
waiting patiently for you.
You're dismissed, General.
I thought your flight left
in the morning.
So did I.
The editor needs to
see me immediately.
Mm.
It's the truth.
I believe you.
Russell is not giving up on
Lansdale, and neither am I.
I'll be back.
Good to know.
Look, uh...
that thing that, uh,
you didn't want
to talk about--
should you ever
change your mind,
I'm an excellent listener.
Thank you.
I appreciate that.
Yeah.
Be safe.
Yeah. You, too.
Be well.