WOMAN:
Once upon a time, there was
a reindeer named Winston.
(bells jingling)
Winston was lost.
He wandered the city instead of
delivering toys in the frost.
(camera shutters clicking)
Did you get it?
(reindeer grunts)
Winston searched
every roof and chimney.
(women gasping)
Where, oh, where
could jolly Santa be?
(siren wails in distance)
Thank you.
(heavy sigh)
BRASS:
Happy holidays.
RUSSELL:
Not for Santa, I hear.
BRASS: There's gonna be
a lot of disappointed kids
this year.
RUSSELL:
Wow. Snow in Vegas.
Well, this White Christmas
is brought to you courtesy of
the Winter Wonderland Company--
the employee Jayson Walt,
he's over there.
Reindeer wrangler,
snowmaker,
jack-of-all-trades.
He comes to work this morning,
finds a dead Santa
and a missing reindeer.
They went all out.
Patrol found Dasher about
an hour ago on the Strip,
blood in his fur.
Animal Control
brought him here, and Jayson
Walt identified him as Dasher.
David Phillips has
the I.D. on the dead guy.
Good luck.
David,
got a name yet?
Lucky for us
the victim is not
a Secret Santa.
He's got business cards,
everything.
"Brad Fante--your friendly
neighborhood I.T. guy."
Works for Bonham Realty.
Must have been
the company Kringle.
Liver temp tells me
he died between
12:00 and 1:00 a.m.
And both
femoral arteries were severed.
So he bled out.
What are those,
bloody hoofprints?
Looks like it.
So the reindeer
sees Santa here die violently,
breaks out of the pen,
tracks through
the fresh blood.
And I thought
Rudolph had it bad.
There's blood
on the runner here.
He was definitely run over
by the sleigh.
Uh... Russell?
I got a lot of
blood at his back.
Could you help me
flip him?
(Phillips grunts)
(sighs heavily)
Five sharp-force injuries.
That's a lot of blood,
so he was still alive
when he was stabbed.
This is not an accident.
Grandma may have
gotten run over
by a reindeer,
but Santa got "sleighed."
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
SANDERS:
It's already 50 degrees,
the sun's still rising.
It's supposed to
get up to 70 today.
Say good-bye to the snow.
SANDERS:
Our main priority
is to record and preserve--
analyze everything
when we get back to the lab.
Are we good
for shoe impressions?
Good?
To collect them from the snow.
I'm guessing
you didn't
process many
cold scenes in L.A.
(laughs) Try none.
All right, well,
heat is usually the battle
here in Vegas,
but today it's snow.
Blood doesn't read
the same way,
the drops blend in,
no spines, and prints
don't lift easily.
Yeah, makes sense.
So we are going to need
liquid cold wax
to process any impressions,
and dry ice, too.
All right.
I'll call Hodges
and have him bring it on over.
Right this way.
Hi. I'm Ryan Bonham.
Sorry I kept you waiting.
I had to check
on my son Blake.
I, uh, just can't
believe all this.
No.
It's a hell of a thing.
Sorry, I'm gonna
have to ask you
a few questions here.
How well did you know
the victim, Mr. Fante?
I didn't know him that well--
I mean, he'd been
with my company for
a few months.
He was all psyched
to organize the Christmas party.
Get along with
the other employees?
Oh, yeah.
Brad worked miracles
with computers.
Everyone loved him.
He made a perfect Santa.
Is there anything you
can tell me about last night?
Not really, no.
I mean, you know, the
company had a great year,
everybody was partying,
they were happy.
And then around 9:00, I went
upstairs to put Blake to bed.
He's six now. Christmas is a
bit of a tough time for him.
Mm.
For me, too.
My, uh...
my wife died...
two years ago, Christmas Eve.
Sorry to hear that.
Yeah.
Uh, anyway, like I said,
I stayed with him,
I fell asleep,
the sirens woke me up,
and I looked out my window...
you know, I thought I'd seen
my share of Christmas tragedy
in my life, but...
I guess not.
You had a long night,
huh, Dash? Yeah.
Bet you're hungry, huh?
That's all right,
we're gonna get you some grub.
Yeah, we'll get you
some food.
Mr. Walt?
Yeah, that's me.
Hey. I'm, uh,
CSI Sanders.
I'm here to...
process your reindeer.
Process? You don't
mean put him down?
No, I...
just need to collect a sample
of blood from his fur.
Why?
Well,
he walked through
a crime scene,
and the blood could
be from our victim
or even from our killer.
Okay.
(grunting)
It's okay, boy.
It's just a little
cotton on a stick.
Good.
Do you always leave
your reindeer out at night?
Oh, yeah, yeah,
they like it.
Yeah, what with the snow?
Reminds them of Iceland.
Only place in the world
you can find real reindeer.
Yeah, they sleep
by the glaciers.
Hey, you think
Dasher saw who did it?
Um...
it's...
certainly possible.
You know, I saw
this thing on the news.
They're giving MRIs
to dogs now.
Their brains
are a lot like ours.
Old Dasher here,
he can't tell us what
he saw, but, you know,
maybe someday we'll know
what he's thinking.
All right, well, uh...
I think I got what
I need. Thanks.
Hey, Dash.
Good boy. That was good.
Yeah.
You got something?
HODGES:
Yeah, partial boot impression.
I checked it against
Santa's--it's not his.
Blood drop inside.
Got blood drops
over here as well.
Man, Greg was right.
You can't tell
directionality.
But they are close
to where the body was.
Could be gravitational.
Suggests...
this is the area
where it all happened.
Santa gets stabbed in the back,
grabs at his wounds,
trying to stop the bleeding,
but the blood is flowing.
Bumps into the sled,
dislodges it.
Sled slides downhill and...
And the elf kingdom weeps.
Time for our
trusty ice wax.
I had to use this
in the infamous
Mount Charleston Chalet Murder.
Death by ski pole.
Long story.
So, how does it
work exactly?
The wax preserves
the impression,
insulating the snow,
preventing any loss of detail
caused by heat
from the exothermic reaction
of the casting material.
And...
voilà-- frosty cast.
Nice. Um, what about
the blood drops?
You can take them to go.
All right.
Why do you think Santa
was hanging out here
all by his lonesome
after the party?
He was probably recovering
from the forced levity
of a hyper-commercialized
holiday
that's lost
all sense of wonder.
Wow.
Somebody got a lot of coal
in his stocking as a kid.
I wish.
Instead of regaling me
with stories of Santa,
my scientist father lectured me
on the implausibility
of the whole thing.
What, he didn't think
a fat man in a sleigh
could make it around the world
in one night?
He also had a problem
with the climate damage caused
by toy factories
in the North Pole.
God, I hope I don't have
you as my Secret Santa.
(chuckles)
I can't believe we're actually
doing it again this year.
Must be Bonham's kid.
I wonder if he saw anything.
BRODY: I don't think
anybody's talked to him yet.
Maybe we should take
a shot at it.
Aren't vaguely Dickensian
suburban kids
Russell's department?
(door opens)
Season's greetings,
Doctor.
Yeah?
How's it going in here?
Well, our friend
here, Mr. Fante,
is definitely on
someone's naughty list.
Looks like
you got Secret Santa'd.
You gonna open it?
Why don't you do
the honors for me, Nick.
All right.
(gasps)
Herbal tea.
Mmm.
I think you got Russell.
(both chuckle)
I think our victim got
more than a stab
in the back.
He's got a cut on the cheek,
and bruising.
Well, maybe
he was punched
before he was knifed.
Fiber in the wound.
STOKES: You know,
that almost looks synthetic.
Killer could have
been wearing gloves.
The stabbing was
particularly vicious.
The killer twisted
the blade.
Well, that's the personal touch
right there.
Okay.
Christmas party,
bunch of booze flowing.
Two guys just got in a fight.
I know we got to wait
on tox, but...
did you find any alcohol
in his stomach?
Nope, just milk
and cookies.
Mr. Claus was a teetotaler.
Okay, there goes
the drunken-brawl theory.
But one thing is for sure.
Jolly St. Nick here
must have pissed somebody off.
WOMAN:
"Winston looked east,
"and he looked west.
"He saw a light in the distance,
"maybe a place to rest.
Winston..."
(phone ringing)
Whoops. Then Mommy got
a call from Daddy,
and she had
to put the book down.
(laughs)
Phone.
(beep)
Is that your mom?
Uh-huh.
She didn't get
to the end of the story.
Yeah.
The Lost Reindeer.
You must watch
that a lot.
Did you watch it with
your daddy last night?
Yeah. He fell asleep.
He was tired.
Well, after your dad went to
sleep, did you happen to see
or hear anything outside?
I saw the Christmas tree lights
go off downtown.
Well, you know, you got
to stay up pretty late.
Do you think maybe you
happened to see anything else?
I saw a reindeer.
I did, too,
right outside there.
It's pretty awesome, right?
Not that reindeer.
The one in the house.
You saw a reindeer
in the house?
On the staircase.
It had its head down,
pawing at the floor,
so I got scared
and shut my door.
I think, young man,
what you were experiencing
was a dream, REM sleep.
During REM sleep,
a pretty awesome
brain chemical called
acetylcholine becomes active,
subduing other
neurotransmitters.
Now, this excess acetylcholine
is what makes you dream.
So, nothing you saw was real.
Is Santa real?
Yes. Yes.
Santa is very real.
(laughs)
♪ ♪
So, what is the
snow report?
Uh, DNA from the blood drops
in the snow are all a match
to our victim, Brad Fante.
And as far as that partial
boot print goes,
it's from a Timberland,
size unknown.
We got a list of all
of the shoes worn
by the 22 guests
who were in attendance
at the party.
No match to any of them.
Nor the home owner, Ryan.
Nor our reindeer wrangler.
So, I guess snow's
a white-out.
Snow far.
I've been letting it melt
so I could strain the water
for more trace.
Oh.
I don't think I'll need
a strainer for that.
Must have been buried
underneath the snow.
Hmm. That looks
biological.
Maybe part
of the victim's intestine?
Possibly.
I'll run it and find out.
Hey, David, uh...
(clears throat)
It's a good look for you.
The antlers are all
business, my friend.
Fiber found in our victim,
Brad Fante's, cheek wound.
Made from specific
modacrylic
polymers and dye.
Used in fake
fur and... this.
Reindeer costume.
Purchased at a local
costume store, complete
with furry hoof gloves.
Now, I'm thinking that some
time before he got knifed,
our Santa took
a left hoof
at the party
from a pantomime reindeer.
You're kidding me.
If the reindeer glove fits,
you need not acquit.
Could also explain
what little Blake Bonham saw
at the bottom of the stairs.
And maybe our party animal
left something behind.
♪ ♪
BRODY:
Hodges' theory that it was
someone in a reindeer costume
at Ryan Bonham's party was
correct, except for one detail.
Ah. It was a woman.
Looking for her
contact lens.
I found it on the staircase,
traced the I.D. number.
RUSSELL:
Rachel Walker, 23.
No record.
This woman worked
at Bonham Realty?
No. Actually,
she worked at another
fine Vegas establishment--
the Cathedral Strip Club.
Featured dancer.
Miss Reindeer.
Well, that's quite an honor.
According to her
bio, she beat out
seven other strippers
for the rack.
Antlers. Crown.
I got it. You know,
I didn't get the sense that
Ryan Bonham's Christmas party
was that kind of party, so,
why did he have Miss Reindeer
at his house?
Well, apparently, Mr. Bonham
didn't know anything about it.
I spoke to the strip club.
It was Brad Fante
who hired the girl
and asked her to
come late at night
"after all the children were
nestled snug in their beds."
So, what
are you thinking?
That after the dancing stopped,
Santa got a little out of hand?
Yeah, and Miss Reindeer
here decided
she didn't want to play anymore
of his reindeer games.
♪ Chestnuts roasting
on an open fire... ♪
(gasping)
♪ Jack Frost nipping... ♪
(snorts)
♪ At your nose ♪
♪ Yuletide carols ♪
♪ Being sung by a choir ♪
♪ And folks dressed up ♪
♪ like Eskimos... ♪
I get it, but,
enough, all right?
Let's get to
the good part.
You asked what happened.
I'm telling you.
I was doing my number,
doing my thing
for Fante and his buddy.
I was okay
with the home movies.
I was not okay
with the free porno.
What do you think
you're doing?
Come on, vixen.
Santa screwing
one of his reindeer?
It'll be the
greatest sex tape of all time!
Are you getting this, Fred?!
No! No!
(grunts)
Get off of me!
Yeah, but a reindeer
punching Santa?
That's just wrong.
He had it coming.
I'm no saint,
but I'm not a whore.
But you could
be a killer.
Look, Rachel,
I get it, I get it.
You're both professional
pole dancers.
You work the stripper pole,
he works the North Pole.
So, he paid for a lap dance,
and then he wanted
to take you to the North Pole,
show you the workshop for free.
And he wouldn't take
"no" for an answer,
so you got in a
little tussle,
you had to defend
yourself--I get it.
Oh!
I'm telling you,
I didn't kill him.
Guy wasn't worth it.
After I hit him,
I went upstairs,
I changed my clothes,
and I got out of there.
Rachel, we have tape of you
slugging Father Christmas!
I know. Fred Larkin.
He recorded the whole thing.
Go ahead, talk to him.
He's the one
that gave me a ride home,
bought me breakfast at R.J.'s.
Fante was alive when we left.
So I go the security cam
footage back from R.J.'s diner.
It confirms Rachel Walker
and Fred Larkin's story.
Doc said T.O.D.
on Brad Fante
was between midnight
and 1:00 a.m.
So, they definitely
have alibis,
according to
the time stamp.
So, where does
that leave us?
With no suspect
and a lot of work to do.
Yeah. New bracelet?
That is very observant of you.
Well, it's why they
pay me the big bucks.
Come on. You're dying
for me to say,
"Thank you.
That was so generous."
I don't know
what you're talking about.
Yes, you do.
No, I don't.
Okay, well,
I'm your Secret Santa.
And I was planning
on matching your generosity
with something
that I think you would
really like.
Well, I hate
to break your heart,
but I'm not your Secret Santa.
Really?
Really.
Well, that's unfortunate.
Very unfortunate for you.
Ah. I hate Christmas.
Hey. Finn said you
found some mystery tissue
in one of the snow samples
I took from the scene.
Not a mystery anymore.
Is it from our victim?
No. In fact,
it's not even human.
Sarda Chiliensis Lineolata.
Otherwise known as
Pacific Bonito.
Bonito?
Well, they use it in sushi.
Did they serve that
at the party?
Well, if so, it's not the only
thing that they were serving.
I ran tox on the fish guts.
Found traces of cocaine.
We know Brad Fante organized
the office party.
He went off-script
hiring Miss Reindeer.
Who knows what else
he had planned for the night.
We know he ordered bonito
with a side of coke.
We know that he tried
to stiff the stripper,
in more ways than one.
Well, if he was cheap
with the stripper,
maybe he stiffed
his dealer, too.
Then got stiffed.
STOKES: This is Brad Fante's
little helper, Fred Larkin.
Not only did he
film the stripper
doing her reindeer
dance, he also
taped most of the party.
So, I've been going
through it, hoping
I'd see the killer getting into
some kind of beef with Santa.
What did you find?
Oh, typical
Christmas party stuff.
A quiet guy singing,
unlikely couple hooking up,
office joker crying
in his beer.
Anything unexpected?
Yeah. I found two Santas.
Take a look at this.
Here's the first thing
I noticed.
Santa pounding a glass of wine.
It's a party. So what?
Well, according to the doc,
he didn't drink alcohol.
Stomach contents were
just milk and cookies.
So, take a look at this.
This is 20 minutes later.
There's our wine-drinking Santa,
and it looks like
he gets a phone call.
Now, it must have been pretty
important, because I think
that's when he
ditched the party
and lent his suit
to Brad Fante,
who, as we know, had his own
plans for what to do with that.
And how do we know
it's the same suit?
Look right here.
The sleeve.
See the stain?
45 minutes later.
Same suit, different watches,
different beverages...
...different Santas.
Well, it's easy for us
to tell them apart,
because we have this
video, we have forensics, but...
what if the killer couldn't?
Well, we've run out of suspects
with motives to kill the guy.
Maybe Brad Fante
was not the target.
No. No, the target...
was this other Santa.
So, who is he?
At Winter Wonderland, we'll
create a winter wonderland
you'll never forget.
We're your first and last stop
for all your holiday needs.
Hey! We'll even supply you
with real snow,
a live reindeer
and all the trimmings.
Including old St. Nick,
himself--ho, ho, ho!
So, come on down
to Winter Wonderland.
And tell 'em Jayson sent you.
So, our reindeer wrangler
neglected to tell us
that "Santa" was
part of the Winter
Wonderland package.
According to Greg,
he passed himself off
as just an employee.
Looks like he owns the company.
That still doesn't tell us
why someone tried
to kill him, though.
I might be able
to help with that.
What do you got?
Well, you know
the cocaine-laced bonito
we found in the snow
at Ryan Bonham's yard?
Well, it turns out that
bonito wasn't
served at the party.
So how'd it
get there?
It was already in the ice.
How does that work?
Well, I ran the
truck manifest.
When it's not working
holiday parties,
it makes a lot of trips
from Mexico to Vegas,
transporting
Pacific Bonito--
on ice.
Bonito stuffed with cocaine.
Which is how remnants
of bonito and coke
got mixed in with ice.
The same ice used
to make the snow.
Jayson Walt thought
he was providing
a little snow for Christmas.
What he
didn't realize
is that he was adding
a little powder to the powder.
Well, that gives us motive
for someone to try to kill him.
Guy's a major
drug runner.
Could've been working
with cartels in Mexico.
That's one Bad Santa.
That's one dead Santa,
if we don't bring him in
before the killer finds him.
Thanks for coming in, Mr. Walt.
I know it's a busy time
of year for you.
LVPD interested
in a White Christmas party?
No.
I'm interested in a dead Santa
that was found
in Ryan Bonham's lawn.
Now, up to 9:33, you
were the guy in the
red suit playing Santa.
You didn't tell us that.
Nobody asked.
Look, pal,
whoever killed the guy
in the suit was after you.
No way. Why would
anyone want to kill me?
I don't know, maybe
'cause you're running drugs
from Mexico in your ice truck.
Yeah, we found
fish guts laced
with cocaine
on Ryan Bonham's lawn.
Okay, look.
This is the part
of the interview where
you help us help you.
Oh, yeah. How's that?
Well, in your
line of business--
and I'm not talking about
spreading holiday cheer
by putting fake snow on
lawns--I'm talking about
the other kind of cheer
with the other kind of snow.
Now, obviously,
you've made enemies.
You tell us who they
are, we'll help you
broker a deal with the DEA.
And what if I don't
want to you help me?
Well, then it's a
quick trip upstate.
And the inmates
up there have
absolutely no
goodwill toward men.
Yeah, I think
I'll take my chances.
I'm trying to
save your life.
Yeah, or maybe you're
trying to work an angle.
Wouldn't be
the first party
to have sushi
and coke delivered.
Plus, I don't buy
that you got evidence
that I'm the delivery boy.
So, if we're
through here,
I'm late for my next Santa gig.
Sit down,
Kringle.
Sit back down!
We have evidence.
We have your snow.
We have your product.
Someone's gonna
read you your rights.
You're under arrest.
Process him.
Nail polish?
"For your mistletoes."
It's cute.
I like.
Total chick gift.
I bet Finn's your Secret Santa.
Maybe.
Or maybe it's you,
trying to cleverly trick me.
Well, I guess we'll just have
to wait for the office party,
and all will be revealed.
In the meantime...
Check this out, I just got
Jayson Walt's phone records.
For the last week,
he has been in touch with
someone at Ely prison.
What, making reservations?
No.
Texting and talking
with his convict
older brother, Gary Lee Walt.
What's Gary in for?
Drug trafficking.
So maybe the little brother
is holding the family business
together while
big brother's inside.
That's what I thought,
until I looked at Gary
Lee's trial transcript.
Last year, Jayson Walt
turned state's evidence
and testified against
his own brother.
Well, he was probably just
trying to save his own ass.
And his own piece
of the drug trafficking pie.
So, why do you think
they're talking now?
Gary Lee just
won an appeal.
He has a hearing
scheduled.
How much you want to bet older
brother's gonna try and convince
younger brother
to change his story?
Yeah.
With a little
cash incentive.
Take a look at this
last communication.
"Jayson: Make it 200."
"Gary Lee: Can't."
"Jayson: No deal, bro."
Brotherly love.
Two days after this exchange,
Brad Fante was
knifed in the back,
just after Jayson loaned
him his Santa suit.
So, big brother
tries to cut a Kringle...
and misses.
I think it's time
for us to make a trip to Ely.
Well, we don't even
have to go that far.
Gary Lee was just admitted
to Desert Palm Hospital.
Kidney failure.
NICK:
Mr. Walt.
I'm CSI Stokes.
With the LVPD.
I'm here to ask
you a few questions
about your brother, Jayson.
What about him?
Well, it seems
like somebody's
trying to kill him.
It's not surprising.
My little brother has
a way of pissing people off.
Like you.
Seems like you'd get
pissed off
pretty easily.
Course, I wouldn't
blame you, after what
he did to you last year--
turning his back
on you like that.
Jayson was just
a scared little kid.
Lied.
He's gonna come clean now.
Really? I don't know, it
doesn't seem like you two
kiss and make
up that easy.
What tells you that?
Pictures.
I think your hit man
made a mistake.
That's supposed to be
your brother, isn't it?
I think you're the one
who's making the mistake.
'Cause Jayson is
the last person in the world
I would want to kill.
Because he's gonna deliver
the greatest
Christmas present ever.
He's gonna give me
my life back.
In court and right here,
in the hospital.
'Cause, you see, we've got
perfect matching
leukocyte antigens.
Jayson's gonna be
your kidney donor.
Real proud of my little bro.
He's stepping up. Family.
Yeah, family.
You know, I've read your texts.
I know you two were
haggling over money, and I
know you were paying him.
Well...we all need
a little incentive.
Yeah, but he wasn't happy with
what you were offering.
And now,
unfortunately for you,
I don't think he's
gonna be available.
Sorry.
News flash.
Jayson and I
arrived at a number.
And we came
to an understanding.
Including a little advance.
For his bail.
His bail.
That's right.
He's getting out just about now.
Tomorrow he'll be in here
saving my sorry ass.
Week after that,
he'll be recanting.
Then I'm going to have
the merriest Christmas
Vegas has ever seen.
Ho, ho, ho.
RUSSELL:
So the guy we thought
had the best motive
for killing Jayson Walt
is actually the guy
who has the least desire
to see any harm come to him.
Yeah, without
his brother's kidney,
Gary Lee's a dead man.
What are you thinking?
You got anything?
The autopsy.
It shows us that the killer
stabbed the victim
and then twisted that knife.
Right. We thought
it was personal.
Okay,
what if it was
more than just personal?
I mean, given
the fact that
Gary Lee needs a
kidney so desperately,
what if their total destruction
was the killer's intent?
You know
what I mean?
You destroy
Jayson Walt's kidneys,
you're in effect
killing Gary Lee Walt.
Murder by proxy.
So our question is
who wants Gary Lee Walt dead?
I give you Gary Lee Walt's
greatest hits.
Allegedly.
These are all
drug related kills
that he is suspected
of ordering.
SANDERS:
Mala Noche's...
Mad-10's... Aquila Cartel.
Anyone of
them could've
ordered the hit.
Yeah, that's what I thought.
Until I came to
this crime scene.
Ryan Bonham's wife, Eva.
He told us that she died two
years ago on Christmas Eve.
This is how.
Eva Bonham worked
at a Savings &amp; Loan.
FINLAY:
Yes. Gary Lee Walt
was laundering
his drug money at that bank.
An executive found out,
was about to go to the police.
But Gary Lee Walt
got to him first.
Eva Bonham was
working late that night
and became collateral damage.
SANDERS:
Leaving behind a husband
to care for their
little boy alone.
So Ryan Bonham has been
in touch with the DA all along.
He knew about the appeal.
He also knew that
it had to be rescheduled
because of Gary Lee Walt's
surgery.
And he must have
known that Jayson Walt
was going to give his
brother his kidney.
And he couldn't stand to
see Gary Lee Walt saved.
Can't say I blame him.
So Ryan hires Jayson Walt
to work his party.
He wants to get him alone,
on his turf...
(grunting)
...except it's the wrong Santa.
Brad.
Ryan....?!
(screaming)
FINLAY:
Ryan panics.
Can't believe
what he's done.
Goes inside and gets
rid of the evidence.
He runs back upstairs
to be with his kid,
wishing he could
will it all away.
Me too.
'Cause now that kid's
going to lose
both his parents.
(sirens wailing)
(tires screech, sirens stop)
Las Vegas Police!
Ryan Bonham!
Go, go, go.
(distant thumping)
Whew...
Blake.
It's okay.
You're safe, son.
I'm a policeman.
Some men came.
They took my daddy.
STOKES:
I heard Ryan Bonham's missing.
What the hell happened to him?
Yeah, some guys broke in.
They trashed the place.
I had a bad feeling.
When the fake Santa, Jayson
Walt, made bail, he disappeared.
Bet he figured out
Ryan tried to kill him?
That's a safe bet.
And what
about the kid,
Blake?
Well, you know, he's okay.
He's a little shaken up.
Yeah? Did he see anything?
I don't know.
He'll only talk to one person.
Who?
Me?!
(scoffs)
Last time I saw him,
I scared him.
He said he wanted
to talk to--
and I quote--
"the funny science man."
A compliment, I suppose, but...
you got to help me out here.
Just relax. Engage him. Here.
Give him this.
Chocolate.
Get him talking.
I'm sure he saw something.
This is a bad idea.
I'm gonna screw this up.
Just, you know,
give it your best shot.
(sighs)
Hey... little man.
Hi.
Sorry. I'm allergic.
Yeah. Me, too.
I like your watch.
I used to have one
just like it.
It's purple.
Good color.
And the diode display.
Groundbreaking technology
for its day.
Not that you...
You're a science man,
right?
You know big words.
Sure. I-I know
some big words.
Did the people with your daddy
use big words?
Uh-huh. "Condestorb."
"Condestorb"?
When they were going,
one man yelled
at the other man.
He was mad because he hadn't
gotten his condestorb fixed.
Do you mean "condenser"?
Yeah! What is that?
It's a machine
that helps freeze things.
Did you see the truck
the men came in, Blake?
Yeah, when they drove up.
When my dad told me to hide.
And was it the same truck that
was at the party at your house?
Uh-huh.
Will my daddy be okay?
As long as he knows
what a great,
smart son he has,
he's gonna be just fine.
He's a very lucky daddy.
Thanks.
Traffic cam
caught Jayson Walt's
ice truck turning off
I-15 onto 215 East
one hour ago.
I'm guessing
that Ryan Bonham is
in the back, on ice, and
they're taking him out of town.
Yeah, but I don't get it.
Why didn't they just
kill him at the house?
Maybe Ryan has something
they want.
So, where do you think
they're going?
My guess is someplace isolated,
where they feel safe...
so they can rough him up.
Maybe...
where they make
their ice.
Why do you say that?
Because when I analyzed
the melted snow,
there was no chlorine
in the water.
And all of Las Vegas'
tap water adds chlorine.
If I test the diatoms
in the melted snow,
I might be able to...
pinpoint the water source.
Give us a location.
♪ ♪
Hey.
So, that party snow came
from a small lake
near Henderson.
So that's
where the truck's going.
Yeah, I ran property records
in Henderson.
Turns out the Walt brothers
have had a warehouse there
since the early '90s.
Good work, Greg.
Well, I hope
it's not too late.
JAYSON:
Where's the box of bank records?
(grunting)
Stop it.
Please stop! Stop.
I'll show you where it is.
No, you're gonna tell me
where to find it!
I can't tell you
Hold it, hold it, hold it.
Hey, hey!
You a lefty or
a righty, Ryan?
No. Wait.
Aw, it doesn't
matter anyway. Go on.
Power it up!
You know,
cops said someone
was trying to kill me--
Santa stabbed in the back
at your house.
Pretty easy to figure out!
You know, the thing about
this ice chipper, see,
you're lucky if it
only takes an arm.
Lot of times, once you get
something in there,
no turning back, Ryan!
Hey! You listening
to me? Huh?
Last chance, Ryan!
I'm tired of waiting.
All right, if that's
how you want it!
No...!
Las Vegas Police!
Put down your weapons!
Back off or I put a bullet
in his head!
Put the gun down, Jayson.
I will do it!
Well, so will I.
I'll bust a cap
right in your kidneys.
I'll kill you
and your brother.
Put the gun down.
Shoot him!
They killed my wife!
Do it!
Put the gun down, Jayson.
(gun clatters)
(groans)
You should've killed him.
Ryan Bonham,
you're under arrest.
Get him out of here.
He made a full confession.
He admitted to killing
Brad Fante by mistake.
He's lucky Jayson Walt
didn't kill him.
He saw them coming.
He told his kid to hide.
Then when they busted in, he
somehow convinced Jayson Walt
that his wife had bank records
that would incriminate both him
and his brother.
There were no records.
Buying time.
Till we could find his kid.
Well...
losing your wife like that...
Anyway...
Oh, there's been a little mix-up
in Jayson Walt's custody.
A Henderson, Nevada,
sheriff showed up--
he's a friend--
and I handed Jayson Walt
over to him.
The weird thing is that his
wristband number got transposed.
He got on the wrong bus.
Where is he now?
He's shuffling off to Buffalo.
Unbelievable, isn't it?
The red tape.
Could take months for him
to get back to Las Vegas.
Well, I guess he won't be
giving his brother
his kidney tomorrow, will he?
It's tragic, isn't it?
So, there are some people
who will be here soon,
very nice people,
and, um, they're going to take
you to see your grandparents,
okay?
Okay.
You know, Blake, um,
this thing with you father,
I'm sure it's hard for
you to understand.
He misses my mom.
I'm sure he does.
I do, too.
(sighs)
Have you ever read
The Lost Reindeer?
I've only heard the first part.
I always wondered what happened
to that reindeer.
We can skip to the end.
"Winston turned the corner
and what did he see?
"A hundred reindeer
"just as lost as he.
♪ ♪
"They laughed
"and sang
until night faded away.
"As long
as they had each other,
"every moment
was Christmas Day.
The end."
♪ ♪