(TV playing, man speaking
indistinctly)
(motorcycle revs in distance,
phone line rings)
WOMAN: 911 operator.
What's your emergency?
(siren wails)
MAN:
I'm at the Sky View Motel.
I was making a delivery.
You have to send someone.
I think they're dead.
I don't know for sure, but...
Slow down, sir.
You need to tell me
what happened.
Are there people injured?
MAN: There's blood.
There's blood everywhere.
(siren chirps)
(sighs wearily)
Well, it's a messy one.
If you don't believe me,
ask the pizza
delivery guy there.
STOKES:
Yeah, is he the one
who called it in?
Yeah, he was
delivering pizzas
to, uh, one of
the rooms nearby.
The door to 114 was ajar,
so he looked in.
What do we have?
Two victims.
Mr. and Mrs. Smith.
Oh, that's original.
Anybody know
who they really are?
No.
And I don't know what
they did to deserve this.
PHILLIPS:
...63... 64... 65...
66, 67...
68... 69... 70...
71, 72...
STOKES:
Talk to me, David.
I'm trying to determine
the number of stab wounds.
But, frankly, there are
just too many to count.
FINLAY:
This is disturbing.
STOKES:
Hey, wait a minute.
You know something?
I've been here.
Yeah, we had that OD out
on the street a while back.
Yeah, yeah,
in the motel, but I mean,
in this room--this exact one.
I-I've been here.
Room 114.
I remember the view of the neon
from that window.
This is it.
You're right.
We have been here before.
Yeah, it was
a dismemberment murder;
victim was in his 20s.
It was about, uh,
two months ago.
No, I think it was more recent.
It was another couple,
but the woman was bludgeoned...
in her sleep.
I am pretty sure
it was the dismemberment.
I'm sorry,
but-but you're both right.
I've been here twice before,
once for the dismemberment
and again for the couple.
And now this.
Anybody else getting a really
bad feeling about this place?
Yeah... yeah, this the world's
most unlucky motel room.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
(indistinct radio communication,
siren wailing in distance)
All right,
that's three murder scenes
all in the same spot.
They got to be related,
don't you think?
Maybe there's a connection
between the victims
or the killer has
a weird fixation of some kind.
I don't think I'm ready to talk
about past crimes yet.
Have to focus on
this one first.
Yeah, I hear you.
I'll take the bathroom.
(man yelling, blade slicing)
(woman screams)
(woman screaming)
BRASS: So, how long have
you been manager here?
Uh, since about the time
I learned to walk.
My parents built this place,
so... I grew up here.
Oh!
Yeah.
All mine now.
Do you have any idea
who might've done this?
Isn't that your business
to figure that out?
I mean, I know we're
not the Bellagio, but...
if I have to drop
the rates any lower,
I might as well just
board the place up.
Yeah. So, you got about, what,
uh, 20 rooms here?
Tell me about the people
who stay in them.
It's like the sign says.
I mean, by the night,
by the week and by the month.
I'm gonna need a list of names.
Well, that could be a problem.
Not that I wouldn't
give it, it's just...
I don't have it.
Come on, man.
The place is 39 bucks a night.
If people have cash,
what do I care
about their names?
Look, none of 'em are
killers, though-- trust me.
How do you know that?
Well, there's no one here
that interesting.
(liquid sloshing)
Hey, Finn!
Looks like the Smiths had
a guest last night.
The towels are damp, and I found
a red hair in the shower drain.
Hmm, that doesn't match either
of our victims.
And there were three
toothbrushes around the sink.
Uh, I found
a receipt for one.
It's from the drugstore around
the corner--last night.
So a guest they didn't plan on.
There's more.
They also bought shampoo
and a pair of scissors,
which have since disappeared.
Could be the murder weapon.
So there was someone in here
before the killing started.
Yeah, who showered
and-- I don't know-- judging
from the toothbrush,
might've been planning
on staying the night.
So what went wrong?
I've been doing this
long enough that nothing
shocks me,
but if a case could...
Just the sheer savagery
involved.
More than a hundred stab wounds
in each victim.
Certainly beyond
what was necessary...
if the goal was
to simply kill them.
Can I see that?
It's, uh, way beyond
what we sometimes see
with crimes of passion
or extreme anger.
This was madness.
RUSSELL: Their names
really were Smith.
ROBBINS:
Richard and Ann.
According to family,
they were in from Flagstaff
for an antique toy
and collectibles convention.
That would explain
the dolls in the room.
Sounds like they were
solid people.
She volunteered, ran pet therapy
at an old folks home.
He worked with the homeless.
Squeaky clean.
Course, that wouldn't be
the first time the...
squeaky-clean have indulged
their dark side here in Vegas.
They could've invited
somebody back to the room,
spice up their life
a little bit.
If so...
certainly got more
than they bargained for.
Hey. So, I... pulled the files
for the other two
motel murder scenes.
It's weird, don't you think?
That a killer would fixate
on one room?
What do you think
the significance is?
Why does he feel
the need to kill there?
Well, that's assuming
that these are all the work
of one killer.
It could be
that there's no connection.
That you're looking for patterns
where there are none.
So it's a coincidence that three
totally unrelated killers
chose this one room?
I'm just saying,
we don't know yet.
All right,
first one: Mark Bell.
11 weeks ago,
he stayed
in Room 114 after his girlfriend
kicked him out.
Yeah, I remember.
I worked this case with Finn.
The maid found him tied
to the bed,
severe lacerations to his legs.
They were nearly cut off.
He bled to death.
There was a bloody knife
found on the floor.
Too smeared to yield
any viable prints.
Detectives, at the time,
thought the attack was related
to a drug debt.
(screaming)
They thought the dealer
was sending a message.
Four weeks ago...
second attack
in the room.
Alex and Tina Garnez.
Nick and I
handled this one.
Their house
had been foreclosed on.
They were living in their car
for months.
Mr. Garnez finally got a job.
Moving to the motel was
supposed to be a step up.
That night, he was sneaking
a cigarette in the bathroom
while his wife slept.
The killer started
with his wife...
...clubbing her
while she was sleeping.
Then he must've surprised
Mr. Garnez in the bathroom...
No!
Overpowered him.
He survived.
He's still in the hospital
recovering.
And then last night...
the Smiths.
(sighs)
Still think we're...
dealing with random,
unrelated events?
STOKES:
All right, Finn,
I'll see you back at the lab.
(helicopter hovering)
Come on now. Open up.
I saw you in there.
Hey.
I was asleep last night.
I was not involved.
I already told the cops.
Oh, yeah, yeah. That's cool.
I'm not, uh...
I'm not here to grill you.
(chuckles)
Kind of looks like you like
to call this place home.
I'm guessing you see everything
that goes on in here.
You... didn't see
anything weird?
Anybody suspicious
running around here lately?
It's not my place to judge
another man in that way.
Only God can judge.
Right... well,
God would want you
to help me catch a
killer, wouldn't he?
I'm sorry.
Now, sir, please, please,
hey, come on, now.
A couple was violently
murdered last night.
A woman a few weeks ago.
A young man before that.
All in the same room,
all innocent victims.
Innocent? There's no one
on this planet who's innocent.
We're all sinners.
Yeah, yeah, well, that-that
doesn't really
help me do my job.
They were called to God.
That's God's plan.
Your job is done.
Yeah, I just...
Might be my biggest
regret about this job--
I know way too much
about hotel bedspreads.
And hotel carpets.
Don't go barefoot.
So, we have
three different bedspreads
from our...
three different
crime scenes.
I ran the DNA.
The bedspread
on the left is
from the very first
murder scene.
I'm guessing
it lived in that room
for who knows how long.
Long enough that I
was able to identify
26 individual
DNA profiles.
Whoa.
Yeah. The replacement
bedspread there was
only in the room
for seven weeks.
So fewer contributions.
16 of them.
And the third bedspread,
from last night's crime scene.
Yielded only
nine contributors.
But here's the thing:
One of them, a male,
is common
to all three bedspreads.
One person,
the same person was in the room
before each of the murders?
Have you run the samples
through CODIS?
It's running
right now.
Here we go.
Randall Wicks, 22.
He must have
just been added
to the system.
There's why-- sexual battery
charge two weeks ago.
Look where he was arrested.
That same motel.
The same room!
I'll call Brass,
get out a broadcast.
Oh, how the mighty have
fallen, huh, Randall?
You used to be
the featured dancer
in the Tangiers
All Male Review.
How'd you let that
gig slip away?
I don't know.
I got bored, so I quit.
Well, or maybe you
found something more
interesting to do, huh?
Oh, hey, man, what the hell?
SANDERS: Three
separate murders
in the same room at
the Sky View Motel.
Your DNA was found in the room
after each of the crimes.
What? Wait a minute--
Sky View Motel?
Was that in room 114?
I use that room,
frequently.
For business.
So... you're
a prostitute?
Dude, I'm a stud,
letting frustrated housewives
get a taste of something
they wouldn't even get
close to otherwise.
Okay, stud, what
about the housewife
you beat up in room 114?
The sexual
battery charge.
Or was that just part of
the pony ride experience?
That was self-defense.
I'm serious.
I was in fear for my life.
Okay...
I meet this woman there, right?
Totally normal at first.
Then we start
getting into it, and...
I don't know,
she goes all crazy.
Starts hallucinating
or something,
screaming at the walls.
Pure freak show.
SANDERS:
And why?
What would make
her do that?
Well, I ain't a doctor
or nothing, but...
must be the sex
just blew her mind.
Yeah, that must
have been it.
(sighs): Well...
aside from being
a complete tool,
what do you think?
Well, he still
could be our killer.
Well, the problem is,
all we have is DNA evidence,
and we can't disprove his story
of how it got in that room.
Well, we do have an eyewitness
who could possibly I.D. Randall.
Alex Garnez, the husband
who survived his wife
being bludgeoned
four weeks ago.
He has massive head injuries.
He's still in the hospital--
we don't even know what
condition he's in.
Well, I talked to his doctor.
She said he's struggling
psychologically.
They have him on suicide watch
after one failed attempt,
but... physically...
she said he's strong
enough to talk to us.
Mr. Garnez.
Um...
I'm CSI Brody,
and this is
CSI Sanders.
I'm sorry,
but we need to talk to you
about the night that
you and your wife were attacked.
How much do you remember?
(panting)
I don't know.
I... I...
I remember her just lying there,
just lying there.
And all the...
blood around her...
We were high school sweethearts.
Did you see the person
who hurt you and your wife?
Do you remember his face?
(woman's faint, distorted cries)
I can see him...
standing over her,
hitting her over...
and over...
and...
and I'm powerless.
I... I can't stop him.
Like there's a wall
between us. I...
Yet I can still hear the
sickening sound of...
blow...
after blow.
Mr. Garnez...
we want to... we want
to show you some photographs
of some faces.
We need you to tell us
if any one of these men
looks like the man that
we've been talking about, okay?
He's not there.
Are you sure?
None of these...
is the man that
killed my Tina.
Hodges, you texted me "911"?
I did.
What is the 911?
Sorry. Your suspect.
He ran from the motel
room barefoot, correct?
Mm-hmm.
Yet he left no shoes behind.
He could have been
carrying his shoes.
He was in too much
of a hurry to put them on.
Mm, maybe. But there
was a bottle of shampoo
that Nick found
in the bathroom.
It contained
one percent permethrin,
formulated to
combat head lice.
Now, I've checked with Doc.
Neither of the Smiths
were head lice sufferers.
So the shampoo
was for the guest.
Yes. Presumably the killer.
Nick found residue on
the wall of the shower.
I've tested it; it contained
five percent permethrin.
Permethrin, for the head lice.
No.
This is five percent,
in a body cream.
It's prescription strength,
used to treat scabies.
I don't want to seem
insensitive, but...
shoeless, head lice,
and scabies--that all
sounds like homeless to me.
Richard Smith worked
with the homeless
back in Flagstaff.
He could have been doing
some sort of outreach,
wanted to help somebody,
brought them in
off the street.
I've already called around.
There's a local shelter
called Street Saviors
who had a scabies
outbreak last week,
where they distributed this
very same prescription cream.
Way to bury the lead, Hodges.
That's part
of my charm.
It's all in the telling.
FINLAY:
The regular.
Yeah. Fruity.
Okay, thanks so much.
Hey. So I talked
to a couple
Hey.
of the outreach
workers.
They saw a guy earlier,
a guy named Rudy.
He's a regular here.
He was barefoot,
had bloodstained clothes.
Sounds like our boy.
FINLAY:
Yeah. According to the locals,
he likes to hang out here,
under the bridge.
Anybody seen Rudy?
Huh?
STOKES:
You seen Rudy?
You know who Rudy is?
Hey, where
does Rudy stay?
Hey, old-timer.
Hey, man.
You seen Rudy anywhere?
Rudy!
(gasping)
What's wrong?
What have you
been doing, man?
(panting)
Huh?
Rudy, you're gonna have
to come with us.
Rudy, it says here
in my files
that you spent some time
in the state hospital.
Had a few psych holds?
Yeah, I have some problems.
What did the doctors
diagnose you with?
Schizophrenia, bipolar disorder,
generalized anxiety,
paranoia...
BRASS:
Well, that's okay.
We get the idea.
Do you recognize these two?
Richard and Ann?
They're angels.
What do you mean?
They rescued me.
How?
I was on the
street, out front
of a drugstore on Cramer.
Oh, that's
right near
the Sky View Motel.
I go there sometimes
to ask for change,
you know, and-and I...
These guys,
they jumped me and-and...
and they beat me,
and they took my change
and they took my shoes.
And-and it probably
would have been worse,
except that Richard and Ann
came along
out of nowhere and...
and chased them away.
Rudy, what happened next?
I told you, they're angels.
They-they-they...
they asked me if
I wanted to stay
in their room with them,
and they got me a toothbrush
and stuff, and they let me
get a shower
and get all cleaned up.
Did something happen
after the shower?
Something happened, didn't it?
(mutters): I don't know.
I don't remember.
Come on, Rudy, think.
Think real hard.
(shuddering breath)
(distorted shout):
No! No!
There were these dolls...
a-and there were
a whole bunch of them,
and they started talking to me
and they were looking at me.
(distorted screaming,
eerie voices speaking)
What were they saying, Rudy?
What did they say?
Did the dolls
tell you to do this?
(gasps, screams)
I...
I did that, didn't I?
I did that with the scissors.
I hurt them.
(shrieking)
(eerie, distorted,
high-pitched laughter)
(shriek echoing)
What about these people?
(Rudy gasping repeatedly)
Did you hurt them, too?
I don't know.
FINLAY: You know, sometimes
I think we forget
what delicate,
complex machines we are.
You know, all it takes are a few
short-circuiting synapses,
or a breakdown
in myelination,
and everything gets thrown
out of whack.
Jules, you just
captured a killer.
I know.
Then why do I feel so bad?
Because he seems like
a nice guy
who got dealt a lousy hand
in life.
So we have him for killing
the Smiths, right?
What about the other
two attacks?
Well, I could go over all the
evidence and make a case.
He's obviously
our prime suspect.
He frequented the area,
and he's obviously unstable.
Good work.
You put some long hours
in on this.
Why-why don't you go home,
get yourself some rest.
(TV playing indistinctly
in distance)
(yelling, panting)
Take it, take it easy!
One plus one is two.
One for me and one for you.
Two plus two is four. (panting)
That's a couple more.
Three plus three is six.
Straight and crooked sticks!
Get away!
(siren wailing)
(muttering)
One plus one is two.
One for me and one for you.
Two plus two is four,
and that's a couple more.
(gasping)
One plus one is two.
One for me and one for you.
Two plus two is four.
That's a couple more.
Three plus
three is six.
Ma'am.
Straight and crooked sticks.
You need to drop
that bottle, do you hear me?
(whimpering)
Four plus four is eight.
Seagulls on the gate!
Five plus five is ten.
Hey!
Do you hear
what I'm saying?!
Drop the bottle!
Ricky doesn't follow directions!
He never follows directions!
(yells)
(Tazer clicking)
Thanks, man.
Seriously, thanks.
Thanks.
All right.
(gasps)
Hey!
Was she staying here?
In the motel?
Uh, yeah, just
since tonight.
What room?
(door creaking)
It's happened again.
(indistinct radio communication,
siren whoops in distance)
How the hell can this be?
I thought we had our killer.
Did we mess up, Jules?
Did we make a mistake
with our-our homeless guy?
No, Rudy's guilty,
maybe not of all three,
but he definitely
killed the Smiths.
Then how do we explain this?
I don't know.
It has to be... unrelated.
Unrelated?
Four murders in the same room
over a three-month period.
That's got to be connected,
don't you think?
(garbled radio transmission)
All right, I'm sorry. Look,
all right, who are
our players tonight?
Who are we talking about here?
Suspect is a woman,
28-year-old
high school math teacher.
Victim was one of her students.
Together in a sleazy,
$39-a-night motel room.
With lingerie, condoms,
sex toys and alcohol.
Wonder what
was going on here, right?
Yeah, according
to the high school Web site,
she was just named
Teacher of the Year.
I'll bet she was.
Hey.
So, this may
sound crazy,
but I'm thinking
that this isn't
what it looks like.
I don't believe
that the teacher
was sleeping with her student.
Yeah, you're right,
that sounds crazy.
Well, listen to this voice mail
I found on her phone.
YOUNG MAN:
Ms. Stone, it's Matthew.
I don't know what to do,
but my parents have been
drinking and fighting,
and I can't go home;
I'm at a motel.
But I'm scared.
I don't know who else to call.
I'm sorry, but you have
to help, please.
BRASS: Ms. Stone, we are
trying to make sense
out of what happened
in that room.
But we need your help
to do that.
STOKES:
Boy, Matthew must
have told you
a really sad story
to lure you to that motel room.
Now, obviously,
from the items he brought along,
he had ideas of getting
romantic with you.
BRASS:
Now, there were a lot of empty
liquor bottles in the room.
Was the young man drunk?
There wasn't any drinking.
First thing I did was dump
all the alcohol down the sink.
I wanted it
clear to Matthew
that nothing was going
to happen.
Did he get upset?
Is that when he threatened you?
He would never.
Matthew's a...
Matthew's a great kid.
He just had a harmless crush,
that's all.
He would never hurt me.
Then why did you kill him?
It wasn't me.
Really? Wasn't you?
Ms. Stone,
look, look at this.
(whimpering, grunts)
That's not me.
I mean, it's me, it's my body,
but I...
I had no control.
It was like there was
something inside me.
I was...
...possessed.
BRASS:
You were what?
(crying):
I was...
I don't know. Part of me
really wants to believe her.
I mean, the woman ranting
and screaming on that video
from last night was nothing
like the woman I met today.
They were two totally
different people.
So, her behavior last night
was completely out of character.
Mm-hmm!
Did the hospital do
a tox screen?
Yeah, it was clean.
Not even alcohol.
Then it's got to be the room.
The room made her do it.
What, like, The Shining? Hmm?
The Overlook Hotel?
It's the one thing
connecting all of the murders.
Right now, it's the only thing.
Okay, so, let's have Hodges
and Henry drag their equipment
out there and test the room,
see what they have to say.
Hmm.
(electronic crackling)
I've got some elevated VOCs
in the air conditioner,
but nothing that would explain
any of the bizarre behavior.
What about you?
You got anything yet?
Could I have five minutes
to look first?
Oh, and I'm very much enjoying
the dirty bathroom.
Thank you for that.
(sighs)
Mm! Mm...
Great. Now I can smell
like a fruit bowl
for the rest of the day.
(electronic crackling)
It looks like
they've got mold
inside the walls of the closet.
I'm going to have
to get a sample.
Do you have the pry bar
in there?
Hey, I have
to open some drywall.
Do you have the pry bar
in your kit?
Hodges!
Seriously?
(sighs)
Hodges, what
are you doing?
I was calling you.
(grunting, huffing)
What are you
looking at?
(grunting, growling)
What, what's
going on with you?
I know who you are.
Okay, look, w-why don't you
have a seat on the toilet...
(continues indistinctly)
I'm gonna help you
out, come here.
I can see what you are!
(yelling)
Hodges, let go of me!
That hurts!
(Hodges grunts, pants)
No... Hodges!
No, no...!
(Hodges pounding on door)
This is Henry Andrews.
I'm at the Sky View Motel,
room 114,
and I have an emergency.
I need police and EMS
immediately.
(Hodges yelling, bellowing)
Excuse me...
Hey! Henry!
Henry?
Hey, man, you all right?
What's going on out here?
I don't know exactly.
He just flipped out.
Nick, I honestly think
he would have killed me.
Hodges?
Yeah, but it
wasn't Hodges.
I mean, if you would've
seen the look in his eyes,
something must have
happened to him in there,
something that
triggered this.
What'd he say to you?
Nothing.
Everything that came out
of him was unintelligible.
It was grunts
and growls.
Hey, so paramedics
hit him
with a sedative.
Once they get him to
the hospital,
maybe we'll figure out
what's going on.
Wait, wait, before he goes,
I-I need a-a... a swab.
Check your vest.
ANDREWS:
Hold up.
Hey, buddy,
I just need
to get some saliva.
Can you help me out?
(mumbling)
Can you open up?
Come on,
just open up.
There you go,
help me out.
There you go.
Good.
Yeah, get him out of here.
DOCTOR:
Vitals are good...
(doctor continues
indistinctly)
RUSSELL: Thanks, Doc.
I appreciate it.
You're welcome.
What did he say?
How's he doing?
He's gonna be okay.
I mean, his vitals are all
in the normal range.
He doesn't seem to be
in any physical distress.
Well, obviously there is
something going on
in that motel room.
Now we need to add Hodges
to the list
of people that went
nuts in there, right?
Homeless guy, the teacher--
Makes me wonder about our
first victim, Mark Bell.
Who's to say he didn't
go crazy, too,
and stab himself in his legs.
If all of this is true,
what's it say about the man
who lost his wife?
ANDREWS:
Hey, guys,
you are not gonna
believe this, but
Hodges was drugged.
What are you talking about?
LSD-- I did an ELISA test
on his saliva.
Somehow, he must've been dosed
while we were
in the room working.
Wait a minute, didn't the
hospital do a tox screen
on the teacher and on Rudy,
and it came back negative?
The standard tox panel
doesn't test for LSD,
so they were probably
dosed, too--
we just had no way
to know it.
But wh-why the violence?
The molecules I found
were highly adulterated,
and cut with a cyclidine
similar to PCP.
Probably came out of
somebody's kitchen sink.
Okay.
Now we know what.
Let's go find out how.
STOKES (muffled):
So, according to Henry,
this lysergic acid glows blue.
And the stuff's potent.
We may not be looking
for much.
SANDERS (muffled):
Wait a minute--
got something over here.
These are tiny drops.
It looks like they might've
been aerosolized.
STOKES: Check it out--
covered in blue.
This is our source
right here.
SANDERS: If Hodges
got sprayed by that,
it would only have to land
on his lips
or in his eye, and it would
be instantly absorbed.
Here, let me bag it.
Hold on here.
I don't think the LSD was
coming from that cartridge.
There's a hose in here.
Yeah, and it's coming
through the wall
from the next room.
(pounding on door)
STOKES: Hey, Oscar, can we use
your bathroom for a second?
Hey! You can't come
in here like this!
Sure we can.
Check it out, Greg.
It's called
probable cause, Oscar.
What do you got?
Found the source.
Oscar, I remember
standing right there
and listening to you
preach to me about God's will.
Is this what you meant? Huh?
Killing six people?
I didn't kill anyone.
You've been spraying LSD
all over the bathroom next door.
You're responsible!
I don't know what
you're talking about.
God sees the truth.
Yes, sir!
God knows my heart!
STOKES: You know what?
I'm tired of hearing that.
Sit down, relax.
I'm gonna get you a ride.
SANDERS: Nick,
take a look at this.
That's an odd place for a TV.
That's the room next door--
room 114.
So not only have you been dosing
the people next door,
you've been recording it, too?
Hey, Nick, I don't see
any recording device.
But there's this transmitter
set up to send a signal
someplace else.
So what's with all
the video stuff?
I don't know.
I just know I'm not
supposed to touch it.
Yeah? Who told you that?
Huh?
Trent, the manager.
He said if I did,
he'd kick me out.
Trent Raeger, got a warrant.
See you downtown.
(door shuts)
Hey, Nick,
you gotta come
and see this.
Our peeper has been looking
at all the rooms,
not just room 114.
Yeah, he's been spending
some quality time in here.
Hmm. These are all souvenirs...
...from his favorite guests.
BRASS: You've been peeping
on room 114 for a long time,
haven't you, Trent?
At what point did you decide
that it wasn't enough
to just be a voyeur?
I mean, when did you decide
that you needed to kill people?
It isn't like that.
Okay, then tell me
what it's like.
Well, it's just about...
...watching, you know?
All the people coming
through the motel.
When I was a kid, we'd get
families on vacation,
and I was curious because
we never took vacations.
We never left.
So...
I had these special places
where I could look
through the walls...
watch them.
(whispers):
Special places.
Then the video age came
and you upgraded
your little hobby, right?
That was pretty cool, too.
I mean, especially when
the motel kind of
went downhill, you know?
That brought all kinds
of crazy stuff.
The crack whores, drunk dudes,
beating their wives, they...
That is a show, believe me.
But even that
got a little old and dull,
so you spiced it up by
dosing people with drugs?
A few months ago, I saw this guy
out on Third, tripping on acid.
He was, like, out of his mind,
and it was just so...
so weird.
And that is when I came up with
that rig for the bathroom.
You have to admit...
it is pretty clever.
Clever.
Five people are dead,
one is in the hospital.
Hey, I just put the gas
in the car... okay?
They're the ones
that crashed it.
Come on...
you've got my tapes;
you've seen 'em.
That first dude,
hacking his legs off.
Or that teacher...
oh, and the homeless guy.
I mean, the dude is
already a total mess,
and then the lady has
all those dolls!
I mean, that was a gift.
Or the poor Mexican guy...
killing his wife.
Honestly, I didn't
see that coming.
I mean, that...
that...
...that was awesome.
(quietly):
Awesome.
What are you looking
at me like that for?
Come on, people go online
every day to look at stuff
that's just like that.
But you manipulated this.
You made this happen.
You made these people,
these innocent people,
do these things.
So what?
What's the difference?
Well, you'll have 25 years
to life to figure that out.
And the weird thing is you're
gonna be in a little room
where people watching you 24/7.
Hey.
I, uh, heard they're going
to be discharging you soon.
Yeah.
I guess I've healed as much
as I'm going to.
Well, I... I came 'cause
I wanted you to know
that we arrested
the man responsible
for what happened to you
and to your wife.
He didn't physically
do the killings,
but he is responsible.
Well, I-I... I'm sorry,
I'm a little confused here.
The man we arrested...
lived in the motel,
and he drugged
several of his guests.
That night, when your wife
went to sleep,
you went into the bathroom
and you snuck a cigarette.
While you were in the bathroom,
you were dosed with
a very potent psychedelic drug,
and it caused a violent
change in your personality
and your behavior.
That face... that you saw...
the man who was hitting
your wife...
Uh... in a little while,
there's going to be some
police officers coming here,
and you're going to need
to go with them, okay?
I'm sorry.
I want to apologize
for anything I may have said
while I wasn't myself.
It wasn't your words so much
as your actions, really.
And, obviously...
I apologize for those, too.
Apology accepted?
Yes.
(sighs with relief)
Apology accepted.
Good.
Then you won't be trying to
get back at me in some way?
No, of course not.
But I wouldn't drink
that coffee, if I were you.