(bird hooting)
(click, scratching)
(stairs squeaking quietly)
♪ ♪
(blade rings)
(screaming)
(sobbing)
No...
(screams)
Please!
Stop! No!
(sirens wail, whoop)
Hey, Nick. Guys.
Don't worry.
She's going to make it.
Hey, I saw you on
TV last week, Ryan.
You're a real hero.
What can I say?
It's not all
it's cracked up to be.
He saved a bunch of kids out
of a burning building last week.
LANGSTON:
Hey, isn't that Margot Wilton.
SANDERS:
First Lady of Vegas.
She's Miss Philanthropy
herself.
She's got more buildings named
after her than you can count.
It's a real slash job.
Bedroom's a horror show.
Upstairs on your left.
It's a real shame.
Ray and I will
take the bedroom. Nick...
I'll find out how he got in.
Guess I'm on
the perimeter.
♪ ♪
Fresh carvings.
Must be what's left
of the boy's face.
So the intruder had to
take the photographs
out of the frames,
obliterate the faces
and then reassemble them.
WILLOWS:
Not once, but twice.
He certainly wasn't in any rush.
Key to the City.
Upside down.
Dust.
Someone just did this.
Clean as a whistle.
Two carved-out faces...
and an upside-down award.
It's up to us
to make it right side up.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
♪ ♪
(door creaks)
Blood on the bed,
the headboard, wall.
This is obviously
where she called for help.
The "9" and the "1"
are covered in blood.
The castoff on the wall
suggests her attacker was
directly over her.
(screaming)
Two voids.
Consistent with someone
kneeling over her...
on top of her.
There was no visible blood
on the stairs we just came up
or the hallway
we just came out of.
There has to be
a trail somewhere.
Here we go.
LANGSTON:
Footprint, handprint,
followed by handprint,
footprint.
That's odd.
Fading as they go out
these doors here.
So this guy gets off the bed
one hand and one foot at time.
That's weird.
STOKES:
Hey.
I found
the point of entry.
No, no, you're a little late,
buddy, I already found it.
Entry and exit.
Looks like he cut
a circular hole
in the glass of
the French door.
Guess he put it back in
on his way out.
I don't know why he'd do that.
Unless he's trying
to make us think
that he's never been
in the house before.
All the other windows
I checked
have been varnished shut,
except this one.
See, the varnish seal
has been cut.
And I got fresh chips
and what appears to be
a dust void on the sill
with a feathering pattern
on either side of the void.
All indicative
of entry and exit.
Somebody has been through
this window, multiple times.
What is that, 12 by 12?
That's pretty tight.
I know neither one of us
are getting through there.
Well, then, it could be
we're looking for a small guy,
or even a kid.
Yeah, or a leprechaun.
Or a leprechaun.
Big ups to Greg-- he found
a second entry point,
but now I've got more questions
than answers.
How about you?
Here's one:
Woman in her 60s,
vulnerable in her bed,
versus a blade-
wielding intruder.
Is she lucky to be alive
or did she survive by design?
All right, now, based on the
messages he left, it's obvious
that he didn't approve
of her Key to the City.
And the child in the wheelchair
obviously didn't sit well
with him.
This all makes me think
it was personal, Nick.
He's been in and out
of her house multiple times.
He could have killed her
whenever he wanted to.
Why tonight?
I think the answer
is in these messages he left.
I mean, it can't be
in the fingerprints,
because he didn't leave any.
Does any of this
make sense to you?
No, but I bet it makes
a lot of sense to him.
We need to examine
the one piece of evidence
the killer shouldn't have
left behind.
Margot Wilton.
MARGOT:
It was very dark.
I think... that he
was African-American.
Strange, uh, slippery.
Slippery how,
was he sweating?
No. Uh, more like...
he was wearing gloves.
The one thing that I can't
get out of my head--
those eyes.
Black holes.
Teeth.
Teeth?
Braces.
Braces?
I don't know.
I'm not sure.
All right,
all right, all right.
Did he say anything to you?
No...
I only heard my own screams.
Well...
You are a very brave woman,
and now I understand why you
received the Key to the City.
I, um, noticed in your home
there were several pictures
of yourself
and a young boy in a wheelchair.
Is that your son?
Robbie.
From my first marriage.
Uh-huh.
He died very young.
He was so sick.
I'm so sorry.
Looks like his spirit
lived on, though.
Um, I read the plaque.
What did it say?
Uh, fortitude, fulfillment
and philanthropy,
was it?
I did it for him.
All I ever wanted
to was help people.
And 50 years later,
Mayor Goodman gave me
the Key to the City.
I'm sorry.
Your cuts are evidence.
Don't you doctors and police
ever talk to one another?
Wouldn't it have
been a lot easier
if that cute
young resident
hadn't stitched
me up at all?
Well, he was just doing
his job, and I'm doing mine.
What's the matter, I'm not cute?
Not right now.
Would you put your finger
right here, please.
(groans)
Say I'm cute.
Go to hell.
You look like you just
fell down a chimney.
That's about the only thing
I haven't printed.
(grunts)
I've been at this
for hours.
I don't have one usable print.
Well, you know what my
Papa Olaf used to tell me...
(sighs)
What's that, Greg?
(Norwegian accent): "Hojern,
when the going gets rough,
keep your chin up."
I was walking the perimeter,
and I noticed a window
above the bedroom window.
This place has an attic
somewhere.
We know this guy has been coming
in and out of here, but that's
one place we haven't looked.
After you.
I don't do attics.
I'm dirty enough.
After you.
Attaboy.
Damn, she's got
a lot of awards.
Yeah, she's got
a lot of everything.
This house is holey.
What?
Look up.
How many pinkies?
I know a rat didn't do that.
Not unless the rat's kinky and
knows how to use a lipstick cam.
(sniffing)
He's been living up here
and keeping one eye
on Margot Wilton.
Hey.
He's, he's been
reading her mail.
These envelope
lips are rippled.
It's pretty obvious
they've been steamed open.
You and Margot have
something in common.
Yeah, what's that?
A stalker.
That was a long time ago.
(grunts)
Nick.
Hmm?
Help me with this bed.
Yeah.
Looks like they were
sleeping together.
But he never touched her
until last night.
Margot Wilton's
house is a bust--
no fingerprints,
no trace, no DNA.
As of right now, the guy we're
chasing is forensic-proof.
He'd be the first.
Which leads us
to the Hourglass of Evidence.
Now, normally,
we collect evidence,
we analyze it,
it leads us to the truth,
but here we have
the absence
of individualized evidence,
so let's flip...
the hourglass.
The absence of evidence
is evidence.
And from that,
we can draw certain conclusions.
So the suspect went
in and out of the house
through a small window.
So he's small.
Which is consistent
with the dust void
under her bed.
No more than five-eight.
WILLOWS:
He's agile.
Virtually spider-walked
off of her bed--
foot, hand,
hand, foot.
LANGSTON:
So we have
a possible male,
slight build, medium height,
physically fit,
younger rather than older.
And... maniacally patient.
He sat in the attic eating
oranges, watching Margot Wilton
for possibly weeks, even months.
Lying under her bed,
reading her mail,
invading her life
without her ever knowing it.
He's diabolical.
So, by analyzing
what's not there,
we begin to fill
the bottom of the hourglass,
which leads us to...
...the truth.
Let's reanalyze the
evidence with fresh eyes.
Looks like urine.
But it's not in the
appropriate anatomical region.
(sniffs)
Doesn't smell
like urine.
You know, uh, Grissom
would have tasted that.
Could be sweat.
It fluoresces
the same as urine.
So you're saying
only his spine
was sweating?
Spines don't have sweat glands.
Well, if it is sweat,
then we can get epithelials.
Hm. Run DNA.
No sweat.
♪ ♪
Wish I could say
I don't have a fetish, but I do.
Should I shut the door?
Amylase confirmed
that the carpet stain
was sweat.
DNA was compromised,
so it was a dead end there,
but the sweat
was not alone.
What was with it?
Well,
here's where the fetish
comes in.
Found trace amounts
of silicone,
cyclopentasiloxane,
and other components
that are commonly found
in latex fetish sprays.
Primary use is to slide on
skintight latex suits.
Hmm.
The victim said her attacker
was a black male adult
who felt slippery.
He was probably wearing latex.
With a zipper
up the back.
Which explains
why his spine
was sweating.
(singsongy):
Time to get kinky.
I knew I should've
shut the door.
WILLOWS:
Doberman head, nice.
That's new.
What do you mean
"that's new"?
You got to keep up
with these things, Nicky.
All sex crimes start
with fantasies.
When it goes from the big head
to the little head,
that's where we come in.
You follow?
I mean, you didn't think I came
in here recreationally, did you?
I don't know, you just referred
to a dog mask in a sex shop
as "nice" and "new."
I had to ask.
You okay?
Are you?
MAN:
Catherine!
Hey!
Hey, I got your call.
Got that
multispeed hoo-hah
they ordered for you.
It was hot
pink, right?
I'm kidding.
Joey's been a great resource
for all my sex crimes.
STOKES:
So...
latex?
Mm!
What is our suspect into?
Well, according
to our trace tech,
it's a silicone-based
fetish spray.
To put on latex,
preferably skintight latex.
It's probably full-body.
Okay, let's talk
silicone spray.
You know,
I only carry one brand.
It's a pretty slow mover.
I did sell a couple bottles,
though, about six months ago,
to a guy who, uh...
oh, he custom-ordered
two latex head-to-toes.
Head-to-toes?
Yeah.
It's full head gear,
gloves, booties.
Every inch covered except for
the eyes, the nose, the mouth.
Well, I know you keep
some kind of records.
Oh, come on,
I got more than that.
I got concept drawings,
I got photos.
I made the suits myself.
Took me a couple days, but
they turned out just so great.
Photos?
I mean, you have
a picture of him?
Yep.
This explains the sweat
stain in the dust void.
He was sweating
through his zipper.
Do you have anything with him
without the mask?
He wouldn't allow it.
That's a pretty tough ask
in a place
like this.
Sure.
Heterochromia.
One blue eye, one brown.
Hmm.
You got anything else
on this guy?
I don't know, let me check.
I remember
he wouldn't leave an address,
he always paid cash,
but... look at that.
Did leave a name.
Ian Moone.
(computer beeping)
(clicks tongue)
(mumbling):
Ian Moone.
Ian...
Moone.
One.
"I am no one."
Uh, be sure to
lock your doors.
Okay.
GIRL:
Go, Mommy.
Car wash! Yay!
It's on a timer, sweetie.
Sit back and relax,
put your earbuds in.
Listen to your music.
Hey. It's me.
I'm at the car wash.
A-And I'm sorry I couldn't
get away earlier to talk, but...
Yeah.
How's my Mr. Everything?
GIRL:
Look, dolly, it's a bubble bath!
Really! (laughs)
Okay.
You know I will.
I always do.
I will
make it happen.
I always do.
I need to see you.
No, I need to see all of you.
Say good-bye!
(screams)
(screaming)
Help me! Help...!
(screaming, blade slashing)
(screaming stops)
(mechanisms whirring)
(fingers squeaking)
(squeaking)
(screams)
What do you think
the "A" stands for?
Are you sure
it was just
the mother and daughter
in the car?
Yeah, just
the two, ma'am.
Well, if they were alone
in a locked car,
how the hell did
this happen, Greg?
Catherine?
Got blood back here.
Mostly smears.
Well, I've got half
of a bloody hand impression.
So do I.
Well, it appears that there was
no blood on him
as he went to kill her,
but he definitely left
traces of her blood
as he was backing out.
SANDERS: Blood transfer
on the hatch release.
Carpet's bone-dry.
He had to be in the car before
it went through
the wash.
Spare tire compartment.
No tire.
Is it possible
that the same guy
who crawled through
the bathroom window
fit into a space like this?
Well, if he was here,
where did he go?
And how did he get away
without being seen?
425A! Suspect
on the premises!
Greg, flashlight.
Damn it!
Who turned on the water?
MAN (shouting):
Shut it down! Shut it down!
Alise... I know you don't
want to talk to anybody,
and I know you're scared,
but I'm a policeman and
I'm trying to do my job, so,
I thought maybe
we'd play a little game.
Maybe... if you let me,
I... I'll talk to your doll.
Would that be okay?
Great. Thank you.
Hello, doll.
My name is James.
I'm trying
to help Alise
out of a tough spot.
So can you tell me,
was anyone else in the car
with Alise and her mom?
No, huh?
You know, I want to believe you,
but, uh, there
had to be somebody.
Maybe you just
didn't see him?
Maybe you...
and Alise were watching
the car wash?
Yeah.
Well, let me ask you
something: is there...
is there anything
that you could tell me
that would help me
catch the man that
hurt Alise's mom?
You can even whisper it,
if you want.
It's okay.
Whisper it in my ear.
Sqwee... gel.
Excuse me?
Could you say that again?
Sqwee... gel.
MAN:
Where is she?
Alise!
Daddy!
Oh, baby.
Oh, my baby.
(whispers):
Oh, my girl.
My girl.
Do you know anyone
who would want to
harm your wife?
Oh...
Uh...
Actually, yes.
Really?
BRASS:
Explain that.
MAN:My wife, uh...
she was recently appointed
to the Family Values Committee
in, uh, Clark County.
She got there
because she...
she single-handedly
went up against these...
these big video game companies
and banned the sale
of, uh,Vehicular Manslaughter
and all those other violent
first-person games, to minors.
Minors.
Kids.
Did she receive any, uh,
crank calls or hate mail,
death threats?
Much more than that.
Really?
Someone broke into our home.
I was at work.
Alise was at day care.
Uh, hey, Doc?
This guy, he...
he put my wife in the hospital.
Okay? He cut her up real bad.
ROBBINS: Carrie Jones,
our car wash victim,
was attacked twice.
Most recent was a few hours ago.
The first attack was probably
no more than a few weeks ago.
PHILLIPS:
Both are sharp-force injuries.
What's your guess
on weapon of choice?
Could be a box cutter.
Maybe a straight razor.
Mm-hmm.
Ray.
Hey.
C.O.D. is sharp-force
injuries to the neck.
Severed the carotid.
All the other wounds
are defensive.
LANGSTON:
Some old... some new.
I had a conversation with
my gut on the way down here.
I just want to see
if my suspicions are correct.
We have...
identical wounds,
similar in length,
double-edged blade.
That means
whoever attacked
Margot Wilton...
killed Carrie Jones.
I need to see what
was under her bed.
STOKES:
Dust void.
Well, he was definitely here.
BRASS:
Sqweegel.
That's the name
the little girl gave the killer.
She was in the car
at the car wash when
her mother was killed.
Now, I'm guessing is,
Sqweegel is the sound
that the mops make as
they go back and forth
across the windshield.
Sqweegel, you know?
LANGSTON:
Yeah.
Traumatic
memory image.
Oh, I got traumatic
memory image for you.
Deja vu.
This is Margot Wilton's
place all over again.
You got same M.O.,
jimmied bathroom window,
multiple entries
and exits-- I bet if
we all look up,
we'll find a hole
with a lipstick cam in it,
no prints,
no DNA.
There it is.
I'm on it.
STOKES:
Got something here.
Ray, get a shot of this.
Uh-huh.
The letter "A."
Just like the car wash.
(passionate breathing)
Lucky for you,
I hate my husband.
I'll take football over
car insurance any day.
LANGSTON:
Car insurance.
Mr. Jones...
what do you do
for a living?
Turn it off.
Just turn it off, please.
Very well.
I can't imagine how difficult
this must be for you,
Mr. Jones, but
unfortunately,
I do have to ask you
another question.
Now, we found this, uh...
DVD under your bed.
Now, did you hire a P.I.
to follow your wife?
Well, why would
I do that?
You tell me.
She's the chair
of the Family Values Committee.
Her whole life has
been about the truth,
honesty and morality.
That's what he meant.
What are you talking about?
When Carrie was attacked,
she told the police, she said,
that animal,
he kept saying to her...
"I know.
Confess."
She said she didn't
know what her attacker
was talking about--
I think she did.
That scarlet letter
on the windshield can
only mean one thing.
Well, she had a dirty
little secret-- she
was a party girl,
cheating on her husband
who didn't have a clue.
But Sqweegel did.
Now, he attacked Carrie
two weeks ago,
didn't kill her,
leaves her alive
with the message:
"I know. Confess."
Gave her a chance
to repent.
I guess she didn't,
because he killed her
in the car wash.
My thought is,
he gave Margot Wilton
the chance to repent as well,
and if she hasn't,
her life's still in danger.
MARGOT:
I have lived there
for 45 years, and
I want to go home.
The department
has the resources
to put you in a hotel
and provide round-
the-clock security.
I don't want to go to a hotel.
With a bunch of strangers
next to me?
Chances of that guy coming back
are a million to one.
You weren't his only victim.
Gentlemen,
this is an
unauthorized interview.
You're compromising Mrs.
Wilton's right to counsel,
not to mention
her freedom of movement.
Need I remind you--
she's a victim, not a suspect.
Oscar, we're just trying
to keep her safe, that's all.
Oh, Jim,
quit with the fear tactics.
LANGSTON: No fear tactics,
Mayor Goodman.
We have every reason to
believe that the first
attack was a warning.
I'll take my chances.
Please take me home.
Jim, I need a minute
with her.
All right. Oscar.
I need to talk to you
privately, please. Over here.
Yes?
I just need one minute.
"I know.
Confess."
Your attacker said the same
thing to a young mother.
Two weeks ago,
he attacked her at home,
gave her a warning,
now she's dead.
What does he want you
to confess, Margot?
What does he know
that you're not telling us?
Does it have something to do
with your son
or the Key to the City?
Your minute's up.
If you so much
knock on that door,
I'll have you in court
tomorrow on harassment.
Pardon my bark;
she's a friend.
Go over my head,
and I'll kill you.
No.
No. No!
(labored breathing)
(shouts)
Looking for your letters?
(Margot yells)
What's going on, Akers?
Got a call about
an abandoned vehicle.
One of our guys
ran the plates
and it came back
to one of ours.
Yeah? Whose is it?
Ryan Fink.
You know that hero paramedic
who saved all those kids?
Yeah, yeah,
I know who that is.
AKERS: This is the car the city
gave him for saving the kids.
It's locked up.
Looks like I got
some blood.
Hand me your stick.
Exigent circumstances.
Watch yourself.
(labored breathing,
latex squeaking)
(screaming)
(shouting, gasping)
(yelling)
(panting)
(screaming)
BRASS: This is not
the kind of situation
where you just stand by
and wait, okay? We gotta go in.
Help me out here.
Hey.
Give me the green light.
Okay. I'll stand by and wait.
I just found blood all
over Ryan Fink's car,
enough to presume
he's dead.
Carrie Jones, Ryan Fink,
Margot Wilton--
all three honored by the city
and now two of them are dead.
I guarantee you she's next.
The whole team's right
behind me. Let's go in.
(moans)
(grunts)
What do you want from me?
I think you know.
I don't know anything.
You know everything.
I read your letters.
I heard your phone calls.
I even watched
while you slept.
I know why you toss
and turn at night.
It's hard to be still
in Robbie's nightmare.
(strains):
He was my baby.
(sobs)
He was so sick, he was in pain.
He'd cry, every night,
in his chair.
He was trapped and so was I.
Tell me about the pool.
How your son's death
was an act of mercy.
A mother's love.
Oh, you bastard.
You don't know
the whole story.
I know everything!
All right!
All right,
I know that you know.
But you have to understand,
my son was dying.
Say it.
Robbie drowned...
and it was not an accident.
I killed him.
Imurderedmy son,
'cause I believed
in my heart that it was
the right thing to do.
Mrs. Wilton?
Are you hurt?
I shot him.
Which way'd he go?
I don't know.
I shot him.
Five shots,
no blood?
The case mouths are crimped.
He replaced
her real ammo with blanks.
This guy thought of everything.
BRASS:
Mitch, get her out of here.
Nick, check upstairs.
The rest of you, on me.
Let's go find this bastard.
Let's go.
Lady, we've got to
get out of here now.
No! My letters!
My letters!
Ray?
It's all right.
Tache noir.
The exposed sclera
has gone black.
(sniffs) He's got a little bit
of a stench
coming off of him,
so he's been dead
for a couple
of hours.
How can that be?
(grunts)
That's Ryan Fink.
The paramedic?
STOKES:
Yup.
LANGSTON:
You see the scars?
Attacked first,
then killed.
Just like Carrie Jones.
Whew!
Margot Wilton was lucky.
That's why he
bought two suits.
But why put them
under the bed?
I think our answer
is in the wind.
MARGOT:
Dear Henry,
I hope I have the courage
to send you this letter.
Because you're his father,
I owe you the truth
about our son.
Robbie begged me
to end his suffering.
He was failing,
more and more each day.
I can't.
You can if you love me.
I did a terrible thing.
I just stood there...
watching him.
I'll never forgive myself.
It's no wonder she insisted
on going back to her house.
She needed to get the letters.
That was her secret.
BRASS:
I got a call from
the fire chief.
Some tipsters have been calling
the fire
department hotline.
There's evidence this guy Fink
had been setting fires
to make himself look
like a hero.
That's hissecret.
And the biggest secret of all:
who is Ian Moone?
(labored breathing)
I am no one.