(moans)
(sighs)
(gasps)
(panting)
(groans)
(fabric tears)
(gasps)
(heavy breathing)
No! Stop, please!
Don't stop.
(metal blade scrapes)
(screams)
(indistinct police radio
transmission)
Hey.
You know that the speed limit
is not a suggestion, right?
You gonna give me
a ticket, copper?
Used to bring
Lindsey up here.
Mount Charleston always
has been a hot spot
for skiers and hikers and...
Now murderers.
You can see the terror
in his eyes.
This man knew
he was going to die.
This is a serious blood pool.
He was alive
when his head was chopped off.
Still tacky.
Fresh kill.
VARTANN:
So the park ranger said
he thought he heard
wolves howling,
but they're not native to
the area, so he came
down here to check it out.
WILLOWS:
Looks like his body's
been posed.
Could be some kind
of a cult killing.
Satanic rituals
are often performed
in a natural setting
like this, but this...
fence is a poor altar.
If this was a ritualistic
killing, there would be some...
sign.
Blood moon.
In the Book of Revelations,
it was considered to be a
precursor to the end of days.
Well, it certainly was
for this poor guy.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
(camera shutter clicks)
STOKES:
No tire tracks, no footprints.
I can't even
see my own.
He's not dressed
for hiking.
Mm-mm.
He had to get out here
some way.
Well, there's no ID on him.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Where is the bug man
when you need him?
I'm right here, buddy.
What is that?
That is a long-horned beetle.
Nick, there's something
else in his mouth,
and it's not moving.
(camera shutter clicks)
LANGSTON:
Hair.
Maybe he got a piece
of his attacker.
(Velcro tears)
Mm-hmm.
Guys, I'm gonna need
some bigger tools.
Yeah, okay.
I've got some
ligature marks on his wrist.
You check the other one,
will you?
Yeah, same thing over here.
But these patterns
are inconsistent
with this barbed wire.
(groans)
Stop, please stop!
STOKES: Looks like somebody
brought chains to the party.
Do you see these abrasions
and cuts here in the chest?
They appear to have been
made by the barbed wire.
Hmm...
So, our victim
ran into the barbed-
wire fence, and then...
our killer... turned him around.
(groans)
Killer wanted to
look him in the eye.
It would have made the killer
feel very powerful.
Hang on, now, Super Dave.
You just gonna chop him up?
Oh, Dr. Robbins said
that he wanted
the head
with the pike,
and the body with the fence.
I'll take the saw.
Okay.
I'll grab the head?
Yep.
Ready?
Mm-hmm.
(saw buzzes)
ROBBINS (grunting):
Okay.
It's like trying to get
meat off a shish kebab.
(grunting)
You all right?
Yeah. Yeah.
Give me a hand, David.
Mm-hmm.
The post went through the
trachea, soft palate,
and all the way
into the brain.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Heads or tails?
I'll take heads.
♪ ♪
(saw buzzing)
Lizzie Borden got an axe
and gave her mother 40 whacks.
Contrary to the poem, Lizzie
Borden gave her parents
a total of 29 whacks.
In this case,
we won't know the number
of whacks
or the type of weapon
that did the whacking
until we boil off the flesh
and examine the tool marks.
(camera shutter clicks)
He has got symmetrical
scars on both palms.
That would support the theory
that we're dealing with
some kind of cult.
Bloodletting
is a common practice.
Abrasions are deep.
He struggled.
It's a powerful thing,
the will to live.
Well, so is the will to kill.
Looks like more than
a dozen chop marks.
Whoa.
The water's beading.
Lotions and massage oils
make water run off
the skin like this.
Yeah.
This man has very little
body hair.
He's been waxed.
From head to toe.
And... everywhere in-between.
LANGSTON:
Doesn't seem to be
any hair regrowth.
This was done recently.
The thing about wax is...
it likes to stick around.
I'll get this
to Hodges.
Hey. I ran our vic's
prints through AFIS.
He's not in the system, and no
one matching his description
has been reported missing.
Well, if he's
a tourist,
it could be that no one
knows he's gone yet.
I got his photo out
to all the hotels,
so maybe somebody
will recognize him.
You know, uh, last night...
Mm-hmm?
was...
Really great.
We gotta do
that more often.
Yeah, why don't you
move in with me?
What did you just say?
(chuckles)
Yeah, I'm, uh... I'm serious.
I'd like to make dinner
for you every night.
Maybe a little
breakfast in bed,
if you're good.
That sounds nice.
I... I'll talk to you later.
Yeah.
I always imagined Wendy and me
moving in together.
Cuddling on the couch.
Watching theIron Chef.
Battle Garbanzo Bean
was our favorite.
Do you have something for me?
Olive oil, rosemary,
and a little lemon juice.
Salad dressing.
Yeah, you throw in
a balsamic, and you have a
vinaigrette, but in this case...
It's the ingredients in the wax
that was used on your victim
for his extensive man-scaping.
Double ouch.
I used to go to the Anubis Spa.
They had this sugar-based wax
which is similar to what
they used in ancient Egypt.
So an olive oil-based wax...
I'm guessing the
Mediterranean Hotel?
STOKES:
So the hotel spa confirmed that
Michael Wilson had a full-body
wax there three days ago.
Should be the room
up here, huh?
Yeah. Yeah,
it's right here.
Front desk recognized
the photograph
that Vartann's been
shopping around.
Said that Wilson came
in from San Diego
and he's here for some
kind of convention.
Hmm.
(beeping, door latch clicks)
STOKES:
Obvious signs of a struggle.
LANGSTON: It would be
pretty hard to take
someone out of a hotel room
against their will
without getting caught
on camera, right?
I'll pull surveillance.
Looks like Mr. Wilson was here
for a special occasion.
STOKES:
Yeah?
(camera clicks)
"Today and for all eternity--
I dedicate my soul to you."
I love you, too, honey.
They're wedding vows.
He was getting married.
STOKES:
Found a yellow contact lens.
That's an
unusual color.
Victim wasn't
wearing contacts.
Huh.
A Celtic love knot.
It's where, uh, the
expression "tying the knot"
came from, you know.
Uh-huh.
I got a couple
of receipts here.
One for flowers,
one for a cake,
and according to this,
they're supposed to be delivered
to the Unity Room of this hotel
on the seventh.
The wedding's today.
(organ playing somber dirge)
(hissing)
(snarls)
You wouldn't happen to have
any garlic on you, would you?
No, I'm fresh out.
Ah.
(hisses)
I think I'm going to be sick.
Julie, we just have
a few more questions.
MAN:
Hasn't she been
through enough?
I'm going to put a stop to this.
Your kind clearly have no
right to badger her like this.
"Our kind"?
Mr. Stewart,
a young man
has been brutally murdered.
We have every right to be here.
And as far as I'm concerned,
you can drop the act.
The act?
Miss Crenshaw,
when was the
last time that you saw
your fiancé?
Uh, yesterday afternoon...
when we rehearsed the ceremony.
So roughly 24 hours ago.
They didn't want to
see each other
before the wedding.
It's tradition.
We embrace the... the
principles and the morals
of centuries past.
Not like the present,
where you drive through a chapel
and Elvis will hand you
a license.
As to Michael's state of mind
last night--
did he seem agitated,
or... unsettled?
MAN 2:
No.
Michael was about to marry
the love of his life.
I've never seen anyone so happy.
Ethan. You're the
best man, right?
Right.
So you were in charge
of the bachelor party?
Bachelor party?
Yeah, did you guys party like a
rap star last night, or what?
We simply dined.
Then Michael went back
to his room
to work on his vows
and meditate.
Vampires meditate?
A true vampiric state
can only be achieved
through discipline
and self-control.
LANGSTON:
Self-control wasn't exercised
in Michael's hotel room.
The place was
completely trashed.
This is all my fault.
I was the one who wanted to
get married at the convention.
Where they let anyone in.
All of our friends were
going to be here, anyway.
I wanted them to see
how happy we were.
Let's go back to
where they let everyone in.
Who's "everyone"?
This is a Covens
and Clans convention.
Vampires, and...
unfortunately werewolves.
Mr. Stewart...
May I see your
hand, please?
Huh.
Miss Crenshaw?
We found the same scar
on Michael's palms.
In the movies, vampires
thirst for blood. Well...
we're not sanguinarians.
For us, blood is a...
a symbol of the life force
that flows through us.
We shed our blood
in ceremonies
to bind one
another together.
Whoever killed Michael
put a stake in my heart, too.
This has Van Helsing
written all over it.
The vampire slayer?
Mm-hmm.
I thought he just staked
them through the heart.
The staking was just to
keep them in their coffins.
If you really want
to kill a vampire,
you have to cut off his head.
Only this guy wasn't
a real vampire.
Well, someone thought so.
You know, a few years ago,
in Romania,
a family dug up their dead
relative because they thought
he was a vampire.
They ripped out his heart,
burned it,
mixed the ashes with water,
and then drank it.
Seriously?
And, much like you,
the Romanian police
didn't believe in vampires,
so they charged the family
with abusing a corpse.
Served three
years in prison.
But the townspeople
thought they were heroes.
Individual stria match.
A single tool
made all these cuts.
Depth impressions range from
one-to-three-eighths of an inch,
indicating varying degrees
of force.
The killer used a curved,
heavy-headed blade,
most likely an axe or a hatchet.
(rock music plays)
Yeah, okay. Thanks, Arch.
(snarls)
Well, so much
for our abduction theory.
Surveillance confirmed that
Michael Wilson left the hotel
at midnight by himself.
LANGSTON:
There had to be
some kind of altercation.
You did see his room.
Yeah, whoever started it
probably finished it
at Mount Charleston.
Ah, whoa.
(laughs deeply)
What do you think?
Creepy.
Yeah.
I do feel powerful.
I feel... you know,
dangerous. Hmm?
I think maybe the reason
these people dress up
like these creatures is to help
them embrace their dark side.
Yeah, yeah, no, I get it.
You kinda scared me
for a minute there.
Okay, okay.
Same contact lens as the one
that we found
in Michael Wilson's room.
They've sold 500 of these
at this convention
in the last two days.
Well, great. That's
impossible to trace.
We'd better hope
DNA comes through.
(sighs): Yeah.
Wow.
Cool eyes. Mom!
I need your credit card.
I think you just turned another
one over to the dark side.
(chuckles)
That's nice... nice...
Remember, you're undead.
Ow.
STOKES:
So you think
it's the neck biting,
the bloodsucking,
or the carnal sex
that's the appeal?
LANGSTON:
It's probably all of the above.
Once you mate,
it's for life.
You know, if it's worth,
uh, living for...
...it's also worth
dying for.
WOMAN (over P.A.):
Wiccans...
bring your best
spells and potions
to the sharing circle,
when the hour strikes...
STOKES:
Whew! That's quite an arsenal.
I didn't realize that vampires
and werewolves needed weapons.
Oh, they don't. You do.
Back to work, honey.
Don't flirt with the dogs.
It's slay or be slayed
out there.
So have you ever
used one of
these weapons to, uh,
slay a vampire yourself?
(chuckles)
If these blades could talk.
No, but seriously,
can I tell
you guys something?
I'm a direct descendant
of the great Van Helsing.
Really?
Yeah. So...
Ridding the world of monsters
is in my blood.
I've seen the evil
they can do.
Killing machines, really.
No conscience, no mercy.
So what kind of weapon
would you recommend
to, say, decapitate
a vampire?
Ooh, I like how you think.
I would go with
the TransVlad 5000.
Top o' the line.
Stainless steel,
leather-wrapped handle,
And how much does
that set you back?
Well, for you young slayers,
I could do...
450 bucks.
Yeah. Kinda steep.
That's a little pricey.
Well, why don't you let
meslashthe price?!
$425, just for today.
We were thinking of something
more along the lines of
the axe or hatchet family?
I get it.
You guys are on
some kind of budget.
You're not yanking
my chain here.
You're not wasting my time?
'Cause I might have to...
(makes slicing noise)
...decapitate you!
I'm just kidding.
Honey, can you get me
the wood axe?
(muttering)
If he doesn't die, he'll-he'll
have to get a tetanus shot.
No, but seriously,
this might
do the trick on your entry-level
blood junkies,
but, uh, no guarantees.
And... (makes stabbing noise)...
no returns.
Heavy head, curved blade
about five inches long.
How many of these
have you sold?
None.
People usually go
for the crossbows,
or the... or the scimitars.
They don't go for something
you could get at Home Depot.
We'll take it.
(laughs):
Oh, man.
Sorry.
That's okay,
this shirt was begging for it.
Recreating the event, I see.
Analyzing tool marks
and blood spatter.
According to Doc Robbins,
Michael Wilson was struck
no less than 18 times.
How many you up to?
About 11.
I keep trying to hit
the same place twice,
but every time I miss,
I have to start over again,
and my hand is killing me.
Want to let me
give it a whack?
All right.
You know my PawPaw used to say
the great thing about wood
is it warms you up twice:
once when you chop it,
and once when you burn it.
(chuckles)
That's my five, your 11,
that makes 16.
I think we shaved a couple
off the killer's total.
Come take a look at this
with me, will you?
The victim was struck
from all sides.
That's very
difficult to do
with a guy
who's chained to a fence.
That would mean the killer
hopped the fence,
so he could take shots
from the other side.
(groans)
Why do that?
We just proved
you can get the job done
standing in the same spot.
Maybe he
didn't know that.
There is another
possibility.
Maybe he
wasn't alone.
HODGES:
That's a hair we found
in your victim's mouth.
Scale patterns
are mosaic.
It's not human.
I ran it against
this exemplar.
Canis lupus.
Wolf hair?
Or, maybe... werewolf.
I have been doing
extensive research.
According to the legend,
vampires enslaved werewolves
during the Trajanic War.
Werewolves revolted, and they've
been mortal enemies ever since.
Like Cain and Abel.
Romulus and Remus.
Tom and Jerry.
I get it.
There were a lot of werewolves
at that convention.
But as scientists, we know
that wannabe werewolves
cannot physically transform
themselves into wolves.
So, where did this
hair come from?
Perhaps one of them
has a four-legged companion.
They say that people
look like their dogs.
Greg's running canine
CODIS right now.
Thank you.
Um, out of curiosity--
uh, will you
and Detective Vartann
be sharing your house
or his?
Really none of your business.
I had love in my grasp,
and I let it slip
through my fingers,
and I don't know if I'll
ever be able to forgive myself.
It's a terrible thing
to wake up to every day.
I'll... keep that in mind.
Your wolf's in the system.
His name's Timber.
WILLOWS:
Hmm, how original.
He was entered into
canine CODIS two years ago,
when his owner assaulted someone
in front of the Tangiers.
Timber, here,
joined in on the fight.
Wolves don't normally
attack humans.
Blame the owner, not the wolf.
Who's the owner?
Kurt Francis.
He's also in the system.
Multiple assaults,
drunk and disorderly, DUI...
SANDERS:
He's registered
at the convention.
He's the leader
of a werewolf pack.
Well, we're looking
for multiple attackers.
SIDLE:
Wolves do hunt in packs.
Maybe werewolves do, too.
(low growls, laughter)
MAN: Get your glasses up.
Come on. Come on.
Looks like we need
another round.
Sorry.
Who's buying
another round?
Yo, yo, check her out.
(howls)
Sorry, guys...
That is a nice
piece of meat. Mm.
MAN: You're right,
Kurtis. Sweet!
How about it, honey?
How about a lap dance?
Whoa, whoa.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Where you going?
Come on!
(indistinct shouts, laughter)
WOMAN:
No! Get your hands off of me!
Come on! Ah!
You're hurting me!
Get your hands off of her.
What do you think you're doing
with that stick, old man?
STOKES:
Relax, relax, relax.
Everybody be cool now.
Be cool now, boys.
Just relax.
Move it along,
old man.
What is that?
Is that wolf hair?
STOKES:
Back up!
The hold I have you in
is called a lateral
vascular hold.
The discomfort you're feeling
is my forefinger
and thumb
constricting your airway,
cutting off the oxygen
to your brain.
(gasping)
You should pass out
right about...
now.
Why don't one of you
take these chains off of me
and give me my vest back?
Well, you can't have it back.
You know,
when I was a kid,
we had a dog,
and when he died
we never once considered
turning him into a jacket.
Eh, never.
Timber was a loyal member
of the pack.
I wanted to keep him with me.
We found some of Timber's hair
in the teeth of a murder victim,
Michael Wilson.
Who?
He was at your convention--
he was of
the vampire persuasion.
Well, I don't hang
with parasites.
Well, you should think about it.
I mean, you have
a lot in common.
You're in the same movies.
LANGSTON:
You know,
there's a creature
in the Philippines
called anaswang.
A what?
Aswang.
It's a half-breed.
Half vampire, half werewolf.
We are nothing like
those bloodsuckers.
There's a reason why
they hide in the dark, you know?
Act like the elite.
Pretend to be, uh...
refined.
You see, us animals...
we're honest.
We follow our instincts.
We give in to our urges.
Like the urge to kill.
We found a contact lens
in Michael Wilson's hotel room.
The DNA says it's yours.
Kurt.
I think you're taking
this mortal enemy thing
a little too far.
Now, where were you
two nights ago?
I don't remember.
There was a full moon,
and I shifted.
You shifted?
When there's
a full moon,
I'mnot as strong,
Ican't control it.
(hits table with cane)
Can you remember where you were
when the sun came up?
I was in my car.
Where was your car?
Self-park garage
at the Mediterranean,
level three.
(quietly):
Good dog.
SIDLE:
This car is a gas guzzler.
You'd think a wolf
would be more
environmentally conscious.
Oh...
I think I know why Kurt Francis
couldn't remember
what happened last night.
That pooch has been
hitting the hooch.
It's not the moonlight
that turns them
into a beast,
it's the moonshine.
SIDLE:
Got some dog collars.
Similar pattern
to the ligature marks.
It's probable
that Kurt and his pack
used these
to restrain
Michael Wilson.
SANDERS:
There's spatter
on the passenger door.
Positive for blood.
The truck might
have been parked
near the fence when
they were killing Michael.
Well, there's blood
in the window well, too.
A lot of it.
The window must have been open.
Then why isn't there any blood
inside the truck,
on the seats?
What is that smell?
Vomit. Is that really what
we're gonna talk about
right now, man?
I'm eating.
Well, you're always eating.
You were saying?
The blood on
Kurt Francis's truck
came back to the vic.
But mixed in with it
were traces of pepsinogen
and hydrochloric acid.
STOKES:
Digestive enzymes.
Yeah, someone drank
Michael Wilson's blood
and then puked it
out the window.
Yeah, Kurt Francis.
No. It did not come back
to Kurt Francis.
Of course-- a vampire.
If we accept the mythology,
werewolves don't drink blood,
vampires do.
So, what was
a vampire doing
in Kurt Francis's truck?
Don't they hate
each other?
Mm-hmm.
I can't tell you
why they were carpooling,
but I can tell you
that the vampire
we're looking for is sick.
Hodges found traces of hematin
and mesoporphyrin
in the vomit.
Both of those are used
to treat porphyria.
It's a blood disorder;
it's also known
as the "vampire disease."
Well, you know,
we had a case
about ten years ago
where the killer had porphyria.
Remember?
She chopped up
her victims and turned them
into protein shakes.
(gags, coughs)
(laughs)
I'm sorry, man.
(coughs)
It's all right.
So we're not
just looking
for a vampire poser.
We're looking
for a sanguinarian.
THOMAS:
By sharing our blood
with Michael,
he takes a part of each
of us into the next world.
It's one in life, one in death.
It's how we honor our dead.
Well, may a stranger
offer a few words?
Uh, no, actually.
Thank you.
Michael lived and died as...
a vampire.
A being hated
for centuries.
Hatred is born of fear,
fear of things
we don't understand.
In medieval times, for example,
when someone saw
a bloated corpse with blood
running from its mouth,
they believed it was a vampire
such as yourselves.
Science now teaches us
that that's just part
of the decomposition process.
It's simply
gasses purging fluids
from the body through the nose
and from the mouth.
This is highly inappropriate
at a memorial service.
STOKES:
You know, you're right, Thomas.
This is a somber occasion,
Dr. Ray.
Maybe we should
lighten things up a little bit.
Maybe we should.
LANGSTON:
What does it say in
the Good Book, Nick?
"Let there be light."
(others gasping)
Science has a way of
revealing other truths
about vampires.
Like... your acute sensitivity
to sunlight.
It's actually
a symptom of a medical condition
called porphyria.
Even...
brief exposure
to sunlight
can cause your skin to...
...burn...
and blister.
STOKES:
The great thing about science
is that it always sheds light
on the subject.
I didn't kill Michael.
When I found him,
he was already dead.
So you thought,
why let all that good blood
go to waste?
You know,
I take offense to that.
You said yourself
that your coven
doesn't drink blood.
No, we don't.
I made an exception
for Michael.
Why?
Because I wanted his soul
to live on through me.
They lured him
to the mountain.
I tried to get there
in time to save him,
but I was too late.
Yeah? Who's "they"?
Wolves.
They had their
noses open that night.
You know, there's only one
problem with your story, Thomas.
You hitched a ride
back to town with the leader
of the wolf pack.
The evidence
tells us
that you and Kurt Francis
killed Michael
together.
See, the thing about
drinking human blood is,
our bodies lack the enzymes
to break it down properly.
It induces vomiting.
I understand
why the werewolves
would want Michael
dead, but...
why wouldheturn against
one of his own?
Maybe Michael
lost faith.
Maybe Michael started to see you
for what you
really are:
a frustrated Web site
designer from London.
Or maybe it was about the girl.
Julie.
You wanted her
all to yourself, didn't you?
I want a lawyer.
LANGSTON:
The yellow contact lens
puts Kurt Francis in
Michael Wilson's hotel room.
Michael's blood
in Kurt's car
puts him at the crime scene
along with Thomas Stewart.
But without the murder
weapon, we can't prove
that either of them
killed Michael.
Right.Butwhen Nick and I
hacked off Jell-O Man's head,
we were covered with blood.
So if Kurt and Thomas
hacked off Michael's head...
The clothes
should prove it.
They should.
♪ ♪
You know, there should be
a lot more blood than this.
WILLOWS:
Could be castoff from
simply being at the scene.
All it proves
is that Kurt and Thomas
were there.
SIDLE:
Well, at theleast,
they were there.
If they only took
one or two swings,
that could account
for the lack of blood.
He was hit with an axe
at least 18 times,
so whether they were just there
or they took a couple of swings,
it means that someone else
took the rest
of the swings.
Yeah. Yeah, another wolf.
Or another vampire.
HODGES:
I admit that a black cloak
does lend a gentleman
a certain kind
of mysterious allure.
There's just one drawback--
it drags along the ground
and collects plenty of trace.
What did you find, David?
Alpine rock butterweed.
It's a flowering herb
that only grows above 2,500 feet
on Mount Charleston
along the south loop trail.
We didn't find any of this stuff
at the crime scene.
Makes me wonder what
else is up there.
SIDLE:
We know that Michael was
running from his attackers.
We know that the chase ended
at the fence.
Where did it begin?
Did you know that a 12-letter
word for "across the woods"
is "Transylvania"?
Grissom?
Is that you, Grissom?
Shut up.
Gil?
I don't think he'd appreciate
you calling him that either.
No, you don't
think so?
I don't.
After all this time.
That's a shame.
All right, here you go.
I'll see you at 2,500.
If you can keep up.
(chuckles)
(groans)
SIDLE:
Alpine rock butterweed.
STOKES:
Mm-hmm.
Big fat tire treads,
consistent with Kurt's
gas guzzler of a truck.
Got something here.
Dirt's been
disturbed.
Another piece.
I know this guy.
That's Kurt Francis.
I can beat that.
Yeah?
I think somebody tried
to bury the hatchet.
STOKES:
This photo was taken
at last year's
convention.
Do you recognize
the werewolf
standing next
to Kurt Francis?
How about now?
Michael Wilson.
He was part
of Kurt's wolf pack?
Looks that way.
I think
Michael was
a wolf who fell for a vampire,
but the only way
he could have her
was to become a vampire himself
and hope
that nobody recognized him
from last year's
convention.
WILLOWS:
Well, someone obviously
recognized him
and that someone
was Kurt Francis.
STOKES:
He followed Michael
to his room, he confronted him,
and he got in his face.
Once a werewolf,
always a werewolf, Michael.
We were brothers.
You betrayed us for one of them!
(grunting)
My guess is that Kurt
went looking for Thomas
to let him know that there
was a traitor in his midst.
And for one night
and one night only,
they joined forces
to kill a common enemy.
Fluorescein green.
Enhances contrast
in latent blood.
Excellent choice.
Thank you.
The handle's
been wiped clean,
but they didn't get
all the blood.
There's some patterns
in the wood.
Huh.
I think I've seen this before.
Look at this.
This is the test axe that Nick
and I used on Jell-O Man.
Hmm.
See the pattern?
Similar markings.
Right.
But not the same.
They came from this.
My, uh, my wedding ring
made a pattern
in blood on the handle.
Kurt Francis wears a ring
that has a wolf insignia.
(camera clicking)
That doesn't look
like a wolf to me.
That's a beautiful
engagement ring.
Thank you.
It's designed to fit
your wedding band, yes?
May I?
And the two halves
become one.
Michael and I liked
the symbolism.
The idea that we'd be
together forever.
Well, we like symbols, too.
They have a way
of making an impression,
especially in blood.
LANGSTON:
When you were swinging
that axe at Michael's head
again and again,
his blood seeped onto
the handle of the axe,
and your ring left behind
an unusual pattern.
You got his blood all over you,
on your clothes, in your hair.
LANGSTON:
CSIs are searching your
hotel room right now.
Even if you washed
your clothes,
even if you
took a shower,
they'll find evidence
of his blood there.
Michael never told you
that he used to be a werewolf,
did he?
How did you find out?
Thomas told Michael and me to
meet him at Mount Charleston for
a pre-wedding ritual.
As soon as we got there,
I knew something was wrong.
Thomas ordered Michael
to hand over
his contacts and his fangs.
What are they doing here?
Michael?
Michael ran
and they ran after him,
and by the time I caught up,
they had chained Michael
to a fence.
(Michael screams)
JULIE:
Stop!
Let me go!
Do something,
help him.
Show her.
MICHAEL:
Don't, stop!
Your beloved
used to be
a werewolf.
Michael said he'd seen me
at the convention last year.
Said he knew we were destined
to be together.
So he changed
who he was because he loved you.
Love built on a lie isn't love.
You can't be someone you're not.
He wasn't one of us.
And that didn't sit
well with anyone.
Did it?
THOMAS:
Traitors must die.
MICHAEL:
Julie, I love you.
It doesn't matter
what side I'm on!
He's not on any side.
He's not one of us,
he's never been one of us,
and he's not
even one of them.
Now, you align yourself
to this man,
that makes you
no better than him.
We're all
watching, Julie.
Choose.
(Michael grunting)
MICHAEL:
Julie.
Julie, this is
all make-believe.
Vampires, werewolves.
None of this
is real.
My love for you--
that's what's real.
We can just walk
away from all this.
Do you really love me?
Yes, with all my
heart, I love you.
That was your mistake.
You can't be you and love me.
No, stop,
don't, no!
(Julie yelling)
If you agree
to testify
against Thomas Stewart
and Kurt Francis,
you may be able to avoid
the death penalty.
I killed Michael.
VARTANN:
Maybe the, uh,
werewolf and vampire
can work out a peace treaty
while they're sharing a cell.
And Julie Crenshaw
will be spending
her honeymoon behind bars.
So much for love.
Well, there's still hope
for the rest of us, I hope.
(chuckles)
You never did give me an answer.
Okay.
Look, if you don't want
to move in together,
you know, I understand.
Lou.
I think that
what we have now
is pretty awesome.
Mm-hmm.
And I just fear
that if we were to
move in together,
we're going to start
to argue about
who forgot to unload
the dishwasher,
all kinds of crap like that.
Besides, we're
both armed.
It could end badly.
(chuckles)
Yeah, but, uh...
I'm willing to risk it.
I'm not.
Can't we just enjoy
what we've got now?
Yeah.
I'll take it.
(ominous music plays)
STOKES:
Man, I saw
this movie when I
was about seven.
Freaked me out.
Really?
Yeah, that particularNosferatu...
(chuckling):
just... scared
me to death.
(both chuckling)
You know,
people invented stories
about werewolves
and vampires
to explain the evil
in the world.
Couldn't believe
that people were capable
of such terrible violence.
Sometimes I can't even
believe it myself.
But I suppose if there were
no evil in the world,
we'd be out of a job.
(beeping)
Speak of the devil.
Triple homicide
at the Tangiers.
(sighs)
Let's go hunt some monsters.