(deep growl)
(thudding)
(footsteps thudding)
(growling)
(rumbling snarl)
(anxious gasping)
(screaming)
(indistinct police radio
communication)
Animal predation.
Coyotes.
Plenty of them out here,
but I didn't see any
when I spotted the body
from the road.
There's no vital response
in the wounds,
so the feast
was postmortem.
And they had plenty
of time to chow down.
Body temp places TOD
four to eight hours ago.
Hey, did you know that
coyotes won't eat the flesh
of crystal
meth users?
Really?
PHILLIPS:
It's true. It's true.
I read it. They can sense
that the stuff is poison.
Well, that places them
at a higher evolutionary mark
than a good deal
of human beings.
What you got, Ray?
Looks like a nylon bag
with some bits of Styrofoam.
I'll get it to Hodges.
There's no wallet,
there's no I.D.
Just his keys.
Anything printed
on the keychain?
If found eaten by animals,
please call...
David.
Sorry. Ink's worn off.
Can you help me roll him?
Sure.
LANGSTON:
Multiple puncture wounds
to the abdomen.
Bullet wounds?
Look at the spacing
of the wounds.
What do you notice?
Well, they're uniform.
That's right.
They're uniform.
So what are you thinking?
The regular spacing,
the curvilinear pattern
of the punctures...
This is what you would
expect from a bite mark.
A bite mark.
From what?
Godzilla.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
Whatever monster
is loose in Vegas,
this so-called bite wasn't
what killed your Desert Doe.
COD was diffuse axonal
injury of the brain,
typically caused by
the sudden deceleration
associated with a car crash,
or a significant fall.
Body stops, brain has momentum,
bad things happen.
As for the, uh,
puncturing implements,
they perforated the skin,
subcutaneous fat,
abdominal muscle,
and the peritoneum.
And they were each at
least three inches long.
And approximately an inch wide,
based on the abrasion rings
around the wounds.
Anything with teeth
and jaws that size
has been extinct for...
65 million years?
True. Uh, that is, for the past
64 million years and 51 weeks.
However, not this week.
The cloth bag that you found
with the little white balls?
The bag is made
of custom spandex,
the balls are expanded
polystyrene foam.
Both, I discovered,
are components used by
an Australian-based
entertainment company
to construct...
simulated muscle.
Simulated muscle
for what?
For possibly the coolest thing
I've ever heard of,
which has been residing
at the Las Vegas Arena
for the past week, and please,
can we just go now?
Please. Go now.
♪ Go now! ♪
♪ Go now. ♪
(footsteps thudding)
(dinosaur bellow,
footsteps thud)
(roars)
(bleats)
(roaring continues)
(roaring)
(birds singing)
Stokes? Sanders?
Detective Reed.
Gardener spotted him
through the window.
Meet Phil Kohler.
His card says
"Investment Strategist,"
the hole in his head
says "exit strategy."
Body temp indicates TOD
was sometime last night.
We didn't find a note,
so no telling what torments
of finance or fairway drove this
country clubber to cash out.
His daughter was murdered.
Excuse me?
Oh, that's right.
Whitney Kohler.
Five years ago.
She and her best friend,
Rachel Beck, they were 15.
Went to the mall together
one day,
never came back.
Couple of days later,
we found Whitney's blood
in a suspect's van.
He's now serving life,
but the bodies were never found.
Yeah, I met Phil
a couple of times.
He and his wife.
Sharon.
Divorce papers.
No stellate tearing
around the wound.
Random powder particles
dispersed all over his face.
So the gun had to have been held
at least a foot or two
away from his head.
It's unusual for suicide.
Looks like he had some
brunette company.
I don't see his wife
in any of these photos, but...
I think she was a brunette.
We've got possible
signs of a struggle.
(grunting)
Phil has the same gold watch on
in every picture.
Well, he's not wearing it now.
Okay.
I'm going to have
a look around the house,
see what else was taken
from this guy.
I bought that watch
for Phil 20 years ago.
Waddled into the jewelry
store nine months pregnant,
maxing out the credit card.
Phil was going
to be a father.
What does the watch have to do
with what happened to Phil?
We didn't find it in his house.
And it's listed among
the disputed possessions
in your divorce paperwork.
I have no idea what happened
to Phil, or his watch.
I haven't spoken
to him in months.
Ms. Kohler, you listed adultery
as the grounds
when you filed for divorce.
Do you have names of any
other women in Phil's life?
Just one.
Carly Beck.
You mean...
the mother of
the other missing girl?
Rachel's mom?
Yeah.
I walked in on them
six months ago.
Shared grief,
Phil called it.
Who knew grief could push
two people together?
I'd only seen it tear
everything apart.
SANDERS:
Using the Glock
that killed Phil Kohler,
I fired a distance
determination pattern.
Found that the muzzle had
to be between 36 to 48 inches
from Kohler's forehead
when fired.
His arm is only 30 inches long.
That's murder.
The gun's unregistered.
Henry...
any luck on
the mystery brunette?
Well, mystery no longer.
The hair was a maternal match
to a known DNA profile.
And it wasn't the wife.
The hair's Carly Beck's.
Carly Beck, LVPD!
Open the door!
Hey, so back at
the vic's house-- my big mouth.
I didn't realize
that you'd known the family.
Ah, it's okay.
Don't worry about it.
'Cause I've been working
on my sensitivity.
Missing daughter's room goes
untouched for five years,
but it's pretty obvious
there's been a few items
removed here recently.
Can you tell what?
There's a new package
of photo paper there.
But I don't see a computer
or printer anywhere.
(Velcro opening)
REED:
Is that Carly's daughter?
I thought you said
the body was never found.
We never found
either one of the girls.
But Carly's daughter
was wearing a gray sweatshirt
when she went missing.
Whitney Kohler
was the one wearing purple.
(recorded birds
twittering, calling)
(door clicks open, then shuts)
Welcome toWalking
with Dinosaurs.
17 life-sized prehistoric beasts
touring the world
in a show
that spans 180 million years
in history in 90 minutes.
I'm the tour manager,
Kyle Adams.
Ray Langston.
And this is David Hodges.
Now I heard you gentlemen
are with the crime lab?
Yes.
How can I help you?
One of them ate a guy.
(laughs):
I'm sorry?
We found a victim who
exhibited some, um,
unique puncture wounds.
We think the injury
may have occurred here.
Do you recognize
this young man?
We'd like to examine
some of the
creatures' mouths.
We're also going
to need to see
a couple of them
fight each other.
No, we're not.
Come on. Please?
Maybe just a little.
(low growling)
(huffs, snarls)
(raspy growls)
(both screeching)
(both snarling,
servomotors whirring)
(quiet huff)
(deep, rumbling growl)
(growling)
(mechanism hisses,
clicks, whirrs)
(clicking, whirring)
(deep growling)
The blood from the T rex's mouth
is definitely human,
and its bottom teeth
match the wounds on our victim.
That doesn't
make sense.
It takes three people
to operate the T rex.
A chassis driver,
a remote operator
to control major movements,
and a second
auxiliary operator.
And the T rex operators know
everyone wants a chance
to manipulate the big beast,
so they lock their control rigs
up after the show.
Nobody was in the arena
after hours?
The entire crew went out for
dinner, then back to our hotel.
Overnight security?
The place was supposed
to be locked up,
but I guess
we were wrong.
(phone ringing)
Excuse me.
This is Langston.
It's Henry.
I got an I.D.
on your Dino Doe.
A Video Spec allowed me
to recreate the text
on the vic's keychain.
It's a logo of the WLVU
paleontology program.
A professor I.D.'d the vic
as Brian Lister,
a student specializing
in herbivorous dinosaurs.
Not a big fan of the predators.
I wonder why.
Anyway, his fiancée is another
student in the program.
We're bringing her in.
Oh, if you need anything,
let me know.
Hodges had to go home sick.
Sick?
(mechanism whirring,
dinosaur purring)
WILLOWS:
We have a broadcast out
on Carly Beck's vehicle.
No known employer.
What do we have from the photo?
Fingerprints on it
belong to both
Carly Beck and
Phil Kohler.
The photo was printed
on the same paper stock that
Nick found in Carly's house.
Yeah, but there was no computer,
printer or camera over there.
Could have been
the items removed
from her daughter's room.
Somehow she printed it;
she brings it to Phil Kohler.
For some reason they struggle,
Phil gets shot, Carly flees.
So if you bring a man a photo
of his dead daughter,
what are you trying to do,
confront him?
Or extort him.
Stolen watch.
She may have been
after money.
We don't know that.
So the bigger question is:
if Carly Beck knows
where Whitney's body is,
does that mean she was
involved in her death?
Eli Holt killed both
of those girls.
Whitney's blood
was in his van.
Mall surveillance
has him circling the lot,
approaching other girls.
But clearly, Carly has some
information that we don't.
And she didn't
share it with us.
You're right.
What about
Carly's daughter Rachel?
If Carly knows
where Whitney's buried,
has she known this whole time
where Rachel is?
No. No, I dealt with Carly
back then,
when her daughter went missing.
Everybody is talking
about the other girl.
Those girls are
best friends.
They went to the mall together.
That man took them both!
Ms. Beck...
Why isn't anybody looking
for my daughter?!
Because we're not
the ones with money?!
Because we're not the ones
who know people?!
No. Now, I go 110%
on every case,
but all I can work with
is the evidence,
and there's only evidence
of Whitney in that man's van.
Listen, I'm doing everything
I can, I promise...
That isn't enough!
(knocking on glass)
I've analyzed the photo
of Whitney Kohler.
The victim exhibits
skeletonization
and mummified tissue.
It's consistent
with our hot, dry climate.
If she was killed
five years ago,
it's possible
Whitney Kohler's been in
this state of decomposition
the past four and a half years.
The photo could have been taken
any time in that span.
The entire time
Holt's been in prison.
Holt could have told anyone
where that body's buried.
A visitor, another inmate.
We got to go talk to him.
BRASS:
Well, Eli Holt's in a coma.
Attempted suicide ten days ago.
Why now?
What set him off?
I don't know.
The prison guards certainly
didn't have any idea.
But the prison sent over
his communication record.
It turns out
that Carly Beck
was writing him
a lot of letters.
But there's no indication
that Holt ever responded.
"Dear Mr. Holt,
"I'd do anything for you
if you'd just tell me
where my Rachel's body is"?
Yeah, there's
a lot of that.
Okay, help me figure this out.
Holt attempts suicide.
Ten days later, the father of
one of his victims gets killed,
after being shown a picture
of his dead daughter
by the other victim's mother.
Right.
What are we missing?
SANDERS: There was more to the
picture of Whitney Kohler.
I enhanced a billboard
in the distant background.
A rep for the
advertising company
told me that this real estate
agent recently placed
five of the same signs
around Vegas.
Any in a rural location
like the photo?
Just one.
On Highway 16,
near mile marker 20.
I was thinking Nick and I
can head out there, visually
recreate the distance from
and vantage of the billboard
in the photo.
We might find something.
(sighs)
(camera clicking)
Based on her broken hyoid,
C.O.D. was strangulation.
Mm-hmm.
But that wasn't all
her killer did to her.
He severed two of her fingers,
partially severed a third.
An abandoned attempt
to obscure her identity.
Or she was tortured.
Well, whatever
the twisted impetus,
I can tell you
the twisted implement.
Width of the kerf mark
on the bone was approximately
30,000ths of an inch wide.
That correlates to
a hacksaw or a band saw.
But the consistency and
directionality of the cut
has me leaning
toward band saw.
Band saw's a heavy
piece of equipment.
Fixed in one place.
Where could Holt have had access
to a saw like that?
So no one was looking
for a band saw five years ago,
but I reinterviewed
Eli Holt's cousins,
and they told me
about this place.
Belonged to Eli's Uncle Bill.
He died four years ago.
Went into probate, no takers.
Yeah, yeah, I interviewed
the uncle during
the investigation.
He was practically
on his death bed.
Said he hadn't seen Eli
in like ten years.
Family falling out.
But Eli used to come here
as a kid,
work with his uncle
in the wood shop.
With his uncle sick,
five years ago
maybe Eli came back with
some projects of his own.
And we've got a primary.
You think Uncle Bill
had any idea
what Eli was doing out here?
Just left
all this evidence behind?
No, I doubt it.
He was probably sneaking
his victims in at night.
Meant to come back
and clean all this stuff up,
but got caught before
he could get around to it.
Yeah. Nobody's been
out here since.
I remember when the girls
first went missing.
It was one of my first weeks
out in the field.
It wasn't even my case,
but I felt like
I should have been doing
something more to help.
Yeah, well, some cases it never
feels like you're doing enough.
These tools are ancient,
except for this shovel.
It's got a
fiberglass handle.
Holt could have purchased it
to bury Whitney.
And Rachel, too.
Brian was so excited to take me
toWalking with Dinosaurs
last night.
And the show was amazing.
Just to see our beloved
Brachiosaurus come to life.
(dinosaurs bleating)
With its long
and graceful neck
and its gentle energy.
What happened after the show?
Brian took me back to my dorm.
And that's the last
I saw of him.
But we were going to
build a life together.
We were going to travel
the world,
learning the lessons
of the great leaf-eaters.
Jane, um,
the crew from
Walking with Dinosaurs
sent over some video
of last night's show.
I was able to find
you and Brian in the crowd.
Now...
you didn't mention
this part of the evening.
ANNOUNCER:
Ladies and gentlemen,
Tyrannosaurus rex!
(crowd cheering)
I didn't think it was relevant.
(roaring)
Ladies and gentlemen,
Tyrannosaurus rex!
I'm gonna go forage
for some vegan concessions.
I couldn't take my eyes
off that hideous beast.
Its obscene jawline.
Its throbbing musculature.
You know, the T rex
was so active,
so relentlessly physical,
that it may have been
one of the few dinos
whose blood pumped... warm.
(crowd cheering,
dinosaur roaring)
Who is this guy?
I don't know.
And it doesn't matter.
I was swallowed up
by the carnivorous moment.
But it was just a moment.
Because Brian and the other
long-necked herbivores--
those are my true loves.
Yeah...
22 pounds of
bite force.
Same as the animatronic
T rex's jaws.
So did you get this at
the toy store or, uh...?
Actually, it's on loan
from an old colleague at WLVU.
(chuckles)
All right, let's see.
Barely wounded.
That means a bite
from the T rex
couldn't have caused
Brian Lister's wounds.
But Brian's blood was
in the mouth of the T rex,
and the bottom teeth are
a perfect match to his wounds.
All right, so if
the creature couldn't have
bitten Brian with
sufficient force, then...
It was staged or additional
force would have
had to have come
from somewhere else.
Let's say that Brian supplied
the additional force.
He brought the momentum
to the monster.
Correct.
Doc Robbins said
his brain injuries
were consistent with a fall.
And since his back
was scavenged,
we don't actually know if
he had any injuries on his back
from the upper teeth.
He may have simply fallen
onto the lower teeth.
Well, if that's the case,
then he would've fallen
from some great height.
These are the parked positions
of the dinosaurs
in which they stand overnight.
Got some fibers in her lip.
It's the same blue and yellow
from our victim's shirt.
How could he have
gotten up there?
Same way I did.
If Brian snuck in,
and the crane was here,
fall from this height
certainly would've
gotten the job done.
(screaming)
Question is:
what made him fall?
Phil Kohler's watch.
Got a hit on
the pawnshop registry.
Shop owner said he bought it
off a lady around noon,
confirmed that it was Carly Beck
off of a photo.
How much money did he give her?
1,500 bucks for the watch.
He also said she came in
a week ago.
Sold him five G's
worth of stuff.
A truck and
all this junk.
This has got to be
from Rachel's bedroom.
Scavenging through
her dead daughter's room,
blowing through five grand
in a week
and coming back for more?
What is Carly Beck into?
She brought something
else in today.
Camera.
Pawnbroker said that
she was begging him
to buy an old computer,
printer and her car, too,
but he passed.
Car? You should...
I've already got
calls going out
to used car dealers in the area,
seeing if she's trying
to unload it.
She ditched
the memory card.
Everything must go.
Catherine, I got the DNA
results from the wood shop.
The blood contributions
were from both girls,
on the saw and
on the floor.
Okay. Well, we just got a hit
on Carly Beck's vehicle.
She sold it 15 minutes ago
to a used car lot for cash
and then just
walked away from the lot.
Well, she couldn't have
gotten that far on foot.
Patrol's canvassing
the area.
(kids chattering playfully)
(siren whoops)
Police!
It's my last chance!
(panting)
(sobbing):
It's my last chance!
OFFICER:
It's okay, ma'am.
(handcuffs clicking)
OFFICER:
It's all right, ma'am.
It's my last chance!
CARLY:
I didn't kill Phil Kohler.
BRASS:
Come on, you were with him.
You ripped off his watch.
Come on.
That's not what...
I-I didn't kill him.
You know me.
I do.
Tell us about the letter, Carly.
I'd been writing to
Eli Holt, begging him
to tell me where
my daughter was.
And for the first time ever,
he wrote back.
He said he remembered
where the girls were buried,
but he didn't remember
which girl was in which grave.
He'd sell me the maps.
$5,000 for one map.
$10,000 for both.
If I told the cops,
the deal was off.
I'd never find her.
You pawned everything you could
to get enough
for one map.
But it was the wrong one,
wasn't it?
CARLY:
When my Rachel went missing,
she was wearing
a gray sweatshirt.
Whitney was
the one wearing purple.
You snapped photos of her body.
You left her out there
in the desert.
What, you just didn't think
to tell anybody?
I told Phil.
I don't know
what you're doing here.
I can't see you anymore.
It's about the girls!
It always is.
But you and I
need to move on with our lives,
and that's not gonna happen.
I know where Whitney's buried.
I-I just need $5,000, and
then I can find Rachel, too.
I just, I thought you
could lend me the money,
and then we'd both
have our girls!
Carly, Carly!
Whoever's telling you that
is lying to you.
You know how many false leads
we've gotten.
They're just preying on you.
No, it's...
No, it's real, Phil!
I just need the money.
It's just another scam.
I'm calling the police.
No! No, no.
Don't call the police!
You're just going to get
your heart broken again.
Get what you can for it.
Because I can't do this anymore.
BRASS:
And all this happened
the night before
Phil was killed?
After Phil's, I went home.
The phone rang.
MAN:
I'm a friend of Eli's.
Want to know
how the map worked out.
It wasn't my daughter.
I want to know
where my daughter is.
Eli told you the deal.
It's five K.
Same locker at the park.
Sunset Friday
or the deal's killed.
I can't get another $5,000.
I-I went to Whitney's dad.
He-He didn't believe me;
he thinks it's a scam.
But I know it's not.
(line clicks)
Hello? Hello?
CARLY:
Honey, Whitney's here.
You going to the mall?
(disconnect tone
beeping over phone)
Please, just get that monster
to tell me where my daughter is.
When'd you get the first map?
Holt sent it to me
three days ago.
Eli Holt has been in a coma
for ten days.
Then who have I been talking to?
Who knows where my daughter is?
LANGSTON: Of course,
it's a little more primal
when you're perfect strangers.
(dinosaur growls,
dramatic music plays on video)
But when you use your credit
card to pay for your ticket,
you don't remain a stranger
to us, not for very long.
Travis Kilborn,
seat 42A.
And, of course,
you knew Jane Lewis
long before that enchanted
prehistoric evening.
You both attend
the same
college paleontology program
with only 12 other students.
You lied to me, Jane.
So here's what we have.
We have dirt in the
tires of your car.
We have blood in
the backseat.
We have your prints on the
Brachiosaurus controls.
So which one of you is going
to tell me what happened?
One of you had better speak up.
(sighs heavily)
Brian just wanted a picture.
The three of us went
to the show.
Had a few drinks afterwards,
and thought it'd be cool
to sneak back into the arena.
You guys, I need a picture
with the Brachiosaurus.
Jane, bring it closer.
Closer.
Move it!
(laughs)
This is awesome.
Closer, closer, closer.
TRAVIS:
It was an accident.
BRIAN:
Take a picture.
Closer. Closer.
Closer, closer, closer.
Little bit more.
(grunts)
(screaming)
TRAVIS:
He was still alive.
Pushed himself off the teeth,
then fell all the way
to the floor.
Brian!
Brian.
(quietly):
Oh, God.
Here. Here.
Put this on him.
All right.
All right, put this over him.
Put this over him!
Yeah...
He was my friend.
Then why not call 911?
Why dump the body?
I panicked.
I thought we'd be
in trouble.
I know it was an accident,
but we were trespassing.
I'm sorry.
We found one other
thing in your car.
A burger wrapper
with lipstick on it.
We, uh, stopped at a place
after we left the desert.
Jane was starving.
For red meat.
They were out of veggie burgers.
Jane, are you sure
you accidentally
knocked Brian out of the crane,
or was a future with him
simply not going
to satisfy your appetite?
I want a lawyer.
STOKES:
So the mail room confirmed
that the Holt letter
and map
was stamped
with their postage machine,
but the postmark indicates
that it was sent
from outside the prison.
Well, probably avoiding
the prison mail screening.
The handwriting on the documents
doesn't even match Holt's.
You know, he could have told
another inmate
where the bodies are buried.
Maybe they're trying to cash in.
Well, the CO supervisor says
that Holt wasn't a talker.
He kept to himself,
mostly.
Open that up,
will you?
(sighs)
He have any visitors?
No, no.
No visitors.
Apparently,
the most exciting day
of his week was his, uh,
tripto the canteen.
STOKES:
Oh, yeah?
What did he buy there?
(clears throat)
On his last shopping spree,
he bought:
couple of candy bars,
bottle of soda
and a notepad.
Well, here's a yellow notepad.
It looks like the top
three sheets are missing.
So he buys a notepad
on the morning
of the day he tries
to kill himself?
And what kind of guy writes
a three-page suicide note?
You can get that done
with one sheet.
Okay, so a note and two maps.
Well, according to the, uh,
responding officer,
Jason Richter,
there was no suicide note.
Was the officer alone
when he responded?
That's a confirm.
We better go round him up.
Jason Richter!
LVPD. Open up.
(alarm beeping)
Take the back.
Hey! Hey!
Get down,
or I will end you.
(alarm beeping)
It's the second map!
12 bucks an hour
to have everything
that comes out of those animals
flung at me?
(grunting, gasping)
RICHTER:I shouldn't have been
so quick to help him.
(grunting)
I thought the maps might be
to some buried loot.
(grunting stops)
Requesting rush medical
to cell 105.
You knew those maps
led to two dead children,
and you still found a way
to make a buck.
It was just that lady's
crap luck
the first map
wasn't her daughter.
Hey... Holt's note
didn't say which map was which.
I gave her a fair shot at it.
A fair shot?
You took Carly Beck
for five grand.
CARLY:
I can't get another $5,000.
I-I-I went to Whitney's dad.
He... he didn't believe me;
he thinks it's a scam.
BRASS:
You knew she wouldn't tell.
You couldn't be so sure
about Phil Kohler.
So you had to silence him.
(crickets chirping)
Who the hell are you?
The time you spent
burning that lady's last
chance to find her daughter,
you should have spent
burning your shirt.
We found it
in your crawl space
with Phil Kohler's
blood on it.
That puts the gun in your hand.
I bet you're wondering how
a guy with so many maps
in front of him can
be so damn lost.
Well, I think I can
help you find your way.
Hodges analyzed the shovel
you found at the primary.
Found something interesting
lodged between the blade
and the handle--
a clump of Bermuda grass seed,
with trace of fertilizer,
a tackifier and green dye.
Now, that particular formula
was unique to only one
hydro-seeding company that was
operating five years ago.
So I went and got a list
of all the projects
they were working on
around the time
of Rachel Beck's disappearance.
One of those locations
was the intersection
of Briarwood Road
and Lowell Road.