♪ ♪
(chopping in time with music)
(banging in time with music)
(man gasping and groaning)
(choking)
(man coughing and gagging)
The truck was headed
to the landfill.
When it passed through
the security gate,
the guard noticed a suspicious
ooze leaking out of the back,
so he notified
the driver.
The driver jumped out,
checked it out and called us.
What is the code
for suspicious ooze?
6-6-6.
Well, at least
the primordial variety--
the stuff of creation,
Heaven and Hell.
Yeah, I'll take "Hell"
for $500, please, Alex.
Is this, your, uh, "ooze"?
Yep.
(truck horn blasts)
MAN: Hey! Shut it down!
Shut it down!
STOKES:
Looks like blood.
(inhales)
Smells like blood.
Okay. Open it up.
STOKES:
Possible body parts.
Looks like it's been
put through a cheese grater.
This is some kind of
hardcore shredding, boys.
Hey.
"Cafe Perka."
Cappuccino machine.
I was thinking about
buying one of these.
Piece of a
steel-belted radial?
Bicycle bell.
(dull ring)
Guess the rest of the bicycle's
in there somewhere.
What do you make of that?
Credit card?
Looks like it used
to be a credit card.
A chopped-up rubber tire,
a coffee maker,
and a cheese-grated body--
if that's what this is.
Not something you see every day.
Here's looking at you, kid.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
(machine whirring
and grinding loudly)
Well, that's one way
to clear a paper jam.
Prototype failed.
It jammed before
it made it to market.
The business
made us destroy it.
You guys said something
about body parts?
STOKES: Yeah. We found
some in a truck
headed for the landfill.
It was mixed in with
a lot of shredded stuff,
much like what comes
out of your machine.
Truck's manifest
led us here.
Got to be some mistake.
Company sends us all kinds
of material to shred.
Electronics,
appliances, apparel,
prototypes,
rejects, recalls.
Hey, somebody has to lose
the Super Bowl, right?
All those hats
and t-shirts--
"We're Number One!"
This is where they turn
out to be number two.
(laughs)
Does that
include bodies?
No. We don't shred people.
Maybe someone fell in.
Well, we've got
cameras everywhere.
Not to mention OSHA.
Someone so much
as gets a paper cut,
gotta shut down.
You're gonna have to shut
it down right now, boss.
We need to take
a look at it.
We want to talk to everybody
who worked that night shift.
Plus we're going
to need to see
what your "eyes" saw.
You guys
got a warrant?
Hey, got one
right here.
You can, uh, shred it
when we're done.
Except for
the big stuff,
most clients send their
material in padlocked bins.
They fill them up
at their offices,
arrange secure transport,
we take care of the rest.
That's it; that's the
whole graveyard shift.
Like I said,
no one fell in.
Well, maybe they
didn't have to.
Padlocked bins,
secure transport...
if I was going
to get rid of a body,
seems like a good way to go.
♪ ♪
(heavy sigh)
(groans)
All this came from the one
truck with the body parts?
Yeah. Looks like
we're in for a long day.
Did you really
sign up for this?
Yeah, as my recent brush
with T-Rex confirms,
the exhilaration
of field work
is the only thing that
gets me out of my head.
Still got Wendy
on your mind, huh?
Yeah.
Believe me, I get it.
Two ships passing-- takes
a while for the fog to clear.
I know what
you need, H.
Good night out
on the town.
Yeah.
When?
All right, guys, we got
paper, plastic, metal,
yuck...
let's call it, shall we?
I got "yuck."
♪ ♪
Oh, Lady Catherine.
Always a delight.
Somebody's in
a good mood.
Well, I enjoy a good puzzle
now and again,
and this one
is grade "A."
You seem in a good mood,
yourself.
You have a... certain glow.
Hodges opened his big mouth.
Detective Vartann's a good man.
Can we, uh...
get to the goo?
I, uh, sent representative
samples to DNA.
We'll see what we get.
Obviously,
the body's too mangled
to determine much.
Weight of the parts
suggests that we're looking
at only one unfortunate soul.
I took a tissue sample.
Put your nose down the scope.
I'll give you a tour.
ROBBINS: Tissue's autolyzed,
with a lack of nuclear detail.
Presence of saprophytic bacteria
started the decomp.
Our victim was DBS.
DBS?
Dead Before Shred.
Time of death's
approximately 36 to 48 hours
before the indignity
of this dice and slice.
C.O.D.?
Well, a portion
of the cranial bone
shows a hint of a beveled edge.
Are you thinking entry wound?
More than thinking.
I also found this.
Ooh.
Bullet frag.
It stuck around.
Greg found bullet
fragments in the grind
from the shredder.
We'll run everything
through ballistics,
see what we find.
♪ ♪
Everything all right?
Huh? Oh, yeah.
Uh, yeah, I'm fine.
You been swimming?
(chuckles)
Oh, uh, shower.
We just went
through a truckload
of garbage and
dead body.
I, um... I still smell,
don't I?
You don't want an
answer to that.
Found a credit card--
well, a piece of one.
Very similar to the one that
you pulled out of the trash
last night,
am I right?
Looks like it.
There were several in
the shredder mix, and these were
more finely diced
than the others,
and Hodges thought that
it merited a closer look.
Is he, uh, running it
through trace?Yeah.
You sure you're all right?
Fine.
Oh. You, uh...
dropped your bean.
(sighs)
SANDERS:
DNA on our D.B. came back.
Confirms one source.
No hits in CODIS.
So far, all we have is an
unidentified white male.
Well, we knew I.D. on this guy
wasn't going to be easy.
He's in a thousand pieces.
Pieces may be all
that we need
as long as they're
the right ones.
I ran trace
on the credit card shards
that G and I found
in the shredder mix.
G?
They were bathed
in high concentrations
of hydrochloric acid,
potassium chloride,
and sodium chloride.
Stomach acid.
Along with
magnesium, potassium,
beta carotene,
zinc and
some essence
of Mercenaria mercenaria.
Spit it out, H.
Quahog clams.
Apparently,
the shards were part
of a not-so-delightful
Manhattan clam chowder.
So what you're saying is, our
victim ate his credit cards?
Or someone made him eat them.
It's like straight out
of an old Mob movie.
You can't pay up, so eat up.
Bullet in the head
for dessert.
Well, we didn't find
enough pieces to reconstruct
the name and number
as it appears on the card, but
we may not have to, because...
we have this.
The magnetic stripe.
Cardholder's
name and number
is encoded repeatedly, along
the length of the stripe.
Yeah, all we need is
a section of it.
Our victim's last supper
may tell us who he is.
(beeping)
(trilling)
Larry LaMotte?!
No way!
You know this guy?
Well, yeah, if it's
the--Larry LaMotte.
Haven't you've seen
his online ads?
Mm-mm.
"How much would you pay
"for peace of mind?
Protect your identity
with I.D.-Preserve."
He owns a credit
protection service.
For a monthly fee,
they help protect
your identity.
I just signed
up last month.
Since when do you worry
about identity theft?
Every aspect of our
life has been reduced
to binary code, Nick.
All we are
is zeroes and ones.
Easy pickins.
My name is Larry LaMotte, and
I want to ask you a question.
How much would you pay
for peace of mind?
Well, the next few minutes
may answer that question and...
it may change your life.
So, we checked
Larry LaMotte's house.
No one home, and all his calls
went to voicemail.
That's not a good sign.
Good morning, gentlemen.
How can I help you?
I'm Detective James Brass,
Las Vegas Police.
This is Dr. Ray Langston
from the crime lab.
We're looking for Larry LaMotte.
Oh, I'm sorry.
He's not available.
May I ask
what this is concerning?
And you are?
Oh. Elaine Travers.
I'm his executive assistant.
Gentlemen, I'm Julius Kaplan.
I'm Mr. LaMotte's
Head of Security.
Is there a problem?
No, no problem, Julius.
We think your boss
may be dead,
so we need to ask
a few questions.
There must be some
misunderstanding.
Mr. LaMotte is on vacation.
Where?
At an undisclosed location,
where, unfortunately,
he can't be reached.
I'll say.
It's okay, Julius.
I can handle this.
Who are you?
I'm Larry LaMotte.
My name is Larry LaMotte, and
I want to ask you a question.
How much would you pay for...?
You're Larry LaMotte?
Yes.
Now, did I hear
you gentlemen correctly?
I'm dead?
You look younger on TV.
Better-looking, too, right?
Marketing 101.
(chuckles)
You got something to sell,
hey, get someone pretty
to sell it, right?
And who is the man in
front of the camera?
Wesley.
Works in the mailroom.
Yeah, he can't string
two sentences together, but
put a script in front of him,
suddenly, he's Brando.
So, gentlemen,
what about this dead thing?
Well, as I was, uh,
telling Mr. Kaplan,
we found a body
shot in the head.
Someone had force-fed
him credit cards.
The credit cards
were in your name.
My name?!
Uh, I-I don't understand.
Have your credit cards
been lost or stolen?
Did you know
that every 79 seconds,
someone has
their identity stolen?
It can take years,
thousands of dollars
to get your good name back.
LANGSTON:
Mr. LaMotte,
if someone has
stolen your identity,
and that person
has ended up dead,
that raises some serious
questions for us.
Like what?
BRASS:
Well, if someone
stole your identity,
it can't be good for business.
I'm the victim here, Detective.
Our company has thousands
of subscribers.
Corporate clients
who depend on us
to protect their data,
their intellectual property.
This company made
$120 million last year.
KAPLAN: In other words,
why would we risk all that
in order to go after
some penny-ante
credit card thief?
Well, that raises
the possibility
that whoever murdered
our victim thinks
they killed
the real Larry LaMotte.
Do you have any
enemies, Larry?
Thousands.
Like you, I make it my mission
to stop criminals.
You wear a badge,
I wear the trust
of every client
who pays $19 a month
to make sure that I'm watching.
It'd be a lot easier
if you just got us a list.
Elaine!
The officers would like
to take a look
at our offenders
files.
And please get
two subscription
packages ready.
Don't worry.
Our brothers
in law enforcement
get a discount.
STOKES:
Larry LaMotte had a lot
of enemies,
but they're all his clients.
Yeah, I see a couple
of thousand have filed
consumer complaints.
Yeah, subscribers claimed
that instead
of protecting their identities,
the company stole them.
Credit card numbers
found their way to Nigeria.
And we know what happens in
Nigeria doesn't stay in Nigeria.
I.D.-Preserve passed it off
as "an unfortunate
security breach."
But one guy didn't buy
that excuse.
Lee Devries, 34.
Machinist.
He drove a truck
right through the window
of I.D.-Preserve.
Starts waving a gun around,
demanding face-time
with Larry LaMotte.
Six months in County.
He got out four weeks ago.
His first job out
of the joint-- working at
a temp agency that supplies
workers to the shredder company.
Sounds like somebody
worth talking to.
I'll call Brass.
Nicky?
Yeah.
Were you planning
on telling me that, uh,
you stopped seeing
the departmental shrink?
Oh, I didn't think
it was a big deal.
I went my mandatory two times.
I thought
that we talked about this.
We did. I went.
That's it? You're done?
Look, I've been getting
in the gym,
I've been eating right,
getting good sleep.
Healthy body,
healthy mind, right?
(sighs)
Catherine...
I can't sit in a room
and talk about how I feel
from one minute to the next.
It's just not my thing.
Sure about that?
Positive.
BRASS:
So, Lee,
where you been
the last 72 hours?
Huh?
Run into Larry LaMotte
by any chance?
I'm gonna make
this simple.
Have you put any bodies
into any shredders lately?
All right, stand up.
Stand up! Stand up!
Back up.
Sit over there.
All right, look...
I'm going to be you.
A more cooperative you.
All right, Detective,
all right.
I'll tell you what happened.
Now you know that I ran
into Larry LaMotte.
You know my history with him.
I got jammed up,
and I got arrested.
But as luck would have it,
I got a second chance at him.
I gathered up
that bastard, right?
I jammed credit cards
down his throat.
I took out my gun,
I popped a cap
right in his brain,
and I took that mess
that used to be
Larry LaMotte,
and you know what?
I didn't know
what to do with it, so,
I put it in-in the shredder
at my work.
That was the end
of Larry LaMotte. Done.
Questions?
I don't know
what you're talking about.
That's not a question.
The guy destroyed my life.
I signed up with
I.D.-Preserve
'cause I was scared somebody
was going to steal my identity.
And the next thing I know, I got
loans taken out in my name,
I got mortgages, I got debts
I can't even begin to pay.
Hell, they even
repossessed my truck
right there
in that scumbag's window.
You got an alibi?
Six of 'em.
Thanks to Larry LaMotte,
there's a half dozen guys
running around out there
saying they're me.
You running
the credit card
we found in the
D.B.'s stomach?
Yeah.
On the computer in the bullpen.
Those are my numbers
on my computer.
I'm checking
my purchases.
Ever since that whole
I.D.-Preserve thing
went shady,
I got a little paranoid.
There are plenty of legit
companies doing this, but...
I can't believe that I trusted
those guys.Yeah.
It's like that friend that
you meet in science camp,
and you find that you have
all the same interests,
and you like to go to
all the same movies,
and do all the
same things, and
then one day,
he offers to give you a haircut.
And you need one,
so you figure, why not?
And then he starts
showing you
this sketchbook, and swears
that he's done nude drawings
of all his friends.
Hodges...
It's not the same.
Oh, of course not, no.
I'm... I'm sorry, G.
I'm just feelin' ya.
So, is this, uh,
bullet fragment
telling you a story?
Once upon a time, a cranium met
a nine-by-19 millimeter
Parabellum round.
The end.
I found this other fragment
in the mix.
SANDERS: It's tarnished,
encased in fibrous tissue.
Looks old.
The fragments from the bullet
that went through Shredder Guy's
head show polygonal rifling,
consistent with a Glock.
Now, this other
fragment has
conventional rifling.
So, the older fragment
is from a different gun.
Right, but could still
come from the same victim.
How?
A previous incident.
It shows signs
of encapsulation.
Over time,
the body's defense mechanism
encapsulates the frag in tissue
to protect against infection.
So far, we have nothing
to identify our shredder guy.
Maybe this shred
of evidence will help.
It's at least worth
a good cleaning.
So we sorted through
the shredded items
in the load with our dead body,
and discovered something.
Most of it can be traced
back to one place.
Let me guess:
I.D.-Preserve.
So, I'm thinking, maybe
the body is in one
of these bins that I.D.-Preserve
uses to send stuff
to the shredder.
And maybe our friend Larry
LaMotte's hands aren't so clean.
Well, I bet that
he would say
that when these bins
left his office,
there was no body inside.
Which is why
I did some checking.
I.D.-Preserve uses
a subcontractor
to handle transport
of its bins.
Guess who runs that company?
Larry LaMotte's
head of security.
Julius Kaplan.
Mm-hmm.
Let's light 'em up.
♪ ♪
SIDLE:
Oh, that's a lot of blood.
I think
we just found our smoking bin.
I traced the credit card
from our victim's stomach.
Card was mailed to a P.O. box
in Gallup, New Mexico.
Which I'm guessing was under
a phony name and address.
Still, sounds like we found
where our identity thief's from.
Guy's pulling
an old-school fraud.
New school stuff
is way more high-tech.
I, uh, pulled
the purchase records
for our man from Gallup.
He bought a ticket
here to Vegas.
Once in town, he made a series
of small-time purchases.
Lucky for us, he wasn't shy.
WILLOWS: Maybe now
our shredder guy has a face.
I'm running
facial recognition,
usual databases: military, DMV.
Hey. Langston and I just
found blood in one of the bins
from I.D.-Preserve.
It is a match
to Shredder Guy.
We can't touch
Larry LaMotte,
but we can go after the man
who touched the bins.
Julius Kaplan!
Las Vegas Police!
Mitch!
♪ ♪
SIDLE (over radio):
We got a body.
End of the line
for Julius Kaplan.
We found where Shredder
Guy had his last meal.
Maybe who served it up
to him, too.
I got a feeling our friend here
did some bad in the world.
Maybe somebody
conjured up some payback.
Liver temp is 78.5.
Puts time of death
at approximately 5:00 p.m.
SIDLE:
Nice place, huh?
Value just dropped
another ten percent.
(laughs)
Single shot, back to front.
Slight upward trajectory.
Round exited out the front.
Fly ball to left...
going...
Caught at the warning track.
A baseball reference.
Charming.
Blame Grissom.
Looks like a .45 auto.
Six lands and grooves,
left-handed twist.
Consistent with a Colt pistol.
Stellate tearing
around the entry.
Could be soot.
Maybe some partially-burned
black powder in the wound track.
Huh.
Contact wound.
Killer put the gun
right up to his head.
High-velocity spatter.
There's an odd void
in the pattern.
Hey, who wants a beer?
I do.
Our host has a fridge full
in his kill room.
Also found
this Glock,
and that's consistent
with the gun
that killed Shredder Guy.
What about Julius here?
Well, the bullet that went
through Kaplan's head says
it's a different gun
that killed him.
The neighbors
across the street
have a surveillance camera.
We might get lucky.
I think I just found our void.
STOKES:
Looks like a match to me.
There's no sign
of forced entry.
Guy's sitting by the pool.
Killer brings
him a beer.
Gets close enough
to put a gun to his head.
(gunshot)
Kaplan knew his killer.
Sure did.
LaMOTTE:
Seeing as this
is a courtesy interview,
uh, I assume counsel is not
necessary, but, uh, I would like
a record of the conversation.
Make sure
you take down every word.
Yes. Yes, sir.
LANGSTON:
I take it you've heard
the news
about your Head of Security,
Julius Kaplan?
Yes, I have.
And I am deeply saddened.
He was a good man.
He was hard worker.
He was a stand-up guy.
BRASS:
Well, not at the end.
As a matter of fact,
not at the beginning,
either, actually.
No, no.
But I get the feeling
that you knew about that.
BRASS:
So, we ran some prints.
Your head of security,
Julius Kaplan--
whose real name, by the
way, is Julius Kirsch,
also known as Julius Child.
And he got that nickname because
he used to be a Mob collector
who would make dinner
for his victims.
But he would always add
an extra ingredient,
you know.
Ground-up casino chips,
a chopped-up
credit card.
Needless to say, I'm shocked.
We were also able to put a face
to our mystery man
from the shredder.
Never seen
him before.
He was dumped
into a shredder
from one of your shred bins.
Well, I wouldn't know anything
about that.
As you know, Julius dealt
with the shredding company.
That's convenient.
Gentlemen, I lost
the same friend today twice.
Obviously, Julius wasn't the
man that I thought he was.
Now, whatever wrongs
he did-- that's on him.
I take this
as a learning experience.
You know, it's like
I say in my seminars.
Assuming someone's
name is easy.
Assuming control
of your life-- that's hard.
JOHNSON: I'm checking the
surveillance cam footage
Nick got from the neighbor
who's across the street
from Larry LaMotte's
security guy.
Julius Kaplan.
Good news is, even though
the camera's angled away
so we can't
see the driver,
we do have an image
of a car leaving the scene
around the time
of Julius' murder.
The bad news is that
another car's passing
at the same time,
which obscures our view.
It's not a lot to work with, but
I might be able
to work a little magic.
STOKES:
Hey, Catherine?
Stay with it.
Yeah.
Ballistics confirms
that the Glock I found
on top of the
can of clams
was the gun that
killed Shredder Guy.
Oh, we liked
the French Chef for the deed.
No, Sara called
that one right.
It just wasn't the gun
that killed Julius.
Hmm.
That was a Colt
.45 pistol.
And that gun
has a history.
Slug matches a robbery/shooting
in Reno six years ago?
Yeah, some guy was found
in a Dumpster, barely alive.
Paramedics rushed him
to the E.R.
72 hours later, he just walks
out of the hospital, vanishes.
John Doe.
So, Reno P.D. sent over
the cold case file.
Here is his shirt
from the E.R.
These frags have some fuzz
on them.
Nobody's perfect.
Kind of looks like a Chia Pet.
Hmm. Cartridge case
from the shooting.
Weren't able
to pull a print, though, huh?
No, the only good thing
about a case going cold is
that technology
has a chance to catch up.
Might get something now.
Okay, so we've got two
shootings, six years apart.
Julius Kaplan
and a John Doe in an alley
shot with a
Colt pistol.
There's got
to be a connection somehow.
WILLOWS: Let's clean up
these frags, see what we get.
♪ ♪
All right,
let me get this straight.
A partial bullet fragment from
a previous injury lodged inside
Shredder Guy
is a perfect match
to a round found
in a John Doe
six years ago?
Shredder Guy and John Doe
are the same person--
were--the same person.
Six years ago, Shredder Guy is
shot in the alley,
robbed and left for dead.
Yet, he survives,
skips town and disappears.
Flash forward six years.
Shredder Guy
returns here to Vegas
with Larry LaMotte's
stolen identity.
But bad news for him,
he runs into Julius Kaplan...
(coughing)
...who cooks him
a special meal.
(crying)
And then kills him
with a Glock.
Then someone kills
Julius Kaplan,
using the same Colt pistol
that shot Shredder Guy
six years ago in the alley.
Two crimes, same shooter?
Could be.
It doesn't make sense,
Catherine.
Shredder Guy had a credit card
in Larry LaMotte's name
sent to him
in New Mexico,
where he was living.
So, why would an identity thief
come all the way to Vegas
to commit fraud
in Larry LaMotte's backyard?
Right.
Maybe he just wanted a free trip
to Vegas on Larry's dime.
Maybe he wanted Larry LaMotte
to know he was in town.
Either way,
something else is going on.
I mean, Julius Kaplan
said it himself.
"Why kill
a penny-ante thief?"
He's not worth the risk.
Well, he might be,
if the thief is threatening
to bring down the entire
I.D.-Preserve empire.
Facial recognition got
a hit on Shredder Guy.
DMV in Florida
had a ten-year-old
driver's license on file.
Check out the name.
Shredder Guy
is Larry LaMotte?
The real Larry LaMotte.
Well, if he's
Larry LaMotte,
then who's Larry LaMotte?
See this cartridge case?
We pulled a six-year-old
print off it.
It has all the personal
information we need
to identify you.
You have a very
impressive CV.
Burglary, fraud,
and identity theft.
BRASS:
Goodbye, Larry LaMotte.
Hello, Arlo Karden.
Arlo Karden doesn't have
the same ring to it,
I'll give you that.
We searched your house.
Guess what we found.
A Colt pistol.
The print on that
cartridge casing
puts you in an alley
six years ago
with, given his penchant
for credit card fraud,
I'm guessing your old
partner in crime.
The real Larry LaMotte.
(Larry groans)
(gun fires)
You thought
you'd killed him.
You thought it was safe
to use his name. Good name.
Not in the system,
like yours.
We, uh...
searched your
phone records.
You received calls
from a prepaid cell,
in Gallup, New Mexico.
BRASS: I-I can just
imagine, you know,
the real Larry,
you know, watching TV,
and seeing some geezer
making money off his name.
So he gets on the Internet,
does a little search
of the profiles
of big-time CEOs,
and then up pops a picture: You.
LANGSTON: Larry called
you up, offered you
"peace of mind" for a price.
But you don't pay retail,
so you get Julius Kaplan
to get you a discount.
Which only leaves one loose end.
Here you go.
(shot fires)
I didn't kill anyone.
Larry said he wanted
five million dollars.
Yeah, yeah, we were partners
back in the day.
Hell, I figured
after all that time,
I mean, I... I owed him.
So I gave him
the money.
KARDEN: I instructed Julius
to deliver the cash.
After that, well...
I think we all
know what happened.
Yeah, everybody always
blames the dead guy.
I'm not the same guy
in that alley.
Not anymore.
A man can change.
As far as
that gun goes,
that doesn't prove anything.
I got workers.
I got people coming in and out
of that house all day long.
And as far
as six years ago goes,
my attorney informs me that,
in the state of Nevada,
the statute of limitations
on assault, even with a gun,
is two years.
(sniffs)
Yeah, I shot Larry LaMotte.
I stole his name.
I left him for dead.
But I only killed him once.
STOKES:
I checked with the bank.
Arlo may be telling the truth,
at least about one thing.
He made a withdrawal
four days ago,
five million in cash.
So, what, you think he's trying
to pay off the real Larry?
Oh, it's possible.
Maybe "Julius Child"
went off-recipe
and whacked the real Larry to
keep the five mill for himself.
It would give Arlo
motive to kill him.
He wanted his money back.
Well, one problem:
We searched Arlo's house,
Julius's house,
I.D.-Preserve.
Where's the
five million?
Oh, hey, Cath...
I got something.
I used Digital Frame Averaging
to process
the surveillance footage
we got from the neighbor
across the street
from Julius
Kaplan's house.
Program got us a partial plate.
Car was rented two days ago
by one Mr. Lee Devries.
That's the guy
that drove his truck
through the window
of I.D.-Preserve.
Guess he got
a little payback.
WILLOWS:
Brass sent units
to Lee Devries' place.
He wasn't there.
He didn't show up
for work, either.
The neighbor said
that he was visiting
his girlfriend
in Henderson.
(cell phone ringing)
Well, if he's got a briefcase
with five million dollars in it,
he's heading to Mexico.
Langston.
Yeah, Jim.
A patrol just spotted
Devries's rental car.
Heading south?
Got it.
(siren wailing)
(indistinct radio transmission)
Lee Devries!
Las Vegas Police!
Devries, get out of the car!
BRASS:
Step away from the car.
(handcuffs rattling)
BRASS:
Information is currency.
That's what they say.
And you turned it
into cold, hard cash.
The all-knowing
executive assistant.
Knows every phone call,
every meeting,
every e-mail,
every intimate detail
of the boss's life.
You knew the real Larry.
You knew about the blackmail.
You knew about your boss
withdrawing five million bucks.
You even knew
about "Julius Child" and
his skills in the kitchen.
Saw an opportunity for
a little quid pro quo.
The thing about the "quo" is,
it's a lot sweeter
when you don't have to share.
(shot fires)
He was a pig.
Just like my boss.
And the "quid pro quo"
started a long time ago.
Except then, it was about
holding on to my job.
"Honey, can you
grab me a cup of coffee?"
"Honey, can you pick up
my dry cleaning?"
"Sweetheart,
"can you come
by my place tonight?
I need a little help--
with something."
You used your boss's gun.
We spoke with
Lee Devries.
He confirms someone accessed
one of his accounts.
You used his identity
to rent a getaway car
that you planned to
dump at the border.
And with five million dollars
missing, well...
naturally, we'd be looking
for Devries and not for you.
And thanks to I.D.-Preserve,
you had all his credit
card information.
Easy peasy.
Like you said, I know every
detail about my boss's life.
His business, too.
He ruined a lot of lives.
People who trusted him,
like Devries.
A little justice
for all of them has got
to be worth something.
Information's currency, right?
STOKES:
Elaine Travers pled out,
gave up her boss.
With all those
defrauded clients,
he's looking at identity
theft times a thousand.
Larry Arlo, whoever
the hell he is,
he's not going
to be getting
much peace of mind
over the next 12 years.
His fellow inmates better keep
their hands in their pockets.
Mm-hmm.
Hey, you out of here?
Yeah, yeah, I think I'm
gonna grab a beer or ten.
You want to join me?
I don't think so.
You sure? We can talk
about our feelings.
(chuckles)
I'll see you tomorrow.
SANDERS: I don't live in
Kyrgyzstan, I've never
even been to Kyrgyzstan,
so how could I spend $1,200
on snacks
and a yurt?
It's unfortunate.
I mean, not only Greg's
identity theft issues,
but, uh, our man-date.
It's been postponed.
Your mandate?
No, no, no.
Not a mandate.
It's a man-date.
It was actually Greg's idea.
Um, we...
meet at the same time
every week, so that I can
put Wendy behind me.
You know, so,
uh, you look...
very nice.Thanks.
Do you have plans?
Yeah.
Well. Okay.
(Sanders continues
indistinctly)
Hey, did you get a haircut?
Uh, no.
Why? Did, um...
Did Greg happen to
mention something, or...?
No.
Oh.
I mean, he might have mentioned
something about a science camp.
But you know
how people talk.
I could show you
mine, but I think
that might be
inappropriate.
You hardly
notice them.
Scars?
Mm.
Of course...
some scars
heal faster than others.
I got a letter
from Nate Haskell
the other day.
He wanted to let me know that,
uh, he was thinking about me.
The kidney bean?
Yeah.
Don't let him get
into your head, Ray.
Well, he's already in there.
Everything that happens to us,
the good and the bad,
is part of us.
Took me a long time
to realize that, uh...
it doesn't have
to define who we are,
We get to decide that.
Good night, Dr. Ray.
Good night, Sarah.