Oh my god that one guy kept coming up
behind me and smelling my hair.
What was with all
the short guys?
He was like,
five feet tall.
I know, he came
up to... there.
Aw! There's not a
decent guy in there.
The one who kept
grabbing my ass--
total reject from
the Jersey Shore.
At least he wasn't dragging
around an oxygen tank.
Oh, ew.
Oh...
See the way he's
looking at her?
It's like she's the
only girl in the world.
I want that.
Where are all
the good men?
(screaming)
(bystanders murmuring)
MAN:
Step back, please. Step back.
Smell that?
Alcohol.
Maybe this guy had a few too
many and fell off his balcony.
Well, the back of his skull
is completely obliterated.
Unfortunately, that won't help
us determine how far he fell.
These injuries
could have occurred
if he fell
five stories or 20.
MADDIE:
It all happened so fast.
It's like the guy just
fell out of the sky.
What are you looking at?
Oh, I'm sorry. You got
something in your, uh...
I do?
Yeah, it's okay.
Don't move.
What is it?
Just a little piece of brains.
You always said you were
looking for a guy with brains.
I'm sorry. I make jokes
when I'm nervous.
That's all right.
Just a couple more questions.
Did you girls hear anything
before he hit the ground?
Any yelling?
Screaming?
I was just looking
for a nice guy.
One with a pulse.
Maybe a badge?
Sorry... I flirt when
I'm nervous, too.
Thank you.
Victim is Brad Malone;
guest at the hotel.
Bad couple of days.
He was down
over 100 grand.
Another $50,000
in unpaid markers.
You got all of that for a hug?
Jerry? He used to
work for my father.
So he just handed over
the casino's financials?
Come on. How well
do you know this guy?
It's really not
what you're thinking.
When Sam died, he... left me
a little piece of the Eclipse.
How little?
It's really no big deal.
Then why haven't
you said anything?
I don't want everyone to know.
So now I'm "everyone"?
Let's just... talk about
this some other time.
Victim is Brad Malone.
He was in suite 730.
Lost his shirt at the casino.
LANGSTON:
And apparently his pants.
NICK:
It could be a jumper.
Vegas is the suicide
capital of America.
Come to gamble,
see a show,
kiss your life goodbye.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
Jumper's name's Brad Malone.
Checked in four days ago.
Divorced twice. No kids.
And he was about
to file for bankruptcy.
Not a lot to live for.
Hmm-mm.
Clothes neatly folded.
Phone and wallet
on the nightstand.
Everything in its place.
Consistent with suicide.
You get your life in order
before you end it.
There's no suicide note.
Nah. They don't
typically leave one.
Got a few recent e-mails.
Past due notices.
Offerings of joy?
No. No signs of sexual activity.
Looks like he spent
his last night alone.
Door's locked.
Latching mechanism only
operates from the inside.
If he jumped off his balcony,
how'd he lock the door
behind him?
Well, maybe he didn't jump,
maybe he was pushed.
Which means...
he wasn't alone.
I'll check it for prints.
Yeah.
We got a print.
BRASS:
Okay, we have a double homicide.
Landlord I.D.'d the bodies
as Lance and Denise Irwin.
Their home was foreclosed
on four months ago,
so they had to move here.
Talk about a step down.
Yeah.
Who called it in?
She did.
The 911 operator said
all she could get out was,
"Help me, help me,"
and then there was no response.
SIDLE:
Huh. No blood on the phone.
Lots of cast-off, though.
On the couch,
the lamp, the ceiling...
Did you see what happened?
If you tell us,
I'll give you a cracker.
Well, if he did see anything,
he's not talking.
So we contacted Animal
Control for the parrot.
You know, it's a
first floor unit.
The window was open,
the screen was ripped,
so that's probably
how the killer got in.
Where's the husband?
The husband
is in the bathroom.
What's going on?
They dead?
Can somebody get this guy out
of here? Take his information?
BRASS: We'll be with you
in a minute, sir.
OFFICER:
Let's go.
MAN: Don't push!
I'm goin', okay?
Whew.
Slight discoloration
of his extremities.
Lividity is just setting in.
The Irwins were killed
less than an hour ago.
Can't tell if
he was stabbed, too.
Nasty head wound, though.
Possible broken nose, too.
So, Mr. Irwin was probably
getting ready to go to work.
He works the 7:00 a.m. shift at
the gas station at the corner.
Looks like Mrs. Irwin
was making him breakfast.
An omelette.
Maybe a frittata.
BRASS:
Oh, how Continental. Lucky guy.
Check out
the family photo.
Matching outfits.
There is something
very wrong with that.
What? That is a
nice family photo.
SANDERS:
Still wrong.
I don't see the cat.
Probably took off.
Okay, so the killer
came through the window
and surprised Mrs. Irwin, right?
SANDERS:
Killer hears the husband
getting out of the shower.
Goes to take care of him.
Hey, uh, guys?
Cash and credit cards
are still here.
You know, come to think of it,
parrots like these are
worth thousands of dollars.
More, if they can talk.
I don't think this is a robbery.
BRASS:
Well, maybe they were targeted.
I'll go talk to the landlord.
See if anybody had
a problem with the Irwins.
Hey, David.
Hey.
I am so sorry I'm late.
It's been one of those days.
They're not going
anywhere.
(sighs)
What is the deal
with glass tables today?
The print on the balcony door
belongs to Malone.
There's only one set
of shoe prints out here.
Size 10, same size
as Mr. Malone.
If he was pushed
from this balcony,
there'd be evidence
of his attacker out here
and there doesn't
appear to be any.
Maybe he was pushed
from somewhere else?
Look where the body landed.
LANGSTON: The body's not
directly below this balcony.
It's under
the one next door.
Suite next door
is registered to
a Stacy Cano and a Dana
Carlston, from Ohio.
No connection to
the victim that we know of.
Drop of blood.
LVPD! Open up!
NICK (quietly):
Got a blood trail.
Hey...
(gasps, screams)
(retching, coughing)
STOKES:
Here you go.
Drink this.
Thank you.
You've got some
minor bruising,
but no open wounds.
And it appears that the blood
that you were both covered in
doesn't belong
to either of you.
Who does it belong
to then?
We were hoping
you could tell us.
Do you recognize this man?
No, I don't think so.
We think he might have been
in your hotel room last night.
You don't remember?
We had a lot to drink.
Everything's
a little hazy.
Do you think that
this is his blood?
(groans)
What happened to him?
He's dead.
Oh, my God.
I'm gonna be sick again.
(retching)
An officer's going to come
by and take you both to the
hospital, get you checked out.
But we're still going
to need to ask you
some more questions.
Okay?
(muffled):
Okay.
The victim suffered
a fractured skull
and intercranial bleed.
Rendered him unconscious.
So the killer attacked
him in the shower
and smashed his head
against the wall.
And he drowned.
Drowned?!
We didn't find any
water in the tub.
You know, it's possible
to drown in an inch of water.
Victim was unconscious.
Couldn't lift his head up.
Drain was clogged.
Water built up.
By the time you arrived,
the water was gone.
But I found something else.
Healed scars
on his upper body.
Could be from some
past altercation.
Guess Mr. Irwin
had some enemies.
MAN (recorded):
You are dead, you hear me?!
You're dead!
You left that message
on the Irwin's voice mail
a couple days ago, Dwayne.
How do you know it was me?
How do I know
it was you?
You called from
your home phone.
Yeah, that doesn't
prove I made the call.
Dude, it's your voice.
All right,
look, Dwayne,
you live next door
to the Irwins.
Your landlord says you
threatened him several times.
You tried
to get him evicted, right?
Yeah, I hated him
all right,
but I didn't kill him.
I thought about killing
that bird, though.
It never shut up.
squawking all day and night.
Hold on a minute.
You mean you threatened
to kill your neighbors
because the bird was
making too much noise?
Wasn't just the bird.
The Irwins were arguing
all the time.
Screaming, throwing things.
It was likeFight Club
over there.
You call the cops?
No, they wanted
to kill each other.
Why not let 'em.
All right, where were you
at 7:00 this morning?
In my apartment.
Your apartment? Alone?
Not exactly.
Not exactly?
What does that mean?
I was having some
pretty hot phone sex with Betsy.
Okay, I'm going to have
to verify that.
How do I get
ahold of Betsy?
You got a credit card?
Only cost you $4.99 a minute.
♪ ♪
WILLOWS: You ladies had
quite a party last night.
We were celebrating.
My divorce was
finalized a week ago.
How long were you married?
Seven years.
Worked two jobs
to send that son of a bitch
to medical school.
And it turned out he was
examining the anatomy
of every girl in the class.
Hmm. I was married
to one of those.
Then you know.
It's been the worst
year of my life.
Oh, I just wanted
to cut loose and have some fun.
Stacy, we found
Brad Malone's fingerprints
on your balcony.
He was staying in
the room next to yours.
Good-looking guy.
I mean, is it possible
that you and Dana
met him in the hall,
invited him
in for drinks?
I honestly--
I wish I could remember.
We were pretty hammered.
Were your drinks ever
out of your sight?
Maybe.
Um, when I was dancing.
Wh-What's the last thing you
remember about last night?
Um, we were at a club...
(cheering)
♪ ♪
Which one?
I have no idea.
We made our way from
one end of the Strip
to the other,
and then it's just like
I'm looking down a long tube.
(echoing laughter)
DANA:I haven't had that much
to drink since college.
My weekends are usually full
of soccer and birthday parties.
Not a lot of adult time.
Do you recall meeting
Brad Malone
in one of the clubs you went to?
I told you I don't remember.
I'm just trying to understand
how he ended up in your suite.
I'd like to know that, too.
Um, well, Dana,
your physical exams indicate
that both you and Stacy engaged
in sexual activity
last night.
Oh, my God.
You're going to be okay.
I'm going to try to help
you figure this out.
My husband and I,
we fell in love when we were 16.
He's the only man
I've ever been with.
LANGSTON:Alcohol affects
the frontal lobe
of the brain, which
controls judgment.
Makes people do things they
wouldn't ordinarily do.
Don't I know it.
One night in college,
I drank so much,
that I woke up the next morning
on my front lawn
with a box of corn flakes
stuck to my head.
Had no idea how it got there.
Why am I not surprised.
Eh. College.
The frontal lobe of the brain
also controls memory,
which is why Dana and Stacy
can't remember anything.
It's kind of hard to remember
a complete stranger
from a three-way
in the middle of the night.
LANGSTON: Hm. That's an odd
place for an iron.
Somebody got steamed.
Positive for blood.
We smelled alcohol
on our victim.
Which means
he had been drinking.
We know the girls
had been drinking.
We know they were in
this room having sex.
So somewhere during
the evening,
the party took a darker turn.
That's the problem with
a menage a trois,
is somebody always
gets left out.
Yes, someone always
gets jealous.
The question is, did one
of those girls get so angry
that she picked up that iron
and used it as a weapon?
Stacy had just come off
a bitter divorce.
Maybe our victim
said something,
did something,
that reminded her of her ex.
She snapped.
She picked up the iron,
struck him in the head,
killed him and then Dana helped
her get rid of the evidence.
And what's that old saying?
"A good friend
will help you move."
A really good friend will help
you move a body.
Hey. Brass said the neighbor's
alibi checked out.
The sex line confirmed
that Dwayne's hands were full
when the Irwins were killed.
Well, he was also right about
the Irwins' marital discord.
Police were called out to their
house at least once a month.
Here are some of
the 911 tapes.
OPERATOR: 911.
What is your emergency?
WOMAN: Help me, please!
He's gonna kill me!
MAN: You call the cops,
you stupid bitch?
(slap)
(woman screaming)
Thin line between love and hate.
Did you run
the prints from the apartment?
Yeah. They all came back
to the Irwins.
I spoke with the landlord
about the window.
Turns out the screen's
been broken for weeks.
Apparently Mr. Irwin
put his fist through it.
So maybe...
there was no intruder.
DENISE IRWIN:
I'm sick of you!
Every single day,
all you do is watch
your stupid football...
SIDLE:
They get into another fight.
This time, Mr. Irwin pulls
a knife on her.
(squawking)
He kills her.
Got her blood all over him,
so he takes a shower.
Slips in her blood
and drowns.
Karma's a bitch.
If we're right, his prints
will be on the knife,
and her blood
will be in the tub.
ROBBINS: Considering the damage
to Brad Malone's skull,
I can't tell you whether
he was struck by an iron.
These cuts are from
the glass table.
On the plus side,
take a look at the abrasions
on his buttocks and thighs.
That's linear clotting.
It means his blood was flowing
when he hit the pavement.
LANGSTON:
These look like drag marks.
I pulled glass and some
interesting trace from them.
LANGSTON:
These look like paint chips.
They're the same color as
the railing at The Eclipse.
That's consistent with being
pushed over backwards.
Mr. Malone's last night
wasn't all bad.
I did a penile swab and found
vaginal secretions.
He had sex close
to time of death.
That's odd.
We found a used condom
in the women's
hotel room.
Parallel linear scrapes
with parabolic edges.
Fingernail marks.
Well, maybe Mr. Malone got
a little too aggressive
with the second woman.
Didn't want to use a condom.
She struck him in the back
of the head with the iron.
That didn't stop him.
So maybe one of them
or both of them
pushed him off the balcony.
In my fantasies, a three-way
never ends in death.
STOKES:
This sheet...
Brad Malone's pants
and the iron.
All this blood came
from the same person.
Brad Malone.
Nope. Unknown male.
You're saying there
was a second man in the room?
I'm saying that three-way
was a four-way.
Oh.
What is he
still doing here?
What happened to
Animal Control?
SANDERS: They must
have forgotten about him.
We should bring him
back to the lab, hmm?
(chuckles)
You hungry, buddy?
What's the point of having
a parrot if he doesn't talk?
Well, he might
be traumatized.
He was living
in an abusive household.
He witnessed Dad
kill Mom.
Now if we could
only prove it.
None of her blood
was in the bathroom.
Doc Robbins said the tub
might have had a clogged drain.
Hopefully, some of her blood
got stuck in the trap
when Mr. Irwin
took a shower.
Yeah, I'm on it.
You know, this would
be a lot easier
if you just told us
what happened.
I found hair and a bunch
of feathers in the trap.
Feathers?
Yeah. Guess
they didn't
just dress him up,
but they gave him showers, too.
Looks like blood
on the feathers.
Hopefully, it belongs
to Mrs. Irwin.
What are you doing?
Well, these blood drops
weren't here before.
Our crime scene's
been contaminated.
What?
The door was sealed.
They're paw prints.
Guess the Cat in the Hat
came back.
Or he's been hiding
here this whole time.
(meowing)
I found him.
Well, you're evidence
now, buddy.
You're coming back
to the lab, too.
Come here. Come here, kitty.
Come on, buddy.
VARTANN:
You're telling me those ladies
from Ohio had two
men in their room?
Yeah.
Wow.
One guy ends up dead,
and the other one's blood
is all over the bedroom.
That must have
been some orgy.
Actually, it was more
of a one-on-one thing.
She never swapped partners.
We found a condom
that contained DNA profiles
of the newly divorced Stacy
and the mystery man.
And Dana's SAE
kit indicated
that she had unprotected sex
with Brad Malone.
And the women claim that they
don't remember any of this?
Come on. Give me a break.
Givemea break.
Do you know what it's like
to wake up naked in a motel room
with no memory
of how you got there?
Your head is
throbbing.
You're bruised,
you're sore.
You've got no idea of what
you did or what was done to you.
But you do?
Well, yeah.
A couple of
years ago, I...
went with a friend to
a John Mayer concert,
and someone
roofied my drink.
What? You were...
you were raped?
No, thank God.
I wasn't. I...
I thought I was.
But... I mean, even
worse than that,
was just having no memory of it.
There was just hours
of my life gone.
How come you...
you never told me any of this?
Not something I like
to talk about.
Yeah, I'm getting used to that.
(knock at door)
Hey.
Sorry to interrupt.
We just got back
Dana and Stacy's tox report.
Stacy's alcohol level was .32.
That's the equivalent
of 13 drinks.
We also found GHB
in their systems.
So they were drugged.
Yeah, it was
in their yard-longs.
But here's the kicker:
Dana had trace amounts of GHB,
but her blood alcohol level
was only .07.
That's not even legally drunk.
Look, I'm telling you,
your soccer mom Dana remembers
a lot more about last night
than she's letting on.
DANA:
Someone drugged us?
Is that why
we don't remember anything?
VARTANN: Well, that's
why Stacy doesn't remember,
but you were only
slightly intoxicated.
Not enough to
cause memory loss.
Dana, you need
to tell us the truth.
We know that
Brad Malone wasn't
the only man
in your room last night.
Who else was there?
I think his name was Kyle.
We never got his last name.
And where did you meet
this Kyle?
At a bar.
I don't remember which one.
And how did he end up
in your room?
Stacy invited him.
We emptied
the minibar.
Then Stacy
wanted to dance, so...
we blasted the stereo.
Is that when Brad
joined the party?
He knocked on our door.
He told us to keep it down.
And Stacy invited him in
for a drink.
And then... she and Kyle
went into the bedroom.
Leaving you alone with Brad.
Well, we found
your vaginal fluid
and Brad's semen on the sofa,
as well as the coffee table.
It seems like things
got pretty crazy.
It... it wasn't like that.
He raped me!
I slept with one
man my whole life.
You think I'm going to have
unprotected sex
with a total stranger?
I begged him to stop.
And because he raped you,
you pushed him off the balcony?
I didn't push him.
Then who did?
After Brad raped me...
I went into the bedroom.
And Kyle grabbed me,
and he... he pulled me down.
He said it was his turn.
All of a sudden,
Brad was there.
Kyle flipped out.
He... he ran at Brad.
Shoved him into the other room.
He-he-he just kept shoving him
and shoving him
and shoving him.
(screaming)
So Dana was raped,
witnessed a murder,
and then she goes to bed
as if nothing had happened?
Kyle said, if she told anyone,
he'd come back and kill her.
She was scared.
Well, was there any evidence
of rape in her physical exam?
There was bruising,
but it was inconclusive.
Well, whatever happened
in that hotel room,
we know our mystery man
Kyle was involved.
We need to find him.
David, you said you had
something you wanted to show me.
Yes. This is from the bedding
in the women's motel room.
Take a look.
LANGSTON:
A feather?
Not just
any feather.
It's premium quality,
hand-harvested
Hungarian goose down.
Now, take a look
at this feather
that Nick found
on the floor.
LANGSTON:
It's synthetic.
Made from a very
specific blend
of polyester fibers.
Mmm.
I managed to trace it
to a manufacturer in China.
They supply
low-end pillows
to several
motels in Vegas,
but their biggest buyer is
a bar called the Pillow Club.
Stacy and Dana said they went
to a lot of clubs,
a lot of bars last night.
Now, I happen to know
from personal experience
that this particular
club does sell
the yard-long drinks,
much like the ones
that you found
in the their suite.
Maybe that's
where they met Kyle.
But what does a club need
with pillows?
So, half-naked people hitting
each other with pillows.
An adult
slumber party.
That's kinky.
Well, you're already
dressed for bed.
It sends a pretty
clear message.
Yeah, add alcohol to the mix.
Gives you permission to
act out your aggressions.
No limits, no taboos.
Excuse me.
What can I get you?
Yeah, we're from the crime lab.
We have reason
to believe
that these two women were
in here drinking last night.
Drinking a lot.
You know who might
have served them?
It was my night off,
but check at the bar.
Our bartender, Kyle,
he was working.
Thanks.
Hey.
Are you Kyle?
Yeah.
What happened to your head?
Oh, I hit it
on the edge of the bar.
Say what?
I said I hit it on
the edge of the...
Aah! Damn!
What the hell, man?
Looks like you
ran into an iron.
Man, girl's lying.
About which part?
The attempted rape
or the murder?
Both.
We know
you had sex
with Stacy Cano.
We also found GHB
in her system.
You're a bartender.
Man, you had easy access.
Yeah, I gave her the drugs,
but she asked for them.
Said she wanted to party,
lose control.
(squeals)
Come on, Dana!
You said that we
were going to have fun.
Drink it!
Whoo!
KYLE:
So Stacy thought we'd bring
the party back to her room.
Then, after you
had sex with her,
you thought you'd just
have sex with Dana?
Hey, I offered to do her,
but the bitch hit me
in the head with an iron.
Don't be like that, girl.
Damn! Come on!
Wait a minute, now.
Dana is the one who hit you
in the head
with the iron.
Yeah. She went mental.
Chased me out in the hallway,
screaming.
Where was Brad Malone
during all this?
You mean the hero
boy next door?
He came out his room to see
what the hell was going on.
Get out!
Are you okay, miss?
None of your
damn business!
Get the hell out of here!
So, you and Mr. Malone
were never
in the ladies' hotel room
at the same time?
I got to the elevator
to see Captain America
taking Dana back to her room.
Where'd you go after that?
E.R.
Took me four hours
to get stitched back up.
You don't believe me,
call Desert Palm.
I'll do that.
ROBBINS:
C.O.D. is exsanguination
due to sharp force injury.
Stabbed once.
Only one stab wound?
You're kidding me, right?
There was castoff
on the walls.
I mean, her blood
was everywhere.
None of the physical evidence
in this case makes any sense.
Only the Irwins' prints
in their apartment.
Only Mrs. Irwin's prints
were on the knife.
Only Mr. Irwin's blood
was in the bathroom.
May-may-may I interject?
Please.
I don't think Mr. Irwin
killed his wife,
though she was the
victim of foul play.
See these scalp
lacerations?
SIDLE:
Yeah.
These are talon marks.
I heard the Irwins
had a parrot.
If you are suggesting
that the bird is a suspect,
he was in his cage with the door
closed when we arrived.
Parrots are extremely smart.
You can teach them
to do almost anything,
even let themselves
in and out of their cages.
Well, yeah, it's true, but...
there's no way
that that bird
picked up a knife
and stabbed Mrs. Irwin.
Right?
(cat hissing, parrot squawking)
Wh-What is with this family?
Even the animals
hate each other.
Why didn't you just
separate them, Hodges?
Even though I project an aura
of raw courage
and unwavering
self-confidence,
I suffer from... ornithophobia.
(squawks)
You're afraid of birds.
Let's just say
that I was terrorized
by a flock of Canadian geese
while visiting my uncle
in Saskatchewan.
Really?
They were Canadian.
I thought they were friendly.
All right, well,
according to Doc Robbins,
the parrot attacked Mrs. Irwin.
We already know that the cat
ran through the crime scene,
so we're gonna have
to process both of them.
I'll take the cat.
(squawking)
(whimpers)
What is that?
What happened to you?
SIDLE: The castoff on the walls
wasn't from the knife.
It was was from the parrot.
He attacked Mrs. Irwin.
We found her DNA
under his talons,
and we found her blood
under his feathers.
When he flapped his wings,
it spattered blood on things.
The parrot killed Mrs. Irwin?
Uh, well, he had
an accomplice, the cat.
Technically, he's responsible
for Mr. Irwin's death.
BRASS: So Sylvester and Tweety
whacked their owners.
Think of it as a series
of unfortunate events.
What do you mean, don't think
of it as a cartoon?
Well, Hodges found traces
of soap on the bird,
and I found feathers
in the bathtub.
Mr. Irwin was giving
the parrot a shower
when the cat attacked.
Okay.
Hodges also found plastic
from the shower curtain
under the cat's claws.
SIDLE:
In his defense,
you know, I think the cat was
probably going after the bird.
The really hate each other.
SIDLE:
The bathroom door was open,
and the cat saw
its opportunity.
Now, Mrs. Irwin
was in the kitchen
making breakfast.
She must have heard
the commotion.
So, she went
to check it out.
There were chopped vegetables
on the counter
so the knife was already
in her hand.
And you know what they say
about running with scissors.
SIDLE:The parrot was trying
to get away from the cat.
(cat yowling)
And in his frenzied state,
he turned his aggression
on Mrs. Irwin.
The evidence
strongly suggests
that Mrs. Irwin, in then trying
to get away from the bird,
fell onto the coffee table.
(parrot squawking)
(glass shattering)
She stabbed herself?
Yeah.
And then the cat
went into hiding
and the bird went back
into its cage
and shut the door.
Remarkably,
it all makes perfect sense.
There is one thing
that we can't explain.
Mrs. Irwin had blood
all over her hands.
How did she call 911 and not
get any blood on the phone?
STOKES:
Bartender's story checks out.
He was in the E.R. when
Malone hit the pavement,
so he didn't do it.
Which means Dana lied.
Yeah, makes you wonder
what else she's lying about.
Like being raped.
Well, if she
wasn't attacked,
why did she push Brad
Malone off the balcony?
We know that she
scratched him.
His epithelials
were under her nails.
Yeah, he's a big guy.
Dana's about your size.
Is it even possible for her
to push him off that balcony?
(grunting)
(Langston groans)
It's possible.
Check out my ass.
Ray, your ass
is a work of art.
But there's no paint
on the backs of your thighs.
Doesn't match Malone's injuries.
Well, that would mean
his thighs would have
to have more contact
with the rail
when he went over.
The only way to replicate
those kind of injuries
is if he was sitting on the
railing when he went over.
Fresh coat of paint?
Well, rape is all about power,
but sitting on a balcony is not
a position of power, so...
maybe Brad Malone
wasn't the aggressor.
We know he and Dana had sex
right before he died.
Did that sex
move out to the balcony?
Well, we found a lot of
partials on the railing.
We assume they were
fingerprints.
Maybe they were
toe prints.
If they were toe prints,
she would have been sitting
in his lap.
Have a seat, boss.
Well, I'm not
getting up there.
Come on, Catherine.
Toes are under the
bottom railing there.
Got it? Okay.
Yo, Ray, you're good.
Ecklie's not
in the building, right?
Seven stories up? Really?
Isn't this a little
Cirque de Soleil?
Oh...
Danger just adds
to the excitement, Nicky.
Suspended Congress.
What?
This position is called
Suspended Congress
in the Kama Sutra.
What? I'm a doctor.
This is my first three-way.
Really?
Yeah, I'm very excited.
Okay.
Okay, so things
are heating up.
Mm-hmm.
They're really
going at it.
Mm-hmm.
It wouldn't take much
for him to fall over now.
No.
(moaning)
(Dana screams)
Yup.
Paint right down the back
of your thighs.
That's match
to Brad Malone's injuries.
WILLOWS:
Brad's death was an accident.
He fell off the balcony while
you were having consensual sex.
You did try
to save him,
which is why
he had the scratches on his arm.
I have three amazing kids.
My husband is the
love of my life.
Not once in 15 years have I
even looked at another man.
Until Brad?
We had this immediate...
connection.
I couldn't stop myself.
I lost control,
and I'm not that person.
You have to understand,
my husband and I
only have sex twice a month.
Lights out, under the covers.
Well, you're not the first woman
to have sex with a stranger...
to have cheated on her husband.
A man died while I was
having sex with him.
Incredible...
mind-blowing sex.
Dana, you're not being charged.
You do have some explaining
to do to your husband.
A bit of advice:
The part about
the mind-blowing sex...
I'd leave that part out.
Hey.
Case closed?
Yeah.
(sighs)
I know you're upset.
You think I'm not being
honest with you, but...
I just don't think couples need
to tell each other everything.
So, who gets to draw that line?
You own a piece of a casino.
That's a big thing to keep
from me.
But, Lou,
that's business.
That has nothing
to do with us.
Well, that says a lot.
I-I-I've had all the
complicated relationships
I could handle.
This is who I am.
Please don't try to change me.
I promise
I won't try to change you.
So, what?
Take it or leave it?
Call me when you decide.
(tapping computer keys)
We found you a good home
with a nice family.
No cats, and they
have another bird.
This is your
last chance.
You attack anyone else
and your goose is cooked.
(trills)
Ahh! Ow. Damn it.
(screeches, trills)
You okay?
Yeah.
(trills)
(dial tone humming)
(buttons beeping)
(line ringing)
OPERATOR:
911. What is your emergency?
(imitates Denise Irwin):
Help me! Help me!
No blood on the phone.
You've been holding out on us.