♪ ♪
What about that?
(indistinct announcement
over P.A.)
Mm!
So what do we got here?
Back away, ma'am.
We go through the boxes
before the customers do.
(whistles)
I smell a Gucci bag
in one of these.
A wig.
I could use a wig.
(grunts)
(gasps, screaming)
(yelling)
(sirens wailing,
helicopter flying over)
Hey.
Dead body inside?
Yeah, but we're not dealing
with a full body.
What do you mean?
So far, we have a head
and a foot.
You know, I actually
shop at this store.
They have some good stuff.
They always sell body parts?
No leakage.
Killer was tidy enough
to wrap the parts in plastic.
Rest of him is probably
in these other boxes.
We're going to have to take
them all back to the lab.
Were these boxes drop-offs
or pickups?
Pickups. The manager said
they just came off the truck.
Where did the truck get them?
All over town.
They don't keep track of which
box comes from which house,
but the store manager
gave me a list of the addresses
on the driver's route.
You know,
I have heard
of donating a body to science.
But to a thrift store?
I wonder how much
the killer thought it was worth?
I mean...
times are tough.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
Excuse me.
Uh, does Ray Langston work here?
Yes, ma'am.
I work with Ray.
Oh, good. I thought
he worked at the morgue
until they sent me
here.
No.
No, he hasn't had that office
over there for a while now.
Is there something I
can help you out with?
I just wanted to say hi to him.
You know, I'm not...
I'm not always in Las Vegas.
I'm sorry. I'm Gloria.
Gloria. You wouldn't happen
to be Ray's wife, would you?
Yeah. Yeah, I'm
Nick Stokes.
It's nice
to meet you.
I'll tell you what. Follow
me and I'll take you to him.
Thank you.
All right,
let's go.
(music blares in distance)
(gunshot)
Oh!
(laughs)
Come on.
Firing six!
(music blaring
from car speakers)
Reloading!
Firing one!
(gunshot)
Here he is.
Of course, right now,
he looks a lot more like Dr. Dre
than Dr. Ray, but...
Ray!
Firing two!
(gunshot)
Ray!
(knocks on hood)
(music stops)
Somebody here to see you.
Gloria.
Uh...
(laughs)
Hi.
What a surprise.
You know, I really have a lot
of work to do, so I'm gonna run.
It was good to see you. Hope to
see you again, Mrs. Langston.
Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you, too.
Yeah.
You got yourself a
really good man here.
I could really use
your help, Hodges.
You know, it took him
a little time to warm up,
but, uh, now
we're family.
Hodges!
What?
(no voice)
Excuse me.
Hi.
Nice to see you.
What part of your job
is this exactly?
Oh, this car was involved
in a drive-by shooting.
The occupants said that
they didn't hear any gunshots,
so we're comparing the
decibel level of the gunfire
to the decibel level of the
music they were listening to.
Sounds like fun.
You leave the dead bodies
out of the equation, it is.
(laughs)
What...?
What brings you to Vegas?
I'm getting married.
Mm.
I, um... I-I got engaged
a couple of months ago,
and I didn't let
you know, and I just...
I didn't want to do
the same thing with the wedding.
Congratulations.
We're just gonna, um, do it
at, like,
a little chapel up the street.
Nothing fancy.
Ray, I know that
you won't come, but
I'd really like you
to meet Phil.
(sighs heavily):
Wow.
I, um...
still consider you
my best friend.
Can I think about it?
Yeah, of course.
Where are you staying?
Uh, at the Eclipse.
If you... If you
change your mind,
why don't you... why don't
you meet us for a drink,
at the lounge,
tomorrow night at 8:00?
I will think about it.
You look really good.
Thank you.
There she is.
Look, look, look.
SIDLE:
She's beautiful.
Well, she's a little bit
different than I expected.
I thought she'd be more bookish.
PHILLIPS:
He's been working
here for two years, and it's
the first time I've seen her.
Dr. Robbins hasn't even met her,
and they're buddies.
STOKES: Looks like sand
or dirt in his mouth.
But the rest
of the head seems pretty clean.
You know, if he had been buried,
he'd be covered in dirt.
Maybe the killer was
trying to shut him up.
STOKES: There's someone else
in his mouth.
SIDLE:What?
Take a look.
Hmm.
Bone fragments.
Ash...
morphology...
Cremated
human remains.
Cremains.
(camera shutter clicking)
(whooshing, crackling)
Guys?
Judging by these curved
tool marks,
some sort of flexible saw
was used.
LANGSTON:
Mm-hmm.
He was four-pointed.
Yeah.
These marks are too narrow
to be rope or handcuffs.
Maybe wire?
Check out his chest.
These faint contusions.
I'll see what I.R.
Photography develops.
Hear you had
a visitor.
Yes.
I would've liked
to have met her.
If I knew she was coming,
I would've introduced you
to her.
Maybe you and Gloria
could come over
for dinner one night this week.
Epiglottis is inflamed.
That means he was alive
when the cremains
were dropped down the hatch.
C.O.D. is asphyxia due to
oropharyngeal obstruction.
Which tells us the cremains
were--the murder weapon.
There is a message
in there somewhere.
You found all
his pieces.
Yes, we did.
What's in the
tox report, Henry?
Well, John Doe was
double-fisting
alcohol and zolpidem.
LANGSTON:
That's a strong sedative.
At these levels, he would've
had to have been comatose
when he ingested the cremains.
That explains his lack
of injuries to his
lips and tongue.
So he was unconscious,
the killer tied him up,
poured the cremains
in his mouth.
(coughing)
His involuntary gag reflex
opened up his gullet,
allowing the cremains
to be sucked into his throat,
asphyxiating him to death.
Why would anyone ever choose
to end up like this?
Money.
Cremation's fast and cheap.
Yeah, well, I'll fork
out the extra dollars
to go six feet under.
I don't like the idea
of being portable.
In a vase,
being passed around
from relative to relative.
No, I'm gonna get a tombstone.
Something that someone
can worship me at. Hmm.
So, we got
pieces of bone.
A surgical screw.
And an intact gold tooth.
Got a good chance of DNA.
STOKES: This is probably
from a hip replacement.
You know, if that crematorium
was doing their job right,
this shouldn't exist.
2,100 degrees for three hours
is what it takes to ensure
the disintegration of a corpse.
Anything less than that,
plastic hip replacements,
silicone implants,
large chunks of bone,
are all going
to be left behind.
How does identifying
the cremains help us
to identify the vic?
I'm thinking the victim
and the dearly cremated
were probably related.
DNA should confirm.
(mellow jazz plays,
people conversing quietly)
Excuse me?
You, uh, are you Ray?
Yes. And you are?
I'm the guy
who's marrying your wife.
Phil Baker.
Phil, nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you, too.
Beer? Wine?
Um... shot of bourbon.
Excuse me.
Can I get a shot of tequila
and a shot of bourbon,
please? Thanks.
So, look, hey,
thanks for coming.
You know, Gloria raves
about you, and, uh...
BARTENDER:
Gentlemen.
Thanks. Thanks. Great.
Here's to you and Gloria.
Thank you.
Hey, looks like you did
the deed before us, huh?
You should have
brought her.
(both laughing)
Well, um...
I see that Gloria is
still fashionably late.
Good to see she didn't
save that one just for me.
Some things never change.
Yeah.
Anyway, look, uh...
You know, Gloria really wants
you to come to the wedding.
And I just want you to know
I'm-I'm-I'm cool with that.
You know? I'm...
Thank you.
LANGSTON:
Hey.
Wow.
Okay.
You actually came!
(laughs)
Wow.
Oh, thank you.
Hi.
Hey.
How you doing?
Good.
Yeah... hey,
we were just,
we were just talking about
the wedding, and, uh...
What?
No. Babe.
GLORIA:
Babe, I told you to not to.
PHIL:
He said he's gonna come.
GLORIA:
No, he's not gonna come.
Okay? He barely made
it for our wedding.
So...
Ray, oh my God.
I'm s...
(chuckles)
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean it
that way. I just...
Yes, you did.
But it's okay.
Because you couldn't
be more right.
I barely made our wedding.
(chuckles)
So want to assure you
that I will be early
for your wedding to Phil.
Y... Y-You're gonna come?
I'm invited?
Yes!
Yes?
(laughs)
I'll be there.
Thanks a lot, man.
Thank you.
GLORIA: Oh, babe.
PHIL: Yeah.
GLORIA:
He's gonna come.
PHIL: I know he's
gonna come-- I told you.
(smooching)
SANDERS:
Hodges got a CODIS hit
off that gold tooth
he found in the cremains.
Joe Malton.
Death row inmate.
Killed his girlfriend
20 years ago,
but he had a heart attack before
they could give him the needle.
Hmm. When did he die?
Two years ago.
Crazy thing is,
the cremains were a mixture.
Two sets of DNA.
Death Row Joe
and an unknown female.
So the killer
poured the cremains
from two different
urns into the victim,
or it was two sources
mixed into one?
But who wants to get mixed
in with a psycho killer?
Well, it sounds like
this crematorium
where Joe was incinerated is
running a shady business.
Cutting corners.
I'll bet they're burning more
than one body at a time.
Hey, boys.
You guys in charge?
(Stokes coughing)
Gross.
Now why'd you have
to go and do that?
See, now you made me mad.
I just wanted
to talk to you.
You're making this harder
than it needs to be, guys.
We'd like to take a
look at your records.
The unknown female cremains
aren't unknown anymore.
They belong
to Sabrina Pose.
Died two years ago
in a car accident.
According to the
crematorium's records,
she was cremated
the same day as Death Row Joe.
Shared this house
with her husband Ronald Pose.
His DMV photo
matches our John Doe.
He live alone?
With his daughter
Camryn, 13. No sign of her.
Well, let's hope
she's at school
or at her friend's house,
and not in some box
like her old man.
I've got a call into CPS.
This house wasn't
on the Thrift Store
pick-up list,
but the one across
the street was.
I'll go check it out.
Thanks.
Yeah, yeah, thanks.
Husband and wife
were both lawyers.
Accounts for the swanky pad.
STOKES: There's a void
on the mantle.
Typical place to put the
urn, over the fireplace.
Maybe the killer
took it with him.
Found his night cap kit.
This looks like ash
on the lampshade here.
Ligature marks
on the bedposts.
This is home plate.
Let's check the bed.
More cremains.
The directionality
of the ash
suggests that
he was dragged
by his feet off the
end of the bed.
I got an ash trail.
Trail ends here.
STOKES: It's easier to sweep
the ash up off the tile
than to get it
out of carpet.
And if you're gonna
chop somebody up,
this is the best
place to do it,
then the easiest
to clean up.
These are recent
cut marks, Sara.
Slaughter tub.
Whew.
There's no blood trail
in the house.
I'm thinking
that the killer
packed up
the parts in here.
So where'd he box him up?
Garage.
(trilling)
♪ ♪
STOKES:
The killer kills the vic
in his own bed,
dismembers him in the tub,
cleans up,
boxes him up in the garage
and then just puts the boxes
on the neighbor's curb for
the thrift store to pick up.
And somebody else disposes
of the body for you.
It's kind of genius.
The house is empty.
Foreclosure.
Belonged to
a minister and his wife.
I'm running
them down now.
All right.
(clears throat)
Why are you at my house?
I'm Nick.
This is Frankie.
We're with
the police department.
The police?
Something's happened,
and we need
to talk to
you about it.
When was the last time
you saw your dad?
Last night.
Before I went to bed.
Look, if you need
to talk to him,
he's probably at work.
Was there anyone else
in the house with
you last night?
No.
How'd you get to
school this morning?
I'm on it.
My dad goes to
work really early,
so I usually just get myself
ready for school.
Can I go now?
No. I'm sorry, Camryn.
You're going to have to go
with Child Services,
just for now.
I just want
to go to my room.
No, no, no, no,
no, Camryn.
I can't let you
go in there.
I can't.
Why not?
'Cause something
really bad's
happened to your dad.
(sobbing)
I'm sorry, honey.
I'm so sorry.
Hey.
Hey. Just got done processing
some prints that Sara sent over.
Got a hit off a work card
that's worth checking out.
Local dancer.
Stripper?
No. She works on the Strip
for some of Vegas's
biggest shows.
All right.
Besides the photo,
what about her
is worth looking at?
She's the vic's
ex-girlfriend.
Ah.
Her prints were all
over his bedroom.
It's obviously a live-in,
'cause she has the same address.
Hey, didn't Nick and Sara
find some dancer's clothes
in a box at the thrift store?
Sure did.
Nick found even more women's
clothes in the garage.
Doesn't sound
like an amicable breakup.
Well, maybe he kicked her out.
Wouldn't let her
take her things.
She probably has a key.
Instead of coming
back for her stuff,
she comes back for revenge.
Well, revenge
is one thing, but, uh...
shoving his dead wife's
ashes down his throat
and slicing him up...
that's a monster.
♪ ♪
(shouts over music):
Excuse me, ladies.
We are looking for
a Sydney Preston.
Sydney Preston?
What's the problem?
We'd like to talk about that
at the station.
I can't. I'm rehearsing.
What's up?
Do you know Ronald Pose?
Yeah. Why?
He's dead.
Do you still want to
talk about that here?
When was the last time you
were in Ron Pose's house?
About two weeks ago...
when I found out
he cheated on me.
And you haven't been back since?
No.Mm-hmm.
According to
your work card,
you still live there.
I moved in with my mom.
Work has been hectic.
Haven't had a chance
to go look for a new place.
Do you recognize
these things?
Are they yours?
So you moved out of Ron
Pose's house two weeks ago,
but your belongings
are still there. Why?
I never got a chance to go back
because I didn't want
to see him.
After the breakup, that...
that's the last thing
that I wanted, so...
I left my stuff there.
What does this have to do
with anything?
This box of dance attire
was found along
with some
other boxes.
In those other boxes,
we found Ron's body parts.
Someone cut him up?
Why would someone do that?
You tell me.
Wait-- you don't think
that I did it?
Why not?
In spite of everything,
I still loved Ron.
Do you?
I love him more
than I've loved any man.
I thought he was the one.
Apparently, I was
one of many.
So Ron saw a lot of women?
He was a juggler.
He had a stable.
You would think that a widower
would be rusty on their skills.
No, uh-uh, not him.
You have any names?
Serina. Tammy.
Julie. Deanna.
The list goes on.Mm-hmm.
All I know is that I didn't want
to be on that list, so I left.
What's going on with Camryn?
Where is she?
She's fine.
She's with
Child Protective Services.
No. She-She doesn't
belong there.
She can stay with me.
Can I leave?
As soon as I get a DNA sample
from you, you are free to go.
Whatever it takes
to get me out of here.
So how long did you live
across from the Poses?
Oh. 15 years.
But even the Lord is not safe
from this hellish economy.
(laughs)
Church foreclosed,
the house went next.
We were forced to move
into a smaller place.
And so you donated
what you couldn't take
to the thrift store.
Unfortunately for us.
Fortunately for someone else.
Hmm.
What is she
doing here?
So, how well do you know
Ms. Preston?
Well, better than
I knew Ron, actually.
He wasn't really
around that much.
But Sydney-- she used
to spent a lot of time
with his daughter Camryn.
I mean, even when
her mother was alive,
she was basically alone,
or with babysitters.
Lawyers-- you know,
they work day and night.
Camryn-- she
raised herself.
But when Ron started dating
Sydney, all that changed.
See, Camryn was an only child,
like Sydney,
and I always felt like they had
a spiritual connection, too.
So, what about Sydney's
relationship with Ron?
Well, it's the first time
since his wife died,
I even saw a
smile on his face.
That is, of course,
until they broke up.
Man, he was screaming.
She didn't want to have
anything to do with him.
It broke Camryn's heart.
Must've felt like
losing another mother.
Sydney came to church
the next day.
Did she tell you
what the fight was all about?
Something about strange videos.
Videos? She say
what was on them?
Girls.
Sex tapes. I don't know.
I didn't pry.
That's not my world.
So, as far as you know,
did Sydney ever come back
to the house
after the big fight?No.
That's the last time I
saw her until just now.
We've got a
lot of evidence.
Yeah, but it adds up
to a whole lot of nothing.
Yeah, probably
'cause we're dealing
with the cleanest
house in Las Vegas.
All the prints
are explainable.
Belonging to either
the vic, his daughter,
the housekeeper
or Sydney Preston.
Prints from the moving boxes
are also explainable.
They come back
to the thrift shop driver,
the victim,
his daughter or Sydney.
And we found no prints
on the wire saw.
Okay.
What about the
blood evidence?
Blood all came back
to the victim.
Killer must've
worn gloves.
STOKES:
So the killer cleaned up.
Knew the neighbors were moving.
The garbage bags and boxes
were in the victim's garage.
Killer knew
the house.
My money's on Sydney.
She had motive.
Their breakup was ugly.
And the minister said
there were sex tapes involved.
You know, we haven't released
the house yet.
I could go back,
look for 'em.
(flame crackling)
(clicking, whirring)
So you just, like,
want me to talk about myself?
MAN:
Yeah. How old you are,
where you're from,
that kind of thing.
I'm 22, I grew up in Cali,
and got into singing
and dancing real young.
Any kids?
One, and she's just--
Wow, that's great.
Okay, let's see you dance.
(dance music begins)
♪ ♪
MAN: Just relax and
tell the camera
a little bit
about yourself.
But you already know me.
The executive
producer doesn't.
That's who's
casting the part.
WOMAN:
Okay. Um,
I'm 22, I go to WLVU--
Where is the sex?
Tell me about it.
It's like watching
American Idol--auditions.
Why would the vic
have these locked up?
He was a lawyer,
not a casting director.
Have you watched
them all?
All but one.
There's 30 tapes.
They're all numbered,
but number 15 is missing.
Well, they come from
Trufant Productions.
Maybe they can tell us
why they were locked up
in a dead man's safe.
Yeah. I under... I understand.
No, that girl is a wax figure.
The last thing
she needs is more procedures.
She should be subletting
some to her girlfriend.
You know what I'm saying?
Hey, that's a big call.
And you're gonna be
in big trouble
if you don't sit
down, Mr. Trufant.
What exactly do you do?
Agent, manager, producer.
Busy man.
What kind of shows
do you produce?
Reality shows
to strip shows
and everything in between.
What am I doing here?
These your tapes?
Not anymore.
I mean, I made them, yeah,
but I-I gave them away.
Who'd you give them to?
She could
book you, you know.
She's a casting director
for the LVPD.
I gave 'em to my buddy, Ron.
I was just trying
to help him out.
Help him out, how?
He's not a club guy.
I've known him
since he was a kid,
and-and he's a little nerdy.
He's not a go-getter.
Always needed a little help
with the ladies.
Especially since his wifey died.
REED:
So, you held
these auditions
to get him laid?
Basically.
I mean, we didn't tell
the girls that, of course.
Said we were producing
a new hip-hop musical.
REED:
So Ron watches the tapes,
and he picks the girls
that he likes?
Yeah, and then
I set up the dates.
Tell the girls
Ron's the executive producer
on the project,
make him sound important.
What happens when they find out
the show is a fake?
I just tell the girls
the project fell through.
Lost the venue,
couldn't get the rights
to the story-- whatever,
blah, blah-- that's easy.
By that time,
the girl is hooked on Ronny.
I mean, once you get past
his nerdy side,
he's a charming guy
with money to blow.
You want to know how many girls
he picked off those tapes?
We can only imagine.
Seriously, so,
what kind of charge am I looking
at for something like this?
I mean, honestly, I thought
it was all legal, you know.
REED: I'm a
homicide detective.
You are here
because Ron was murdered.
Well, Ron's, Ron's my boy.
I'd never do anything
to hurt him.
You got copies of those tapes?
Of course.
Yeah, I keep all the originals.
I'd like to take a look
at number 15.
(whirrs, beeps)
TRUFANT:
Beautiful Sydney,
what's up?
You know. Another day,
another casting.
What's up with you?
TRUFANT: Ah, you know,
same old thing.
Just putting together
another show.
So, Sydney finds Ron's
secret stash of tapes.
She realizes she was
auditioning to be
his girlfriend.
She feels betrayed,
kills him,
slices him up
and takes the tape.
I think the cremains
were Sydney's way of telling Ron
that he belonged
with his wife.
In death.
TRUFANT:
What's with the guitar?
I'm taking lessons.
Let me see it.
Okay.
I thought that I would play you
a little something.
Yeah.
That guitar was in
one of the boxes
from the thrift store.
We have that in evidence.
Those guitar strings are strong
and thin enough to
make those ligature marks
on the body and bedposts.
Hey, guys.
I got the infrared
photos from Autopsy.
There's some odd-looking
bruises on the victim's chest.
Check it out.
Looks like the killer
was pressing down
pretty hard on him
with something.
Well, the shape
of those bruises
look an awful lot
like Sydney's knee pads.
(coughing)
SIDLE:
Guitar's missing
four strings.
Just the amount needed
to tie up our vic.
This guitar is clean.
I'm not getting a single print.
Maybe DNA--
we'll have more luck.
SANDERS:
Wear pattern's a match.
Sydney was wearing these
knee pads when she killed him.
See, Cam? We're closer to
getting you out of here.
Today?
Few days at the most.
And I'll come live
with you, right?
Where else would you go?
(chuckles)
What are they doing here?
REED:
Hey, Camryn.
Ms. Preston, we need you
to come with us.
Why?
We can talk
about it downtown.
Please don't go.
Don't worry, I'll be back
here for you, okay, Cam?
No, I'll come with you.
Just let me go.
I don't want to be here alone.
Well, I'll stay here with you.
If you want.
We'll order a pizza
up in here. I don't care.
We can watch a movie or
something. You hungry?
Everything's going
to be okay, Cam.
Hey, it's going
to be all right.
This is bordering
on harassment.
I didn't do
anything wrong.
You haven't been
honest with us.
I told you
everything I know.
About Serina and Julie
and Tara and Deanna,
but not about
these other women.
I believe this
is the reason
you broke up with Ron.
You found these audition
tapes, and you snapped.
Maybe I did.
Here's this-this
geeky business guy,
who wasn't my type at all.
Wasn't out
in the club every night,
or-or spitting
mad game at me.
I fell in love
with him anyway.
Till I found out
he was the shadiest
of them all.
I felt angry, betrayed.
I didn't want anyone to know
I fell for something
so stupid,
including you guys.
All right.
Are these
your knee pads?
Yeah.
Is this your guitar?
Yes.
All right.
The guitar is missing
four strings.
We believe those strings
were used to tie Ron down.
The knee pads were used
to hold him down
while he was choking
on his wife's remains.
I left these things back
there at the house.
And then you went
back for them.
Decided to pack up
a few boxes of Ron.
You know, you sound
real crazy right now.
No, crazy is what we found
when we processed
the knee pads for DNA.
Inside the knee pads, we found
DNA from two contributors.
A major one
and a minor one.
You were
the minor contributor.
But that's weird.
They're your knee pads.
The major contributor
had half of Ron's DNA.
Half...--of Ron's DNA.
Now, who would have
half of Ron's DNA?
His daughter Camryn.
I used to let her use
my stuff all the time.
If someone besides you and
Camryn used the knee pads,
we would have found DNA.
We didn't.
That means either
you killed Ron,
or the two of you
killed him together.
I didn't kill anyone,
let alone use a
child to help me.
I love that little girl.
That means there's only
one other possibility, Sydney.
No, there's not.
There's got to be
an explanation.
Let me talk to her.
I knew you'd get me
out of that place.
I didn't get you out.
The police did.
Look...
they think we did something
bad to your dad.
But we didn't.
I know that.
You know that.
But they don't.
If you know what happened
to your Dad, you
have to tell me.
Or else we'll never get
to see each other again.
Did anyone come see your dad
at the house that night?
Maybe another girl?
I won't get mad,
I promise.
You can tell me.
Did you hear anything?
Did you see anything?
Please tell me.
Who else was there?
What happened, Cam?
Just tell me.
He got mad, Syd.
Just because I was
playing your guitar.
♪ ♪
Honey, turn it down.
I'm trying to do some work.
(music stops)
I told you to stop playing
with Sydney's stuff, didn't I?
Get rid of it!
There's no Sydney anymore!
Sydney's dead!
You get it?
My birthday parties were always
thrown by my grandparents.
And when they died,
they were thrown
by my babysitters.
Until you showed up.
I didn't have parents
until you showed up.
What are you trying to say?
(crying)
When he said you were dead,
I wanted him dead.
CAMRYN (over speaker): So after
he took his sleeping pills,
I snuck into his room
and tied him down.
Fed him my mom's ashes.
(Ron gagging)
Dragged him into the bathroom.
Put him in the boxes.
Got rid of your stuff,
like he wanted me to do.
And I left it all
on the minister's curb.
I hated my mom and my dad.
They didn't have me
to love me.
I just looked good
on their Christmas card.
(over speakers):
He belonged with her.
I belong with you.
I don't believe you.
Now do you believe me?
What are you doing?
Where are you going?
Are you mad?
(crying)
It's always very difficult to
accept the truth about people.
Especially about
people that we love.
Denying it doesn't
make it go away.
What's going to happen to her?
LANGSTON:
She'll be detained, tried,
and, if convicted,
she'll be in juvenile detention
until she's an adult.
After that, it's pretty much
up to the courts.
I love you, Syd.
Where you going,
looking so sharp?
My wife's getting married.
Hmm?
My ex-wife is getting married.
But you still
wear the ring.
Yeah.
I don't even know
why I do that.
I mean, we got
divorced two years ago.
I suppose it just represents
the best part of my life.
I thought you were
living the best part
of your life right now,
here with us.
Yeah, you're right.
I am.
(laughs)
(sighs heavily)
I loved her a lot, Nick.
I miss her. And...
when she came
to visit the other day,
I saw this look in her eyes
I'd seen many times before,
whenever she was really happy.
So...
So... you're happy she's happy.
Yeah, I guess that's one
way of looking at it.
Well, it's big
of you to go.
You're a good guy.
But you might want
to do yourself a favor--
take that ring off
before you go.