(scanner beeping)
You blind, lady?
Express checkout,
15 items or less.
I'm sorry, how much is it?
(Spanish rap music
playing outside)
Holly, please stop.
Sweetie, I'm sorry, okay?
I'm sorry...
What are you waiting for,
morning? Just pay!
(cell phone ringing)
I'm gonna have to write a check.
Aw, come on! It's cash only!
(Spanish rap music
playing outside)
(Spanish rap music playing)
Turn that crap down!
Your noise-- turn it down!
(turning up volume)
(three gunshots)
(gunshot)
(sirens approaching)
Well, I was needing to hit
the grocery store this morning.
(camera shutter clicks)
Looks like someone
had the same idea.
BRASS: Shots were fired,
these two went down.
Apparently,
this whole thing started
because of musical differences.
The smoker says the
gangbangers did it.
There was a patrol
car in the area.
They apprehended the gangbangers
in the lot, searched the car,
didn't find a gun.
Now, the
male victim--
his name is
Hector Cortero.
He's been working
here two weeks,
and he's a cart collector.
Prison tattoos.
Shooting could be gang related.
Yeah, now, the female victim--
we don't know
who she is yet,
but, uh, apparently,
she's just an unlucky customer.
One bag of groceries,
no purse,
no keys, no cell
phone in her pocket.
You know,
this could be a robbery.
Bagger's prints
are in the system,
but according to AFIS,
his real name is Hector Atoya.
He got a rap sheet?
Yeah, he did one year
for a no-hit drive-by.
This could be retaliation.
Second vic witnesses
and becomes collateral damage.
Bagger's only hit once.
She's hit three times.
Two small-caliber gunshot wounds
to the left chest,
one to the right eye.
Powder burns around
the wound suggest
that it was at close range.
Looks like an execution.
Which would make our soccer mom
the primary target, but why?
Hey, this, uh, jerk over here
just told me that
our female vic had a kid.
A kid?!
You get a description?
Yeah, little girl, about
three years old; blonde hair.
Oh, and she had
two bags of groceries.
She had a child
and two bags of groceries.
I'm thinking she had a car.
We have a void.
Maybe a tire
crushed those pretzels.
She puts the child in first,
gets one bag of groceries
in the car and then...
STOKES:
Bang.
Killer jacks her ride,
without knowing the kid's
in the backseat.
Yeah, this is Brass.
I'm down at the double 419
down at Honolulu.
We have a stolen vehicle
with an abducted
three-year-old
blonde female.
We now have a 418/427.
AMBER Alert will be forthcoming.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
You see these things,
you hear about them,
you never think
you'll be involved.
So the victim was
in your line?
Mm-hmm.
And had you seen her
in here before?
Was she a regular?
Oh, no. Uh-uh, no.
I never saw her before.
I've been working here
a few years.
She had the cutest little kid
with her, too.
She had too many items
for the express line, but I
don't think that was on purpose.
Just, she seemed
in a hurry and upset.
Upset?
Mm-hmm.
How upset?
First, I thought it was just
the guy behind her.
The "Express Line Nazi."
Yeah, yeah, we already
talked to him, but you think
she was upset about
something else?
Her hands were shaking.
The whole time, she seemed like
she was about to cry.
Oh, and her cell phone rang.
Oh, it did?
Mm-hmm.
She didn't answer it.
Express line, so she,
uh, she paid cash?
No. She didn't have enough.
I let her write a check.
Hey, Archie, it's Nick.
Listen, I got a name
and driver's license number
on our female victim.
Christine Moore.
Nevada DL number 2266758771.
2008 Dodge Caravan.
Plate: John-Henry-
Victor-George-357.
Anybody else
on the registration?
Next of kin, anything like that?
Daniel Moore.
Probably her husband.
But registration's secured.
Guy's got some kind of
protected status.
Hmm.
Well, that may be
what got his wife killed.
Thanks.
♪ ♪
Huh.
Looks like a .22.
Used to be the preferred caliber
for mobsters and assassins.
Nowadays they go for
a Glock four-oh.
Thank you, Ten Cent.
Why don't you
move him to Autopsy
and try not to bust any rhymes
on the way out.
I make no promises.
Agent Moore, FBI.
Uh, how can I help you?
Looking for the female vic
of the supermarket shooting.
She's in the washroom.
But I... Hey.
Whoa.
Hold it right there.
Agent Moore, FBI.
Yeah, congratulations.
Nobody comes in here
without my authorization.
Christine is my wife.
I'm sorry for your loss,
but that's all the more reason
for you not
to be in here.
No one should ever see
their loved one like this.
This is what I wanted
to see-- her eye.
It's probably postmortem,
if that's any consolation.
(yells)
Oh, geez.
Let me see that.
Keep your
hand elevated.
David, find
the first aid kit!
Hold this.
Agent Moore. Captain Jim Brass.
I came as soon as I could.
We have an AMBER Alert
out on your daughter.
But I need you
to keep it together.
Can you give me a second?
Yeah.
Hold it up.
Now, I know this is tough,
but when a wife
is murdered,
I got to ask the husband:
do you have an alibi
for last night?
I was on a case.
I can save you
a lot of time.
I know who killed Christine.
The name is Rylan Gauss.
And he has my daughter.
Hey.
So I got an AG waiver
on Christine Moore's
missing cell phone.
She got a message five minutes
before she was killed.
Checker at the market said
Christine received a call
that she didn't answer.
That was from
a Trent Moore.
Guy sounds young.
Maybe her son.
TRENT (frightened):
It's him, Christine.
It's Gauss.
I've seen him.
He's following you and Holly!
I-I don't know what to do!
He's going to kill us all,
just like Dad said!
I'm gonna give you some
temporary stitches
in a little bit,
but they won't hold long,
so I would advise you
to get an X-ray
and some antibiotics.
Rylan Gauss is a federal case.
I don't know anything about it.
What can you tell
me about him?
He's a serial pedophile.
He steals the little girls
right out of their beds.
The mother intervened
on the last one.
Gauss shot her
in the eye.
Ah, just like, uh...
Yeah.
...your wife.
I chased him
for ten years.
Six little girls.
I never found any of them.
Nothing to link him
to any of the crimes.
I was able to nail him for the
murder of the mother, though.
25-to-life.
How'd the guy get
out of prison?
52 days ago,
the conviction
was overturned.
The appeals court tossed out
the lead batch analysis
that the Bureau used to
link the murder bullet
to Gauss' live ammo.
Has he contacted you
or threatened you?
Me and my family.
Given his M.O.,
my daughter doesn't
have much time.
And I don't even
want to think...
All right,
enough already, okay?
We're done.
Okay, take
it easy.
Thanks a lot, Doc.
Yeah.
Is there anyone else that
Gauss, uh, may be after?
I have a son
from my first marriage.
What's his name?
Trent.
Hey, Trent, it's Dad.
You call me back immediately.
Katie, it's Mr. Moore.
Could I speak
with Trent, please?
You sure he's not out
on a delivery or...?
No, when you see him,
you make him call me.
No, it's an emergency.
Trent didn't show up
to work today.
It's not like him.
Let's go.
(sirens whooping)
Trent?!
Las Vegas Police!
Trent?
He has Trent.
If Gauss was here,
he would've shot you
coming through the door.
You got to ratchet it
down a notch,
okay?
Control, this is Brass. I need
an APB out on Rylan Gauss,
white male in his 30s,
armed and dangerous.
Bastard's got my whole family.
(gun cocks)
Ready?
Rylan Gauss, Vegas PD!
We got a warrant!
It's all clear.
We'll take it
from here, boys.
Thank you.
If I was Gauss, out for revenge,
I'd kill Agent Moore's wife
and his teenage son.
And take the little girl,
'cause I get off on it.
Yeah.
Check the bed.
Nothing but porno mags.
Where else could he hide her?
Let's tear the place apart.
SIDLE:
Looks like the point of entry.
There's some granular trace
on the sill.
It's corn starch.
From cheap latex gloves.
That's Gauss' M.O.
He always wears them.
Guy comes in through the
window, he jimmies it open
with a chisel-- that's what
that mark is, right there.
Agent Moore,
with all due respect,
you need to back off
and let me do my job.
You're... overlaying
my shoe impressions.
It's not going to be that
hard to distinguish, okay?
Gauss wears a size 10,
Nosumi soles.
Agent Moore?
You are contaminating
my crime scene.
Hey, buddy.
We get it, okay?
The crime scene investigator
is a professional.
She's working as fast
as she can, all right?
Well, I've seen it
too many times, okay?
Cop-fast turns
into hostage-late.
Hey, hey, back off!
All right? Back off.
I'll take care of
Gauss myself, then.
BRASS:
Let him go, Mitch.
Go ahead, get out of here.
Looks like we got a pill dump.
People don't usually
throw away narcotics
unless they have to.
Olanzapine and aripiprazole.
Trent Moore was on meds,
antidepressants.
Hmm.
So Rylan Gauss flushed them?
It's a good way
to control a hostage.
He could've kept a few,
used them to force
the kid's cooperation.
That's assuming that
Trent Moore is still alive.
The agent who delivered
these files said that
Daniel Moore is the FBI's
top pedophile hunter.
Ironic-- his own kids
get snatched.
Yeah, well, not so ironic if one
of the guys he's been chasing
decided to turn the tables
on him.
All right, the offender profile
says that Rylan Gauss
started in his early 20s,
followed a typical escalation
pattern-- indecent exposure,
couple of burglary charges.
HODGES:
Social Services investigated
an incident involving
a female cousin.
Four years old.
Gauss' parents
wouldn't cooperate.
I hate it when the families
protect these guys.
All right, well,
let's look for anything
about how long he usually
kept the girls,
or where he might
have taken them.
Hey, Nicky.
I got something.
It's a, uh...
clothes hanger made into
some kind of a tool.
Maybe for fishing something
out of a tight space?
Let me see that thing.
Yeah, there's something
behind this panel.
If it's kiddy porn, we got him.
An Elephant Named Herman.
My Puppy Dog Tale,
Kitty Cat Clues?
Children's read-aloud books.
They never caught Gauss
with any evidence
from his victims.
Personal items belonging
to the missing girls
disappeared just prior
to their abductions,
including children's books.
The items disappeared
while the victims
were playing in the park.
Gauss selects his victims
from local parks.
That's where he does
his shopping.
The Animal Fair.
He didn't just go out
and buy these.
Looks like they got
some years on 'em.
Maybe the belonged
to the victims.
They could be trophies.
Print 'em.
(phone rings)
This is Catherine.
Is there a park
near your location?
Yeah, we passed one
as we were driving
into the neighborhood. Why?
Gauss doesn't keep
his victims long.
And when he's done, he goes back
out hunting in parks.
There he is right there.
What the hell is
Agent Moore doing here?
Gun!
WILLOWS:
Agent Moore, put your gun down!
(gun cocks)
WILLOWS:
Stand down!
GAUSS (grunting):
Get off me.
Where is she?!
Where's who?
Where's Holly Moore?
I don't even know who that is!
Fine. You're under arrest.
GAUSS:
Let go of me.
(kids laughing,
shouting on video)
What's that about?
It's not illegal
to make a video.
That-that's a cute little girl.
I wish I had one just like her.
What were you doing
in the park, Rylan?
On a play date?
After you were done
with Holly Moore?
I spent five years
in prison.
I like parks,
open spaces.
I like to look at pretty things.
Where's Holly Moore?
Is that any relation
to a Daniel Moore?
Come on. You know it is.
You threatened her whole family.
Oh, did you lose that sweet
(over intercom):
little girl of yours, Daniel?
I'm sorry.
Oh, but you have two children,
so you still have one left,
right?
BRASS:
Yeah, right.
Let's talk about Trent Moore.
He certainly had a lot
to say about you.
TRENT (recording):
It's him, Christine.
It's Gauss. I've seen him.
He's following you and Holly!
I don't know what to do!
He-he's going to kill us all,
just like Dad said!
No, no, no.
No, that's a frame-up.
I went to prison for a crime
I didn't commit.
It didn't work the first time,
and he's trying to get me again.
He accused me of being a psycho.
Me, a psycho?!
The guy stalks me
my whole life!
He's the sick one!
You hear that, Daniel?!
You're the sick one!
So where were you last night?
Oh, last night?
Yeah.
Um, I was in a...
a bar, the Red Lamp,
off of Fremont.
The bartender's name
was, um, Terry.
Talked about how he needs
a new head gasket for his car.
He'll remember the conversation.
You just have to ask him.
Feel pretty good
about that, huh?
What do you think?
You're just gonna waltz out
of here, whistling a tune?
(whistles "The Animal Fair")
♪ I went to the animal fair ♪
♪ The birds and the beasts
were there ♪
♪ And the big baboon
by the light of the moon ♪
♪ Was combing his auburn... ♪
♪ Hair. ♪
I bet you know all the
words to that, don't you?
Yeah, we found
your stash of books, buddy.
And the lab guys
are going over
the prints right now.
And I'll tell
you something.
If we find one print
that matches up
with any of those
missing girls,
that'll be your last walk
in the park.
(siren wails)
MITCHELL: AMBER Alert picked up
the Moore minivan.
Car seat, no little girl.
SIDLE: The grocery store
is across town,
but we're walking distance
to Gauss's place.
Van's out of gas.
I have cookie crumbs
on the car seat
and half a juice box.
Half a sandwich, egg salad.
From Cordon's Ranch Market,
dated yesterday.
Christine Moore must have
bought it.
How many three-year-olds
do you know like egg salad?
I don't know any
three-year-olds,
but I do know that
if Christine didn't eat it,
and Holly didn't eat it,
then whoever was driving
this car must have.
Right?
Gauss.
♪ ♪
(computer beeps)
Ran the sandwich cellophane
against Gauss's prints.
No match.
Whoever ate the sandwich
took the girl.
If it wasn't Gauss, who was it?
The books we found in Gauss's
apartment had no prints.
They're in no way a connection
to any of these missing girls.
You gotta be
kidding me.
No, sir, I'm not.
All we found were traces of
cornstarch between the pages.
Yeah. Because Gauss
wears latex gloves.
He sits there torturing
these little girls
while he's reading to them
from their own favorite books.
I advise you not to leave town.
Oh, no, I'm not going anywhere.
Just keep Mr. FBI away from me,
or I'll have to get
a restraining order.
GAUSS:
Oh, hey.
Uh, I hope your kids
are all right, there, Danny.
You know,
all that time wasted on me.
Only have yourself
to blame.
Only yourself.
You're just going to let him go?
If we do anything now,
it'll only come back
to hurt us when we
do try to nail him.
When is that going to be?
Jim! He just as much admitted
that my kids are dead.
Hey, when I put him in prison,
he's gonna stay there!
Not going to get out
on some technicality.
And by the way, his alibi
checks out, you know.
Not only with the bartender,
but several patrons who he
was drinking with all night.
Rylan Gauss didn't
kill your wife!
He was in a bar.
MOORE:
Gauss is the only angle.
You heard Trent's voice mail.
Gauss is stalking my family,
and now you're just going
to let him go.
Hey, file a complaint.
I'll have him arrested.
Are we on the same side
here anymore?
(sighs, groans)
Is it just me, or does he
not seem that broken up
about his dead wife?
It's his focus;
it's all about Gauss,
even when the evidence
points away from him.
You know, Nicky, I've known a
lot of guys like Daniel Moore.
When things go bad, both
professionally or personally,
it's always the bastard
that got away.
And Rylan Gauss makes
one hell of a boogeyman.
Hey, Catherine.
I just got off the phone
with Christine Moore's sister.
She called to arrange
release of the body
to a mortuary in Wichita.
Isn't that usually
up to the spouse?
Unless the spouses are in
the middle of an ugly divorce.
Did Agent Moore mention that?
No, he left that out.
Yeah, that's what I figured.
So I gave her my best Quincy,
and she was more than happy
to rat out her brother-in-law.
Christine was asking for sole
custody of her daughter,
and filing for guardianship
of her stepson.
Guardianship?
Trent's 18.
He's been living on his own.
Christine was going
to court to prove
that Moore was
an unfit father.
According to her sister,
the plan was
to move both kids
back to Kansas.
Okay, well...
If Daniel Moore weren't FBI,
we'd be looking at him
for the murder of his wife.
Jim? I need you to verify
the alibi for Daniel Moore.
AKERS:
Good call, Cap.
Agent Moore's car is
parked around back.
It's still warm.
Rylan Gauss's apartment is the
last place this guy should be.
Let's hope he didn't
do anything stupid.
Drop it.
Now!
My gun hasn't been fired.
You can check it.
I want your backup piece.
It's in the small of my back.
I'm reaching now.
Two fingers.
Son of a bitch was down
when I got here.
Not that I didn't come here
looking to kneecap him.
Torture him until he told me
where my kids are.
But unfortunately,
someone beat me to it.
Yeah, right.
Let's go.
ANDREWS:
The pills you collected from
Trent Moore's bathroom floor
are antidepressants, but they're
also used in combination
to treat emerging schizophrenia.
Do we know if the kid had
any psychological problems?
No, we don't. He was living
alone, holding down a job.
Not atypical.
When the disease becomes
full-blown in adulthood,
medications ramp up in
proportion to the increase
in delusions and paranoia.
Agent Moore never mentioned
that his son is schizophrenic.
He's got a bad habit
of leaving things out.
I know we think Gauss killed
Trent, but if he didn't,
and Trent's been off his meds
for the past 24 hours,
then there's a
good probability
he's in the middle of a
full-blown psychotic episode.
Sandwich wrapper.
Trent likes egg salad.
Which puts him in the van,
when Christine and Holly
came out of the supermarket.
He was probably there
the whole time.
Question is,
what was he doing in the minivan
with Christine and Holly,
at 4:00 a.m.?
Whatever the reason,
he witnessed the shooting.
PHILLIPS:
Three GSWs to the torso.
Small caliber.
Same as the supermarket.
Well, if Agent Moore shot Gauss,
did he also shoot his wife?
PHILLIPS: They were going
through a nasty divorce.
Position of the body suggests
he was hit as he entered.
Agent Moore must've
been lying in wait.
But how? Where's the .22?
We didn't find it on him.
So why ditch a throw-away,
and then come back
and stand over the body with
your service weapon out?
Fast First Deliveries.
Agent Moore's son
works for a messenger service.
That wasn't here before.
74% of children who are abducted
are dead within three hours.
It's been 24.
So the longer we sit here
talking about what I didn't do,
the less chance I have
of ever seeing them again.
I know the numbers, all right?
I want to talk about Trent.
Your son is a
clinically diagnosed
paranoid schizophrenic.
My son, Trent, is fine.
He's just fine.
What are you talking about?
We found psychotropic
meds in his apartment.
Now, clearly, he's under
psychiatric treatment.
The meds just make you crazy.
I told Christine
he didn't need to take them.
Oh, and this is based on what,
your experience
as a psychoanalyst?
Don't push that angle on me.
You know the job.
We hunt down these scum
who torture and rape children.
And you just got to suck it up.
'Cause there's no little pill
that's just going to make
this world a better place.
You know, your behavior has
been erratic since I met you.
They say that mental illness
runs in families.
Okay, come on, here it comes:
Everybody drinks the Kool-Aid,
now-- Christine, you,
$200 shrinks.
Well, not me.
And not my son.
We're the crazy people now?
My son and I are crazy,
while Rylan Gauss is sane?
Go to hell.
Gauss is dead.
You want to know
what's really crazy?
We have evidence that Trent
was in Gauss's apartment.
Now, does your
son have access
to a small-caliber firearm,
specifically, a .22?
Gauss was killed with a .22?
As was Christine,
as was the bagger.
Now, we're pulling slugs
from the autopsy right now,
and I think we're going
to get a match.
Trent was with Christine,
in the minivan,
at the grocery store, at
the time of the shooting.
Now, what is Trent's
relationship with
his little sister Holly?
I refuse to believe this--
any of it!
Well, let me tell you
what I believe, okay?
Trent was not kidnapped.
He stopped taking his meds.
He's having a
psychotic episode.
He killed Gauss.
And as hard as this is to say,
I think he killed Christine.
Now the question is,
would he harm
his little sister Holly?
He loves Holly.
If Trent had Holly,
where would he take her?
My first wife died of cancer
when Trent was ten.
They were very close.
Sometimes, he just likes
to go back to the old house.
Where's the old house?
House is gone.
Now what?
SIDLE:
Well, there's a shed over there.
Roof over his head,
place to keep Holly warm,
a place to think.
This is it.
(whimpering)
I hear something.
(quietly):
I'd like to talk to him.
He's more comfortable
with women.
Okay.
I'll cover you.
Trent?
Are you in there?
My name is Sara.
I'm here to help you.
Where's Holly?
Is she okay?
Are you alone?
(sobbing)
Trent?
We've been looking for you
and your sister.
It's okay.
You're safe now, you
can put the gun down.
Rylan Gauss. Rylan Gauss did it.
He has my baby sister.
He killed Christine.
Okay.
Rylan Gauss
can't hurt you anymore.
Dad was right.
He's always right.
Have to always, always watch
for Rylan Gauss.
Did you used to play here,
in this shed?
When you lived here
with your mother?
(sobs)
I know she loved
you, Trent.
And she would want you
to put the gun down.
If you hurt yourself,
who's going to take
care of your sister?
Rylan Gauss was there.
I saw him.
Where did he take her?
He follows us.
He talks to me.
Gauss is dead.
You know that.
No.
He's me. I did it.
I killed her! I'm Rylan Gauss,
I'm Rylan Gauss, ask my dad!
Okay, okay, Rylan.
Okay, listen, put the
gun down, all right?
I kill little girls!
He-he has their pictures,
ask my dad.
Please, please, give
me the gun. Okay?
It's okay.
Give me the gun, Rylan.
Give it to me.
(sobbing loudly)
It's okay. It's okay.
It's okay.
♪ ♪
(knocks on door)
Any info from Trent?
No, no. Maybe when his meds
kick in,
he'll tell us
where Holly is,
but at the moment,
he's Mark David Chapman
shooting John Lennon
thinking he's John Lennon.
I hope it's not too late.
Me, too.
I believe we have
an infestation.
Hmm,Cimex lectularius,
aka the common bedbug.
Where did you find this?
I processed the ball cap that
you found in Gauss's apartment.
Hey, do you know
if Sara found
any bedbugs
at Trent Moore's place?
Negative. Nor did I
see bugs in the shed,
but I did see bug
bites on Trent.
But we didn't find any
in Gauss's apartment.
Hey, are you sure
this didn't come
from your house
there, itchy?
No. My mother is very clean.
Maybe Trent picked them up
wherever he has Holly stashed.
Fire in the hole! Two shots!
WILLOWS:The bullets
that killed Rylan Gauss
came from Trent Moore's .22.
(three gunshots, Gauss groans)
Trent's gun does not match
the bullets
that killed Christine Moore
or the bagger at the market.
So there's another .22
in play?
Any leads on the shooter?
Trent told Sara it was Gauss.
Well, Christine Moore was shot
in the eye
at close range--
that's Gauss's M.O.
But we know that Gauss
wasn't the shooter.
So who else knew his M.O.?
Maybe a disgruntled husband
going through a nasty divorce
who's hunting a serial pedophile
for ten years
and trying to put back in
prison for good.
Maybe somebody like that.
Thanks, Catherine.
I'll get back to you.
Okay, so what happened?
You and Christine
had an argument, huh?
You were sitting around
watching, waiting.
You watched her
pull out of the garage.
She was leaving in
the middle of the night,
she was leaving you,
and she's taking
your kids with her.
But what you didn't know
was Trent was in the car.
Did Trent tell you
where Holly is?
Trent doesn't even know
where he is.
He doesn't even
knowwhohe is.
Most of the time
he thinks he's Rylan Gauss.
A parent's obsession
becomes a kid's delusion.
Trent thinks Gauss
killed Christine.
But you and I know different.
I just wanted to give Trent
a normal life.
And I wanted justice
for those girls.
Somewhere in between, I just
ruined everything I ever loved.
Look, you gotta be honest
with your kid.
You gotta tell him
straight up
what happened in
that grocery store parking lot,
and maybe shock him
into reality,
because little Holly's
three years old
and she's out there alone
and we don't have
much time.
You and I both took an oath
to protect the innocent.
Well, here's the time.
You gotta confess
to your son.
You gotta tell him
that Rylan Gauss wasn't the only
bad guy in his life.
(door shuts)
I killed them:
your daughter, your wife!
No, you didn't.
You're Trent.
You're my son.
And you love Holly
and you loved Christine.
He broke into my apartment
and told me he was
coming after them.
I fought him,
but I couldn't stop him.
MOORE:
It's not real.
It was you...
thinking you were Rylan Gauss.
That's why I went
to Christine...
to warn her.
To-to save Holly.
He killed them, Daddy, like
you always said he would.
Trent, look at me.
Where's your sister, hmm?
'Cause I know you took her
someplace safe.
Rylan Gauss took her.
He took her.Itook her.
I took her.
Trent, stop it!
You are not Rylan Gauss.
You are my son.
Rylan Gauss, Rylan Gauss,
Rylan Gauss.
Son, you killed Rylan!
You did it!
Rylan Gauss is dead.
You were at the supermarket
with Holly...
...and you sawme.
Not Rylan Gauss, me.
Daniel?
(three gunshots)
(gunshot)
MOORE:
I didn't know you were there.
I wanted to put Gauss away
for good.
I didn't want Christine
to take you away from me.
(gunshot)
Now tell me...
where's your sister?
Where's Holly, hmm?
I don't know.
She's gone.
She's gone. I-I lost her.
(sobbing)
I lost her!
Well, we got
our confession.
I'd rather we had
the little girl.
STOKES: Archie looked
for surveillance
in the supermarket
parking lot.
Came up empty.
But?
But he was able to catch
Christine's minivan
on a traffic cam.
Check it out.
Trent was driving the van.
Traffic cam picked this up
ten minutes after the shooting.
Trent turned north
off of Honolulu onto Glenwood.
That van's really booking.
So, after Christine was shot,
Trent panicked.
Thought that Rylan Gauss
was after them.
And he was trying
to protect his sister.
Well, after he turned
onto Glenwood,
he disappears off the radar.
If he stashed her somewhere,
I might be able
to get you an area.
So he stopped
somewhere in the 'hood.
WILLOWS:
It's a good-sized area.
Yeah, but he was running out
of gas.
He was scared.
He didn't have
a lot of money.
He needed a safe
place for Holly
so he could
go after Gauss.
Maybe a motel.
Yeah, maybe one
with bedbugs.
I'll call Environmental Health,
check out the complaints
at the motels in the area.
No luck.
What do you got?
The manager
recognized Trent,
but he didn't recognize
the little girl.
Room seven.
Bedbugs.
She was here.
(girl crying in distance)
Las Vegas Police.
(speaks Spanish)
STOKES:
Yes, yes, we are looking
for the little girl.
The young man asked me
to watch her for
a little while
but he never
came back.
It's okay.
Come on out there.
I didn't know what to do.
I took care of her.
No, you did
the right thing.
Hi, Holly.
My name is Jim.
Boy, we've been looking
all over for you.
Come on. I'm gonna take
you home. Come on.