Previously on CSI:
WILLOWS: Haskell reached
out from prison,
said he had something to offer
on the Dr. Jekyll case.
BRASS: Were you two gonna
fly this over my head?
This was my decision, Jim.
Hey, last time I checked,
CSI worked for me.
You need me;
I don't need you.
I give you good information.
I got you to the place.
STOKES:Go back there and
see what that guy's going.
(gunshots)
Clark!
Come on, I'll buy you
a drink at P.J.'s.
I'll catch up to you.
You killed Jekyll.
You look like you came out
of it relatively unscathed.
Good-bye, Nate.
(groaning)
(weak, gasping breaths)
(gasping weakly)
Haskell...
(alarm blaring)
MAN:
Get in there!
(electrical crackling, buzzing)
I need emergency
to lockup right now.
Come on. Come on...
Let's move!
HASKELL:
Ray! Ray! Ray!
Come on!
Ray!
Lockdown!
WILLOWS:
Ray.
Ray, it's Catherine.
It's okay.
You're gonna be just fine.
EMT: All right, guys, watch out.
We're coming through!
Stay with me, Ray.
Get set up.
NURSE: I've tried
paging ultrasound.
They're not responding.
Go another one
coming in-- watch it!
DOCTOR:
Call respiratory--
I'm gonna need
to intubate him.
Okay, set him here.
DOCTOR:
Ray, can you hear me?
NURSE:
Respiratory on the way.
Can you hear me?
Ray?
He can wait.
DOCTOR: He's seizing... Give me
five milligrams of Perced.
Open the I.V.-- wide open.
NURSE: I'm going to start
a second line,
try to get some blood.
(alarm beeping)
TECH:
BP's 70/40.
Pulse is 140.
He's crashing.
DOCTOR:
Prep O.R.
Gotta open him up,
see what's going on inside.
Call X-Ray!
Got a stat chest!
Ray...
would you like
to pray together?
Don't be ashamed.
All the others did.
(panting, gasping)
You're gonna be
all right, Ray.
STOKES:
You're gonna be all right.
You're gonna be okay.
(echoing): Ray... you're
gonna be all right.
You're gonna
be all right.
DOCTOR: Call the O.R., tell 'em
we're on the way right now.
You're gonna be okay.
All right, let's
move him. Here we go.
TECH:
Clear, please!
(quietly):
I know your heart's
in the right
place, Nick,
but the family,
would be more comfortable
if you weren't here.
Now, I've been
where you are,
I know how you feel,
but sometimes
the best thing is
just to walk away.
Okay?
That's the right thing.
ECKLIE: Officer Franklin Clark
died a hero.
He wore the badge proudly,
and he saw his life
tragically cut short
when he put duty
ahead of all else.
He will be remembered
as a family man...
as a friend...
and all of us who knew him,
who will always remember him,
we stand shoulder to shoulder
in honoring his memory.
To Officer Clark's children,
Tarik and Brandon,
we promise you today...
(over radio): that we will never
let you forget
what a great man your dad was.
Go back there and see
what that guy's doing.
ECKLIE: And as you stand
with your family...
...know that we
are your family, too.
You will never be alone.
OFFICER:
Atten-hut!
Ready...
(bagpipes play "Amazing Grace")
...fire!
Shotgun!
Fire!
(rifles fire)
STOKES:
Clark!
(rifles fire)
Fire!
Quarter arms.
DISPATCH (over radio):
Control advising all units,
Officer Franklin Clark,
P-number 4-3-5-2-8-4--
(voice breaking):
secure, final.
(bagpipes continue playing
"Amazing Grace")
("Amazing Grace" continues
in distance)
(quiet, rhythmic clicking)
(clicking)
(people screaming)
STOKES: No, no, go back,
go back, go back!
(gunshots)
There's another bomb!
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
ECKLIE:
Yeah, three explosions, yes.
Two fatalities, about, uh,
a dozen injured,
three critical.
Well, it could have been
a lot worse.
No, Mr. Mayor, I'm not trying
to minimize the situation.
Look, do yourself a favor,
turn on your television.
Nicky... can you hear me?
Tinnitis.
(vomits)
It's temporary.
So is the nausea.
Normal after you get hit
with a blast wave.
(loudly): I think I popped
a couple stitches.
What tipped you off?
What?
What tipped you off
about the explosion?
Periplaneta Americana.
Cockroaches?
Yeah, they were
all over the van--
you know,
daylight's not
really their thing.
I think they
were attracted
to the clicking sound
of the detonators,
like a mating call
or something.
Hey, thank God
Okay.
you're okay, Nick.
Nate Haskell did this.
And if he'd stayed in
prison where he belongs,
I wouldn't have lost
two of my men.
It's always easy to quarterback
after the fact.
Bomb squad says
it's all clear, it's yours.
All right, well,
I'm gonna need video
from all the news teams.
On the ground
and in the air.
Okay.
Catch up with you later.
Oh, Nicky, why are
you flanking me?
You've already been
a hero today.
Go to the hospital.
I can't hear you.
The hospital!
Not so fast.
This jacket's evidence.
Now, that was
my best suit.
Have you seen your car?
NEWSMAN:
Investigators are combing
through the debris,
looking for clues that might
identify the perpetrators
of this horrendous crime.
No one has stepped forward
to claim credit
for the bombing.
Sources within LVPD admit they
have no solid lead...
How you feeling, man?
(sighs quietly)
How's Nick?
He's lucky to be alive.
LANGSTON:
That's the fourth
bomb dog in five minutes.
Should we evacuate?
Just a precaution.
(labored breathing)
You know what this
button's for, right?
Morphine clouds my thinking.
Okay.
You're thinking
Haskell did this?
But how'd he do it?
I mean, his mail
and his phone calls are
monitored by the penitentiary.
He has no contact
with other inmates.
He'd have had to
have outside help.
I mean, he's used
acolytes before.
I need my laptop...
and my cell phone, Jim.
Come on, Ray, give it a rest.
Don't forget my charger.
Okay.
I still owe you that drink.
Jim...
you talk to Haskell,
you play your game, not his.
(quietly):
Okay.
Man's got an amazing attitude
for a guy who lost a kidney.
Does he know that?
Mm-hmm.
Fortunately,
God gave him two.
How's Ray?
He's gonna make
a full recovery.
Thank goodness.
I want Ray to live
a long, long time,
so that every time he unzips
his pants to take a leak
he'll think of me.
Yeah, he'll
always remember
what a putz you are.
You know, you're
a smart guy, Nate.
You've been three steps ahead of
us during this whole game.
Four.
Well, five.
But you're here
to see if I decided to go out...
with a bang.
Did you?
What's different about you?
This has been so nice.
You're my first visitor.
Let me guess.
The blast turned over
this new kinder, gentler leaf
in you.
If you don't mind,
I'd like to eat my lunch.
Could you untie me, please?
Bon appétit.
Your next meal will
be through a hole
in a cell door.
Take him back to Ely.
(sighs)
WOMAN:
Those, uh,
prills are unexploded
ammonium nitrate
from your van bomb.
You know, you're lucky
only one of those barrels
went off,
or we'd be scraping you up
off the pavement
with a putty knife,
or a spatula.
Yeah.
New bomb tech, huh?
You're Monahan, right?
Anyone crazy enough
to wave a pistol
at 100 armed cops...
You can call me Kacey.
Copy that.
All right, the brains
of the bomb
are usually
within the first 20 yards.
Heavier stuff
flies farther.
Detonators tend
to be light.
And the brains should lead us
to our big bad bomber.
Bomb was designed
to maximize chaos... injuries.
Well, the good news--
it's left us a lot of evidence.
That looks like
brain matter.
(inhales)
Cell phone detonator.
I haven't seen one
of these since Iraq.
Does a cell phone trigger
make a clicking sound?
Not usually.
We have got
three different bombs.
Which means, there's possibly
three detonators.
WILLOWS: This is a composite
image of the bomb site.
GCMS identified residue
from the casket
and tombstone bombs
as smokeless gunpowder.
Specifically,
Nosumi Pro Formula Four.
You can buy it at any gun store.
What it tells us is that
the first two bombs were
low explosive devices.
Low explosive. Why?
Easy to acquire, easy to build.
The van bomb's
a different story.
It's high-explosive.
ANFO--
Ammonium Nitrate, Fuel Oil.
Same stuff that destroyed
the Federal Building
in Oklahoma City.
WILLOWS:
Yeah, it was the kill bomb.
Well, how do we think
the bombs got there?
The casket bomb
was placed
with Officer Clark's body
at the funeral home.
It's open 24/7.
There's no security.
The Claymore was placed
in a flower arrangement,
which was delivered
by a company called, uh,
Bouquet Builders. Now,
they reported their van stolen
two days ago.
Let's go back
to the low explosive devices.
First one--
the casket bomb, was designed
to scare, not to kill.
(explosion, people screaming)
LANGSTON: Cops are trained
to take cover under fire.
The only cover
was the tombstones,
right in the path
of the second bomb.
There was only one way to go--
right into the path
of the van bomb.
(beeping quietly)
(people screaming)
Shock.
Run.
Kill.
Bombers are unlike any other
criminals, except poisoners.
They plan meticulously,
they nurse long grudges,
and they retaliate
far out of proportion
to any injury
they feel they've received.
That sounds like Nate Haskell.
Nate Haskell likes
to kill people one at a time.
Yeah, he gets off
on the intimacy
of inflicting pain
and slow death.
He's not one for mass murder.
Are you saying it
wasn't Nate Haskell?
Yes.
Then who the hell is it?
Someone with a grudge
against cops.
(groans)
(sighs)
Go home, Nicky.
You're tired.
No, I'm-I'm... I'm okay.
I mean, everybody's
tired, right?
Everybody wasn't shot
and then blown up.
(laughs quietly)
It's not funny.
I almost lost you.
I almost lost Ray.
And I don't want
to lose this case
because you're
maxed out.
You need to sit down with
the department shrink.
Oh, come on.
It's mandatory after
a shooting incident.
Yeah, I-I know the rules.
But it's not about rules, Nicky.
It's about you.
Look, the time I waste
talking to a shrink is time
I could be helping you out
on this case.
You can't just John Wayne this
like everything else.
(sighs)
After losing Warrick,
I thought, if I just
worked hard enough,
if I focused completely
on the cases
that I... I wouldn't have
to think about his death.
There isn't
enough work in the world...
I realized
that I couldn't do my job
without talking to somebody.
I never knew that about you.
Well, I'm...
I'm good at hiding things.
Like you.
(sighs)
Just ask yourself
this, okay?
If you got a callout tomorrow
to the restaurant where
you got shot and
Officer Clark died,
could you focus?
Could you be there
for your team?
Would you want you
backing you up right now?
Make that call.
(camera shutter clicking)
Officers Morales
and Hooper.
Both had kids.
(camera shutter clicks)
This poor soul's been
through here twice.
Once in the line of duty,
and then a bomb.
Makes you want to slug someone.
And then some.
Explosive must have been
beneath his thorax.
Trauma lessens
as it moves out from there.
Mostly plastic and wire.
No shrapnel.
Consistent
with our theory
that the coffin bomb
was designed to cause panic.
I can't stop thinking
about his family.
Losing a husband
is horrible enough
without the funeral
ending up like this.
I spoke to his wife.
Told her he was already
in a better place.
Do you believe that?
I believe that
it helped her.
Hmm... Maybe Officer Clark
just helped us.
I may have found
the bomber's signature.
You see the way
the wires are twisted
and then soldered?
Well, if you put a wire
on a post and then twist it,
most people are happy with that.
This guy soldered it, too.
He didn't leave anything
to chance.
He is meticulous.
Maybe even OCD.
Sounds like you admire this guy.
(laughs)
Yeah, I admire the work.
Doc Robbins just pulled
this SIM card out of
Officer Clark's body.
You want to bet
that's from the cell phone
that detonated the casket bomb?
SANDERS:
Let's plug it in,
and see who reached out
and touched someone.
(beeping)
Hey, bomber, we got your number.
So the cell number came
back to a Thomas Rand.
He's a local kid.
A Marine deployed
to Afghanistan.
Says here he was
a demolition specialist,
4th Engineers, 1st Marines.
So the guy knows bombs.
Yeah, but if you look at
the bottom of the page,
he was killed in
action last month.
Well, maybe a friend or relative
is looking for payback, huh?
Well, that's just what
I'm going to ask his wife.
Mrs. Rand.
(clears throat)
Hello.
Thank you for coming in.
I'm Captain
Jim Brass.
Look, uh, I know your husband
was killed recently,
bravely serving our
country in Afghanistan.
I'm sorry for
your loss.
Yeah, that's what
the Marines said
when they came to the house.
The insurance agent...
Mrs. Rand, I know.
I... I'm a former Marine.
I served in Vietnam.
I saw a lot. I lost
a lot of friends.
I understand your anger.
My daughter is four,
and I have a son on the way.
All right.
What'd you do with your
husband's cell phone,
the 0-1-0-1 number?
I don't know.
I-I gave most of his stuff
away to charity.
Why?
Because it was used
to detonate a bomb
at a funeral.
Th-that policeman's funeral?
The-the one that's on the news?
Exactly.
So, what'd you do with it?
Who'd you give it to?
A-A community center.
Um, it was a charity drive.
They were collecting
cell phones for soldiers.
Which community center?
MAN:
Are you ready for a new America?
Where hard work pays off?
(indistinct shouts, cheers)
This country's been hijacked
by profiteers!
Big banks, Wall Street,
giant corporations.
They have a license to steal
at our expense.
(various shouts)
Their credit cards
keep us in debt.
That's it!
Their mortgages...
leverage the future
of our families.
So what I say is,
we stop playing their game.
(shouts, cheers)
That's right!
Stop paying our taxes that
pay for their failures.
Yes!
Cut up your cards!
Credit, driver's license,
Social Security.
They can't control you
if they can't find you.
(cheering, shouting)
Sure, there are those who say,
hold on there,
hold on there, Dr. Huxbee--
why can't we reason
with Washington?
HUXBEE: ...engage in
constructive dialogue,
change our country
from inside the system?"
Brother Ralph Harvey
went down that road,
and where is he now?
He's in jail!
Brother Ralph was
exercising his right...
to drive hisown car...
down a public road.
His crime: driving
without a license.
Ralph is no criminal!
He's a decent man.
He took me and my brother
when we didn't have anyone.
And now the government
took him away from us.
And why?
Because Ralph dared to live
as a new American.
And you see what happens
when we speak truth to power.
The profiteers send in
their mercenaries.
Las Vegas Police.
OFFICER:
I need everyone
to get up
against the wall
and let me
see your hands.
Your authorities
are not good here.
I'll give you authority
if you don't get up
against the wall.
HUXBEE: Uh, no, no resistance,
brothers and sisters.
Don't play their power game.
(clamoring)
(labored breathing,
monitor beeping)
Just say no, huh?
Hey, you pack a real...
mean right hook.
Like Gandhi,
I turn the other cheek.
Just wasn't mine.
Look, I been, uh...
analyizing the
blast patterns.
We've confirmed
one initial device,
followed by two secondaries.
It's all about timing.
If I'm the bomber,
I'm not gonna set off
those two explosions
unless all of my targets
are in the kill zone, right?
You think the bomber
had "eyes on."
He had to be there.
I've been looking for
him in the news footage.
Here's what I've found.
That is not Southwest.
No, it's a radio-
controlled model.
Here's what caught my attention.
1: The casket bomb goes off.
Cell phone detonated.
2: The Claymore.
At this point,
the plane clearly loses control.
3: The van bomb goes off.
Now...
a remote-controlled plane
dips and crashes
almost at the same time
that the last two bombs go off.
They were radio-detonated.
Probably by
the same controller.
Probably by whoever
was flying the plane.
Remote-controlled planes have
a range of about 2,500 feet.
That means those
last two explosions
could have been set off
from no more than a half a mile.
Bomber's in the wind,
but the plane isn't.
That's it, kiddo.
Have a seat.
You got a wallet on you, boss?
No I.D., no credit card.
Do you got anything
with your name on it?
I burned 'em.
Emancipated myself.
Okay, well, congratulations,
you're not gonna need 'em
where you're going.
Now, open up.
We're on the same side, sister.
I love this country,
revere our Constitution.
But dark forces are afoot.
Think about who
you really work for.
I work for the people
of Clark County.
Do you?
Shut up.
BRASS:
Released?
Half of these dingbats
were assaulting
a police officer,
including the one standing
in front of you now.
Yeah, I get it Jim,
but you found no weapons
or explosives on their premises.
Oh, a cell phone from
their center detonated the bomb,
so someone had to be involved.
Where's the evidence?
Well, I don't know--
CSI's working on it.
It takes time.
These guys got no I.D.
You let them go, they're
in the wind, it's buh-bye.
All right, we can legally
hold them until we process
the transitory evidence.
Lab is backed up, I'm not
inclined to approve overtime,
so... I can buy you
24 hours.
Okay.
SANDERS:
All right.
I'm here.
Got a perfect view
of the grave site.
How far away are you?
At least a football field.
You're still well within range.
Well, Ray, I don't see
any plane around here.
Maybe he took it with him.
Nobody ever looks up.
Looks up what?
Looks up looks up.
In the sky.
In "plane" sight.
(whirring)
You asked me if a
cell phone detonator
could make a click-click.
Answer: No.
But a radio-controlled
detonator...
(quiet, rhythmic clicking)
Are you hearing that?
I switched the frequency.
I found this 18 yards
from the van bomb.
It's a servo switch,
just like the one
that operates
this plane.
See?
It's clicking because
it's searching for a signal
from the radio controller
and not finding one.
I switched it
back to "A."
(whirrs)
And we are back
in business.
So some guy's innocently
flying this plane around,
he flicks a switch
and... he's a bomber?
(heavy sigh)
Somebody please
give me some good news.
That shiner'll go away
in about a week.
(groans)
The last two bombs
were radio-controlled,
detonated by whoever was flying
that model airplane around.
The better news is that
Greg got a print off of it.
Came back to an Alex McCann, 21.
Went through foster care.
He's already in
the system for B&amp;E,
couple of petties.
No address, but...
WILLOWS: We got a McCann
in custody--
a Jason McCann.
Yeah, yeah, that was one
of the people that I processed.
16 years old.
Could be a younger brother.
Certainly old enough
to be involved.
STOKES: Well, the owner
of Hank's Hobby Shop
said the kid that
bought that plane
fit Jason's description, so...
So let me get my hooks into him.
He's not gonna talk to you.
Okay, well,
are you gonna tell me
how to do my job again?
We know how well
that turned out, right?
I'm gonna tell you
how not to blow this.
In case you haven't noticed,
it's already blown.
All right, let me go.
What are you
gonna do, Nick,
give the kid a lollipop?
It's the least I can do
for Officer Clark.
I mean, I owe him
that much, don't you think?
Where's your gun,
your vest, your badge?
You off work or something?
Well, no,
I only wear my vest
when I'm in the field,
and you can't really have
your gun on in this room,
and I'm not a cop,
so I don't have a badge.
I just... have an I.D.
You still represent
the authority.
Everything I hate.
Just like...
you probably hate me.
No, what I hate's got
nothing to do with you, man.
You know what I
really hate right now,
it's kind of
eating me alive?
A few days ago,
a police officer lost
his life on my watch,
'cause I didn't have his back.
And he had a wife
and two kids.
When I went to the funeral
to pay my respects,
his family asked me to leave.
I hated that, you know.
But I got involved
in law enforcement
because I want to try
and help people.
And that's the only
reason I'm here, man,
is trying
to help you out.
Do you have
a brother named Alex?
(sighs)
Hm?
Well, if you really love him
and you don't want
any more people to die,
you need to go ahead
and tell me where he is
right now.
(sighs)
They're gonna kill him,
aren't they?
Not if I can help it.
I didn't have anything to do
with the bombs, I swear.
I just bought the airplane.
I believe you.
But what's the deal
with your brother?
When the cops arrested Ralph,
Alex snapped.
Ralph was like
a father to us.
He was a decent man.
And the cops treated him
like a lowlife.
So your brother's
waging war against
the entire
Las Vegas police force
because of the way
that Ralph was treated?
He told me
he was just gonna throw
a scare in the cops.
Not blow them up.
Okay, look, all you're
guilty of right now
is buying a model
airplane--
and that's not a crime,
last time I checked.
But it is a crime
to make bombs and go around
trying to kill people,
like your brother's doing.
So you got to go ahead
and tell me where
he is, Jason.
I can't.
Why not?
If you really want
to protect him,
you've got to help me
get him into custody
as soon as possible before
somebody else gets hurt.
Where is he?
He's got a house
in Old Henderson.
Where?
On Landon.
Landon.
Good man.
You better hurry.
That show at the funeral
was just fireworks
compared to what's coming.
I don't see
anybody inside.
Okay, I've got
to tell you, Nick--
that is a really bad idea.
Well, I appreciate you having
so much confidence in me,
but ARMOR's still
20 minutes out,
and according
to that kid Jason...
I get it.
We don't have time.
But can we just make sure
we don't blow us both up?
That's a good idea, yeah.
Trip wire.
Seriously?
Uh-huh.
There's no battery.
Okay.
We are in luck.
The circuit's not powered.
(door creaks)
MONAHAN (on phone):
Ray, we're inside.
Okay, we've got
nine empty bomb cases
and a bowl of ice.
Ice means he hasn't
been gone that long.
There's some white crystals
here-- it looks like some meth.
Hold on.
(crackling)
Kacey?
MONAHAN:
We're okay.
He's using TATP.
Triacetone triperoxide.
You pack those
pipes with it,
it'll bring down a casino.
Tell me more about the ice.
Well, you need a serious chill
to precipitate
the explosive but...
looks like our boy
didn't finish the job.
STOKES: Maybe this is
the reason why.
Hydrochloric acid.
Final mixer
in the TATP cocktail.
Bottle's empty.
Maybe Alex went shopping.
(blipping)
(alarm chirps twice)
(police siren whoops)
Alex McCann,
you're under arrest!
Get your hands in the air,
get down on the ground.
Get down on the
ground right now!
Son, drop the bag
and get down!
No... No, no, no!
(shots firing)
Nick, drop it.
Nicky!
Huh?
Drop it. You all right?
Yeah.
You all right?
Huh? Yeah.
OFFICER: Dispatch,
this is Ida three-two.
We have a male
suspect down.
Requesting EMS.
DISPATCH (over radio):
Ida three-two, copy that.
EMS has been notified.
He was planning to hit PD.
Well, you just saved
a lot of cops' lives.
(sighs)
Next time Brass tries
to beat you up,
or you beat yourself up,
remember that.
Well, the bomber's dead.
That's one less wack job
running loose in the world.
I call that a
good day's work.
Where are we with our friends
from the community center?
Well, none of them
had criminal records.
Nothing ties them
to the bombing,
so I let them walk.
Except the younger brother.
He had prior knowledge.
The D.A.'s going to
want to talk to him.
I didn't wake you, did I?
(chuckles)
I brought you
a little something.
Is it a tie?
Okay.
That's beautiful.
Thank you.
You're going to be
out of here in a few days.
It'll help you
get back on your feet.
When I lost my legs,
I had to let go
of some dreams.
I was never going
to be Fred Astaire.
Lost a little off my jump shot.
But I still dance
with my wife
and shoot hoops once a week.
I'm never going
to be a kidney donor.
Ray...
no matter how much we think
we can control in life,
there's always going
to be this much
we have
no control over.
When you accept that,
you can move on.
(sighs)
(phone beeps on)
I thought
you went home.
Oh, I'm trying.
I'm too tired.
(cell phone rings)
Where are we headed?
You're going home.
I'll take Greg.
(phone beeps off)
Hey.
Hi.
Where we headed, Andy?
Uh, just, uh,
follow your noses.
SANDERS: Phew!
Akers wasn't kidding.
I smell urine,
alcohol...
No decomp, though.
This is recent.
Caucasian male, between
30 and 50 years old.
It's hard to tell with
these homeless guys.
Somebody called it in
about, uh, 20 minutes ago.
You need some sleep, Lou.
Don't we all?
Blunt force trauma.
Looks like
somebody dragged him.
There's a pup tent and some
old bottles back there.
He might have been squatting.
Why don't you guys
take the blood trail?
I'll take
Mr. Aromatic.
Every so often, a trash run?
Kind of refreshing.
That's the spirit, David.
SANDERS:
Spatter.
Looks like
we found our primary.
There's the tent.
(flashlight switch clicking)
Damn.
Do you have any
extra batteries?
Why kill a guy and drag him into
the middle of an empty room?
Thanks.
David, wait.
Lou! Greg!
Don't touch anything!
We're okay.
Thanks.
It isn't over.