Baked Brie and
raspberry preserves.
It's a delight for the
eye and the palate.
(all laugh)
Well, my wife doesn't
just shine onstage.
Oh...
I told you,
the best restaurants in L.A.
couldn't hold a candle
to Gloria.
Oh, Phil.
He has a much higher opinion
of my cooking than I do.
(laughs)
No, it really,
it's so, so sweet of you guys
to invite us over.
Since Will and I moved
to town, we've...
had a hard time meeting people.
Well, you just haven't
met the right ones.
I'll say.
(laughs)
(all laughing)
Another drink-- you have to
allow a guest to do something.
Oh, hell,
it's not a school night, huh?
Oh... I don't have to drive.
(Gloria laughs)
GLORIA: Thank you.
PHIL: Thanks.
(conversing quietly)
(low murmurs)
Oh, I must...
I might have to skip the wine
at dinner.
I mean...
(laughs softly)
Oh, that's a
beautiful ring.
Thank you.
(laughs)
Phil has great taste.
Tell me, Gloria,
how did you meet your husband?
Oh, God, it's one of
those crazy stories. Um...
blind date, and somewhere
midway through the evening,
Phil and I realized
that we weren't the ones
the host was trying to set up.
(laughs)
I meant Ray.
How did you meet Ray?
Who... who the hell are you?
(Gloria whimpers)
(Phil mutters)
Phil!
(gasps)
(crickets chirping)
(no audio)
(phone ringing)
Langston.
WILLOWS (over phone):
Ray.
Cops found a body. John Doe.
Haskell?
Looks like his work.
They're holding the crime scene.
Where?
L.A.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
WILLOWS:
Detective Sosa?
Who's asking?
Catherine Willows with
the Las Vegas Crime Lab.
This is Ray Langston.
Thank you for calling us.
I didn't call you--
S.I.D. did.
Ask me, you people
just wasted a trip.
(siren wailing nearby)
SOSA:
Hey, Brody!
Vegas is here.
Willows. Langston.
Enjoy.
Welcome to L.A.
Another hour and I'd had
to get some bread.
Do you always eat
at your crime scenes?
Always keep
some in my kit.
Especially if I know
I'm going to be sharing.
They do like peanut butter.
And they really loved him.
Sorry, buddy,
you're evidence.
Excuse me.
LANGSTON:
Significant animal predation.
BRODY:
Little guy was hungry.
T.O.D.?
48 to 72 hours ago.
Here.
Looks like
12 sharp-force injuries.
All postmortem.
BRODY: We got word to be on
the lookout for Nate Haskell.
That's why I called you guys.
I went over Sosa's head.
Please tell me
I'm not going to lose mine.
Well, the last DJK murder victim
had ten postmortem stab wounds.
If it's Haskell,
he skipped ahead.
Nah, Haskell considers me
to be his 11th victim,
even though he didn't
get to stick me 11 times.
Well, thanks for holding
the crime scene, Brody.
We're going to need to turn him.
Excuse me, you Ray?
Yes. And you are?
I'm the guy who's going
to marry your wife.
(Gloria laughs)
All clear.
(indistinct radio transmission)
I'll call in S.I.D.
Ray, I-I don't think
that you should be here.
Let's see, uh...
I can have a car
take you downtown.
Hello! That's evidence!
WILLOWS:
Ray, what are you doing?
SANDERS: Condo security company
gave us access
to the surveillance files.
The time stamp here is 8:37.
Metadata says it's from
three nights ago.
I got Gloria and Phil
coming home,
but somebody else leaving...
intheircar.
WILLOWS: Well, there's no sign
of Gloria and Phil.
My vote's
for the trunk.
Greg, can you get us
a better look?
Whoa.
WILLOWS:
Tina Vincent.
Who?
Latest bride of Haskell.
WILLOWS:
Is there a passenger?
This angle's not helping us.
Maybe this will.
See if I can lose the fun house.
It's him. It's Haskell.
I thought you said
he changed his face?
We were wrong.
Guess I was wrong about
that wasted trip, huh?
WILLOWS: Greg, LAPD has given us
their full cooperation.
Get traffic cam footage
from three nights ago.
See if you can follow the car.
Copy that.
You have
my cooperation.
Don't forget,
it's still my city.
(helicopter blades whirring
nearby)
He gained their trust,
Catherine. He was here.
We'll find him, Ray.
And we'll
find Gloria.
"Three days and three nights
of Heaven on Earth.
"And then...
just Heaven."
Haskell's words.
It's what he does
with his victims.
It's already been 72 hours.
That means she's already gone.
We'll see what
the evidence says.
I don't think
I can do this, boss.
I'll call Sara.
I'll have a car take you
back to the airport.
Thanks.
LANGSTON:
Let's talk about something
you enjoyed-- your first kill.
You never forget your first,
but I think
that's a little intimate
for this stage
of our relationship.
LANGSTON:
Tell us your definition of fun.
Fun is taking something away
from somebody.
HASKELL:
Oh, Ray...
there is a moral
to this story.
Officer, would you mind
pulling up over here?
Sir?
There's a bar over here.
I want to have a drink
before I get on the plane.
Flight's in a half-hour.
There's a flight
to Vegas every hour.
I'll take the next one.
Look, you're welcome
to join me.
I'm on duty... sir.
(sighs)
I'll wait for you out front.
(phone line ringing)
(phone beeps)
LANGSTON:
Hey, it's Ray.
I know you're working.
I didn't expect you to answer,
but, uh...
you're the only one
I can talk to.
The only person who I think
will truly understand this.
At least,
I hope you'll understand
when I've done
what I have to do.
You know,
we all make choices...
live with the consequences.
The only person
I have ever loved...
(door opens)
is dead.
(continues over recording):
And now...
there's only one thing left
for me to do.
Good-bye, Al.
There's residue
on the glass.
They were drugged.
If Haskell's up
to his old tricks,
it's probably
Salvia divinorum.
I'll have the L.A. lab run it.
Did you meet S.I.D. Brody?
Yeah.
She seems familiar.
So, I found blood in the shower.
Looks like Haskell cleaned up.
I have yet to
process his gift.
I'll give
S.I.D. a hand.
Okay.
(distant siren wailing)
BRODY: Does this look
like high-velocity
blood spatter to you?
SIDLE:
Yes, it does.
Coroner's report said
Phil Baker was strangled
with a ligature--
probably his own tie.
Blunt-force trauma
to the head,
12 postmortem stab wounds--
I don't see all that
causing this.
SIDLE:
Gunshots maybe?
Tina Vincent popped
two people in Vegas.
I'm hoping that we don't have
to add Gloria to the list.
(insect buzzing)
You hear that?
What?
(buzzing continues)
Megaselia scalaris.
Little buggers corrupted
our crime scene.
(insects buzzing)
BRODY:
No gunshot.
They painted the wall.
So...
Haskell's M.O.: kill the man,
dump the body,
take the woman alive.
Hmm.
Oh... blood and tissue.
Postmortem stab wounds, anyone?
The flies weren't
the only artists in this room.
Phil Baker was
struck in the head,
then strangled.
Stabbed postmortem.
The blood
was the paint,
the body the brush.
Dragged him around,
created a Picasso.
You're thinking that all this
blood came from just one source.
Haskell wanted Langston
to feel the horror
of what happened in this room.
He wanted to get
inside his head.
Hey.
Your boy Sanders
helped us track down
the Bakers' car.
Dumped in K-Town,
blood in the trunk.
But no Gloria?
Way ahead of you.
I got guys searching
the park and all
around the observatory.
But you may need a
search party yourself.
Ray Langston ditched his
escort to the airport.
And this morning's little
"bull in a china shop" act
says he's dangerous.
Tell me he's not armed.
I don't want
any serial numbers.
Hey, I run
a respectable joint here.
Is that respectable
enough for you?
I also need a laptop.
Gates or Jobs?
Let me take a look in the back.
I'm throwing in
a holster for free.
PAWNBROKER:
That do it for you?
How much for the laptop?
Five more bills.
(long sigh)
Sold.
No negotiating?
Well, I like that.
Hey, Willoughby Observatory--
it's the best view
in town.
Nicky, I need you in L.A.
I can't find Ray.
He's not answering his phone.
Yeah, I know.
I'm worried.
He called the doc.
He didn't sound real good.
It sounds like
he's in a dark place.
Well, he's here somewhere.
We got to find him.
All right. I'm on my way.
I'll find his ass.
We opened up Gloria's
social network page.
Found she'd been tagged
in a friend's photo.
SIDLE:
We now know where
Gloria and Phil met
Haskell and Tina.
It was a benefit concert
four nights ago.
Gloria was the main attraction.
Gloria and Phil invited
Haskell and Tina for drinks
the next night.
"Willoughby J. Willoughby."
Is that supposed to be
some kind of joke?
Another of Haskell's
riddles, maybe?
Well, the postcard
that was left
at the crime scene
had a picture
of Willoughby Canyon
and Observatory on it.
So what's he
trying to say?
I don't know.
Maybe it has something to do
with this guy Willoughby
or some kind of
L.A. lore or history.
Oh, don't look at me.
I... always did
better in science.
SIDLE:
You know,
we do know somebody
who's into both.
Willoughby J. Willoughby
was a wealthy L.A. benefactor
who made his fortune
in shipping.
But the bulk of his profits
were thought to have come
from money-laundering.
Explains the
benefactor part.
Trying to clean
up his act.
Yeah, well, it didn't last.
'Cause in 1943, he shot his wife
in the head during an argument.
Attack on his wife.
I think I'm starting
to get the joke.
The postcard, the ring,
"Gloria in
Excelsis Deo."
Haskell wanted Ray
to come out and play.
So... some kind
of an invitation.
WILLOWS:
Except we're the ones
who are gonna
crash the party.
Greg, I want to know
everything there is to know
about Willoughby J. Willoughby.
Work your magic.
Do my best.
♪ ♪
(bag drops to ground)
(panting quietly)
You know why I'm here.
(indistinct radio transmissions)
Hey.
I drove straight
from the airport to
S.I.D., checked in.
Sara told me you'd be here.
Detective Sosa, this
is CSI Nick Stokes.
Hey, man.
Wow. Anybody left in
Vegas to catch crooks?
Yeah, there's still
a couple of us.
So, what's going on here?
Got a call. Shots fired.
Units responded,
found a Caucasian female.
Who is she?
WILLOWS (sighs):
Tina Vincent.
Somebody worked her over pretty
good.
Looks like she
might've gotten
a couple of licks in, though.
Nine-mil.
One in the leg,
one in the head,
and a whole lot
of ugly in between.
I used to work Narco--
whoever did this
wanted information.
Or he was just
a sadistic bastard.
SOSA:
Excuse me, what do you two
think you're doing?
Gonna process the scene.
Look, I'm all
about cooperating,
but I'd prefer to have
my people handle this.
WILLOWS:
Look, Detective Sosa,
this is still a DJK case.
You find Ray Langston yet?
Maybehefoundher.
Stokes.
It's Stokes, right?
Yeah.
BRODY:
At lvpdcsi.com?
STOKES:
Yeah.
(cell phone rings)
Forgot something.
Thanks.
Morgan.
I just figured it out--
you're Conrad's daughter.
Before the divorce.
(laughs)
Last time I saw you,
you were just a kid.
So you don't
go by Ecklie.
I took my stepdad's last name.
I'll catch you guys later.
I like her style.
BRODY:
I processed
Tina Vincent's room.
Prints I lifted place
three people there--
Nate Haskell,
Tina Vincent...
SOSA:
And CSI Raymond Langston.
You want to explain that to me?
I can't.
I got enough trouble
chasing down the bad guys;
I don't need
to be chasing
the good ones, too.
Look, we don't know
what happened in that room.
Yeah, we do.
Someone tortured that girl
till they got what they
wanted, then they put
a bullet through her head.
Now, I'm gonna ask you again:
does Ray
Langston carry?
No.
What about blood evidence?
I found blood
on the doorknob
and on the vic's ring,
along with epithelials
under her fingernails.
Consistent
with a struggle.
DNA comes back to an unknown
African-American male.
You run it against
CSI Langston?
I would have,
but... he wasn't in the system.
How is that possible?
Man's a CSI.
Submission is voluntary.
Great.
So if I ever want
to kill someone, I'll
just transfer to Vegas.
Ray's not a murderer.
No?
He's definitely a suspect.
(sighs)
(exhales)
How did you find me?
I'm part hound dog.
I pinged your cell,
traced it back
to a tower near
Dodger Stadium,
then checked out
all the motels one
cut above fleabag.
It was really
pretty easy.
When did you start
carrying a gun again?
You need to go home, Nick.
You're not taking me back.
I'm not here
to take you back;
I'm here to help you out.
Haskell wantsme.
All right?
He doesn't want you.
Raymond...
Tina Vincent's dead.
Now, I know
you didn't kill her...
but you need to tell me
what happened.
Haskell wanted me to find her.
(grunts, laughs)
Where is he, Tina?
You want to hurt me?
You're going to tell me
what I want to know.
(Tina laughing)
And did she?
All she would said is that Nate
wanted me to have that.
Said the blood on
it was Gloria's.
It used every ounce of my
strength not to hurt her.
Well, Haskell came back
after you left
and he put a real good hurting
on her
for you.
You do realize
what he's doing, don't you?
Yes, yes, he's isolating me.
He's making you
a fugitive.
He's cutting you off
from everyone and everything.
And believe me, if it was
this easy for me to find you,
LAPD won't have a problem.
Take a look at this.
I found this
at Tina Vincent's crime scene.
"You never forget your first."
Same ticket, same message.
What is he saying?
This sick bastard is leaving us
a bread crumb trail.
All we have to do is figure out
where it leads.
I can't exactly
call the lab now, can I?
I can.
STOKES (over phone):
How we doing, Greg?
(hushed):
Ask him about Langston.
I found the manufacturer
of the tickets.
(hushed):
Ask him about Langston.
Running the numbers through the
company's database right now.
Will you ask him?
Shut up.
STOKES:
What?
Um, sorry.
I wasn't talking to you.
Uh, Nick, yeah, it's me.
Um, I heard the news, and, uh,
while I can empathize with Ray,
I feel I must express my concern
that his Dirty Harry style
antics
of late can only reflect badly
on the team.
Hodges, put Greg
back on the phone.
Yeah, will do.
Just tell me,
is there any news from Ray?
But when I find him, you'll
be the first to know.
Give me that.
All right,
I think I got something.
According to this,
the tickets were delivered
to L.A.
Part of a shipment
to the Santa Monica Pier.
(music playing in distance)
The carousel.
"You never forget your first."
What are you talking about?
My first date with Gloria
was on a carousel in Baltimore.
How would Haskell
know something like that?
We may be walking
into something here.
You got my back, right?
Always.
(door closes)
(carousel music begins playing)
This isn't our first date, Ray.
It's just our first
without a chaperone.
STOKES:
Get your hands up.
Ahh... Ray!
No fair.
You're under arrest,
you son of a bitch.
Yeah.
(two gunshots)
STOKES:
Where is he?
I got the other side.
(door opens)
Outside, Ray.
(chain rattles)
(rattles)
(passengers screaming happily)
(bell ringing)
(people chatting, laughing)
Haskell, hold it right there.
Drop the gun!
I'm a CSI, in pursuit
of a suspect.
Look, I don't care who the hell
you are-- drop the gun!
You're making a big mistake.
Listen to me!
No, you listen!
Drop the gun, get on your knees
and put your hands
behind your head!
Do it, now!
I'm not getting on my knees.
(handcuffs clicking)
(man speaks indistinctly
over speaker)
(woman laughing, bell ringing)
(people chatting, laughing)
Don't move!
Drop the gun!
Listen to him, Ray.
(gunshot)
It can't end like this, Ray.
Oh, I know
how you feel, Ray,
but if you pull that trigger
now, you'll kill more than me.
Two people die, Ray!
She's still alive!
Gloria's still alive, Ray!
OFFICER:
Drop the gun, now!
(gun clatters)
(passengers screaming happily)
SOSA:
Nate Haskell is responsible for
the deaths of over 25 people,
including four law enforcement
officers in Las Vegas.
And last night he damn near
took the life of one of my men.
So how come
he didn't take yours?
I can't answer that.
That's a load of crap.
Where'd you get the gun?
I took it from an assailant
who attempted to mug me
in MacArthur Park.
My intention was to turn it in.
You know something...
you're lucky Officer Davies
was wearing a vest...
and that the slug
we took out of it
was a match to the bullet
that killed Tina Vincent.
But you knew
where to find her.
And you knew
where to find Haskell.
Now, I don't care
if you're inside his head,
or he's inside yours.
You know what's going on here.
You got a choice.
You talk to me, or I'm putting
your ass on a plane
back to Vegas myself.
Am I being charged with a crime?
I'll be the one
to get him on the plane.
You know, if it was up to me,
I'd send you all home.
But then, I got
a problem--
Haskell drops another body
and it's my ass in the sling
'cause I'm the moron
who sent the Haskell experts
back to Vegas.
So no free airfare then?
How about no more surprises?
I'll meet you back
at S.I.D.
I'll go check in with Morgan.
I told you to find him, Nicky.
I did find him.
I should've known.
You had to have his back,
had to cowboy up
on some vigilante mission.
I mean, I get him,
but you have no excuse.
So are you sending
me home, now, too?
Oh, I'd like to, but I can't,
because I need you here.
And, luckily, LAPD is giving you
a second chance.
Ray...
you're going back
to Vegas.
Do I have to post a guard
at your door?
No, that won't be necessary.
We'll get him.
SIDLE:
Smooth, polished surface.
It looks like beach sand.
Recovered
from Tina Vincent's room.
Well, that makes sense--
Haskell was at the pier,
he spent some time at the beach.
Found more
than just beach sand.
I think he's been spending time
somewhere else.
Put your nose down that one.
Nesosilicates, garnet.
There's chips of paint
in the mix.
This sand is from construction.
Sandblasting, maybe.
Plenty of that downtown,
at least until the economy
hit the skids.
Maybe Haskell's squatting.
Or it's where
he left Gloria's body.
The rings of a tree
will give up its history.
Blast the paint off
the side of a building,
layers are going to tell you
the same story.
Time for a little chip and dip.
(beeps)
(sighs)
ROBBINS:
Hey, Ray.
Hey.
Thanks for coming
to get me.
Well, Catherine didn't
give me much choice.
Yeah.
But I would've
been here anyway.
What's going on?
Haskell could've killed me,
he didn't.
Yeah, well, maybe he
didn't want to kill you.
He just...
wants to keep hurting you.
Can we go back to the office
for a while?
You're on leave, Ray.
You think that's a good idea?
I don't know.
You think it's a good idea
for me to just go home
and sit in an empty house?
Come on.
The trace that we thought
was sand in Tina Vincent's room
turned out to be
commercial sandblasting.
Found paint chips
in the mix.
Gave us a profile
of the building.
You're thinking if we find the
building, we may find Haskell.
STOKES:
Base layer
had traces of concrete.
Suggests it's industrial.
12 layers?
Damn. You figure buildings
get a new coat of paint
every six to eight years.
Place is old.
But the sandblasting suggests
it's under renovation,
at least at some point recently.
SIDLE:
Chemical composition
of the paint
indicated epoxy formulations--
maintenance paint
used in railings, fire doors...
STOKES:
So, what,
we're talking
about a school, hospital,
or government building?
Narrows it down.
Let's have LAPD pull
building
and demolition permits
over the last three years.
We'll start there.
Nice work, Morgan.
Yeah, thanks.
Hey.
Access denied.
Yeah, you're probably
thinking virus,
but, uh, it's Willows.
Catherine pulled
my privileges?
I'm sure
it's just temporary.
You're damn right
it's only temporary
'cause you're going
to give me your
passcode right now.
No, I can't do that.
Or I'm going
to go all Dirty Harry on you.
You were listening.
I'm going to do this one time.
(typing)
Willoughby J. Willoughby.
LANGSTON:
"Born 1895, died 1963.
"Shipping magnate,
"Willoughby donated
thousands of acres of land
to the city of
Los Angeles."
What's going on?
You can be part of the problem
or part of the solution.
Solution.
Back to Willoughby J.
Willoughby, huh?
Thought we left
him behind
with Tina Vincent
at The Penwick.
We did.
Not so sure about Haskell,
though.
Man shoots his wife
in the head, kills her.
I mean, there's got to
be... some deeper meaning.
He didn't kill her.
She survived?
Yes.
Is that significant?
Yes. Tell me more
about the crime.
SANDERS:
LAPD faxed me copies
of the old case files.
Apparently, Willoughby
was a bigamist.
Willoughby J. Willoughby--
a name so nice,
he married twice.
Willoughby's
second wife Audrey
was from Las Vegas.
The night of the shooting,
Wife Number One--
Sylvia-- surprised
Willoughby and Wife Number Two
during a tryst at The Penwick.
One thing led to another, and
Willoughby shot Wife Number One.
So Wife Number Two
witnessed the crime?
Along with
her seven-year-old son,
who was staying
in the adjoining room.
HODGES:
And that seven-year-old boy
is Nate Haskell.
If Nate Haskell
were 75 years old.
What was the boy's name?
Arvin.
Wife Number One survives.
Do we know what happened
to Wife Number Two?
According to court records,
uh, Audrey Willoughby,
two years following
the shooting, was committed
to a psychiatric facility--
St. Collette's Hospital in L.A.
The boy was placed
into the custody
of his uncle,
and that's
pretty much where
the trail ends.
Hmm.
Wife died the same year
the hospital closed
in the mid-1980s.
Is there a problem?
Catherine said
that Haskell might be hiding out
in an industrial building,
maybe a hospital.
One from around the same era...
...undergoing renovations.
I've, uh, got to call Catherine.
David.
Yeah.
Would you mind getting us
some coffee?
Absolutely.
Thank you.
(sighs)
STOKES:
Mr. Thorpe,
do you know where Tina
and this squirrelly guy
are shacking up?
The old house
across the road.
♪ ♪
HASKELL:
She's still alive!
Gloria's still alive, Ray!
Hello, Nate.
DISPATCHER:
Show Detective Sosa
responding code three
to St. Collette's Hospital
with Las Vegas CSI,
requesting additional backup.
♪ ♪
(clock ticking)
(door creaking)
(lightbulb crackling)
(monitor beeping)
(floorboards creaking)
(grunts weakly)
Mr. Thorpe.
Help me.
Please.
Mr. Thorpe,
where's your son?
Warner...
Where is he?
Please...
help.
Charlie-07, Langston.
Request immediate backup
and paramedics to my location--
the old Thorpe farm.
Code three.
(chain rattling)
GLORIA (weakly):
Ray?
Ray.
(moans quietly)
Gloria.
I'm gonna get
you out of here.
(door creaking)
Welcome home, Ray.
Welcome home.