Hey, Nick.
Hey, there he is!
Where are you heading?
Well, if I don't go
to the gym now,
I won't go at all.
You feeling
obligated to leave Doc Robbins
a good-looking corpse?
(chuckles)
Yeah, something like that.
Hey, you got a big day
in court today, don't you?
Yeah. Nate Haskell.
Putting my game face on.
Well... I'd tell you
to give him hell,
but that's probably
where he's going anyway.
Good luck.
Thanks.
Yeah.
(lock buzzes)
HASKELL:
Your Honor, I've spent
the last three days
in this courtroom
trying to control myself,
which has not been easy,
I assure you.
The media has tried to portray
me as some sort of monster,
some seven-headed beast
who sprang from a smoking pit
to spread death across the land.
But here I sit,
caged, before you,
a man like any other man,
with only one head,
with two hands,
and with a troubled heart.
Objection.
Is there a point here,
Your Honor?
Mr. Haskell, I advise you
to let your attorney
do the talking.
But I object to that,
Your Honor.
The jury needs to see
the real Nate Haskell;
the vulnerable little boy who
was sadistically abused
by an alcoholic father.
For the record...
that traumatized child
still trembles in me.
I know there's some
in this courtroom
who can relate to my torment.
Unfortunately, Your Honor, my
attorney is not one of them.
You know,
he doesn't even like me.
Your Honor!
The court
has appointed him.
But I, I would like
to un-appoint him.
See how he shies away from me.
How can I trust him?
The only one who can speak
for Nate Haskell
is Nate Haskell.
JUDGE:
Mr. Haskell.
Are you asking
to represent yourself?
I believe the legal term
is pro per, Your Honor.
JUDGE: For the record,
I think you're making a mistake.
But...
(gavel bangs)
so ordered.
Let the record show
that Mr. Haskell
is now proceeding pro per.
But, I warn you,
Mr. Haskell,
there will be
no delays in this trial.
Oh, excellent, Your Honor.
Excellent.
I say...
Let's get it on. Hm?
(gallery murmuring)
(phone rings)
Stokes.
BOY:
You said you wanted
to be my friend.
Yeah, who's this?
You said you wouldn't
let the cops kill my brother.
And then you empty your gun
into him?
Jason McCann?
I should just let you die,
like you did Alex.
How'd you get my number?
Wait,
they're coming. I gotta go.
Whatever you do, don't go home.
(hangs up)
Control,
this is Charlie 0-5 Stokes.
I'm at 922 Rose Avenue.
You, uh,
better get the bomb squad
out here.
Code three.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
BOMB SQUAD TECH:
M67 frag grenade in a can.
Pretty simple
booby-trap.
Kill zone up to five meters.
All right, Stokes.
Back up, slowly.
Might be more surprises.
I hope not.
I'm already eight lives down...
if you know what I mean.
I hear you, brother.
(relieved sigh)
(siren wails)
Right this way.
Get off me! I'm all right.
Yes, sir.
BOMB TECH (over radio):
No sign of forced entry.
But we'll play it safe.
We'll sweep
the rest of the house
for any more explosives.
BOMB SQUAD TECH:
Okay!
I safetied the device.
I'll blow it
and I'll send you what's left.
Don't forget the trip-wire knot.
BOMB SQUAD TECH:
I'll send it in the package.
You can bronze it for Stokes.
Along with this piece
of his wall.
"Sic semper tyrannis."
"Thus always to tyrants."
Slogan for every whack job.
They came to my house!
That kid has my private number!
I tell you what-- if they're
looking for a fight,
they found one.
I'm not afraid to die.
Let's see if they are.
Nick, come on now.
I'm serious!
I know you're serious.
Just dial it down.
Come on.
Did you see anything?
I don't know.
There was a maroon van.
Wi-with, uh, uh,
an extended cab
on the roof-- you know?-- I-I
didn't think anything of it.
Neighbors saw that
same van; it's gone.
You think they were
sitting in that van,
waiting for me to blow up?
Huh?
You said that Jason McCann
called you?
Yeah, I mean, I think
that kid saved my life/
Nick, that kid
should be in jail.
He helped blow up
a police funeral.
Come on.
WILLOWS:
Yeah, the D.A.
couldn't make
the case back then.
Now, all of a sudden,
you've got a bomb
that shows up
on your doorstep,
and he calls you...
just in time.
No, it's no coincidence.
Hail his ass in to PD.
Thank you, Dr. Langston.
No further questions.
Well, Ray, shall we...
go back to the moment
I stabbed you?
Will you describe
for the court
and me...
how it felt...
when I plunged my shank
into your kidney?
PROSECUTOR: Objection!
Irrelevant. Defense is
indulging in gratuitous sadism.
Question goes to state
of mind, Your Honor,
which is key to my defense.
Overruled.
I'll allow it, for now.
Well, Ray, how did it feel?
Painful.
Can you be
more specific?
More... poetic?
You're a published writer, Ray.
Describe the
sensation
when my shank
first pierced your skin.
Sharp.
White-hot.
And after that...
what did you feel?
(gasps)
Lightheaded. Very lightheaded.
Oh...
And-and-and
as you laid down then,
and your life was
draining away,
you gazed into my eyes.
What did you feel then, Ray?
Disbelief.
That's a thought.
Give me a feeling.
Fear.
What?
You felt what?
I was afraid
I was going to die.
Yes.
A perfectly normal
human reaction
to a horrific experience.
Objection!
Sustained.
The defendant
will confine himself
to questioning the witness.
Boring, but fine.
Ray?
When I look at you,
when I see the anguish
I caused you,
I feel... nothing.
Objection!
Defense is testifying!
HASKELL:
Don't you think
I wantto feel something, Ray?
The emotions
that a normal human being feels?
Look at that: Steady,
calm, emotionless.
That's just not right!
Your Honor!
This is outrageous.
Sustained. Strike
the defendant's last statement.
The jury
is instructed
to disregard it.
No further questions,
Your Honor.
SIDLE: Bomber used a Z-type
bowline on the grenade?
Makes him a lefty.
Most people
don't tie anything
more complicated
than their shoes.
Less than 15% of the
population are lefties.
He added a half hitch
to the end.
You know, it's weird.
It's the same signature
that Alex McCann used
on the bombs at the police
funeral, and he's dead.
Well, we know
he wasn't acting alone.
What about his brother Jason.
Maybe he's a lefty?
Let's check LIMS.
Mm... Doesn't say.
Well, we're bringing him in.
I'm going to call Nick,
and tell him to get
his autograph,
and maybe we'll get lucky.
Hey.
(sighs heavily)
It's a pretty nasty bruise.
How'd you get that?
I fell.
Mm.
I want to thank you
for calling me when you did,
or I wouldn't be here right now.
That took a lot of guts.
I'm sure there's some people
out there
who didn't
appreciate it.
Probably the same
people who...
put a grenade in my yard.
You give me a name...
and I can help you.
I can't.
They will kill me.
Dr. Huxbee.
Just the guy
I wanted to talk to.
I'm Jason McCann's
legal guardian.
I heard you pulled him
out of school.
Is he under arrest?
No.
Then he's coming with me.
Let's have a little chat first.
We have nothing to talk about.
Oh, you'd be surprised.
Come on.
Oh, I saw Jason when he came in.
Pretty nasty shiner the kid has.
So what happened?
He mouthed off, so you laid
a little old-fashioned
discipline on him?
Jason fell...
skateboarding.
Yeah. Sure.
I checked out your file.
Before you got your PhD
in political theory,
you were in the Coast Guard.
Must have tied a few
bowline hitches
back then, huh?
Is that where you
learned to make bombs?
I told you before,
I'm opposed to violence.
Right.
You just make 'em,
you don't plant 'em.
That's too dangerous,
too much shrapnel
in the air.
Do I need to call
my attorney?
I came for Jason.
Just sign this release.
Then you can go back to your
public speaking engagements
where you trash
this country
that gives you the freedom
to spew all your crap.
STOKES:
I know you're between a rock
and a hard place here,
but I'll protect you.
Like you protected
my brother, right?
Hey,
your brother didn't
give me a choice, man.
You think that
makes it hurt any less?
HUXBEE:
Jason.
Let's go.
Hey, you still have my number.
He seems scared, but
I can't read him, Jim.
You shot his brother.
Why would he want
to saveyourlife?
Huh?
Grenade fragments
had a story to tell.
Found trace amounts
of benzyl benzoate.
Well, that's an acetone;
it's not in grenades.
Exactly.
So if Nick's grenade
were military issue,
it would have been
filled with Comp-B.
Acetone-- that's one
of the ingredients
in triacetone-
triperoxide, TATP.
That's the same explosive
that Jason McCann's brother
used to make pipe bombs.
So somebody is filling
empty grenades
instead of pipes.
Well, you can buy empty grenades
as commemoratives
and fill them with
any boom you want.
Hey. Remember how
Huxbee was bragging
about living off the grid
and ditching his plastic
and all that?
Yeah.
Well, looks
like some bank
made him an offer for
a low-interest credit card
even he
couldn't refuse.
WILLOWS:
Guy's become a shopaholic.
HODGES: Retail
therapy can be
very effective
in relieving
that Armageddon stress.
Well, Huxbee's not buying
a lot of sterno and camo,
but he did buy
serious quantities
of acetone and pool acid.
Maybe he was looking to start
his own Armageddon.
Thanks for coming.
Yeah, I hope
we're not wasting
your time here, Kip.
You kidding?
I live for this.
So, Dr. Huxbee's
old landlord didn't
agree with his politics,
so he booted him out
of the old meeting hall,
and Huxbee signed
a new lease here.
WILLOWS: Credit cards, leases--
gets the doc back on the grid.
We got an R.O. on this truck?
Yeah, it's Huxbee's--
so he must be inside.
Dr. Huxbee?
LVPD. We have a warrant.
(calls):
Huxbee?
We need to talk.
Got some blood here.
WILLOWS:
It's Huxbee.
He's dead.
Guy just sprung
Jason McCann from PD;
now he's dead?
Where's Jason?
WILLOWS:
You know, this scene
looks a little too familiar.
Dead body in the middle
of a room?
KIP:
Body's wired.
Are you kidding me?
I don't see any explosives.
(power generator whines,
activating)
Oh, crap.
That can't be good.
You think?
VARTANN:
What is it with you?
You some kind of
a bomb magnet?
All right, guys,
let's get out of here.
The whole place
might be rigged.
Retrace your steps.
WILLOWS:
Hang on.
What is that?
Looks like some kind of sensor.
Yeah.
You're not
gonna like this.
One door in, one door out.
We're not going anywhere.
Control, KA-135.
We have a 445
at 3027 Rosemont Boulevard.
Control, KA-13...
(radio static)
Radio's dead.
What?
Phone, too.
Seriously?
Must be jamming
the signals.
Fantastic.
We're on our own.
Well... come on, man,
you're the rock star here.
Time to start playing,
bud. Let's go.
Photo-sensor chip
under the DB armed
the bombs and lasers.
We break any
of those beams,
that much C-4 is gonna
take us all out.
We got to diffuse this bad boy.
WILLOWS:
Yeah.
How arewegoing to get to it?
KIP: I'm still
working on it.
Keyless car entry
receiver circuit.
Fob transmitter's
probably connected
to the lasers.
That clock say
14 minutes?
That's a lifetime.
VARTANN:
To disarm it, or is that
just what we've got left?
Both.
Dr. Corey,
two weeks ago you brought
a mobile MRI machine
to Ely State Prison
to conduct a test on me.
Yes. I...
scanned your brain
while you were shown
a series of crime photographs.
HASKELL:
Describe the photos.
COREY:
They were graphic, uh,
extremely violent.
Images of mutilated
and dismembered bodies.
What happens, Doctor,
to the average person's brain
when they're shown such images?
This...
is the orbital cortex.
It governs, uh,
moral decision making,
aggression, impulse control.
It's lit up like
a Christmas tree.
It's so beautiful, Doctor.
COREY:
Well, it's because
it's being stimulated.
Clearly,
the, uh, subject
was deeply disturbed
by the images.
HASKELL:
And how does this compare
to a scan of...
myorbital cortex?
COREY:
Well...
as you can see,
yours is pitch black;
there is no activity.
Your orbital cortex
is profoundly
impaired.
Doctor, do you know what caused
this... this defect?
You possess
a genetic mutation:
the Monoamine
Oxidase A, or MAO-A gene.
Otherwise known as
the warrior gene,
for its association
with aggression.
HASKELL:
Doctor, what is the significance
of this warrior gene
for someone like me?
COREY:
Well, according
to numerous studies,
if you suffered severe
childhood abuse
and possessed this gene,
it increases your chances
of committing
a violent crime by...
four hundred percent.
Doctor, you complete me,
or at least you complete
my understanding of me.
Objection.
I know,
counsel is testifying.
Sustained, sustained.
JUDGE:
Mr. Haskell,
I've given you
a lot of leeway
because you're pro per,
but if you try to
do my job again,
I will hold you
in contempt.
Mea culpa, Your Honor.
So, Dr. Corey,
it is your
expert opinion
that I cannot be held
responsible for my actions,
for any of them?
That is correct.
HASKELL:
So it is true what they say,
that I am a monster,
buta monster
made of biology
beyond my control.
So convicting me
of attempted murder
would be like
convicting a blind man
of being unable to see.
Who's the real victim here?!
(sobbing):
Who's the real victim?
KIP:
Bomb out of reach,
clock facing us--
they want us to see how
much time we have left,
force our hand.
Yeah, that's 'cause
they're watching us.
They want
to see us sweat.
Yeah, here we go.
WILLOWS:
They've been a step ahead
of us this
whole time.
Yep.
Well... they want
to play with lasers,
I'll give 'em lasers.
(electronic crackle)
(sighs)
All right,
guys, ideas?
Well, we can't go
through the beams,
so maybe we go over 'em.
Yeah, there's plenty
of pallets and lumber.
Yeah.
Yeah, enough to build
a stairway to Heaven.
(loud popping)
WILLOWS:
Lou!
(groaning)
You don't want
to be next.
That goes for you,
too, Stokes.
KIP:
Nine-mil cartridges
set into the wood.
Nails as firing pins.
Very smart.
Yeah, smarter than me.
All right, you're good
along that line.
It's bad,
isn't it?
(gasps)
He may have nicked an artery.
I'm gonna apply
some pressure.
Okay.
It's gonna hurt.
(grunts)
Sorry.
God, I hate it
when you're right.
We want to get out here,
we better start stacking.
All right, you guys go for it.
I'm gonna stay with Lou.
Careful what you pick up.
Yeah, copy that.
You should find
more compassion in
your heart for Nate.
The man has a disease.
I'm sorry, who are you?
I'm Vivian, Nate's fiancée.
His one true love.
I see. Did Nate give
you that pendant?
Yes.
I wonder if
you understand the
significance of it.
Oh, Nate's a very spiritual man.
I was referring
to his first two victims,
Joel Steiner and Tiffany Cohen.
They both wore
identical Stars of David.
They were two
young people
very much in love, just
starting out in life,
when he kidnapped them,
murdered Joel, so
that he could rape
and torture Tiffany
at his leisure.
Well, you heard that expert;
he's not responsible
for his actions.
Besides, the love of
a good woman can change any man.
Now, why don't
you tell that to the
seven women that we found
buried under
his floorboards?
Vivian.
Join the prayer circle.
I see you've met
the Brides of Haskell.
They're all wearing
identical Stars of David.
Well, serial killers
have groupies, Ray.
Well, they may not be
the only ones listening
to this psychobabble.
You should have seen
the jury listening
to his expert witness,
this Dr. Corey.
Haskell's going to try
and use the MAO-A defense
to get all of his
convictions overturned, Jim.
That's a long shot, Ray.
You heard of Willie Sutton,
bank robber, right?
Sentenced to over 100 years.
Studied civil rights
law in jail.
Got all of his
convictions overturned.
He died a free man.
Captain Brass?
Ready for testimony.
Okay, my turn on the hot seat.
See you later.
Hey, stay with me.
We're gonna get you out of here.
We're all gonna get out of here.
STOKES:
All right, Kip.
Once you're in, you're in.
You ready, wild man?
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
If I were you,
I'd stick that landing, bud.
(gasps)
You're good.
(sighs)
All right.
Clock's ticking.
Big capacitors.
Just a come-on.
You know, I don't think Huxbee
or Jason McCann
pulled this off.
You might want to
find some shelter.
All we got is plywood.
That's no good against C-4?
It can't hurt.
Yeah. All right.
I'll be right back.
Hey.
Hey. We got
to get him to cover.
(Lou groans)
Can you sit
up for me, Lou?
Okay.
I got it.
Yeah?
Aah!
Piece of cake.
(all groaning)
(panting)
Watch that.
(whispers)
Stay strong, Lou.
(both panting)
Ah, hell.
What? What?
Mercury switch.
That doesn't sound good.
Anti-tampering device.
Works on gravity.
Normally I'd cut the main power,
but this baby's got
a collapsing circuit.
Translation?
I cut the power lead,
it triggers the bomb.
I've got to cut
these two conductors separately,
make sure the wires don't touch.
STOKES:
All right.
You get to cover.
Hell, no, man.
I'm staying right here with you.
Ah, you're the wild man.
Less than a minute.
Plenty of time.
45 seconds.
(grunts)
First cut.
(sighs)
Second cut.
(whirring off)
(sighs)
It stopped.
I hate to
disappoint you, Stokes,
but you're not dying today.
(laughs)
Damn!
Good job.
Let's get him
to a hospital.
You're my hero, man.
(sighs)
He got it.
He got it. We're good.
We're good, Lou.
Come here.
It's all right
Yeah.
(generator whines,
powering up)
Get down!
(sirens wailing)
Over here.
I got three people down.
One female
in a CSI vest. Requesting
two additional paramedics.
It's okay.
We're gonna get you out of here.
One of my victims has
life-threatening injuries.
So Nick and Catherine
are all right?
And what about Vartann?
Good. Listen, Greg, get the name
of his attending for me
so I can follow up after.
Oh, um, batter up.
Got to go.
Thanks for
letting me know.
PROSECUTOR :
So, as a medical doctor,
what is your opinion
about Dr. Corey's theory
that individuals
with the MAO-A gene
are predisposed
to violence?
It is my opinion
that it is utter nonsense.
Sure, there have been
several studies
that claim
that there's a link
between the MAO-A gene
and violent behavior,
but there are just
as many studies
that dispute those findings.
Dr. Corey's conclusions
are not neuroscience.
They're neuromythology.
PROSECUTOR:
Could you give
us an example?
LANGSTON:
Alcoholics are
genetically predisposed
to alcoholism,
which is a known disease,
but we don't give drunks a pass
if they decide
to get behind the wheel
of a vehicle and kill people.
The law is interested
in whether or not
a person understands
the difference
between right and wrong,
and the defendant
knows the difference
between right and wrong.
He takes pleasure
in committing sadistic crimes
that he knows
are against the law.
The fact that he has tried
to cover up those crimes
is evidence
of his consciousness of guilt.
No further questions,
Your Honor.
I have nothing
but questions.
Dr. Langston, are
you a psychiatrist?
A neurologist?
A geneticist?
No. My field is
research pathology.
Then you have no expertise
in this area at all, correct?
No?
You mean yes.
You just testified to a complete
lack of credentials.
So, on what would you
base any expertise?
Personal experience.
Like you, I was abused by
an alcoholic father as a child,
and, like you,
I have the MAO-A gene.
DNA isn't destiny.
We're all responsible
for our own actions.
I share the same gene
with you, Nate,
but I've never murdered anyone.
I take satisfaction
in bringing justice
to victims,
not killing them
and torturing them.
Which is the only way
that you can feel any connection
to another human being.
Don't you think that was
a little below the belt, Ray?
Welcome back.
The doctors
patched you up.
You're going to be okay.
But Kip didn't make it.
(sighs)
Did we get 'em?
We will.
Thanks...
for being here.
Where else would I be?
You get some rest.
I'll be back.
Okay.
How's he doing?
Good, I think.
How you doing?
I'm still in one piece.
Yeah, you should probably
get checked out anyway.
That's usually my line.
(laughs)
Hey, you're always
taking care of me.
How about
I take care of you for a change?
Okay.
Thanks, Nicky.
Sometime between
being bludgeoned
and the postmortem
blast injuries,
Huxbee managed to get
himself shot in the head.
Single GSW,
execution style.
Were you able
to recover the bullet?
Nine millimeter
hollow-point.
Ballistics sent
over a report.
Hmm.
Gunshot was overkill.
Blunt force trauma
was the cause of death.
IBIS hit.
The same gun was used
in a break-in
at a National Guard armory
in Salt Lake
nine months ago.
What did they take?
Couple of M-9s...
Wow. 20 pounds of C-4.
You know, the armory is not
our only link to the military.
I ran the serial number on
the camera from the warehouse.
It was purchased
two years ago at an Army PX
in Black Rock Arsenal, Virginia.
The buyer paid cash.
Maybe at the PX in Virginia,
but not at Meyer's Hardware
Store in North Las Vegas.
I just ran Huxbee's recent
credit card purchases.
Guess who swiped
his plastic.
SANDERS: That's definitely
Jason McCann on the left.
Using Huxbee's card, or a
card he took out in his name.
SANDERS: To buy
bomb-making materials.
Okay, so, Mr. Non-Violence
loses his temper,
gives Jason the
back of his hand.
Explains Jason's bruise in P.D.
Then Huxbee springs him,
tells Jason that he's a
threat to their movement.
It's got to stop.
So Jason decides
Huxbee'sgot to stop.
Breathing, that is.
We know that he didn't
make the bomb alone.
Let's push in
on this guy.
SANDERS:
Army field jacket.
Think the guy's dumb enough
to wear a jacket
with his name on it?
Let's check him
against all personnel
at Black Rock Arsenal
for the last two years.
JUDGE:
Madame Foreperson,
have you reached a verdict?
We have, Your Honor.
In the case
of Nathaniel Haskell,
Case Number 20433,
Clark County Criminal Court.
As to the count of
attempted murder,
the jury finds
the defendant guilty.
It's an injustice.
The whole world
is watching.
JUDGE: Sentencing will be
on February 28.
This court
is now adjourned.
Well done.
Thanks to you.
SIDLE:
So, Greg was able
to I.D. the guy in
the hardware store
with Jason McCann.
His name is
Timothy Johnson.
STOKES:
Specialty 89 Delta?
That's explosive
ordinance disposal.
Yeah.
And a less-than-honorable
discharge two years ago.
According to
Nevada DMV,
he owns a maroon Chevy van.
Jason's been playing me
this whole time.
Calling me, acting like
he's trying to save my life
was just bait to get me,
Catherine and Vartann
in that building
at the same time,
so he could blow us
all to smithereens.
And Kip's the one
who paid for it.
You know, it was all three
who took his brother down.
Damn! How could I
not see that, Sara?
Now, wait a minute,
wait a minute.
You saw the tripwire.
That's the
important thing.
You know what I want to know?
Is Jason pulling the strings,
or is someone else
pullinghisstrings?
Well, we thought it was Huxbee.
It's got to be
this dude, Johnson.
Well, we got to find them;
they still have a lot of C-4.
(sighs) Okay, what
about that DMV address?
It's no good.
Greg ran it.
The guy used an abandoned house;
it's the end of the line.
Maybe not.
Kids and their phones.
That dumb-ass called me.
I think he deserves
a call back, don't you?
Hello?
Hey, Jason.
It's Nick Stokes.
How's it going?
Bet you weren't expecting
to hear from me, were you?
No, actually, I wasn't.
Maybe we should
just continue
our conversation right now,
what do you think?
I mean, we were interrupted.
I think we have a lot
to talk about, don't you?
Jason.
Come on, talk to me,
you little punk.
(beep)
I don't think he
likes you anymore.
Oh, he's gonna like me
a lot less, believe me.
I got the cell tower.
CT-16, south receiver,
22 miles west of Searchlight.
Not too many people out there.
Probably not a lot
of maroon vans, either.
(sirens wailing)
Captain Brass,
Air One here.
Got a visual?
Affirmative.
Maroon van, two WMA's
matching suspect's description.
BRASS:
Hang back. Maintain visual.
This is Charlie-O-five.
What's their position, Air One?
Just turning west
onto State Route 164.
Hey, they're headed
for California, Jim.
We take 95 south,
we can cut 'em off.
Just try to keep up.
The last cage
on the left.
Thank you.
Hi, Ray.
You...
were magnificent on
the witness stand.
That MAO-A revelation
of yours...
Delightfully unexpected.
You know,
a good lawyer
never asks a question that
he doesn't have the answer to.
Beware the sin
of pride, Ray.
But I feel it was
a positive experience,
because now I feel
even closer to you.
Discovering we share more
than just your kidney.
Do you have chills, Ray?
No. Steady.
Calm.
Question, though.
How long have you known that
you were an MAO-A gene carrier?
You heard Dr. Corey,
Ray-- months, maybe...
maybe longer.
No, you must
have known
before your first kill.
My firsthumankill.
You talk about a good excuse
to start having some fun, huh?
Oh,Ray...
it's like a mirror with you.
(chuckles)
It's like playing
with myself, only...
better.
So, how long have you known?
Ray,
you know my job history
and that I never, ever
had one in my life.
So I had to
have income.
Blood donations,
sperm bank,
the odd psychological
research study-- those
cute grad students,
they pay
good money.
The first studies
on the MAO-A gene
didn't happen until the 1970s.
How did you know, Nate?
I wanted to be the
first kid on my block
to have one, Ray,
so I could blame everything
on my father.
I just prayed to God
to bring me one
of those genes, Ray.
You can't alter your DNA.
You either have the gene
or you don't.
Trust me, Ray...
if you want
something
bad enough,
you can will it to happen.
Look at those women;
they fight over me, Ray.
It's 'cause I will it.
You're really giving yourself
a little bit too much credit.
No,
I'm a chick magnet, Ray,
and you know that.
You're a magnet
for the walking wounded.
Look at you
in this cage.
You're pathetic.
Whatever.
You know what
I dream of more
than sex, Ray?
What?
Freedom.
I bet you do.
You've killed 14 people.
There's no gene
that's gonna magically
make you free, not for that.
Power of positive thinking, Ray.
And I'm very positive.
I thought you were smarter
than your brother, huh?
But you had to
make it personal.
It's always been personal.
They killed my brother;
now they're gonna pay.
Well, you think you're the
only guy who lost someone?
I've had more friends
bleed out in my arms
in the middle of a damn
sandbox than I can count,
but at least I know
what I'm fighting for--
real freedom.
Stop talking to me
like I am some kid.
I brought you in!
I taught you
everything,
you little punk!
Not just how to make
bombs but how to bring
this freedom fight home,
stay alive,
live to fight another day
and not go
strength against strength
and take on the whole damn LVPD.
You're just gonna
get us killed, kid.
I'm not afraid.
AIR OFFICER (over P.A.):
Stop the car. Stop the car!
What are you doing?
Run it!
Shut the hell up.
(sirens wail, then stop)
BRASS:
Johnson! McCann!
Get out of the car!
I'm not dying today.
Don't quit on me.
BRASS:
Throw your weapons
out the window,
and step out of the car now.
Got no choice.
Look at all those guns.
Shut up!
BRASS:
You're surrounded!
Get out of the car!
I'll give up,
but only to Stokes.
SANDERS:
Don't even think about it.
Yeah, I'm right here.
So give up.
I want to talk to you.
We'll talk.
Get out of there!
JOHNSON:
Jase, look at me.
Live to fight another day,
remember?
(cocking)
Get out.
I'm coming out!
Get your hands on your head,
turn around
and get down
on your knees!
Get down on
your knees!
McCann, get out of the car!
Throw the
weapon out!
Hands on your head!
Get down on
your knees!
He's wired!
He's got a bomb!
He's lying! There's no bomb!
Look! Don't shoot!
JOHNSON:
Don't shoot! No!
(gunshot)
(gunfire)
Hold your fire.
(car alarm chirps)
I need to see Nate Haskell.
I need to see him right away.
Okay.
Hey, Haskell?
Your buddy's...
What the...?
Hey, inmate, get up.
Show us your
wrist band.
He switched them.
So where is he?
A minimum-security van
just left
about ten minutes ago.
(tires screech)
(distorted gunshots, yelling)
Nate! Now we
can finally...
Let's take my car.
Oh, your hands
are so cold.
Oh, we'll fix that.
INMATE: Let's get out
of here! Come on!
Come on.