LANGSTON:
You see an address?
STOKES:
Man, I don't
even see any houses.
LANGSTON:
I didn't know they had
this much farmland
outside of Vegas.
Welcome to Nessus.
Half a dozen slot machines,
one blackjack table
and manure--
lots and lots of manure.
LANGSTON:
I can't see it,
but I can sure smell it.
Nick, I'm telling you,
we passed the crime scene.
No, no, just keep going.
I've had plenty
of 419s out here.
What's up with this GPS?
Whoa!
Holy cow!
(moos)
STOKES:
You know, you kill
one of those in India,
you spend six months in jail.
Moo!
Control, this is Langston.
(cow moos)
We're lost.
(honking horn)
What took you
guys so long?
You hit a cow or something?
Better not.
They're 1,600 bucks apiece.
And they don't milk
when they're riled.
(sighs)
Where's the body?
I'll show you.
Watch your step there.
(squishing)
AKERS: Farmer went camping
at the Virgin River.
Came back tonight
to feed the cows,
and saw this.
Ah, manure with hint
of decomp.
AKERS:
Well, it's definitely got legs,
but no hands.
First generation,
third instar larvae.
Been dead 96-plus hours.
White female adult.
That's not all we have.
Killers sometimes
remove the head and hands
to avoid identification.
Don't usually dump 'em
with the body.
LANGSTON: I don't think
this is her hand.
It's too thick.
The ridges are wide.
Tells me it was a male.
Yeah, so's this.
She-body, he-hands.
We're gonna have to go
through this whole haystack,
see if we can find
the rest of them.
It's easier
than looking for needles.
(phone rings)
Langston.
What?!
Yeah, be right there.
Sorry, Nick, gotta go.
Hey, where you going?!
We're gonna have to search
this whole farm!
Think you just
lost your ride.
(SVU speeds off)
I'll handle it.
HASKELL: I know you're
starting to question
your commitment
to your job, Ray.
And I don't think
I'm the only one.
WILLOWS: Your friend
Haskell surfaced.
HASKELL: I thought I left you
enough bread crumbs to follow.
Did I need to make a video, Ray?
I'm getting tired
of doing all the work
in the relationship.
And, you know,
when I feel unwanted,
bad things happen.
Maybe you're just afraid
to catch me.
Maybe you don't like
looking in the mirror, Ray.
what you see.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
Maybe you don't like looking
in the mirror, Ray.
Where did you get this?
Vivian Tinsdale's parents.
Vivian Tinsdale.
One of Haskell's brides.
Yeah.
Yeah. You walked in
at the end of the movie.
You need to see the opening.
(sobbing):
Please, Daddy, I'm sorry,
but you're the only one
who can save me.
Daddy, he's done things to me!
And the things he says
he's gonna do...!
(sobbing)
Please, Daddy, whatever
he wants, just pay him!
When did they get this?
Four days ago.
She's probably already dead.
Mr. Tinsdale,
it took you four days
to come forward
with this video?
Who are you?
Ray Langston.
I've been investigating Nate
Haskell for two years.
Why didn't you come
forward sooner?
Well, my computer marked
Vivian's e-mails as spam.
I didn't see them
until last night.
That's still 24 hours ago.
Officer, we haven't spoken
to Vivian in years.
She's a stranger to us.
Now she's asking for our help.
So you're saying you don't care?
Listen, my daughter
is mentally ill.
She's a sociopath
and a pathological liar.
How do you explain
the bruises on her face?
Well, I assume
they're self-inflicted.
So you're saying
the video's a scam?
I'm saying that the only time
we ever hear
from our daughter is
when she's asking for money.
She's not getting another dime.
You have the video. My husband
and I are going to go.
Look, that video
and your daughter
are our only link we have
to an escaped serial killer.
If you're right and Vivian is
only interested in money,
you'll get a call from Haskell.
When that call comes,
we need to be there.
We all want the same thing:
we don't want Nate Haskell
to kill your daughter.
Or anyone else.
Now please help us.
ROBBINS:
Hey, Nick.
Hey.
Please, don't ask me
if I need a hand.
Actually, I was gonna tell you
you smell like a Porta Potti.
Thank you, sir.
ROBBINS:
Obvious sharp-force trauma.
Crushed and cut carpals.
Skin on the anterior aspect of
the wrist looks like
it's been pulled and snapped
from the forearm.
My guess is the killer got a
little happy with a hand ax.
So you think this guy was alive
when his hands waved good-bye
to the rest of his body?
Well, no contusions
around the cut.
Postmortem hack job.
Go ahead and print.
No, these fingers
are too dehydrated.
I'm gonna have to PVS them.
If you compare his hand
to her wrist,
there are similar crushing
and cutting injuries
to the radius and ulna.
Same tool, same killer.
JOHNSON:
Video camera's clock and GPS
were turned off.
No metadata.
No way to tell when
or where it was shot.
Mm, the video was e-mailed
to the Tinsdales.
You should be able
to trace that.
Working on it.
Haskell bounced it around
the Web a half-dozen times.
JOHNSON:
Well! Deputy Chief Curtis.
The shield looks good on you.
Congrats on the promotion.
Thanks, Archie.
You must be Ray Langston.
Sofia Curtis.
Nice to meet you.
Just got the nod
from the sheriff to head up
the Haskell task force.
FYI, I'm calling in the feds.
That might not be the best move.
We've had sightings of Haskell
from Bangor to San Diego.
We got reason to believe
he's crossed state lines.
That makes it federal.
What about the video?
The Tinsdales live here
in Vegas.
Why demand a ransom and then not
stick around to collect it?
Haskell made no specific demand
for money.
So, even if it's not about
money, it's about the Tinsdales.
That connects him to Vegas.
We both know how this works.
The lab will still process
the evidence.
You're not relinquishing
control.
This video is
the first solid lead
we've had in months.
Unless you got proof that
Haskell's still in state,
I'm making the call.
Got it.
Haskell must be
getting some I.T. support.
He uploaded the video from
a open Wi-Fi hot spot
near the Vegas Motor Speedway.
I know him.
I knew I was right.
You got lucky today.
Police officers
at the Tinsdale house
just intercepted a call
from Haskell.
I got him on the line now.
Run a trace.
WOMAN:
Yes, sir, running it now.
HASKELL:
Avery, pencils ready?
AVERY:
Just give me a second.
HASKELL:
Now, you really should be
better prepared
for this kind of thing, Avery.
I hope you're not stalling
so my good friend Ray Langston
can trace this.
Maybe I should hang up
right now.
No, don't. I'm here.
HASKELL: Provenzi Park,
5:30, bench by the playground.
No cops. You hear that, Ray?
(click, dial tone)
"No user information."
Disposable phone.
He's probably disposed of it
already.
Shout-out from Haskell.
The man does like
sticking it to you.
All right, 5:30.
That gives us two hours.
STOKES:
Hey.
Well, thank you
for showering.
Well, I didn't necessarily do it
for you, but you're welcome.
Got a C.O.D. yet?
No. I don't even
have a head.
Torso's fairly fit, rules out
most natural causes.
Can anything else help
us get an I.D. on her?
Appendectomy scar.
Cervix shows no prior
pregnancies,
no tattoos,
no implants,
but small scar on the abdomen
could be from liposuction.
Left femur has
an old radial fracture.
Slight calcification.
Age: early to mid-30s.
Woman in her 30's, appendectomy,
lipo and a busted leg.
All you need now is a name.
(phone rings)
I just got a hit off
one of the hands.
Came back to a Graham Kole.
Greg DMV'd him, got an address.
It's a doctor's office.
Plastic surgeon
with his hands cut off, huh?
Maybe he messed up some psycho
hooker's boob job.
Yeah, what kind of a surgeon
works out of a strip mall
next to a taco joint?
(groans)
Well, we got a warrant.
We do, don't we?
Mm-hmm.
(glass crunching underfoot)
SANDERS:
There's the head, neck, arms
and rest of Dr. Kole.
STOKES:
Two blood pools...
two victims.
Good chance this is our primary.
JOHNSON:
Mr. Tinsdale.
Mr. Tinsdale, if you can
hear me, please cough.
(coughs)
Okay, we're good.
(phone rings)
I don't think
it's his cell phone.
Tell him to answer it.
Mr. Tinsdale, please find that
phone and answer it.
Hold it up to your right ear
so I can record
the caller's voice in
your earpiece.
Hello?
The other ear. The right ear.
Tell him the right ear.
LANGSTON:
What's he doing?
Mr. Tinsdale,
switch sides, please.
Your other ear.
Wait a minute.
You're breaking up.
Yeah, there, I can hear you.
Too bad we can't.
That wasn't the deal.
I did what you asked.
Where's Vivian?
I want to talk to her right now.
Yes, I see it.
It's the pink one?
Yes, I have it.
All right, I understand.
BRASS: Well, happy big
birthday, baby.
He better hope
that's not a bomb.
LANGSTON:
He's being directed.
Scan the park.
Turn to the woman
by the playground.
I thinks she's got
eyes on Tinsdale.
Archie, give me a better look.
Damn! That's Tina Vincent!
It's a bride!
OFFICER (over radio):
She spotted us.
Suspect now on foot,
running southbound.
OFFICER:
LVPD! Down on the ground! Now!
BOY:
Whoa! She's gone!
Out of the way!
(shrieking)
Where is he?!
(chuckles)
Where's Nate?
(laughs)
Where is he?!
Ray! Hey, Ray!
(laughing)
WILLOWS:
What were you doing in
the park, Tina?
TINA:
What do people do in parks?
Walk dogs.
Walk themselves.
I find it very...
soothing.
I find it very
coincidental
given your relationship
with Nate Haskell.
Relationship? No.
I admire him.
I admire his courage because
he's clearly a victim
of the justice system
that is bent on persecuting him
for crimes he could not commit.
You were present at his
recent trial along with
Vivian Tinsdale-- what's your
relationship with her?
She disgusts me.
And I think she's a bad
influence on Nate.
It sounds like you've seen
Vivian and Nate recently.
LAWYER:
My client didn't say that.
Don't put words in her mouth.
I couldn't if I tried.
Where is Nate Haskell now?
Where's Vivian?
Are you aware that she's
been kidnapped?
My client's told you
what she knows.
Last I checked, a walk
in the park is not a crime.
But a cop beating up on an
innocent civilian is.
I'll be in touch.
Oh, your prisons
couldn't hold Nate.
He willed himself to be free.
Tell Ray Langston
he'll never catch him...
not until Nate wills it.
Where is Hodges?
Uh, he's moving out of his
mother's place... finally.
I'm not sure who's more
traumatized.
Is, uh, is that
the package from the park?
I heard Haskell.
left you a present.
It's evidence.
I assume it's been X-rayed?
Yes, the Bomb Squad
scanned it.
I just checked it for trace.
I need to print it.
Where's Mandy?
Uh, Denver.
Conference.
You're in luck.
I've worked in
every forensic
discipline except QD.
Too many paper cuts.
Let me help you.
You do the box,
I'll do the tape.
Ray, the size says
probably male.
He left it dead center.
Exquisite ridge detail.
Sloppy, sloppy.
Not sloppy. Intentional.
It's Haskell's way
of signing the package.
Run it anyway.
LANGSTON:
Do you recognize this man?
Yeah, I sure
as hell do.
Where'd you get that?
Who is he?
That's Jack.
That's Jack York.
It was Vivian's
first husband.
This was in the box you gave me.
You have any idea
why Nate Haskell wanted you
to give me this photograph?
No, I don't.
BRASS:
Tell us about Jack York.
Well, he was just one
in a long line of men
that took advantage of Vivian.
Except this one she married.
Only lasted a few months.
BRASS:
Where is he?
We'd like to
talk to him.
Well, I can't help you.
He took off.
I mean, Jack was bad news.
He didn't love Vivian,
only her money.
That day in the park,
what did you and
Haskell talk about?
Well, I could only hear about
half of what he was saying.
"That wasn't the deal!
I did what you asked.
Where's Vivian?"
Sounds like you two had
a conversation.
He was yelling at me,
making demands.
Most of it was about you.
BRASS:
"That wasn't the deal."
That sounds like it was
about you, pal.
I told you what I know.
He made no demands for ransom?
He gave you no instructions?
We have a warrant
for your computer,
bank records, cell phone
and credit cards.
We're going to take
a very long look
at everything in your life.
This blood's dry and flaky.
It's days old.
Matches the time line of the
maggots I found on the bodies.
No bone chips,
no bone fragments.
Not enough blood to
suggest dismemberment.
They might have
been killed here,
but they were probably
cut up somewhere else.
(camera shutter clicking)
Small blood trace.
Looks like
he just stripped these off.
You know, I think Dr. Kole
might have been seeing a patient
right before he became
one of these blood pools.
Got a chart.
Medical sticker's
been ripped off.
It's empty.
Maybe the patient had something
to do with this.
Okay, so, the patient kills
the doctor and the nurse?
If the doctor was
working on someone
with the nurse
by his side,
this second blood pool's
probably hers.
And the spider trajectory
points back
to the doorway,
and not to the patient.
Maybe the shooter.
A little groggy, huh?
You're looking good.
Hey, what are
you doing here?
(cartridge casings clatter)
Bullet--
looks like a nine mill.
Hmm. I don't see
any cartridge casings.
Well, one of the victims
was definitely shot.
There's tissue on the bullet.
Through and through.
We need to get this back
to the lab,
see if the tissue on the bullet
matches the hands or the torso.
♪ ♪
Uh, Ms. Kole?
Hi. I'm CSI Stokes.
I'm very sorry
for your loss.
Boy, is my life starting
to look up.
(laughs)
(giggles)
I need to get
your fingerprints.
If you can get past these,
be my guest.
We'll see what
we can do.
Why don't you have
a seat for me?
By the way,
I didn't kill
my crappy husband.
Well, if you didn't kill
your crappy husband,
who do you think did?
Did you know that Vegas is the
fugitive capital of the world?
I didn't know that.
Yeah.
Right hand, please.
And, uh, Graham
did a few, um,
faces, if you know
what I mean.
I get it.
Do you?
Yeah. Please.
So, when was the last time
that you saw Graham?
When he told me
to turn my vibrator down.
He didn't speak
to me for weeks.
It was a Monday, so it must have
been about five days ago.
And when he didn't come home,
how come you just didn't
call the police?
Because I knew where he was.
He was either at the Wynn
or the Encore.
Hmm. And why would
he stay at a hotel
if he's got a house
here in town?
Because he doesn't
have a vibrator.
And he would be
bringing home the real thing.
And then I would be up
all night long
listening to nothing but,
"Oh! Oh, God.
"Oh, Graham,
you're the best.
"Oh, gosh, there's nobody
like you."
Guys like fake.
Some guys do.
Oh, okay.
And do you have
any idea who this affair
might have been with?
Nursey Newtox.
You know what you need to do?
Tell me.
You need to put up
"Wanted" posters of a girl
who looks just like me--
minus 20 years--
with a touch of silicon,
a dash of collagen, rhino,
Botox and lipo,
and the perkiest
double-D's you've seen
this side of the Hoover Dam.
And this nurse,
does she have a name?
Teagan.
Teagan Murphy.
I mean, who has a name
like Teagan?
Mm.
Right? Give me a break.
(low whirring)
(beeping)
STOKES:
I got a name on Kole's nurse.
I ran her
through the DMV.
I'm heading over
there right now.
Should be able to pull
some exemplars for DNA.
You all right, bud?
The bullet that we found
at Kole's office
is a match to the gun used
during Haskell's escape.
Whoa, wait a minute.
Now, that gun was fired
by one of Haskell's brides.
SANDERS: And if the gun
was at Kole's office,
one of the brides was there.
And the brides go...
where Haskell goes.
If Haskell was at that office,
do you think there's a chance
he had some plastic surgery,
changed his face?
And killed the doctor
and his nurse
to cover his tracks.
If we're right
about this,
Haskell could be just
another face in the crowd.
Which means we don't know
who we're looking for anymore.
WILLOWS:
Here's what we have:
Haskell's out there,
and he may have a new face.
Well, the new face
is a game changer.
I'm sick of
this guy.
He's like the Joker inBatman.
Except without the laughs.
We have no hard evidence
that puts Haskell
at the plastic surgeon's.
That may be wishful thinking.
Ballistics only puts a gun,
used by one of Haskell's brides,
at the scene.
After the trial,
I saw all of Haskell's brides,
including Tina,
in the parking lot.
The only ones that weren't there
were Robin and Vivian.
Well, we know it wasn't Robin
that talked to Kole,
because she was popped
during the escape.
Most likely by Vivian after
she shot the four prison guards.
If Vivian is Bonnie
to Haskell's Clyde,
why is Haskell
holding her for ransom?
He's not.
The timeline's wrong.
While Daddy's getting a video
of his little girl
begging for her life,
Vivian is off killing
the doctor and the nurse.
So Haskell and Vivian
are working together.
There was no kidnapping.
So why the dog-and-pony show
at the park?
I don't know, but it must have
something to do with Haskell
sending me this photograph
of Vivian's ex.
Well, Tinsdale knows,
but he's not talking.
(phone rings)
Hey, Archie.
Be right there.
We may not need Tinsdale.
What have you
got, Archie?
Yeah, well, Tinsdale
didn't help us out at the park,
but his computer
is helping us out plenty.
That video file he brought in
wasn't the first message
he got from Haskell.
You got to be kidding me.
Nope.
I pulled this off
of deep memory.
Must've thought he deleted it.
When did this
video file come in?
One week before the
one he showed us.
Put it up, put it up,
put it up.
I'm sorry I can't get
a better image quality here.
HASKELL:
You have been so generous
with me already, Avery,
giving me your daughter.
She is such a fragile flower.
And we both know why.
She's told me some secrets.
Very naughty, Avery.
Yet the more I hear about you,
the more I like you.
You're my kind of guy.
But not everyone is
as open-minded as I am, Avery,
so you're gonna have
to open your wallet.
It's so tawdry
to talk about amounts,
but how about $2 million?
JOHNSON:
That's it.
Now we know
why Haskell
made no ransom demand
and why Tinsdale
showed no real interest in
getting his daughter back.
This is all about blackmail.
Haskell had
already been paid.
Secrets between
father and daughter.
Clearly, Vivian's
bad taste in men started early.
If Tinsdale wanted to hide
his dirty little secret,
why would he come forward?
Because Haskell
forced him to.
I pulled
Tinsdale's bank records.
He withdrew $2 million,
in cash, five days ago.
Told the bank manager
it was for some
offshore investment deal.
(scoffs)
He lied to us.
He just bought Haskell
$2 million worth of freedom,
the son of a bitch.
I know where you're going, Ray.
Don't try
to stop me, Catherine!
Okay, then go ahead.
You'll be doing exactly
what Haskell wants you to do.
Haskell sent you
Jack York's photo for a reason.
York disappeared
right after he married Vivian.
He came between
father and daughter.
Maybe Tinsdale killed him.
Vivian knew about it.
She told Haskell.
This is a game.
This is a dance
between you and Haskell.
Haskell isn't talking
to Tinsdale on the video.
He's talking toyou.
Catch me if you can.
Well, he wants to play...
Ray.
(sighs)
What do you want
me to do, boss?
You don't do this alone.
We go after Haskell together.
(siren whoops)
(doorbell rings twice)
Mrs. Tinsdale,
are you all right?
What happened?
My husband's in the study.
He's dead.
BRASS:
.38 special.
So, you think it's suicide
or an assist
from the wife?
I'm checking both
both for GSR.
Contact wound.
Single exit to the
back of the head.
The pattern on the wall is
consistent with an upward angle.
(gunshot)
Bullet exited the head
and entered the wall.
The blood
on Mrs. Tinsdale
is probably transfer
from embracing him.
Well, why kill himself now?
He already paid Haskell
$2 million for his silence.
Take a look around.
Maybe Haskell
wanted more money.
Didn't we take
his computer, Jim?
BRASS:
He bought himself a new one.
LANGSTON:
Looks like new video.
Avery, I know we had a deal.
I really appreciate the money.
Financial security
in... in midlife
is so important.
But, Avery, the...
the home movies that Vivian
has shown me-- not the...
family trip to Washington.
The other one.
You know, I'm not a...
fan of the police or the church,
but what you did was a sin.
So I do have to file-share it
with my friends in uniform.
I have no choice.
Oh, and, Ray...
there isa moral to this story.
It wasn't his fault.
He didn't want it.
Excuse me?
She came to him.
Vivian... was a child.
You were her mother.
It was your job to protect her.
Do you think it's strange
that I gave birth
to the true bride
of my husband?
♪ ♪
Hey.
Hey. Did you, uh,
you got the DNA results?
Are you sure you got
all the body parts that
were out at that farm?
I'm sure I'm not gonna like
what you're about to tell me.
Well, the major blood
pool from Kole's office
matches exemplars
from Dr. Kole.
Okay.
The secondary
blood pool
plus the tissue from the bullet
you pulled out of the wall
is a match
to the nurse.
Go on.
The DNA from the nurse
is not a match to your torso.
But if that torso isn't
the nurse, then who is it?
And what's it doing
in a haystack
with the doctor's hands?
Good question.
Okay, at least tell me the
patient on the tape was Haskell.
Well...
Oh, come on, man,
you're killing me.
The blood was definitely male,
but not in the system.
And not Haskell.
So it's possible we're
looking for another victim.
And more parts, too.
Let's get back out to that farm.
(cow mooing)
Looking for
more body parts?
Thought you
already did that.
No, actually, we'd like
to ask you a few questions,
if you don't mind,
Mr. Thorpe.
Sure.
Do you recognize this man?
What about her?
THORPE:
Sorry, no.
STOKES: Well, do you
recognize any of these people?
Show him the rest of 'em.
THORPE:
Don't know this one.
But this other pretty girl,
that's my cousin's
daughter Tina.
You're related to Tina Vincent?
She's Irma's sister's
fourth daughter.
Wild one.
Wild in the eye.
She's been staying
out here for a bit.
What's this about?
What about
this man?
He's a friend of Tina's.
Can't say for sure.
But one day
this fella showed up,
kind of squirrelly,
and they started
shacking up.
The guy was
in a car accident;
face was bandaged.
Could be him.
And do you know where
Tina and this squirrelly guy
are shacking up?
The old house
across the road.
(sighs)
Tire tracks.
Wide tread.
Yellow paint over there
says low clearance.
High-end sports car.
(engine revs, tires squeal)
Driver left in a hurry.
Not using much juice.
No water flow.
STOKES:
Electronics gear.
Think we just found
where those videos came from.
I can see you.
What do you mean?
Inside, on the monitor.
Found a minivan around back.
It's clean.
Backup's still ten minutes out.
What do you want to do?
Let's get it on.
Let me take it, Nick.
(door creaks)
(medium-tempo classical
cello music playing)
You hear that?
It's music.
♪ ♪
Smell that?
It's decomp.
STOKES:
Snap, crackle, maggot.
(crunching)
That's Bach's cello solo in G.
I studied the cello;
it's a beautiful piece.
Man, that's
just not right.
Talk about "not right."
BRASS:
Well, we hit the jackpot.
Found the rest of Dr. Kole,
his nurse,
what was left of Vivian
Tinsdale, and a bonus body.
That the I.D.?
Yeah.
Calvin Frost,
white male,
San Diego address.
He rented an exotic car
on the Strip a week ago--
yellow Porsche.
Never returned it.
So where's the car now?
We're still looking for it.
But the blood on the gloves
in the doctor's office
came back as a match to Frost.
Which makes him
Dr. Kole's last patient.
I found Calvin Frost's chart.
New patient.
First visit...
day of the murders.
Says that he tripped
and took a header
in the men's room
at the Orpheus,
and Kole stitched him up.
So he had the bad luck
of being on the table
when Haskell
and Vivian showed up,
making him collateral damage.
We thought the chart that
we found on the floor belonged
to the guy on the table,
so if I'm holding Frost's file,
whose empty chart did we find?
Haskell's.
He killed the doctor
and the nurse
and probably took his records
to cover his tracks.
Well, I'll print Frost's chart
and see who put it
back into the cabinet.
Well, if we find
Haskell's fingerprints,
that means he was still in Vegas
four or five days ago.
Welcome to the
chop shop--
body parts here,
bodies across the hall.
David, I'd like to see
Vivian's hands, please.
Well, I got two lefts
and a right.
Now, Dr. Robbins used tool marks
to determine
which hands were Vivian's.
I used nail polish.
Vivian is wearing Fuchsia Flare.
Positive for lead.
Vivian fired a gun
shortly before she was killed.
Doc.
I know you're
anxious for answers.
Dr. Kole took a nine-
mil in the chest.
Nurse had a nine-mil
perforate her head.
There's your
through and through.
What about Calvin Frost here?
Like Vivian Tinsdale,
he was shot
in the head.
T.O.D.?
All four victims were killed
within hours of each other,
four to five
days ago.
You didn't feel
a thing, did you?
Thank God.
Hey, what are you doing?
Aah!
LANGSTON:
So, the evidence says
that Vivian was our shooter,
but we have no evidence
that Calvin Frost
was killed at the office.
If they're going
to kill him anyway,
why not shoot him there?
Maybe Haskell and Vivian
needed someone
to help them carry the bodies.
So they drove out to
the house, shot Frost,
and then commenced
to choppin'?
Then someone used
the same gun to shoot Vivian
and then began
chopping her up.
Haskell?
Chopping up bodies and
leaving the job unfinished?
Leaving parts
in a haystack
and then the rest
in a bathtub?
Whatever Haskell is,
he's not disorganized.
That's not his M.O.
Hmm.
Tina...Tina.
She was his connection
to the farm,
she was his eyes
at the park.
She's his new number one.
JOHNSON:
Hey, Catherine.
I traced the
serial numbers
from the electronics
at the farmhouse.
All purchased
by Tina Vincent,
and here's the kicker--
I pulled the metadata
off her video
camera's SD card.
All those videos Haskell
sent to Tinsdale--
all recorded
on the same day
eight weeks ago,
specifically on the day
after Haskell escaped.
He's been playing us
this whole time.
WILLOWS:
I printed Frost's chart.
Tina Vincent was
all over it,
yet we didn't find
a single Haskell print
in that entire office.
Doesn't mean he wasn't there,
just not lately.
Well, we do know that both Tina
and Vivian were at the scene.
Vivian's dead
and Tina Vincent's in the wind.
LANGSTON:
We won't find her or
Haskell, not looking here.
They're not in Vegas.
The video,
the ransom demand, the park,
the murders at Dr. Kole's--
they were all intended
to make us think
that Haskell was still here
in Vegas.
And now you think he isn't?
Eight weeks ago,
Haskell escaped from custody
with Vivian's help.
Then he went to Dr. Kole's
for plastic surgery.
Then he and Tina
started making movies
of Vivian in the old house
to send to Daddy.
Nate was careful
to stay in the background.
He didn't want us to know
that he'd changed his face.
Then he sent the two brides
to kill the doctor
and the nurse.
They removed his chart
but not before they kidnapped
the patient on the table,
took his car, his clothes,
and the two bodies,
brought them back to the house
where they murdered him.
(both women laughing)
LANGSTON:
And that's when
bride turned on bride.
Then Tina murdered Vivian.
Now Tina starts
to chop up the bodies.
She disperses
the body parts sloppily,
scattering them,
not unlike her scattered mind.
(laughing)
Two days later,
Tina shows up in a park
to keep an eye on Mr. Tinsdale.
Then she disappears.
WILLOWS:
Haskell and Tina--
they're both fugitives.
Traveling as a couple draws
less attention.
So Haskell's got a new face,
$2 million,
trades in his old bride
for a younger one
and gets a new car in the deal.
Plastic surgery,
cash, bimbo, Porsche.
BRASS: Well, if he's
not in Vegas,
I can think of another
place he might fit in.
We need to call LAPD.
(cello music playing)
♪ ♪
(applause)
Thank you.
Isn't she just heavenly?
I think so.
She's my wife.
Really!
You're a very lucky man.