GUARD:
Move, keep moving.
(cell door clangs)
(buzzer sounds)
(indistinct voices)
All right.
Noses to the wall!
All right, let's
step to the wall.
(smooching)
What you looking at, Beaner?
One ugly-ass white bitch.
(clamoring)
Get back up against the wall!
This is Officer Malone on
the North Corridor. Inmate 415.
Request immediate backup.
Get down or you're going
in the hole!
Move, move!
(alarm blaring,
clamoring continues)
GUARD:
Hands on the wall!
You heard me?!
(alarm stops)
(buzzer sounds)
CSIs coming in.
(door clangs)
I hate that sound.
WARDEN: You guys might want
to take your jackets
and turn them inside out.
Half these guys
are in here
'cause of you.
Let them take a good,
long look, then.
I'm good.
(buzzer sounds)
MAN: Yeah, we got 'em in full
lockdown, Clark County.
(loud clang)
Jim.
Hey.
What's the story?
How'd it happen?
A corrections officer
was walking a bunch
of the Aryan Brotherhood
by another bunch
of not very Aryan brothers.
Never a good idea.
So, collateral damage? Wrong
place, wrong time, or what?
Maybe, maybe not.
Guy's a cop.
Vance Tolsom.
Brime County Deputy.
He and I worked
a bunch of cases
back in the day.
Guy was a son
of a bitch.
He had a short fuse, and he
didn't take crap from anybody.
STOKES: Well, he was stabbed
multiple times.
Somebody really
wanted this guy dead.
How'd he end up in prison
in the first place?
He killed
his wife Anne-Marie.
She was a cop, too.
When she got out
of the Academy,
I was her T.O.
What was an ex-cop doing
in general population ward?
In keep-away for
the first six months.
Bitching about going nuts,
said he was willing
to take his chances.
Mixed in pretty well
for the past three years.
Too bad.
Vance was going
to get a new trial.
BRASS: Vance always bragged
how he was bulletproof.
Well, he wasn't stab proof.
Medical tape on the handle.
It's going to be difficult
to get prints off that.
We got shoe impressions
in the blood.
And the blood on their jumps
should tell us something.
Mm-hmm.
Listen up!
I want your sneakers!
I want your jumps!
I want your DNA!
I want to see your hands!
I want to see your eyes!
This man you killed was a cop!
So there will be consequences!
Prison will not protect you!
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
Okay, open up.
Yeah, I'm pretty sure I'm
already in your database.
At least twice.
But it wasn't me.
That's why I'm going to collect
your DNA
and swab that blood
off your hands,
give you a fair shake
this time. What do you say?
Yeah, thanks.
Hey.
Hey, hey.
Just leave
your hands alone.
You'll get a chance
to clean them up
after I'm done.
LANGSTON:
Cut 'em off.
Take off your shirt.
Don't make me ask you
again. Take it off.
(clears throat)
You like what you see?
Hmm?
Take off your
pants, Adolf,
and I'll tell you.
You want some help?!
PHILLIPS:
22...
23, 24, 25...
26 and 27.
Final count is
27 sharp force injuries
to the upper torso
and neck region.
Prison is an ugly place
to get killed.
ROBBINS: I will be sure to
put that in my report
under bonus features:
"David Phillips on Life
Behind Bars: It Sucks."
I'm just saying that lack
of access to real weapons
leads to some
unnecessary roughness.
You just missed David's elegy
on prison life.
I'll have to wait
for the CD, I guess.
Hmm.
Oh, Vance.
Used to be a
good-looking guy.
Charming.
Not someone you'd want
to cross, though.
So what have you got?
Well, C.O.D. is obvious.
Exsanguination due to
multiple sharp force injuries.
None deeper than two inches.
Left and right
jugular-carotid complex
are pretty much shredded.
So the assailant should
be covered in blood.
It's a roughly triangular-shaped
piece of metal,
sharpened to a point.
(shouting)
Wounds are consistent
with a right-handed assailant.
(indistinct, distant voices)
BRASS: Find anything
interesting?
Uh...
It looks like Vance was
appealing his conviction
on grounds of new evidence.
What new evidence?
Uh...
Police bias.
Stuff like that. I still have
a lot of work to do here, Jim.
You know, if I were in prison
for killing my wife,
I don't think I'd put
her photo on the wall.
Wow. She's sexy.
Yeah, yeah. Well,
she's good-looking.
BRASS: Yeah. I remember Anne-
Marie's first day on the job.
She walked in the squad room
and every guy's neck
practically snapped.
She knew how to work it, too.
Was she married
to Vance back then?
No. They didn't hook up
till after she was
transferred to Brime.
Marriage was a mistake.
She wasn't
the settling-down type.
Vance told anybody
who would listen
that he'd never let her go.
Could be why he killed her.
A woman like Anne-Marie
could make a man do a lot
of things he'd regret.
Hey.
Hey. So I, uh, pulled
the video surveillance.
It's a total pile-on.
You can't really see anything.
Nice colors, though.
Kind of like
a Redskins game.
With one dead Cowboy.
SANDERS: And someone else
calling the plays.
One guy gives
the other a signal.
No way this jumped off
by accident.
And only one guy gets stuck.
An ex-cop.
This was a hit.
♪ ♪
(whirring)
So, if we say that our victim,
Vance Tolsom,
was here...
Well, the trajectory
of the blood spatter
and the void
on his right side
would put
Jose Castia here.
The bloodstains
and the void on Carlos Salavar
would put him here.
Which just leaves
Tomas Molinez.
Arterial
spurting pattern,
straight shot,
no void,
would put him
directly in front
of our victim.
(sighs)
Carlos,
Jose...
slide in from
the side.
Probably pin Vance's arms down.
(screaming)
(clamoring)
They were just the wing-men.
Looks like we found our doer.
BRASS:
Tomas Molinez.
Formerly employed by
Riverton, Marx and Flegel,
Certified Public
Accountants.
So you're currently two
years into a 30-year bid
for a triple fatal DUI.
Family in a van.
So you're the one
holding the shiv.
So if I were you, Tomas,
I'd make a deal
with me. Now.
Last time I heard that,
I got stuck with 30 years.
You have no idea what it's like
to be in that place.
No, I don't.
Because
I don't drink and drive.
Look, you're still a
relatively young man.
I mean, let's make
a deal. Let's talk.
Shave off a few years,
so you don't have to
leave prison in a walker.
You know?
You think I'm an idiot.
Look, I killed a cop.
I am tired
of being everybody's bitch.
Cop killer?
That's a different story.
It gives me status, juice.
Even if I get life, it's still
better than what I've got now.
Man...
(sighs)
Well, that is sad.
All right, look,
we deal on that,
but you know
how this works.
You got to give something to get
something, so give me something.
Look, if I rat,
I am dead tomorrow.
So you can't give me names.
So give me a reason why.
Why the cop?
Someone have issues
with him on the inside?
Look, I overheard somechisme.
The hit was a favor
for somebody
on the outside.
STOKES:
Hey, Catherine,
you got a minute?
Sure. What's up?
You mind if I shut your door
for a second?
All right.
Wind-up's got me curious.
Well, I found a little something
in Vance's cell.
I thought I'd give you
a heads-up.
Yeah, he was putting together
a case for a new trial,
and apparently,
his wife was sleeping around
before and after
they said "I do."
Look, I knew Anne-Marie.
She wasn't doing anything
the guys in the
department weren't doing.
Yeah, 'cause they were
all doing it with her.
Yeah, and probably
getting attaboyed for it.
Double standard.
The point is, he put together
a list of bedfellows.
I don't know where
this list came from,
or why it didn't come up
at his trial, but listen.
It reads like a who's who of
Southern Nevada law enforcement.
Anybody we know?
Ecklie's on there.
Really?
Wow. Oh, good for him.
Brass, too.
Well,
Jim used to be a player
back in the day.
Kind of had that Jersey,
Jack Nicholson thing.
Who else?
Ah, let's
see here.
Atwater, Bastille,
Bracket, Brooks,
Cavaliere. I'm only
up to the C's.
You want me to keep going?
Uh, let me guess.
Vega? Um, McKeen,
for sure, right?
Mm-hmm.
Vartann
is on here, as well.
Sorry to be the one
to break that to you.
Ancient history.
Well, according
to Vance's notes, he's convinced
that Anne-Marie's real murderer
is a cop on this list.
Well, half these guys
worked Anne-Marie's murder.
Yeah, I know. I read the file.
Brass was lead for LVPD,
and Vartann was his second.
Why didn't those guys
recuse themselves?
(mutters):
I don't know.
Book the evidence,
make me copies, I'll take care
of the notifications.
Oh, boy, when this
hits the fan, it's going
to come back on all of us.
So, I was riding the party train
pretty nonstop back then.
I mean, work was like
an interruption to my fun, yeah.
So, um, there was a homicide
convention in New Orleans.
Anne-Marie was there.
She was certainly sexy,
and-and available,
so we hooked up, and, um,
when Anne-Marie was murdered,
I went up the chain of command,
I-I... I told my boss
about our involvement,
he told me not to sweat it.
You know,
I-I did the right thing, yeah.
So what about you, Conrad?
Well, I didn't handle any of the
evidence. My team did.
And it was just...
It was... It was just
dinner with benefits.
Anne-Marie stopped by the lab
to discuss a case.
She was hungry.
One thing led to another,
and to a...
to a room at the Gold Coast.
BRASS:
Gold Coast.
Couldn't do any better
than that?
You know,
Anne-Marie's car
was found on the county line.
I mean,
LVPD assisted Brime Sheriffs,
but Brime was in charge
of the investigation.
Plenty of Brime guys
on that list.
WILLOWS:
Look, Vance
got whacked just as he was about
to get a new trial,
dredge up the past.
Maybe somebody didn't want
the truth to come out.
Yeah, somebody
who could reach into prison.
Well, those two bangers
who put Tomas Molinez up
for the hit--
they're from Brime County.
Okay, so that's where we start,
with the bangers.
♪ ♪
Jose, is this medical marijuana?
What's the matter?
You depressed about something?
LANGSTON:
You on the family plan?
You know, texting can be
very expensive,
Carlos. Could get you
another five years.
WARDEN:
Gentlemen, ran across
something interesting
in the visitor log.
Yeah? What's what?
Other than
his lawyer,
Vance has had only one
visitor, Jody Cambry.
Who's Jody Cambry?
His dead
wife's sister.
She was here pretty much
every week for three months.
Guy kills her sister.
Why would she come visit him?
Maybe she wanted
to see the man suffer.
WOMAN:
Yeah, I hated him.
And I hated the fact
he wouldn't leave me alone.
Wrote to me every week.
I just threw his letters away.
So, why'd you go see him?
One day, I opened up
one of his letters.
He wanted to talk.
He had something important
he needed to tell me.
I thought maybe he would tell
me where he buried Anne-Marie.
That's not what happened.
Hmm.
Vance swore up and down
that he was innocent.
That it was all a setup.
And you believed him?
Enough that I started
looking into things.
Talking to people.
Annie's friends,
other cops, family.
Everybody had a story about
some guy Annie had been with.
Thing is,
a lot of them had
investigated her murder.
That's grounds for a new trial.
So I started putting
together a list.
What, you think one of the guys
on your list is the real killer?
I think
Annie could make any guy crazy.
Before she died,
Annie told me
she'd fallen in love again.
Said this guy was the one.
She was going to leave Vance.
She wouldn't tell me who he was.
So he could be any one
of the guys on that list?
All I know is
that he was a cop.
Annie only dated cops.
I also know Vance was
never going to let her go.
So... whoever she
was leading on...
...she was playing
a dangerous game.
Why didn't you bring up
any of this at the trial?
Because back then,
like everyone else,
I thought
Vance killed her.
What makes you
so sure he didn't?
I just know.
(crowd chatter)
How's the leg?
Ah, it's better.
This is, uh...
This is new, seeing you
outside of the office,
middle of the day
with your clothes on.
Well, I thought that maybe
you and I should have
a cup of coffee.
Okay.
Excuse me?
Um... (clears throat)
You know, uh,
I met Anne-Marie
at the Academy,
and, uh, yes,
we had some good times
over the years.
It's all over the department
about the list.
I guess I'm on it?
Is this my unofficial heads-up?
Lou, you had a relationship
with a murder victim,
you worked the case,
and you didn't think you should
have recused yourself?
Oh. So this is more
of anofficialheads-up.
Well, Vance claimed that
there was a rush to judgment.
That you guys didn't even look
past him for the real killer.
"You guys"?
What? Are-Are you saying--
that, um, I didn't do my job
because I had a thing
with Anne-Marie?
When Warrick was murdered,
did you recuse yourself?
Did your team
recuse themselves?
Hell, Nick nearly put a bullet
through Undersheriff McKeen.
Then again, that's Nick.
You're sure
that Vance was good for it?
Yeah, I'm sure.
Look, he threatened Anne-Marie
more than once, all right?
In front of other cops.
His words: "If you ever try
to leave me, I'll kill you."
Guys say a lot of things.
What was your evidence?
Oh, come on.
Really, you want me to run it?
I do.
Okay.
Brime County never found
Anne-Marie's body,
but they did find her car.
Vance torched it, but Ecklie's
team still found blood.
And they also found
Vance's bloody clothes
and a bloody kitchen knife
from their kitchen
in a Dumpster off the 160.
Now in the pocket,
there was a matchbook
which we tied
to the arson of the car.
It was a good case.
Maybe too good.
Okay, you know,
I've never heard you say that
about any of the cases
that you've closed.
I'm just saying that a cop
that's smart enough
to disappear his wife's body
should be smart enough
to disappear the evidence.
You know what?
If this inquisition is over,
I got work to do.
Thank you.
Uh, just forget
the coffee. Sorry.
(keypad beeps)
Greg, I need you to pull
all of the Anne-Marie Tolsom
evidence.
Rerun everything.
♪ ♪
(machine beeping)
(printer beeps)
I reran all the blood evidence
from Anne-Marie's case--
the car, Vance's clothes,
the knife.
Found high
levels of EDTA.
What made you test for that?
It doesn't come up
in standard tox tests.
Well, because the time
stamp on this photo
was two hours after
the car was found.
Blood clots
after about 20 minutes.
I don't see any clotting.
Exactly. When
blood clots,
the fibrinogen
in the blood forms a big net,
catching
all the red blood cells.
The clot retracts into a clump
that would have left a ring
of straw-colored serum.
STOKES:
So somebody collected
Anne-Marie's blood
and added an anticoagulant.
Now, the only reason somebody
would do something like that
is if you were gonna store it.
Ortransport it
and plant it...
whenever and
wherever they want.
So... the blood evidence
wasallplanted.
STOKES:
Vance was right.
He was framed.
Probably by
the real killer.
And most definitely by someone
with knowledge of serology.
WILLOWS:
Yeah, a cop, or a CSI.
STOKES:
You know what?
I've seen this before.
This...
matchbook trick.
Here we go--
in 1995,
a torched car in Salt Lake
traced back to a murder
in Brime County.
Suspect was arrested in Pahrump.
All right, where are
we going with this?
Planted blood evidence.
The matchbook?
What cops know about forensics,
they learn from their cases.
Who was the arresting officer?
Lucas Martin.
He was the lead detective
in Anne-Marie's murder
in Brime County.
1997-- case in Brime,
staged crime scene
with EDTA blood--
investigating officer...
Lucas Martin.
There you go.
So maybe he
was Anne-Marie's
mystery lover.
Why isn't he on the list?
The sister didn't
know his name-- she just assumed
he was a cop on that list.
Okay. (sighs) Lucas Martin was
Anne-Marie's final conquest.
When she wouldn't
leave Vance for him,
he snapped, killed her,
and framed Vance for it,
and he did it by taking cues
from his old cases.
STOKES:
Anne-Marie's body
was never found.
At least we know now
where to look.
(dogs barking and baying)
ECKLIE:
Do you mind telling me why
there's a crime scene here
but no 419, no 420,
just a... a call at
4:30 in the morning?
We're anticipating
a crime scene, Conrad.
That seems to
be your team's
M.O. lately-- what,
you don't get enough work,
you got to go out
and look for it?
Actually, Conrad,
it is a crime scene.
It's about ten years old, but...
SANDERS:
We're working
a theory on the "List" case.
Yeah, I think
you're familiar with it.
Yeah, don't be a
smart-ass, Stokes.
(hound baying)
Picked up a scent, Captain.
With any luck, we're gonna find
the body of Anne-Marie Tolsom.
Catherine.
I want the full 411.
We think that Detective
Lucas Martin killed Anne-Marie,
and that he used knowledge
of his old cases
to plant evidence
implicating Vance.
He planted Anne-Marie
the same way.
All right, so why this place?
Well, Martin worked a case here.
A case in which a guy
killed his girlfriend,
dumped her body.
The Brime County Sheriffs
would never have found her body,
but the guy confessed.
(dogs barking)
Let's go. Go.
ECKLIE:
I don't see any Brime County
participation here.
Well, that's where
you come in.
I was hoping you'd
give them a call.
Catherine, I can see this
circus from the highway.
I don't need
to call anyone.
(barking continues in distance)
(hound baying)
There's something in there.
Go ahead, Nick.
Let's see what's behind
door number two, shall we?
(insects buzzing)
Blow flies.
Yeah.
Something's dead.
(doors creaking loudly)
(doors slam)
(flies buzzing)
More flies.
Two sets of footprints.
WILLOWS:
No telling how long
they've been here.
More footprints.
There's a body.
Fresh.
It's not Anne-Marie.
No, that's her sister, Jody.
Man, I just
talked to her.
Two GSW's
to the back of the head.
Size of the entry wounds:
medium caliber.
Maybe nine-mil.
Brime County issues nine-mils.
(gasping)
(siren wailing in distance)
(siren approaching)
(siren stops)
What the hell are
you people doing here?
Detective Lucas Martin.
I saw you at, uh,
Steve Jackson's
wedding last year.
You know Jim Brass--
you two worked
the Anne-Marie Tolsom case.
You ever hear of
professional courtesy?
We're on the trail of
Anne-Marie's body.
You wouldn't know anything
about that, would you?
Well, I damn straight would.
I turned over this whole
county looking for her.
She's not here.
Well, somebody is.
We just found Anne-Marie's
sister, Jody Cambry.
She's been shot dead.
Lucas Martin,
Catherine Willows.
When was the last time you
fired your gun, Detective?
Screw you, bitch.
I think you mean,
"Screw you, CSI Willows."
It's okay.
I'll get a warrant.
Let's go.
Go ahead, start without me.
Mrs. Robbins
always does.
I was talking about dinner.
Go ahead, take a look.
(sighs)
ROBBINS: I'd recognize
that shape anywhere.
She was pistol-whipped.
(groans, gunshots)
Two bullets within
three inches of each other.
Killer had training in firearms.
And all of the evidence
points to a cop.
From what I've heard,
everything's pointing
to Detective Lucas Martin.
Well, then
let's get those
two bullets out of her
and see if they
point to him, too.
♪ ♪
(quiet beep)
BRASS:
We pulled two slugs
out of Jody Cambry's head,
right where you left them.
I can dummy up a report
like this in about five minutes.
My duty weapon was
never out of my sight,
and it's never been fired.
No, notthatgun.
We're cops--
we have guns that have guns.
I'm talking about the attaboy
that Judge Grantson gave you
after the Domingo Flan trial.
That gun.
The Sig nine-mil.
It was in the database
before you even got it.
And ballistics matched it
to the Jody Cambry murder.
I don't have that gun anymore.
Well, that's a relief.
That means there's a record,
assuming that you went through
proper channels to sell it.
I sold it to a guy
at a gun show.
Out of state.
Well, now it's in state.
Maybe it got homesick.
You charging me?
As a matter of fact, I am.
You better lawyer up
and call the union,
'cause you're under arrest.
Did you hear
the good news?
Brass booked Lucas Martin
for Jody's murder,
and that's just
for starters.
Well, there might
be a problem.
(wry chuckle)
I am too tired to
hear that, Ray.
Jody died yesterday,
20-hundred hours.
I checked the duty log.
Lucas Martin was working.
Well, that doesn't actually mean
that he was working
the entire time.
I knew a cop once who painted
his house while on duty.
It's still an alibi.
What about the epithelials
under Jody's nails?
Still waiting for results.
Look, if Martin ordered
the hit on Vance,
he must have reached out
to Carlos Salavar.
Carlos isn't talking, Ray.
Maybe he'll listen.
Where are the real cops at,
lab rat?
I thought we'd have
a conversation, you and me.
Conversation.
Mm-hmm.
So you don't want to stick
nothing in my mouth, hm?
That's what
y'all do, right?
I know that Lucas Martin
contacted you
and put the hit on that cop.
You don't know jack.
I got your phone, Carlos,
all your texts
to your sister Reina
about your nephew Chuy
getting busted for drugs
and going to jail.
I know she has four
other kids at home.
She never had $5,000
to pay Chuy's bail.
Then all of a sudden,
she has $5,000?
Five G's just like that?
(quietly)
You and I both know
where that kind of money
comes from, don't we?
Escucha, mi amigo.
Amigo,one phone call,
they roll your sister up.
Her kids, they go
to Child Services.
You know what happens in
Child Services, don't you?
Oh, that's right...
you grew up there.
(grunting)
You want to swell up, go ahead--
call somebody in here;
they can help
you with that.
You gonna let
your sister go down
and those kids go
into Child Services
because of a cop?
I'm gonna ask you
one more time, Carlos.
Where did your sister
get the $5,000?
Que baboso.
You got no idea, bro.
I don't know no Lucas Martin.
You got the wrong cop.
(pounds table)
(door opens and closes)
(grunts)
Sorry.
(exhales)
Running from
another stripper?
Burlesque dancer.
And that's not funny.
I'm sorry.
So I ran
the epithelials
from Jody Cambry's
fingernails.
Yeah.
You're not going
to believe this.
Try me.
Well,
they didn't come
from Lucas Martin.
In fact, they're not even male.
Epithelials are
a sibling match
to Jody.
(scoffs)
What?
Yeah, and Jody only has
one sibling-- Anne-Marie Tolsom.
So that means
that Anne-Marie is alive.
We thought that
all this evidence was planted
to cover up a murder.
We now know that it was planted
to cover Anne-Marie's
disappearance.
And put Vance in prison for
a crime he didn't commit.
I thought he was
good for it.
Yeah, me, too.
I believe
you were led
by Lucas Martin
and Anne-Marie.
For love.
Martin helped her to get
out from under Vance.
Great, we just solved
a four-year-old case
we didn't even know was open.
We still got two real murders
with two real bodies.
Well, if you believe
the gangbanger,
Martin's not helping her
anymore.
Yeah, some other cop put
the hit out on Vance?
Give me a break.
Martin's gun shot Jody.
We found her at one
of his old body dump sites.
I mean, it sounds to me
like he's helping her.
Well, I hate to defend the guy,
but, you know, really,
a cop using his own gun
that he knows is in the system--
I mean, that is beyond dumb.
Martin said
he had gotten rid of the gun,
and any cop in Brime County
should know
about that dump site.
Well, the evidence puts
Anne-Marie at the scene.
Maybe the gun was
in her hand.
BRASS: Who'd you give
the gun to, Lucas?
No gun show story?
'Cause that was funny.
I could listen
to that again.
I didn't kill Jody.
You know, I want to believe
you, man, I'm trying,
but all the evidence
points to you...
unless you gave your gun
to Anne-Marie, you know.
Oh, yeah, surprise, we, we know
that Anne-Marie is still alive,
and we know the two of you
framed Vance for murder
and now she's throwing you
under the bus
and trying to frame you.
Hey... I get it.
I get the obsession.
Anne-Marie is a force
of nature, you know.
She makes everybody feel like
you're the only
guy in the world.
I get it.
I loved her.
Still do.
We were in love,
we were going to be together,
and we both know Vance is
a bad guy-- bad to her.
I didn't want him
coming after us.
So you put Vance in prison,
Anne-Marie disappears,
and, uh, you, you, uh,
you tag along later.
That the plan?
That was the plan.
I'd wait a couple years,
put in my papers.
End of the summer,
I'm retiring.
Meanwhile, I see her
when I can.
Mm-hmm, send her any money?
That's a loaded
question,
'cause we know that you're
sending $1,000 a month
to some orphan fund in Mexico.
$1,000 a month
on a cop's salary?
And that's a lot of love
for thepoquito niños.
So here's
the new plan.
What we're going to work on
is a minimum sentence
at a minimum-
security prison.
Tell me about the gun.
I gave it to Annie
for protection.
Where is she?
I don't know.
When I told her
I was putting in for retirement,
she stopped returning my calls.
Jim...
I swear to you, I didn't
even know she was in town
until you told me
Jody got popped with my gun.
She's tough, huh?
I mean, when
Anne-Marie dumps you,
she really dumps you hard.
All right.
Well, all right, Jim.
We're at Jody's place now,
so we'll see what we can dig up.
All right, thanks.
(phone beeps)
Hey, Anne-Marie dumped
Lucas Martin
three months ago.
Now, that's
right around
the same time Jody started
visiting Vance in prison.
I don't see any connection.
Bye-bye,
sugar daddy.
What's she going
to do for money now?
Get a new daddy.
Or...
reach out to her schoolteacher
sister, who's collected
on the life insurance.
Here we go.
On January 1,
Jody's money market account
shows a balance
of half a million and change.
The account was opened
two years ago.
Well, that sounds like
Anne-Marie's life insurance.
Mm-hmm.
SANDERS: That's about
what a cop gets.
STOKES: Jody had a big heart.
On January 5, she transferred
half the money
to an orphans' fund in Mexico.
SANDERS: "Save the Niños."
That's the same charity that
Lucas Martin was donating to.
Jody knew Anne-Marie was alive.
Yeah, maybe not till
after January 5.
Three months ago.
You know, it all fits.
Dump Lucas, reach
out to the sister.
Yeah, well, Jody should have
reached out to the cops.
Yeah, maybe she didn't want
to betray her sister
or maybe she didn't want to let
Vance rot in prison either.
That's probably
why she went to go see him.
She knew he was innocent.
There's a bunch of payments
to a law firm...
and one final transaction--
$110,000 wire transfer to
Save the Niños Orphans' Fund...
in Mexico...
last night...
11:47 p.m.
At 11:47,
Jody was already dead,
Lucas Martin
was in jail.
Anne-Marie was here.
She cleaned out
Jody's account.
I think I know why
Anne-Marie took the risk
of coming back to Vegas.
She had to stop Vance from
getting a second trial.
Killing him would have
eliminated that problem,
but there was still Jody.
There was always a chance that
Jody would rat out her sister.
Right, so Anne-Marie had
to kill her, too.
Why are you doing this?
I would have kept
your secret.
For how long?
You're my sister.
Forever.
Who better to frame
for Jody's murder
than Lucas Martin?
And we thought that Lucas killed
Jody, and we thought
that he arranged for
the hit on Vance, but he didn't.
So who did?
Maybe another cop.
It's a long list.
(chuckles) I wish I knew that
many guys I could depend on.
You just need one.
Uh, should I stay,
or is this case-related?
Stay.
While at the Academy,
Anne-Marie was with a lot
of guys, pre-list.
Anyway, I was trying
to make a connection
between Anne-Marie
and the prison,
and I remembered this guy
from the Academy who--
he couldn't cut it,
got tossed.
The two of them were close--
you know, friends.
Well, apparently
he started
a new career
in corrections.
LANGSTON:
Jarrod Malone.
He's a C.O.
He's on Vance's cell block.
Yeah, what are the odds?
(jail door clanging)
Annie, people are starting
to ask questions.
Okay?
It's not going to be okay.
Lucas got busted; he's going
down, I could be next.
How do I know what he said?
Look, we got to act fast.
Where are you?
I'll meet you.
My shift's over at midnight.
I'll be there.
♪ ♪
Just had to make
sure you were alone.
Not that I don't
trust you.
It's kind of nice...
but I'm not wearing
a wire.
Can I see your cell phone?
(both chuckle)
You're good;
it's not wired either.
Well, a girl's got to be
real careful, you know.
Especially when
she's dead.
Got the tickets?
Morning flight.
Mr. and Mrs. Nobody.
You're going
to love Mexico.
You know, I think
I'm gonna like Costa Rica
a little bit better,
along with a hundred grand.
That wasn't the plan.
I know, but I've been
thinking about that and,
Vance and Lucas.
And now you don't trust me?
Jody was
your sister.
You did that
to your family.
She shouldn't have
gone to Vance.
And so you took care
of both of 'em?
Look, Jody was soft.
She always needed
to fix things.
She didn't understand men.
And you,
you can't be trusted.
(both chuckle)
You're right about that.
(sirens wailing)
Annie, I know you got a gun.
I want to see your hands.
On your knees.
You son of a bitch.
I like you, but not enough
to do 25 to life for you.
BRASS:
I know what you're thinking--
you already died once.
But don't do it for real
this time, okay?
Oh, come on, Jimmy, you wouldn't
shoot an unarmed woman,
would you?
VARTANN:
I think he'd shoot you.
I know I would.
Turn around.
Unarmed, huh?
(patting)
Ooh.
Seems like old
times, Lou.
(handcuffs clicking)
You always did
have the touch.
Yeah, well,
you've lost yours.
We don't need
to wire the guy.
The whole world
is wired.
I could hear your heart
beating from inside the van.
You've been gone
a long time, baby.
Now you're going away
for even longer.
Let's see how many men
are on the jury.