WILLOWS:
Cops found a body.
LANGSTON:
Where?
L.A.
Ray, we'll find Gloria.
It's been 72 hours.
That means she's
already gone.
She's still alive!
Gloria's still alive, Ray!
WILLOWS:I don't think
that you should be here.
You're going back
to Vegas.
This sick bastard's
leaving us a bread crumb trail.
LANGSTON:
Request immediate backup.
My location-- the
old Thorpe farm.
Welcome home, Ray.
Glad you could make
the family reunion.
I assume you met Dad.
He knew you were here the whole
time. He was protecting you?
He's never protected me
in my life, Ray.
Never knew me,
never knew my genius.
Had no idea of my extraordinary,
uh, uh, accomplishments.
So when he came home, I gave him
a little show-and-tell.
Now I'm wearing the pants.
You don't become
a real man until you take
that first swing at dad.
Oh, you know me so well, Ray.
Except with me,
it's many swings, many dads.
Many, many-- Ray!
Careful. I've gotten
very good with this.
I don't think you want
to shoot me, Warner.
I think you need me too much.
These last few kills--
the thrill is gone.
And I blame you.
No.
You never
forget your first, right?
Tell me, who is Nate Haskell?
You're digging, Ray.
You're digging, and you're gonna
keep digging for a long time,
because the ghosts
in this house have finally
stopped talking.
Right, Dad?
(grunting)
Hey, come on, Ray. Huh?
Come on, Ray!
(grunts)
(grunting)
(panting)
(wheezing)
What's the matter, Ray?
We're just getting started.
No. We're done.
(grunts)
(panting)
(sighs)
(grunts)
(panting)
You're all right,
Gloria.
You're gonna be fine.
I'm disappointed
in you, Ray.
I told you, we share
something very special.
I told you, we're nothing alike.
Aren't you curious, Ray?
Don't you wonder
why she's still alive?
Ask her what I did to her.
(switchblade clicks open)
Yeah.
Ask.
(panting)
MAN:
Captain?
Cover the back.
(siren approaching)
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
(sirens blaring)
OFFICER (over radio): The
suspect's on the first floor.
He's down.
Proceed with caution.
You guys secure down here.
I'm gonna head
up and join Brass.
Got it.
Copy that.
Gloria...
Mm?
It's over.
I'm not going
to leave you.
Just gonna get you
to the hospital now.
Everything's
going to be fine.
Ray, listen to me.
You don't say anything...
to anyone, get it?
Nothing, nobody.
Mitch, Akers--
meet me out front?
MITCHELL (over radio): Copy.
I have the car standing by.
BRASS:
Put him in the car.
Nobody talks to him.
That's an order.
Yep. Got it, Captain.
(siren approaching)
OFFICER (over radio): This is
Metro holding Code Three
to Desert Palm Hospital.
Ray!
SIDLE:
We chased Haskell from Vegas
to L.A. and back
and end up finding him here.
They always go home.
BRASS:
Home?!
This house is owned
by Arvin Thorpe,
the farmer
from across the street.
Langston discovered
that Haskell's real name is
Warner Thorpe.
That makes Haskell
the farmer's son?
The farmer must have been
lying to us.
Well, he's still lying...
upstairs with a bullet in him.
Face up.
Came through the banister
and landed here.
Backwards.
Took a beating beforehand.
Blunt force trauma,
nose is broken.
Thank God Ray's okay.
They duked it out; Ray won.
It's a classic case
of self-defense.
We all know the
history of this.
Internal Affairs is going to be
all over it.
We need to give Ray
all the help we can.
I'll be outside.
"You never forget your first."
Haskell left the same message
for Langston
in Tina Vincent's room in L.A.
Trail leads upstairs.
Tickets to the fight.
Ray was lured here.
Haskell's house.
Home field advantage.
I guess
Ray had more to fight for.
WOMAN: Trauma's prepped
and ready, Doctor.
You're going to be okay, Gloria.
You hear me?
You're gonna be just fine.
You're gonna be all right.
Dr. Langston,
you have to let her go.
I promise, we're going
to take good care of her.
Ray...
thank God you're all right.
You know, I'd give you a hug
right now, but unfortunately,
you're evidence, if
you know what I mean.
I understand.
I need to be in there
with Gloria.
Ray, we've got
to do this by the book.
I'll process Gloria, and
Nick will take
your clothes.
You saved her life, Ray.
That's all that matters.
What is this?
I don't know.
(sighs)
All right.
I'm going to need your clothes
there, too, bud.
All right.
(sighs)
ECKLIE:
Jim?
I.A.'s already here.
No, in your office.
You still out
at the Thorpe house?
Okay. No, no, no,
I'll handle it.
I.A. works for me.
Being boss should be good
for something. Yeah.
Detective Schulz,
Brass is, uh,
still out at the scene.
Figure we could start
without him.
Probably finish, too.
This is all going
to be pretty straightforward.
Always tricky
to estimate that, isn't it?
Simpler these
officer-involved cases look,
the more surprises
seem to pop up.
I've seen plenty of claims
of self-defense turn out
to be cold-blooded murder
and a life sentence in Ely.
When do I talk
to CSI Langston?
Well, let's give the guy
a couple days.
He's been through
the wringer in two cities...
You saying you want to delay?
We all want to put this to bed,
Detective, Langston included.
Who wouldn't, in his situation?
You'll get your interview.
Thanks for coming in.
Got it.
So, Haskell traveled
approximately 132 inches.
Let her rip, Dave.
Yeah.
(sighs)
This wood is thick.
Took a lot of force.
(yelling)
Contusion on the back.
Looks about the same width
as the railing.
Guys like Haskell
don't go down easy.
Single penetrating GSW
to Dad's head.
Multiple lacerations.
Scabbed over.
Dad took a beating at least
an hour before he died.
Got a baker's dozen
of stab wounds to the abdomen.
A lot of this blood
could be explained
by Dad's injuries.
Contributions
could be
from Gloria
and Langston, too.
Some of it's got
to be from Haskell.
More than some,
given the condition of his face.
Shoot, sample, sort.
♪ ♪
(whimpering)
(panting and whimpering)
Oh, God.
(sobbing)
(screams)
WILLOWS:
You're going
to make it through this, Gloria.
You survived.
He's dead
and you're not.
You beat him.
Nine-mil.
Gun Haskell used
to shoot Dad?
And Tina Vincent
in L.A., I bet.
It's empty.
Only one round in Dad.
Other shots fired at
Langston and Gloria?
We can't talk to them until
after they talk to I.A.,
but we can let
the walls talk,
look for bullet holes,
cartridge casings.
This wallpaper is
covering something.
Old blood.
It's kids' wallpaper.
I think this was
Haskell's boyhood room.
Yeah, there is
a lot of blood.
Medium velocity,
heavier drops from castoff.
Nate Haskell might have
died in this house,
but I think a serial killer
was born in this room.
(low, indistinct
police radio communication)
So this is
where the S.O.B. grew up?
First sample's
not human.
He did say
his first kill was a cat.
Serials love to start
with animals,
move on to human victims.
You know, kids don't wallpaper
their own rooms.
At the very least,
Dad knew what his son
was up to in here.
Maybe he was up
to it with him.
He never called the cops.
Maybe they shared hobbies.
Langston might have been
up against more
than one killer.
SIDLE:Greg's checking out
the master bedroom now.
The Thorpes didn't even paper
over the carnage in this room.
They didn't even repaint it,
just washed all
the blood away.
Or so they thought.
What the hell went on
in this house?
Whatever it was,
Arvin Thorpe didn't want
anyone poking around here.
He bought
this house in 1958,
listed it as his primary
residence until '76,
when he bought the house across
the road and moved in there.
Then lived there
till his last lying day.
Yeah, but he never rented
this place out, never sold it.
Guy like Arvin-- this property
was keeping all his secrets.
All this old blood,
father and son killers--
the more bodies we
find around here,
the better it
is for Ray.
Why don't you and Sara
keep working
the current case analysis?
I'll have Catherine
send me over some help.
Floors, walls, basement, yard--
I'm gonna rip
this hellhole apart.
DOCTOR:
Gloria is clearly suffering
acute traumatic stress--
alert but not making
eye contact,
not communicating.
No, no, no, no, no.
I'm monitoring
for tachycardia.
You do not talk
to him.
He is not
her husband.
You do not talk to him
about my daughter.
What did he tell you,
that he's a doctor, too?
Well, he's not.
He is nothing
to my daughter
but the one responsible
for all of this.
Mrs. Parkes, why don't we
take this somewhere...?
Get security
and get him out of here.
He's the one
that did this to her.
He's the one that brought
this monster into her life.
You did this to her.
Nora...
Go!
Get out of my sight.
I am taking my daughter
back to Baltimore with me.
I have already arranged
the transportation.
Let's talk about
the best timetable...
I am taking
my daughter home!
Got the DNA reports
from all the blood
we sampled
in the hallway.
I figure
we color-code
each of the blood donors.
Blue for Langston,
green for Gloria,
orange for Arvin Thorpe.
And Haskell's
yellow-- perfect.
♪ ♪
It's almost all
Haskell's blood.
You collected a chunk
of Haskell's scalp
with a hair from right here.
Blood spatter from Haskell on
the adjacent section of wall.
Langston had Haskell
on his back.
Ground or pounded his head
into the floor.
SANDERS:
So Ray got a few good blows in.
Just because Langston had
Haskell on the floor
doesn't mean that he had him
under control.
Langston's
shoe prints
in Haskell's blood
heading to the spot
where Haskell went
through the
banister?
Stomping through blood
that was already on the floor.
Yeah, but it was
only Langston's
shoe prints.
Tangled up with Haskell,
battling him
back towards the banister,
Haskell would have stepped
into the same blood.
Langston had him off his feet.
He drove him
towards the banister.
Maybe Haskell
still had
the gun and jumped Langston.
Langston did
what he had to do.
He was fighting for his life.
Greg, if, if we were talking
about two anonymous people
locked in a fight...
I'd still say it was a fight.
Fights are
unpredictable,
anything can happen.
Yeah, but
one person
can utterly dominate the other,
have full control over them
and throw them
to their death.
I-I'm not saying
that that's what happened--
and we both know
that Haskell was a monster--
but we're looking
for the truth here...
right?
Any bodies yet?
Hey.
So far, just a few family pets
who lost the owner lottery--
two cats and a dog,
no collars, no way
to date 'em-- and these graves
progress in size.
I got a bad feeling
about a couple of those.
I got something.
Neither Rex nor Fluffy.
ECKLIE:
It's human.
You guys are going
to need a hand here.
I've still got my kit in my car;
let me grab it.
That's the spirit.
CSI Willows.
Detective, what
are you doing here?
Paying my respects;
surprised I was the first one.
Is that your unofficial way of
asking for my team's report?
I can make it official.
You will get it
when we're done
processing
all the evidence.
We've been down
this road before--
Warrick Brown,
now Ray Langston.
I talked to LAPD.
Your guy bought a gun.
For all I know,
he slapped around
Tina Vincent.
I don't think he'd hesitate
to kill Nate Haskell.
I think you're getting
ahead of the evidence.
Well, I'm ahead
of you.
See for yourself.
Your friend Schulz
was just here.
Yeah, I had the pleasure.
So what do we have?
Well, Dad here was
maybe Haskell's
one justifiable murder.
Haskell had long-
healed bone traumas--
ribs, fibula, tibia,
spiral breaks--
indicative
of childhood abuse.
But his father didn't
put him on this table.
Langston did.
Catherine, if it
were my wife
tied up in that room,
I'll tell you...
Doc, I get it.
But is that how you think
Schulz is going to look at this?
Ray killed someone.
I need to know it was
the only way, the right way.
Tell me there's something
on this body
that's going
to make this case.
Okay. Nate Haskell
died as a result
of atlanto-occipital
disarticulation,
consistent with his position
of impact on the stairs.
Prior to death, he endured
multiple blunt force traumas
to his face and body
as you would see in a
serious fist fight.
Well, Haskell fell
backwards through the railing,
and landed on his back.
How did he shatter his knee?
Could be from the fall,
could be from the fight.
And the kidney
is severely damaged.
Is that from the fall, too?
Or the fight?
Either way, I'd call
it karma, wouldn't you?
Doc, my opinion is not what
we should be
worried about right now.
(sighs)
I found a couple of marks on
his wrists that I can't explain.
Is this from the handcuffs?
Not consistent with Brass's
two-rail metal cuffs that were
on the body when I received it.
Okay, so, Haskell was cuffed
or bound by something else.
By someone else.
Did Schulz see this?
I'll tell what I told Schulz.
These marks, the knee,
the kidney damage--
none of it affects the
conclusions of my C.O.D.
I'm going to go
get some air.
(sighs)
Gloria's SAE report came in.
It's on the table, but you don't
want to look at that, Ray.
I need to, Catherine.
(whimpering)
(sighs)
(inhales, exhales)
(indistinct radio communication,
camera shutter clicking)
ECKLIE:
Small mandible, wide pelvis.
Adult female.
Color matches
the surrounding dirt.
She's been here
at least a decade.
STOKES:
Skull's crushed in.
That's not really
Haskell's style.
Killer's style develops.
This may be
an early rough draft.
What do you got, David?
Adult male.
SANDERS:
Polyester?
'70s, maybe?
ECKLIE:
Pockets are empty.
STOKES:
Supra Lux. What's that?
My grandma had a pink oven
with that logo on it.
Wait a sec.
Long before
point-and-click shopping,
even before washed-up celebs
hawked skin cream
on late-night TV,
sales was a ground war,
and the foot soldiers
were traveling salesmen.
Sometimes, to show you just
how cool their product was,
salesmen would come knocking
at your door armed with
a salesman's sample.
A little, semi-working model
of the product.
Supra-Lux.
I noticed it when we
were in here earlier.
So, you think some time in
the late '70s, a salesman
knocks on this door,
and Nate Haskell,
or Warner Thorpe, kills him,
and then takes this little toy
fridge as his first souvenir?
Yeah, only he didn't
just take his model.
He took his name.
(camera shutter clicking)
Hey, Doc.
Hey.
So... this is
Douglas Nathan Haskell,
reported missing
in 1976, by his wife Elaine.
He was on a Supra-Lux sales
swing through Southern Nevada.
DNA is a match to some
of the old blood we found
in Nate's childhood bedroom.
We were also able
to recover DNA
off of our female
skeleton's molar.
And as you can see there,
we ran that.
Hey.
So, all of these were
found in his backyard.
Whoa. All right,
who are they?
This one gave him his name.
This one gave him life.
Mother.
Yeah.
That's Lois Thorpe.
She worked as an aid
in an elementary school.
One day in 1968, she just
didn't show up for work.
So, the principal called
the police, filed a report.
Arvin said she ran off.
Multiple fractures
to her skull.
Healed sternal fractures.
Posterior rib fractures.
Beaten to death
after a long prelude of abuse.
STOKES:
She's a DNA match
to blood we found
in the Thorpe master bedroom.
Now, if she died in 1968,
the boy would have only been
eight years old?
And incapable of beating
his mother to death.
So, Father killed Mother.
STOKES:The wall spattered
with themom's blood was right
on the other side
of the little boy's room,
so he had to have heard
those beatings over
and over again.
(thudding, angry grunting,
mother whimpering)
ROBBINS:
These animal skeletons
exhibit a mix
of violent method.
Some of the skeletons
complete, unharmed,
possibly suffocation deaths.
The others-- their bones
crushed into tiny pieces.
Standard
serial killer evolution.
In 1976, he graduated
to humans.
At 16 years old, Warner Thorpe
meets Douglas Nathan Haskell,
a traveling appliance salesman.
Hello.
STOKES:
Soon after, Warner Thorpe just
stopped showing up for school.
And Nate Haskell is unleashed
on the world.
WILLOWS:
I.A. is on our ass.
They want the report.
Do we know what happened
between Langston and Haskell?
Well...
um...
the blood evidence says that
Langston dominated in the fight.
He had Haskell on his back.
He even had him off his feet
at one point.
He carried him to the banister.
So, reasonably,
Langston should have been able
to subdue him,
to restrain him, to cuff him.
There were marks
on Haskell's wrists.
I compared the abrasions to the
department-issued flex-cuffs.
Are you suggesting
that Langston cuffed Haskell,
shoved him through the railing,
and then cut the restraints off?
Greg and I didn't find
any flex-cuffs at the scene.
Well, the banister left
a continuous
and unbroken contusion
across Haskell's back,
so his arms weren't
behind his back.
There was nothing between
that banister and his back
when he hit it.
Suggests he
wasn't cuffed.
There is another possibility.
Langston could have cut
the cuffs off Haskell
before throwing him
through the railing.
There were no cuffs
found at the scene.
And if we let the evidence
speak, it's telling us,
no cuffs present, no cuffs used.
Mrs. Parkes?
I'm Catherine Willows
with the Crime Lab.
You work with Ray.
Yes.
What are you doing here?
I'm the one that
processed your daughter
when she arrived here.
I just wanted to check
on how she's doing.
You want to ask her questions,
you want her to relive it.
That's what
you people do.
Well, she's not talking,
so please, just go.
Mrs. Parkes, my job is not
to make anyone relive
their nightmares, but
sometimes I'm left
with a few questions.
I just need a minute
with Gloria.
Eight years old.
She made a list of all
the big places
she was going to play music.
And she made it
all come true.
She could have done
anything she wanted.
Do you know why
their marriage ended?
Because Ray was afraid
to have a baby with her.
Not just nerves.
Fear that something bad
inside him
would be passed on.
That man has always scared me.
Doesn't he scare you?
Gloria?
Mm.
I just wanted to ask...
...if you were doing okay.
I'm tired.
(quietly):
I understand.
I'll let you rest.
Mm.
Thank you.
What are you doing?
Isn't that Langston's kit?
There were marks
on Haskell's wrists.
They look like flex-cuffs.
So now you're checking to see
if his kit is still stocked
with three
department-issue cuffs?
Yep.
What if it was me?
My kit?
I'd open it.
We have all had
our moment in the dark
where we had to fight
our way out,
and when we did, it was
up to the rest of the team
to shine a light
onto that darkness
to see what happened.
That's our job.
I just need to know
what I'm dealing with
and then I will deal with it.
Three cuffs.
Satisfied?
That the report
for I.A.?
That took longer
than I expected.
There was a question
about whether Langston
might have used flex-
cuffs on Haskell.
And?
Greg and Sara didn't find any
at the scene,
but you were
the first responder.
Is that a question?
I didn't see
any mention of flex-cuffs
in your report.
No, you didn't.
I presume Ray had
all three pairs in his kit.
All three, yeah,
you've got quite a memory there.
Know how to stock a kit.
You have a problem,
you have about five seconds
to spit it out.
I look out
for my team.
How about you?
Now, are you going
to sign that or what?
I already did.
We all did.
I made you a copy.
Save you time.
The evidence supports CSI
Langston acting in self-defense.
If you care about her,
don't go in there.
The doctor says
Gloria is okay
to fly back
to Baltimore with me,
and we're leaving
in the morning.
She doesn't want
to talk about this.
She wants to forget, and the
sight of you would just...
I understand, Nora.
I know I'm responsible for
what's happened to her.
I'd like to try
and find a way
to atone for it,
if I can.
I know that we have
never liked each other.
I've never understood
what Gloria saw in you, but...
(sighs) ...what I said
to you earlier...
It's not for me
to blame or judge you.
That's okay, she'll do that.
Well, she
can't speak
for herself yet,
so if that's the answer
you're looking for,
you're going
to have to wait.
She needs
to go home to heal.
I hope you find peace, Ray.
(phone vibrating)
♪ ♪
What are you
doing here?
You know, it's weird, I...
I just got off the phone
with the police officer
in the black-and-white
across the street.
He's looking out
for trespassers.
He's wrangling
these crime geeks
who want to spend a night
in the House of Haskell.
Now, that wouldn't
be you, would it?
You killed a murderer
in self-defense.
You get that, right?
I get that, uh,
I did everything I
could do for Gloria.
Look, Jim, I knew what
I was walking into.
Nice to see you leading
this dance finally, Ray.
I can feel your
pulse, Nate.
Feel your heart beating.
(weakly):
Can you...?
(grunts)
If I'd hit you a
moment earlier,
just the upstroke of
your heartbeat's T-wave,
I could have induced
commotio cordis,
or instant death.
But you didn't, Ray.
This is a slow dance.
You made sure of that.
You spent a lifetime trying
to make me suffer...
like you made a lot
of other people.
(grunts)
Scarred me for life!
Took my kidney.
Well, I'm gonna help
myself to one of yours.
(grunting)
Let it go.
Let it out, Ray,
let it out!
(laughing):
Let it out.
There's still
more in you, Ray,
still more
of me in there.
There's a little bit
of me in her, too, Ray.
I think I know where you
want to take me, Nate.
But you know
something?
I'm already there.
(grunting)
(screams)
It's all right, Nate.
It's all right,
It's all right.
I'll take you the
rest of the way.
(both yell)
(thud)
Look... we are the only
two people in the world
who know what
really happened here,
and this stays
between you and me
'cause if I.A.
gets ahold of it,
Internal Affairs is going
to kick this up
to a criminal case.
They'll try you
for murder, Ray,
they'll lock you up,
and it won't just be you
you'll be crucifying.
What?
I had white chalk
on my hands--
transfer
from Gloria.
Music notes.
(cello playing)
(giggles)
"The Swan"
by Saint-Saens.
It's not really the story
for a first date...
(laughs)
...but, um...
that piece of music...
saved my life.
Saved her life.
She knew
you'd come back for her.
You did
the right thing, brother.
(Langston sighs)
After everything
that's happened
between the two of you,
it's natural that you'd need
some reflection.
Reflection.
That's what he saw
when he looked at me.
That's what he wanted
you to believe.
He wanted to bring you
into that house with him.
He wanted to make you a
helpless child, just like him,
huddled against
that bedroom wall
with nothing but terror
on the other side.
My daddy was on the other side
of that wall in my house.
The difference
between me
and Nate Haskell is that
I decided to train myself
to be good,
like other people.
"Be good, Ray."
Even scratched it
into my desk
when I was little--
"be good."
Be good.
Youaregood.
SCHULZ:
This is the formal interview
of CSI Raymond Langston...
...with regard to the incident
resulting in the death
of Warner Thorpe,
aka Nate Haskell.
CSI Langston has been informed
of his administrative rights
and understands the nature
of this investigation.
We will commence
with CSI Langston's account
of the facts in this case...
The fact is...
that I killed a man.
That's why you're here.
Question is:
how did you kill him?
Was it self-defense...
or murder?