(drums beating rapid,
complex rhythms)
(drumming continues)
(cell phone rings)
Gil? I'm here already.
Where are you?
I'm still in Peru.
Are you at the party?
Hold on, uh...
Hold on, Gil. I can't hear you.
Sounds like taiko drums in
the background.
The deaf love the vibrations.
they can feel them
on their skin.
Wh-why are you still in Peru?
Is everything okay?
Found another mass grave.
(static crackling):
Government asked me to stay.
...you there?
Gil? Gil!
(drumming ends)
(applause, cheers)
SIDLE:
Mrs. Grissom!
Hi!
Sara, I want you to meet
someone. Julia Holden...
head of the department
of deaf cultural studies.
Nice to meet you,
Professor.
Julia, please.
My students don't even
call me Professor.
Sara's Gil's wife.
Oh, the otherMrs. Grissom.
It's Sara Sidle.
She didn't take his name.
Julia's been
like a daughter to me.
I'm so proud of her.
Published author,
lecturer, foremost authority
on deaf culture
in the country.
Hmm.
Ladies!
You look beautiful tonight!
Have you met my
daughter-in-law, Sara?
Hi. I'm Dr. Eric Lambert.
I'm the director
of the Gilbert Foundation.
Oh, so you're the one who gets
to choose the grant winner.
Half a million dollars!
And they're all
a good candidate.
Julia runs
the selection committee,
and she's very passionate
about the candidates.
Sorry. I have a stack
of papers on my desk.
I better get going.
Bye.
So, where's your son?
Gil got stuck in Peru.
He's been doing
some consulting work for the...
government.
He's-he's not coming.
Seems like my son's
away from home a lot.
(combo playing mellow jazz)
(explosion thunders,
car alarms wailing)
SIDLE:
Julia!
SIDLE: Hey!
Get away from the car!
No! Get back!
It's gonna blow!
(Julia yelling)
Julia, he-he's dead.
Lambert is dead.
He's gone.
He's dead.
(sobbing)
He's gone.
You have to stay back!
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
Hey.
STOKES: Wait a minute.
You did something different.
Oh, my goodness.
I almost didn't recognize you.
Yeah, yeah. Did you get
a haircut or something?
Please tell me...
Yes, we have
your work clothes.
Here's your coveralls.
Thank you.
Here's a seat
for you.
So who's the victim?
Uh, Dr. Eric Lambert.
He's the director of
the Gilbert Foundation.
I met him at the party.
STOKES:
Black-tie event.
Was it an open bar?
You know, he did
have a drink in his hand.
LANGSTON:
Possible drunk driver.
Hit the streetlight;
car exploded.
Were you
the first one to respond?
Uh... no.
Actually, she was.
Uh, going to try
and go talk to her.
My signing's pretty terrible.
We'll, uh, we'll check
out the vehicle.
Um... I need to ask
you some questions.
Is that all right?
Did you see what happened?
Wait...
Wait, wait, wait.
I-I-I don't understand.
It's too fast.
Excuse me, excuse me--
you were at the party?
Uh, yes.
Dennis Palmer.
Could you
interpret for me?
Sure, sure.
SIDLE:
Julia, what exactly
did you see?
I was in my office,
when I felt the explosion.
You felt it?
The vibrations.
My windows rattled. So I got up
to see what was happening.
That'swhen I saw the fire.
I ran from my office
as fast as I could.
That's when I saw
it was Dr. Lambert.
I wish I could have
saved him.
(siren whoops)
Reminds me of my first case.
Except you're not wearing
a tie this time.
Gonna be hard
to burrito him like that.
I could put him in
the passenger seat of the van.
Then we could use
the carpool lane.
Always looking for the
silver lining, eh, David?
Yeah. That's me.
Okay, guys. Come on.
Two things make a car go boom--
ruptured gas tank and a spark.
LANGSTON: Rough terrain.
Sliding down this hill,
there's a lot of things that
could have ruptured the tank.
Yeah, and metal dragging
over the rocks,
could have caused
a spark.
If it was anywhere
near the tank.
Puncture, spark, boom.
We're in a ravine at the
edge of campus, yet
all the witnesses say that
they felt the explosion.
But if the car
blew up down here,
the shock waves
would've been...
absorbed by the hill, right?
No skid marks.
Means the driver didn't
pump the brakes
or turn the wheel at all.
Looks like he went
clean over.
Mm-hmm.
(inhales)
That's gasoline.
You know, I don't think
this explosion happened
down in the ravine.
There's a debris trail here.
Yeah, here we go.
Got something here.
This looks like
a detonator, Ray.
I think I have
another piece of it here, Nick.
Lambert... didn't just
drive into this ravine.
He had a little help.
We got a point
of explosion here.
Okay...
so the explosion kills him
or incapacitates him,
the car continues on
till it rolls over the edge.
This was no accident.
Someone planted a bomb
in Lambert's car.
ROBBINS:
Dr. Lambert showed no signs
of smoke inhalation.
WILLOWS: So he was dead
before the car caught fire.
The force of the blast
ruptured his aorta.
Died almost
instantaneously.
Thank you,
Doctor.
Yeah.
Sara.
So, what did you find out
about Dr. Lambert?
Well, he was
never married.
No bitter ex-wife.
No greedy kids.
I'm going to check
with the school
and see if he
had any enemies.
What if you just check
with your mother-in-law?
She's pretty
dialed-in there.
Uh, yeah, communication's
not really our strong suit.
I thought you were
learning to sign.
I am.
I-I'm... I'm improving.
It's not really
a language barrier,
it's just kind
of a barrier.
She's very hard
to get close to.
She questions everything.
She's got to be right
about everything.
She's mostly unavailable.
(chuckling):
Sorry.
What?
Oh, it's...
you just described Grissom.
Like mother, like son.
Greg... what
have you got
going on here?
I'm almost done rendering
a 3-D simulation of
your car bombing.
Based on where the car
was when it exploded,
how much gas was in the tank,
and using standard
temperature and pressure,
I was able to calculate
the size of the explosion
and the shock waves
it produced.
Now, the white dots represent
our witnesses and their
respective locations,
at the time of the explosion.
Simulation's complete.
Let's blow somebody up.
The shock waves hit the dorm
and the surrounding buildings,
like our witnesses said;
except they never reached
the Humanities building,
though our witness there
claims she had felt it.
It's impossible.
SANDERS:
Yeah. The dormitories
are blocking
the Humanities building.
Who's the witness?
(beep)
WILLOWS:
Julia Holden.
She lied to me.
WILLOWS: You think
she was involved?
SIDLE: If she was,
we'll need evidence to prove it.
No sign of any nitrates
or bomb-making materials yet.
Well, maybe she made
the bomb somewhere else.
Oop. Incoming.
OFFICER: Sorry, ma'am.
Can't go in there.
SIDLE:
It's okay.
What are you doing here?
Well, we're... conducting
a murder investigation.
What's going on, Nick?
Mrs. Grissom, we have reason
to believe that...
that somebody might have planted
a bomb in Dr. Lambert's car.
A bomb?!
Yes, ma'am.
You don't think
Julia had anything
to do with it?
SIDLE:
Julia...
you...
were not being honest...
about where you were
when the bomb went off.
Where were you really?
I haven't
done anything wrong.
Okay. We're executing a search
warrant, and we're gonna need
both of you
to wait in the hall
until we're done.
You don't seem to be
winning any points with
your mother-in-law.
She really seems
to like me, though.
STOKES:
What's that?
It's a message...
a transcript from
Julia's voice mail.
Dr. Lambert called her
the night that he was killed.
What's the message?
SIDLE:
"Julia, we need to talk.
"This relationship
has to end.
"You know the risks
involved, to us
"and to the school.
We can't let it
continue."
BRASS:
So, let me guess,
Lambert dumped you,
and you blew him up.
I wasn't sleeping
with Dr. Lambert.
And I certainly
didn't kill him.
So he wasn't the man that
you were having sex with
at the party?
BRASS:
You lied to us about
being in your
office at the time
of the explosion.
I think you planted
the bomb in his car,
and then you followed him
to make sure it detonated.
And then you pretended
like you just got there
and you were
trying to save him.
I told you,
I didn't kill him.
Obviously...
there's a conflict
of interest here.
What's she talking about?
My history with your husband.
What history?
We were involved.
Intimately.
Well, this is awkward.
He didn't tell you?
I assumed
married people told
each other everything.
My marriage has nothing
to do with this case.
It does now.
(clears throat)
So, Julia Holden agreed
to give us a DNA sample
but wouldn't say anything
else without her lawyer.
Yeah, of course she wouldn't.
She totally played me.
She knew exactly who
I was, and she knew
that I didn't know anything
about her and Gil.
Come on, I mean,
for all you know,
they only went out
a couple of times.
Well, they slept together.
She made that perfectly clear.
She also made it perfectly clear
that she would not continue
with the interview
until I was out of the room.
What did Brass say?
What do you think?
He wants you off the case.
I said no.
I told him that
you're a professional,
and completely capable
of being objective.
Thanks.
Youare capable of being
professional
and objective, right?
Yes, I am.
Great.
We didn't find
any evidence
of bomb-making materials at
Julia's office or her house.
Maybe the guys'll
find something.
They're checking
Lambert's car now.
(groans quietly)
Well, this used
to be a gas tank.
Yeah. Not much
left of it.
(clanking)
What is that, a magnet?
Industrial-strength magnet.
Must have used it
to secure the bomb
to the gas tank.
(grunts)
I think you're losing your
superpowers there, Dr. Ray.
(chuckles)
Come on, let's
go check it out.
Yeah...
this thing is...
pretty badly scorched.
STOKES: These are all the bomb
fragments we got on the road.
We've got a detonator, but...
we still haven't found
a timer of any kind.
Lambert's car
was left unattended
during the party--
that's a perfect
opportunity for someone
to come along and...
plant the bomb.
Killer waits
for Lambert to leave the party,
follow him--
when the car gets
close enough to the ravine,
flip a switch and boom,
car blows up
and goes off the road.
That means that
the killer was on campus.
Let's get the fragments
over to Trace,
see if we can get
anything off of 'em.
I found nitrates
on the bomb fragments
consistent with
smokeless gunpowder.
The last time we saw
smokeless gunpowder
was in the bombs
planted at the police funeral.
Except those devices
were more sophisticated.
Yeah, well,
based on the scorch marks,
I'm guessing that this was used
to hold the explosives.
The curved shape
would have given the blast
the directional component,
driving it upward
into the gas tank.
I've recovered a
partial serial number
and manufacturer's mark--
I'm just running it now.
Hm. Looks like you got a hit.
Company that makes
consumer products for the deaf.
Looks like our
bell-shaped charge
started its life as
part of something called the...
Shake Alert.
I got one of those.
What do you need with
a deaf fire alarm?
My mother snores like a bear.
So I sleep
with ear plugs.
If there's a fire,
then the Shake Alert
receives a signal
from any standard
smoke detector
and... shakes my bed,
wakes me up and saves my life.
Okay.
This Shake Alert
came from a batch
installed in the dorms
at Gilbert College.
(music blaring)
♪ ♪
(turns music off)
(turns on music)
(music playing in distance)
Sorry.
Hey, Sara?
Yeah.
This fire alarm
is different than
the other ones.
It's white-- all the
other ones were black.
Could be brand-new.
Whose room is this?
Michael Porter.
He's Julia
Holden's T.A.
STOKES: What happened to your
old fire alarm, Michael?
I don't know.
I didn't even know
it was replaced.
You weren't at the party
last night--
were you in your room
the whole time?
Yes.
Really, I should've
been at the party.
Apparently,
Julia and Dr. Lambert
didn't consider
my research project
worthy of
the Gilbert Grant.
Well, a half million dollars is
a lot of money to miss out on.
I've been Julia's
T.A. for two years,
doing research,
I even picked up
her dry cleaning.
Then suddenly
this Sean Wyatt guy
shows up from England--
it's like he's the chosen one.
And a finalist for the grant.
He's Julia's pet.
Was Sean
Dr. Lambert's pet as well?
Hardly.
A few days ago,
I saw them arguing.
It got pretty heated.
(angry grunt)
What was that
argument about?
I'm not sure.
But Dr. Lambert
said something like,
"If you don't
fix this, I will."
SIDLE:
Sean Wyatt is
a big fan of Julia's work.
He's got a lot
of her books.
This kid's in the
deaf studies program
and she's his advisor, so...
(quiet beeping)
Sara? Hm?
Positive for nitrates.
Okay, well, we know that Sean
and Dr. Lambert had a fight.
Maybe Lambert decided
not to give him
the half-million dollars.
And Sean decides
to get rid of him?
Yeah.
With Lambert
out of the way,
Julia gets to choose
the grant winner,
and Sean gets
the half a million.
Sean is Julia's student.
She was the first one
at the scene andshe lied.
You still like Julia
Holden for this, don't you?
I do.
Why? None of the physical
evidence points to her.
I am not making this personal.
Okay.
All right,
maybe a little.
You know, it would've
been nice if Gil had told
me about him and Julia.
It's ancient history--
I'm sure it happened
before the two of you
even got together.
She ispretty.
Yeah.
Yeah, she's pretty.
She's very pretty,
actually.
Hi, Mrs. G.
Oh, great.
Hi, Betty.
Um, I'll catch up.
Okay. See you
back at the lab.
I heard you called Julia
in for more questioning.
Well, yes-- she's a suspect
in Dr. Lambert's murder.
Julia would never
hurt anyone.
I know her.
Obviously, she was intimately
involved with your son.
Thanks for the heads-up,
by the way.
I thought you knew.
No.
Maybe if you and Gil saw
each other more often,
you'd know more
about each other.
Betty...
a man was murdered,
someone you know.
If there was
something going on
between Julia and Dr. Lambert,
you have to tell me.
Dr. Lambert was a
stickler for rules
and deadlines.
Lately, Julia's
been distracted.
Late with paperwork,
missing classes.
Any idea why?
I asked her about it.
She said everything was fine.
Thank you.
Hey, I tested
the nitrates
in Sean Wyatt's room.
Did he have a plant?
A dead fern
and a cactus.
Ah.
The classic male green thumb.
Explains why the nitrates are
less consistent with explosives
and more consistent
with fertilizer.
I did, however, find something
on the sheets you collected
from his dorm room.
Hair and vaginal
contributions.
Both from Julia Holden.
Having sex with
one of her students.
Maybe Sean
was the one
that Julia was having sex with
in the bathroom.
Ooh.
Quite the libertine.
Not unlike Lady Heather.
Clearly, Grissom has
a yen for sexually
adventurous women
whose voracious appetites
can only be sated by dangerous
and unbridled passion.
Thank you.
(clears throat)
Um, at-at least
most of the time.
That is, until he
realized, of course,
that even though you can
have sexual satisfaction,
it doesn't hold a candle
to spirited
intellectual stimulation.
Not...
to say that
you and Grissom don't...
have a great
sex life, um...
I mean, when you happen to be
in the same city... (chuckles)
Isn't that your phone
down the hall?
Yes, it is. Thank you.
Grissom and I have great sex.
I'm sure you do.
Okay, so, um...
Lambert... (clears throat)
left a message
on Julia's phone
about a relationship
that had to end--
maybe he was talking about Sean.
Sex with a student is a huge
scandal for the school, and...
it's kind of a career ender
for Julia Holden.
Maybe Sean didn't just
kill Lambert for the money,
maybe he killed him for love.
Okay.
Mr. Wyatt,
we found evidence in your room
that you and Julia Holden
had a sexual relationship,
and my guess is that Lambert
found out about it,
and that's what
your argument was about.
Am I going too fast for you?
Okay.
(sighs)
Yes.
He demanded that I
withdraw my application
to the Gilbert Grant.
He told me that
my affair with Julia could
be seen as favoritism.
Oh, you think?
And then you put
a bomb in his car.
You killed Lambert,
Julia gets to keep her job,
you get to keep your grant--
everybody wins.
No, I loved Julia.
And yes, I wanted the grant,
but I didn't kill anyone.
You were at the party,
you had motive and opportunity.
When Lambert left,
you followed him.
I left the party beforehe did.
Where'd you go?
I went back to
my dorm room.
Can anyone confirm that?
Julia.
She arrived at quarter to 10:00,
and left before 11:00.
Just before the explosion.
What do you want now?
We have more questions for you.
You need to come with us.
Fine. Let me call my lawyer.
Fine.
(alarm blaring)
Are you guys all right?
Yeah, we're fine.
We're fine.
You okay?
SIDE: Yeah.
LANGSTON: The paramedics took
Julia Holden to the hospital,
possible concussion.
Right before the explosion,
we saw Michael,
Julia's T.A., place
a package on her desk.
You think it was the bomb?
Well, we already
know that Michael had a beef
with Julia and Dr. Lambert.
LANGSTON: The bomb
in Dr. Lambert's car
didn't give us much,
but, here, we're
in a contained space
and there was no fire--
we should be able
to collect
a lot more evidence.
Yeah... yeah, maybe enough
to pin this on Michael.
SIDLE: Piece of a box.
Looks like the bomb was
hidden in a package.
STOKES:
You know, most...
package bombs are rigged
to explode when you open them,
but I think this one
was a little bit different.
Got a resistor-- it creates
a delay, like a timer.
If you're gonna
hand-deliver a bomb,
you want to make sure
you have time to get away.
I would never kill anyone.
Really?
Your computer
says different.
Nice stalker wall.
You had a grudge against Julia
because she recommended
Sean Wyatt for the grant
instead of you.
I was angry.
I needed to vent.
I should have had a chance
at that grant--
they took it from me.
I did not put the bomb
in Dr. Lambert's car
or Julia's office.
Michael, you have the skills.
Your major is
electrical engineering.
You're doing R&amp;D
on deaf assist devices.
We recovered a resistor
from the bomb
in Julia's office
that traces to a batch
that you ordered
for your research.
You've got the wrong person.
The parts you're talking
about were stolen from me.
I reported it
to the campus police.
Go ahead and ask them.
Oh, we will.
Somebody's setting me up.
Who would do that?
Have you checked
into Sean Wyatt?
I mean, really
looked into him?
There's something
strange.
I don't know
exactly what it is,
but... something's
just not right with him.
WOMAN (over P.A.): Dr. Alist,
call the page operator.
Dr. Alist, call the page
operator.
Mind if I join you?
I hope you're not here
to accuse Julia
of blowing up
her own office.
Actually, we have
a new suspect-- Michael.
He's Julia's T.A.
I find it
so hard to believe
that there's someone
in this school,
in our community,
capable of such violence.
When I went to take
Julia's statement just now,
I saw her talking
to Sean Wyatt,
and he signed something
that I didn't recognize,
nor did he.
Do you know
what this means?
That means "sweet pea" in LSQ.
It's Quebec Sign Language.
Sign language is just
like any other language--
it varies by... region,
has its own
dialect, slang...
Oh, I know that, but
Sean is from England--
why would he be
speaking Quebecoise?
Maybe he spent
some time in Quebec
and picked up
some of the slang.
It's possible.
When Gil and I first
got back from Europe,
there were
certain phrases
that stuck with me
for a while, too.
Don't you miss it?
Europe?
Being with your husband.
What kind of marriage
do you have?
You two barely
even see each other.
You don't even live
in the same town.
We talk every day,
we see each other
at least once a month.
That is not a marriage.
I lost my husband
too soon.
But in all the years
that we were married,
we never spent
one night apart.
It's unconventional,
but what Gil and I have works.
We love each other.
We're a family, and...
You know what, if...
if you don't want
to be a part of it,
that's your call.
♪ ♪
STOKES:The bomb in
Julia Holden's office used
the same smokeless gunpowder as
the bomb in Dr. Lambert's car.
No surprise.
Check this out--
this resistor
keeps electricity from
reaching the detonator
for a specific
amount of time.
Now, in this case,
ten minutes.
SIDLE:
Wow, that is not
a lot of time to wrap
and deliver the bomb
before it exploded.
No, it is not.
That's why the bomber used
a remote to arm it.
So whoever wanted
to blow up Julia Holden
had to make sure
that bomb was
in her office
and that
she was there
before they set that timer.
Bomber had to be nearby.
Try within earshot.
When the bomber used the remote,
it sent a signal
to the receiver.
(beeping)
Now, that beeping sound
tells the bomber
that the device is armed.
So whoever did this
could hear just fine.
So Michael wasn't the bomber?
WILLOWS:
We're looking
for somebody outside
the deaf community.
Yes and no.
I had nothing to do with
that bomb in Julia's office.
I love her.
I'd never
hurt her.
Then this lie detector
test will prove it.
SIDLE: We're gonna show you
a series of pictures
and measure your
brain's response.
Are you ready?
Go ahead.
(electronic oscillations,
clicking)
He recollects Julia Holden.
(electronic oscillations,
clicks, pops)
No recollection
of the bomb materials.
(electronic tones, clicking)
No recollection of the bombing.
Sean, I've got
some bad news-- you failed.
I didn't set that bomb.
The machine's inaccurate--
everybody knows that.
Well, you're right, Sean, uh,
polygraphs aren't reliable.
Thank you very much.
It's okay.
But we didn't give
you a polygraph,
we gave you an Auditory
Evoked Potential Test.
It actually measures your
brain's response to sound.
During the test, we played
a series of clicking sounds.
You acted as though
you didn't hear them,
but your brain said otherwise.
The spikes in
your brain wave
indicate that you hear
just fine.
You're not deaf, Sean.
You're a fraud.
You're also a killer.
Sean Wyatt still
isn't talking,
with or without
an interpreter.
So he faked being deaf
for the half-a-million
dollar grant.
And if Dr. Lambert found
out that he was a fraud,
that would be motive
for murder right there.
Well, Sean lied
about being deaf;
makes you wonder what
else he's lying about.
SIDLE:
His real name
is Sean Wyatt Leblanc,
and he's not from England
he's from Canada--
Montreal to be exact.
And he lied about everything.
Including being deaf.
It's not possible.
We gave him an Auditory
Evoked Potential Test.
He can hear.
It can't be easy to fool an
entire campus of deaf students
including a smart,
savvy professor.
One that he was intimately
involved with.
Are you saying that I knew?
Sean's transcripts were forged
using paper with a
Gilbert College watermark,
which means that he had help
from someone inside the school.
No. When I met Sean,
he was already a student.
I was his thesis advisor.
We started spending
a lot of time together.
One night, we were working late
and he kissed me.
I should have
put a stop to it.
But when a young,
good-looking guy
tells you that you're beautiful
and he can't get enough of you,
you want to believe it.
I fell in love with him.
I haven't felt that
for a long time.
With all that time that you
and Sean spent together,
you never suspected
that he could hear?
There was a time that I saw
him sign something wrong.
It was Quebec Sign Language.
And I asked him about it.
He said that it was our secret
term of endearment.
Something that no one
on the campus would understand.
My career has been my life.
I didn't realize
how lonely I was.
We... we all have this need
to find that one person
to connect with.
And when we do,
we find that we're overlooking
their imperfections
and disappointments.
He was using me.
I'm sorry, Julia.
Is there anything
that you know about Sean?
Anything that
might help us?
One night I did go
into his room--
while he was e-mailing--
and e was using a different
e-mail address.
It was in French.
I thought maybe
it was another girl.
He said, no, it was
just an old friend.
Do you know who
he was writing to?
No.
But I do remember the e-mail
address that he was using.
I got an A.G. waiver
on the e-mail account
that Julia gave us.
Oh.
The e-mail's
practically a blueprint
for the entire grant scam,
starting with getting
accepted to the school.
And finishing with the bombings?
No, but there was
a threat implied.
Sean was clearly worried that
Dr. Lambert was on to him.
He and his partner knew
they had to do something.
Who's his partner?
His cousin from Montreal.
But fortunately, we don't have
to go that far to find him.
He's been hiding
in plain sight.
BRASS:
Dennis Palmer.
It must feel
a little lonely,
huh, Dennis?
Being an interpreter
for the deaf?
I mean, you're part
of everyone's
intimate conversations,
but somehow you're
on the outside.
You're... you know,
you're like...
Invisible?
Yeah-- invisible.
Exactly.
It's part of the job.
It's also part of the job
to have access to all
the buildings on campus,
including Julia
Holden's office.
We checked.
You used your key card
to enter Julia's building
30 minutes before the explosion.
I was dropping a transcript off
in Dr. Gardner's...
We searched your room.
You know,
for an invisible man,
you leave a lot
of evidence behind.
We found receipts for
gunpowder and pipes.
We knew you were at the
party with Dr. Lambert.
So you planted that
bomb under his car.
You dropped off the package
that Michael Porter delivered
to Julia's office.
(beeping)
When we searched your room,
we found e-mails
between you and Sean.
Now we know this whole
con was your idea.
You're the inside guy.
You forged his transcript.
Did you teach him
how to sign as well?
I learned sign language
as a kid.
My mother's deaf.
So Dennis got you
into the school,
and you agreed to split
the cash with him, right?
It was easy money.
Dennis said they were
just giving it away.
You know, if you're in
a wheelchair or you're deaf,
society throws money at you.
I mean, they have
all these grants
for deaf students.
Meanwhile, I'm working my ass
off for next to nothing.
So you thought you'd
bilk the system.
But you got greedy.
You went after
the big prize--
the half-a-million
dollar grant, right?
A prize that big,
we needed an edge.
Is that why you
seduced Julia?
I needed her endorsement.
But then I started
to care about her.
That was the first complication.
And Lambert was the second.
Lambert found out
I didn't go to Cambridge.
Said he wouldn't go
to the police
if I withdrew
my grant application
and left the school.
So you thought if you
get rid of Lambert,
you might still have
a shot at the big money.
Thought we could make it
look like an accident.
But why the second bomb?
I mean, why target Julia?
I was trying to take
the heat off of Sean,
put it on Michael.
Dennis promised me
that Julia wouldn't get hurt.
Said she wouldn't even
be in her office.
And you believed him.
(no voice):
I'm sorry.
You all right?
GRISSOM:
The graves were littered
with pupa casings.
Looked like somebody dumped
a ton of Rice Krispies
on top of a bunch
of Halloween skeletons.
(laughs)
It indicated that it wasn't
a proper burial.
During the Inca period, there
was no great punishment.
We think it was meant
as a warning--
don't mess with the Moche.
Aha.
So anyway, how a was your week?
What'd you do?
Well, I almost
got blown up twice.
I accused
your ex-girlfriend of murder.
And, oh, I...
I told off your mother.
Oh, good. You kept busy.
Yeah. See what happens
when you stand me up?
Who's that?
Uh, it's your mother.
Hi, Mom.
You never came to the office
when I was working there.
I heard you and Sara had
an exciting week.
African violets.
They're beautiful.
I told her you liked
vegetation.
Thank you.
Um, I'm sorry, too.
Can we start over?
When I come back,
the three of us will
go out to dinner.
Soon.
Your mother is talking
about our sex life.
In Incan society, the Moche
elders would pass down
their knowledge
of sexual pleasure
to the younger generation.
Their stories were documented
on their pottery.
Little ceramic jars
called "sex pots."
Sex pots.
Sometimes too much.
Love you both.
Love you, too.
Bye.