Second 430-B
out here this month.
Lady can't give up
her cats, man.
(scoffs)
Even when they're dead?
Oof!
That doesn't
smell like cat.
Las Vegas police!
Control, 1-George-12,
possible 4-19, requesting
backup and CSI to our location.
Your turn.
DISPATCH:
Copy that. We'll notify CSI
and a unit to back up 2-4.
What, you getting soft, man?
I don't think we're
getting in this way.
Mitch and Akers said
there's a way in around back.
They didn't go in, did they?
Eyeballs only.
They said they didn't want to
disturb a potential crime scene.
The victim is probably the
homeowner, Marta Santiago.
She live alone?
As far as we know.
The county declared this
place a risk to public safety.
They ordered a
forced clean-out.
Supposed to happen
by next Friday.
Oh.
Ah, how bad can it be?
(flies buzzing)
Hey, watch your, uh...
Yeah.
Whew.
(cats yowling in distance)
So how do you
want to do this?
Well, I'd say "hug the walls,"
if I could see them.
Goat trails seem to
be our only option.
Unless you're
into Dumpster diving.
Mm-hmm.
Okay, I'll take the high road,
you take the low road?
Document as we go?Yeah.
Great.
(rat squeaks)
Ugh.
(cat meows)
(squeaking)
(coughing)
(cat yowls, Nick yells)
Are you okay?
Yeah.
How could someone
live like this?
Well, it smells more like
somebody died like this.
(squeaks)
Son of a bitch!
What was that?
Think I just saw a rat
wearing a saddle.
(squishy crunch)
That doesn't
sound good.
I think I just
became evidence.
I think you just
found Mrs. Santiago.
Nick.
Smile.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
Hey, I heard you
really stepped in it.
Directly in it.
Look at that.
That's nasty in there, man.
Oh, I, uh, called
the coroner's office.
Asked them to hold off
until we cleared a path.
Well, good luck with that.
Sara's inside.
Hope you brought
another pair of shoes.
(rapid popping)
What the...? Hello!
SANDERS:
It's just me.
Bubble wrap.
Wouldn't want to throw that out.
Where are--you?
Hang a right at
the sewing machine,
and a left
at the Mason jars.
Which sewing machine?
Uh, just follow the North Star.
David is going to
have fun with this.
Looks like she melted
right into the rug.
Oh, so that's what that is.
WOMAN:
What are you doing in my house?
I have the paper
you gave me.
Mrs. Santiago?
Is that you?
WOMAN:
Don't make me call the police.
Ma'am, we are the police.
WOMAN:
Dr. Prescott...
you promised I'd have
until next week.
Ma'am, I'm not
Dr. Prescott.
My name is Sara Sidle.
I'm with the crime lab.
You have
a decomposing body here.
Would you mind
stepping out?
We'd like to ask
you a few questions.
WOMAN:
Okay. I'm coming.
SIDLE:
Hold on. Uh...
Why don't you stay there?
I'm going to come to you.
Oh, you're not going to take
a picture of me, are you?
Ma'am, is there anyone else
in the house with you?
My whole life is
in this house.
I mean, is there
anyone else
living in the house
with you right now.
Ghosts.
Uh, Mrs. Santiago, I need you
to take a look at something.
If I do, will you leave?
I can't promise you that.
Please, come with me.
It's important.
(gasps)
That's Diana's dress!
That's my daughter!
That's my baby! Diana!SIDLE:
Okay, look,
We're going to take very
good care of her, okay?
I promise.
Don't touch that!
What?
Put it down! You need
to stop that, right now!
Maybe you should put that down.
You need to stop! Right now!
Put it down, Nick.
Ma'am, why don't we
step outside, okay?
We're gonna...
just gonna go outside.
SIDLE: If you'd just come
with me, all right?
So sorry.
Hey.
You didn't clear
a path for the body.
You kidding me?
You're Super Dave.
(flies buzzing)
Disgusting.
You ready?
Yeah.
(body squishing)
Come on. Come on.
Yeah, you got it?
I appreciate Nick doing
the Y-incision for me.
Though I generally
prefer a scalpel to a boot.
Victim appears to be
in her early 20s.
How long do you think she
was lying dead in the house?
Post-mortem interval is anywhere
from five to seven days.
So her mother didn't
notice for a week.
So what do you got
for cause of death?
Epidural hematoma.
That means she
didn't die instantly.
Accidental or deliberate,
I can't say,
but I do know that it was
a single blow to the head.
LANGSTON: The wound impression
looks like a giant bar code.
Have you ever seen
anything like that before?
No, it's one weapon which has
thus far escaped my attention.
Whatever it was,
if it was in the house...
she probably
didn't throw it out.
So, Diana wasn't
Mrs. Santiago's only child.
The case file mentioned
another daughter and a son.
Both grown.
Brass is trying
to track them down.
Good luck finding anything in
here, let alone a murder weapon.
I'm not so sure we're
dealing with a murder here.
Sara, look at this place.
Whether the mother hit
the daughter with something,
or it fell off one of
these big piles of crap,
this house killed her.
I've got blood drops.
What?
Right here.
SIDLE:
I lost the trail.
That's a lot of blood.
STOKES:
Sure is.
You think Doc Robbins
was right about that
single--blow to the head?
It's a generalized reaction.
STOKES:
Of course it is, 'cause the
luminol's reacting to all the
cat urine, feces, and God knows
what else in this place.
We could use
hydrogen peroxide.
Got some on you?
I do.
It'll foam up when it makes
contact with the blood.
Yeah. Nice.
(sighs)
Somebody tried to
tidy up in here.
Maybe Diana.
That could explain how she
ended up melted into the rug.
You know, the court
ordered Mrs. Santiago
to clean this place up.
Diana came over to help...
Diana! No!
No! No,no, no...!
We've got to clear this out.
No, no! No!
Please!
No!
I told you to stop!
Mm, getting a little ahead
of the evidence, Nick.
You think?
MAN (in distance):
What are you doing here?
You have...
you have authorization for this?
MAN 2: Calm down...
I'll check that out.
You can't be here.
This is my mother's house.
Sir, I understand, but
you need to step back.
SIDLE: Excuse me.
Uh, you're Mrs. Santiago's son?
I'm Julian Santiago.
She's my mother.
What's going on here?
We're investigating
a homicide.
My mother's dead?
We believe it's
your sister Diana.
(gasps)
(moans)
I'm very sorry for your loss.
Wh-what happened?
Well, that's what we're
trying to sort out.
When was the last time
that you spoke with Diana?
She called me
about a week ago.
Said Mom got a letter
from Dr. Prescott
about the forced
clean-out.
She asked if I could help.
I told her I'd call her back.
Did you?
No.
You also have, um, another
sister, isn't that right?
Alisa.
Hav-have-haven't spoken
to her in a while.
Why is that?
She's not the easiest
person to deal with.
I mean, you've seen
the inside of this house.
Alisa had the hardest
time with it, growing up.
Well, we're going to need a
number where we can reach her.
Uh, yeah.
LANGSTON: What happened
in that house, Dr. Prescott?
Do you believe that
Mrs. Santiago is capable
of hurting her daughter?
Based on my observation, no.
She's a hoarder, not a killer.
I've been assigned to
Mrs. Santiago's case
for the past two years.
She's well-groomed, she has
a job, works as a librarian,
supports herself;
she's quite high-functioning.
Except inside that house.
We can't fully explain
the phenomenon of hoarding.
It crosses over into several
categories of mental illness:
OCD, impulse control,
dissociative behavior.
And, in her case?
Based on my interviews
with her and her children,
the nature of her hoarding
goes beyond the inability
to throw things away.
For her, it's about...
safeguarding memories.
Keeping things that are
important to her,
and her family, close to her.
Family is everything.
Well, if that
were the case,
then how could she just
leave her daughter's dead body
lying in the
house for a week?
Well, every hoarder
experiences
something called
"clutter blindness."
For a level-one hoarder,
it can mean ignoring
a stack of newspapers
piling up in a room.
What level is Mrs. Santiago?
Level Five.
The most extreme.
LANGSTON:
So you're telling me that this
"clutter blindness" would
allow her to live in the house
with her daughter's
dead body... indefinitely?
Unfortunately, yes.
When can I go home?
Soon. Soon.
We just need to understand
what happened to Diana.
Let's go back
to last week.
I saw the two of you
together at the house.
My memory's pretty bad.
Are you going to
throw that away?
It's out of ink, Marta.
That's the pen you handed
Diana, to write down
all her information.
Name, address, phone.
When you came by
to hand me the letter,
the letter that
said I had until
5:00 p.m. on November 5th
to clean up.
Your memory's not
as bad as you think.
Is it?
LANGSTON: What can you tell me
about this clock?
It's a family heirloom.
My husband's grandfather
brought it back from Spain.
Before World War II.
And whose blood
is that on it?
It's Diana's.
SIDLE:
Blood trail ends here.
This must be where
she was hit.
How did the blood
get on the rug?
It was an accident.
We found our bar code.
Do you know what this is?
Diana was throwing things away.
She said she found something.
What did she find?
SANTIAGO:
I didn't want to look,
I just wanted her
to stop what she was doing!
And then everything
was falling; she was bleeding.
She said she was okay.
She left.
Didn't come back.
Can you tell us what
it was that she found?
May I please go home?
(gunshot)
SIDLE:
Are you okay?
STOKES:
Yeah.
SANDERS: Don't touch it
until I can clear it.
Geez, Louise.
(laughing)
Hey, guys?
Over here.
Whoa.
Looks like you stepped
in it this time.
Ooh!
Scorpion and her babies.
SIDLE: You're kidding me.
STOKES:
And a big one.
SANDERS:
They usually move in well after
all the meat's off the bones.
Okay, sloping forehead,
narrow pelvis,
inlet's nearly heart-shaped.
Definitely male.
What do you make of the ribbon?
SIDLE:
It's not your typical ligature.
Look how he's tied up.
Wrists tied in front.
So it wasn't about
restraining him.
Think we found Mr. Santiago?
Case file did mention something
about him passing
away 10 years ago.
Maybe she didn't
want to spring for the urn.
I gotta tell you, man,
this place is disgusting.
It's not the crime scene
that's bugging me.
It's what created it.
Well, look, Nick, you're
talking about a woman here,
who has clearly been through
some kind of a major trauma.
You can be traumatized
and still take out
the damn trash.
There's no excuse for this.
You know, I'm starting to think
this whole hoarding thing's
a pretty good
cover for a killer.
That's your theory.
I don't think so.
You know, someone
needs to go
process Mrs. Santiago,
so... I guess I'll go do that.
And you guys can
finish up this room.
What's her deal?
(sighs)
Well, I got a feeling
this is not the last body
we're gonna find
in this house.
ROBBINS:
Well, unless she married young,
I don't think you're
looking at Mr. Santiago.
Indications are male Caucasian,
five feet, seven inches tall.
Uh, age between
15 and 17 years.
LANGSTON: No apparent injuries
to the bones.
No beveling,
no tool marks,
No fractures.
All right. Adolescent male.
That narrows the possibilities.
Could be... an overdose.
Only way to determine
that is bone marrow.
And I know you
must miss the days of
research pathology--
care for a slice?
Don't mind if I do.
(saw whirring)
Thank you.
Mrs. Santiago.
I'm going to need
to take your clothes,
and the rest of your
personal possessions.
Why?
What's happening?
You're being booked.
We found another
body in your house.
Where?
I'm sorry. I'm going to need
to get your clothes, now.
No. I want to go home!
I understand,
Mrs. Santiago; I do.
Um... you know...
I really need you
to do something
for me right now.
Do you think
you could do that?
Could you give me your hand?
It's going to
be really easy.
We're just going
to step over here.
Just put your hand over
the envelope, like this.
There you go.
All right?
ANDREWS:
Bone marrow cells exhibited
some curious anomalies,
which you might find with
dyserythropoietic anemia,
or thrombocytopenia.
Henry, did you run
a heavy metals test?
Yeah.
And I got you John Doe's C.O.D.
"Acute arsenic poisoning."
Levels were off the charts.
No way this was
poisoning over time.
Victim was given
one massive dose of arsenic.
So... what's up
with you and Nick?
I just don't think
he gets it, you know?
What happened in this house,
something caused it to happen.
Something triggered it.
Death of her husband, perhaps?
A woman alone, with kids...
Couldn't let go of the
things that she had left?
Yeah.
It spiraled out of control.
Dr. Prescott,
this is Nick Stokes.
Nick, Dr. Prescott
is Mrs. Santiago's case worker.
Oh. Nice to meet you, Doctor.
Hey.
So, now we're
talking about murder.
This woman's killing people and
packing them away in her house.
Okay, look,
I can't explain the presence
of the John Doe or
the arsenic,
but Marta is
incapable of violence.
Ooh, I don't know about that.
You ever touch anything of hers?
Dr. Prescott,
for argument's sake,
if there are
more bodies here,
is there some method
by which Mrs. Santiago
might be hiding them?
I don't think you're going
to find any more bodies.
LANGSTON:
I'm sure you don't.However,
if you're asking
if a hoarder like Marta
has some sort of system,
then that answer is yes.
Most of us live our
lives categorically.
Pots and pans
go in the kitchen,
tools go in the toolbox,
underwear goes in the drawer,
but Marta organizes her world
visually and spatially
by stacking.
What does this have to do
with our crime scene?
We're trying to learn how to
read these rooms, Nick.
I don't get it.
So we're trash whispering now?
Yes, and if we listen carefully,
we might be able to find
what we're looking for.
I haven't been in this part
of the house in a few months,
but these storage bins
weren't here before.
Looks like these items were
pushed in from the hallway.
All right, what
would that tell us?
I don't know.
Marta was shifting
her possessions
from one side of the house
to the other.
Why would she do that?
Because the city told her
to clean this place up.
These look like time capsules.
What's that?
A time capsule's
an impulsive act
by a hoarder to throw away
groups of items
into a single container
at a single moment in time.
However, the intention is
to deal with these items later.
All of those items
belong to Alisa.
Alisa.
Is this her room?
Doctor, why is
this room clean?
I don't know what would trigger
something like this.
STOKES:
I do.
And I bet
we're gonna find her body
somewhere in this house.
(knocking)
You guys need to see this.
Hands in front,
bound with red ribbon.
Is Alisa one of them?
Well, from the looks of it,
I'd say three more boys.
STOKES:
Whatever comes
in this house,
doesn't seem
to make it back out.
SIDLE: Our first John Doe is
16-year-old Matthew Price.
His DNA got a hit
off the U.S. Directory
of Missing Persons.
So did two of the three
of our backyard John Does.
Ryan Hoff, age 17
and Derrick Kennedy,also 16.
Henry confirmed C.O.D.
on all four boys
was acute arsenic poisoning.
SIDLE: Well, these three
were all I.D.'d as runaways
and referred to the Avenues
of Care Halfway House
by the county as part
of their plea agreements.
Guess who the director
of the halfway house is.
LANGSTON:
Julian Santiago.
The son is the one
dumping the bodies.
Maybe Mrs. Santiago isn't
the only one in the family
who can't let go.
BRASS:
You've been busy.
We've been busy, too.
We know all about
your job at the halfway house.
Avenues of Care--
"A refuge for troubled teens."
I guess they didn't know
how much trouble
they were really in.
SIDLE:
Matthew Price--
when he was alive,
we talked to his father.
He said that six months ago
he drove up from Mesquite
to pick his son up
at the halfway house.
But when he got there,
you said that his son ran away.
Well, it's unfortunate
for these types of kids,
but it does happen.
Sure it does.
SIDLE:
Matthew's father said
his son talked a lot
about a girl.
Her name was Alisa Santiago.
BRASS: They met when
she volunteered
at your halfway house.
I told you
my sister had problems.
So I tried to help
her the way
I helped myself--
by helping others.
So yes, I got her a job
at the halfway house.
Right. Where she met Matthew
and Ryan and Derrick.
Love.
It's a beautiful thing.
SIDLE: Except when
it turns to obsession,
control, violence.
We talked to your coworkers
at the halfway house.
They said Alisa was
a very popular girl
and you didn't like that.
Must be hard for
an older brother
to watch his younger sister
mess with all those boys.
We all thought
that your mother did this.
Look, whatever freaky
fantasies you have
about these young boys
and your sister--
I don't care.
What I care about is why
you used a sick woman
to bury your crimes.
This is completely insane.
That cell phone number
that you gave me for Alisa--
service was disconnected
four months ago.
She's six months
behind on her rent.
Where is she?
I want a lawyer.
(sighs)
No blood, no fluids, nothing.
If Alisa was killed
in this room,
there'd be evidence of it.
Well, these swabs are negative.
Well, Mrs. Santiago cleaned
this room for a reason.
According to Dr. Prescott,
she took all
of Alisa's belongings,
put them outside here
in the hallway in
these time capsules.
She said it was triggered
by an event.
When it comes to
this lady, pick one.
Family was the most important
thing to Mrs. Santiago.
Which is why,
if Julian killed his sister,
she'd want to protect him.
And the best way to protect him
is to hide the evidence.
It's a two-fer.
Mom gets to keep both children
closer to her bosom.
So...
Mementos of Alisa's
graduation from college.
A prom dress.
What is that?
A quinceañera dress.
This is like we're
going back in time.
It's a regression.
Like she's putting her
back into the womb.
(door creaking)
Nick.
(flies buzzing)
(gasping)
(sighs)
Alisa?
I'm Nick Stokes.
My partner and I were
the ones that found you.
You remember me?
Hmm?
You feel up to answering
a couple of questions?
Where's my mom?
She's in custody.
Why?
We'll get to her in a minute.
Let's talk about
you first.
(sighs)
You want to tell me
who did this to you?
It's okay.
Nobody's going to mess with you.
You don't know that.
I can protect you,
but I need to know who did this.
Are you afraid of your brother?
Look, I know you're scared,
but you can speak up now.
Is he the one
who did this to you?
My mother did this to me.
The garbage, the bodies--
that part I was handling okay.
But this...
this is some
kind of twisted.
Is hoarding people
part of hoarding?
My understanding of it is that
hoarding is more
self-destructive.
The damage inflicted
on others is more
emotional than
it is physical.
You don't think both daughters
were being held here, do you?
Diana certainly seems to have
had more freedom of movement.
Alisa and the boys...
That's another story.
So everything I heard is true.
How long was Alisa held here?
Well, the evidence indicates
that she was here for a while
and that she was cared for
behind a wall of time capsules.
If you
consider a mom
chaining her daughter
to a bed "caring."
Something doesn't add up.
(whirring)
SANDERS:
So I was able to recover
the serial number
from the handcuffs
used to
restrain Alisa.
Tracked back to a batch order
belonging to a local gun shop.
The owner faxed me the
credit card receipt.
Nice work.
Well, Greg just
I.D.'d our jailer:
Julian Santiago.
He purchased the handcuffs.
So what?
He also has a carry permit.
He works with
juvenile offenders.
All the hard evidence
points to Mrs. Santiago.
LANGSTON:
What Nick means is that
there were two sets of
prints in the bedroom.
There were Alisa's prints
and her mother's prints.
STOKES: And the scrapings
that you collected
under Mrs. Santiago's nails were
a match to the talcum powder
and the skin lotion
next to the bed, so...
So that puts Mrs. Santiago
in the bedroom, not Julian.
Okay. But Julian
is still our connection
to those dead boys in
the bedroom.
Maybe Mrs. Santiago
was being dominated
by her son; maybe she wasn't
acting out of free will.
What is it about this woman
that has you so blind?
What is it about this case
that has you acting
like such an ass right now?
Oh, I'm an ass now?
There is a very real possibility
that Julian killed those boys
to keep them away
from his sister,
and he's using his mother and
her house to bury the evidence.
You're absolutely right.
There is that possibility.
So why don't we
stick to the evidence
that we have?
Can we try that?
Okay.
Fine.
So, the evidence
that we have suggests
that Diana Santiago's
murder was an accident.
We can't prove
either suspect committed murder.
What we do know is
that Mrs. Santiago falsely
imprisoned Alisa.
So what do you want
to do about it?
Julian lawyered up,
so I guess we can take another
look at the mother.
All right. I'll talk to her.
We've spent some time
together, we've connected.
That's not gonna happen.
I'll talk to her.
Good luck
with that, Nick.
(clears throat)
What?
You know, I've been
where you've been, Sara.
And sometimes I find it's
best to take a deep breath
and walk away.
What's up?
Where's Mrs. Santiago?
Her son got her a lawyer.
(heavy sigh)
That shuts us down.
They buried those boys.
And now that lawyer
is trying to bury us.
LANGSTON: Well, we know what
there legal strategy's gonna be.
Mom blames son.
Son blames mom.
Yeah, and if all else fails,
Mom pleads insanity.
All they gotta dois send
a jury through
this house, and she walks.
They'll run
the clock down on us.
(sighs)
We never found
the source
of the arsenic.
What about this red ribbon?
STOKES: Hodges didn't
recover any trace.
He sent swabs to DNA,
which came back negative.
Was he looking for epithelials?
That's a good question.
LANGSTON:
Looks like the killer tore
these strands with his teeth.
You see how the edges line up,
one strand linking to another?
So they're all
from the same roll.
Which means we're looking
at a timeline of the murders.
So, the boys
we identified--
when did
the first victim disappear?
Ryan Hoff went missing from the
halfway house 17 months ago.
All right, what about
the second boy?
Derrick Kennedy, ten months ago.
Matthew Price, six months ago.
Six months ago,
that's the last time
the killer used
this roll of ribbon.
So vagaries of time,
decomp, and the elements
compromised the DNA
on these strands.
But maybe it didn't
compromise the source.
We need to find
that roll of ribbon.
Is it wrong this place
is starting to feel like home?
You guys got
a picture?
Yes, Dr. Prescott and I
are with you now.
Go ahead, Doctor.
The last time I was
in the house,
I remember seeing Christmas
decorations unopened.
Stacked near the dresser.
Okay. Which dresser?
It should be to the
right of the window
near the bed.
Got it.
(sighs)
This could take till Christmas.
Not if you take into
account "churning."
Churning?
Over time, a hoarder's
stack of items gets
shuffled and shifted
around; churned.
How does this help us?
The roll of ribbon
that you're looking for was
last used, what, six months ago?
That's right.
So you might expect it
to be buried
under six months of stuff.
But it may, in fact,
have been churned
somewhere closer
to the surface.
Look for a reel
ribbon box.
Marta tends to keep her items
in the original packaging.
There's a box
of rat poison over here.
Not exactly
the Christmas spirit.
SIDLE: Arsenic in
its original packaging.
Ribbon not so much.
LANGSTON:
We have your fingerprints.
We have your DNA.
You brought this boy
into this home!
He doesn't belong here!
He has to go!
LANGSTON: We know what happened
inside that house.
Your mother's illness was
hidden behind four walls,
but yours was buried in a much
deeper place, wasn't it, Alisa?
Your mother caught you
dragging Matthew Price's body
out to your little garden
of bones, didn't she?
She knew what you had
done to those boys.
How you lured them
and seduced them.
Killed them.
Buried them.
She knew she had to stop you.
When I said my mother
did this to me, I meant it.
She drove my father
to his death.
Then she drove Julian away.
She drove everyone away.
Except those boys.
You made sure of that.
I hate her.
Well, she loves you.
Believe it or not,
she acted out of love.
By chaining me up
like an animal?
To protect you
from yourself
and from people like me.
Now, I understand
why you didn't cry out when
we first entered that house.
I want to go home.
That's not going to happen.
Are you sure about that?
You said it yourself.
I'm sick.
JULIAN: I got out of that house
the first chance I could.
Alisa wasn't so lucky.
She was trapped
in my mother's insanity.
It turned her
into a monster.
I don't know.
We're both
professionals, you know.
We know that what
your sister did
goes way beyond any damage that
your mother inflicted on her.
Julian...
your sister is a predator.
Your mother's illness
is not what drove her to kill.
I'm not so sure.
My mother was
schizophrenic.
One night,
she got a butcher knife
out of a drawer.
She walked into the bedroom.
And while my father
was sleeping,
she stabbed him in the heart.
Again and again.
To say that my childhood
was screwed up
is an understatement.
But I survived it.
Just like you did.
You and your sister
grew up together
in that house, and you took
two completely different paths.
Sometimes when we're faced
with crimes that are so...
incomprehensible...
we want answers.
We want to believe that
there's some order to things.
Sometimes there just isn't.
I spoke to the DA
and the city attorney.
If your mother agrees to get
help, they won't prosecute.
What happens after that...
that's up to you
and your mother.
I can see your wheels turning.
¿En qué piensas?
What's on your mind, Nick?
I still don't get it.
The clutter or the pathology?
Both.
Hmm.
The philosopher Erich Fromm,
he forecast a, uh, society that
was obsessed with possessions.
He believed that
human beings had
two basic orientations:
having and being.
Now, a person with a having
orientation seeks to acquire
and possess things,
property, even people.
But a person with
a being orientation
focuses on the experience.
They derive meaning
from exchanging,
engaging and sharing
with other people.
Sounds like
the right way to be.
Unfortunately, Fromm also
predicted that a culture
driven by commercialism,
like the one
we live in today,
is doomed to
the having orientation.
Which leads to dissatisfaction
and emptiness.
When you consider that,
in 1960, there was no such thing
as public storage in America,
today there's over two billion
square feet dedicated to it,
makes you think he had a point.
So, society's to blame,
is that it?
The point is there's always
going to be extremes
like Mrs. Santiago.
Things don't have
to mean everything,
nor do they have to be
devoid of meaning.
They are one of
the ways in which
we can experience
and enjoy life.
As long as they don't
get in the way of living.
SIDLE:
Here you go.
Thank you.
Will you be taking me home now?
Actually, you'll be
going with your son.
I guess it's for the best.
I tried to be
a good mother.
I know.
Hey.
I was heading out, I,
uh, saw your light on.
Well, you know, this case
has compelled me to, uh,
clean out this desk
once and for all.
(both chuckle)
How's that going?
Oh, pretty good,
pretty good.
You know, I almost threw out
something Grissom gave me.
Ah, yeah.
Blue marble.
Oh.
Mm-hmm.
You know what he said
when he gave that to me?
Something profound, I'm sure.
He said, "Nicky...
if life ever gets crazy..."
"Roll with it."
He gave me the same marble.
(both laugh)
You should hold
onto that.
Yeah, right.