♪ ♪
Okay, back
that thing up.
I thought you just wanted
to steal some gloss off my lips.
(giggling)
And you bought it.
(sighs)
Hey.
You are hotter than
anyone in there.
WOMAN:
For $1,000,
I'll take you
around the world.
MAN: I think I love you.
God should just flush
this city down the toilet.
Look, hey...
I'm going to go find our limo.
Where it's safe.
(gunshots)
(screaming)
(car alarm blaring)
Huskins, you first
responding?
Yes, sir.
We got one dead guy
in the limo,
the rest are cuts
and bruises.
So, what's the story?
Witnesses are pretty much
in sync.
They heard, uh,
several gunshots
from down the street,
they saw the limo
and everybody started
hightailin' it.
Right.
Running the Bulls,
Las Vegas style.
(chuckling)
So, I got a feeling the
driver didn't see anything.
No, sir.
Make sure you
do Nystagmus
before we pound him
through the FSTs.
Limo equals drugs
and whatnot.
And collect all
the cell phones.
Are we authorized
to do that, sir?
No.
Hey, anybody have any photos
or video of the crash?
If you do, I promise to get
them on Channel 8 News.
(clamoring)
Wow.
You better wear gloves
before you do the collection
There's a lot of interrupted
lap dances out there.
Yes, sir.
We got one on the guy
in the limo.
A passenger.
Paramedics are working
on him now.
Name's Kellen Tyford.
Oh, Kellen. I know Kellen.
Calls himself "Drops."
This is what happens
when you don't wear
your seatbelt.
PHILLIPS:
That's why I always do.
It's the law.
Even in limos.
PHILLIPS:
Found a wallet.
Got a license.
Vic's name is
"Champ Landley."
SANDERS:
Open champagne bottle.
White powder residue.
I'll guess coke.
GRISSOM:
Well, then that must be...
his brain on drugs.
Party till you drop.
Or get shot,
whichever comes first.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
Konnichiwa.
Konnichiwa. Look.
I ain't in the mood, man.
So, let me guess, you don't have
any blood on your hands.
Oh, look at that, you do.
Yeah, I got blood
on my face, too.
How about that?
So, who's the dead guy?
It's Champ.
Yeah, we know that,
but who's he to you?
Huh?
It's family, man.
So, he's your "cuz",
he's your gang buddy.
Look, B, I ain't no Blud
and I ain't no Crip.
Champ's just a cool kid I knew
from around the way.
I met his ass over two decades
ago riding my Big Wheel.
We go back like your hairline.
That's family.
So, how did his b-l-u-d end up
on your face?
We was parlayin', chillin',
slidin' to the strip club,
mindin' our own.
(glasses clink)
(thudding)
(gunshot)
So, what'd you do,
piss off some rapper band again?
The only bands I'm playin' with
now is
the one's I'm ripping off stacks
of green.
And I ain't talking
about weed, B.
You're the big cheese maker.
What's your secret,
anyway?
I promote events,
parties.
I help the club life pop.
Well, you must be throwing
some pretty crappy parties
for someone to want you
and your buddy dead.
Huh?
So, tell me.
Who lit you up?
I don't know, okay?
Could be everybody, man,
could be nobody.
Okay.
Let's start with everybody.
I know a lot of people--
friends and foes.
They know I come
here late night.
Or maybe, maybe the limo driver
cut somebody off
and we're the victims
of road rage, how about that?
Look, we're going to take you
down to the station.
You can't be ser...
I'm the one that got shot at!
You know the rigamarole:
we need an official statement,
we need your clothes,
we need your prints,
we need your DNA.
Because you're
a concerned citizen.
You want to help us
find out who did this.
Unless you already know.
Got a nine mill over here.
.45 auto casing.
This neighborhood
rains lead.
Yeah, and we have to process
every last drop of it.
We're going to make Bobby
Dawson's boat payment
this month.
HODGES:
I was right.
This is a lot
like garbage colleting.
You're not helping, Hodges.
I have no intention to.
Field rotation for the Lab Techs
was Ecklie's idea.
He was very explicit
that I was only allowed
to observe.
Looks like a .38,
maybe a .357.
GRISSOM:
It's a little small
for those
golf-ball size holes we found
in that limo.
(clears throat)
A little help?
.50 caliber.
Casing looks new.
I bet it's
from a Desert Eagle.
Or a coffee shop.
I could drink an espresso
out of that thing.
CURTIS:
Residential area.
Not much traffic.
Landscaper found the body,
called 911.
Driver's license is
in her purse.
Her name's Melissa Gentry,
lives off Nellis.
We're trying to
contact the family.
BROWN:
Little bit outside
of her neighborhood, isn't it?
Definitely.
Party clothes shredded.
Breaded abrasions.
Must've hit the ground moving.
WILLOWS:
No car keys and no
unaccounted for...
cars in the vicinity.
You thinking she got jacked?
She gets taken along
for the ride,
jumps out trying to escape.
(screaming)
Maybe she was killed first,
and this is a body dump
at high speed.
I'm going to go bang
on some doors,
see if anyone heard anything.
I'm gonna go see if
I can figure out
where this started.
♪ ♪
(chuckling):
Whoa! "Crime Lab Nick Stokes!"
I see we're in between
bad haircuts.
Drops.
Told you
I'd see you later.
It's called
criminal activity.
Stand up
and hold your hands up
for me, please.
Now, come on, Crime Lab,
I thought we was old buddies.
The only thing we have
in common, Kellen,
are the dead bodies that seem
to keep piling up around you.
Turn around, please.
Well, first of all...
I ain't never killed nobody
in my life.
Second, I don't have a record.
Never even done
a day in jail.
Well, you keep heading down
this road
and, unfortunately, that's
where you're going to end up.
Yeah, well...
this, this ain't me.
I'm not used to this.
As a matter of fact,
I don't even know
what that is.
It's a test
for gunshot residue.
Hands up.
Oh, yeah, uh...
the powder from a gun.
You ain't gonna find none
of that.
Maybe not.
Okay, now, I need you to remove
all of your clothing,
including your shoes.
You can put these on
for now
and I'll come back
to get them
when you're done.
No, thanks.
Uh, I got one of my queens
bringing me a suit.
I will not be throwing
on these nasty ass scrubs.
You are covered in blood.
Your clothes are evidence now
and I'm going to come back in
here and I'm going to get them.
If not, you're just going to be
standing here in your underwear.
What underwear?
I don't wear drawers.
(wry laugh)
This is not a compromise,
Kellen.
You might want
to close your eyes
or turn around
or something.
Come in.
Come in slow,
slow, slow.
All right, stop.
♪ ♪
50 AE casings came
back clean on IBIS,
but Ballistics was able
to pull type and caliber
from the copper jacket
fragments inside the limo.
Consistent with .50 caliber
Desert Eagle handgun.
Yeah.
Blood on the
seats suggests
that the victim was sitting
here, on the left,
with Drops somewhere
to the right.
Six shots into the limo.
Autopsy reports cause of death
was single gunshot wound
to the head
with variable trajectory,
so one of those was
the kill shot.
Yeah, it's
just hard
to say which one.
The crash tossed everything
all over the place.
And it's basically
one big mess now.
Sounds like Drops's story is
holding up, though.
Gentlemen.
Follow me.
STOKES:
There were two
shots fired
through the glass,
but as you can see,
different sizes,
different calibers.
Big one's consistent
with the .50.
Yeah, but check out
the beveling
on the impacts.
Um, based on the beveling,
these shots were fired
from opposite directions.
GRISSOM:
Tinting film is applied
to the inside
of a window,
so the small-caliber round was
fired from inside the limo.
Well, I analyzed
the radial cracks
from both holes.
The cracks from
the shot
that was fired out
was terminated by the cracks
from the shot that was fired in.
Someone inside the limo had
a gun.
And, evidently, Drops
wasn't telling us
the whole story after all.
DROPS:
Look, I didn't lie, all right?
I just left a couple
of things out.
Well, you want
to fill in the blanks
before I ship you
for obstruction?
We shot back;
it's that simple.
We?
You both had guns?
Nah, man, just one of us.
Well, I bet I can
guess which one.
'Cause you're the only person
in the limo
with a registered .38 revolver.
(gunshot, tires squealing)
(gunshots, bullets ricocheting)
I guess you know
that blood is
a good way
to wash off GSR, right?
Nah, my dude.
Look, I ain't do no shooting.
All right? Somebody jacked that
piece off me, like, a year ago.
You're telling me that
you didn't shoot a gun
from inside the limo?
You're blaming it
on a dead guy,
a dead guy who just
happens to have
the same gun as you.
What can I say, man?
.38's back in style.
Besides, man, Champ
always had heat.
Everybody know that.
He got my back.
You know, I know
everything about you, Kellen.
You're just a small-time
street thug
and drug dealer
from Northtown.
You got the nickname "Drops"
'cause when you sold
the chronic,
you made a lot of drops.
Wow, and here I was thinking
that I got
that name based off
my boxing skills,
seeing as how I used to drop
fools in the squared circle.
I don't know, you're a little
slow behind the jab.
And all you do is a lot
of bobbing and weaving.
So get me the gun, and I'll
let you have your massage.
I tossed it after
the shooting, man.
Look, CSI's been
all over that area,
they didn't find any guns.
That's because a gun like that
in a hood like that,
that's rent money, baby.
Excuse me, beautiful.
We're gonna wrap up
these chicken wings
and take them to go.
Whoa, okay, easy now, Kojaks.
No gun, no happy ending.
Come on.
Don't tell me you're tired
of the field already.
No, I had to catch up
on my Perez Hilton.
I take it you're not gonna
pull a Sanders on us, then?
Let's see:
Clean, friendly lab,
bullet-strewn,
urine-soaked street--
that's a tough call.
You have something for me?
Oh, most definitely.
I I.D.'d the serial number
on the piece of plastic
Warrick found in the street.
Yeah?
It's a GMC
seatbelt adjuster.
Keeps the shoulder
harness webbing
from rubbing on the neck.
Okay. You got make
and model of that car?
HODGES:
Sure do.
But I don't think
it's gonna help you much.
Oh.
That's it.
ROBBINS:
She had atlanto-occipital
dislocation,
a basilar skull fracture
and contre-coup injuries
from bouncing her head
on the ground.
C.O.D. is craniocerebral trauma.
And are those ligature marks?
They are.
The right wrist
was broken.
Take a look at the shoulder.
The humeral head's in front
of the usual articulation.
Completely dislocated.
She was dragged by her wrist.
We found a
seatbelt adjuster
at the scene.
Maybe she was dragged
by a seatbelt.
(screaming)
Whatever it was,
the dragging went on a while.
Abrasions on her elbows,
ribs, and knee caps
go down to the bone.
Her eyes.
What about them?
They're the wrong color.
They were green.
You mean these?
Green contacts.
BROWN:
I'm sorry for your
loss, Mrs. Gentry,
but we could really
use your help.
Is there anyone
in this neighborhood
that your daughter
might have been
going to see
last night?
(sobbing)
(cell phone ringing)
Excuse me.
Hey, Cath.
Are you serious?
You're kidding, right?
I'm actually with
the mother right now.
I'll handle it.
I'm sorry.
I don't know why
Melissa would have...
Ma'am, your daughter's alive.
What?
We made a mistake.
The victim that we found was
carrying your daughter's I.D.
Are you sure?
Yes. She just spoke
with my supervisor,
she's fine.
(laughing)
It's a miracle.
Oh, thank God.
(sobbing):
It's a miracle!
All right.
There's just
one thing.
We still need to
identify the victim.
Could you tell me
if you recognize this girl?
That's Simone.
(sobbing):
Oh, no.
That's Simone Molinez.
That's my daughter's
best friend.
(sobbing):
Oh...
There were no drugs or alcohol
in the limo driver's system.
Really?
What about Drops?
Also clean.
As was your head shot vic.
Club scene's getting
really tame these days.
There's got to be something
on the rolled-up hundred.
It's positive
for cocaine,
along with every Benjamin
in the country.
But no coke in the driver
or the passengers?
That doesn't
make any sense.
♪ ♪
You know, if you're still
having trouble coming to terms
with the fact that this is
no longer your lab,
I suggest counseling.
I would like you
to run this for me, please.
Okay.
Hmm. Boogers on a nose straw.
Yep.
Well, in recognition of
your years of previous service,
I will make it a priority.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
I gave Simone my license
a couple of months ago.
She was always getting her
fakes snatched by bouncers,
so I gave her
my expired one.
Bouncers only ever
look at the birth date.
We look alike.
Kind of, in ways,
like her nose and...
parts of her
chin and cheeks.
And we both have nice butts.
But... that's not on a license.
Do you know anyone
who'd want to hurt Simone?
No way.
She was so nice,
super cool...
all about fun.
Any guys involved?
Yeah.
Mostly guys.
Guys with money.
Like who?
I never met
any of them.
They weren't long-term things.
She would just go out
with them to party.
She have sex with these guys?
No, no sex.
She would just use them
to get drunk
and hang out at penthouses.
Where was Simone last night?
I don't know,
but she always starts off
her night at the same place:
The Gold Square on Sunset.
That place is a dive.
That's not the kind of place
to find rich guys.
It was kind of
a confidence builder for her.
Simone was a star in there.
She'd always come out with
at least a couple numbers.
CURTIS:
Gold Square Bar, gold wad
of tissue in her purse--
figured it was worth
checking out.
Looks like a
bar napkin.
Yeah, that's been shaped,
rolled and twisted.
Las Vegas origami.
Pretty corny.
Probably work on me.
(chuckles):
That bad, huh?
(chuckles)
Here we are.
"Carey."
Looks like this Carey
was hitting on the vic.
Maybe in more ways than one.
(footsteps approaching)
Hey.
Um, I got your
DNA results.
Yeah, and?
Well, there were two
donors on the nose straw.
There was one unknown female
and one half-known male.
So a sibling match?
Yeah.
Greg, the male is the brother
of Demitrius James.
SANDERS:
One guy decided
not to run away.
He picked up a rock
and started coming
at me with it.
(Marla wailing, sobbing)
MARLA JAMES:
You didn't run over a mob,
you ran over one boy!
My boy!
AARON JAMES:
How tough you feel
when your not
in your big SUV, huh?
Asked you a
question, killer.
I asked you a question!
GRISSOM:
This image was captured
on a cell phone at the scene.
We believe that that
is Aaron James.
That fuzzy blob?
We also found evidence
of Aaron James inside the limo.
Well, I hope it's
better than this photo.
It's DNA, along with traces
of cocaine
on a rolled-up $100 bill.
Which doesn't place
him in the limo.
That bill could
have been brought
in there by anyone.
We found a pattern in the blood
on the seat next to the vic's.
It doesn't match the clothes
from the limo driver or Drops',
so there was at least one
other passenger in that limo,
and we need
to question Aaron James.
This city just paid Aaron James
and his mother $2.5 million
because you ran
his brother over.
Are you trying to find a way
to give them more money?
I'm just trying to do my job.
You want
to talk
to Aaron James, give me
more than snot on a bill,
and a dot on a crummy photo.
This is a PR
nightmare in
the making.
We still don't have
a murder weapon.
Aaron James could be
destroying evidence right now.
All right, first of all,
stop talking.
You're off
the case.
Everything he touched
gets reprocessed.
There's nothing
wrong with my work.
Okay. I know that.
It's just standard procedure.
Oh, procedure.
Open your mouth one more time,
and you're on suspension.
I'm trying to avoid a
harassment suit here.
This is cover-our-ass time.
Keep me apprised.
This would have been
so much easier
if you had been the black guy.
We're looking
for Carey Corville.
That's me, Bob.
M... Hottest cops
I've ever seen.
Yeah, might be
the hottest chicks
I've seen all week.
You guys are here to get me,
take me away.
Pat him down.
Am I under arrest for something?
Yeah, that depends.
This your idea of romance?
Can't really arrest me for that.
We found it
in Simone Molinez's purse.
She kept that, for real?
Oh, it's on.
What are you guys doing with it?
She's dead.
Oh.
Well, listen, I don't know
nothing about none of that.
Sh-She was breathing
when I left her.
(loud chatter,
music playing)
That's sweet.
But I have a boyfriend.
So you say.
Come on.
I'm not that hard up.
Look, she
didn't like me.
So what?
On to the next who will.
You've got a GMC truck?
Where is it?
(sniffing)
Disinfectant.
Seat's damp.
WILLOWS:
Hey, Carey,
there's blood
in your car.
Yeah, it's, uh,
my boy, Scotty.
He had a nosebleed.
Scotty who?
Scotty Brittington?
WILLOWS:
Well, it's a hell
of a lot of blood
for a nosebleed.
Looks more consistent
with the body of
a bloody girl.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
CURTIS:
Where would we find
your boy Scotty?
I don't know. He's kind of hard
to get a hold of easy.
Address and phone.
We're going to see
what your boy has to
say about this blood.
Until then,
you're coming with us.
(phone ringing)
(phone beeps on)
This is Catherine.
CURTIS:
It's me.
Scott Brittington wasn't at any
of his usual haunts,
so I checked the hospitals,
and guess what?
He was admitted last night
with a severe puncture wound
to his shoulder.
He told the staff
it was a work injury,
but during surgery,
they extracted
a bullet fragment.
Interesting line of work.
Doc thinks someone tried
to dig it out
to avoid police notification,
which actually made it
a lot worse.
(screaming)
Dude, it's...
Keep going.
I can't go to the hospital
with a bullet in me.
Cops'll be all over us.
(squishing)
(screaming)
It's all right, man.
I got it, I got it.
(panting)
Needle-nose pliers aren't
exactly a fine surgical tool.
CURTIS:
Yeah, that's for sure.
WILLOWS:
You talk to Scott?
Well, I'm on my way
to his room right now.
WILLOWS:
If he's anything
like his friend,
I'll sure he'll give you plenty
of attitude.
Let me know
what he has to say.
DOCTOR: All right,
let's call it, people.
We've done
what we could.
I don't think
it's going to be much.
(computer beeping)
(sighs)
(beeps)
WILLOWS:
A .38 fragment recovered
from a suspect in my homicide
matched a .38 bullet
that Greg found
near the strip
club drive-by.
SIDLE:
So the guys
in the GMC truck got
into a shoot-out
with the guys
in the limo.
(tires squealing)
(gunfire)
(screaming)
Tie score--
one dead on each side.
Over what?
Why were these guys
shooting each other up?
It's got to be about the girl.
Her DNA matched the unknown
female contribution
on the hundred dollar bill,
so, she was in the limo.
But that bill doesn't put her
in there
any more than it does Aaron.
No, but it proves
she was with Aaron
at some point in the night.
Wait a minute.
Why would Simone even be
with those guys?
Because of Drops.
He knows everybody
in the club scene,
especially the party girls.
He could have
picked her up anywhere.
Simone blows off the broke guys
to party with the rich guys.
The broke guys feel dissed,
so they track down the limo
and retaliate.
Yeah. Yeah.
And somewhere in between,
Simone just gets... tossed.
All right, how are we going
to prove any of this?
I mean, we're not going
to get any answers
from the suspect in the truck.
He's lawyered up.
So is Drops.
And the Undersheriff isn't
letting anyone talk to Aaron.
What about the seat belt
adjuster you found?
No match to the truck.
Doesn't even have
seat belt adjusters.
What about the limo?
SIDLE:
It's not a GMC.
It's a Lincoln Continental.
Yeah, but maybe not entirely.
Stretch limos
are custom-made.
You take a Lincoln
Continental, cut it apart,
stretch it with whatever
parts you have available:
Ford, Chrysler,
General Motors,
doesn't matter.
Looks like the same
belt adjuster.
This one's missing.
This blood has to be
from the shooting.
This is from something else.
There shouldn't be blood
on this part of the seat belt.
Think the Undersheriff
will let us talk to Aaron now?
If the DNA matches
Simone Molinez's,
anyone that was in this limo
is up for murder.
The, uh, Undersheriff
won't have a choice.
OFFICER MITCHELL:
From the hood to the hills.
Didn't take him long
to spend the taxpayers' money.
CURTIS:
Hey, knock it off.
You need to look
in the fridge.
Mrs. James?
(music playing)
Oh, hell, no.
I got company.
We have a warrant
to search the premises.
A warrant? A warrant for what?!
We also need
to speak to Aaron.
Oh, we're not talking to nobody.
This is harassment!
That could be considered
assaulting an officer.
Let's not make this harder
than it has to be.
Somebody get me a phone!
All right, ten ball,
corner pocket.
Mr. James?
We need to talk
to you down at
the station.
You're not under arrest.
We just want
to talk.
Yeah, right.
I hear soda water
works better.
What'd work better is if I took
it out and shot it.
So long as I don't see it
on the 11:00 news.
(chuckles)
The James kid, he lawyered up?
Yeah.
Yeah, his attorney's
on his way.
You holding a
press conference?
Yeah, I'm on my way there now.
How do I look?
Like fresh meat.
Oh. Hope I hold
my temper as well as you.
You've got a big future
in this department.
Send the dry cleaning bill
to my office.
SIDLE:
I checked the mom's room
and the guest rooms,
no sign of any weapons, but...
I did find these
in the laundry room.
Look familiar?
Yeah. Any trace of blood?
Nothing obvious.
They were just washed.
(sniffs)
They smell like bleach.
Great. What about the, uh,
the hoodie in that
cell phone picture?
It looked like Aaron
was wearing one.
Yeah, it's still wet.
Aaron wears his clothes baggy.
He probably keeps
them out of the dryer
so they won't shrink.
Looks like the little
hood left us something.
(glass breaking)
ATTORNEY:
You're right.
My client is guilty
of partying
in Las Vegas.
But with this
de minimus amount,
you wouldn't be able to
hold him for possession.
Those jeans? Come on.
You'd probably find
that same pattern
on at least a couple
thousand asses in this town.
There's nothing here
that places my client
in that limo at the
time of the shooting.
How about this?
CURTIS:
A piece of Champ Landley's
skull
in the hood of your sweater.
I'd say you were
definitely there.
ATTORNEY:
Look, scared kid makes
a couple of mistakes.
It's peer pressure,
all right?
It's a misdemeanor,
at best.
You want to put LVPD
through PR hell
for that?
CURTIS:
No.
Not just that.
Simone Molinez was
dragged to death from your limo
before the shoot-out.
Aaron was in the car
when she was being dragged.
I'd say that makes him
a prime suspect.
No, no, no,
hold it, hold it.
I don't know this girl.
Okay, she came up to Drops
at the Gold Square.
Aaron, don't say...
No, hold up, man.
I didn't kill anybody.
What's a guy like Drops
doing at a dump
like the Gold Square?
Drops grew up
in that 'hood.
Guess he, uh...
wanted to claim
his old territory.
♪ ♪
AARON:
We own that place.
Picking up a girl in there
was like stealing.
Drops had been trying
to open up his own club.
Asked me to invest.
Before I got my money,
guy like Drops
wouldn't have said,
"What up," to me,
let alone ask me out
to talk business.
I felt like a big shot.
What's the big deal?
We think it's
that big shot attitude
that's exactly
what got you shot.
♪ ♪
CURTIS:
Taking that girl
out of the Gold Square,
you pissed off
a couple of locals.
Everyone knows
Drops ends his nights
at the strip club.
They were waiting for you.
Look, I had nothing
to do with that.
And I definitely didn't
kick her out of that limo.
CURTIS:
So who did then?
ATTORNEY:
Aaron, unless you want
to go to jail, son,
don't say another word.
You observed the interview?
If the Undersheriff had
seen you, he would've
gone ballistic.
Well, I'm still
off the case.
Besides, I just happened
to be listening,
and I heard Aaron
say that he didn't
kick the girl
out of the limo.
You want me
to check the body?
Well, bruises get more
distinguished as a
body decomposes,
so just see if there's
anything we missed.
MARLA:
That's the one I
want to talk to.
I'm on it.
RECEPTIONIST:
Miss, excuse me.
You're not allowed back there!
Taking one of my boys wasn't
good enough for
you, was it?
Now you've
got to take both?
What did we ever do to you?
Mrs. James,
I don't have anything
against you or your family.
Then what is it?
Is it about the money?
Then take it!
I just want my boy back!
Mrs. James,
you need to calm down...
I'm not talking to you!
Well, you're going to get
yourself into trouble here.
OFFICER:
Ma'am...
You're going to have to leave.
Protecting the nice white boy
from the mean black lady.
You've got
to help me.
You owe me.
You owe me!
What do I owe you?
(chuckles)
Yeah, like you don't know.
I'll tell you what I know:
I know that Demitrius
was a killer.
And Aaron-- Aaron made
the decision to hang out
with Drops.
He made
the decision to do drugs,
and to bring that girl
into the limo.
That's not on me.
It's on him, and you.
Aaron is all I have left.
(camera beeps)
BRASS:
This bruise on
Simone Molinez's body
matches the heel
of your buddy Champ's
dress shoe.
Man, forensics
be jammin' a brother up.
No doubt. And you saw him do it.
Look, he was just trying to show
a potential investor
a good time, that's all.
The boy got a short fuse.
All right.
Whatever.
Why don't you really
hook up my man?
Champ, come on, man.
What's wrong with you, man?
She's a lady.
Let me out the car!
Oh, you want out?
Get out.
Tell the driver to stop.
We're in a hurry!
You want out,
you get out now!
No!
(screaming)
Hey!
So, what, he pushed
her out of the car
because she wouldn't
have sex with Aaron?
Champ thought it was a bad look.
Bad? Bad for what?
Champ gets a bonus
when business is good.
You got booze, bling, girls,
guns and drugs in a limo.
Would you call that doing
legitimate business?
Yeah.
So, um...
what's a few
scrapes and bruises
on this girl got
to do with me?
Yeah, a few scrapes
and bruises, a broken wrist
dislocated shoulder,
broken neck--
add it up: it equals death.
Death? Wait a minute, no way.
See, first of all,
that limo was turtlestepping' it
down the block.
It's like fallin' off a bike.
Yeah, maybe so, if she wasn't
tangled up in the seat belt.
What, you didn't hear her
dragging on the street?
The speakers were on blast.
I couldn't even
hear my cell phone
and that was
on vibrate.
My client has
corroborated your evidence.
Are we free to go?
What? No!
I'm charging you with the
murder of Scott Brittington.
Scott... Who?
The guy you shot.
Okay, we already went over that.
Champ was the shooter.
Yeah, so you say.
But you're the only
one in the limo
with a registered .38.
And you didn't
toss that gun after you used it,
you gave it to Aaron.
DROPS:
Trust me, son,
you don't want
to be here when
the cops come, okay?
Here, take the ratchet,
and make it disappear.
Take the ratchet!
Don't worry about it;
I got you covered.
BRASS:
Aaron leaves the scene
with your murder weapon,
and you take his spot
like he was never there.
Captain Brass,
I've seen the ballistics report.
The shots
fired from inside
the limo were fired second.
That's textbook self-defense.
"Textbook self-defense."
Told you, forensics be
jammin' a brother up.
I'll take my chances
with the jury.
I'm going to see your
arms behind your back
sooner than you think.
Counselor.
(door opens and closes)
And all this time I thought
I was paying you too much.
Give me some.
The DA tells me
you requested
he go easy on Aaron James.
Yeah.
He's getting
a suspended sentence.
Released on his
own recognizance.
GRISSOM:
Tell me something.
If the kid's brother
hadn't died,
would you have done the same?
I don't know. I just, uh...
You think it's wrong?
Doesn't matter what I think.