(creaking)
(TV playing indistinctly)
HOST:
...nice and hot, 'kay?
And again, we always add
the salt and pepper.
(static crackles)
(mutters):
Piece of crap.
...hits the pan and you want to
listen for that sound.
That is the most
important sound.
(creaks)
Jay?
Is that you?
...next we're gonna add
the tomatoes,
which sometimes
have enough sugar,
but really when you've got
the natural sugar...
(groaning)
HOST:
...tomatoes, some tomato juice.
Now if you don't... if tomatoes
aren't in season,
they're not really...
WILLOWS:
CSI processed the knife
and found blood from
four different sources,
three of which were intermingled
together on the blade.
One matched Addie Finch,
the victim.
The other two were also female.
And based on the number of
DNA markers they have in common,
they're either sisters
or mother and daughter.
They are not related
to Addie Finch.
And both remain unidentified.
And the fourth DNA source?
When I disassembled the knife,
I found blood on the tang,
which is the steel area
under the handle.
Were you able
to identify this DNA?
It was a match to the victim's
son, Jay Gregory Finch.
The defendant.
That's right.
JUDGE HYAK:
Cross-examination,
Mr. Novak?
Did you recover the knife
from the scene three years ago?
No, the defendant
turned it in to P.D.
A man comes home...
only to find his mother
bleeding on the floor,
a knife stuck in her chest.
In a desperate attempt
to save her life,
he removes the knife
from her chest.
But it's too late.
He takes the knife in question
to the authorities,
cooperates with
their investigation,
and then you charge him
with murder.
The defendant did not
call for help,
and he waited five days
to turn it in.
He was in shock.
You found two unknown sources
of blood on that knife.
Isn't it possible
that one or both of them
killed Addie Finch?
Objection.
Speculative.
I'll allow it.
It's possible.
However, Mr. Finch's blood
was found isolated
near the handle.
Stabbing is a messy business.
I believe that Mr. Finch
cut himself...
You've been warned about
speculation, Ms. Willows.
It's not speculation.
From his birth until
the time of his mother's death,
Mr. Finch lived in that house.
Isn't it equally possible
he cut himself
on that knife
at a separate occasion?
Yes, but...
For the record,
her answer was
"Yes, it's possible."
No further questions.
Though Addie Finch received
multiple stab wounds,
the actual cause of death
was a gunshot wound.
Isn't that correct?
We believe that
the defendant stabbed
his mother multiple times,
stood over her while
she was dying, and
shot her in the forehead
to complete the act.
You recovered a bullet
from Ms. Finch's body.
Did you also recover a gun?
No.
So you have nothing with which
to forensically match
the bullet?
The bullet was a .38.
The defendant's father,
who passed away
in 1989, was seen in
photographs holding a .38.
We also found
an empty gun case
in the defendant's closet,
which tested positive
for chromium steel.
My belt buckle is also
made of metal.
If I kept it in a box, wouldn't
it also test positive?
Do you keep it in
a velvet-lined gun box?
No further questions.
On the sole count of murder
in the first degree,
we, the jury, find the
defendant, Jay Gregory Finch...
not guilty.
(gavel bangs)
Thank you.
Take care of yourself.
Quite the salesman,
Mr. Novak.
Not a hard sell.
Finch is guilty.
You once said
the same about me.
You were wrong then, too.
Yeah, you're not a murderer,
you just set them free.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
BRASS:
Why didn't you bring
the knife directly to us?
I get these
anxiety attacks...
since I hit my head real bad
playing football my senior year.
I get these brutal headaches.
So, I climb into my car
and drive.
Sometimes for days.
It... it calms me.
Mom and I took care
of each other.
We were a good team.
What a load of crap.
We found his bags
packed near the door.
Addie raised a momma's boy
and she'd finally had enough.
She was kicking his ass out
and he snapped.
Did Finch have
a history of violence?
No, but his CT scan
showed damage
to the amygdala
and the frontal lobe.
That kind of injury has been
known to change personality,
to make a person more
inclined to violence.
We need to ID his
other two victims.
Charge Finch
with a new crime.
No double jeopardy.
We can even use
the knife again.
Catherine, we tried
three years ago.
There were no other
female related crimes
in the Vegas metro area
that week.
He drove for five days, Nick.
Yes, and as I recall,
we put out a broadcast
covering cities statewide.
But not to any of
the small towns in between.
They aren't connected
to a central network.
Needle in a haystack.
It's our job to find
a needle in a haystack.
How did you know about this?
I saw an approved leave of
absence form on Ecklie's desk.
Don't worry, I didn't say
anything to anyone else.
Did you think
that you were going to
teach at my alma mater
in the dead of winter
without warm clothes?
I thought you went to college
in San Diego.
Graduate school.
Undergraduate was
all about the Bay State.
Crazy times, my friend,
crazy times.
Those Hampshire girls
down in Amherst?
Insane.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
What are you teaching?
The seasonal fluctuations
in observed behaviors
of the Walden Pond
swamp mosquito.
Excellent.
I don't know what college
was like for you,
but for me it was
a new beginning,
a chance to
reinvent myself.
For the first time in my
life, I felt like I fit in.
Not like now.
I mean...
you and I are close,
but sometimes I just don't
think the others get me.
WILLOWS (knocks):
You got a second?
He's kind of busy.
Oh.
When you get a chance,
hit the Purple Pint.
Ask for Cookie.
Tell her Davey Hodges
sent you.
Drinks'll be on the house.
Crazy times.
Yeah.
Jay Finch got an oil change the
day that he killed his mother.
We compared the odometer reading
on the work order
against what it read
when we impounded his car.
The difference
was 350 miles.
We used that to create
a search radius.
Nick and I just spent
six hours on the phone with
sheriffs in every county
inside that area.
There was one unsolved case
that matched our criteria
in Larkston.
A Laura Montoya and her
12-year-old daughter,
Robyn.
Why are we talking about this?
Finch got off, didn't he?
And I don't buy it.
I need to go to Larkston.
You can't.
Look, I want a second shot
at this guy.
I want to get him
before he kills again.
I'm going on sabbatical.
You're gonna be the acting
supervisor while I'm gone.
When are you leaving?
Tomorrow night.
I'll be back before then.
How long have you
known about this?
(garbled police dispatches)
Need a vacation?
I guess I should be grateful
you didn't stop by my house.
And get a gun in my face?
No, thank you.
I can take a hint.
What do you want?
I'm here waving a white flag.
Look, I owe you
an apology.
I regret the way I've behaved
toward you in the past.
I've sobered up, and
I want to make amends.
Climbing the 12 Steps.
Got a few more to go.
Well, you can check me
off the list.
Thank you for stopping by.
Hey...
which pissed
you off more,
that Finch went free
or that I won?
I'm 50-50.
There's still
hope for me.
You all right?
Perfect timing.
Let's go.
♪ ♪
STOKES:
Sabbatical's usually
a euphemism for "sayonara."
I don't think Grissom's
coming back.
Why wouldn't he?
I don't know,
he shaved his beard,
he's lost a little weight,
he's been leaving
when shift is over.
I think he even took a day off
last week.
Maybe he's got himself
a girlfriend.
That's what I'm saying.
You know, I thought you were
going to leave
a few months ago.
Why, 'cause I shaved my beard?
(laughing)
No, I mean, I...
you don't really
have to work anymore
if you don't want to, right?
What are you talking about?
Well... Sam, with your dad...
the whole thing.
Oh, is that what people think?
That daddy's little girl
got herself a big inheritance?
Well, let me tell
you something, Nicky.
All of Sam's money is tied up
in a big hole in the ground
on a very nice piece
of Strip real estate,
but I got no dog
in that fight.
Now you guys aren't here
to make me look bad, are you?
No.
Just busting chops.
Sheriff Beth McGuire.
Nick Stokes.
Nice to meet you.
Catherine Willows.
Hi.
I just read that file
that you sent over.
Jay Finch, he looks like
a real son of a bitch.
Laura Montoya, she was
a good friend of mine.
So, uh...
hey, Ronnie.
How you doing?
I would really be happy
to see this case solved.
Yeah, as would we.
Why don't you... run us
through it, Sheriff?
Okay. Uh...
Laura...
and her daughter
were right... here
eating burgers and
drinking shakes.
They were the last
customers of the night.
Jake Hanson closed up,
and then he left
and they were still
right here, eating.
I'm heading home, girls.
Don't you stay all night.
Stay hi to
your mom, Jake.
And I was called
about 10:00 p.m.
Couple of local
skateboarders.
They saw the blood
and they just, you know,
called it in.
No bodies?
No. Just a
blood pool...
here.
I found some blood
drops leading out
through the parking lot
towards the main road.
Abduction?
I don't know.
One minute, my best friend
is just having an Oreo
smoothie with her kid,
and then the next minute
all I got is blood drops.
Did you identify who
the blood belonged to?
We sent a sample
to the Reno Lab.
Came back a match to Laura.
Mother's the
bigger threat.
Probably took
her out first.
And once she was injured,
the daughter got
scared into compliance.
Any idea on the mode of death?
Well, I know your guy
used a knife and a gun,
but I didn't
recover any weapons.
We're gonna need a blood sample
to compare to our knife.
I-I got that back in the
fridge at the station.
You know, there are
quite a few nicks
in the pavement down here.
So if Laura was
seated here...
the shooter
would've had to
aim downward
to impact the asphalt.
Then this would have been
the trajectory of the bullet.
Now, there's what appears to be
a ricochet mark headed
in the right direction.
Killer shoots Laura
from behind...
(gunshot)
Wait a minute.
Oh, yeah.
I think we're
in business, ladies.
Hey, Gris.
So, uh, Hodges tells me
you're flying the coop.
What's the matter, you
sick of baby-sitting?
Just the opposite.
I'm a teacher
without any students.
I've still got a lot to learn.
Besides, having you around kinda
keeps me honest.
Whether you know it or not,
you're the rock of my team.
Catherine's going to be
in charge for a while
while I'm gone.
Be there for her
like you've been
there for me
and we'll all be fine.
Thanks. It means a lot.
You know I got you covered.
What, are you sending
those to the... the Louvre?
Ernie Dell did kill
with an artistic touch.
.25 caliber.
Finch used a .38.
No dice, huh?
Finch could've used
a different gun,
but chances are, yeah,
they're unrelated.
When you guys called, I...
I let myself believe
that Laura was still alive.
Well, now, I'm, I'm just
gonna pray that she's dead.
I just don't want to think
about the alternative.
Thank you
for your help, Beth.
I gotta call her
sister in Denver.
This'll be the second time
I've gotten her hopes up.
There was a first time?
Well, there was
a double murder
the day after
Laura went missing.
It was about 20 miles
outside of Larkston.
A Mary Acheson
and her daughter,
Heather Curtis.
At first, I,
I thought it was related
to the disappearance
of Robin and Laura,
but, but it wasn't.
Why didn't you
tell us this before?
It's a closed case.
We got the guy.
Robert Guffey.
Okay... He's in, uh...
Carson City. He's doing
a life term
in the Nevada state prison.
Yeah. His bloody fingerprints
were all over the crime scene,
and he confessed the next day.
So you initially thought
that Guffey was also good
for your friend Laura
and her daughter's abduction.
What changed your mind?
There was no
evidence to link him
and he had an alibi.
Plus, he would only admit to
Heather and Mary's murders.
How'd he kill them?
Stabbed, then shot.
This is Heather Curtis.
She and her husband lived
with Mary Acheson,
her mother.
So, uh...
Shawn was at work,
and then he
called home, and then
when nobody answered the phone,
he knew that
something was wrong.
So the son was home?
He was hiding.
That. That's Robert Guffey.
So Guffey knew the victims?
He was their plumber.
Yeah. Old house,
bad pipes.
Oh, he was there all the time.
Says here he has
a history of violence.
Beat his girlfriend.
Oh, yeah, and his ex-wife
has a T.R.O. against him.
But this is
his very first murder.
Unless, of course,
he killed Addie Finch first.
So maybe you're looking
for my guy.
Was Guffey in Vegas that week?
I don't know.
I didn't ask him.
Did you recover a handgun?
Yeah. Oh, yeah, at his house.
It was a .38,
same caliber as your case.
But you couldn't match
the bullets to it?
Reno Lab said that the
bullets were too damaged,
you know, from bouncing around
inside the victims' skulls
so they just couldn't get
any kind of comparison at all.
I'm assuming you have the blood
samples from the two victims?
They're at the Reno Lab,
but, uh...
I can do you one better.
You can take your own samples.
Just a sec,
I'm gonna open this thing.
You thinking what
I'm thinking?
Looks like Addie
Finch's house.
Danny and Shawn got
an apartment in town.
They've never been back here.
And Shawn, he can't quite bring
himself to sell the place.
So, nothing inside's been
touched in three years?
Nope. This door
is a time machine.
This blood pool
belongs to Mary,
the mom.
And, uh...
this blood
down here belongs to
Heather, the daughter.
Screen door's ripped.
Must have been a struggle.
We printed it,
only got smeared partials.
Mary answers the door.
The killer forces
his way in...
stabs her.
(groaning)
Heather comes to
her mother's aid.
Mom?
Gets stabbed herself.
(screaming)
And flees to the kitchen.
The killer finishes Mary off
and hunts Heather down.
He catches up
with Heather
and executes her as well.
(gunshot)
This is where we found Danny.
Poor little guy
had peed in his pants.
He wouldn't come out
to anybody but his dad.
Is this the phone that you
pulled Guffey's prints from?
Uh... yeah.
Guffey admitted
to having made
an anonymous
911 call
from the house
at 3:20 p.m.
And he didn't stick around.
Whose blood on
the door handle?
Oh, we tested it.
That's a mixture
of the victims'.
I think whoever did
this might have seen
Danny's toys
in the backyard,
thought the job
wasn't done yet...
and went outside
to finish it.
(thumps wood)
(gunshots)
He shot the rabbits.
I believe
that Guffey thought
that Danny was inside.
We got a confession.
We didn't need
those bullets,
so we didn't
collect them.
So we found one bullet
in Addie Finch,
you found one in
Mary, one in Heather.
There was three
in this hutch.
If all these bullets were
shot from the same .38,
six would kick it.
Three murders,
one gun, one killer.
But was it Guffey,
or was it Finch?
Well, these bullets should
answer that question.
Let's start digging.
♪ ♪
(device beeping)
There's enough here
for a comparison.
Good. Good, if it
matches Guffey's gun,
he stays in prison,
but if it doesn't,
we've got no gun
to tie to Finch.
You need to get all the evidence
back to the lab.
What are you gonna do?
I'm gonna go see Guffey.
He's not gonna talk
to you, Catherine.
We'll see.
Hey, how's it going
on your civil case?
Did you get a lawyer?
LVPD said they'll provide me
with an attorney.
Get your own counsel,
Greg.
That's your right.
Well, are you gonna
give me a raise?
Because otherwise,
I can't afford that.
Call the PPACE,
talk to your union rep.
This was
an on-duty incident.
They'll provide you
with an attorney.
How's the union lawyer gonna be
any different?
The department's only interest
is the department.
They'll throw you
under the bus
to protect themselves.
When's your deposition?
Three weeks from tomorrow.
Stick to whatever you put
in the report.
Don't waiver,
be consistent.
Everything's gonna be fine.
WILLOWS:
Hi, you've reached CSI
Catherine Willows.
Please leave a message
at the tone.
Yeah, Cath, it's Doc Robbins.
I reviewed the autopsy photos
on all three victims.
The wounds appear consistent
in all three cases.
Vics were stabbed in the chest,
and then presumably
while choking on their own
blood, they were shot.
C.O.D. for each:
single GSW to the head.
Robert Guffey?
I don't know you.
You can call me Catherine.
Unless you're here
for a conjugal,
I'm not calling you anything.
What do you like to be called?
"The best I ever had."
There was a murder
that was committed in Vegas
two days before the
Acheson-Curtis murders.
I think the same person
committed both crimes
and I think that person is you.
Mr. Guffey, this is how
this is going to work.
Every time you answer
one of my questions,
I unbutton a button.
Are you ready?
(chuckles)
Does that count as a question?
You recognize this woman?
Nope.
That's it.
Playing ball.
Why did you kill Mary Acheson
and Heather Curtis?
Ah, 'cause sometimes
women get killed.
Oh,
don't be like that.
Well, that wasn't an answer.
It was enough
for those other cops.
What's that supposed to mean?
That, uh, means I didn't do it.
Well, then why did you confess?
They had me
in a room for 12 hours...
no food, no water, no sleep.
I had to beg
to use the bathroom.
So now you're claiming
you were coerced.
I've been claiming that
since day one.
I recanted
the next morning.
Button.
That bitch cop...
grabs my arm,
points to this vein and says,
"That's where
the needle will go
when they put you down
like the dog you are."
If I wanted to avoid the death
penalty, all I had to tell her
was what she and-and-and her
deputies
wanted to hear.
That's worth two.
Just pace yourself.
How come your prints
were found all over the house?
Front door was open...
Mary? Mary?!
There are two dead bodies
at the Curtis house.
No, no, no, no.
So you called for help,
but didn't stick around.
I done... a few nights in prison
for smacking my wife around,
my girlfriend before that.
I knew how it'd look.
No good deed, right?
How about just one more
for good behavior?
Let's see if your story
checks out.
Hey, Nick.
Hey.
Where's Catherine?
Not back yet. I got a ride
here with a local deputy.
She told me she was going
to be back before I left.
Oh, yeah.
Listen, about that...
I told my folks
when I went to college
I'd be back, you know?
Go to work at the D.A.'s office
with my dad.
You can kinda see
how that turned out.
Anyway, I just wanted
to say it's been great, man.
Really, I've learned
a lot from you, man.
I'll be back in four weeks.
Stop hugging me.
Yes, sir.
♪ ♪
Hey, Catherine, I tested
the rabbit bullet
to Guffey's gun. No match.
He's probably innocent.
But, but it did match the stria
to the bullet that killed
Addie Finch.
Which brings us back
to Jay Finch
and his missing .38.
Yes, ma'am, it does.
Well, look, the only way
we're gonna get a conviction
is we place Finch
at the Curtis house.
In the meantime, have Brass
put a tail on Finch.
I'm not sure
if he's a flight risk.
I don't want to take a chance.
Okay, okay.
And hey, one more thing.
Tell the Sheriff that I ran
the bullet
from her abduction case
through IBIS and there was no
hit as well. Sorry.
I'll tell her.
Robert Guffey alleges
that he was coerced
into a false confession.
And you've never heard
that one before?
Did anything unorthodox happen
during his interrogation?
What is your point, Catherine?
Did you ever do an interrogation
tired, Beth?
Use your frustration,
snap at the suspect
just so you can go home?
Use all that edge
to get a confession?
Am I being interrogated now?
You questioned Robert Guffey
the exact week your best friend
and her daughter
disappeared.
That's not just edge,
that's a whole blade.
I was sure Guffey was guilty
till you showed up.
Who admits to a crime
he didn't commit?
Who does that?
People under duress.
You come into this town,
you make me wrong,
and then you go ride off
into the sunset.
And where does that leave me?
With the opportunity
to right a wrong.
Sir, someone will be with you...
Look, I already
told you, babe,
I ain't going anywhere.
So unless you want
to have a really
screwed-up day,
I suggest you get
her down here now.
Mr. Novak.
Where's Willows?
Out.
How can I help you?
Why the hell is this department
tailing my client?
Concern for his safety?
That's cute.
Jay Finch was acquitted
of his mother's murder.
He deserves all the rights
of a free man.
With all due respect,
Mr. Novak, no laws
have been broken here.
You can't try Finch twice
for the same crime.
No, but you can
for a different crime.
Oh, I see.
This is a personal vendetta
by CSI Willows.
Personal to who?
Me. She's a man-hater.
No surprise,
but how long
do we have to pay
for the sins of her father?
You know, Catherine and I
get along just great.
Maybe it's you.
Well, you tell Catherine she
continues badgering my client,
I will file a claim
with the Attorney General's
office for oppression
under cover of law.
Duly noted.
What do you mean, he's innocent?
He confessed.
I screwed up, Shawn.
He dragged their blood
through my house
and took off.
This is bull...
I spent three years
trying to get those memories
out of my head.
Are you telling me
it's gonna start
all over again?
I get that.
I get that, Shawn.
I really do.
And I wouldn't drag you
and Danny out here
if it weren't important.
Guffey was in your house,
but probably after the fact.
We believe we know
who actually committed
the crimes.
And unless we find
the evidence
that he was in there,
we'll never know for sure.
Mr. Curtis, your son
was the only one
that got out alive.
He may have seen something.
I don't think
I can go in there.
How can I ask my son to do it?
May I ask him?
Thank you.
Hi, Danny.
I'm Catherine.
I'm trying to catch
the bad guy that
hurt your mom
and your grandma,
and I could really
use your help.
Do you think they're with God?
What do you think?
I think they're still in there.
Why?
They're waiting to fly up
to heaven.
What are they waiting for?
For me to say good-bye.
Come on, Dad.
Mom had made cookies.
(cookie jar mooing)
HEATHER:
Danny, I can hear you.
Put the cookie back.
I hid in here.
He's a lot bigger now.
Heather always said
he grew fast.
Then there was someone
at the door.
No!
MAN:
This is my house!
HEATHER:
Mom, what's going on? Mom?
(screaming)
(Mary and Heather groaning)
(sobbing)
(choking gasps)
(gunshot)
(Danny panting)
(cookie jar mooing)
And then what happened, Danny?
I heard him eat a cookie.
Then he went out
the back door.
I heard some more bangs.
Thought he was gone,
and then he came back in
through the front door,
called the police.
Guffey.
You did great, buddy.
(mooing)
Say good-bye, Dad.
Good-bye, baby.
(shutter snapping)
(beeping)
(blipping)
♪ ♪
(cell phone rings)
(hangs up)
Hey, Catherine.
Wendy found two DNA markers
from the bloody
fingerprint on
the cookie jar.
Related females--
Heather and Mary.
And the knife?
Also a match.
We got him, Nick.
AFIS hit-- Jay Finch.
(windmill creaking)
♪ ♪
(mouthing)
Mr. Finch, Las Vegas Police.
Put the knife down.
Stand back with
your hands up.
(panting)
What are you doing in my house?
Mr. Finch, put
the knife down.
This is my house.
I'm not gonna
ask you again.
Put it down.
No...
(siren blips)
(garbled police dispatches)
Norman Bates is keeping his
mother alive and well.
Yeah, looks like everything's
still in the exact same place.
Including the gun.
He kept the gun case in here.
We searched everywhere
the first time.
He ditched the gun.
(sighs)
In court, he was always
writing in his notebook.
Now I know why.
(shutter snapping)
Now I think I know why Finch
stopped by the Curtis farm.
He'd been
driving for days.
He was exhausted,
disoriented.
He thought he was home.
This is my house.
No, you have
the wrong house.
What are you doing
in my house?
I'm sorry, you have
the wrong house...
Old woman answers the door,
denies him access...
And all Finch saw was his mom.
And then he saw red.
This is my house!
Mom?
(groaning)
(gunshot)
Do you always get
what you want?
Clearly not, but you
don't have enough tricks
in your bag to get
him off this time.
I don't take on cases I don't
think I can win.
Hey, you really want
to defend the innocent?
There's a guy doing life
up in Carson City
that could use an
advocate-- Robert Guffey.
Might even out
your karma.
Ah, you're worried
about me.
Just looking to keep my
faith in the court system.
Everyone deserves
justice.
If not the first time
around, then the second.
Hey.
My cab's here.
So, you're going.
Yeah.
I'll see you when you get back.
I'll miss you.