♪ ♪
BRASS:
Her name is Penny Garden.
Age 65.
Retired cocktail waitress.
Been living here since
the Rat Pack days.
She may have served them drinks.
Well, they must have
tipped well because
20 years ago, this was
a nice neighborhood.
Anyway, a guy next door
heard a racket,
called 911.
Down the hallway,
there's a spare bedroom.
The bed's unmade.
So if the vic
had a houseguest,
they're nowhere to be found,
so I'm going to dig around.
GRISSOM:
Unfortunately,
these windows aren't tempered.
Very dangerous if broken.
And she went through
face first.
SIDLE:
The door's right here--
I doubt she missed it.
Maybe she had some help.
God.
(screaming)
Those coupons on the floor
on top of the glass
suggests they were scattered
after the window broke.
Maybe they went through the room
after they killed her.
There's nothing particularly
valuable here.
There used to be.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
Control, Control, this is
CSI Sanders. I need some help.
WOMAN:
Control,
go with the information.
Assault in progress.
How many suspects?
Are they armed?
Ma'am, please, they gotta
get here quicker than this.
Thank you, ladies
and gentlemen.
My name is Pete Athens.
I am the coroner
of Clark County; I want
to thank you all for being here.
Coroner inquests
go back to medieval times
during the reign
of Richard I in England.
In fact, "coroner" comes
from the word "crown."
A public inquest was one of the
crown's checks and balances
on the powers of the sheriff.
And today,
a thousand years later,
it serves the same purpose
in our county-- checks
and balances on the sheriff
and for those who work for him.
The Honorable Clayton Trueblood
will be our hearing master.
He's not a judge, but he's going
to be more like a, um...
a traffic cop,
because an inquest
isn't a trial.
We're going to examine
the death of Demetrius James.
The assistant district attorney
Valerie Nichols will present
the facts in the case,
introduce the witnesses
and ask them questions.
Any member of the jury
may also ask questions,
either orally or in writing.
I understand that there are
family members
of the deceased present.
I'm very sorry for your loss,
and I want you to know
that as what the state
calls "interested parties,"
you may ask questions, too.
When all the facts have been
presented, the jury will then
rule the death in question
as either justifiable,
excusable or criminal.
Cut's pretty deep.
Let's try and keep her head on
while we move her.
On three:
One, two, three.
Hi.
Grissom said you
could use some help.
What haven't you done?
The rest of the house.
Hope I die before I get old.
Man, I was just lampin'
in the crib with my boys
when all of a sudden, psssh.
I thought someone
was breaking in next door.
Took a look over the fence,
old Penny was breaking out.
Did you hear anything?
Any voices, yelling, screaming?
Mm-mm. I don't even think
Mrs. Penny could scream.
She had, like, a real
low, raspy voice.
Yeah. Well, you
think that's sexy?
Is that the
way you roll?
Huh?
All right,
I'll take that
for a "no." You see
anybody leave the house?
No, sir. Not last night.
Who's she got
staying with her?
Don't know his name,
but I seen him
always going
in and out of there.
Describe him.
White dude. Skinny.
Always wears jeans
and white tees.
Man.
I liked that old lady.
She made some good victuals
and always had an extra
stogie if I was out.
This is my card.
If you see that white
skinny guy, give me
a call, will you?
Yeah.
All right?
You talk to that
guy in that house?
Been there twice.
Still nobody home.
Put someone on his doorstep
until he shows.
He's got security cameras.
I want the video.
CURTIS:
The first attack that night
occurred just after midnight,
in the employee parking
structure at the Golden
Sapphire Hotel.
A group of youths ranging
from teens to early 20s
attacked Vasco Ruiz,
a hotel dishwasher
on his way to his car.
He was apparently
selected at random.
Mr. Ruiz was found
dead at the scene.
And what was the mob's
next move?
Approximately 30 minutes
after the first attack,
not far away,
at the Holiday Motel,
they attacked their next victim,
Jessica Hershbaum.
(screaming):
Stop it! Stop it!
Now, Miss Hershbaum survived.
She's alive.
But she has physical and
emotional scars from the attack
that she may never recover from.
So when Mr. Sanders
was coming to your crime scene,
would he have known about these
first two swarming attacks?
Absolutely.
CSI was still processing
those crime scenes,
and then I heard on my radio
about another attack--
the third that night--
and that a CSI was
one of the victims.
Is this the location
of the third swarming attack?
Yes.
I drove over there immediately.
And what did you find?
Three men,
all seriously injured.
Stanley Tanner was unconscious,
as was Demetrius James.
The mob had pulled
CSI Sanders from his vehicle
and beaten him.
But it was his intervention that
saved Stanley Tanner's life.
While I appreciate
your participation
in the process here,
I don't find this
question relevant.
Excuse me, Your Honor.
The question's
quite relevant.
Are we just going
through the motions here,
so it looks like someone
actually asked
whether or not it's okay
to run over
black kids
in the street?
JUDGE:
Do you have a question, sir?
Yeah.
Are you also going to be
censoring verbal questions?
Relevance is
at my discretion here.
Now, please, take your seat.
ROBBINS:
Multiple lacerations
on face, neck
shoulders-- if it weren't for
the couple dozen glass fragments
I tweezed out, I'd say somebody
went to town on her
with a straight razor.
C.O.D. is exsanguination
due to sharp force injury
to the jugular-carotid
complex,
but she was already
on her way out.
Cannonballs of tumors
on her lungs.
Man... her cancer had cancer.
I guess she liked smoking
more than living, huh?
Or else she wanted to die
with a cigarette in her mouth.
You know, Catherine found
antidepressants, laxatives,
acid-reflux meds
in her house,
but I don't think
she found anything for pain.
I guarantee you,
this lady was in pain.
She must have been
taking something for it.
Maybe the killer
took it with him.
Well, there's a big market
for that stuff now.
I'll get her medical records.
Did you find something?
Bloody glass.
The killer on his way out?
MAN:
You can't keep me
out of there!
This is where
I live, man!
Sorry, son.
This is a crime scene.
You don't want
to be in there.
Look, I just want to see
my Auntie Penny.
Where is she?
Calm... calm down.
I don't want to calm down!
Do you live here?
Yeah, that's what I was
just telling this guy.
What's going on?
What's your name?
Henry. Henry Briney.
Henry, I'm going to need you
to come down
to the police station,
give us a statement.
For what?
Um...
Sorry to tell you,
but your aunt is dead.
NICHOLS:
Mr. Tanner, can you tell us
what injuries you sustained
as a result of the attack?
Cuts, some of them pretty bad,
mostly on my face.
Broke left arm,
crushed windpipe,
one eye socket cracked,
broke right ankle.
And I got
this headache
they tell me
might be permanent.
Would it be correct to say
that while you
were being attacked,
you felt like
your life was in danger?
Hell, yeah.
I have a question.
Go ahead.
Did you actually see
Demetrius James attacking you?
Oh, I couldn't tell who was who.
I mean, hell,
my hands were on my face.
I was just trying
to stay alive.
If Mr. Sanders hadn't
shown up just then,
I'd have been
like that first guy-- dead.
There was a large laceration
where Demetrius James' head
hit the ground when he fell.
Underlying that wound
was a fracture
of the occipital bone,
which crosses
at the base of the skull.
The motion of the impact
caused the brain to
collide with the bony
protrusions
inside the skull,
resulting in what
we call contra-coup contusions.
There was also prominent
cerebral edema-- or swelling--
as well as hemorrhages
of the brain stem.
So your official cause
of death was...?
Blunt force trauma to the head
following a motor
vehicle collision.
So this was a death
at the hands of another?
Yes.
And what do you call
that kind of death?
A homicide.
So where did
you go last night?
Movies.
Oh, a ticket stub.
That's good.
Who'd you go with?
You went by yourself?
Who else would I go with?
I don't know. A friend?
No. I don't have friends.
Okay, so the movie ended.
You're all by yourself,
then what?
I sat in the keno lounge
all night,
hit the grocery store,
and then came home to cops.
Why are you staying
at your Aunt Penny's?
Because my parents
threw me out.
Why would
they do that?
Because they don't like me.
Let me see your arms.
Are you booting
that good "doodgie"?
You ever use intravenous drugs?
Not anymore,
but I did for a while.
You know, your Aunt Penny
had some scrips
for some pain medication--
oxycontin,
fentanyl, methadone.
When we searched
her house,
we didn't find any.
Did you take them?
No, I didn't take them.
She must have
taken them.
I don't touch them.
I just got out of rehab.
Haven't touched a pill,
line or needle
in six months.
My parents threw me out,
and she took me in.
I would not screw her over.
We're going to need to take
your clothes and your shoes.
Any luck?
No.
No blood on the nephew's
shoes or clothes.
Drug panel on his urine
came back negative.
He's clean.
What about
Auntie Penny?
No pain meds
in her system either.
We've got a lot
of serious drugs
that are unaccounted for.
These glass fragments
are from the mob
breaking out the windows
of CSI Sanders' Denali.
That's how
they dragged him out.
This is a clump
of his hair,
torn from his scalp.
And that's the rock
Demetrius James
used as a weapon.
According to who?
This is the first
we've even
heard that Demetrius James
had a weapon.
In his report, Mr. Sanders
testified to that fact.
The rock was found at the scene.
How do we know the cops
didn't plant it there?
Sir, I've warned you.
I'd like to answer
that question.
Usually, when
someone plants
a weapon, whoever did it
puts it right beside
the body--
in this case,
the rock was found near
the front tire of the Denali.
Skid marks suggest
it was dropped upon impact.
A rock against
two tons of steel.
No. More like
one man against an extremely
violent, out of control mob.
What's department policy
in a situation like that?
It has always been
department policy
not to harm innocent civilians.
You call for backup,
you try to be a good witness,
and you stay out of the way.
So what makes it okay
to start running over people?
Well, when those people
are wearing masks,
running around
beating people up.
Man, D.J. was going
to a costume party.
One victim was dead.
Another was
seriously injured.
Another fatality imminent.
I'd say the use of deadly force
in this case
was consistent
with department policy,
absolutely.
NICHOLS:
Demetrius James
was going
to finish off the victim
with the rock.
You're a liar!
My brother
wasn't a killer!
Excuse me.
Demetrius was going to college
Mrs. James.
He had a 3.6 GPA.
We are all very sorry
for your loss,
but you are not a witness here.
You didn't know him!
(shouting)
I do! We knew him!
Judge, can we have
some order here?
You didn't run over a mob,
you ran over one boy!
My boy!
(crying)
Judge?
Mrs. James' comments
give context
to the events
of the night in question.
I'd like to hear
what she has to say.
Why is Trueblood
letting her do this?
It's probably good
for his campaign.
He's running for Assembly.
Now you tell me.
Got your page.
Surveillance footage
from the neighborhood watch
guy across the street.
Yeah, he was paranoid,
but lazy.
Had four security
cameras on his house,
three of them
were cardboard boxes.
Homemade security
is the worst.
Okay, so the nephew comes
in and out of the house
a couple times
during the day.
It's a whole different
story next door.
Okay, this guy
comes out of the house and
meets with a different car
at least three
times and hour.
He's slinging drugs.
BRASS:
The white one is
carisoprodol.
It's a muscle relaxant.
Yeah, I strained my pecs
bench pressing.
Oh, yeah.
And the blue one
is Prevalis.
You look a little
young to need that.
Well, I've had
my share of women.
Mr. Johnson's gotten
bored over the years, so?
Well, he's going to get
really bored in prison.
You hope.
What, you gonna bust me
for selling Prevalis?
Well, you think a guy in my job
doesn't know
what goes on in the clubs
and in the street?
You ever hear of
a Las Vegas Cocktail.
I don't drink.
It's a combination
of carisoprodol, Prevalis
and very strong painkiller
called fentanyl.
Problem is, fentanyl's
hard to get.
I mean, doctors
don't just
give it away, you got to be
in really
serious pain to get it,
like dying
of cancer.
On the street it's
called "perc-a-pop".
Now, Penny Garden
was prescribed 40 a month.
Problem is, we couldn't find
any in her house.
So what, you think I stole them?
Yeah, I do.
Where are the pops, old lady?
Get out of my house.
Where are they?
I'll call the police.
No you won't.
Never.
Never, never, never.
Look, I told you,
I liked the lady.
She made me dinner.
She lent me smokes, man.
You liked her 'cause she had
what you needed.
No, man. No way.
Hey, I need a lawyer in here.
So we have a drug dealer
and a former drug user,
both of which would have
motive to steal Penny's drugs.
Well, there wasn't
any trace of fentanyl
in the nephew's system.
He's broke,
he's unemployed,
maybe he's stealing
them Penny
so he can sell them
to the neighbor.
If that's the case,
it's motive for both.
HENRY:
Excuse me.
Hi, Henry.
What are you
doing here?
Um... I just found this
on my porch--
I opened it
and thought I should
bring it down to you guys.
It's... pretty creepy.
SIDLE:
If one was horrifying...
...what is two?
Possible serial killer.
I'd say that it takes the nephew
and the neighbor off the hook.
I doubt either one of them
could afford a mini-contractor,
anyway.
A bloody doll.
Similar to the one
in the other miniature.
GRISSOM:
Look at the blood
on the doll's forehead.
Same pattern
on both.
Could be two different
views of the same subject.
Maybe it's a signature.
Yeah, but we have
no context.
It could mean or represent
just about anything.
Okay...
again, the miniature
suggests that the killer
had an intimate
familiarity
with victim, home and habits.
So what do they have
in common?
Izzy Delancy, 50-year-old
white male,
washed-up rock star.
Penny Garden, cancer-stricken
retiree.
Different friends,
different family,
different social circles.
Why wasn't this one
left at the crime
scene like that one?
(rattling)
Marla and Aaron James
are not sworn witnesses.
If they were, they couldn't
be in the courtroom
during testimony and that
would effectively take
away their rights
as interested parties
to question witnesses.
So please try to remember
that their remarks
are not evidence.
Go ahead.
My sons didn't grow up
with a father.
Barely had a mother...
on account of me
working all the time.
They got into trouble.
Mostly 'cause of where we live.
Aaron here, he got into
a whole lot of trouble.
And I did my time, too.
I did my time,
but that wasn't D.J.
He was helping me
turn my life around.
Coached me on
my GED.
Made me feel like there was
a chance for me, you know.
Man, you have no idea
what you killed
when you killed my brother.
Everyone was moved by the
compelling testimony...
Today, in the courthouse,
...of the victim's mother...
it wasn't the judge,
the jury or the lawyer,
instead it was the mother,
of Demitrius James
that had the courtroom asking
did her her son behave...
Hey.
Nichols was right.
This isn't a trial,
it's a circus.
Yeah, I heard.
Starring the mother.
I feel like I should
say something.
Like what?
I don't know.
Sorry?
You going to apologize
to the mother of a guy
who beat one man
to death
and was trying to do
the same to you?
That's as good as
saying you're guilty
and setting yourself up for one
hell of a civil suit besides.
You did nothing wrong.
I just want to be able
to sleep again.
We put ourselves in
harm's way every single day
and sometimes, we pay one hell
of a price for surviving it.
Other people will never
understand that.
No way D.J. was
a violent person.
My son is not a killer.
He was trying to stop
that killing.
♪ ♪
Hey.
How'd it go in there?
I don't know.
Really?
Yeah.
You know, I know it was
a hardcore situation
that Greg ran up on, but
you think it ever would
have occurred to him
to just put it in reverse
and get the hell out of there?
Well, that's not the question.
What a jury wants to know
is did Greg do
what any reasonable person
would have done
under the circumstances.
I know Greg must have been
scared as hell, man.
What can we do
to help him?
We'll put the jury behind
the wheel of the car.
♪ ♪
BROWN:
All right, the Denali's
black box reports
only five seconds before impact.
Now, Greg was idling with
his foot on the brake.
And then he accelerated
for no more than two seconds.
Yeah, according to the
acceleration skid marks,
the front end went
from there to there
with D.J. coming at him.
Want to give it a go?
Take it for a spin?
Yeah.
(engine starting)
You ready?
Ready.
Go.
(engine revving)
Stop.
With this kid running at him
the whole time,
there's no way Greg could
have avoided hitting him.
You think a jury
will see it that way?
(loud exhale)
How tough you feel
when you're not in
your big SUV, huh?
I asked you a
question, killer.
Excuse me.
JUDGE:
In the cause now pending
before this court,
do you swear to tell the truth,
the whole truth and nothing
but the truth?
I do.
Be seated.
NICHOLS:
All right, let's take a look
at the official transcript
of your call for backup.
01:54 and 21 seconds,
Dispatch Control answers.
Would you please
read your response.
"Control, Control,
this is CSI Sanders.
I need some help."
You took a couple of seconds
to look at the street signs.
There's a few
more exchanges
and then dispatch
tells you:
"Closest unit
has a five minute ETA."
Five minutes.
Control continues-- "Rolling
Code 3. Are they armed?"
Please read your response.
I don't know, I don't know.
Ma'am, please, listen:
They gotta get here
quicker than this.
Copy that.
What'd you do?
I thought I'd try
to break up the mob.
I turned into the alley,
hit the horn, yelled, anything.
Did that stop
the beating?
Not entirely.
One guy decided not to run away.
Instead, he turned around,
picked up a rock...
and moved like
he was going
to finish off the victim.
But he turned and started
coming at me with it.
Oh, come on, that's just
his word, man.
His word against
my brother's word!
Mr. James.
You know, we can't get
his side, now can we?
All right. Your Honor?
JUDGE: Ms. Nichols,
the man has a right to speak.
Sit down. Come on.
At this point,
did you fear for your life?
Yes.
Did you have
a weapon, a gun?
No.
What were you thinking
when D.J. left Stanley Tanner's
unconscious body
and ran at you
with that rock?
I thought that he could make
me his next target.
I thought he wanted to kill me.
No matter what, I knew that I
had to incapacitate him.
Now it's taken us
several minutes
to go through the events
of that night.
And I'm sure that you've all
formed some kind of opinion
about what happened.
But, right now,
let's put ourselves
in Mr. Sanders' position.
Let's see how much
time Greg had
to save a man's life.
Seconds.
Mere seconds.
What would you have done?
(people murmuring)
Mr. Sanders,
was it your intention
to kill Demitrius James?
No.
I wish he hadn't come at me.
I wish that
he had just run away.
Mr. Sanders...
aren't you leaving
something out?
I don't think so.
You testified at
a criminal trial
earlier that day,
didn't you?
Yes.
A.D.A. Ulrich
must've been pleased
with your testimony.
She took you to dinner
at the Tillerman.
I'm looking at a copy of
her credit card receipt.
How was the sea bass?
And the bottle of Pinot
Grigio Santa
Margherita 2005,
how was that?
NICHOLS:
Your Honor...
I... wasn't on shift,
and I only had...
Mr. Sanders,
I'm sure the jury's wondering,
if you hadn't been drinking
before going to work,
would Demitrius James
still be alive?
Alcohol wasn't...
a factor.
A.D.A. Ulrich insisted
on ordering the wine.
I drank half a glass.
About six ounces.
At my weight, 150,
that would give me
a blood-alcohol content
of .02%.
Even without food,
the alcohol burn-off rate
would be .015% per hour...
meaning that there was
no alcohol in my bloodstream
after 90 minutes, well before
I reported for my shift
and about... seven hours
before the incident.
(people murmuring)
SIDLE:
This is where we found
your aunt's fentanyl, so we
know that you didn't take it.
Which means you've gone
from a suspect...
To a witness.
Now it's up to you
to help us find the real killer.
If you really
cared about Penny,
you'll tell us the
truth about everything.
So this is off the record?
Yeah.
(sighs):
So I ain't going to jail?
Yeah, what do you
want to know?
Who was Penny hiding
her drugs from?
I don't know.
Maybe it was me.
Although I never
would've taken them.
Or maybe you should ask
the guy next-door.
No, man, I'd never take
those things from her.
I buy 'em,
50 bucks a pop.
(man coughs)
Did you know your aunt
was selling her drugs?
Yeah, I had an idea.
I figured it was how she
was supporting her habit.
Which one?
I guess
I should've said "habits."
Um, she loved her liqueur,
and she loved her cigarettes,
but what she really loved
was video poker.
She liked the sound
the coins made when
she hit a jackpot.
She offered me a couple
of bucks a week to keep
the house clean, and...
(laughs):
and she paid me in
nickels and quarters.
Can you think...
of anyone else
that might have known
that those drugs were there?
No. I lived with her
for a couple of months, and...
and she never had anyone over
but me.
I know that look.
You just figured
something out.
This is much better
than dead rock star kitchen.
The whole al fresco thing?
Come on, share.
Please?
Look carefully at
the back of the doll
and at the pillow
on the chair.
There appears to be remnants
of glue on both.
HODGES:
So the doll was originally
glued to the back
of the chair.
I think the killer
expected the victim to die
in this chair.
Well, if that's the case, then
how did the killer expect to...
kill her?
JUDGE:
I understand the jury
has reached a verdict?
WOMAN:
We have, Your Honor.
We, the jury in this inquest,
find the death
of Demitrius James excusable.
(people murmuring)
Well, thank you,
ladies and gentlemen,
Judge Trueblood.
This inquest is concluded.
"Excusa..." No.
See, "excusable" is a lawful act
with no intention to kill.
"Justifiable" means that the
action was the only alternative.
That's what they
should have found.
It's okay.
I think they may
have it right.
Look, look, I got nothing
against Mr. Sanders personally,
but all these inquests
ever really seem to do
is protect the cops.
I'm just trying to speak
for someone who can't
speak for himself.
We should be in
a criminal court...
...about any death
at the hands of law enforcement.
The rights of the
working people of...
Things have a way of
working themselves out.
Mr. Sanders, Mr. Sanders, do you
think the verdict was fair?
Was your killing Demitrius James
excusable?
This kid saved
my damn life.
He is a hero,
a genuine hero.
(birds chirping)
♪ ♪
(humming quietly)
(continues humming)
♪ ♪
(chuckles)
(finger strikes paper)
Penny Garden was poisoned
with nicotine.
Well, that's not exactly
a surprise--
the woman smoked
liked a chimney.
She didn't smoke it.
She drank it.
Liquid nicotine.
Truman Capote used it
as a murder weapon
in his story,
"Hand-Carved Coffins,"
and our killer put it
in Aunt Penny's liqueur bottle.
GRISSOM:
A cigarette introduces
approximately one milligram
of nicotine into the body.
The liqueur contained
over 60.
A dose that massive can induce
severe convulsions...
(coughing)
(clattering)
...and evidently, mess up
a meticulously crafted murder.
That's why the miniature wasn't
at the crime scene.
The killer was compelled
to fix it,
so that it would match
what actually happened.
Liquid nicotine is in a lot
of smoking cessation products.
Yeah. Commonly available
to just about anyone.
Any luck with
the vic's calls?
Kind of. I data-mined
the home phone numbers
of Izzy Delancy
and Penny Garden.
They actually had ten
numbers in common.
Information,
couple of mail-order catalogs,
power company, Moviefone.
There's one other number
which turned out to be
an untraceable
disposable cell phone--
suggests someone who
doesn't want to be found.
SANDERS:
Hey, boss,
unless you need me for
something, I'm gonna take off.
Yeah. Take off that suit, too.
And Greg...
you did a good job.
I'm glad you think so.
(engine starts)
(engine revs)
You've been served.
(tires squealing)
What is it, Archie?
Oh, hey, Gris.
I was just looking
at footage
from the next-door
neighbor's,
the night the package
was delivered.
(tapping keys)
Never underestimate
the Neighborhood Watch.
I don't see a delivery truck.
Well, fortunately for us,
this was a personal delivery...
right to our front door.