RADIO HOST:
Welcome back to
the voice of Las Vegas,
KWMS Radio.
The city remains in mourning,
as we try to make sense
of the murder of Assemblyman
Danilo Zamesca.
After his only son
was gunned down by
a drug dealer,
Zamesca dedicated his life
to public service.
He set his sights
on the drug traffickers
and the drug suppliers.
He believed you get drugs
off the streets by putting
the suppliers out of business.
That was his mission.
His murder's rocked headlines,
uniting Democrats
and Republicans alike,
all of us asking
the same question:
(camera shutter clicking)
What happened out there?
Peg from Sunrise Manor,
you're on.
PEG:
Danilo Zamesca spoke truth
to power and got killed for it.
(camera shutter clicking)
I don't think there's anybody
out there who has the courage
to stand up and take his place.
(camera shutter clicking)
HOST:
Roger from MacDonald Ranch.
ROGER:
If this guy was pure
as the driven snow,
what's he doing out
in the middle of nowhere
with drugs in his car?
Give me a break.
He was dirty,
just like the rest of them.
HOST:
Okay, Roger,
thank you for calling.
Manuel from Henderson,
what do you have to say?
MANUEL:
The whole system
is corrupt, man.
In the next election, we need
a new broom that sweeps clean.
(camera clicking)
Looks like some sort of foam.
Found it next to
the tire impression.
♪ ♪
(computer beeping)
BRASS:
So CSI got a fingerprint
off the drinking straw
we found at the scene.
Guys like Thomas Simon
never get their hands dirty.
No. It was
a very clean print.
And Ballistics matched some
shell casings that we found
at Simon's McMansion
on that raid last year.
Did you find the gun?
No. So Zamesca was trying
to put Simon out of business,
and it cost him his life.
(rock music playing)
Hey.
I have a warrant
for Thomas Simon.
Is he here?
He's the owner, man.
But even I haven't seen him
in, like, three weeks.
Sorry.
McKEEN:
The biggest drug supplier
on the West Coast
kills a public official,
and we can't find him.
I'm just the
undersheriff.
I have one job:
make the sheriff look smart.
You're not helping.
BRASS:
We busted our hump
trying to
find this guy.
Science can only do
so much with a cold trail.
You ever seen a man's face
change into
that kind of a demon?
My eggs are runny.
I couldn't have
been more specific
with the waitress.
You gonna eat those?
Oh, you want my pancakes?
Yeah, sure,
knock yourself out.
Here.
Thank you.
I don't hear a solution.
We could try something
I did in Philly.
It's, um, a little unorthodox.
I only want to know
if it works.
Philly, yes.
Baltimore, no.
Is that why you're in Vegas?
Fifty-fifty.
I can live with those odds.
So, are you waiting
for a drumroll?
It's called "reverse forensics."
WILLOWS: Oh.
We fake a crime scene.
Basically.
How do we get around entrapment?
Well, it's not
entrapment
if you're not enticing anyone
to commit a crime.
The goal is to make Simon
think he's off the hook.
So what's the catch?
Whole thing's a catch.
The hardest part is
stopping leaks.
You've got to be willing
to deceive
the people you work with.
Assuming they can be deceived,
which they can't.
Not your call.
You know,
I can think of nine,
no, ten ways
that this could screw up.
At least.
So don't screw it up.
The first thing we need is
a victim, somebody we own.
And you need a fall guy to
play the role of "killer,"
somebody who's jake with
having his mug shot everywhere.
In Baltimore,
we used a snitch.
So you're going to have
to bring the D.A. into this.
(scoffs)
The D.A.?
That bitch won't like it.
Thanks for breakfast.
(scoffs)
You ever notice
how it's the, uh,
guys with all the money
that never pay?
Sure,
that's how they keep
all the money.
Here, let me get it.
No, I got it. New guy.
Thank you.
You know, Catherine,
if we do our job right
and catch the bad guy, nobody's
going to remember the rest.
I'll remember.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me,
who are you, you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
Hey, Mike.
Do you guys, uh, organize
your files by case number?
In a perfect world.
We hired this, uh,
knucklehead
named Mahoney.
He had this dyslexic
filing system.
So what do you think?
Does the dyslexic atheist
not believe in dog?
What?
Oh... I get it.
Hey.
I need you on
a 411 tonight.
Stolen motor vehicles?
You got to be kidding me.
P.D. recovered 20
stolen motorcycles.
They're at the
Dupont Towing Lot.
Can't you slide it to Days?
BROWN:
Hey, guys.
Take Warrick
with you.
It'll go faster.
Okay.
What'll go faster?
Giddyup.
(meows)
What's happening, Rat?
Boy, you got to
love junkies, huh?
What stamina,
what willpower.
I mean, even the rain
doesn't keep them away.
It doesn't keep the cops away
either, I guess, huh?
You nervous, Rat? Relax,
relax, I'm just here to talk.
Listen, you like
game shows?
Because I got a
deal; listen to this.
First place is
a life-changing experience.
You get a whole new life.
What's second place?
There is no
second place, Rat.
Either way, you don't get
to work the alley anymore.
Screw you.
Screw me?
No, no.
Screw you. Look,
take my deal.
Otherwise, you're
in possession
of a controlled
substance,
and with
your record,
that's a mandatory sentence.
Okay.
If you want information,
just ask me.
Just that I'm...
All right, let's
walk, walk with me.
It's a little
complicated.
You own a gun?
That's K-E-P-P-L-E-R,
Michael Keppler.
Yeah, check it out.
Okay, I got to go.
(hangs up phone)
What's going on?
Um, nothing I
can talk about.
Keep me posted
on the 419.
Greg's going to meet
you at the scene.
Okay.
Ten to one,
it's Internal Affairs.
Got a vibe off Keppler
the minute he blew in.
Always with a suit.
If you got any dirty laundry,
I hope you used bleach.
(box cutter rattles)
(sighs)
(rings bell)
(coughs)
What?
I'm CSI Stokes,
this is Brown.
Where's your paperwork?
We're from the crime lab,
dude.
I still need paperwork.
We're here to process those
stolen motorcycles, man.
I need authorization,
fellas, in writing.
Wh-What if,
what if I promise to come
back and give it to you later?
Okay, cut us
some slack here, man.
You think we really feel
like being down here?
How do you want to handle this?
You want to shoot our way in?
I'd love to bust a cap
in his knee.
Sir, don't make us call
your supervisor.
Now, come on.
(bangs on door)
Come on!
PHILLIPS:
We got third instar maggots.
(exhales)
With this smell, she's been dead
at least 48 hours.
Toys are all here.
Needle, syringe,
tubing, candle, spoon.
It looks like heroin.
CURTIS:
Manager said
he found her like this
when he came by for a visit.
Said they were friends,
but he was a little unclear
of her name.
Monique something or other.
Maybe she was, uh,
working off the rent.
No I.D. on the body.
I'll take a look around for it.
Needle marks
are sclerotic.
Chronic user. Probable O.D.
(camera shutter clicking)
SARA:
Scorpio.
Ruled by Pluto.
Athough since it's not
a planet anymore...
I'm not sure how that works.
Maybe it's a "dwarf" sign.
Like Pluto is, you know,
a "dwarf" planet now.
Car keys.
Cell phone.
No "Mom" or "Dad" listed.
There's a lot of food
for a junkie.
SARA:
Maybe she
had a roommate.
Zamesca was shot three times
with a nine millimeter.
We've got two sets
of shoe impressions.
Two sets of tire
impressions.
A plastic
"Jumbo Cola" cup.
Drugs were found
in Zamesca's car,
in plain view, but
his tox was negative.
Drugs were planted.
Crime scene was a
remote location.
That's in our favor.
Car was a bloody mess.
Our "victim" was kind enough
to donate a pint of his blood.
Did Mr. Holstein
also donate his brain matter
and bone fragments?
Brass recruited him
from Narco, undercover cop.
Opted to keep his brains intact.
Well, without actually
shooting the guy,
this scene is going to be
slightly less than perfect,
but it's just you and me
out there.
No, can't be.
We're going to need a third
person processing the scene
to make it look kosher--
someone who's not in on it.
Well, if we use one of my guys,
they're going to figure it out.
Keep them away from the car.
I'm not used to faking it.
When's the last time
you had to?
Registration's expired.
Want to bet she's not insured?
Monique Carter.
155 North Court, Henderson.
Oh, that's a good
neighborhood.
Well, this used
to be a nice car.
Maybe she traded in
her old lifestyle
to ride the "H" train.
Now, the manager wants
it out of here.
So, I'll have it towed.
It looks like an
impact from a weapon.
Very good observation, David.
Shave the area.
Call Sara.
We may be looking
at a homicide.
Hey, Henry.
Hey.
It's heroin mixed
with cocaine and
methamphetamine.
I was just
going to page you
because these are
the same components
from the drugs you
found in Zamesca's car.
Really?
Should I call Sara?
It's her case.
Henry, I need you to step out
and get a cup of coffee.
Well, I can't leave
my evidence out.
This is not a request.
Firing one.
(fires gun)
Is there a problem?
F.Y.I., Bobby Dawson
is a bit of a control freak.
Doesn't like anyone
in here unsupervised.
So he got one accidental
discharge on his record.
I'm sure he doesn't
want another one.
Unless...
of course, this is an I.A.
investigation,
and, uh, Bobby is his subject.
Interesting
that Grissom,
champion of the little guys,
is on sabbatical.
Interesting, especially
if he planned it that way.
This is my own blood, right?
'Cause it's starting
to drip in my mouth.
It's all yours.
You can get out now,
Detective, and...
I know, don't touch anything.
You got it.
Oh, and there's some
fresh clothes in the
back of the vehicle.
Got any brandy?
Sorry, man.
So, Mike,
you said
reverse forensics
didn't work in
Baltimore. How come?
Smart cops.
You steal cars
before you became a CSI?
Stealing cars gets old fast.
I like more of a challenge.
Note to self.
Okay, you can drop that cup now.
Yeah, I'm not done yet.
He said drop it.
About my new identity, um,
I don't want to
go to Denver.
I think I'd rather
go someplace
where I'd fit in... like Maui.
EZEKIEL:
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
And I want a threesome with
Beyonce and Scarlett Johansson.
Drop the cup and get your
rat ass in the car.
I drop the cup.
Casual.
Excuse me?
Simon.
His soda.
He wasn't expecting trouble.
KEPPLER:
Get out of my car...
walk over to Zamesca.
Didn't come here to kill him...
came to talk.
Hand him the photo.
Then something doesn't
go as planned.
I drop the drink...
grab my gun.
Murder was Plan B.
Plan A was the photograph.
Anti-drug crusader doing lines.
Career buster.
Looks like he
underestimated Zamesca.
He was a hard
man to kill.
Simon panicked.
Which explains why he
left evidence behind this time.
And why he had to disappear.
And why we're
doing this.
I'm going to call it in.
DISPATCHER:
911, is this an emergency?
Yes, someone's
been shot.
I'm a quarter mile west of
Mountain's Edge and Durango.
There's a man bleeding
from the head in his car.
Looks like a gunshot wound,
but I didn't see a gun.
He's dead for sure.
Sir, may I have your name?
(phone beeps off)
CONTROL:
419, possible 420,
quarter mile west
of Mountain's Edge and Durango.
Possible man down,
gunshot wound to the head.
2-0cean-2, 2-0cean-34,
please respond.
Show time.
Control, this is 2-Zero-3,
Charlie-Captain-Brass.
I am with Charlie-Zero-4-Willows
and Charlie-Zero-9-Keppler.
We're around the corner.
Our E.T.A. is five minutes.
We'll be responding also.
DR. ROBBINS:
C.O.D. was blunt force trauma
to the right temporal region.
(phone rings)
Wound's inconsistent
with a fall.
(phone ringing)
You fall into something,
say a coffee table, wound's
always deeper on one end.
(phone ringing)
Depth here is uniform.
(yelling):
Would somone please
answer that phone?
Sorry. Tox confirms
high level of heroin,
cocaine, methamphetamine
in her system.
I opened up her arm under
a fresh needle mark,
drew out one milliliter
of dark liquid.
The drugs were puddled.
Means they
didn't circulate
in her bloodstream.
Injection was postmortem.
Dead girls don't shoot up.
PHILLIPS:
Sorry.
Catherine needs to speak to you.
Says it's urgent.
Right.
ROBBINS:
I'm in the middle of an autopsy,
Catherine.
Sorry. I'm at a 420.
Similar M.O.to Zamesca.
Press is all over us.
I need permission to get
the body out of here ASAP.
That's fine. Just photograph
and diagram it
before transporting.
Of course. Now,
which mortuary's on call?
Kentworth.
You have that number?
I'll take care of it.
Thanks, Doc.
NICK:
This is so lame.
How much do you want to bet half
the prints come back to the cops
who recovered these bikes.
They never wear gloves.
Brown.
Hey, Cath.
We'll see you there.
Well, in that case...
I'll see you there.
Boy, she has got it
in for me today.
Well, giddyup.
(laughs)
WARRICK:
CSI coming through.
Thank you.
Where's the body?
Called the morticians
to get it out of here.
Gunshot victim.
Got I.D.?
Ezekiel Holstein.
Local.
Brass is running him now.
Hey, Cath, didn't you find
Zamesca near here?
Yeah.
Got the "Jumbo" cup.
Shoe and tire
impressions.
Shot in his car.
Think Simon's coming out
of hiding?
Or it's a copycat.
Want me to take
the backseat?
No, um,
take the perimeter,
get started on a diagram.
Okay, Sarge.
Not my first barbecue.
Thanks, Warrick.
REPORTER:
Undersheriff McKeen,
is this related
to the Zamesca murder?
We're in the process
of conducting
an investigation,
so I don't have
all the facts.
But there does appear
to be some similarities
to Assemblyman Zamesca's murder.
UNDERSHERIFF MCKEEN:
Uh, I have no further
comments at this time.
BRASS:
Ezekiel Holstein.
Date of birth: 07-14-72.
Do a records check.
Oh, and, uh,
contact Narco.
May be drug-related.
I really feel good
about this.
APARTMENT MANAGER:
Monique's dead body
means I got to get
the carpet cleaned.
You said
the scene was clear,
I called
the cleaning service.
It's a good way
to cover your tracks.
Like I said,
she'd been shacked up
with some guy.
Can you describe him?
Average-looking,
white dude.
I only saw him
from a distance.
He was driving
her car.
Look, she was a nice,
smart lady.
She helped me get out of a jam
with my insurance company.
I know she liked
the "candy",
but she did not deserve
to go out that way.
SANDERS:
I ran Monique
Carter's phone
records.
Someone made a dozen calls
from her cell yesterday.
She was dead yesterday.
Yeah, and we recovered
her phone
from her apartment,
so someone was yakking
while she was lying dead
on the floor dead.
Let's run those numbers.
HODGES:
Hey, how's the King
of property crimes?
My socks keep disappearing
in the dryer.
You want to
tackle that one?
What are you doing with the cup
from my Zamesca scene?
That's not your cup.
It's from Catherine
and Warrick's 420.
They found the same kind
of cup at their scene?
Same everything.
Watch the news lately?
Hey, what about my socks?
They're not gonna
find themselves.
Uh, excuse me.
Uh, what are you doing?
Hi, Mike Keppler.
Sorry, didn't get a chance
to introduce myself
before I, uh, invaded your lab.
Uh, well, can I help you
with something?
Yeah, I'm looking for the
ballistics on Holstein.
Uh, yeah, just about
to run them.
Great.
Mind if I sit in?
Bullet that killed
Holstein was a nine-mill,
same caliber as Zamesca,
but no match.
Killer could have
used a different gun.
Thanks, Bobby.
See you later.
Hey, Doc.
Hey, Nick.
Want you to catch me up
with Catherine and Warrick.
I haven't seen them.
Where's the body
from their 420?
Uh, it hasn't come in yet.
It was a mortuary pickup.
Who's this?
It's Monique Carter.
Heroin addict, got
whacked on the head.
She involved
with Catherine's 420?
If she was, nobody told me.
Will you send me a photo
of this tattoo?
And when the body comes in
at the mortuary,
will you give me a call?
I'll get right on it.
Seat's been pushed
all the way back.
Manager said he saw
a guy driving.
She was a lawyer.
Suspended for failure
to pay her
Bar Association dues.
Lose all that to drugs,
you gotta be in a lot of pain.
Or you think you're too smart
to get addicted.
You guys seen
Catherine around?
She's not answering
her cell phone.
Mm-mm.
Anything from your scene
link back to Zamesca?
No. Why?
Because I think
your d.b.'s
the unidentified woman
in the photo I found.
Really?
And, excuse me,
we found this same type
of material
at the Zamesca scene.
If we can match it
back to this car...
You could place the car
at the scene.
And Simon
behind the wheel.
Got a partial print
off the straw
from the soda cup.
AFIS hit Edwin Dennison,
aka "Rat".
Small-time drug dealer
with a big-time rap sheet.
Well, I'll get Brass
to bring him in, huh?
Nice work.
I just connected Sara's vic
to Simon.
Yeah, you might want
to hear this.
BROWN:
What's the connection?
Well, I think,
that Simon was driving her BMW
to meet Zamesca.
Nick, we got a print
from the Holstein case.
Street dealer.
We're bringing him in now.
And he looks dirty
for Zamesca, too.
Excuse me.
I grew up in this town.
I know about
playing the odds.
You are gambling
with my team.
We talked about
the risk going in.
It's not like we
can quit now.
I'm not quitting.
But I don't like it.
And I hate lying
to my guys.
(reporters clamoring)
REPORTER:
Mr. Dennison, could
we have a comment?
Is this relating
to the...
Good afternoon.
The Las Vegas
Police Department
has successfully apprehended
a suspect, one Edwin Dennison,
who's confessed
of multiple homicides,
including that
of Assemblyman Danilo Zamesca.
Mr. Dennison admitted
to luring Mr. Zamesca
to a remote location,
while seeking his help
to escape the drug trade.
When Mr. Zamesca encouraged him
to surrender to police,
Mr. Dennison shot him.
He later shot Mr. Holstein
during a dispute
over a drug deal.
I'd like to say
how very proud I am
of the swift and efficient work
done that my department has done
in tracking down
and apprehending
this dangerous criminal...
You know that Dawson guy
gets kind of uptight
when people touch his stuff.
Well, the Holstein scene
bullet was fired
from the same gun that you found
in Rat's car.
(fires gun)
Done deal.
I'm not so sure.
If this bullet went through
the window
and a guy's head...
it would have pieces of glass
and bits of bone in it.
This hollow point's clean.
There's no sand-blasted effect.
Hmm.
The DNA sample yet,
might have been
cleaned already.
There's still blood on it.
I see your point.
Maybe autopsy will show
something.
Hey, Nick.
I can't find the evidence
in the Holstein case.
What do you want it for?
Because that guy who confessed
to killing Zamesca didn't do it.
Sheriff's jumping the gun.
We have evidence
and a confession.
You can't just come in here
and take over my case.
Is there a reason you don't want
me to see that file, Catherine?
Nick, as your supervisor,
I'm ordering you to back off.
Thanks.
Uh, it's freezing.
Why are we having
a meeting outside?
'Cause Catherine
and Keppler are in there.
What, have you guys been
listening to Hodges?
No, and this isn't
about Keppler being I.A. anyway.
This is about Catherine having
a false confession
and standing by it.
You'd better be able
to back that one up, man.
Zamesca knew Sara
and Greg's vic.
He's dead, she's dead,
same drugs are found
at both scenes,
and then...
those same drugs showed up
at your crime scene?
Could have come
from the same supplier.
We see that
all the time.
I don't think
it's a coincidence.
You know, Catherine...
Catherine ordered Henry
to step out of his lab
without putting drug
evidence away.
Why would she do that?
I did see Keppler checking out
Zamesca's file yesterday.
I didn't think anything strange
about it then,
but now...
Okay, so...
maybe there is
an I.A. investigation
I can't find
the Holstein evidence.
What?
Catherine
put it in a temporary locker.
Why didn't she put it
where it belongs?
The Holstein bullet was
a little bit too clean,
and Keppler didn't seem
at all concerned about it.
He said that we would see
at autopsy.
Well, it's kind of hard
to have an autopsy
when you don't
have a body, man.
I talked to Doc Robbins, he's
still trying to track it down.
And the mortuary has no record
of Catherine's phone
call whatsoever.
Do we have access to any
of the Holstein evidence?
We got the car.
Catherine sent it
to the impound.
Well, at least we
know where it is.
All right, that's it, we're
a team now, the four of us.
We can't trust Catherine
and we can't trust Keppler.
I'm serious.
I'm gonna run with this one.
I'll run with you.
You?
I'm in.
Hey. Hey, you!
Try to stop me and I'll
have you put in jail.
(objects rattling)
(phone dialing)
Brown.
Hey, Warrick, it's Nick.
When is the last time you found
high-velocity exit spatter
with no brain and no bone?
Never.
Got the evidence yet?
(knocking)
You know what? Sara's here.
And she has the key.
Got to go.
You know...
I really hate
deceiving people
because, eventually,
you get what you give.
I hate being deceived.
Yes.
All right.
(slams box)
Anything I collected, we ignore.
♪ ♪
You running your own samples?
Smart, considering
that you're
the odds-on favorite
in the I.A. pool.
There's a pool now?
Oh, yeah.
Who's number two?
That would be me.
Number three?
Grissom.
How's it going
in here?
This glass wasn't shot out.
Take a look at that.
Spark plug?
The only mark
a spark plug makes
is a nick at the center.
Now, who would know about that?
Crooks.
And cops.
And, hey, get this.
The blood found
in Holstein's car
had high levels
of EDTA.
Anti-coagulant.
Means the blood didn't come from
his head; it came from his arm.
That means
this crime scene was staged.
Well, if Keppler is I.A.,
Catherine can't tell us anything
if she wanted to.
Yeah, if this is all I.A.
BS, then why would they
play it out in the press?
I should talk to Brass.
Maybe he could shed
some light.
(speaking inaudibly)
Let's roll.
(sirens blaring)
(up-tempo electronic music
playing)
OFFICER (over radio):
I got a 20 on Simon,
right here.
(gun cocks)
BRASS:
Thomas Simon,
you're under arrest!
You two--
step over there.
(record scratches, music stops)
Is there a problem, Detective?
A problem?
We're charging you
with the murder
of Danilo Zamesca.
You already got a guy
for that murder.
I saw it on the news.
Well, it's good to meet
an informed citizen.
Nine-millimeter.
Get him out of here.
(indistinct chatter
inside)
WOMAN:
Even your own district attorney
said she wasn't aware.
MAN:
There's no way you'll get a jury
to believe
this evidence wasn't fabricated.
(Brass sighs)
Which one of you
screwed this up?
I'm looking at him.
You dropped
the ball, man.
You never cleared this operation
with the D.A.,
and now, she says she can't tell
fact from fiction.
She's not going to file charges
against Simon.
She's a tight-ass--
I told her what I thought
she needed to know.
BRASS:
Did you hear what I said?
Now, what are you going
to tell the sheriff?
It's called reverse forensics.
Reverse forensics?
Simon had to believe it
when he saw it on the news.
He was a fugitive.
The only way to get him
to show his face was
to make him think
he was off the hook.
And your only option was
to fabricate evidence
and make me process it?
How could you think
that we wouldn't figure it out?
It's kind of what we do.
I understand how you all feel.
I am sorry.
I did not have a choice.
We trust you
with our lives,
Catherine.
You could have trusted us
with this.
Sara?
If I have something to say
to you, Catherine,
I'm gonna say it in private.
No offense.
WILLOWS:
Okay, look.
We can still
get Simon.
He only walked on Zamesca.
He drove Monique Carter's
vehicle out into the desert.
Nick's established that.
Did he kill her, too?
SANDERS:
Three calls were made
from Monique's cell phone
to Simon's strip club
after she died.
There's another
half a dozen calls
to Hugh Griffin,
Bud Small, Frank Townsend.
All known associates.
He was using her
phone to do business,
thinking it was safe.
Oh, yeah, the last call
was made to his wife's cell.
What hasn't been cleaned?
SIDLE:
Furniture.
If Simon was hiding out
here for a couple of weeks,
he had to eat, sleep
and use the bathroom.
So, what did the
cleaners miss?
There used to be a pillow here.
Maybe...
he slept on the couch.
I'm going to
pull some hair
'cause you never know.
STOKES:
We'd have to get
a court order
to compel a DNA
sample from Simon.
That takes time.
Brass can only stall
this guy's release for a
couple hours, you know.
Yeah, it's going to take days
to sort through these.
(sighs)
Sara.
It's a pullout.
♪ ♪
(woman yelling)
RADIO HOST:
Welcome back to the voice
of Las Vegas, KWMS radio.
Today, Thomas Simon,
alleged drug kingpin,
was charged with the slaying of
former attorney Monique Carter.
Ms. Carter and Assemblyman
Zamesca were classmates
in law school,
and police are continuing
to investigate the link
between the two crimes.
So I dig up a ghost.
I know he has a son
who was killed
by drug dealers,
she's being killed
by drugs.
He's got a savior complex,
so I use her to lure him
out into the desert.
It's why I drive her car.
So he'll recognize it,
feel safe.
You are aware that you talk
about the killer
in the first person?
That's the point, isn't it?
Clouds my judgment to identify
with the victims.
Our job is
to catch killers.
(sighs)
Guess it helps me
to think like one.
You want to, uh, get
a drink or something?
Nah.
No, I'm, I'm tired.
I'm going home.
Nick.
Nick!
Let it go, man.
Tonight we're talking about the
anti-drug legislation
sponsored by the late Assemblyman
Danilo Zamesca.
It was passed into law today
by the Nevada State Legislature.
Tony from Seven Hills,
you're on the air.