(water running)
(sports announcer talking
on radio)
(sports announcer continues)
Mommy, up.
Up, Mommy, up.
Not now, baby, Mommy's busy.
Go find Daddy.
Aah...
Honey, I cannot find
my navy suit.
Oh, I'm sorry, shoot.
I meant to get it this morning,
but Henry was doing
his ear-itchy thing,
so I took him to Dr. Neilsen.
I'll get it
first thing tomorrow.
Oh, I have an early meeting,
sweetie.
So go get it.
Oh... all right.
Daddy, no leave.
Aw... daddy no leave.
(giggling)
You give him a bath, I'll go.
DISC JOCKEY:
Welcome to LVRP, Rat Pack Radio.
Here's an oldie but a goodie
by two salty dogs
of stage and screen,
Bobby Darin and Johnny Mercer.
(singing along with radio)
♪ ♪
(song continues)
(song continues over car radio)
(turns off car)
(humming)
(car alarm beeps)
(indistinct police radio
transmission)
Bad day when you
can't even run
a simple errand.
Everybody's got
dirty laundry.
Sometimes
it gets you killed.
What would she have done
if she didn't have
a second story?
Every death has at
least two stories.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
Two GSWs to the chest.
Rigor hasn't set.
Probably been dead
less than four hours.
Thanks, David.
Mr. Chen works here
alone with his wife,
and English is not
their first language.
I'm not even
real sure
that it's their second,
but what I did gather
is that the steam machines
are very noisy,
so neither one of them
really heard anything.
Mr. Chen
found the body when
he was closing up around 9:00.
Said she's a regular customer.
Well, I got a phone and keys,
but no purse.
Mugging?
Take the purse, leave the Lexus?
Yeah, that's not real savvy,
is it?
Hmm.
Car's been keyed.
Registered to a
Dr. Gary Sinclair.
Yeah, that's gonna probably
be the husband.
"Gary Home"
has called her six times
in the last hour.
Wife and mother.
I'll check the trash cans
for the complex,
see if I can find her purse.
Maybe they dumped
what they couldn't liquidate.
Well, she obviously doesn't have
any kids.
Place is like a museum.
This chick hung out
with some big wigs.
GRISSOM:
She was a big wig.
Jill Case,
Editor-in-Chief
of the Las Vegas Globe.
She was a wunderkind.
One of the youngest women
in history to run a newspaper.
Well, I've been all
around the house, no
sign of a forced entry.
Consistent with suicide.
So is this.
You can't even use a whole sheet
of paper for your suicide note?
Well, I don't know,
maybe if you feel
like you don't deserve
to take up space on the planet,
you don't deserve
a whole piece of paper.
BROWN:
She obviously ate
at Joie de Vive.
It's the only place
that still serves old school
swan doggie bags.
BRASS:
Yeah, dressed
in a fancy outfit,
having a fancy meal.
If you're planning
on killing yourself,
why do you bring home
a doggie bag?
It's human nature.
We continue
to perform
the routine motions of our life
until the moment of our death.
♪ ♪
DNA's been sent out,
but this is one case
where I don't need
to wait for results.
Identical twins?
You got to be kidding me.
They're even wearing
the same toenail polish.
And both...
wore the same watch, too.
Oh, it's just too much.
Well...
(sighs):
...eight year olds
dressing alike
I kind of get,
but grown women? That's weird.
Some people like it.
I'm a twin.
Really?
Well, I was.
My twin died in utero.
My mother didn't tell me
about it until I was an adult.
When I decided
to become a coroner,
she blamed herself.
She said it was
because I'd spent so many days
living next to a dead body.
Well, speaking of
dead bodies, uh...
Right.
Right. Jill has petechia
around the eyes,
bruising around the neck,
and a broken clavicle.
All consistent
with a hanging.
And I extracted these
from Amanda.
One went straight
to the heart.
The other penetrated
the right lung.
Sharp shooter or close range.
Don't tell me they died
at the same moment.
Not quite.
Amanda was a couple hours
ahead of her sister.
(knocking)
Our two cases have become one.
Could still be two cases.
What happened to Mr.
No-Such-Thing-As-Coincidence?
Simplest hypothesis is
usually the correct one.
If you hear hooves,
think horses not zebras.
What would the horses
be in this case?
Murder/suicide.
Jill killed
Amanda.
Felt guilty, then
killed herself.
And, uh, what do you got
to support that?
Did you notice any
photos of Amanda
or her family in Jill's house?
No.
Right.
And I looked through
Amanda's phone book,
Jill was not even in it.
Well, maybe she had
her number memorized.
Brass spoke with
Jill's attorney
for next of kin.
None existed.
She's leaving a small
fortune to various charities.
It just sounds to me
like estrangement.
Okay, even
if that's not
the exact way
it went down,
I'll bet you a dollar
that the twins
deaths are related.
Two women found dead
on opposite sides of town.
If they didn't look alike,
would you still link them?
If they're relatives, yes.
Sisters, husband and wife,
father and son.
Okay.
Okay, what?
I'll take the bet.
I must've called
her ten times,
then after about an hour
I got so worried.
Did your wife have any enemies?
Anyone she was fighting with?
No, she was a good wife,
great mother.
There's no one...
HENRY:
Home, Daddy,
home.
Okay, buddy.
Can you-- hey, you know what?
Come over here.
Can you come over here
and draw your butterfly
that you draw?
What was her relationship
like with Jill?
Jill who?
Her twin sister, Jill Case.
Amanda didn't have a sister.
DNA tells us otherwise.
My wife was an only child.
Sh-she was adopted, but...
Is it possible that...
your wife knew she had
a twin, but she hadn't
told you?
Well, I'd like to think no.
That we told
each other everything.
But that's not...
True?
A marriage.
Married, Detective?
No.
Something weird happens
between two people
who know each other for years,
see each other every day.
Every night I drive home
from the hospital
and I think of 12 things
I want to tell Amanda.
And then I get home
and, uh... she's cooking.
And we read stories
to Henry and then...
the phone rings, so I--
you know, you say,
"Oh, I'll just tell her
tomorrow. Tomorrow."
(sniffs)
I'd like to meet her.
Jill.
I'm sorry that's...
that's not possible.
We found them both...
last night.
What happened?
Right now...
we don't know.
HENRY:
It's okay, Daddy.
Let's go home
and see Mommy.
Okay.
(computer beeps)
Hey. I got your text.
What's up?
Sing it, dude. This is huge.
Oh...
♪ Oh, Mandy ♪
♪ Oh, you came and you... ♪
(clears throat)
(louder):
♪ Oh, Mandy ♪
♪ Well, you came and you gave ♪
♪ Without taking ♪
♪ But I sent you away... ♪
(holds note)
♪ Oh, Mandy. ♪
Okay. I got a hit off of that
envelope you found
in Amanda's purse.
It's a Dora Pomerantz.
Oh, that would make sense.
The letter was
signed "Dora."
Do you wanna know why
she's in the system?
Mrs. Pomerantz?
Who wants to know?
Detective Curtis
and CSI Nick Stokes.
Hi.
We just need to ask
you a few questions.
About what?
Your twins.
That was a very
long time ago.
We were just curious
about the circumstances
under which they were adopted.
I was 18 years old
when I got pregnant.
Charlie said he'd stay with me.
Then he got drafted to Vietnam.
Came home six months later...
in a box.
These two chirping birds.
"Waa, waa, waa."
I couldn't get
them to stop.
I couldn't take it.
So one day I just...
Boop... snapped.
That was it. No more babies.
I spent ten years
in a state facility, you know?
We were aware.
How have you
been since?
Oh... fine.
A smart doctor put me
in touch with an equine
assisted
therapy program.
Saved my life.
Horses don't have judgments.
They have needs. Meet the
needs, the horse is happy.
Helped retrain my brain.
Healthy enough to get back
in touch with your daughters?
Oh, no. Uh...
not recommended.
Sometimes you just
can't go back.
Is that why you wrote
Amanda this letter saying,
"Please do not ever
contact me again?"
Who's Amanda?
One of your daughters.
We keep envelopes loose
in a desk drawer.
I must've touched it
before she sent it.
Who?
The handwriting, it's Tiffany's.
I'm sorry. Who's Tiffany?
I had no idea my mom
had given up a kid.
But I did know
that there was no way
she could handle
dealing with it.
So... you always go
through your mom's mail?
Yeah. My dad and I
have a system.
We screen all her mail.
Why's that?
She's got
this problem.
Any time a children's charity
solicitation comes,
she donates
and not just a little.
Half my college fund was gone
before we realized
what was going on.
So you thought Amanda
had her hand out?
Wasn't worth the risk.
The anti-depressants
and the horses help,
but my mom's barely hanging on.
And I only have
a year left before
I go to college.
I just need her
to hang on one more year.
So, I sent the polite response
and hoped it was over.
Did Jill ever try
to contact your mom?
Who's Jill?
SIMMS:
So I got bad news
and weird news.
Which would you
like to hear first?
Bad.
Bad news:
I got nothing from
the blue stocking
that was found in the trash.
Weird news: I tested
the red lipstick
on Gary Sinclair's collar
and I got DNA, but
it wasn't his wife's.
Well, based on
the contents of her
purse, she's more
the lip balm type.
You know I like to be thorough,
so... I ran it through CODIS
and I actually got a hit:
Natal Peled.
She's in the system
from a rape charge in L.A.
They don't put victim's
DNA in the database.
No, they don't.
Yeah, I had to know,
so I called a friend of mine
at L.A. Sheriff's Department,
and apparently, Natal was
a nurse at a Hollywood hospital.
And she went to the annual
Christmas party,
she fed this doctor a bunch
of cocktails,
slipped him a Viagra,
and then took him
up to a hotel room.
And rumor has it,
it was in order to have
unprotected, you know...
baby-making sex.
So he pressed charges,
she was arrested,
and then they settled
out of court.
And now Natal's a nurse
at our very own Dessert Palm.
With Amanda's husband,
Dr. Gary Sinclair.
Doctors have a name
for what Natal is.
What she is?
A woman who trolls
hospitals looking
to land themselves a doctor.
Call them bedpans:
shiny, full of crap,
and... best when dumped.
NATAL:
Of course we slept together.
Who wouldn't want
to get with this?
Of course he's
gonna deny it
because of that
little wife of his.
So you met his wife, Amanda?
Please. Yes, I've met her.
Always coming
by the hospital,
check up on him.
Talk about paranoid.
Hey, with you around...
sounds like she had
pretty good reason.
Mr. Stokes...
men are like tigers--
if you can't tame them,
you must let
them roam free.
I go now, yeah?
Yes. It seems that
the paint on the Sabra's key
is consistent
with Lexus factory issue.
Color's Galactic Grey
Mica IE9.
Same as Amanda's.
So... crazy chick
keys the wife's car.
Is it gateway violence
that led to murder,
or just another coincidence
like everything else
in this case?
I almost keyed
a car once.
You what?
I know, but, in the
end, I couldn't go
through with it.
So I peed on the
door handles instead.
So they'd freeze up
and can't get them open?
No. It was San Diego.
Over a girl?
Over a "B."
Professor gave me
one on my term paper.
I felt I deserved an "A".
So she definitely
keyed the car,
and may or may not have
been doing the husband.
I'm going with yes.
Ballistics came back on the
bullets that killed Amanda.
There's only one gun with a
six right polygonal barrel
that comes in a .41 caliber:
A Baby Eagle--
Israeli military issue.
Israeli guns
are really hard to find.
Unless you served in the
Israeli army like Natal.
Okay. Okay, I certainly
wouldn't put it past her,
but what about the husband?
Classic "he said, she said."
They're either acting
in cahoots, trying to
confuse us, or Natal
is acting on her own,
thinking that the wife
is the obstacle
standing between them.
Nothing quite says
"I love you" like,
"I killed your wife
so we can be together."
Sir, we have a warrant
to search the premises,
and we need you
to come down to the station.
If you can't make arrangements
for your child,
we have a Child Services
Advocate who can take him.
This is ridiculous.
I've been nothing
but cooperative.
You harass me at
my place of work.
You harass me at my home.
Now you want
to take my kid away?
Sir, are you resisting?
I didn't kill my wife.
I was giving my son a bath.
I couldn't have done it.
Can I at least put my shoes on?
(car alarm chirps)
(song plays on radio)
(engine starts)
What have you got?
A smoking gun.
You're not going
to like the answer.
The DNA on the cigarette
butts doesn't match Natal.
Come on.
You can't tell me we're back
to square one on this deal.
Well, we're not.
DNA was female,
so I ran it against Amanda,
thinking, I don't know,
maybe she takes super-secret
cigarette breaks.
And it wasn't a match, but they
do have seven loci in common.
So, is there
another sister maybe?
Tiffany.
I'm confused.
This is 'cause I was smoking?
Well, no, smoking
is bad for you,
but, no, this is really more
about where you were smoking.
I'm an only child who
lives on a horse farm
in the middle
of nowhere
with a horse-
whispering mother
and a dad who works all
the time to avoid her.
When Amanda's
letter came...
I was so excited
at the idea of
having a sister.
I was jumping
out of my skin.
So I told my mom I
joined cheerleading.
And after school,
I would...
You'd what?
It started where I
would just drive by.
And then it escalated?
Well...
once, I saw her
in the yard,
playing with
her little boy.
So I started
parking out front.
Hoping to see
her again.
Basically, I would
just sit there,
imagining her in my life.
She'd make me tea.
And we'd go over
my college applications
and talk about boys.
It was like a TV commercial.
And then what?
Did your...
curiosity...
become an obsession?
Oh, my God.
No.
I could barely
get up the courage
to introduce myself.
That's why I'd just
sit there smoking.
And then my stomach would hurt,
so I would just drive home.
And now, I'll never
get the chance.
♪ ♪
(camera shutter clicking)
Hey, Grissom said
you might need some help.
What?
I don't know, you don't look
like you've been
put through the ringer.
Well, I guess
the inquest was the easy part.
Now the kid's family
wants to sue me.
Know any good lawyers?
I hate lawyers.
Want to take the bathroom?
Sure.
I found her naughty drawer.
My favorite part
of any bedroom search.
I don't believe
these girls anymore.
Looks like someone's been
elevated to drawer status.
Well, apparently,
love can't cure all that ails.
Alprazolam, clonazepam,
diazepam and sertraline--
all in her medicine cabinet.
Well, I said dude had a drawer,
I didn't say it was love.
HOFFMAN:
She had OCD-related depression,
which is
very deceiving
because the sufferers
are high functioning.
It's not your usual, you know,
"lie on the couch
and listen to the Beatles"
kind of depression.
Did she ever talk about family?
You know,
when a patient dies,
the doctor-patient
confidentiality clause is void.
But I'm just sort of feeling
a little uncomfortable.
Do I have to...
call a lawyer?
It's entirely your choice.
We can subpoena
her records,
or you and I can talk.
Okay.
All she would say was
that she didn't get along
with her parents,
and that, um, you know,
relationships in general
were difficult.
I mean,
her condition made her
excel professionally
but flop personally.
We, uh, checked
her records.
She was adopted as an infant.
Her parents never told her.
Huh.
Well, that explains her
abandonment-attachment issues,
and why she always felt like
a square peg in a round family.
Did you believe
she was suicidal?
Off the record, no, I don't.
I don't think
she was suicidal, I thought,
I actually thought
she was getting better.
So then how does
an attractive, successful
36-year-old woman hang herself
from her own balcony?
'Cause the choice was there.
At the end of the day, when
an obsessive brain is presented
with a choice,
it just, sometimes,
it just can't shut off
the clatter of the idea
until it sees it through
to conclusion.
The idea found its way in.
ROBBINS:
It wasn't suicide.
These bruises developed
postmortem.
Two on the front,
eight on the back.
Strangulation.
Murder.
(beep)
WOMAN:
No, she missed the morning news
meeting, all the section editors
are biting my head off.
Look, I don't have
a straight answer for you.
No, I've called,
I've e-mailed, I've texted.
She'd have to be lying dead in
a ditch not to answer her phone.
I know. Bye.
Can I help you?
I'm Detective Jim Brass,
Las Vegas Police.
This is Warrick Brown
from the Crime Lab.
We have a warrant to
search Jill Case's office.
Okay, is she in
some kind of trouble?
Well, it wasn't
a ditch.
Oh, my God.
I...
God.
What's going on?
Back off. Get away.
All of you, go! Go!
Look, you can't drop a hot one
in a room full of vultures.
They smell blood.
Half of them were
wanting to pry her ass
out of that chair for months.
BRASS:
I'll need a list of all
the employees who work
for the paper--
can you provide that?
I don't have access
to that kind of information.
You're gonna have to go
down to Human Resources.
Human Resources.
Okay.
You're on your own.
I'll be taking a look
inside her office, okay?
Did Jill have a computer?
Yeah, her laptop, of course.
It was like an extra limb.
What's with the locked drawer?
That was a new thing.
She's always been neurotic,
but lately she's been secretive,
like sneaky-- rolling
her own calls,
making her own appointments,
talking with editors
from other newspapers.
Honestly, I just thought
she was looking for another job.
Did you ever
try to open this drawer?
Are you kidding?
She had the only key,
and protecting her privacy
was how I kept my job.
JOHNSON:
Because Amanda's murder
is still unsolved,
I cross-checked the
twins' address books.
Now, they have
no contacts in common, but...
there are a couple
freaky things.
So Amanda was set
to pick up dry cleaning
in the morning,
but it looks as though
she had a sick child,
so she went
at night instead.
JOHNSON:
Right.
And if she'd gone earlier
than she was supposed to,
she might've
run into Jill,
who was scheduled
to pick up
her dry cleaning at
8:30 in the morning.
But it gets better.
Based on receipts
from Amanda's planner
and Quicken listings
from Jill's Treo,
they used the
same dry cleaner,
same car dealership,
they both had a weakness
for the same frozen yogurt
and blended mochas,
and in two weeks,
Jill was scheduled to teach
a university extension class
in photography.
Guess who was signed
up to take the class?
Amanda.
Huh.
They would've finally met.
WILLOWS:
So having the same
toe nail polish
and watch made sense
when we thought they knew
each other, but now?
I mean, they even have almost
the same handwriting.
GRISSOM:
Well, people's
first explanation
with twins is always
parapsychology,
but the truth is,
there's a lot of biological
encoding at work.
I mean, if you have
the same musculature
and bone structure in your hand,
the chance of writing the same
is not out of the question.
If beauty is in the eye
of the beholder,
and you both see
with the same eyes
or taste with the same tongue...
Well, I don't know
whose eyes she was using
for this guy.
Jill was scheduled to have
dinner at Joie de Vive
on the night she died.
So Warrick called over and
got the surveillance footage.
I don't have an ID yet.
I do.
Her relationship with me was the
most intimate she's ever had.
I actually felt like
we were making progress.
Until the murder.
What are you talking about?
She committed suicide.
Did I tell you that?
What are--
What are you suggesting,
that I murdered my own patient?
Let me run down
the sequence of events.
So you took your
"girlfriend" out to dinner.
Then you brought her home for a
little tie me up, tie me down.
But things get wonky
and in the throes of passion,
you remembered, "Wait a minute,
she's a patient.
Uh-oh."
So she had a history
of depression.
So you used that knowledge
to cover it up.
Well, we did go to dinner
that night,
but afterwards
I dropped her off.
Because she said
she had to work to do.
I didn't even go inside,
so I don't even understand
your question.
Are you saying
the two of you
never had rough sex?
Now, be careful here, doctor.
Yeah, It's true that,
in the past, we engaged
in some, you know,
some, uh, role playing sex games
to help get her comfortable,
but...
But what?
She was the "S." I was the "M."
Hey, um...
you know, how we thought that
the shrink was a slam dunk
for Jill's
strangulation-hanging-combo?
Yeah.
Well, I ran his DNA
against the epithelials
we found on the leash.
And the epithelials are
male, but they're not his.
Thanks.
News on our case...
The shrink
might not have done it?
How did you know?
Because Archie
found us another
strong suspect.
You know,
that flash drive
that I found in the locked
drawer in Jill Case's office,
I thought it was
just a bunch of
photos but it turns out
there was a little bit more
than meets the eye.
You mean the flash drive
was a Transformer?
No.
Well,
the pictures kind of were.
Check it out.
Look familiar?
This got bought
by the A.P.
It was on the front page
of the Las Vegas Globe.
It won a Pulitzer.
It was everywhere.
Okay. So what?
These are Jake Lenoir's
photographs taken
in Iraq last summer.
Watch this.
The front page news
was actually a composite?
Well, it's a...
essentially an art project.
And Jill printed it.
I assume she didn't realize
it until it was too late.
And before she died,
she was trying to figure out
how to handle it.
The only thing standing
between Jake
and the rest
of his career
was the truth.
And Jill Case.
Well, must be fun to be you.
Got a job that
takes you around the world,
get to meet some great girls,
even win some awards.
So why would an
adrenaline junkie
like you, waste his time
with Photoshopping?
Let me tell you something
that the, um... newspapers,
TV stations
don't want to hear.
There's nothing over there
to photograph.
Insurgents?
They fire off their
outdated weapons,
then run the other way.
When we do midnight raids
in the villages,
you know what
the people tell us?
"AliBaba not here."
We are fighting
a fictional character.
And you got thousands
of soldiers over there,
kids, 18 years old,
pumped up on testosterone,
full of nicotine,
and caffeine, waiting for
something to bloody well happen.
And you know what?
You pray for a roadside bomb
because it feels like action.
But you can't photograph
the taste of gasoline.
It just looks like smoke.
So one day, yeah,
I'm screwing around
on my computer.
Couple of soldiers come by,
took a look at what I'm doing.
You know what they say?
They say, "Yeah, yeah,
that's our war.
That's what it's like
waiting and bodyhauling."
So I had it. I had
the image that
said it all.
So yes, I used a lie
to tell the truth.
Well, thanks for the insight.
But I'm looking for
another kind of confession.
I'm here to bust you
for the murder of Jill Case.
What?
Come on, she was hip
to your, uh, you know
cut and paste scheme and
she was going to blow
the whistle on you.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, well, I heard
she committed suicide and look--
Oh, is that
what you heard?
Yeah.
Me and her,
we-we had a history, okay.
We dated.
But if she felt like
outing me for this
all I had to do was accuse her
of sexual harassment
and we both go down.
Maybe ethical journalism was
worth the price for her.
Doubtful.
Without her job,
she had nothing.
Well, for a while, she had you.
Yeah, but not
for long.
Bird was rigid
in everything she did.
Having sex with her
was like... eating glass.
The lab did a DNA test.
Your skin cells are
all over the dog leash
that was used to hang her.
Well, I was probably
the last person
to actually walk that dog.
God knows she never did.
Guess this is more like
his crash pad
between foreign
assignments.
I'm sorry,
I just don't see Miss Neat
Knickers and this guy
making it as a couple, you know.
Still no laptop.
Steal it, scrub it and lose it.
This guy's smart.
This is all just circumstantial.
Now we know how he got her
to write the suicide note.
She wasn't sorry to be living.
She was sorry
that Jake was such a liar.
Well, this is more like
what we need.
Warrick.
Didn't Nick's case have
a blue thigh high stocking?
Yeah.
Even if he was the one
that strangled Jill,
there was no blood
at the crime scene.
Well, with two gunshots
to the chest,
Jill's twin sister
was a bloody mess.
Checkmate?
So he killed them both.
You must have
thought you were
losing your mind?
Let me run it for you.
Jill always picked up her dry
cleaning on Thursday nights.
So right place, right time,
right car,
looks like the right woman,
You thought it was done.
So you go to the house,
get the computer files
and you think you're seeing
your conscious
walk through the door.
The first time you had a plan.
Make it look like a mugging.
The second time,
you had to improvise.
So there were two of them.
I dated Jill.
She kept the most rigid schedule
of anyone I've ever met,
you know.
It was always Thursday night
pick up the dry cleaning night.
And I mean, God forbid I wanted
to see a movie or catch a show
or something.
Leave it to Jill
to be so thorough.
Makes me have to kill her twice.
We were both right.
That's a federal offense,
you know.
I heard the guys
solved a double murder.
Mm-hmm.
I spent the day
sitting on a bench
outside the courtroom,
they never got to me.
That sucks.
Feeling transcendental?
Hmm?
Thoreau. I, uh,
I haven't read him
since college.
Me, neither.
It holds up.
"I would rather sit on a pumpkin
and have it all to myself,
than be crowded
on a velvet cushion."
Oh, look,
you missed one.
Sixty-three down.
"Misanthrope."
I won't wait up.