GRISSOM (echoing):
The details.
WILLOWS (echoing):
Terrifying... I think
Malibu Barbie did it.
GRISSOM:
Well, then there's a lot more
to Barbie than
just a pretty face.
'Cause this is a perfect
half-inch-scale model
of the room.
HODGES:
Three different views
of the same dead doll.
WILLOWS:
Assuming that
they're all Dell foster kids,
there's 13 of them.
MAN:
I found a common element
in all four miniatures:
bleach.
NEWSWOMAN:
...stunned by the death
of former top-ranked
junior middleweight
Lorenzo "Happy" Morales,
whose body was found floating
in a pool late last night
at the Sugarcane Ranch Brothel
in Bryant County.
Morales, best known
for his ability
to take a punch,
was reportedly attempting
a comeback to boxing.
LVPD is investigating
the incident,
which they are treating
as a homicide.
(laughs)
(microwave oven beeping)
(giggling)
(pop music playing
over speakers)
(gasping)
(panicky panting)
(horn beeping)
(neon buzzing)
(techno music playing)
♪ ♪
(knocking at door)
Hey, boss, heard you got a lead
on another one
of the Dell fosters.
Just got an e-mail.
Raymond Dell.
Died two years ago
in some bizarre back hoe
incident in Rapid City.
Okay.
That's good.
One less suspect.
(phone ringing)
Grissom.
BRASS:
Court order for another Dell kid
in Old Henderson--
the 1621 Water Street--
it just came through.
Are you up for a house call?
I'll meet you there.
BRASS:
So, we've been trying
to contact Mr. Dell
for a couple
of weeks.
Have you heard
from him?
No, but that's probably
'cause the rent's due.
See, around here, we mostly
have the kind of tenants
who don't like
to pay their bills much.
(clears throat)
This is the one.
I wonder why.
Trevor Dell, open up.
Las Vegas Police.
MAN:
You got my authority
to use deadly force.
Hey, shut up
and stand back.
(door thudding open)
BRASS:
Anybody home?
This is the police.
Somebody likes it cold.
Vegas in May,
plus global warming.
Hey, Gil, we got a body.
(phone beeps)
Yeah, Control,
this is Jim Brass.
I got a 419
at 1621 Water Street,
Apartment 2B.
What, you lose your interest
in dead bodies?
No.
But I'm afraid the Miniature
Killer was here first.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
(indistinct background
radio communication)
Two distinct lacerations--
one on the forehead,
one on the back of the skull.
Lividity is fixed.
Decomp is pretty well developed.
Air-conditioning
would have slowed that
and accelerated mummification.
Body's been sealed
in the apartment.
There's no insect
activity.
GRISSOM:
So much for T.O.D.
Could be a couple
of days to a few weeks.
Miniature Killer?
(sighs)
It's hard to say.
Haven't found a miniature
of the scene yet.
Just this.
Clothes match.
The, uh, vic's a P.T. nurse, but
there's no blood on the doll,
and it's not posed
like the body.
Bleach at the scene,
just like the others.
Maybe
this one wasn't planned.
Maybe the killer has
to make the miniature
after the fact, which is why
it's so cold in here, to
preserve the body.
GRISSOM:
I don't think
we can rule anything out.
It's all yours, my dear.
(humming)
♪ ♪
Comparing construction materials
of the new doll
to see if it's the same work
as the others?
(beep)
Yeah.
Is there any doubt?
I live by
the Uncertainty Principle.
The mere act
of observing a phenomenon
changes
its nature.
So in trying
to catch the killer,
we've changed his behavior.
I'm certain we have.
(squeak)
What?
A fingerprint.
Well, there was
no physical trace on any
of the other dolls
or the miniatures.
Maybe he's finally
gotten careless.
WOMAN:
Uh, Natalie?
Davis? Natalie Davis?
You're next, hon.
WOMAN:
Ooh-ee.
Izzy Delancy.
Hoity-toity, hmm?
It's a real shame
what happened to him, huh?
Were you there
for all that nonsense?
Too bad, huh?
(laughing)
(sighs)
You're a little lawbreaker.
Says here,
you, uh,
prefer to be
paid in cash.
You like working
off the books, huh?
Good ol' Uncle Sam probably
not too happy about that, huh?
That's...
because... I-I...
(tauntingly):
Uh, uh, uh, ooh,
uh, uh.
(guffawing)
You speak English, you
got all your papers.
No, fine.
It's fine.
But in all seriousness,
you wouldn't mind having
your fingerprints done?
See, we were lucky
enough to get a contract
for the municipal buildings
downtown.
You know, mayor's office,
police department.
Yeah.
But, you know,
they require a background check
for anyone going to
work in that building,
even temps.
Sure.
That'd be okay.
Yeah...
Listen, hon,
you seem like a real
nice girl, real nice, but
we're called Platinum Maids
for a reason.
I-I just don't see the sparkle.
No.
No, I'm very good.
And I have exceptional
attention to detail.
You clean in between the blinds?
No.
More like memory.
I can see a room one time
and remember
where everything is.
After just
one time?
Uh-huh.
Okay.
Describe the reception area.
There's a lavender orchid
on the reception desk.
It's top bloom is about
to open.
A glass coffee cup
with a chip on the edge.
A half inch of coffee
still in the cup.
Cut glass bowl full
of chocolate Kisses--
two gold, one purple.
A glass vase
with a rose etched in the glass.
Three leaves
etched on its stalk.
You sit tight.
I got some choices for you.
(water pouring,
camera shutter beeping)
(camera beeping,
clicking)
(beeping and clicking)
(squeak)
BROWN:
Victim's cell phone
and I.M. logs
show no activity
for the past 12 days.
So far, that's the best I can do
for a time of death.
According to
the doc,
C.O.D. was cerebral
hemorrhage due
to multiple blunt
force trauma.
SIDLE:
The head injuries
are consistent
with the blood stains
on the sink and
the wall behind it.
It does suggest
a struggle.
(glass shattering)
It's... kind of up close
and personal for this killer.
Hodges ran fabric,
paint,
glue, and plastic samples
of the Trevor doll.
The materials were consistent
with the previous Minis.
No luck with that print?
It was only
a partial,
not enough to put
through AFIS.
But there were epithelials
in the print.
Wendy's running DNA.
Hello there.
Can I help you?
I need to order a special part.
Well, why don't you just
check out our spaceship isle.
Yeah.
I'll be right
with you
after I help this little
fellow over here.
Look, you really need to
buy these polyhedral dice.
Just in case.
You're always
losing them, man.
I just come from
the police.
They showed me your
miniatures and
they showed me
some pictures of
some dead people.
The cops know
I helped you
put some of that stuff together.
They know I delivered
that package
to the old lady's house,
like you asked
me to.
They think I killed,
I killed all those people.
You didn't?
Natalie, did you kill them?
Did you kill those people?
Yes.
Why?
They're going to put
you in jail, honey.
(sighs)
Unless there's something else?
If you had a good reason...
they'll listen to that.
Raymundo...
...did he put his
hands on you?
Yes...
that smell...
And the old lady?
And that pervert
rock star?
If they done something to you
just tell me what it was.
Honey...
I know there's some
people out there
that deserve killin'...
and you... you had good
reason to kill 'em, right?
Yes.
All right.
I want you to listen to me.
What you've done
is done.
I can't fix that.
But I can still
take care of you.
I ain't going to let
the police get you.
But you got to
promise me
you won't kill
nobody else.
Promise me you'll
be a good girl.
(child-like):
Your special girl?
That's right.
My special girl.
I promise.
You were the one thing
I thought I'd done right.
GRISSOM:
I found
a thriving miniature
hobbyist
community on line.
Sites where people meet, chat,
exchange building tips,
list stores
they shop in.
So that's why
you built this thing?
I mean...
other than
to creep us all out?
Items like Trevor Dell's
metal bracelet
are difficult to make, even
for skilled craftsmen.
I'm trying to
find people
who specialize
in miniature metal work.
SIMMS:
Hey,
I got DNA off the Trevor doll.
There were two contributors:
the vic and an unknown.
There was nothing
in CODIS, but...
the unknown was XX.
The Miniature Killer's a woman?
Female serial killers
are rare enough.
Delusional psychosis in women...
rarer still.
Well, "female" cuts the list
down a little bit.
We could also narrow it down
even further
by cross-referencing the dates
that Trevor lived with Ernie.
I mean,
that's got
to be enough to get the foster
records released, right?
Family court judge was explicit:
"No fishing expeditions."
We need to go in with a name.
(beeping)
Come on down
to Schuster's Hobby Shop.
A whole world awaits you.
GRISSOM:
I'll be back.
I have to go see
the Shadowcaster
of the Forgotten Realms.
Unless the female killer
was an Amazon,
I kind of doubt a guy
like this was just...
beat around
his own bathroom.
You have another theory?
In the Penny Garden case,
the victim was...
poisoned,
then died falling
out a window
after going into
convulsions.
Right.
In the Barbara
Tallman case,
the method of murder was gassing
but was disguised
by potential poisoning
and suffocation.
You think I overlooked
something?
You know, I asked
for an expanded tox panel.
It came back clean
as a whistle.
Well...
take a look at this.
That little
round spot...
is that discoloration
consistent with decomp?
Maybe not.
And idea what it is?
No.
But I can find out.
GRISSOM:
Hello, Art.
Well, hey,
Dr. Grissom.
How's the, uh,
miniature going?
Coming along,
thank you.
We found another one.
Oh, man.
He struck again?
I think so.
By any chance,
did you make this bracelet?
Oh, yeah, I made that.
For a chick, man.
Uh...
let's see...
Natalie.
She have a last name?
Uh, I-I didn't think
to write it down.
"Paid cash.
Call cell phone
when ready."
It's the same cell number
we already have.
Do you remember what
she looked like?
Late 20s, early 30s...
She's about yay high.
Uh, brown hair.
Uh, she's kind
of a Skinny chick.
Weird.
Weird how?
I got guys
who come in here trying to
recreate Civil War battles
hoping for a different outcome.
I get the desperate
housewives who are trying
to build the perfect
Thanksgiving dinner.
Control freaks
with social problems
that's my bread and butter,
but, uh, this chick, she had...
crazy eyes, you know.
Was that the last
time you saw her?
You know what?
She came in a few days ago.
She... yeah!
She bought one
of these.
Battery powered
micro-motor?
You just attach that to anything
you want to animate.
Just like, uh...
like this, see.
No one ever wins.
♪ ♪
ROBBINS:
The nuclear streaming indicates
that Trevor Dell was subjected
to a significant electrical
current.
The shock must have sent him
into convulsions,
resulting in several impact
injuries.
He was electrocuted?!
From what?
If I could tell you that,
you'd be out of a job.
All the outlets in the bathroom
are dead.
Must be on a separate circuit
than the lights.
I just reset
the breaker.
That do the trick?
(beeping)
We're hot.
What you got?
Possible burn mark
on the tile.
If this is where Trevor's foot
grounded out,
he must've been at the sink
when he got zapped.
The outlet doesn't
look scorched.
Looks like
some burned skin.
The sink is still damp.
Hey, hit that crack.
(beeping)
I think we may have found
the Mini Killer's booby trap.
(electrical buzzing,
Trevor moaning)
Hot wire's touching one
of the metal brackets
that's holding up
the sink.
WILLOWS:
Sink is cracked,
water pours in,
touches the bracket...
Trevor touches
the water...
zap.
You can see where it's been rigged.
Whoever tapped into
this power line
must've gained access
from the apartment
on the other side
of this wall.
You're saying the killer's
the next door neighbor?
(knocking)
LVPD! Open the door!
Hey, here's another one
for you.
You sure, uh, get a lot
of packages...
Oh!
Oh, God!
The big guy's
a wannabe composer.
Quit his day job to write
the next Dreamgirls.
Anyway, he didn't
pay his bills
and the power company
shut off his lights.
So the genius steals
power from his neighbor
and ends up electrifying
Trevor's sink.
Yeah, another weird
tragedy for the Dell family.
Doesn't explain what
that doll was doing
there, though.
Well, the guy
liked action figures.
Maybe his sister,
the Miniature Killer,
gave it to him as a gift.
GRISSOM (on phone):
Grissom.
Hey, Grissom, it's Sofia.
"Female Dell foster child,
first name Natalie"
was finally specific enough.
Family Court just ordered CPS
to release her records.
Sorry, did I totally
flake on an appointment?
We're not with
Social Services.
We're here to ask you
about a foster child
you had a number
of years ago.
Oh, geez.
You can try.
We've had about 60.
Yeah, honey?
You said we could
watch Dora,
Mm-hmm.
but Simon's
watching soccer.
Well, Simon has TV
privileges until
4:00, so tell him
(chuckles) that now
it's your turn.
Ha-ha!
Nicely please, thank you.
Her birth name
was Natalie Davis.
Mm-hmm.
She would've
been about seven
when she came
to you in 1982.
Oh, '82.
My God...
Let's see.
Let's take a look.
What did you get?
Oh! Good for you.
Congratulations.
Do you take a photo
of every child?
Every single one,
their first night here.
I just feel like it gives them
a sense of belonging right away.
Most of them come to us
so damaged
they don't know what it's like
to belong to anything.
Here we are.
Oh, Natalie.
Yeah, shy as anything
until I tried to do her laundry
and then she screamed
her little head off.
Do you use bleach,
Mrs. Wetzel?
Have you ever even seen
a load of kids' laundry?
Of course I use bleach.
Excuse me a second.
According to
Child Services,
she only stayed
with you a week.
Do you remember why?
Yeah, a couple of nights
into her stay,
she climbed up
to the top bunk
and pushed another
little girl out.
Of course we talked to her
about it, but she did it again
the very next night,
almost broke her collarbone.
So you just sent her back?
After a few dozen kids,
you get real good
at knowing the difference
between damaged and broken.
And Natalie was broken.
(low whirring)
(sharp thudding)
CATHERINE:
"Great Rainone
and His Little Bisque Doll."
Oh, that looks like
the doll images from
the Miniatures.
What's a bisque?
Fired unglazed pottery.
Her biological father
was Christopher Davis,
a ventriloquist.
A grown man who sticks
his hand up the back
of a doll and speaks
like a girl.
Sounds healthy.
I Googled him.
Who's Chloe?
Natalie's younger sister.
1981, she fell out of
a tree house and died.
But her father's
still alive.
And still performing.
So how do you feel today, Chloe?
(falsetto voice):
I'm not doing so good, Daddy.
Well there,
what's the matter, doll face?
Well, I feel like a hobo.
A hobo?
Now you know what that
stands for don't ya?
That stands for
"homeward bound."
But, I ain't got
no home, Daddy.
Well now, that's silly.
Chloe, everybody's got a home.
Where do you live?
I live in a box.
In a box?
A box that's giving me
a pain in my sawdust.
(florid piano intro)
A pain in your sawdust?
♪ I got a pain
in my sawdust ♪
♪ That's what's the matter
with me ♪
♪ Something is wrong
with my little inside ♪
♪ I'm just as sick as can be ♪
♪ Don't let me faint,
someone get me a fan ♪
♪ Someone else run
for the medicine man ♪
♪ Everyone hurry
as fast as you can ♪
♪ I got a pain in my... ♪
♪ Sawdust. ♪
(scattered applause)
Okay, we're
in a David Lynch movie.
Where's the dwarf?
♪ As sure as the stars ♪
♪ Shine above ♪
♪ You are nobody ♪
♪ Till somebody loves you ♪
♪ So find yourself somebody ♪
♪ Get yourself somebody ♪
♪ You are nobody,
nobody, nobody... ♪
Yeah, that was
my other daughter.
So, being a performer
and a parent had to have
been hard at times.
Well, my folks were
in vaudeville.
It wasn't hard
until my wife passed away.
Natalie was
six and Chloe was four.
It was, um, pepper and salt.
Darkness and light.
Within the year, my
whole family was just...
Poof. Gone.
What happened?
Can I tell
the story, Daddy?
Sure, sweetheart.
It was a sunny day in June.
And my sister
who couldn't hold a tune
was playing with me
in our house in the tree...
CHLOE:
Hi, Daddy.
RAINONE:
Hey, Chloe.
(screams)
CHLOE DOLL:
I fell to the ground
with an awful sound.
A puddle of blood
as big as the sea
was all that was left
of dear old me.
CATHERINE:
Had the girls been fighting?
Chloe would never fight.
How did Natalie deal with it?
I don't know.
It was hard on both of us.
I tried for a while,
but I just couldn't handle it.
I had to give her up.
♪ ♪
The Great Rainone
is in great denial.
Of course, losing a child
at the hands of another
could do that to you.
You do agree that Natalie
killed Chloe, right?
Yeah, I was just wondering
what it must've
looked like to her.
(elevator bell dings)
♪ ♪
(car alarm beeps off)
Sara?
(phone beeps)
Control, this is Jim Brass.
Yeah, we found Sara Sidle's car,
but she's missing.
There's no sign of her.
Looks like an abduction.
(phone ringing)
Come on, Sara, pick up.
Please pick up.
Who was in my office
while I was gone?
No one. Just some girl
from janitorial.
She went in, vacuumed,
emptied out the trash.
That's all.
SANDERS:
The doll's still alive.
That means Sara's still alive.
Generic stretch
of desert.
She could be anywhere
in a four-state radius.
Let's just focus on the details.
There's always something
to go on.
She has to make these
in advance, right?
But how do you
plan a car wreck?
There's no way to know how
the car's going to land.
Unless you wreck the car first,
and then put her under it.
STOKES:
I think I got
a VIN number.
SANDERS:
Give me the first six.
STOKES:
King-Sam-Victor-four-five-three.
GRISSOM:
Her name is
Natalie Davis,
and she works
for our janitorial service.
What?
Here in the lab?
For over a month.
She's never been arrested,
so there's nothing to flag
on a security check.
She used Ernie Dell's
address on her work form.
She has no home phone
and no driver's license.
(beep)
Okay, I got it.
A 2007
red Mustang totaled outside
The Trip Wire Bar
six weeks ago.
Driver fatality. DWI.
Car went to scrap.
Lead CSI on the case--
Sara Sidle.
Pull up the case photos.
(typing, computer beeps)
(beep)
Oh, my God.
She was at the crime scene.
So, she salvages the car,
and somehow gets it out
to the desert,
and then grabs Sara,
and puts her under it?
BROWN:
I don't get it.
What does Sara
have to do with bleach?
WILLOWS:
I don't know.
This just feels different.
It is different.
This girl holds me responsible
for the death
of Ernie Dell.
I took away the only person
she ever loved,
so she's going
to do the same thing to me.
GRISSOM:
It's not about
a psychotic
reaction to bleach,
or some dead sister
or the doll.
"NotUrLittleBisqueDoll..."
(typing,
computer trilling)
(beep)
(tapping keypad)
This is Gil Grissom at CSI.
I need to get
an Attorney General's Waiver.
MAN:
Go, go, go!
Move, move!
She went out
the window!
She's headed for the alley.
♪ ♪
BRASS: I don't want
to waste time
screwing around
with this nutcase.
I'm going to get some
bleach and drip it on her
until she gives
up the location.
And they can't accuse us
of police brutality for that.
I want to talk
to her, Jim.
Alone.
Hi, Natalie.
My name's Gil.
It's so nice
to finally meet you.
I, uh...
probably shouldn't
say this,
but... I'm
a huge fan.
I've been a crime scene
investigator for 22 years.
I've worked over
2,000 homicides,
and you are by far...
the best I've ever seen.
I mean...
...you're such a
great artist.
And to be so young
and so talented and...
so pretty.
I've thought about
you every night for
the last nine months.
I even tried to do
what you do.
I built my own
miniature.
You saw it?
How'd I do?
Do you play chess?
I play as a hobby.
It quiets my mind, you know?
Soothes me.
At one point,
I became so consumed by it
that whenever I closed my eyes,
I could see the chess pieces
moving all around the board.
I was obsessed
with correcting
all my bad moves.
I wondered if a game
could ever be played
without a mistake.
I'd love to play
you sometime.
I'm so impressed
by the way
you embrace your passion.
You'd make a great CSI.
This last one
was brilliant.
You studied our
crime scene so well.
Tracking the car to the junkyard
and then towing it
all the way out to the desert
where you knew
we wouldn't find it.
And then...
the way you killed Sara.
(quiet gasp)
I didn't kill her.
You didn't?
This is about her.
Her, her, her!
It's always about her.
No, it isn't, Natalie.
It's about you.
It's always
about her.
(Natalie panting)
(both grunt)
(gasping)
"Oh, sad
"was the day
for the little bisque doll,
"for they cut
all her stitches away,
"and found the seat
of the terrible
ache;
T'was a delicate task..."
Natalie, listen to me--
tell me where she is.
"For none of the doctors
had ever before
Natalie...
...performed
on a dolly's inside."
Please tell me
where Sara is.
"They tried to restuff her
"but didn't know how,
and this was
her wail as she died..."
Stop it! Just stop this!
Tell me where Sara is!
"I've got a pain in my sawdust.
"That's what's
the matter with me.
"Something is wrong
with my little inside.
"I'm just as sick
as can be.
"Don't let me faint.
"Someone get me a fan.
"Someone please run
for the medicine man.
"Everyone hurry
"as fast as you can,
'cause I've got a pain
in my sawdust.