(applause)
♪ ♪
(indistinct conversations,
applause)
(applause and whistles)
♪ ♪
(electricity buzzing)
(explosion)
(cheering)
(woman screams)
(indistinct conversations)
(screams)
(camera shutters clicking)
(indistinct radio transmission)
I always liked
the circus.
Yeah, it's fun trying
to figure out the magic tricks.
Well, that's taking
the fun out of it.
Hey, the coroner's
on his way.
Vic's a Jane Doe,
no I.D.
Green powder on her dress.
Is she with the show?
According to statements,
she wasn't a part
of Cirque du Soleil.
Well, there's plenty
of surveillance.
Yeah, but the body
was discovered backstage.
What's it doing out here?
I think he wants to tell you.
Hi. Michel Souray,
company manager of KA.
I'm sorry to meet you
under these circumstances.
Why'd you move the body?
SOURAY:
Backstage can be
a dangerous place
if you don't know
your way around.
So the Cirque
organization
made a special
agreement
with Clark County.
Any accidents that occur
inside our facility
are under Cirque
jurisdiction.
Our personnel
immediately
transported her outside
and the paramedics
arrived within minutes.
I have no idea who
the poor girl is
and I know every
face on our staff.
Watch your step.
During the performance,
the stages above you
are always moving.
We found
the body here
in the crush zone.
Well, we know where she died.
Where'd she come from?
Where would you
like to start?
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me
who are you, you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
(shutter clicks)
Looks like he ate a .38 special.
The gun's still in his hand.
How many suicides have
you seen like that?
Personally?
None.
Me, either.
I haven't found a suicide note.
Maybe it was staged.
Sorry, got held up
at the "meet the future
in-laws" dinner.
Did they love you?
I got a little too excited
talking about work.
They stopped eating.
Oh.
David, the gun is still in his
hand; it's yours to clear.
Yes, sir.
Rigor's setting in fast.
It happens when it's
hot like tonight.
(gunshot)
Oh, are you all right?
You all right?
It's all right
everyone, a misfire.
Hey.
At least we know one person
who shot the dead guy.
Good to see you on
your feet again, Jim.
You've never seen
me off them, Sam.
You know, this
is like old times.
You, me, a party.
A dead body.
This is supposed
to be a celebration.
The Eclipse is going
to be my legacy.
We break ground next year.
So I'm guessing you knew
the victim-- Robert O'Brien?
He invested in
The Eclipse.
Did you hear the shot?
No. Must've taken place
during the implosion.
You think he shot himself?
You think he didn't?
Well, he was about to make
a lot of money
in your casino; why would he?
Look, I hardly
knew the guy.
Or his partner, Joe Hirschoff.
They were marketing
the project in L.A.
They had a little money,
so I sold them a few shares.
How much is a share?
Two million.
You want it?
When was the last
time you saw him?
Everyone was gathering on
the other side of the roof.
I think he went off
with his partner.
I got it.
Aircraft carrier.
That's what this place
reminds me of.
Of course,
an aircraft carrier
was built for national security
and this is a ton of hi-tech,
twisted steel for the sake
of entertainment.
It's not just
entertainment, Nick.
The cirque's
about the power
of imagination--
it's how we were
able to put a man on the moon.
I've got a monogram necklace.
A.F.D.
Well, it's not
an I.D.,
but I'll settle for initials.
Did you and Mr. O'Brien
arrive together?
Yeah, we're in
a suite downstairs.
And you've been
with him since?
Mostly.
A couple minutes before,
um, the implosion,
I went to get us margaritas.
When I came back,
Robert was gone.
I knew he didn't
want to miss it,
so I went looking.
I was by the elevator.
I thought maybe Robert
had gone back to the suite.
Then I heard that girl scream.
I just knew.
Are you taking any medication?
May I see that?
Alprazolam.
It's for stress.
My job is very stressful.
Does Mr. O'Brien own a gun?
He hates guns, we both do.
Could you hold your hands out
for me like this please?
Why?
Gunshot residue test.
Robert shot himself.
And this is
how we prove it.
SIDLE:
Right palm down.
(sniffs)
Am I smelling alcohol
on your hand?
Yeah.
When I saw Robert,
I spilled the drinks.
ROBBINS:
Standard S.A.E. was collected.
No signs
of sexual trauma indicated.
Several linear
red-brown abrasions
on the chest and back.
Marginal contusions.
Palpable underlying
rib and sternal fractures.
(crackling)
Huh, Rice Krispies.
Subcutaneous emphysema.
Air in the tissue
indicates victim
was most likely subjected
to significant crushing force
across the torso.
(groaning)
(screaming)
You know, this crush zone
is clearly marked.
Yeah, and anybody familiar
with the stage
would know to avoid that area.
Looks like blood on the edge
of this lift.
It might have been unavoidable.
ROBBINS:
Her liver was lacerated.
If she'd been alive
when the crushing occurred,
these lacerations would of
resulted in hemoperitoneum
and, uh, bilateral
hemothorax.
But there was no
significant hemorrhage
in the abdominal
or thoracic cavities.
So she was dead
before she was crushed.
Yeah, C.O.D. was temporal
laceration of the brain
due to skull fracture.
Initially,
I assumed it was associated
with a crushing trauma.
It wasn't.
So the fatal blow was
a separate event.
Mm-hmm.
Well, the way things move
around on that stage,
it could have
happened anywhere.
She looks like she's
probably in her mid-20s.
She's in good shape.
Yeah.
Is well toned.
She got calluses
on her hands and feet.
Could be a dancer
or a gymnast.
But if she wasn't
part of Cirque,
what was she doing there?
BRASS:
Hey Sheriff, how's it going?
What can I do for you?
This is about what
I can do for you.
Really?
I've asked the Mayor to
give you a commendation.
Medal of Valor.
Congratulations.
Well, that's-that's nice,
uh, do I have to be there?
As a matter of protocol,
I'd say you damn well
better be, Captain.
Well, you know,
Ben, if--
Look, I'm going to
say a few nice things,
hand you a plaque,
we'll shake hands,
a whole lot of reporters
will be there
to take pictures
of the big event.
It'll be magic.
Yeah.
My office will call
you to set it up.
I was going to vote
for you anyway.
HODGES:
The green powder
on your vic's dress
is open-celled phenolic foam.
Holds more than 40 times
its weight in water.
Reminds me of this girl
I knew in college--
I don't need
to hear about that.
She was a florist.
The foam's used
almost exclusively
in floral arrangements.
Wait a minute.
The security guard at KAsaid
that he let a young woman
through the artists' entrance
with a delivery of flowers.
He escorted her
to the green room,
but didn't remember
seeing her leave.
Ah, the old flower
delivery trick.
Works every time.
Huh.
SANDERS:
Cirque du Soleil has cameras
all over that theatre.
They use them for
performance review.
I went through all the feeds
the Cirque guys sent over,
and I have to tell you,
Siegfried &amp; Roy's
disappearing elephant
no longer impresses me.
I'll tell you
how they did that later.
STOKES:
There's the vic,
right?
Yup, 11-D.
Artist's entrance.
Girl has the same kind
of dress and hair color
as the vic.
As far as I can see,
they managed
to stay hidden backstage
for most of the performance.
It's dark,
they're wearing
black...
crew's focused
on their jobs...
it's possible
nobody saw them.
The guy left alone,
same way they came in,
just before
the show ended.
I tried to make out a face,
but there's not
much detail here.
However, look at this.
Check this out.
GRISSOM:
She dropped something.
I think it's a purse.
There was no purse
near the body.
Or anywhere else backstage.
If we find it,
it might get us an ID.
STOKES:
Give me the time code
when she dropped the purse.
Okay, who's in
the burrito?
It's apparent suicide,
from Sam Braun's party.
Sara and Warrick's case.
Gunshot to the head.
What's this?
He bled out in the bag.
I guess I forgot
to tape them shut.
This blood corrupts any GSR.
Clean it up.
♪ ♪
SARA:
Hey, Doc,
you tell me.
Suicide or homicide?
Either side at this point.
According to Tox,
B.A.C. was point-one-nine.
That's over twice
the legal limit.
My guess,
based on the whiffing the
stomach contents, tequila.
You're good,
he was drinking margaritas.
Tox also found
alprazolam in his bloodstream.
Yeah, his partner has
a prescription for it.
He was also the one bringing
him drinks.
Hmm.
Hand me that
trajectory rod.
Sure.
Thank you.
Sara, hold this
in would you?
Sure.
Here we go.
However he got it,
he probably would've been
too stoned to stand.
It would of made it easier
to stick a gun in his mouth
at this angle.
(people cheering)
Look in there.
Sesame seeds?
I think so.
I found them in the oral cavity,
but not in the stomach contents.
It's hard to swallow when
you have a gun in your mouth.
STOKES:
Okay, let me know
when the Cliff Deck
is where it was
at that point in the show.
Um, I think it was just before
the "Wash Up to the Shore"
scene.
That was at, uh,
21 minutes, 37 seconds.
MAN (over radio):
Copy that.
Yeah, that's great.
That's great right there,
thanks.
Okay...
go find your friend.
Okay, move the Deck
into its next position, please.
Copy that,
foot deck is on the move.
Initiating dump sequence.
Amazing.
Ground cork.
From the audience,
it looks like real sand.
You know,
if you want
to dive in here
and give me a hand
this might go
a little faster.
(giggles)
Nice try.
Okay, hang on.
I think I found something.
This isn't the purse I dropped.
Celia Noel, Wisconsin.
Well, the initials
on the necklace
that Catherine found were
"A-F-D".
Well, clearly
not her initials,
but check this out.
It looks like she hit every
Cirque show in town.
Apparently one a little bit
harder than the others.
BURDICK:
On May 11, 2006,
with an innocent life
hanging in the balance,
Captain Brass went into that
hotel room alone,
face-to-face
with a deranged killer.
Brass looks like
he's about to puke.
Captain Brass
was severely wounded,
Or punch someone.
but the hostage's life
was saved.
And for these actions
which exemplify the dedication
of the Las Vegas
Police Department,
the City thanks you.
REPORTER:
This is Captain Brass'
second commendation
in the line of duty.
The first was in...
I got you a
veggie burger.
Thanks.
What about me?
I didn't know you were here.
Soy sorry.
Where's the love?
So we found some gunk
in the revolver's forcing cone.
Hodges ID'd it as...
melted sesame seeds.
Doc Robbins found sesame seeds
in the vic's mouth.
Any prints on the gun?
No.
The grip was checked, we don't
usually get prints off those.
Is it registered?
In California,
to a Joe Hirschoff.
Really?
Yeah.
He said he hated guns.
Check this out...
I researched ownership
in The Eclipse project.
The vic and Joe Hirschoff
held their share
as joint tenants.
Really?
Which means...
With Robert dead,
Joe automatically
and immediately
owns all the shares.
Sounds like
a great reason to kill.
Why did you lie?
I didn't lie.
I bought the gun
when I moved to L.A.
White kid
from a small town...
Put it in a closet.
Forgot it was there.
How did Robert get it?
I don't...
Going through my stuff, I guess.
Did he take your pills?
'Cause we found them
in his bloodstream.
I don't know.
You don't know?
No, I don't know.
Robert was depressed.
Maybe he did.
You know, we did a credit
check on you, Joe.
You're in hock for over
a million dollars.
It's personal debt--
that's heavy paper.
I'm leveraged.
(chuckles)
Yeah, I'm leveraged.
So what?
(chuckling):
I live well...
I live well
by believing in myself.
No, you live well by playing the
come line with borrowed money.
You know, Joe,
you're the type of guy--
you see something you like,
you got to have it,
including your partner's share
in The Eclipse.
So you put your pills in
his drink, he nods off,
you wrap his fingers around
your gun, and then you get
to live really well.
I want my lawyer.
SIDLE:
Is this everything?
BROWN:
Everything from Hirschoff's
and O'Brien's room
that I could get
under the warrant.
No suicide note?
Not even in the Holy Bible.
That is the first place
I look, too.
Did the suite have a kitchen?
No.
Why pack an oven mitt?
Sesame seeds.
The blood on the necklace
was the victim's.
A.F.D.
Arcadia Federation
of Dance.
Celia Noel was a dancer,
which would explain her
fascination with Cirque.
You still like to dance?
I don't mean the way
you used to, I...
I know what you mean,
and yes, I do.
I think I have a line
on the victim's date.
Now, four of the tickets
that we pulled from her purse
were charged
to her credit card,
but the Zumanity
ticket was purchased
with a different card,
one belonging
to a gentleman named Arnie...
Clifton.
He should have
paid cash.
Yeah, Celia and I
scoped out Zumanity.
Sexy stuff.
CURTIS:
Right up your alley.
I've got all kinds
of alleys, but, uh,
yeah, I'd say
that's one of them.
How'd you two meet?
I touched her feet
for over an hour.
She tried on 20 pairs of shoes.
Did she invite you to the show?
Yeah.
Did you pay for it?
I'm a gentleman.
Best toe cleavage I ever saw.
CURTIS:
What did you do
after the show?
Nothing.
We had a nice time; she split.
Haven't seen her since.
We have.
She's dead.
Backstage at KA.
You didn't join her
for the double feature?
(scoffs)
Nah, man, not me.
Look, uh,
are we done, 'cause I got
to get back to work.
STOKES:
No, we're not done here.
You got sand in your shoes.
Finely ground particles
of Portuguese cork.
Same stuff they use
backstage at KA,
which places you
at the crime scene.
Okay, so what if I was there?
You were there
with a woman
who wound up dead,
which is why you're here.
Zumanity got me all worked up.
She was grabbing on me.
I-I was down to do
whatever she wanted.
What did she want to do?
Go backstage at KA, see it
up close and personal.
She was bananas about that show.
She said to meet her
near the artists' entrance
just after the show started.
I did. She let me in.
And you thought if you went
with her, you'd get laid?
I figured maybe backstage at KA
was her version
of the mile high club.
Come on, come on.
Celia, just relax
for a minute.
Come on.
Something clipped her
in the side of the head.
She fell.
She didn't even scream.
I was just so freaked out,
I bailed, I'm telling you.
I tried to warn her,
but she was just too fired up.
She kept trying to get closer
and closer and closer.
Yeah, and you let her.
You need to write
a statement.
I perfected my butterfly
technique on chicken breasts.
I sauté them
in a chardonnay reduction
with herbes de Provence.
Drives women wild.
Well, Mom.
Now say the magic words.
"Shut up, Hodges"?
No. "Open sesame."
Hand me that can of Ferro-Trace.
I live to serve.
The gun was transported to
the hotel room in the oven mitt.
Only question is,
who brought it to the party?
SIDLE:
The trail of seeds proved it.
It was suicide, after all.
(gunshot)
It's the first time
I've ever seen a suicide
where the gun stays
in the vic's hand.
I have an explanation
for that, too.
Dupuytren's contracture.
It's a rare condition,
characterized
by progressive fibrosis
of the palmar fascia,
The tissues thicken...
...contracting the fingers.
He couldn't let go of the gun.
The condition was still
in its early stages,
which is why
it looked like rigor.
Do we have any idea
why he killed himself?
Depression, maybe.
You know, according
to my supervisor,
we're not really
in the business of why, but...
(phone rings)
I got to go.
Bye.
SIDLE:
These are Robert's
personal effects.
I'm very sorry for your loss.
Okay. I'll do it.
Hey, Jim.
What's up?
Where's your hardware?
Oh, come on, come on.
Don't even try it;
you were all over the news.
Let's see it.
(groans)
Wow.
That's beautiful.
What's with
all the modesty?
It should be
up on your wall, man.
For what?
For taking a bullet
or not dying?
For being brave.
You know, Warrick,
I'll tell you something.
I walked into that hotel room,
and 23 years of police work
told me I knew
what that guy was about.
And he played me
like a damn rookie.
He beat me at my own game.
I mean, what's the dumbest
thing you've ever done?
You want to make a poster
of it, put it on your wall?
I don't think so.
(plaque clattering)
But thanks for coming by.
All right.
So do you think
Grissom will show?
Not if he thinks
he has to dance.
(chuckles)
MAN (over speaker):
Ladies and gentlemen,
tomorrow night,
more than 18,000 people are
going to come and see this guy
at the Thomas and Mack Center.
But tonight, you guys
are going to hear him first.
Everybody give it up
for Mr. John Mayer!
(applause and cheering)
Ooh. I like him.
I think you got to dance.
Come on, let's go.
My God.
(soulful pop melody playing)
♪ Me and all my friends,
we're all misunderstood ♪
♪ They say we stand
for nothing ♪
♪ And there's no way
we ever could ♪
♪ Now we see
everything is going wrong ♪
♪ With the world
and those who lead it ♪
♪ We just feel
like we don't have the means ♪
♪ To rise above and beat it,
so we keep waiting ♪
♪ Waiting ♪
♪ Waiting on the world
to change ♪
♪ We keep on waiting ♪
♪ Waiting ♪
♪ Waiting on the world
to change ♪
♪ It's hard to beat the system ♪
♪ When we're standing
at a distance ♪
♪So we keep waiting ♪
♪ Waiting ♪
♪ Waiting on the world
to change ♪
♪ Now if we had the power ♪
♪ To bring our neighbors
home from war ♪
♪ They would have never
missed a Christmas ♪
♪ No more ribbons on the door ♪
♪ When you trust
your television ♪
♪ What you get is what you got ♪
♪ 'Cause when they own
the information, oh ♪
♪ They can bend it
all they want ♪
♪ That's why we're waiting ♪
♪ Waiting ♪
♪ Waiting on the world
to change ♪
♪ We keep on waiting ♪
♪ Waiting ♪
♪ Waiting on the world
to change ♪
♪ One day our generation is
gonna rule the population ♪
♪ So we keep on waiting ♪
♪ Waiting ♪
♪ Waiting on the world
to change ♪
♪ Waiting
on the world to change ♪
♪ Waiting on the world
to change ♪
♪ Waiting
on the world to change. ♪
(applause and cheering)
(chuckling):
Oh...
Awesome.
(whooping)
I think I know her.
I know that guy.
Yeah, I bet you do.
Ask her to dance.
Yeah?
I'm going
to get a drink.
You're sure?
Go for it.
Hey, Nicky.
(intro to "Slow Dancing
In A Burning Room" plays)
The guy down there wants
to buy you your next drink.
No, thanks.
♪ It's not a silly
little moment ♪
♪ It's not the storm
before the calm ♪
♪ This is the deep
and dying breath of ♪
♪ This love that we've
been working on ♪
♪ Can't seem to hold you
like I want to ♪
♪ So I can feel you in my arms ♪
♪ Nobody's gonna come
and save you ♪
♪ We pulled so many
false alarms ♪
♪ We're going down ♪
♪ And you can see it too ♪
♪ And you know
that we're doomed ♪
♪ My dear we're ♪
♪ Slow dancing in a... ♪
(song fades)
Have you ever seen
anything like this?
No.
The detail is...
Terrifying.
GRISSOM:
Impressive.
And yes...
terrifying.
Which do you
think came first:
the chicken or the egg?
I've always been an egg man.
But this time, I don't know.
(Willows groans)
(groans)
(shutter clicks)
(dialing)
WOMAN (on phone):
Las Vegas Crime Lab?
How can I help you?