WOMAN: (laughs): Oh,
you were so on tonight, Cammie.
I was channeling my nerves
in a positive way.
Somebody's got
to hold it together.
(women laughing)
I swear, Janice can't
dance a straight line.
Pigeon-toed.
Should have stayed on
the bluebell line. B.G.
Well, you know
how she scored
that principal
role, right?
Bad on her feet,
good on her back.
Oh, Libby, can
you believe this?
I am so sick
of this pigsty.
Been like this ever since Lauren
got her creepy new boyfriend.
He's a musician.
My mom dated a musician--
total freeloaders.
If I get bumped to
principal this week,
I am so out of here.
Take me with you.
Becca fell off
the wagon again.
The nicotine
dancer diet.
(hip-hop music blasting)
(phone rings)
WOMEN (on machine):
Hey! You've reached
Showgirl Heaven.
Please leave a message
at the tone. Thanks. Bye.
WOMAN:
Cammie, great audition today.
You made it, girl.
You're principal.
Call me for the details.
Congrats!
(machine beeps, disconnects)
Everyone's in my room.
Follow the music.
Be right there.
Hey, guys.
(muffled scream)
Libby?
Libby!
(camera shutter clicking)
Hell of a way to spend
your night off.
How many bodies
do you have in there?
Three.
Grissom's
down the hall,
first door on your right.
Just follow the blood.
(gasps)
My date got canceled.
I'm sure he had a good excuse.
Looks like sexual assault.
Bound, pants pulled down.
Yeah.
Where do you want me?
Next bedroom.
There's another body in there.
Well, that makes five.
The dispatch said
there were six.
According to Brass,
the boyfriend of one of
the victims found the bodies.
Said there were six roommates,
all showgirls.
Evidently, one
didn't come home.
She picked the right night.
Hot scene!
Suspect under the bed!
Sara!
(sputters):
Please... please help me.
Please.
Hold on.
Victim down!
Call an ambulance!
Dispatch, this is CSI Grissom...
You're safe now, okay?
You're safe now.
It's going to be okay.
Help me. Help me.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
Up until a few hours ago,
this was considered
one of the safest
neighborhoods in Las Vegas.
But with the discovery
of six young women
brutally slain
in their beds...
I got here at 3:45.
I've been dating Becca
about a month.
When I saw all that blood
on the stairs,
I just... I just knew.
Jonathan, do you have
a key to the house?
Becca gave it to me.
I usually try to come over
and say good night,
but I was... I was late.
Had a couple
clients in town.
But I didn't need the key.
Front door was open.
If we brought you some photos,
would you be able
to ID the girls
for us?
(helicopter flies overhead)
Look, I know
this is tough,
but did she give you anything?
She told me her name.
When I went into the room,
she thought that I was him.
Anything else?
It didn't make any sense.
Can you tell
me your name?
Ca... Cam... Cammie.
Cammie, I'm Sara.
Who did this to you, Cammie?
Mm-an.... mm-an.
The man, what did he look like?
Poor w...
Poor wine...
Breast...
Breast... knife...
He-he stabbed you in the chest?
(grunts)
No.
I need some help here!
Bye... Fin...
(gasps)
No, no. No.
STOKES: Looks like
he was about a size 11.
You been up there yet?
PHILLIPS:
I've been through all
the bedrooms. She's the last.
Rebecca Mayford.
Boyfriend ID'd her.
Neck's clean.
The other five victims'
throats were transected.
There are at least
a dozen stab wounds
to the chest
and abdomen.
Yeah. He took his time with her.
The others were
killed efficiently.
Liver temp is 95.6.
Been dead
at least two hours, which
is consistent with four
of the five other victims.
David, don't move any
of the bodies just yet, okay?
You got it.
Hey.
What did
you find?
Partial footprint.
Whoever kicked in this window
was barefoot.
She's wearing socks.
Yeah, but some
of the others weren't.
Means one of them must have
been in here at some point.
I don't think this was her room.
GRISSOM:
What else?
Looks like the bindings
were cut from the sheets.
It takes at least a few minutes
to cut up a sheet.
I think when he came to this
house, he was unprepared.
He had to use things
that were already here.
They say a disorganized killer
is apt to obtain
his victims by chance.
Luck of the draw.
Busy night.
She looks so familiar.
When I first
started doing this,
everybody I worked on
reminded me of someone.
Somehow,
we all get past it.
I'm not so sure
that's a good thing.
I'll start
with the bathroom.
The girl in this picture
is the victim from my room.
MAN'S RECORDED VOICE FROM BEAR:
Becca, I'm so crazy about you.
I just wanted to tell you
happy three-week anniversary!
You're awesome!
And I love you bear-y much.
Sounds like Becca
was still a kid.
Yeah. Well,
not when she was onstage.
So, Grissom, I found
beige carpet fibers
on all three victims.
It's consistent with
the hallway carpet.
I've also found rug
burns on their knees.
Killer herded them all
into here,
he used the sheets from that bed
to tie them up,
then dragged them all
down the hallway
to the other two bedrooms
to kill them.
(muffled screams)
What about Becca?
Why wasn't she dragged
somewhere else?
Maybe he wanted
to get her alone.
Maybe she excited him...
or pissed him off.
Either way,
he was brutal with her.
She was the messiest kill.
He had a gun.
I found grip and
slide impressions
in some powder on
the bathroom counter.
Well, a gun is one good
way for crowd control.
Why didn't he
just shoot them?
Noise factor?
You can't scream once
your throat's been slit.
Yeah.
He had all the time he needed
'cause the neighbors
couldn't hear a thing.
(garbled radio transmission)
(camera shutter clicking)
(door opening)
He used a chair to jam
this door.
I heard about what happened.
You okay?
I'm fine.
There's a custom-made label
on a wine bottle over there.
"Love, Lewis."
SIDLE:
Who did this to you, Cammie?
Mm-an.... mm-an.
The man,
what did he look like?
Poor w...
Poor wine.
Cammie said something.
"Poor wine."
Maybe it had something to do
with this bottle.
"Poor wine."
Maybe he forced wine
down her throat.
Tox will tell us.
It was good
that you were there
for her, Sara.
She didn't have
to die alone.
We usually show up too late
to meet the victim.
RADIO REPORTER:
Police have confirmed
there are a total of six victims
in the Green Valley
showgirl murders.
The names have not yet
been released
pending individual
identification
and notification
of their families.
According to police sources,
there are no suspects
at this time.
LVPD has asked anyone
with any information
to call the following
hotline number:
702-555-0132.
Again, that number...
(camera shutter clicking)
♪ ♪
ROBBINS:
All six victims
had ligature marks
on their ankles and wrists.
Jenn Smith was the only one
with rib fractures.
She took some abuse.
Except for Becca Mayford,
COD was exsanguination through
incised wounds to the neck
with a sharp-edged
instrument.
How did Cammie Brookston
survive until we got there?
Well, in her case,
there was only a partial
transection of the jugular.
Shallower cut, slower bleed.
I found her at least two hours
after the attacks.
She must've applied
pressure to her wound.
That would've bought her
some time.
So if we'd have
found her sooner,
she would still be alive.
Sara, there's nothing
you could've done.
Well, she has a C-section
uterine scar.
Hairline, almost invisible.
She has a child.
Well, she gave birth
some time ago.
Any signs of sexual assault?
Not with Cammie.
I found semen in the vaginas
of Emily Wilson
and Lauren Walderson.
Both had mild reddening
and some superficial abrasion
at the vaginal introitus.
They could have had
consensual sex
in the hours prior
to the attack.
This young lady was raped.
Rebecca Mayford had lacerations
at 3:00.
Contusions extended from 4:00
to 8:00 and 10:00 to 12:00.
Any semen?
No.
But, uh, look at
these puncture wounds.
Stab wounds have
a large cutting component
to the margins.
Several of these stabs
have additional tracks
through the organ suggesting
a partial withdrawal
and re-thrust of the blade.
Is that everything then?
Not quite.
He left something
behind.
SIDLE:
The tip of the knife.
GRISSOM:
Yes, sir, I understand that,
but, uh, we're still analyzing
the evidence.
As soon as we have something
to report, we'll report it.
Okay.
I may have something for
you to feed to the monster.
An attack order based
on the blood evidence.
In the bathroom trash,
I found six bloody
paper towels.
Wendy ran the DNA.
Each towel has blood
from only one victim.
Bottom of the pile--
first victim,
top of the pile-- last.
And the pattern
on each
is consistent with
the knife being wiped off.
I think that the killer
cleaned off the knife
after each kill.
First was Emily...
then Lauren...
Both found in Warrick's bedroom.
Libby was next.
She was found dead
in Sara's bedroom.
Then Cammie was attacked,
followed by Jennifer.
She was found on the floor
in Warrick's bedroom.
There's no logic to any of this.
But you were right,
Becca was attacked last.
It was all of her blood that was
tracked throughout the house.
He stepped in her blood,
walks into the bathroom
to clean off the knife,
back out into the hallway
down the stairs.
But why would he clean off
the knife between victims?
To maintain control.
I see a clean knife,
I think that the others
are still alive and...
I'm more compliant.
This is Sara Sidle.
Leave a message after the tone.
(beeps)
Sara, the knife tip Doc Robbins
extracted from Becca Mayford
isn't metal, it's ceramic...
and extremely sharp.
I accept your thank you
in advance and you're welcome.
(buzzing)
Hello?
Uh, no, ma'am, Libby's not here.
My name is David Hodges.
I work for the Las Vegas
crime lab.
Well, ma'am, uh...
I can't really say...
but I can give you the number
of someone who can.
Did your daughter Libby
wear a heart-shaped necklace?
Y-Y-Yes, yeah, I-I'm still here.
Uh, ma'am...
I don't know quite
how to say this, but, um...
I'm afraid I have some bad news.
I matched Jenn Smith's
footprints with a partial
Grissom lifted from
that broken window.
According to Catherine's
attack order,
Cammie was stabbed first
and then Jenn.
He didn't get sloppy
with Cammie,
he got distracted.
So he was with Cammie
when Jenn tried to escape.
(banging, muffled yelling)
(glass cracks)
Which explains
Jenn's fractures.
He kicked the crap
out of her.
He must have gone
to the bathroom,
cleaned off the knife,
then dragged Jenn down
the hallway to kill her.
He never went back
to check on Cammie.
BROWN:
Six girls, one lock.
JOHNSON:
I ran the names
of all the victims.
This article's
the only common link.
"They pooled their money
and lived the dream in style."
JOHNSON:
This could definitely
bait a killer.
The only thing missing
from this is their address.
It says "Green Valley,"
it's got a photo of the house.
If you looked hard enough,
you could find it.
Lewis Greyburg
wrote the article.
"Lewis" is the name
on a custom wine label
that we found
at the crime scene.
Do me a favor.
Could you zoom in
on that photo?
Oh, my God.
I knew I recognized her.
Emily Wilson.
Figures you'd know
a showgirl.
Take it you've
seen her dance, then, huh?
No, last time I saw her,
she was still wearing braces.
(dog barking in distance)
Warrick Brown.
I remember you standing
on my steps
with those guilty green eyes,
afraid to come in
because you knew your
grandma would size you up
no matter what kind of trouble
you got into.
I don't remember any trouble.
Like when you were
13 years old
and you took her new Buick
out for a spin.
Oh, and I banged the bumper
trying to parallel park.
I forgot about that one.
Mm-hmm.
I haven't seen you
since your grandma passed.
Yeah, the old neighborhood
reminds me
how much
I miss her.
So why you here?
I came to see you.
Oh.
Let me take that
for you.
New family painted
right over my history.
That's 'cause they're
making their own history.
You know, my daughter
Chelsea died last August.
Oh, God.
Mm-hmm. Lung cancer.
She never smoked
a day in her life,
but her sorry husband did.
He's healthy
as an ox.
Mrs. Wilson...
You were always
interrupting your grandma.
but-but she liked that.
That's because you were
thinking, she said.
Oh, she was proud of you.
You remember my little
granddaughter, Emily.
The next time you
drive up the Strip,
you, you going to see
her little buns in lights
'cause she's a dancer now.
Uh-huh.
Um...
What, what, what, what?
I'm working this case.
Those six showgirls...
The ones in the news?
Emily listed you
as the next of kin.
No.
Oh, oh, please, God...
No!
I'm so sorry.
I'm sorry.
Oh...
We're pursuing a number of leads
based on evidence
gathered at the scene.
Now, we believe
that our suspect targeted
one individual in particular
and that's where the
investigation is focused.
Look, look, we have every
available police officer
out looking for him.
He can run, but he can't hide.
So, Mr. Greyburg, you
don't want a lawyer?
Why would I need a lawyer?
I sent the wine over
to express my gratitude
for their cooperation
on the article.
How did you get to know them?
I followed them around for
a week as part of my research.
They were nice kids.
Uh, with big hearts.
It's an airhead piece.
My editor gave me
an angle,
I ran with it.
But those girls
raised $12,000
for a fellow showgirl
with breast cancer.
They organized their
own walk-a-thon.
They gave out swag bags,
kitchen stuff.
What kind of kitchen stuff?
Uh...
cutting board, juicer,
kitchen knife.
Breast...
breast...
He stabbed you in the chest?
No!
Sara.
What did the knife look like?
It had a purple handle embossed
with the name of their friend
and the date.
It was ceramic.
Killer shoes.
There were multiple shoe
impressions in blood
at the house,
looked just like those.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Look, I didn't kill
those girls.
Where were you last night,
Mr. Greyburg?
I was at home alone
working on my novel.
STOKES:
Prove it.
We'll take your little ceramic
knife, give us your shoes,
and we'll take a sample
of your DNA.
You can have whatever you want.
Just stop looking
at me that way.
Wendy swabbed the ligatures
cut from the sheet
for epithelials.
Each knot had one DNA source
on it; female,
but not from the victim
who was tied up.
So he forced them
to tie each other up.
Tighter!
Please don't make me do this.
Thanks.
It was all Wendy.
Hey, Greg.
The, uh, civil suit
that was filed
by the Demitrius James family,
DA decided
not to go to trial.
So the city's agreed
to a payout; $2.5 million.
$2.5 million?
That's like saying
I'm the guilty one.
It's just
political pragmatism.
City wants to cut their losses.
So they did throw me
under the bus.
Comes with the job.
Ran a laser ablation on the
knife tip from Becca's spine.
Zirconium oxide,
otherwise known as ceramic.
Basically,
ceramic is glass.
Both the exemplar that
you got from the reporter
and the murder weapon
have the same composition,
color, texture and thickness.
The killer could have
gotten the knife
from a swag bag
at the walk-a-thon.
Either that or he could
have gotten it from the house.
You find me the broken knife,
and I'll match the tip.
What's wrong with you?
Nothing.
You ever
do the right thing
and still feel
guilty about it?
Yeah.
Sucks, doesn't it?
So I lifted two sets of prints
from the wine bottle,
but there's no match
to any of the victims.
Any hits?
One set was smudges.
I'm guessing whoever
they belonged to works
with their hands.
You know,
calloused, cut.
The other set came back
to a Chris Mullins.
His work card's
in the system.
He's a musician
at the Legs show
where all the
girls danced.
Well, there's a cold brewski
on the table.
We must have just missed him.
Captain?
Yeah, what?
Neighbor gave
this guy up.
Mullins hangs out
at a bar right
down the street.
All right, we'll check it out.
But first we're going
to lose the radio cars.
Post an unmarked.
I'm going to put a broadcast out
on his vehicle.
He's gotta come home
sometime.
Control, this is 2-0-3 Charlie,
Captain Brass.
(over radio): Go ahead, Captain.
(sirens wailing)
Whoo!
Did you call for backup?
Look, uh, two squad cars
just passed rolling Code Three.
I'm at 562
Herrick Drive.
Where are they en route to?
Units are responding
to a 415 Baker in progress
outside the Trip Wire Bar.
Person down, suspect possibly
still in location.
All right, copy that.
I'm headed to the 415B location.
Assault with
a deadly weapon?
Feeling lucky?
Sir, could you move
your hand, please?
Please?
Thank you.
BRASS:
Hey, what do you got?
Marlon Frost, out of state.
Bar patron found him.
Anyone see the suspect?
Mm-mm, no witnesses.
Okay, I'm going inside.
Chris Mullins hangs out here.
Somebody's got
to know something.
Incise wound
to the neck?
Yeah.
Seems to be flavor
of the week.
Did he say anything?
I don't think he can.
STOKES:
Hey, Sara?
Got a knife over here.
Tip's broken off.
That's probably going to be
the murder weapon right there.
(woman whimpering, man grunting)
And it matches the one
from the swag bag.
Crime scene's only
a couple blocks from here.
I'm going to go
with the vic.
I'm going to collect
his clothes.
You sure that's really
such a good idea?
Hold up!
I'm coming with you.
My name is Sara.
Just hold on.
You're going to be fine.
(grunting)
Do you know who did this to you?
BRASS:
Seen this guy?
Marlon Frost?
He was just stabbed
in the parking lot.
Yeah, I seen him around
last couple of days.
Friendly enough.
What, did he get into an
argument or something here?
It's not that
type of place.
Yeah, right.
Uh, how about this guy?
You see him? Chris Mullins?
Yeah, he's a regular of mine.
A-lister with the ladies,
you know.
Has he been in lately?
Why don't you check in the back?
Great.
(toilet flushes)
Chris Mullins?
Yeah?
I hope you washed your hands.
I didn't stab that guy,
I didn't kill those girls.
I will cop to drinking
their wine.
So you're in the house
the night of the murders.
I'd been messing around
with Lauren since last weekend.
You know, you don't seem
too upset that she's dead.
How come your fingerprints
are in every single room
of the house?
It's kind of an inside joke.
We did it
in all her roommates' beds
just to see if they noticed.
But you're only having
sex with Lauren, right?
She was a good place to put it
till something better
came along.
I guess that's funny
to somebody.
But when we get
a warrant
for your DNA and match it
to the semen we found in
Lauren and Emily, the joke
is going to be on you, pal.
I was supposed to meet Lauren
after her last show.
She was late.
Emily was home.
And you couldn't help yourself,
right, stud?
Girl politics.
One wants what the other has.
Why not give it?
So I guess when
Lauren came home,
you gave it to her, too.
Is that right, Santa?
And what about Becca?
Was she blonde?
I didn't meet all the roommates.
Boy, you have an answer
for everything, huh?
What about the
guy in the bar?
What about him,
what did he do,
look at you the wrong
way, bum a smoke?
Or did he want you
to give it to him, too?
You know what?
Lawyer. Now.
BROWN:
Well, DNA confirmed that
Mullins had sex
with Emily and Lauren.
Assuming he's the killer,
why didn't we find
any semen in Becca?
Maybe by the time he got to her,
he was unable to ejaculate.
I was able to make a physical
match between the broken tip
in Becca and the knife recovered
from outside the bar.
GRISSOM:
Was the same knife used
to stab Marlon Frost?
STOKES:
We don't know yet.
Sara's at the hospital now--
she's bringing back a DNA sample
to compare.
Whoever...
shanked Frost
killed those girls.
Did you get any prints
on that knife?
Yeah. No ridge detail.
Same smudges were found
on the wine bottles
and in the bedrooms.
GRISSOM:
Smudges won't put the knife
in Mullins' hands, though.
I don't get it.
He stabs the guy
and walks back in the bar.
All the evidence at the house
suggests that the killer
was unfamiliar with the layout.
And by his own admission,
Mullins had been
in that house
at least a couple of nights.
Well, that's also
how he could've made
the connection to Becca.
(camera shutter clicking)
Mr. Frost,
I'll be out of your way soon.
I'm sure you want
to get some sleep.
I just need to get
your fingerprints.
It's routine.
I promise it won't hurt.
♪ ♪
SIDLE (grunting):
Get off me!
(Sidle gasps)
(woman gasping, yelling)
(distant clattering)
(gasps)
(glass breaking)
(gasping breaths):
Port... port wine... port wine.
He has a vascular birthmark,
a port wine stain,
on his upper chest--
that's what Cammie was
trying to tell me.
We can get DNA
off his bloody clothes,
but we have no blood or semen
at the scene to compare it to.
His prints are useless--
they're all calluses.
They only leave smudges,
like the kind we found
on the broken knife.
I think the bastard
tried to kill himself.
Sara, slow down.
Frost isn't going anywhere.
I am going to nail
this son of a bitch,
and I don't want him to think
for a single second
that he is going
to get away with this.
Okay, one step at a time.
Frost smelled like
alcohol when they
took him into the E.R,
so they ran a tox.
His BAC came back .34--
only a chronic alcoholic
can function at those levels.
You know what I think?
I think he polished off
the wine at the scene
straight from the bottle.
GRISSOM:
So his DNA should be on it.
BRASS:
The suspect's name is
David Marlon. M-A-R-L-O-N.
Also known as
Marlon Frost.
Released from
California state penitentiary
where he served time
for sexual assault.
Mr. Marlon is also wanted in
the questioning of the assault
of an elderly woman in
north Lake Tahoe one week ago.
We believe he stole her vehicle
and then fled to Las Vegas.
Where'd Brass find it?
A block away from the bar.
Guy didn't even bother
to switch plates.
Smart.
(chuckles):
Whoa.
One, two...
three, four, five, six...
ladies' handbags.
Rebecca Mayford.
Becca.
Mm. Looks like she was
trying to quit smoking.
And failing.
Miserably.
There is only one
missing.
Here we go.
Bought at the Trip Wire Bar
at 12:48 a.m.
same night as the murders.
That's where Marlon and Becca
crossed paths.
There you go.
Appreciate it. Bye.
I got a gun.
It's plastic.
It's a toy.
Looks real to me.
Imagine if you're petrified.
How'd you find me?
Cammie had these
in her wallet.
We tracked you from
the birth certificate.
She's a cutie.
What's her name?
Fin.
After Cammie's grandmother.
But her adoptive parents
call her Annabelle.
She kept in touch with them?
They're pretty cool.
We didn't have contact, but...
they would send Cammie a photo
every year on Fin's birthday.
And every year,
Cammie and I would get together,
have a beer, look at it.
Biggest regret of my life
is not marrying Cammie
and raising Fin together.
I wanted to, but...
she said we were too young.
Maybe if we had...
Corey...
you can't blame yourself.
Were you with her
when she died?
At least Cammie died
knowing kindness.
SIDLE:
Stay with me, Cammie.
Bye... Fin...
(weak gasp)
(stops breathing)
MARLON:
I watched the life
go out of their eyes.
Um, life drains.
That's... that's how
you can tell they're dead.
They have, uh, empty eyes.
BRASS:
That's not what
I asked you.
What I asked you was,
why did you kill them?
I saw this girl I liked
at the bar.
I followed her home.
I knew she wanted to party.
I chose her.
Girls act... sometimes like they
don't want what they want...
because they want you
to take it.
They like that.
But this girl...
she was flirting with me.
And I... I just gave her
the party of her life.
You know, there's something
I don't understand, Marlon.
(whispers):
Why are you smiling?
You feel good about this?
I don't feel anything.
Nothing.
(on TV):
Las Vegas PD has confirmed
that David Marlon confessed
earlier today
to the murders of
the six Green Valley showgirls.
He was found within a block
of the crime scene
in an apparent suicide attempt.
I've just been informed...
I held his hand.
...has confirmed the names
of the six victims.
They are Cammie...
Just like I held hers.
Libby Cooperson 22,
Becca Mayfield, 20...
I lost perspective.
...Lauren Walderson 21
and Emily Wilson, 19.
Their families have organized
a candlelight vigil
that will begin here tonight.