♪ ♪
(indistinct police radio
transmission)
BRASS:
Construction
crew found him
when they came
into work this morning.
The woman's dead.
The guy's still alive,
but he's not talking.
Wouldn't even give me
his name, even after
I gave him my name.
GRISSOM:
Did you, uh, pull his wallet?
No, everything is just
the way I found it.
I mean, I figure some
knucklehead, you know,
came in off the street,
found him,
figured he had a free pass,
and picked his pocket.
(Willows and Brass laughing)
Anyway, I'm, uh...
I'm talking to people.
I'll, uh, I'll let you know
what we find out.
GRISSOM:
Catherine...
Do you need a minute?
(laughing):
Yes, I'm...
Yes, I'm... (clears throat)
I mean...
No, Gil. I'm good.
So, how's
your day going?
(chuckling)
Lady...
the best day I ever had is worse
than the worst day
you've ever imagined.
Oh, I doubt that.
Who's your lady friend?
Never saw that woman before
in my life.
Uh, look, you're
not going anywhere.
It'll be a lot better for
you if you just cooperate
and tell us what happened.
You want to know
what happened?
Mm-hmm.
Figure it out yourself.
That's the fun part.
(Willows chuckles)
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
(indistinct police radio
transmission)
CURTIS:
Hey.
STOKES:
¿Que pasa?
CURTIS:
One of the residents reported
smelling a gas leak at 6:00 a.m.
He, uh, called the gas company.
They arrived;
they evacuated the building.
I'm surprised anyone
picked out a gas leak
through the rest
of the stench around here.
Yeah, smells like
used diapers.
The gas boys traced the leak
to this apartment,
and that was when they found...
this.
Whoa.
Alyona Ivanovna.
Manager said she's lived here
alone for 27 years.
Head in the oven...
It's kind of a classic, huh?
BROWN:
Maybe not.
I mean, this apartment
is neat as a pin.
A lady this tidy
wouldn't leave a broken dish
in a rack like that, you know?
It doesn't necessarily indicate
foul play.
I checked the doors
and the window.
There's no sign
of forced entry.
What do you make of this?
A busted phone...
with gray hairs in it.
She's definitely got
gray hair.
(hammering)
(construction workers shouting
indistinctly)
Single stab wound,
just below the sternum.
It feels domestic.
Crime of passion?
Him?
PHILLIPS:
Good point.
(loud clattering)
Hey!
Hey! Hey!
(jackhammer stops)
You ready to give me a name?
You know, you are
in a very deep hole,
in every sense
of the word, my friend.
Think about that
while we chisel you out.
It's going to take
a few hours...
assuming we're careful.
See ya.
(clattering resumes)
It's just a guess,
but I'd say she's in rigor.
PHILLIPS:
Blunt-force trauma
on the forehead,
and on the base of the skull.
I doubt very highly
that those were self-induced.
Look at that:
it's dented.
Looks like she may have been
slammed into her own oven.
Yep.
PHILLIPS:
She's been dead
at least 12 hours.
I've got a substance
on her... right ear.
She doesn't really look like
the hair gel type.
Hang on a second, fellas.
Look at that.
Her dentures...
they were in upside down.
Hey. You're coming with me.
We got another 419
out by Nellis.
Wow, busy night.
Any details?
They tell me it tastes
just like chicken.
(chickens clucking)
(indistinct police radio
transmission)
BRASS:
The dead guy in the bath
is Raymundo Suarez.
He works the night shift.
He cleans the equipment
from 8:00 p.m. to 4:00 a.m.
The day-shift guys came in,
found him like this.
The foreman here
called it in.
This basin is designed to
transfer an electrical current.
Of course it does.
It's a stun bath.
We use it to stun
the chickens
before they go
into the next room.
Where they get
their throats cut.
Which is why
we electrocute them first.
It's humane.
SANDERS:
Was the current on
when you found the body?
No, sir, it was off;
it stays off all night.
FOREMAN:
Hey, uh, how long
is this gonna take?
As long as it takes.
I got a lot of birds piling up
outside.
They're gonna die
out there in that heat.
BRASS:
Well, it's not like they're
gonna do any better in here.
Come on, I want
to talk to your crew.
Maybe he was high.
Passes out and falls in?
How does he end up face down
in the middle of the bath?
Kind of tough to drown
in three inches of water.
Not impossible, though.
If he hit the water
when the current was on,
his muscles could've
contracted,
making it impossible for him
to get out.
SANDERS:
But the machine's off at night,
and it was off
when they found the body.
Which means someone turned it
off after he was dead.
Yeah.
Who?
(chickens clucking)
BRASS:
All right, what's your name,
and what do you do here?
Name's Ernie Dell.
Maintenance man.
I work 3:00 to 11:00.
Mm-hmm.
You see the victim
last night?
Uh, yeah, and Raymundo
was just fine when I left.
You and Raymundo
get along?
Kept my nose
out of his business;
he kept his out of mine.
Didn't have a problem with him.
But you know somebody who did?
Well, between you and me,
the guy you ought to be talking
to is Ike Mannleigh.
Oh. You mean the guy
who owns the company?
Well, Raymundo's pretty far down
on the pecking order.
You think the big boss
had a problem with him?
No. Not unless you think
a guy banging your wife
is a problem.
(erotic moaning)
(chickens clucking)
(woman moaning)
Can't blame him, though.
Bubbles Mannleigh is
a cheap whore.
Did you and Bubbles
take a tumble?
Me? Nah.
Reminds me too much
of my mother.
Besides, uh...
Bubbles likes the dark meat.
(camera shutter clicking)
Unappetizing place to get
your rocks off.
Not if you have
a poultry fetish.
You got something?
Yeah, I think so.
One more chance.
♪ ♪
SIDLE:
You look like a kid
who's just found
the prize at the bottom
of a Cracker Jacks box.
Definitely some kind of doll.
It sure is.
Three
different views
of the same
dead doll.
Maybe this is more
than a signature.
Maybe there's something
these victims have in common.
First two victims were white,
third Hispanic,
two men,
one woman, one rich,
two poor, one young,
two old, one famous,
two obscure...
Yeah.
And unfortunately,
this is the best lead
we have for their killer.
This is the most
that Archie
could get
off that video?
Yeah, well, with the
equipment we have here.
I'm getting Raymundo's
cell phone records.
I'm gonna see if any of his
calls are a match to the numbers
that Penny Garden
and Izzy Delancy had in common.
Whatever happened
with that number
we got off
the disposable cell phone?
Any luck with that?
Disposable phone numbers
are assigned
by the carrier
to the phone distributors.
It took a little bit of legwork,
but I did find the store
where the phone was sold.
Let me guess.
It was paid for with cash.
Yeah.
Mannleigh Chickens.
What about it?
I'll let you know.
See how it feels?
You know, we're getting
kind of backed up in here.
The only one I hear
complaining about it is you.
Your cement lady's
approximately
40 to 45 years old.
COD is exsanguination
due to laceration
of the right ventricle.
Wound seven centimeters long,
five millimeters wide.
That looks like it could be
a double-edged blade.
It's pretty thick, too.
Well, it passed into the heart
with point of entry midline
just below the xiphoid process.
Upward thrust.
I just said that.
Okay.
Any idea
what the weapon
might have been?
If I knew, I would've told you.
I got to get
to work.
Taxpayers are getting
their money's worth tonight.
(camera shutter clicking)
Thank you.
Tingles.
You take them out,
he puts them back in.
What is it?
It's acetic acid.
Do you do feet?
I got a bunion
that could use some soaking.
What's this do?
Takes your
fingerprints.
Mmm.
Good luck with that.
How's Mr. Hoffa?
Hey, Jim.
Cathy and I are just
getting reacquainted.
Will Gilbert be stopping by?
I take it we don't
have a name yet.
No.
I bet you ten bucks that
I have you made by 9:00 p.m.
You're on.
Okay, Hodges.
What do you got?
HODGES:
The green trace
on your old lady.
Adipic acid, disodium phosphate,
sodium citrate,
fumaric acid, Yellow #5,
Blue #1,
BHA, a whole lot of gelatin,
and sugar.
Which is?
Oh, come on.
There's always room for it.
Just tell me
what it is, Hodges.
Jell-O. Lime Jell-O.
Lime Jell-O?
I tell you what.
You tell me why.
♪ ♪
(camera clicking)
CURTIS:
Clear.
(chuckles):
Oh, boy.
Looks like somebody
cleaned up in a hurry.
More green Jell-O.
Sofia, you get
a tenant's name
for this apartment?
According to
the management office,
this apartment's a sublet,
has been for years.
He's not sure
who lives here.
I got blood, too.
This place has a direct view
of the old lady's apartment.
So, what, the guy's
killing the old lady,
he sees he's being watched,
and he, what,
comes back here
and whacks the witness?
It's possible.
But why get rid of this body
and leave the old lady?
IZZY:
Hi. I'm Izzy Delancy.
And back in my bad old days,
I'd do almost anything
to sell albums.
People even accused me of
biting the heads off
live chickens on stage.
I'm not proud of that.
But I've worked hard to change.
And with the help
of the good Lord,
14 years of therapy
and two loving wives,
I humbly believe
I've made progress.
But this story is not
about Izzy Delancy.
It's about something
much, much bigger:
cruelty.
Did you know that every day
in the United States,
more chickens are killed
than all the people
in the Rwandan genocide?
Now, you may argue,
"Izzy, African people
are not a food source."
Well, you're missing
the point entirely.
Cruelty is cruelty,
whether the victim be a chicken
or a malnourished African.
Where did you find this?
I like animals,
and after
the Delancy murder,
I brushed up on my history.
As it turns out,
three years ago,
Izzy Delancy had
a midlife awakening
and became
an animal rights activist.
He starred in and financed this
PSA targeting Mannleigh Chickens
as the epitome
of everything that is wrong
in the slaughter industry.
It takes a manly man
to make a Mannleigh chicken.
(rooster crowing)
IZZY:
Now, perhaps you've purchased
Mannleigh Roasters,
Fryers or Assorted Parts
at your local grocery store,
and you believe
you're eating chicken.
But what you're really eating
is cruelty.
Our undercover investigators
secretly recorded
workers at a Mannleigh
processing plant
throwing loose animals
up against the wall,
stomping up and down on them,
kicking them across the room.
How bad did Mannleigh
get hurt by this?
His sales
dropped 60%.
He launched
a very expensive PR campaign
to rehabilitate his image,
including
retrofitting a plant
with cruelty-free
equipment.
His business never recovered.
He probably hated Delancy.
MANNLEIGH:
I have no idea
how Raymundo ended up dead.
I liked that boy.
Apparently, so did your wife.
She was spending
some quality time
with Raymundo down at the plant.
If I killed every guy
that banged my Bubbles,
they'd be stacking up
like cord wood.
So you have no problem with it?
Look. Bubbles is
an insatiable slut,
but she's my slut,
and I love her.
I don't expect you
to understand.
Oh, I get it.
Do you know this woman?
I've never seen her
before in my life.
How about him?
Let's not screw around here.
You know I knew him,
and you know I hated him.
That jerk nearly put me
into Chapter 11.
He ended up dead, too.
And I sent his wife a Hallmark
and a case of frozen
chickens the day he died.
He was murdered.
That's what I heard, too.
We're done here.
You want to call
my attorney or should I?
♪ ♪
Whoo, whoo-whoo!
Thank you, Hodges.
I can see that it's a train.
Yeah, it's
Locomotiveville.
Sorry. Thought you
might be a member.
(siren whoops)
(police radio indistinct)
(knocking)
Ernie Dell?
Las Vegas Police. Open up.
Clear.
Nobody's home.
(electricity powers on)
(model trains run along tracks)
BRASS:
Sanders.
There's a workshop
in the basement.
♪ ♪
CURTIS:
One of the other residents
ID'd the tenant
in the sublet apartment
as Paula Sullivan.
That's good.
Well, it's better
than good.
Apparently Paula Sullivan
does a little day care
on the side.
We have a witness.
Hi. I'm Warrick Brown
from the Crime Lab.
Hi.
My Suzy was in that
apartment yesterday.
And she was filthy
when they sent her back,
and I marched right
over there to give Paula
a piece of my mind,
and she wasn't home.
Paula wasn't there.
Max watched me.
He's nice.
Her husband. Neither of them
was there when I went back.
Well, ma'am, we're going to need
your daughter's clothes
from yesterday.
I like you. You're a giant.
(chuckles)
And you're a princess.
Thank you.
BROWN:
Okay, Suzy,
tell me about Max.
What's Max like?
Max is my friend.
He's a lion tamer
and an astronaut and a spy.
Guy always kinda
creeped me out.
How come you didn't know
that Paula Sullivan wasn't home?
We live across the courtyard.
Bye.
I send Suzy over.
I watch until she gets inside.
I went in.
It was a big mess.
A big mess?
What color was the mess?
Red and green.
(door opens and closes)
MAN:
Don't eat that.
(giggling)
Max came into the kitchen
in his underpants.
Hmm...
Did Max try to hug you
or touch you?
Oh, no. He went
and got dressed.
Did Max seem surprised
to see all that
big mess there?
(mumbles):
I don't know.
What did Max do next?
He started cleaning
up the big mess.
I bet he didn't want
to get in trouble.
I bet you're right.
You know what?
Could you help me?
I've got a picture
right here.
And I have
some crayons, too.
Could you draw where
the red and the green
is in the room?
So the green was all the way up
here in the cabinets, too?
He, um, he had to stand
on a chair to reach it.
Did you help him
clean up the mess?
At first, but
then he said
there was sharp stuff,
so I watched TV.
(TV playing I Love Lucy)
And then what happened?
Then I watched some more TV.
Then I watched
some more TV,
and then I watched some more TV,
and then I went home.
♪ ♪
(molding gun clicking)
BRASS:
Do these belong to you?
You know damned well they do.
You took 'em from my house.
They're mine
and I want them back.
So you worked
with Raymundo Suarez.
Did you know
Izzy Delancy?
Everybody knows Izzy Delancy.
He's famous.
Used to do it to his music.
And how did he
thank you for that?
Public humiliation?
And you knew
Penny Garden.
Who?
You delivered a package
to her house.
You're a handyman.
What'd you fix for her?
I don't know anything
about that.
Lots of guys got them shirts.
Do you have
any idea how...
...your work ended up
at crime scenes from
three different murders?
I've been making scale models
since I was nine years old.
I sell my stuff at craft fairs,
to hobby shops,
over the Internet,
every damned place.
Sold things to hundreds
of people over the years.
Any of them could have ended up
in the hands of your killer.
You're just picking
on an old man
'cause you got nothing.
We're just talking here, Ernie.
We're just talking.
You charging me with something?
You want a cup of coffee, Ernie?
We got decaf.
Charge me or let me go.
I want a lawyer.
You're free to go.
So was he right?
Are we really just
picking on an old man
or is he the bad guy?
Well, he's associated
peripherally
with all the victims,
and he certainly has
the right skills.
Yeah... he spent
half his life
in Locomotiveville.
I know what it's like to lose
yourself in little things.
After a while it gets to you.
WILLOWS (on phone):
We're coming up goose eggs
on Cement Boy
and his lady friend.
BRASS:
You got to be kidding?
No hits on AFIS,
no hits on CODIS.
Guy's got no work card,
and his keys weren't a match
for any vehicle
in a three-block radius
of the construction site.
Unbelievable.
Apparently, just a couple
of law-abiding folk.
Well, keep me posted.
(closes cell phone)
Hello, Jim.
Hello.
Hello... who?
You know, I don't need
your name to arrest you.
I can call you John Doe.
Okay, let's assume
for the moment
that you did know
the dead lady
laying five feet from
where we found you.
I'm gonna go out
on a limb here
and say that you
killed her, and then you tried
to dispose of her body,
but you did something
very, very stupid.
Are you with me so far?
Interesting.
Do you have the time, Jim?
Yeah.
'Cause it looks like
it's half-past.
You owe me ten bucks.
(chuckles)
Make sure this goes
in his personal effects.
Now, I'm gonna suggest
you get a name tag,
put the name "Trixie" on it,
'cause that's what
your cell mates
will be calling you.
Take him
to his cell.
Anybody want anything
from the vending machines?
Come on. It's on me.
Actually, it's on Jimbo.
Took this baby off of
Captain Brass myself.
Look at me, generating income
my first day in the joint.
Yeah, Mom would be so proud.
Not hungry? Soda, maybe?
Anybody?
Hi, Max!
Hi, Suzy.
(imitating Suzy):
"Hi, Max."
Yeah, I killed my wife,
but it was an accident.
You accidentally
stabbed her through the heart?
That's right.
Believe me or don't believe me.
I don't care. It's the truth.
(groans)
(groans):
Oh, Max.
You got coffee
on your shirt.
You're gonna
be late again.
Could I please
just get some...
Oh!
(groans):
Oh.
Idiot.
(groans):
Oh.
God...
(smoke detector beeping)
(grunts)
BRASS:
Max, I want to believe you,
but I...
(chuckles)
MAX:
If I wanted to kill her,
do you think I would've
dropped a bowl of Jell-O
and stabbed her
with a piece of broken glass?
But if it was an accident,
why didn't you just
pick up the phone
and call the police?
Because I killed my granny.
Okay?
(muffled screams,
air pumping steadily)
MAX:
It was a long time ago,
and it was an accident.
(flatline tone beeping)
She stroked out.
It wasn't my fault.
They never should've
put the oxygen line there.
They let me
off for that,
but I didn't think anyone
would believe me this time.
You were never convicted
of killing your grandmother.
No.
Which is why you don't
have a record.
You would've found out
eventually
and held it against me.
All right,
what about your neighbor?
Mrs. Ivanovna-- did you kill
her or was that an accident?
I just wanted to talk to her.
MAX:
You know, I thought
I could make it be okay.
Mrs. Ivanovna?
Hello.
What do you want?
Good morning.
Uh, I was wondering if I
might borrow some sugar.
I get sugar.
You stay.
Sure.
I get sugar.
Stay!
Yeah.
I get.
Yes.
I get. You stay.
I can't have my coffee
without my sugar.
The last thing I wanted to do
was hurt that lady.
Mrs. Ivanovna,
it's not what you think!
No, Mrs. Ivanovna,
it's not what you think.
You don't understand.
It was an accident.
Mrs. Ivanovna?
She was dead.
So, you know, I thought...
maybe I'd make it
look like a suicide.
(sighs)
It was not...
a good start to the day.
♪ ♪
Don't eat that!
After Suzy went back
to her mother,
I decided to, you know...
What, to give your wife--
your beloved wife--
a proper burial?
Something like that.
But along the way,
I had a bit of car trouble.
♪ ♪
Few hours later,
some punk wanders over
and swiped my wallet.
That's my life.
That's who I am.
I'm the guy who
buys his daughter
a puppy for her eighth birthday,
and the next day, he backs out
of the driveway and...
BRASS:
No. No.
Don't tell me
you ran over the puppy.
MAX:
No.
I ran over my daughter.
20 years later,
she still walks funny.
(stifled laughter)
(laughing):
I'm sorry.
It's horrible.
But it's really funny.
(laughing)
It's horrible
and it's funny.
Are you okay?
A guy kills two people
before breakfast
that he had no intention
of killing
when he woke up that morning.
By all accounts,
he's led a meager life,
an unnoticed life.
And then all of
a sudden, in a flash,
it's over.
And now, for him,
the real suffering begins.
You're tired.
Yeah.
SIDLE:
Hey.
Guess what.
Mankind has reached
a new evolutionary plateau,
and starting tomorrow, no one
will rape, murder or maim again.
Uh, no.
Too bad.
But we did catch a break on that
disposable cell phone number.
Raymundo Suarez
called it as well.
No, he didn't.
But according to the carrier,
additional minutes were
recently purchased with a credit
card belonging to Ernie Dell.
Brass is already on it.
They're picking him up.
We've got the
miniature killer.
♪ ♪
(beep)
RECORDED VOICE:
You have new messages.
My name is Ernest Edward Dell.
I was born in 1946
in Ames, Iowa.
My life's been hard,
but I don't complain.
I never expected better.
I'm good with my hands.
I make things. I fix things.
I'm a handyman.
That's what I am.
A man has a right
to an honest day's pay.
Me, I service
the machinery of death
so that people can eat.
If that makes me evil,
then so be it.
I'm not the sociable type.
I know that.
Spend any amount of time
around people,
you get your heart broke.
Treachery, hypocrisy.
Promise of love.
(model train running)
Look into the mouth of a person,
and you'll find lies
wriggling there like maggots
waiting to grow wings.
The world has gone mad.
A man could kill
from sunup to sunset,
and still his work
would never be done.