(spurs jingling)
(thunder rumbling)
(jangling spurs
approaching)
(thunder crashing)
You're late.
Now say it.
(tinny piano playing off-key)
I said... say it.
You have to say it.
Say it.
(gagging)
Is she going
to be okay?
Yes, ma'am,
she's stable.
Severe trauma to the neck.
Heather, I'm Catherine Willows.
I don't know if you remember me.
It's going to be all right.
Like a bad penny, some people
just keep showing up.
Did you call Grissom?
Who found her?
Guy over there
in the ten gallon--
Vernon Porter.
He's a night watchman.
All the employees are required
to wear that cowboy getup.
That's the job that
cops get after they retire.
You've got something
to look forward to, Jim.
(piano playing jaunty tune)
Yes, ma'am.
WILLOWS:
Chewing tobacco. Looks fresh.
(piano playing)
Lady Heather has
a house for this.
Why take her show
on the road?
Do you think you
know how to...?
Yeah.
(piano stops)
Oh, you're a genius.
Well, this is
where we found her.
WILLOWS:
Did she have
ligature marks?
On her neck, yeah.
Well, that doesn't
make any sense.
She was a dominatrix.
Not a submissive.
Maybe the party just got
out of control.
Or somebody didn't know
the rules.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
How you doing?
These files are
out of control.
Typos, white-outs,
names missing,
whole sections missing.
20 years ago,
the county was still
using typewriters.
Did you find anything?
Ernie Dell's foster child.
Donna Catalani.
Lived with the
Dells for a year.
Her CASA report came
with a supplemental.
They forgot to black out
her social security number.
We can use that
to track her down,
unless the adoptives
changed it.
Good. I'll run it.
I have to pull you off of this.
Days is down to four CSIs.
You're on loan-out.
Why can't Days keep anybody?
Money, stress, Ecklie, maybe.
Just help them
with their backlog.
So you're sure that
the gate was locked?
I come on at 6:00
when Oakley's closes.
The first thing I do
is lock the gate.
Make my rounds
every two hours.
8:00, 10:00, 12:00--
everything was Code 4.
When did things go Code 3?
Found the main gate unlocked
at 0214.
Went to check out the street,
heard that music.
Found her on the floor,
called it in.
SIDLE:
This is a family theme park.
I'm assuming they don't
actually serve alcohol here.
Must have brought their own.
Single malt, 30 years old.
S &amp; M is a rich man's sport.
Kind of like hockey--
a lot of equipment.
How much do you think
a night like this would cost?
Heather told me, five years ago,
she was clearing
20 grand a week.
And that was before
ladyheather.com.
What is she like?
Beautiful...
smart, intense...
charming.
The only woman I've ever seen
rattle Grissom.
I mean, he kind
of liked that
forensic anthropologist,
Terry Miller.
Remember her?
Yeah.
But she wasn't enough
of a challenge for him.
Heather, on the other hand...
uninhibited and can beat him
at mental chess.
They had chemistry.
And he is a scientist.
I have no proof
and I know he'd
never tell me,
but I'm certain they
spent the night together.
Wonder which one
wore the chaps.
Lots of... (clears throat)
...coins and toothpicks.
They don't sweep under here.
I mean, more power
to him, really,
to find somebody outside of work
'cause you start fishing
from the company pier, and...
asking for trouble.
I got a shot glass.
Looks like there's some
lipstick around the rim.
My fantasy does not
include costumes,
or pain...
and certainly
not sawdust.
You?
CURTIS:
Patrol found her.
Any witnesses?
No. No businesses open,
no cars on the side streets.
So how'd she get here?
CURTIS:
Well, in this
neighborhood,
unless she's a hooker,
I doubt she walked.
I'm going to go
make some calls,
see if any of
these places
have any security cameras.
Thanks.
That's a pretty nasty
head wound.
Where's Super Dave?
He's probably at the 420
on Flamingo.
They left their purse.
Oh!
The thing is heavier
than my kid.
Ever get hit in the head
with one of these?
No. Gentlemen don't get hit
in the head with those.
BROWN:
Gentlemen...
Keysha Sayrun?
Well, that's not her.
Maybe it's not her purse.
BROWN:
There's a whole bunch
of wallets in here.
Driver's permit.
Kid's only 15--
has got a credit card?
She's got to be
a pickpocket.
Aw, man, that's a shame.
Look at her.
She could be anything
she wanted to be.
Makes you wonder
what happens to people.
I got her.
Faith Maroney.
Twenty-five...
from Southern Highlands.
Sometimes I miss the days
when I didn't take this job
so personally, Warrick.
Yeah? Well, I miss
the days
when we only had
five homicides a week.
(phone ringing)
Grissom.
Catherine.
I'm on my way.
I was planning
an Old West party.
I was checking out
the facilities.
So why couldn't you
check them out during
normal business hours?
It was my normal
business hours.
You know, we spoke
to the night watchman.
He said the gate was locked.
How did you get in?
I know the owner.
Do you know him the way
you know Judge Fincher?
Because I know
that's how you got
out of jail last time.
I need a name.
Mr. Oakley.
I have his number,
but not on me.
You'll have to look it up.
(knocking)
Hi.
I'm with the crime lab.
Sara Sidle.
I'm here to
collect your clothes
and trace evidence
from your body.
Can I say no?
Why would you want to?
Did the nurse forget
to collect an SAE kit?
Not necessary.
You don't want help,
that's okay by me.
Just don't waste
my time.
I've got a lot of cases
on my desk that need
my attention.
So when you come out
of your haze, give me a call.
(door closing)
I don't respond well to men
who judge me
based solely on my profession.
I get that a lot, too.
Law enforcement.
May I move your hair?
These look like rope marks
on your neck.
Grissom.
I'll be done in a minute.
(yawns)
What's the matter, Doc,
you been hitting it
a little too hard?
No, canine-induced
insomnia.
We're fostering some
puppies-- Jack Russells.
Had me up all night.
How about a puppy
to keep you company?
No, if I stay up all night,
it's not going to be
because of a puppy.
C.O.D.?
Okay, blunt
force trauma
to the left temporal
region of the skull.
The skull's fractured.
Any idea what kind of weapon
might have been used?
No, but I found these
imbedded in the skull.
Paint chips?
Could she have been
hit by a car?
Well, it's possible.
But if she was standing
when she was hit,
I'd expect to find pedestrian
fractures on her legs.
And there are no
run-over marks,
so she wasn't in
a prone position.
So if she wasn't standing
or lying down...
She was somewhere
in-between.
Stokes, you ready
for a cup of coffee?
No, thanks.
I'm only going to be
about another ten minutes here,
okay?
Your call.
Hey.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
You all right, man?
You all right?
Are you here in
a professional capacity?
Does it make
a difference?
Maybe not to you.
I feel exposed.
The last time
you saw me...
You had just lost your daughter.
That's not all
I lost that night.
Heather!
If a client did this,
and left you to die,
why are you protecting him?
I'm not.
Tell me the truth.
Did they check your glucose
level when you came in?
Heather?
She's diabetic.
I think she's going into shock.
The patient
never told us.
Captain, I'll need a copy
of the police report
for my insurance.
Oh, sure, sure, sure.
We'll get to that.
But, first, I need to
straighten out
a few things.
Mr. Oakley,
did you give Heather Kessler
permission
to enter the park after hours?
No, I didn't.
I did.
She called the office.
Wanted to know about
renting out Oakley's Saloon
for a private party.
Well, you know what she does
for a living, right?
Money's money--
doesn't matter who's
handing it to you,
right, Dad?
As long as you're
not breaking the law.
So you have no problem
with a dominatrix doing business
at a family theme park?
Captain, sometimes, my son,
he... he doesn't think
things all the way through.
But I'm learning.
So how did she get in?
I swung by.
Wanted to meet her.
After midnight?
Yeah.
Told her to lock up
when she was done.
You should have stayed, Ben.
You got liability
to think about.
Right, Dad.
'Cause you always do.
Captain, is this about it?
Well, I'd like to talk
to Benny a little more.
We need
to confirm his statement.
(camera clicking)
There were no security cameras
at the crime scene,
but Ms. Maroney
had multiple arrests
for petty theft and shoplifting.
She had just been released
on court-ordered rehab
for kleptomania.
She got noodles,
hairpins,
dish towels, a can of tuna.
She didn't care what she took.
She just had to take it.
You know, I was thinking.
If she pinched my wallet,
and I whacked her for it,
I'd probably get back my wallet
before I split.
Which means the theft victims
are probably not the suspects.
Got anything else?
A couple of loose receipts,
all from last night,
all paid in cash.
A pack of gum
from the Bargain Bin, a soda
from Carlisa's,
and a Bloody Mary
from Diane's Steakhouse.
Which is less than quarter
of a mile from the crime scene.
At 9:52 p.m.
Patrol found her
just after 11:00.
I'll start at the steakhouse
and backtrack.
Hey.
What? Have you been shaving
with a broken beer bottle?
No, no. Some drunk driver
ran into a radio car
at my crime scene.
Friggin' idiot.
Yeah. I heard you pulled
the friggin' idiot's friend
out of a burning car.
Nothing was on fire.
I didn't pull anybody
from anywhere.
Oh, so humble.
You know, some people are just
destined for greatness.
Run these against the paint
chips from the body, please.
Sure. You mean the engine black
over canary yellow paint chips
from a Ford automobile? Yeah.
If I had a yellow car,
I'd paint over it, too.
So the victim was hit by a car.
Steakhouse called
Faith Maroney a cab.
They have a direct line
to this place.
Well, the car that hit her
was yellow and black.
Paint color's
not going to help us
narrow it down any, is it?
No.
You guys from Strip-O-Gram?
Excuse me?
'Cause last year,
for my birthday,
a cop showed up
with a phony badge,
started tearing his clothes off
and trying to rub up on me.
I'm an excellent tipper.
Well, I'm sure you are,
but, uh,
no, ma'am, we're
not dancers.
We're here about
the warrant.
Okay, then.
So we dispatched
20 cabs to Diane's Steakhouse
last night.
Around 10:00?
Received a call
at 10:01.
Dispatched number 29.
Chandru Kambhatla.
He doesn't come on until 8:00.
Well, we're going to need to see
that cab and your trip sheet.
Number 29's right there.
Keys are inside.
No joy riding,
and don't leave the doors off
like you did last time.
Hey, we just take them apart.
We don't put them
back together, now.
That's why nobody likes
to deal with your asses!
(both laughing)
Hey, Nick,
there's a camera in here.
Maybe that'll be able
to tell us
if Princess Pickpocket
was one of his fares.
Front bumper screens positive
for blood.
Hey.
I got robbed last week,
filed a report.
How come you're helping
Chandru and not me?
This isn't a robbery, sir.
Then, what is it?
Do you know the guy
that drives this cab?
Sure.
You see him last night?
I had to cut out early.
My wife's sick.
But, uh, Dru's solid.
Got to respect a guy
who comes here
and wants
to be legit.
Goes to work, pays his taxes,
studying to be a citizen.
If you want to know about state
capitals, you just ask Dru.
Did you know
that Vegas
is not the
capital of Nevada?
Thanks for the info, fellas.
Go get 'em.
(siren wailing in distance)
WILLOWS:
The substance that I found
under the saloon window
was chewing tobacco.
The night watchman chews.
Yeah, Vernon Porter.
He was fired from the
force back in Chicago.
Yeah, I know,
I checked him out.
Oh.
He got
in an off-duty incident.
He was in a fight in a bar
and a woman was hospitalized.
I'm thinking he had
a front row seat.
Well, you know,
it fits his profile.
He could have waited
till Heather's client left--
there's always a client...
Yeah.
...and then attacked her.
You know,
I should have checked
to see if he was
wearing underwear.
There's no way that
he could afford her.
So why would Heather
cover for him?
Unless he's
just a witness.
Well, you want to see a man
about a horse?
GRISSOM:
Any results
on Heather Kessler?
So far, all the prints
come back to her.
Player piano, whiskey
bottle, shot glass.
There was some lipstick
around the rim.
I haven't had a
chance to test it.
You think it's
her shade?
Heather's not supposed to
drink because of her diabetes,
which could explain
the hypoglycemia and shock.
Catherine found a pair
of men's underwear
in the toilet.
Any evidence on them would
have been washed away,
but she also found
seminal fluid
in a tissue on
the floor nearby.
She was sexually assaulted?
She refused an SAE kit,
so we'll never know.
There were no
defensive wounds,
no skin or rope fibers
under her nails.
At first blush, I figured
he might have ambushed her,
except that I noted
three separate
strangulation
attempts on her neck.
She had time to fight back.
This makes no sense.
She's very strong.
And tough as nails.
Why didn't she fight?
Gate's unlocked again.
Well, it's ten after.
Probably unlocked
'cause he's doing his rounds.
Maybe.
Ah, the Wild West,
partner.
Okay, come on,
Jim, give it up.
I know you
know something
about Grissom
and Lady Heather.
I know something a lot juicier
than Grissom and Lady He...
Oh, yeah, he's dead.
He took one in the back.
Who shot the sheriff?
(indistinct radio transmission)
Bullet entered
through his back.
(grunts)
No exit wound.
There's some swelling
under his lip.
Ugh, disgusting.
You get mouth cancer from this.
David, hand me his cell phone.
Sure.
Ruger Single Six.
Gun hasn't been fired.
Guess who he called yesterday?
Lady Heather.
Might have threatened her.
And we both know
how she likes
to settle her own scores.
I'm going to
get a warrant,
but it may take me some time
because I have to find a judge
who isn't a client of hers.
STOKES:
You sure you've never
seen her before?
You don't
remember her?
No, sir.
That picture
was taken by the
camera inside your cab.
Why don't you
take another look?
Recognize her now?
You know, a lot of
people get in my cab.
There's always a big
convention in town.
Hey. Dru. I was born at night,
but not last night, okay?
You picked her up
at the steakhouse.
I know the last time
she was seen alive,
was in your yellow cab.
I know she was killed
by a yellow car.
I found blood on your
front bumper.
Okay, I, uh, I remember her now.
She wanted to go to MGM.
There is bad traffic,
so she tells me
to let her out.
She wants to walk.
Where'd you let her out?
Near the Monte Carlo.
Mr. Kambhatla,
if I match the paint
from your cab
to the paint
we found in her skull,
do you realize how much
trouble you're in?
'Cause I'm not sure
you really do.
Scotty.
JOHNSON:
The older types of cameras
only take stills.
They take them sequentially
for 20 seconds
any time a passenger
door is opened.
Can you clarify
the background?
Yeah.
NICK:
I recognize the
graphitti on that bench.
That's the street we found
her on, right there.
So Mr. Kambhatla
was lying.
That's nowhere near
the Monte Carlo.
Go back to number two.
The wallet in her
hand is... black.
And her wallet was white.
Go back, show me the last
three photos, Archie.
Yeah.
JOHNSON:
Okay, so he's looking at her.
Looks down.
He's looking
for something.
He looks up.
STOKES:
Well, he's pissed.
So she did snatch
his wallet after all.
BROWN:
And he ran her down
and took it back.
Well, we have
him in custody.
We have his wallet.
Let's, uh, go see if
her prints are on it.
Yeah. Thanks, Arch.
Yeah.
This window wasn't
broken yesterday.
And I got a bullet
in a poker player.
Well, the one that killed
Porter's still inside him.
Porter was shot
in the back.
He was facing away
from the saloon.
(gunshot)
To get to the window,
this bullet had to be fired
from the opposite direction.
(gunshot)
There were
two shooters.
Lead bullet. Cannelure.
We're looking
for a revolver.
Oh, wow.
WILLOWS:
These look authentic.
All revolvers.
Case is unlocked.
I'll get the guns to ballistics.
I'll process the ammo boxes.
Sofia,
Faith Maroney's prints
were found on the cab
driver's wallet
so there's your motive.
No problem.
The paint from
the dead girl's skull
matched the paint
on Chandru's cab.
Page two.
The paint chips from the street
are not a match
to the paint chips
from her skull.
Are you sure about this?
I just finished a diabolical
soduku in six minutes flat.
I'm positive.
Then what color were
the other paint chips?
What did you have for lunch?
I had a ham
sandwich.
Hmm?
It's a clue.
Your sandwich.
Oh.
The paint chips
you collected are
from two different cars,
stuck together as a
result of impact.
Yellow paint, black
paint, clear coat.
The other half--
clear coat,
black paint, yellow paint,
clear coat, white.
That's a lot of canary yellow
and engine black.
Cab-on-cab hate?
One half of the sandwich
is from Dru's 29.
What about the other half?
You're looking
for a white Ford
that's been repainted
yellow and black.
Sweet.
I'm glad I figured that out.
C.O.D.'s a single gunshot wound
to the lower lumbar region.
Bullet entered here and then
traveled slightly upward.
Where is the bullet?
Well, that's
the fun part.
He didn't die from
the initial wound.
It entered through his back
and then penetrated
the inferior vena cava.
(gunshot)
It traveled through that vessel
into his right lung.
It's called a bullet embolus.
and it's hard to find.
Most medical examiners
would have missed it.
Full metal jacket,
nine millimeter.
The bullet that I found at the
saloon was from a revolver.
Colt single-action Army.
The gun that won the west.
That bullet is from
a 20th century,
high-capacity,
semi-automatic pistol.
I... see a lot of bullets.
(sighs)
Well, it looks like Friendly
bought a small fleet
of white cabs
from another company last
year that went belly-up.
How small are
we talking?
Seventy-five.
Paint samples
from 75 cabs?
Well, we'll be back in
the lab by next week.
Hey, Warrick.
I got what looks like
fresh damage over here.
Do we know that guy?
JOHNSON:
Gus's cab is equipped
with a new camera.
Video, not stills.
Motion-activated.
So the impact
turns it on, huh?
STOKES:
Freeze that and grab
a number off that cab.
JOHNSON:
7029-- that's Dru's cab.
If Dru was dispatched,
then what was Gus doing
at that steakhouse?
Well, he had to be staging,
trying to steal Dru's fare.
Looks like Gus took
the fight to the streets.
He hit him again right there.
BROWN:
Whoa.
Well, that's the corner.
And we know from the paint chips
we found on the ground
that Gus's cab collided
with Dru's on that street.
Well, the airbags
didn't deploy, so
he must have been going
under 15 miles an hour.
I can't see Dru's cab, so Gus
must have rear-ended him
when he was stopped.
STOKES:
It's physics.
Gus's cab
transferred most of its
energy into Dru's--
more than enough to
launch him into the girl.
and car bumpers
are designed
to absorb the impact
from another vehicle,
but the bumper hitting her?
Would have been like a...
elephant hitting a flea.
You were in the wrong.
You were the one
who was staging.
So why road rage
Mr. Kambhatla?
Because he was gonna
report it and get me fired.
I'm two months from retirement.
My wife's got MS.
I need my health benefits.
But I didn't
hit that girl.
He did.
STOKES:
It's a bad neighborhood.
Nothing's open out there.
So why'd you drop her off?
She was screaming at me,
"Screw you, pull over."
Sorry.
You guys are crazy. I want out
of this cab right now.
$6.25, please.
No way. I'm not paying
for this ride.
Hey, wait!
You're a tease!
Give me back my wallet!
He tries to steal my fare.
She tries to steal my wallet,
and I am arrested.
So why didn't you just
report the accident?
You hit a pedestrian,
it is always your fault.
Hey, you were stopped
and Gus hit you,
pushing your cab into her.
Now, that's not your fault.
Okay?
Gus said it was.
And he has been driving
for 30 years.
My cab hit her,
so I am guilty.
Yeah, well, Gus doesn't
know the law, but I do.
What else did
he say to you?
Mr. Kambhatla,
this may be the last chance you
have to tell me the truth, now.
We made a deal.
Okay. Okay.
What kind of deal?
He said if I don't
report him for staging,
and hitting me,
then he would keep quiet
about me hitting the girl.
And I can stay
in this country...
with my mother and sisters.
I need to be here to
make money for them.
I'm telling the truth now.
Is going to be okay, right?
No, sir, unfortunately,
that's not the way it works.
I've got you
for obstruction,
for fleeing the scene,
and now you're an accessory.
I'm sorry, man.
I know you're confused, but...
you just made a deal
with the wrong guy.
This isn't a good time.
We have a warrant
to search your house.
And you'd better
put some sunblock on
because we're
going downtown.
My memory isn't any better
than it was yesterday.
I'm not up to it.
Well, we'll swing
by the hospital.
And you can explain to
them why you checked
yourself out early,
against doctor's orders.
We're investigating
a homicide.
I don't understand.
Where were you
last night?
You may come in.
I was here.
Can anyone verify that?
Preferably someone not
on the payroll.
Captain Brass would like to know
where I was last night.
She was here.
GRISSOM:
With me.
WILLOWS:
You were there all night.
Want to explain why?
Look, I know that
you don't go home and cuddle
your insects every single night,
but why would
you go there knowing
that we're in the middle
of an investigation?
And now she's a prime suspect
with you as her alibi.
It was a social call,
that's all.
So, when your personal life
gets tangled up in a case,
that's off limits?
Yes.
Isn't that a little
hypocritical?
Apparently so.
You know I'd slap you, but
I think you'd enjoy it too much.
Look, I went to Heather's
on a hunch.
There's something
not right with her.
Your timing sucked.
What's this?
So now you're building
your own?
Yeah.
Keeps my hands busy.
You think I paid someone
to kill Porter
and then used Grissom
as my alibi?
And with your history, yes.
How do you know
Vernon Porter?
He did some work for me.
I helped him get the job
at Oakley's.
You know what? That's the first
thing you said to me
that doesn't sound like a lie.
What kind of work?
I needed to locate someone.
So an ex-cop does
some legwork for you.
So what happened--
did you have a falling out
or he threaten you?
(keypad beeping)
ELECTRONIC VOICE:
First skipped message.
Received yesterday at 12:02 p.m.
MAN:
Hey, Heather, Vernon.
Looks like you got yourself
into something.
If you need anything, call me.
Call me anyway.
Let me know you're okay.
Does that sound like a man
who wants to hurt me,
Captain Brass?
Oh, I don't know, Heather.
I don't know.
I mean, you get assaulted
at Old West Town where he works,
he calls it in,
then he ends up dead.
What is it,
just one big coincidence?
I already told you
I was there on business.
Mr. Porter had nothing
to do with it.
Yeah, but it was your business
that got him killed.
Come on, come on,
we both know
that you weren't there
for some Western hoedown.
So what were you
doing there?
The semen on the tissue
in the bathroom
did not come from Vernon Porter.
Well, the underwear
that I pulled from the toilet
was a 38-inch waist.
Porter was a 34.
He didn't attack Heather.
But we know he was there.
One of Heather's clients pays
for a kinky Wild West fantasy
only to discover he had
an audience?
Well, I don't want
to derail this,
but why kill Porter and not go
after Heather?
'Cause she's
not talking.
Her business
is based on discretion.
Couldn't count on Porter's
discretion.
(ring tone playing)
So this client goes back
to Oakley's the next night
and shoots Porter.
Oh, Mandy got a hit
off the revolver
and the ammo box.
Benjamin Oakley.
His family owns the place.
He had access.
Yeah, I'm calling Brass.
Sara will fill you in.
WILLOWS:
Jim...
We may have a suspect.
I'm the only one
Heather trusts.
I get it.
Sara...
Yeah?
It's fine.
Do what you need to do.
HEATHER:
When the submissive accepts
they're in control,
that's when they embrace
their true power.
They can say "stop."
They can choose
to either end the pain
or continue enduring it.
But...
higher consciousness
doesn't negate
our animal instinct to survive.
Dr. Grissom,
you requested
a custody file from the court.
Thank you, Judy.
I'm assuming it's for
your investigation
into the Miniature Killer.
Everybody in the lab
believes you're gonna get him.
She's all I have left of Zoe.
Can you tell if she's
ever given birth?
There was some scarring
on her pelvic bones,
but given the condition
of the body,
it's hard to say
for sure.
GRISSOM:
This is your granddaughter.
Did you take this picture?
I hired someone to find her.
I can't give her love,
but I can give her the freedom
to be who she wants to be.
Is this official
police business?
No.
Did Heather send you?
No, I'm just a friend of hers.
Did she tell you about me?
Not really.
We were married
very young.
Didn't last long.
Heather left
without telling me
she was pregnant.
I wasn't aware I had a child
until after Zoe
was already dead.
That's Zoe's daughter,
Heather's granddaughter.
Her name is Alison.
So why are you here?
I'm just trying to understand
what's happening to her.
(girl speaking indistinctly)
I'm aware that the court
has denied her
visitation rights.
Wouldn't you?
I'm not sure.
Has Heather tried to give you
any money for Alison?
Yes, the day
before yesterday
I got a call
from the bank.
Heather had set up
a very generous trust fund
for her,
no strings attached.
I assumed she sold her house.
Can you tell me how much?
$843,508.
I know Heather had closed
her business a few months ago
trying to convince the judge
she'd be a fit guardian,
so it had to be from the sale.
I wonder if she calculated
the exact amount
it would cost
to raise a child
and put her through college,
especially at Harvard.
That's where she sent Zoe.
But it wasn't her house
that she sold.
You took a shot at Porter.
That's attempted murder.
Your dad's not going
to like that, Benny.
This is a warrant for your DNA.
Why do you need my DNA?
To prove that you also attacked
Heather Kessler.
BRASS:
And that makes two
attempted murders.
And that adds up to a
lot of jail time, bud.
Open up.
I didn't touch her, okay?
I didn't kill Porter.
What do you want, a gold star
for being a bad shot?
(sighs)
Porter knew I lied.
He wanted 50 grand
to keep his mouth shut.
And I was gonna pay him.
I went to the bank
to get the money, but
somebody drained the account.
There was a million dollars
in that account last week.
Who authorized the transfer?
Jack Oakley.
I went there to kill my father.
I knew he was going
to meet Heather,
but for some reason,
she didn't show.
And Porter got up the courage
to ask my dad for the money.
He'd seen my father
with Heather.
You sick bastard!
You got 24 hours,
then I turn you in!
(gunshot)
The Marquis de Sade's
got nothing on my old man.
Inflicting pain
is his idea of foreplay.
You're your mother's son,
not mine.
Do you know how
much money he spent
abusing women?
He didn't leave anything
for my mother and me
except for more abuse.
It had to stop.
Where is he?
His phone's off; every time
his phone's off, he's with her.
Is he at the saloon?
No, he wouldn't do that,
not after Porter.
He's got to be
at Heather's.
(siren wails in distance)
BRASS:
So your sick fantasy
was to kill her.
I didn't do anything.
She solicited me.
Strictly a business deal.
She needed the money.
I paid her close to $1 million
for this, you know that?
That's about all
I'm gonna say.
I'll be talking
with my lawyer.
Too bad you spent the million.
You could use it
on your defense.
Look, Heather,
for what it's worth,
I think you're
in the clear.
The D.A.'s not gonna
press charges.
Attempted murder,
assisted suicide,
the lines
are kind of blurred.
But do yourself a favor.
Get some help.
(siren blips)
(indistinct radio
communication)
(knocking)
Leave me alone.
I didn't ask you to save me.
I know.
What am I supposed to do?
I'm your friend.
Besides, there's someone
I want you to meet.