♪ ♪
Yeah, that's my real photo
on my profile.
Excuse me.
Well, I exercise a lot.
Kind of an animal
about it.
Hey.
Did you see me last night?
Yeah, you were feeling no pain.
Who was I with?
Describe him.
Was he white,
black, tall?
Hair color, car?
Look, lady, I get paid
not to notice.
Who was room 229
registered to?
Catherine Willows.
You used your credit card.
I think Malibu Barbie did it.
Well, then there's
a lot more to Barbie
than just a pretty
face, 'cause this
is a perfect half-inch scale
model of the the room.
And assuming that the killer
is the same person
who made the miniature...
It would of taken weeks.
Maybe even months to create
with this kind of detail.
Certainly qualifies
as premeditation.
Yeah, but take a look
at he blood pools.
They're identical.
There's no predicting
a blood pool,
it's inherently random.
Killer must of stuck around
to match the scene.
It's real blood.
That is a level of obsession
that gives even you
a run for your money.
"If Dusty Fell,"
Izzy Delancy.
I have never heard of him.
Probably before your time.
I'll download it.
I checked the perimeter,
property is gated with a code.
There is no sign of forced entry
on the windows or the doors.
Of course if a girl can get into
Brad Pitt's underwear drawer,
and take a nap on his bed,
I guess anything is possible.
Lividity suggests he
hasn't been moved.
He was probably
sitting right here
when he was killed.
Looks like blunt
force trauma.
No spatter
or cast off.
Sometimes it only takes one hit.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
(people screaming)
Oh, great, you're here,
thanks for coming.
I can't believe you're leaving
Izzy Delancy's death scene.
Groupies are already
starting to gather.
I have something that
I have to take care of.
Nick and Sofia are
talking with the family,
Grissom's in the kitchen,
you can process the bedrooms?
Thanks.
Mrs. Delancy?
(sighs)
No, that's Mrs. Delancy.
I'm Annie, the nanny.
I'm going to need
to photograph your hands.
To look for blood, right?
Blood evidence, yeah,
and defensive wounds.
I'm also going to get a sample
of your DNA and
your fingerprints.
So, why don't you
hand little Nora
to her mom for right now, okay?
No, Mrs. D never holds the baby.
(whispering):
She's got a bad back.
I should warn you,
I'm a little freaked.
When I get nervous
or scared or whatever
I have this problem
where I talk a lot.
I've had it since I was little
I just keep talking...
You found the body?
Tuesday is Chinese.
Izzy insists...
on having...
a really strict eating schedule.
I have to start cooking by 4:00
and when I went
into the kitchen...
Baby's don't eat bok choy.
Yeah, I wonder what
you're going to have for--
(gasps)
(screaming)
I immediately called 9-1-1.
Speaking of which, can I get
a copy of the police report?
Why don't you...
Where is your shirt?
(laughs)
Right after it all went down
the baby spit up on it
and I put it in the laundry.
Mmm.
It happens
all the time.
Nobody minds.
(camera shutter clicking)
Hey, what's
going on?
I may have been roofied
and raped.
I woke up here.
What?
I, uh, improvised
my own a rape kit.
I've got pubic combing,
nail scrapings, vaginal swab,
urine samples...
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
did you call it in?
I called you.
Catherine, doing it yourself
is going to make anything
that you get inadmissible.
Yeah, I know procedure,
I didn't want
an official investigation.
I-I just want to know
what happened.
Okay, all right.
Uh...
I got to get this, uh,
stuff to the lab.
Room 229,
it's right up there.
Please print it.
And keep it between us.
Okay.
Thanks.
I went out for a latte.
I got home around 5:00.
I never even went
into the kitchen.
I just went straight upstairs
and took a shower.
(sighs)
God that means that he was dead
this whole time.
We believe whoever killed your
husband had access to the house.
Yeah, do you think anyone else
had the... the gate code?
Just the housekeepers.
And the handymen,
and the pool guys.
And the gardeners,
and the...
messengers and...
the caterers.
MRS. DELANCY:
I can tell you where you should
start looking.
(whispers):
Sven.
Are you accusing your son
of killing your husband?
(laughs)
He is not my son.
That's Izzy's kid
from his first wife.
Oh.
He has real problems.
(whispering):
His mom was like a cokehead
or something.
CURTIS:
Hey, how you doing?
How you
doing man?
I've been better.
What time did you
get back from school?
Around 4:00.
And then what did you do?
Homework, games.
Did you...
see your dad at all?
No, I usually don't see him
until dinner.
And then...
I get picked up right after, so.
By who?
My mom.
You don't live here full time?
Tuesdays and every other
Saturday.
Well, that's got to be tough.
Whatever.
I just go where I'm told.
WOMAN:
Let me in,
I am his mother.
I know, baby, I know.
This is really hard.
It's okay
to be upset, okay.
What's on your finger...
Did you fingerprint my son?
We fingerprinted everyone in
the house, DNA samples as well.
Is he a suspect?
He didn't refuse
and Mrs. Delancy was here.
Sleeping with his father does
not make her his mother, okay.
I'm his mother.
Where were you this afternoon?
I was taking a walk.
Can anyone confirm that?
No.
Come on.
Let's go.
(camera shutter clicking)
(drawer sliding)
(beeping)
(device purring softly)
(objects rattling)
Bleach was used in this kitchen
but not to clean up the blood.
So the aging rocker
bit it in the kitchen
with the marble
rolling pin?
If only the who
was as easy as the how.
(inhales deeply)
Oh, hey. You got to
be pulling a double
if you're in my lab
at this hour.
Yeah.
What's up?
You need a hand?
No. Thanks.
Oh. ABA card.
It's negative for semen.
I said I didn't
need your help.
Oh, thank you,
but there's no drinking or
eating allowed in the lab.
It's a urine sample.
My bad.
Get it to Tox.
And... check this
for spermicide.
Call me with the results.
Did you run out of proper swabs?
Just do it.
What's the case number?
Consider this
a proficiency exam.
Muggs?
Sam. What are you doing here?
Just wanted to
see your face,
and I missed you at
the implosion party.
Oh, yeah.
I heard about
that, um...
I'm sorry I missed that.
When's Lily get back
from her cruise?
Monday.
How about
a family dinner?
Uh, yeah, I'll call you
when she's had a chance
to catch her breath.
You know you don't always
need a reason to call me.
I know you're busy.
I'll see you later.
MEN (over faint rock music):
♪ Knows how to get
what she wants ♪
what she needs, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ Yeah, she knows just
how to play, what to say ♪
♪ Make you give her anything ♪
(guitar solo)
(clears throat)
(music stops)
(sighs)
Cause of death?
♪ Blunt force trauma ♪
♪ To the back of the skull ♪
♪ And a fracturing of
the occipital lobe ♪
♪ There was massive hemorrhaging
on the brain ♪
♪ And death
was probably swift ♪
♪ Yeah. ♪
Sorry, Izzy.
Now... what is that?
The key to our mystery?
(chuckles)
(door closes)
(machinery whirring)
WILLOWS:
Excuse me.
What can I do you for?
You were working last night.
Always. I own the place.
Do you remember me?
I was... I was here.
Was a busy night, I'm sorry.
(sighs)
Well... do you have
any surveillance cameras
in the place?
What's this about?
I'm with the Crime Lab.
Yeah, that's the only one.
Just gets
the cash register.
So you've got nothing
that covers the customers
or the dance floor, or...?
No need to.
(scoffs)
♪ ♪
Find something?
No.
No prints, no hairs, no fibers.
Materials are common
hobby shop issue, but the blood
matches the victim's.
Are you interested in motive?
Sofia just spent
the last two hours
with the sheriff,
the head of the Olympia Casino,
and a couple of dozen lawyers.
Apparently, Izzy Delancy owned
the rights to his own songs.
The Olympia was negotiating
to purchase them
for a medley show
based on his music.
Izzy never got a chance
to sign the contracts.
Dead rock star, nut job family,
and a company hungry
for the next Mamma Mia!
Who inherits the music rights?
The son, Sven,
but he's a minor, so the rights
would be controlled
by his mother, Dusty.
It's illegal to benefit
from a criminal act.
If either one of them
committed the murder...
Then the rights would go to
Izzy's current wife, Madeline.
Well, that's motive for her.
But how does
this fit in?
ECKLIE (sighs):
Maybe we should release it
to the media.
Someone might have
unwittingly
made a component
of the miniature.
If they came forward,
that could help us.
What's the point of gratifying
the murderer with publicity?
Izzy Delancy is famous;
the press wants answers.
Don't we all?
Sara, this is your case, too--
what do you think?
I, uh... I agree with Grissom.
Of course you do.
I looked into the key
that Izzy swallowed.
Turns out that Bumblebee
is a safe company.
Sofia asked Madeline about it.
She says she knew that there
was a safe in the house
but didn't know where it was--
my kind of marriage.
So the key could've been
in his system
anywhere from a few minutes
to several days?
Right. So if robbery was
the motive for murder
and Izzy swallowed the key
to keep something hidden,
maybe whatever is in that
safe will lead us to who.
(sighs)
(click)
(camera shutter clicking)
(gasps lightly)
You're late.
(sighs):
I did the best I could, Lindsey.
You said you would
watch the rehearsal.
Work just...
really got out of hand.
Surprise.
(sighs)
Lindsey.
I really am sorry.
I hate it when work
gets in the way.
I love to watch you dance.
Fine. Whatever.
I got a solo.
You did?
That's so great!
It's Romeo and Juliet.
Fanta...
(Willows grunts)
(groans)
Is my daughter okay?
Lindsey!
Lindsey...!
WILLOWS:
I don't need that. I'm fine.
Ma'am, you need to put this
on, for your own safety.
You suffered
a head trauma.
There could be serious
delayed problems.
I'm refusing treatment.
Just give me the release form.
Ma'am, I strongly recommend
you put this on...
Just give me the damn form!
Hey, hey, hey.
Catherine.
They got Lindsey.
I know.
They took Lindsey.
It's all over
the radio, I heard.
It was an SUV.
And it was
silver or brown.
We're gonna
get Lindsey back, okay?
And they drove
that direction.
I never saw it coming.
Okay.
They came from
this direction.
Slow down,
slow down.
(tires squealing)
These are acceleration marks.
They were waiting for us.
I should've told you, but
I didn't want a sermon.
I did my own rape kit.
Came back negative.
Thank God.
These events
have to be connected.
We'll check your old cases
for possible suspects.
I'll ask Ecklie if he can kick
in some help from day shift.
I appreciate that.
You've got to stay at
arm's length, Catherine.
I-I know.
Nothing but partials.
That's impossible.
I ran the VIN number
on the Cougar that hit you.
A place sold it
yesterday for cash.
Catherine, I'm really sorry
for leaving you there.
Don't go there, Nick.
They were gonna get to me,
one way or another.
It had to have been
at least two guys--
one who was driving the Cougar,
and the other in the SUV.
(groaning)
He reached through the window.
Print the inside of that handle.
Okay.
Sam?
It just happened.
Who told you?
Well, I can't talk right now.
I'll let you know
when we find something out.
Sure, Sam.
Sam!
What do you know about
what happened to Lindsey?
What do you know about it?
Who's using us
to get to you?
This is your granddaughter
we're talking about.
What the hell
do you know?
Front desk found this
in the quick checkout bin.
"Can you guess what
you're going to give me?"
What does that mean?
Who's behind this?
I don't know.
This was just found.
Same place.
Where is she?
Who has her?
I swear, I don't know.
Like hell!
I blame you!
I blame you for this!
I never wanted to involve you
personally or professionally
in any
of my business.
Business?
You don't have a business.
You're a thug
in thousand dollar shoes!
Thanks for not
disappointing me, Sam.
Okay, but could you
take a break
or get a cup of tea
or something here?
Think I got something.
What?
Mandy ran the print that
I picked up from your car,
and it's a match to
an open burglary case,
from a few months ago.
I think it was yours, Warrick.
I got it.
Oh, this is from this couple
from San Francisco.
Bought a second home
in Seven Hills,
came back and found it tossed.
The chair.
Look at that.
Las Vegas police you're under arrest.
Gun! Gun!
(gunshots)
Call a paramedic!
Lindsey!
Mom!
Where are you,
Lindsey?!
(muffled screaming)
Lindsey! Lindsey!
Lindsey!
Catherine!
Don't touch her.
If you want a conviction,
you have to let me
do this, all right?
Let me do it,
all right?
All right.
WILLOWS:
I'm right here, Lindsey.
Right here.
I'm right here.
(muffled cries)
(sobbing)
Deep breaths.
(breathes deeply)
Breathe easy.
Deep breaths.
Almost. Almost.
Okay. It's okay.
I got you.
I got you. Everything's okay.
(sobbing):
Mom.
It's okay.
It's okay, baby.
Everything's okay.
(sobbing):
Mom.
I got you.
Everything's okay.
It's okay.
How's Lindsey?
(sighs)
She says she's fine.
The doctor is
assessing her now.
We still don't
have an ID.
Prints put him
in the motel.
Can you place
him at the bar?
Yeah.
Yeah, he was there.
The accident was a two-man job.
Can you remember anybody else?
I can't get a face.
SIDLE:
Greg found the mother lode.
The Nanny saved
all of her e-mails
on her computer.
She was sending private
Delancy family photos
to an editor
at Scandal Pages magazine.
Based on a sliding
scale of salaciousness,
Scandal Pages was
depositing money
into Annie's PayPal account.
So I have the DNA combo
from Sven's bed sheets,
and none of it was
actually Sven's.
Whoa.
CURTIS:
Annie Lansfield,
Cornstalk Queen of
Tidioute, Pennsylvania.
You move to Vegas
to become famous
and ended up
doing diaper duty
for a washed-up
rock star.
Do you want to tell me
how you ended up
in a safe that even his wife
didn't know about?
I clean for extra cash.
I know the house
better than anyone.
I knew where
the safe was.
I just didn't have
a key, until...
Honey, I need some money
to buy clothes for Emma.
I just gave you
money for that.
She's a baby.
She grows.
You know, this wouldn't
even be an issue
if you would sign
those damn contracts.
Really?
Well, that is between
me and my music.
And you,
you will never
see this safe.
(laughing
maniacally)
Gold digger!
Dig for that!
(chuckling)
The E.R. doctor said it would
pass in a couple of days.
They gave us
a copy of the X-ray
to keep on file
with the general physician.
It had the perfect outline
of the key.
So, I took the X-ray
to a key shop,
told them my kid swallowed it.
Resourceful.
But I put everything back.
After making Scandal Pages
money off it.
Look, a few years ago,
Izzy went on this
big health kick--
vegetarian, blah, blah.
He claimed that
all those chicken heads
that he bit on stage were fake.
When I found them,
I was just so excited.
Do you know how much
Scandal Pages pays
for an urban
legend story?
A lot.
Here's a scandal:
we got evidence
of sex between you and
Izzy Delancy in Sven's bed.
Or how about this:
if you killed him,
you'd be the first to crack open
that whole story.
Exclusive pics,
the whole deal.
It took 911 a while to come.
I just got a quick pic.
You said it-- I'm resourceful,
not a murderer.
I didn't do it.
NARRATOR:
It seemed more
like a fairy tale.
Hard living rocker,
Izzy Delancy met Dusty DeCosta.
They fell in love.
He wrote a hit song about her.
She was to become his first
wife... or was she?
Where did you find this?
Oh, I dug deep.
In a potentially
shocking display
of distrust and business acumen,
Izzy Delancy, after ten years
of dating Dusty DeCosta,
finally wed her in a beautiful,
flower-filled ceremony
in Malaysia.
The ceremony was everything
a girl could hope for--
beautiful, romantic,
well-attended.
The only thing it wasn't?
Legal.
Much to Dusty's surprise, years
later, after filing for divorce
and custody of their then
eight-year-old son, Sven,
she was shocked to discover
that the Malaysian Shaman
was not recognized by the United
States as an officiant.
Izzy has never released
an official statement
on the subject...
Sounds like motive to me.
Oh. Hi.
Listen, you're going to have
to follow me
'cause I'm late for a client.
What is it you want?
We were wondering
if you could tell us about
your relationship with Izzy?
Oh, God.
So I'm a suspect now?
That's precious.
Okay. The man makes a mint off
of singing about our sex life,
barely offers a
relationship to our son,
kicks me out of a house
we built together,
leaves me with nothing, and now
you want to put me in jail?
Rich. Really rich.
Izzy was a smart
business man.
He owned all the rights
to his music.
What does that matter to me?
Do I get royalty checks
for being his muse.
(chuckles)
SIDLE:
Exactly.
But with Izzy dead,
the rights go to Sven.
Ostensibly you.
And you still don't an alibi for
the afternoon of Izzy's death.
I do,
it's just embarrassing to me.
The "new" Mrs. Delancy
called a meeting.
She tells me about
the Olympia offer,
Izzy's being difficult
about the deal,
so would I talk to him
because he listens to me still.
(scoffs)
Had he started sleeping
with the nanny yet?
Yeah.
Did Madeline tell you
that was her old job?
No.
Look, I'd like to pin it on her,
I really would, but I can't
because I was with her at the
Espresso Drop all afternoon.
I really have to go.
What are those
drawings on the table?
Oh, those are Sven's.
(giggles)
Some mothers
get sport trophies,
I get perfectly rendered
skyscrapers.
He wants to be an urban planner.
He's kind of
obsessed with models.
You guys let
yourself out, okay?
If Sven is capable of creating
these kind of 3-D renderings,
he definitely could've
built that Miniature.
Son defending the honor
of his mother?
Name that Greek tragedy.
Yes, I'm angry with my father
for the way
he treated my mother.
I'm angry with my father
for sleeping with Annie.
for naming me Sven.
But I've been in therapy
twice a week since I was six.
I'm tired of adults
asking me if I'm angry.
Besides, I'm...
I'm not the only one
who's pissed at my dad.
Right, but your mom
and Madeline are covered.
They were together at the time
of your father's death.
(over intercom):
So maybe you were so angry
with your father,
that you channeled your anger
and used your skills
as a model builder
to build this.
And a nice...
heavy object to do this.
I always faint
at the sight of blood.
If that's the case, he probably
did not commit the murder
and he certainly
didn't paint the Miniature
with his father's blood.
And there's a test we can do
to prove it.
GRISSOM:
We're using a tilt table
and we're injecting him
with isoproterenol.
We're testing his sensitivity
to his vagus nerve.
Basically,
we're looking to find out
if the nerves that control
his blood pressure
are predisposed
to short circuit
when he gets
an adrenaline rush.
You're telling me that this
could keep him out of jail?
Unless he was faking it.
(sighs)
♪ ♪
(knocks softly)
I hear we're out of suspects.
Not necessarily.
Could be anybody in town.
Or anybody out of town
for that matter.
That's a lot
of suspects.
What do you want us to do?
I don't know.
I'll deal with it.
I ran DNA on the guy
who was holding Lindsey.
Did you get a name?
Um, kind of.
See, this guy has markers
that are found in, like,
ten percent of the population
which reminded me
of some other results
that I'd been processing
recently.
13 alleles in common
with Robert O'Brien?
The suicide from Sam Braun's
implosion party.
The guy who grabbed Lindsey
is Robert O'Brien's brother?
Right.
So when that came up,
I ran all the other exemplars
from the O'Brien case,
and I got a hit
on a piece of hair
from the duct tape
that they used to bind Lindsey.
Joe Hirschoff.
O'Brien's partner.
WILLOWS:
Hi, Sam.
(chuckles)
Everybody in town
knows you're here
every Thursday night.
And usually
with my mother.
I'll be right along.
She doesn't mean a thing.
It's all show.
Look, Muggs,
yesterday was...
Just save it.
I only came here to tell you
to call off your guys.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Joe Hirschoff and his partner
invested everything they had
in The Eclipse.
But it went bankrupt
before you broke ground.
You formed a new corporation
to finish the project,
leaving those guys
with nothing.
Sometimes that's the way it goes
in business.
Uh-huh.
O'Brien and Hirschoff
lost $20 million, right?
O'Brien caved
and stuck a gun in his mouth.
Hirschoff wants you
to pay him back.
So, where is he?
Come on, Sam, this isn't
Old Vegas anymore.
Let the police handle it.
Or have you
already killed him?
(chuckles)
I give you my word, no.
(no audio)