(meowing)
(paper shuffling and tearing)
Catherine, layout room,
right away!
WILLOWS:
Gil, where's the fire?
It's been sitting in my office
for the last four weeks.
But...
We caught the Miniature
serial killer; he confessed.
Yeah, I watched him
blow his brains out.
But I think the package
was postmarked after
he killed himself.
So maybe he arranged
to have it sent postmortem.
The three other murders,
the miniature was
left at the scene.
This one was addressed to me.
So, now it's personal?
GRISSOM:
The victim appears to be
a Caucasian female
with lots of books.
It could be an office,
somebody's living room...
or a modern hotel lobby.
When I was gone, did anybody
work a scene like this?
No... at least
not on our shift.
I'll check with days and swing,
and see if anybody caught
a case that matches.
Never mind.
Why not?
Take a look
at the early edition.
It's dated the day
after tomorrow.
This murder hasn't happened yet.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
(camera shutter clicking)
My name is Ernest Edward Dell.
I was born in 1946
in Ames, Iowa.
My life's been hard,
but I don't complain.
I never expected better.
I'm good with my hands.
I make things.
I fix things.
I'm a handyman.
That's what I am.
I'm not the sociable type.
I-I know that.
You spend any amount of time
around people,
you get your heart broke--
treachery, hypocrisy...
the promise of love.
A man has a right
to an honest day's pay.
Me, I service the machinery
of death so that people can eat.
If that makes me evil,
then so be it.
The Miniature Killer murdered
three people over a period
of roughly six months.
Ernie Dell was either
directly or indirectly
related to all of them.
What's with the bloody dolls?
We're not sure.
There's a different perspective
of that same image
in all of the miniatures.
We're thinking it could
be some kind of signature.
Look into the mouth of a person
and you'll find lies
wriggling there like maggots
waiting to grow wings.
The world has... has gone mad.
A man could kill from sunup
to sunset, and still his work
would never be done.
(gunshot)
Remember the Blue Paint killers?
Maybe Ernie Dell had a partner.
Like an apprentice,
an accomplice,
something like that.
Or a disciple.
You guys make models
when you were kids?
Tanks and airplanes.
Classic cars.
These miniatures
are obsessively precise,
half-inch scale models
of the crime scenes.
They probably took weeks
of focused effort to create.
I don't think the killer's
into team sports.
Izzy Delancy...
he was a rock star.
You know, famous brings out
the nut jobs.
Maybe we're just looking
at a copycat.
The miniatures were never
released to the press.
No photos, nothing.
You can't copy
what you can't see.
Other people had access
to those files.
Maybe it was a cop.
Or somebody in the lab.
It's been known to happen.
Yeah, so, Ernie Dell takes
the rap for three murders,
and then eats a .38. Why?
I think he was trying
to protect someone--
someone that he cared
a lot about.
Prints and DNA are going over
the package and wrapping paper.
They won't find anything.
Return address was an empty lot.
Any clue
as to who the victim is?
No, I even went
through her little purse.
Well, she's not wearing
a wedding ring.
She's probably single.
Her eyes appear
to be bloodshot.
Petechial hemorrhaging?
GRISSOM:
Look at this.
Blue smudges on the pillow.
Blue mascara on the victim.
Our vic gets comfortable,
grabs a little shut-eye...
...and never wakes up.
She's going to be smothered.
It would seem so.
WILLOWS:
If you interpret
this headline literally,
the doll is the victim.
That's different
than the others.
Methods change.
Killers evolve.
What?
Keppler said something
like that once.
He did come down
on the right side.
GRISSOM:
These books are all arranged
by subject matter:
art, religion, science...
The victim is apparently
well-educated.
That's from the
Izzy Delancy miniature.
What's it doing here?
I don't know.
GRISSOM:
There's something
on the surface.
Looks like brush strokes.
(cart rattling)
Hey, Sara, I heard
we got another miniature.
Is that true?
Yeah, it's like Ernie Dell
was covering for someone.
No kidding?
Hey, you were the one
who checked for next of kin
after his suicide, right?
SOP.Snail mail, email,
bank accounts,
police records, Google.
All I got was
he's a widower.
Received his wife's
Social Security benefits.
He had to be connected
to somebody.
It's kind of early for court.
Finally rescheduled my
deposition for the civil suit.
You know,
Demitrius James' family is suing
the city for 3.5 million.
That's going to be
a long deposition.
Home movies.
♪ ♪
(knocking)
Hey, boss. We're ordering
out for breakfast.
You have a cat,
don't you, Hodges?
Mr. K.
Kobayashi-Mare.
It's in reference to...
Do you ever take him
out of the house?
My little Kobe? No way.
Vegas is coyote country.
So if this is a house cat,
then this must be
somebody's home.
HODGES:
Tsk, tsk.
Looks like he's
been in the milk.
Yeah.
Maybe the victim has as well.
The previous murders
have all involved
the victim's habits
and routines.
So maybe this time,
it's a little something extra
in her afternoon tea.
So they're going to be poisoned.
GRISSOM:
She lays down
for her usual nap,
the cat sneaks a sip,
and neither one
ever wakes up again.
It doesn't matter how she dies
if we can't figure out
who she is or where she is.
Well, you can't figure that out
on an empty stomach.
If you don't like
this restaurant,
there's plenty of others
to choose from.
I choose these two.
♪ ♪
BRASS:
We're looking for a building
whose exterior
looks exactly like this.
So what are we looking at, Rick?
We've got a modernist structure
with cement beams
steel rails, frosted glass.
Something like that.
Probably, but whatever it is,
it should match exactly.
The killer's hyper-specific.
Well, maybe that'll work
in our favor.
Even if we find a match,
we could already be too late.
Let's check it out.
Nick Stokes, LVPD.
We're looking for a woman
that lives in this building.
She looks like this.
Have you ever seen her?
That looks like a doll.
Yeah, well, it's actually
a death threat.
Time is of the
essence here.
Can you help us out?
Anyone in the building
look like this?
No.
She's got a cat.
Well, that narrows
it down to about
a hundred tenants.
That's her home.
1106.
That's Ms. Tallman's place.
(muffled music plays)
(music grows louder)
(knocking)
Ms. Tallman? Las Vegas Police.
You need to open
your door, please.
Ms. Tallman?
Open and stand clear.
(loud music blasting)
(door opens)
(singing along)
(screaming)
(music continues blasting)
Please, ma'am, calm down.
We're with the Crime Lab.
This isn't a lab.
This is my home.
You must be confused.
No, we're not confused.
We're here for your protection.
(clicks music off)
Ms. Tallman...
Dr. Tallman.
Dr. Tallman...
I need you to take
a look at this.
Did you make this for me?
That's very sweet.
It's a death threat.
Who would want to kill me?
Doctor, do you normally
take a nap around
the same time every day
covering your face
and eyes with the pillow?
Yes, at 4:00 p.m.
I... I have tea and cookies
every day when I wake up.
Have you been
watching me?
No, Miss, no, but we think
someone else has.
Doctor, your life is in danger.
We need you to get dressed
and come with us, please.
Am I in trouble?
STOKES:
No, ma'am.
No, not anymore.
This officer will help you
get your things, okay?
No, no, no.
I'll go get my things.
I want you to know that
you young men are
refreshingly polite.
Thank you.
Is she on something?
She may have already
been poisoned.
We'll get her
to the hospital.
We should collect blood for tox.
And any open food or drink.
Hey, go on, shoo!
The killer did plan
every detail.
Except for us showing up.
(static, bell dinging,
kids laughing)
That's got to be
Ernie Dell's wife.
Quite the bash.
(train whistle blows,
kids laughing)
They must love kids.
(singing
"Happy Birthday To You")
Is that Ernie's son?
There's no record of a son,
but it sure looks like it.
SIDLE:
One, two, three, four, five
birthday candles in 1988
would make him around 24 now.
(all laughing)
JOHNSON:
Hmm. Don't look like
a very happy birthday.
Did you get
the boy's name?
Cake never made it on camera.
How about audio?
It sucks. '80s video cam
with built-in,
non-directional mic,
pulls in nothing
but wind and train noise.
So let's process it.
This is processed.
We ran tox
on Ms. Tallman's blood
as well as her milk
and cookies.
She was negative
on everything
from pharmaceuticals
and illicits,
to herbicides, pesticides
and heavy metals.
You sure she was
going to be poisoned?
No, but I'm pretty sure
she was scheduled to die today.
In each of the
previous cases,
the killer was at the scene
to commit the murder.
So maybe he was planning
to show up at the condo.
Well, it'd be kind
of rude not to greet
him, don't you think?
I'm ready for my close-up.
Definitely beats
walking the beat.
Feed's good.
Officer Kamen, how's your read?
Time to go to sleep.
All units, this is Brass.
Maintain a low profile.
That means I don't want
to see a uniform
within three blocks
of this place, okay?
Where you headed?
11.
Oh, sorry. Ten.
Go on up.
(elevator bell dings)
MAN:
Hold the elevator.
What floor?
11.
Someone's coming up.
White male with a suitcase.
We got a possible.
LVPD. Up against the wall.
What?
She said hands
against the wall.
What's your business here, sir?
Nothing.
I mean, this is
my sister's place.
I'm Peyton Tallman.
Where's Barbara?
Did something happen to her?
This officer will
explain everything
to your satisfaction.
Get him out of here.
What?
BRASS (on phone):
Peyton Tallman's ID checks out.
And I kind of doubt
the killer's going to make
a miniature crime scene
of his own sister's house.
And we have nothing to link him
to the other three murders?
He wants to see his sister.
I'll let you know
how that goes down.
Okay. Thanks.
(phone beeps off)
♪ ♪
Okay, that's it.
Killer's not
gonna show.
Let's call it a night.
All right, I know
you must be exhausted
after your brutal day
in the field,
but it's time to go.
Officer Kamen?
(camera shutter clicking,
garbled radio transmission)
She's pale.
No sign of trauma.
COD'll have to wait
till autopsy.
Sorry.
Not as sorry as I am.
(garbled radio transmission)
Look, I know
we've all had a tough day,
but the sooner we get done here,
the sooner we can all go home.
(sniffles)
Why? So my little Tripper
can run out to greet me?
Barbara.
I'm sorry about your cat, ma'am.
We lost an officer.
How much did you love her?
Barbara, please.
When my guys went
to your house, they said
you were a little out of it,
but you're thinking clearly
now, right?
(scoffs)
Well, having your home invaded
can be a little bracing.
Captain, how can we help?
Can you tell me why
anyone would want to kill you?
No.
But you can.
Well, Barbara was a
highly regarded psychotherapist.
Is.
That hasn't changed.
Is or was?
I'm retired.
You seem a little young
to be retired.
I got tired of it.
Can you tell me why one of her
patients would want to kill her?
No.
Well, no,
it's-it's possible.
She, um... she counseled
a lot of at-risk adults,
um, halfway house
kids, pro bono.
I also treated
suburban sexual dysfunction
for $300 an hour.
PEYTON:
She helped a lot
of people.
Did you work out of your home?
For the last few years.
Treat any sociopaths?
(laughs)
That's not a term for which
there's any diagnostic criteria.
You're not looking
for one of my patients.
Well, maybe I am.
Maybe I'm looking for
a 20-something-year-old male,
last name of Dell.
Won't say.
She can't say.
It's doctor-patient
confidentiality.
But you're retired.
Well, you know where I live.
Are you done yet?
No, we're not done yet.
At least, I'm not done yet.
All right, look,
let's start again, all right?
Let's...
Maybe we started off
on the wrong foot, all right?
Look, I'm asking you
as a professional,
as a psychotherapist,
please... help me out here.
Okay? Tell me...
what am I looking for?
Repetition...
attention to detail indicates
obsessive-compulsive disorder.
Obvious antisocial personality.
Uh, yeah,
four bodies--
I'd call that antisocial.
Most murderers lack
impulse control,
inability
to plan ahead, but...
this one's different.
Different how?
He conceives murder...
visualizes it.
Then he takes all that horror
that he's imagined.
He compresses it
into these little rooms.
These models literally indicate
repressed rage.
And when you start
taking that apart,
all that rage
comes flying out...
...and you will have let
the monster out of the box.
Stop hovering, Hodges.
You're in
or you're out.
In.
So, she wasn't poisoned, huh?
No.
Hand me a scalpel.
Tweezers.
Nice lungs.
(computer beeps)
(phone ringing, beep)
Grissom.
ROBBINS:
Yeah, Gil, uh,
got a good idea on COD
for your asphyxiated officer.
Internal organ color nailed it
on both the autopsy
and necropsy as...
Carbon monoxide poisoning.
You know,
nobody likes when you do that.
So, how did CO get
into the room?
That I don't know.
(phone beeps off)
(beeping)
(beeps)
(trilling and beeps)
(beep)
STOKES:
The timer goes off,
activating the motor,
which closes the flue
and drops powdered charcoal
onto the flames,
producing carbon monoxide.
Fumes have nowhere to go
but out into the apartment,
into Officer Kamen.
And the cat.
You know, this timer was
geared to run for weeks.
It could have easily
been put in place
a month ago.
That's why the killer
felt safe enough
to send me the miniature.
He never intended
to be at the scene.
There was no danger
of being caught.
Hey, Sara,
check this out.
I was digging through
Mannleigh Chicken's
employee health
insurance records...
45 million Americans
without health coverage,
and a chicken slaughterhouse
provides medical benefits?
Izzy Delancy's
animal rights PSA
forced the company
to clean up its act
in all departments.
Anyway, Ernie Dell had
one dependent listed:
a son.
"Lionel Dell."
Unbelievable.
Yeah, the man
loved his trains.
Lionel changed his name
to Mitchell Douglas
after he turned 18,
and get this.
He did time in
a halfway house
after getting busted
for fentanyl.
Which connects him
to the fentanyl-dealing
sexagenarian, Penny Garden.
Where's young Dell now?
Lionel Dell?
My name is Mitch Douglas.
I'm Sara Sidle.
I'm with the Crime Lab.
I was wondering
if you knew this woman.
She used to sell fentanyl.
Want me to pee in a cup?
What about this guy?
He's dead, too.
He was found face down in
a chicken stun bath in a place
your dad used to work.
He worked a lot of places.
I met a lot of people.
Did you know
Izzy Delancy?
Yeah.
His music sucks.
What do all these stiffs got
to do with me?
What was your relationship like
with your father?
Before or after
he blew his brains out?
Let's start with... before.
You ever step in a pile of crap,
but you're wearing boots,
so you can't just
scrape it off.
You got to dig it
out with a stick,
but even that
doesn't work,
so you just end up
tossing the boots in the trash?
It was kind of like that.
And after?
Much better.
You gonna arrest me?
We're just talking.
I'm not.
(knocking)
Did you know Officer Kamen?
No.
Me, neither.
I was watching her die,
and I didn't even realize it.
Look, Sofia, there weren't
any carbon monoxide sensors
in the apartment,
so no one could have known.
Yeah.
And in fact,
if I hadn't have gone away,
we'd have had another month
to work with;
you'd have never been
in that position.
It doesn't make you feel
any better either, does it?
You know, the scene's
been released.
Ms. Tallman was
pretty insistent.
We offered
to leave a uniform with her,
but she wasn't having it.
So, what are
you looking for?
The miniature's
complete.
It's not perfect, though.
Officer Kamen
was not the intended victim.
Well, she was dressed like her.
She died in the right position.
So did the cat.
I'm still not sure
it's perfect enough.
(phone rings)
Grissom.
Yeah.
Okay.
Now, it's perfect.
(camera shutter clicking)
(garbled radio transmission)
It's déjà vu all over again.
Not entirely.
There's some kind of liquid.
It looks like it fell
and splashes on the floor...
on the body...
and it looks like...
the ear.
This could be the source.
WILLOWS:
Killer returns to...
complete the miniature
the old-fashioned way.
And things get a little messy.
But in the end...
he puts everything right back
where it belongs.
TALLMAN:
What happened to my sister
was not just some
isolated tragedy.
There have been
four other murders,
four deaths which could
have been prevented
had the public been warned
by the people
sworn to protect us.
Barbara Tallman was the latest
victim of a serial killer...
the LVPD has known about
for months.
What do they call him?
They call him
"The Miniature Killer,"
because he makes little models
of his victims
posed in the places
where they die.
I feel for the guy, but he just
made our job a lot harder.
It was inevitable.
With each murder,
the amount of information
that could leak rose
exponentially.
TALLMAN:
I'm a private person,
but if this prevents
just one tragedy,
then it's worth it.
Trace report on the
second crime scene or...
or should I say second murder?
Crime scene is the same.
Haven't finished processing
all the samples, but
the water from the vase
is consistent with the water
found on the victim's clothing.
There's chlorine bleach
in the samples.
Why put bleach in vase water?
I knew you'd ask that.
Well, I had this girlfriend
who was a florist...
The one with the water
retention problem.
You remembered.
Anyway...
she said that if
you add a few drops of
bleach to your water,
it kills bacteria,
and gives your flowers
a nice long life,
but add too much...
the flowers die.
Grissom, we may have caught
a break on Barbara Tallman.
She did pro bono work
at Lionel Dell's halfway house.
Okay, so maybe I met her.
So what?
CURTIS:
So, she's dead.
That's four stiffs
associated with you, Lionel.
Five, if you count Ernie.
I don't.
You know, you keep saying
that you hated your dad,
but I'm not buying it.
You go through your life alone.
You're good with your hands.
You have weird hobbies.
You make little things.
And when that gets tricky...
you call your father.
CURTIS:
Maybe Ernie didn't know
you were a killer.
Police start poking around,
asking questions,
showing him pictures.
And when Ernie sees these...
he knows exactly
what his little boy's become.
SIDLE:
To the rest of the
world, a monster,
but to him...
just a little boy knocking over
his birthday cake.
So he confesses to crimes
you committed,
shoots himself in the head;
It's a dead end for us.
New start for you.
If only.
Let me tell you about Ernie.
What he cared about
in this life was...
his wife, his trains,
and his kids.
In that order.
Kids? You're an only child.
Again, if only.
If you're looking
for a love connection, then...
then you should maybe go talk
to one of the chosen ones.
What are you talking about?
Fosters.
My parents had, like... dozens.
They'd come and go,
some before I was born.
My mom loved kids.
Dad loved Mom.
I guess as soon
as I came around...
the love ran out.
And then Mom dies...
the kids leave...
and Ernie's left with me.
Ernie didn't take a bullet
for me.
But it's a beautiful thought.
I pulled these fibers
out of her nasal passages.
Well,they appear
to be consistent
with the sofa pillow cushion
at the scene.
COD was asphyxiation.
Now...
what is wrong with this brain?
Other than the fact
that it's out of its skull?
Pigmentation's unusual.
Bingo... or keno
or whatever you prefer.
Pronounced lack
of pigmentation
near the midbrain,
along with...
clearly diminished
substantia nigra.
She had Parkinson's.
Nick and Warrick did say
that she was a little...
spacey when they met her, but
they didn't mention any shaking.
Her disease was advanced.
She was on
some pretty heavy meds.
Would they have shown up
on a poison tox panel?
No, but those kinds
of medications
can cause
abnormal thinking and behavior.
Takes somebody with a very
strong will to keep it hidden.
WILLOWS:
Hey!
How'd it go with the Sheriff?
Media's all over him.
Which means he's all
over the Undersheriff,
who's all over Ecklie,
who's blaming me
for not going public
with the Izzy Delancy Miniature
like he told me to.
Well, I got the final trace
report on the bleach water
that spilled at
the scene, but...
the fluid in the ear
was biological.
Water and proteins.
Lipocalin, lactoferrin,
lysozyme.
Tears.
Mm-hmm.
The victim was crying?
The smudges are from the pillow.
There were no tear tracks.
I don't think
the victim was crying.
I think the killer was.
WILLOWS:
When you cry,
your tears sometimes can pick
up skin cells from your cheek.
The DNA in your tears
that were found on your sister's
body prove that you were there.
I imagine it was the hardest
thing you've ever done.
But you did it.
You should've seen Barbara
when she was young.
She was fierce.
And fearless.
She protected me.
She was the smartest,
the funniest,
best friend I could ask for
in life.
The Parkinson's just robbed her
of everything.
She'd take medication;
she'd go away.
She'd get off medication.
She'd become lucid again,
only in agony.
She wanted to die
in her own home.
There's no... assisted suicide
protection in Nevada.
She said this was
the perfect opportunity.
She could get what she wanted,
and...
everyone would blame
the Miniature Killer.
I understand.
You're under arrest.
We reran the footage several
times to get a head count.
Assuming that they're
all Dell foster kids,
there's 13 of them.
At this birthday party?
Yeah.
Lionel only remembered
the first names,
and only a few of those.
Getting the DHS records
is going to be tough.
Judges hate giving them out
unless we can demonstrate
a pressing need...
and even then,
they're spotty.
And a lot of a foster kids
change their names
when they age out.
Ernie Dell confessed
and killed himself
to protect someone
that he loved.
And that someone
has murdered five people.
Eenie, meeny, miney, mo.
Catch a monster by the toe.