Urine.
(sniffing)
I don't smell it.
Ever since
Father started
leaving the church
open at night.
The church has gotten
a lot more use.
Yeah, as an orgy house
and a toilet.
No. People come in at all hours
of the night to pray.
"Dear Jesus, please keep me from
blowing all my laundry money
on the nickel slots
at the Gas 'N' Go."
Oh, somebody's done
their business
right here
next to Jesus.
Oh, no, not again.
Right here on the eve
of the apocalypse, a miracle.
(garbled radio transmissions)
Somebody went to a lot of
trouble to get her up there.
Why? I wonder.
Somebody had a grudge
against the church
or somebody
in the church.
Or maybe they were
just mad at God.
Well, Jesus died
for our sins.
What sin did she die for?
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me
who are you, you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
(camera clicking)
You know, if you
think about it,
this is one of the oldest ways
to kill somebody.
Considering where we are,
highly symbolic.
All right, what do you got?
How we gonna do this?
Well, the two-by-four is tied
to the scaffold
with a single loop.
There is an empty pulley
up here.
We could lower her down
with that.
That's probably how the killer
got her up there
in the first place.
Then he ditched the rope.
I wouldn't be surprised to find
it around here someplace.
First things first.
We'll use our rope;
I'll run it through this pulley,
and then let you
take the weight.
I'll mark the rope,
cut the knot;
down she goes.
Ready?
Yeah.
You take the weight.
I'll cut it on three.
One,
two,
three.
Got it?
Yeah, ready.
Oh.
Whoever tied her up there
had to be strong enough
to deadlift her weight.
Yeah, either that
or highly motivated.
You know how it is
once somebody's
adrenaline gets pumping.
Feel like they
can do anything.
All right, that's it.
(siren whoops)
(garbled radio transmission)
Look, shouldn't Father
Frank be here by now?
Father Frank lives
in manana land.
Well, I'm sure
he's on his way.
Father Frank is
a wonderful priest.
And since he's been here,
church attendance has tripled.
Among our female congregants.
(sighs)
And we have
sponsors for
our building fund.
One sponsor.
The Big Hombre?
The car dealership.
Time of death
was sometime
between 2:00
and 4:00.
Nasty head wound.
She was actively bleeding,
so she had to have been alive
when she was tied
to the cross.
Good chance she died
of suffocation.
Like Jesus.
Well, Jesus had
a footrest.
He was able to lift himself up
and take short breaths.
But this young lady was hanging.
Her pectoral muscles
probably became
paralyzed
and the intercostal muscles
were unable to function.
She was able to breathe out,
but not breathe in.
In time, carbon dioxide
built up
in her lungs and bloodstream.
Edema built up
in the chest cavity.
Heart went into fibrillation.
(heart beating rapidly)
Gruesome torture in any century.
WILLOWS:
In 18 years, this is
my first crucifixion.
In a Catholic church
with no crucifixes.
GRISSOM:
I imagine the priest
is a resurrection
theologian,
as opposed to
a crucifixion theologian.
They believe in forgiveness
rather than penance.
We could all use
a little forgiveness.
She was bleeding
from her head wounds,
and the beating didn't
take place up there.
WILLOWS:
Well, the blood pool
is gravitational.
And the blood trail...
...the tips are pointing
towards the statue.
She was bleeding on the way in.
I'll backtrack, see if I can
find the point of origin.
Excuse me, huh?
I-I got to go, Father.
I'll see you.
Okay.
I'm the pastor of the church.
Hey, Captain.
He'll take
care of you.
Thank you.
Father Frank Berlin.
I'm Jim Brass, Las Vegas Police.
You were supposed to be here
45 minutes ago. Where you been?
Been serving breakfast
at the shelter.
I understand there's been
a death in the church.
How soon before
you're out of here?
Father, this is
a murder investigation.
It's just
we hold Mass at 10:00.
Yeah, I understand.
Sorry, Father, but, uh,
this is a crime scene.
You're not gonna get
your church back for a while.
Is it all right if we set Mass
in the community center?
Yeah, sure, I have
no problem with that.
FRANK:
Sister, would you
tell the choir
we'll be singing
"In Paradisum."
I'll take care
of it, Father.
We sing the hymn for the dead
every time we have a death.
Sisters couldn't
identify the victim,
so we'll need you
to take a look.
Sorry. I didn't mean
to sound cavalier.
It's just we've had over
half a dozen deaths this year.
We've never had to close
the church.
That's because,
in this neighborhood,
those derelicts and drug addicts
died of heatstroke, overdose
and old age.
None of them were strung
up in the rafters.
Father Frank Berlin,
this is Gil Grissom
from the crime lab.
Do you recognize her?
I'll take that
as a no.
Excuse me, Father.
Is that blood
on your jacket?
We had a fight in the shelter.
I had to break it up.
We're gonna need
to take your clothes.
No, you can't have my clothes.
BRASS:
Then you have to come
downtown to the police station.
If you're gonna
say Mass later,
you have to change
anyway, right?
Greg, go with him,
collect his clothing.
Is it a bigger sin to lie
if you're a priest?
I hope so.
(strikes match)
This one's for you, Sam.
When will I get those back?
I only have
three sets of clothes.
Respectfully, Father, a woman's
been murdered in your church
and your clothes
have blood on them.
You're lucky you're
not under arrest.
(choir singing ethereal song
in foreign language)
♪ ♪
Was there bougainvillea
at the crime scene?
Two shrubs at the
entrance of the church.
A row of four on the wall
of the community center.
Three bushes behind the rectory
adjacent to the statue
of St. Jude.
Did you anticipate that question
in order to impress me with
your powers of observation?
Memory's a gift.
Mmm.
From whom?
Who do you think?
Well, I wouldn't necessarily
call myself an atheist,
but I am not sold on the notion
of a higher power.
However,
I used to love
the stories
of the saint.
This job certainly
challenges your faith.
Yes, it does.
But I have science.
I believe we need
a little of both.
Sometimes
I think
we made up God
just to have someone
to blame for our mistakes.
It's just a theory.
♪ ♪
(car alarm blares)
(chuckling):
Hey.
Hey!
Hey, I found it.
Rope, nails, hammers,
everything.
Oh, yeah.
Something I said?
No, dear.
I didn't offend you,
did I?
Did I say something offensive
to you as a Catholic?
I'm not really a Catholic
anymore, you know.
I suppose I practice a kind
of secular Catholicism
that involves ritualizing
certain aspects of everyday life
and imbuing them with
a spiritual intensity
they might not
otherwise possess,
but I don't want to put
too fine a point on it.
And the rosary beads
are a part of that.
This belonged to my mother.
Take a look
at this pattern.
Five series of
ten beads each
representing the
"Five Mysteries"
separated by five
"Our Father" beads.
Who would strangle someone
with a rosary?
Probably the same person
who would crucify someone
in a church.
St. Jude.
Patron saint of lost causes.
And that's why it's
so difficult to keep
the local kids from
defacing this statue.
Did you run those tests
on my clothes?
We did. The blood
on your clothes is not a match
to the blood on the victim.
So do I get my clothes back?
Not just yet.
I have a favor to ask.
You steal my clothes
and then you want to ask
for another favor?
We'd like permission
to search your rectory
and the nun's apartments.
Just because
someone dies in our church
doesn't mean we have anything
to do with it.
Well, we want to eliminate you
as suspects.
That's what you said
when you fingerprinted us,
and the truth is you don't
have enough for a warrant.
You're right.
But you have nothing to hide.
You really think
if I killed a woman,
I'd leave her body
in my own church?
It's so obvious
that it obviates suspicion.
Mmm, I'm not that smart.
Well, that's hardly
the argument to make.
What is it you're looking for?
Rosaries.
Mr. Grissom,
I didn't realize you were here.
That's all right, Sister.
We don't have to hide anything
from Mr. Grissom.
Uh, he's here
to confiscate our rosaries.
I don't know where mine are.
Do you?
It's probably in the sacristy.
We'll need all the rosaries.
Uh, even Sister Elizabeth's?
She's not going to like that.
Happy day for Sister Elizabeth,
for she delights
in what she dislikes.
♪ ♪
The killer used materials
from the church:
the rope, the 2x4s,
and one of these hammers.
I just haven't
found it yet.
But all this was
in the same utility closet.
He didn't bring
anything with him?
Hmm-mm.
What does this
feel like to you?
Inside job.
I mean maybe one
of the construction workers
wasn't a fan
of the victim.
I'm going to call Brass.
What?
I've solved your case.
Bull.
No, cow.
Those hairs you found
on the scaffold:
not human.
Bovine.
They have red cows?
You betcha, partner.
Guernseys.
Maybe the scaffold
was used somewhere else.
Like on a farm.
Or maybe it was
secondary transfer.
Well, you can
take care of that.
I've done all
the heavy lifting.
As usual.
Oh, hi.
Hi.
I saw you
at the crime scene.
I thought you were on desk duty
until the coroner's inquest.
Yeah, I was starting
to get a serious case
of trucker butt so I told
Grissom that I wanted to, uh,
get back out with the team.
Yeah, there's no
therapy like work.
You doing okay?
Yeah.
Well, hang in there.
All right.
(sighs)
Mr. Bombay.
We found your keys
at the scene of our murder.
We also found
your car close by.
I don't know anything
about a murder.
Well, we also found
a wad of bloody tissues
in the front seat
of your vehicle.
What... what's going on?
You tell me.
I loaned my car to a woman
I work with last night.
She sings at my club.
Charlotte Danville.
Is she all right?
Was this your friend?
Yeah, that's her.
Who did... who did this to her?
Why did she borrow your car?
She had to...
She had to do another set
and needed
to change her clothes.
Doesn't she have her own car?
She had a Lexus.
Totally tricked out.
So why did she borrow yours?
I don't know.
I didn't get the whole story.
She seemed upset.
She was talking to this guy.
I had to send a waitress over
to remind her
that she was
getting paid to sing.
You ever see the
guy move forward?
Yeah, it's that guy
that sells cars on television.
Uh... Cody White.
The Big Hombre.
I mean, but a lot of guys
came in to see Charlotte.
I mean, it's not like
she slept around or anything.
I tried.
Can I go now?
Not without an alibi.
Where did you
spend the night?
I allowed myself to succumb
to the pleasures of Donna.
And she kept me up
to the wee hours of the morning
gratifying her abnormal lust.
She sleeps with her eyes open.
Yeah, this is it.
Well, this car's already
been cleaned and detailed.
It's ready to be sold.
Well, I guess it's
a change of plans.
No.
No, there's not
a change of planes.
This baby's staying
right where she sits.
I'm not in the
give-away-the-car-to-cops
business.
I'm in the sell-the-car-
to-willing-victims business.
Mr. White, we have
a court order
to examine this car
for evidence related
to the murder of
Charlotte Danville.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
Charlotte?
She and I are friends.
I... I knew her.
Yeah, I know.
We have a witness
who places you arguing
with her last night.
You may be one of the last
people to see her alive.
Yeah.
I was with her.
I went to see Charlotte
to give her the car.
Helped Charlotte
through
a rough patch,
but lately she been ducking me.
What am I supposed to do now?
Walk home?
I'll give you
money for a cab.
Tomorrow, we'll see about
getting you a good used car.
Some junker.
Thanks a lot.
Some friend you are.
Take your damn car.
Guess that's what you get
for helping a friend, you know.
Look, I feel awful about
about Charlotte. I really do.
But I'll tell you this:
whatever happened
happened after I got this car.
Well, I feel awful too, but
the car is coming with me.
WILLOWS:
No sign of forced entry.
Does this look
like the condo
of a woman who
sings weekends
at the Gorilla Room?
Looks like the fight
started here.
Got some blood, some
here on the pillow.
But no blood trail.
The real beating took place
in the bushes at the church.
This was just the opening act.
Explains the bloody tissue found
in the backseat of Hugo's car.
I guess she got a bloody
nose or a fat lip here,
ran out and used Hugo's car
to go to the church.
CURTIS:
The killer must have
followed her
and caught up
with her there.
She had quite the career.
Sofia.
You recognize that guy?
Father Frank.
I mean, a lot
younger, obviously.
You know him?
No.
That's the Big Hombre.
He sells cars on TV.
She's known these guys forever.
Here's a rosary.
Looks like
it's broken.
Hmm. Could be the one
she was strangled with.
And here's her purse
and cell phone.
You don't leave home without
those unless you're in a hurry.
Or you're
being chased.
TV's on pause.
(singing karaoke on TV)
Well, there they are again.
Someone was taking a trip
down memory lane.
♪ They tear us apart ♪
There was a man in her life.
Mr. Frisky.
Drain smells like whiskey,
empty bottles in the trash,
more liquor than you could
use in a wild weekend.
She might have been
going on the wagon.
Folic acid.
Fresh fruit, vegetables,
plenty of milk.
You think
she was pregnant?
We'll have Robbins
run a pregnancy test.
(computer beeps)
(beeping continues)
♪ ♪
Hey.
Got another rosary
for your collection.
Where'd you get this?
Catherine found it
in Charlotte's condo.
There is some evidence
that the fight
started there.
Charlotte's bag and
cell phone were there,
as if she left
in a hurry.
Are those
Father Frank's?
Yeah.
Where's Father Frank?
Father Frank is hearing
confessions tonight.
It's St. Bart's
all over again.
Only that time, he
went in handcuffs.
That never happened.
It was just a rumor.
(grunts loudly)
Hey!
Didn't your mother tell you
you're not supposed
to fight in church?
Cody White.
What's up, hombre?
Father Frank and I
are actually old friends.
Just having a conversation
about church finances.
But aren't you the one
who's funding the renovation
of the church?
Not anymore.
Well, there you go.
We done here?
BRASS:
Yeah.
So what sins did he commit
to earn
the punch-out penance?
Let's talk
about it downtown.
GRISSOM:
These are unique rosaries,
Father.
Handmade in Italy.
And they're
sequentially numbered
on the back.
So we know that they were
purchased together.
One of them is yours; one we
found at the victim's condo.
Did you give it to her?
Yes.
BRASS:
You know, Father, when we
asked you if you knew her,
you said you didn't.
After I saw Charlotte's body,
I don't recall
being asked any questions.
Um, uh, maybe I said "no"
to what I was seeing.
I don't really remember
much about yesterday.
What about the night before?
I was at the shelter.
You know,
we can't find anyone
who remembers seeing you there
after midnight.
Because I wasn't there
past midnight.
Where were you?
One of our regulars, Marty,
came in high on crack.
He got into an argument,
a fight with one
of the other men, and I...
What time was that?
Uh, it was late.
I don't wear a watch.
We had to call
the paramedics;
you can check with them.
Charlotte died around 2:00 a.m.
Where were you then?
I was out with Marty
trying to walk off his high
to keep him out of trouble.
Does Crackhead Marty
have a last name?
I-I don't know.
You know, Father, listen,
I'm telling you,
these answers--
none of them work for me.
Well, then put me in jail.
I'll still be doing exactly
the same work I'm doing out here
with exactly the same results.
I don't want to do that.
(knocking)
BRASS:
Sister Bridget?
I think you should
see this, Cap.
I'm sorry I didn't
come forward
sooner, Father.
We caught her trying to bring
this into the building.
This is the hammer I used
to build the cross.
FRANK:
No, no, she didn't.
She must've got that
out of my office
at the shelter.
I took it off Marty.
Father, sit down, please.
Sister, excuse me, but...
could you tell us
how you managed to haul
the victim's body
to the top of the scaffolding?
I used the rope and the pulley,
the one the
workmen use.
But why did you kill her?
Because she had to be stopped.
She was coming for Father,
and I couldn't
let that happen.
Now...
do your job.
Arrest me.
Sister, how much do you weigh?
123 pounds.
It's a question of physics.
Charlotte weighed 140 pounds,
plus the weight of the cross.
You don't weigh enough
or have enough strength
to have hoisted the body
17 feet into the air.
It was a miracle.
The only miracle is I'm not
charging you with obstruction.
♪ ♪
(beeping)
Father Frank.
The blood on the hammer
is a match
to the blood found
on the Father's clothes,
but none of it is
from Charlotte.
Well, you know, he told me
that he broke up
a fight at the shelter.
I think Sister Bridget
found the bloody hammer
and confessed to the murder
because she thought
Father Frank was guilty.
If she thinks he did it,
maybe he did it.
But why does she think
that he did it?
You know,
his move from St. Bart's
to St. Jude's involved
a female parishioner
who committed suicide.
No charges were filed,
but the parish board
asked that he be removed.
SIDLE:
I can do you one better.
Catherine found two sets
of semen stains
on Charlotte's bedding.
Unknown contributor
on the bed skirt.
Probably doesn't
get washed as often.
But the one on the sheet
is a match to Father Frank.
It's probably
more recent.
And here is
the big thing:
Uh, Doc Robbins says
that Charlotte was
about ten weeks pregnant.
STOKES:
Maybe he's the unwilling
father of her unborn child.
Well, DNA will
give us a profile.
One more thing
that he did not tell us.
We didn't ask.
BRASS:
I don't know, I mean,
most people give
their friends,
uh, subscriptions to
Fruit of the Month club.
(chuckling)
But you gave your friend
Charlotte a condo and a car.
It's like I told you before,
I was helping her out.
I was letting her live there
and use the car
till she got on her feet.
She came back to Vegas
broke and strung out,
and I was helping her.
So it was supposed to
be a short-term thing?
It was supposed to be
short-term, but it was endless.
Sort of like
renovating St. Jude's.
So is that what the fight
in the church was about?
No, that's not
what the fight was about.
I went to talk to him
about Charlotte.
I thought maybe
taking the car back had
something to do with her death.
I don't know. Then he said
something; I said...
I don't even remember,
to tell you the truth.
But I'll tell you this:
he lost it.
I've never seen
Frank like that.
So do you always have
personal conversations
in the confessional?
Can't talk to him in his office
with that Sister Bridget
hovering around.
Besides, I'd never want
his relationship with Charlotte
to be open to misinterpretation.
Now, why would
their relationship
be open to misinterpretation?
They were more than friends.
GRISSOM:
Going by her scrapbook,
this seems to have been
a golden time in Charlotte's
life-- high school.
There's a lot of pictures
of the three of them together,
but the only two-shots
are of Frank and Charlotte
except for this one.
Evidently, she went
to her prom with Cody.
STOKES:
She looks thrilled. (sarcastic)
The next picture of Frank,
he's in a seminary.
Maybe, uh,
giving up Charlotte
was the sacrifice he made
to join the Church.
I need to ask you
a few more questions.
Go ahead and ask the question
you really want to know.
Who killed Charlotte Danville?
I did.
(sighs)
(elevator bell dings)
Single malt express
is leaving the station
as soon as
I get home.
Look, I know it sounds nuts,
but this is not the way
a resurrection theologian would
kill his pregnant mistress.
He confessed.
He's a Catholic.
They're full of guilt.
He's a priest,
for God's sakes.
That's the whole point
of the priesthood.
No sleeping around.
More energy for
good works and
noble deeds.
Now you find me some evidence
to exonerate the good Father,
and we'll talk.
WILLOWS:
Hi. I heard Grissom wants us
to keep digging.
This Charlotte's car?
Yeah.
I found blood smears,
but they've been washed.
Cody said he repo'd
the car at the club
and drove it back to the lot.
There shouldn't be any blood
in this car.
Well, unless Father Frank
drove it that night,
and we've got no reason
to believe
that he did.
Which brings us back to Cody.
Do you have a big enough sample
for DNA?
No.
But I do know
one spot the
detailers never hit.
Bloody shoe impression
on the brake pedal.
Well, I'll compare it
to Father Frank's shoes.
If it's not a match, I'll get
a warrant for Cody's shoes.
I'll get a sample
of the blood to DNA.
CODY:
I'm trying to shoot
a commercial here,
so I don't see
why this can't wait.
I can't even read this,
so why don't you tell me
what it is that you want?
Your boots and a DNA sample.
Well, there's my wife.
Candy!
Get my damn lawyer
on the phone now.
What's wrong?
Would... would you just do it,
please?
We found rust-colored fur
on the scaffold
at the crime scene.
CURTIS:
Well, I'll call
a judge and get him to amend
the warrant to include the vest.
J-J-J-J-J-J... Hold on
for a minute, all right?
Would you just hang on?
Hey, I found these
in his office.
Positive for blood
on the right sole.
Where's my wife?
Candy?!
Well, Big Hombre,
it looks like
you're going to the hoosegow.
(panting)
So, you don't like crucifixes,
but maybe you made an exception
when you found out
Charlotte was pregnant, hmm?
GRISSOM:
Father...
I want you to take
a look at this.
I'm responsible for her murder.
I could never do that.
In my world, Father,
you're either guilty
or innocent.
Well, in my world,
you can be both.
The blood on your boot
is Charlotte's.
Your footprint was found
on the brake pedal
of her car
in blood.
The lab also matched hair
from your fur vest
to hair found dried
in the blood of the
victim in the church.
(laughs)
Now matter how much evidence
you have, I'm the Big Hombre.
I get whatever I want,
including store-bought justice.
And yet, the one thing
you couldn't get
was Charlotte's love.
Yeah, like I said,
I only saw her that last time
to get the car.
♪ Come the day you're mine ♪
(men scatting along)
♪ Come the day you're ♪
♪ Mine. ♪
(applause)
Thanks for coming.
Come on. I'd come every night
if you wanted me to.
You know that.
Here's the car back.
You really are a good friend.
No, you gave her the car.
You gave her everything.
And how did she pay you back?
She dumped you
for your best friend.
(keys jangling)
Here's the car back.
And I'm moving.
Why would you do that?
I can't do this anymore.
It's not right.
I'm in love with another man.
I'm sorry, Cody.
That's what you got for me?
You got, you're sorry?
I'm sorry, too.
GRISSOM:
We, uh,
found a letter
you wrote to the Bishop
and pulled it
off your computer.
"The spirit has left
my vocation.
"I've crossed a line
in my discipline
"and committed an act
that has left me unfit
for the priesthood."
What act is that?
Putting my love for Charlotte
above my love for God.
So, you were leaving
the priesthood?
I was leaving
because I loved her,
and I wanted to be with her
in all ways.
Her dying doesn't change that.
I still love her.
I talked to the Monsignor.
It's a complicated process,
but I told him I'm leaving.
Are you sure?
I prayed about it.
What came to me was
that God is love.
Wherever there is true love,
God is, as well.
I have to follow my heart.
And we only made love once,
but in the wake of that,
I found the husband in me,
the father in me.
I wanted
to be those men for her.
And I always loved her.
And what if the baby
wasn't yours?
A child is always welcome.
Yeah, I decorated her condo,
you know that?
I bought her that car.
Special-ordered the paint
to match the color of her eyes.
She didn't care as long
as she had a place to stay.
That's all she cared about.
She cared about Father Frank,
didn't she?
Did you suspect that she
was leaving you for him?
Should have, but I didn't.
What are you doing here?
Look, I'm sorry about
the dress, all right?
I have to get back to the club.
Wait, wait, wait.
I want to know who
you're leaving me for.
No.
(slaps)
(groaning)
What is that?
It's Frank, isn't it?
(shouting):
Isn't it?
(groaning)
It's always
been Frank.
(choking)
You know, he doesn't think
you did it.
But I think
that you know
who killed Charlotte.
He came to the church that day
to confess, didn't he?
Bless me, Father,
for I have sinned.
My last confession
was two weeks ago.
I lied to my wife seven times.
I cheated an old lady
out of a classic car.
And I killed my best friend
for cheating on me with you.
You know I can't discuss that.
You know, in Vegas,
it's routine
to hear the most heinous sins,
and as a priest, you listen,
and in Christ's name,
you forgive.
I knew she'd go running to him.
She'd always run back to Frank,
and I knew he wouldn't be there.
He was never there.
Is that when
you thought of
crucifying her
in Frank's church?
I don't know
how I came up with that.
You know, Frank always
used to talk
about the problem of human evil.
How...
you better watch out
'cause it'd come into you
in times of despair.
Something terrible
came into me that night.
I loved Charlotte more
than anything.
The paternity test came back.
You were
the father.
You killed your own baby.
(sobbing)
You were my friend.
You should have come
to me like a man.
Can you forgive him?
That's Christ's mandate.
You know what that means.
You have no choice.