(siren wailing)
Fellas, another incident
at Lolita's.
What now?
An erotic athlete
claiming a 420-Z.
The paramedics have
her on a stretcher.
What the hell's
an erotic athlete?
Well, I hope it's a tight end
in a G-string.
Nice.
(laughs)
Greg?
Yeah.
419 at Tagliferri's
restaurant on 8th Avenue.
All right.
Thanks.
I'm on it.
Cath?
Huh?
415-B at the HaHaHa.
What's the weapon?
A Taser? Come on!
An angry clown got pissed
at some heckler
with clogged arteries,
and it caused a heart attack.
So, Greg-O gets a hit
at a mob restaurant,
and I get a clown
who can't take a joke?
Trust me, you don't want
Greg's 419.
SIDLE:
Hey. Hey.
Hey.
CDC needs someone out
at the Omdi-Tech offices
on Boulder Highway.
I'm sure it's not hazardous,
or they wouldn't
let us collect it.
Okay. You
coming with?
No, I'm spending
the night in autopsy
with the Lake Mead floater.
Well, enjoy.
That guy was putrid.
Oh, by the way...
(touch tones beeping)
(phone beeps open)
(phone ringing)
(monkey laughing)
HODGES:
Four crime scene miniatures,
four murder victims,
and one diabolical killer
with an obsessive streak
who still remains at large.
I don't know if any
of you have noticed
how distracted
Grissom's been lately,
but it's these.
Keeping him up at night.
You know
the combination?
Of course.
Grissom could use some
fresh eyes on the case,
and that's why
I've asked you here.
Obviously,
this could be perceived
as insulting
to the CSIs
who formerly worked the case,
so secrecy is
of the utmost importance.
Double down low.
WEBSTER: (British accent):
Oh, James,
it's Moneypenny.
M needs you back at HQ.
Shoe phone was Get Smart,
though.
Oh, that's right.
99 was so hot.
Mm.
Four people are dead,
the killer is still out there,
and you're mocking?
We're mocking you.
Ah. You in or out?
I don't really
know anything
about these cases.
We'll review.
I don't know.
I have a lot of work to do.
And by work, you mean
IM'ing your Icelandic pen pal
who thinks that you look
like Warrick Brown because
that's the picture
you posted.
How...?
I just know.
Archie, in?
What the hell, but
I got to leave early.
I got a surfing trip
in Santa Barbara
this weekend.
Miss Mockery?
Well, we can't leave the lab,
we can't talk to suspects.
What exactly does Grissom
wants us to do?
It's not always
what you look at that matters,
it's what you see.
That's Thoreau.
Oh, is it? Hmm.
JOHNSON:
Okay, Professor.
And your point would be?
The answers lie in these.
We're lab techs.
We think differently
than field guys.
They deal with people,
we deal with things.
Maybe we can't find the killer,
but I think
we can find
the thing that links
all four murders.
This is an
opportunity.
We have one shift
to show Grissom
what we're made of.
Tonight, we could be heroes.
All right, all right.
I'm in.
It's time to think
outside the box.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
♪ ♪
The first miniature was found
at the crime scene
seven months ago.
The victim is Izzy Delancy,
washed-up rock star.
Blunt force trauma
to the back of the head.
Bonked with a rolling pin,
found in the drawer
at the scene.
Stalker maybe?
Izzy didn't have
any known stalkers,
and there was no
forced entry.
Suspects include
his first wife,
his current wife,
the nanny he was schtuping
and his teenage son.
Motive thought to be sex?
And-or money.
Izzy's music library
was for sale.
Mucho dinero
to be gained.
So?
So...
nothing.
Every suspect was exonerated.
All we were
left with
was this...
GRISSOM:
A perfect, half-inch scale model
of the room.
And assuming that the killer
is the same person
who made the miniature...
It would have taken weeks,
maybe even months to create
with this kind of detail.
It certainly qualifies
as premeditation.
It's real blood.
The killer actually
stuck around
to match the blood pool
at the scene.
Ah, ah, ah, ah!
What?
What are you doing?
Sitting.
No, no. You're tempting fate.
You know how
you should never try on
someone else's
engagement ring,
hold the Oscar,
use the excuse
that your grandmother died
when she didn't...
WEBSTER: I tried on
Suzie Quinceworthy's
diamond ring
last year.
It looked really good on her,
and looked terrible on me.
I don't think an
emerald cut flatters
my little ten-ies.
Will I never marry?
I'll marry you.
Although, you know, my
grandmother's still alive.
She lives down in Boca.
I don't know if you know this,
but I am
the shuffleboard champion
of the Boca Surf
and Sand.
Mm.
Lady killer of the senior set.
Rock on.
I can do an open marriage.
Why do you guys keep doing that?
Do what?
JOHNSON:
Hodges, relax, man.
I don't want to run the lab.
We are guests
in the man's office.
If there was one person
who was more respectful
of space and boundaries,
it's Grissom.
You could at least
offer him the same courtesy.
Wait.
Is he okay
with us being in here?
He said he'd be in Autopsy,
won't be back for hours.
Anyway, they never solved
Izzy Delancy's murder.
Two months later,
Penny Garden was found dead
in her house.
(thunder rumbles, record plays
scratchy '50s record)
(rolling thunder)
(sighs)
(record continues playing)
(crackling thunder)
WEBSTER:
Suspects included
her ex-junkie
nephew who was
living with her,
and her drug-dealing
neighbor,
who was buying
prescription meds from her.
Obvious motives--
drugs and money.
Did either of them have
any connection to Izzy Delancy?
No.
CSIs didn't
even realize
this was a Miniature case
until this was
anonymously delivered
to the scene the next day.
And why wasn't it left with
the body like the other one?
Good question.
Grissom and I really noodled
over that one.
Look carefully at
the back of the doll,
and at the pillow
on the chair.
There appears
to be remnants
of glue on both.
So the doll was originally
glued to the back
of the chair.
I think the killer expected
the victim to die
in this chair.
Well, if that's the case,
then how did the killer expect
to... kill her?
HODGES:
The killer knew
that Penny was always stinko
on Cherry Herring
by coupon-clipping time, so...
ANDREWS:
He laced her booze
with liquid nicotine,
which induced convulsions.
(coughing)
JOHNSON:
And when she went all twitchy
and through the window...
WEBSTER:
The OCD killer had
to match it with his mini,
which is why
it showed up late.
Red dog barks at midnight.
What are you guys doing in here?
Nothing.
Yeah.
All right, freakboy, your phone
has been ringing off the hook,
so I finally answered it,
and Warrick and Nick said
they have a ton of trace,
and they really need you
to clear the decks.
No problem.
After you.
Hmm. Irides brown.
No apparent puncture wounds,
abrasions or lacerations.
COD appears
to be drowning.
We did pull him out
of Lake Mead you know.
Right. Based on decomp,
I'd put TOD around
48 hours ago.
Where's his head, David?
They haven't found it yet.
Day shift.
(short laugh)
(gurgles)
(gurgling, sucking)
Uh-oh. He's got gas.
Phew.
Yeah, he's going
to be a stinker.
You want a mask?
No, I'm all right.
(sloshing)
(slurping and bubbling)
What the hell?
(gurgling)
Rat!
(clattering)
Nice work.
At least I tried to get him.
Where were you?
I hate rats.
(glass shattering,
high-pitched scream)
Wow. Don't bother
being discerning.
BROWN:
Hey, what can I say?
Erotic athletes are kind of
gratuitous with the hands.
And lube on latex leaves
excellent ridge detail.
What's with the, uh,
blast from the past?
You got new evidence
on the miniatures?
Um, just refiling
some stuff.
Uh, G-on-G action.
It's not really a big question
as to who did it, is it?
One ring, six women.
Ursula Major claims Ursula Minor
was responsible
for the pile drive.
Only you, my dear,
will know for sure.
Have fun.
Is that condensation?
Oh, no, it's-it's lube...
I think.
Yeah, these bikinis are
from the erotic athletes
at Lolita's bar.
This woman, Lucy Pavorotti,
broke her neck
flipping around up there.
Well, now she's suing everybody.
Okay. I'm on it.
Nothing?
What?
Nothing at all?
I'm all ready for "Luscious Lucy
likey Lolita's lubey."
Or something.
Every man is not an end
but a beginning.
Today I rise above
and step up.
Have a nice day.
Good point.
Hey, I've been meaning
to ask you about something
you might be interested in.
(cell phone buzzing)
The Forensic Academy
has their conference in June.
and I'm going to be speaking
on field work.
But the thing
about it is, man,
I'm just no good when it comes
to IR trace technology.
But now you... you are.
Oh.
So... what do you think?
It's in Iowa.
Which is... as fun as
you want to make it, but...
So according to this,
a month after
Penny Garden's murder,
Grissom investigated
an electrocution
at the Mannleigh
chicken plant.
The victim was Raymundo Suarez,
early 30s,
a nighttime janitor.
It looked like a possible
industrial accident,
or maybe even
a workplace homicide.
Right up until they found
the perfect half-inch scale
cast metal mini.
Suspects included the boss,
Ike Mannleigh.
Raymundo was sleeping
with his wife, Bubbles.
(woman moaning)
I can't even do it
with my cat watching.
Wait. Sex, drugs, rock and roll.
Do you think it's a pattern?
No, 'cause
according to this,
sex may not have
actually been the issue.
Yeah, Ike Mannleigh
was exonerated,
and another coworker,
Ernie Dell,
he looked good
for all of the murders.
Yeah, that's right,
he was caught on tape
in an animal rights PSA
made by Izzy Delancy.
Yes, he was.
Look at this.
Ew.
Yeah, tell me about it.
I had to scan this thing
for hours.
Haven't been able to eat chicken
since.
Anyway, Ernie Dell
was really into model trains.
You know, the way a serial
killer's really into pets.
JOHNSON:
So when CSIs went to his house,
they found these molds for all
these creepy little things.
Some of which matched pieces
from the Izzy Delancy
miniature.
Ernie was caught on some
neighborhood watch
surveillance video
delivering the mini
to Penny Garden's house.
This guy can't stay away
from a camera.
You don't know
how right you are.
He confessed on live video,
e-mailed it directly
to Grissom.
My name is Ernest Edward Dell.
I was born in 1946
in Ames, Iowa.
(tape fast-forwarding)
...spend any amount of time
around people,
you get your heart broke.
Treachery.
Hypocrisy.
The promise of love.
A man could kill from sunup
to sunset
and still his work
would never be done.
(gunshot)
Wendy?
Could I speak
with you a moment?
Sure.
This is exactly why I didn't
invite you to join us.
You take over everything.
Uh...
Grissom asked me
to gather some techs
to review the
Miniature cases.
Like a think tank.
Yeah, I know, they told me.
So, kudos to you.
I hand selected them with
careful consideration
to group dynamics.
Well, I can see that.
I mean, it's you
and your back up singers.
You're Davy Hodges
and the Lemmings.
You should take your act
on the road.
ANDREWS:
We can hear you.
Look, the only reason
that you don't like me
is because I actually
stand up to you.
Which, by the way,
is exactly what you need.
You know I would be good
at all this miniature stuff.
That's not the
only reason.
Really? Okay, what is it?
You think
you're too cool.
Oh, my God.
What are we, 12?
I don't know, are we?
It's just a rat, fellas.
Why are you wearing
the HazMat gear?
He made me do it.
It's a wild animal
covered with potentially
biohazardous material
with claws.
Rabies, scabies,
AIDS, hepatitis.
I'm thinking of this suit
as a giant rubber glove.
ROBBINS:
The vic's intestines?
What are you doing?
Rats are neophobic--
they fear the new.
We stand a better
chance of catching him
by giving him what
he's used to.
(scratching)
(thumping)
Pestilence, alive and well.
(electrical crackling)
(crackling continues,
power whining)
I think he's onto us, Doc.
ANDREWS:
Miniature number four
was another home,
a unit in a high-rise condo,
complete
with a working fireplace...
(cat meows)
...and a dead cat.
(cutting cardboard)
(tape tearing)
But the MO on this one
was full of anomalies.
It was sent to the Crime Lab
shortly after Ernie Dell's
suicide,
but before the murder
had actually been committed.
And the really weird part
was the package was addressed
directly to Grissom.
But why, to taunt him?
Like suddenly
it's personal?
The intended victim
was Barbara Tallman.
A therapist.
But we got there first.
PD set up a sting
which resulted in the death
of an undercover officer, while
a roomful of detectives watched.
Oy.
Again, the killer
knew the habits
of the victim.
This one always took
an afternoon nap.
Based on her position
on the couch,
the CSIs thought that
the intended cause of death
might be suffocation
or poisoning.
But they found something else
instead.
ANDREWS:
Yeah, here,
it looks like the killer put
some kind of gizmo on the flue.
See, the timer went off,
activated a motor
which sealed the flap
and dropped powdered charcoal
onto the fire,
producing carbon monoxide.
So the fumes had nowhere to go
but out into the apartment
and into
the undercover officer.
(knocking on glass)
Later, Betties.
Quitter.
Glory whore.
Who were the suspects?
Somebody directly
connected with Ernie.
Somebody worth
killing himself for.
Maybe his son Lionel.
Looks like Lionel Dell
knew Barbara Tallman.
LIONEL:
Okay, so maybe
I met her, so what?
CURTIS:
So, she's dead.
That's four stiffs
associated with you, Lionel.
Five, if you count Ernie.
I don't.
You know, you keep saying
that you hated your dad,
but I'm not buying it.
You go through your life alone,
you're good
with your hands,
you have weird hobbies,
you make little things.
And when that
gets tricky...
...you call your father.
Let me tell you about Ernie.
What he cared about
in his life was...
his wife, his trains,
and his kids,
in that order.
Kids?
You're an only child.
(chuckles)
Again, if only.
If you're looking
for a love connection,
then you should maybe
go talk to one of
the chosen ones.
What are you talking about?
Fosters.
My parents had, like, dozens.
They'd come and go,
some before I was born.
My mom loved kids.
Dad loved Mom.
I guess, as soon as
I came around,
the love ran out.
I had a friend
who tried to reconnect
with some of her old
foster siblings.
And honestly, it's
next to impossible.
The system
protects minors,
they change their names,
and some of them just
fall right off the map.
Well, the only
link we have
is a disposable
cell phone number.
Calls made to
all four victims?
Mm-hmm.
And additional minutes
purchased on the phone
with Ernie Dell's credit card
after his death.
Yeah, online billing.
You can just keep spending and
paying until the card expires.
So what happened when
they called the number?
They did call the
number, right?
I'm sure they did.
(dialing)
What are you doing?
Shh.
(line ringing)
(beep)
COMPUTERIZED VOICE:
Leave a message after the tone.
(beep)
Nice one, Simms.
Now they have
my cell phone number.
Well, the victims
don't have much in common,
so I say we go metaphoric.
Hypocrisy.
Yeah, I get it.
There's Izzy the vegan
eating bacon;
Penny, the cigarette smoking
cancer patient;
Raymundo, the church-going
adulterer;
and Barbara,
the overmedicated shrink.
This is the United States
of America.
Hypocrisy is the new
national anthem.
Forget it.
Stretching.
Grissom said they checked
for commonalities between
victims and got nowhere.
I was reading
an article
in the JFS
about literary forensics.
They use a computer program
to analyze documents
to determine authorship.
For instance,
when the book Primary Colors
was first published anonymously,
people knew it was
one of Clinton's speech writers,
so they compared word usage
and phrasing with the writers
on his staff and discovered
who'd probably written it.
I say we look at the work
to find the author.
Try to figure out who it is
by what message
they're trying to send.
What?
That was a very good idea.
Well, I have one occasionally.
Okay.
Look, clearly the killer
is into signatures, right?
I mean, the miniatures
themselves are signatures,
and then within each miniature,
they all have
this doll thing.
That creepy little Sally.
Well, we're working
under the assumption
that the killer was
a foster kid, right?
With probably
an abusive childhood.
So a bloody baby doll?
I mean, it's really not
that much of a stretch
to say that the doll
represents the killer.
Grissom had something on that.
"Freud's Theory of the Uncanny
"raises the point
that as children,
"we want the doll
to come to life,
"but as adults, we are
terrified by the idea.
"Doll could represent the
uncanny that is feared,
the Sandman."
Right. Or exactly
what I just said.
So, we're looking
for an obsessive,
meticulous,
dark-ass misanthrope
who seeks recognition
for his efforts.
When would I find the time?
I'm always here.
(chuckles)
Can I have a chip?
No.
Here.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
All the miniatures have food.
Eggs...
booze...
Tea and cookies...
And a chicken?
But is it considered food if
it's still alive and clucking?
You've never lived
in Pennsylvania.
I think if the killer
is trying to make
some sort of
anti-food statement,
there are much better places
in Vegas to do it.
Like blowing up a buffet.
Yeah. Gluttons
eating crab legs.
That's exactly
where I'd start.
(chuckles)
(cell phone ringing)
Did you guys see Scream?
(cell phone continues ringing)
(beep)
Hello?
Oh, hi, Catherine.
Have I seen Wendy?
Uh, no.
She hasn't been at
her desk all day long.
Give me...
Here, let me
look for her.
Oh, oh, wait,
here she is.
(whispers):
Loser.
Hey, Catherine,
what's up?
Hey, you said you were gonna
rush DNA off that Taser
that I checked in.
Yeah, I did.
And the blood on
the Taser tips did match
your heart attack victim,
but I also found
a second male contributor
who's probably your suspect.
Run the unknown against
the semen that I found
on the clown wig
from my Peeping Tom case
last month.
Um, sure. Why?
Let's just say I got a real
good hunch about this one.
Who's the big
clown now, huh?
What about music?
Izzy has gold records,
Penny had a record player,
Barbara had high-end
stereo equipment.
Yeah, but what about
the chicken plant?
The squeals of dying chickens?
No go, amigo.
What about flowers?
The flower delivery guy
might have access to the space.
Well, I see flowers
in Penny's and Barbara's,
but not Izzy's.
Flour canister?
Stop that.
Besides, I don't think
the slaughterhouse
would be into the lobby bouquet.
What about mail?
A crazed postal worker.
Wouldn't be the first time.
There's mail on the counter,
mail on the floors,
mail on the desk...
No mail in the henhouse.
Maybe they have puns in common.
Look, if this
is really about
the killer trying
to reveal something,
is there anything that's
gotten more in-your-face
with each successive miniature?
Well, the way he kills
has certainly gotten
more complicated.
Blunt force trauma
to poison to electrocution
to a timed booby trap of carbon
monoxide in the fireplace.
What about newspaper?
Starts out on the counter,
then all over the floor,
then with the doll,
as the headline.
That's bolder
and bolder.
See, again, there's no newspaper
in the chicken plant,
not even shredded in the cages.
Okay, buzz kill.
You come up with a theory.
Hey, it's not me,
it's the Chicken plant.
That's the streak-breaker.
Well, then, maybe we should
start with that one
and work our way out.
Can you smell that?
Yes.
You shouldn't be able
to smell that through your suit.
Good to know.
(groans softly)
Did you know that rodents have
skeletons with flexible joints?
No.
If they can get their head
through something,
the rest of their body
can contort to fit.
They can crawl into spaces
as small as a quarter.
Lousy varmints.
(Robbins chuckles)
Bastard hit the main line.
That's not the only thing
he's got in his mouth.
What do you
think, Doc?
My guess would be
black tar heroin.
Looks like the rat ate the mule.
Okay, look, we gave it a try.
There's nothing in this thing
but machinery.
Let's just put it back.
Chill out.
What's this?
SIMMS:
You freaking broke it!
That's destroying
evidence.
I can fix it.
Have any of you guys
seen Grissom?
HODGES:
Some garlic bread?
Nice Chianti, maybe?
Kiss my ass.
I'd like to see you
crawl around in a Dumpster
determining the difference
between blood and marinara sauce
with six mobster goons
giving you the stink eye.
Wouldn't know
anything about that.
We're holed up in a lab all day.
What are
you guys doing?
You know, forget it.
I don't even care.
I need to go
take a shower.
Would one of you please
call janitorial
and have them clean my Denali?
Sure.
Oh, and, uh,
we think the killer might
have threw up in the alley.
Full panel.
Enjoy.
Got to go.
Good luck.
"NaOCl."
Bleach.
There was bleach
at the Izzy Delancy scene.
HODGES:
And in the vase water
at Barbara Tillman's condo.
SIMMS:
Why?
HODGES:
Put a few drop in the water,
helps kill bacteria
keeps the flowers blooming
a long time.
Put too much bleach,
flowers die.
What about Penny?
Okay.
You stay here.
I'm going to switch this
out for the Penny Garden.
No, you know what? No.
Look, this entire thing
has turned into a three-ring
circus, 'cause every time
we get something,
something else just comes along
and proves us wrong.
And, honestly, I think
you've lost your damn mind.
I mean, what makes
you think if the CSIs
can't solve this, that we can?
Seriously. I'm a
little tired of your
delusions of grandeur.
And I'm way behind in work,
and I'm sick of sneaking around.
So that's it.
I'm out.
(devices beeping)
Hey.
Here you go.
I checked
under the keys.
Crusty white stains,
pale blue under ALS.
Semen, huh?
What made you check
under the keys?
A buttprint
on the credenza.
Yeah, okay, that's gross.
CDC contacted us,
because the whole office
has a herpes
simplex 1 outbreak,
and nobody could
figure out why.
I guess you never
really know what's
going on in your office.
Hey, Sara?
Is it true
that the Miniature cases
have been keeping Grissom
up at night?
How would I know?
I just thought that maybe
you guys all talk about this it,
and... Hodges told me that
Grissom confided in him
and...
You know what? Never mind.
Just forget I even asked.
Well, listen, I-I
don't know what Hodges
has been telling you, but...
do you really think that Grissom
would confide in him?
About anything?
No.
Of course not.
You are a liar and an ass.
I mean, if you want
to go running around
like Sir Galahad,
just yanking swords
willy-nilly,
that is totally
your business.
But you put all of
us at risk here.
I think we might be onto
something with the bleach.
Hey! Stop!
Archie and Henry
gave up a full day's work
thinking that they were doing
something to help Grissom.
And Grissom never even asked you
to do this in the first place.
Technically,
all I said to them
was that Grissom needed
our help, which is true.
I only lied to you.
Aren't you worried
about your own caseload?
I've trained them all to
believe that the laser ablater
and mass spec take twice
as long as they actually do.
Oh, my God.
I cannot believe you.
I can't believe that,
for half a second, I actually
thought that I might...
You what?
Nothing.
What on God's green earth
possessed you to do this?
(package rustling)
It's my lucky day.
What?
♪ ♪
(beeping)
Yes.
SIDLE:
Well, enjoy.
That guy was putrid.
Oh, by the way,
you left
the miniatures unlocked.
GRISSOM:
Yeah, I've been looking
at those a lot lately.
HODGES:
When you walked away,
it was like the stars aligned.
It was my lucky day.
Lucky?
You're a scientist.
I was trying to help Grissom.
(chuckles)
Come on.
If Gil Grissom were here,
he'd slap your face.
CURTIS:
Yeah, I recognize him.
His street name's
Ralo Perez.
He's a drug runner
for the Jamaican mob.
According to sources,
he was skimming,
swallowing a couple balloons
for personal use.
He dropped out of sight
a couple of weeks ago.
He dropped
into Lake Mead.
Well, that's one
off my desk.
Well, I'll get
the drugs to Tox,
and we'll wrap this up.
♪ ♪
This better be good, Dave.
Bleach.
What?
I found a common element
in all four miniatures...
bleach.
There's a bottle of it
in the trash at Izzy's;
there's a barrel of it
at the chicken plant,
There's, uh, bleach in the
flower water at Barbara's condo,
and now...
a bleach coupon
in Penny's.
This-this may sound crazy,
but if the killer
is a housekeeper
or a janitor, they
would certainly know
the ins and outs
of each location, uh,
what goes in what drawer,
what book on what bookshelf.
Hours of operation,
habits, schedules.
I've thought a lot about
the killer's pathology,
and there doesn't
seem to be any regular
interval between murders,
which makes me think that
they're triggered by something.
Maybe... maybe the killer
is triggered by bleach.
The bellows.
I'm sorry?
James Tilly Matthews.
Early 19th century London.
Matthews was in Bedlam Hospital
awaiting trial.
Doctors were trying to determine
his sanity.
Several interviewed him.
Half thought he was sane,
half insane.
Turns out he
was perfectly normal...
except when someone
mentioned politics.
At that point,
he'd go into a rage
about the little men
who lived underground
and used a bellows
to push thoughts into his mind,
as well as the minds
of Parliament and the Queen.
A specific object
or word
that triggers the urge to kill.
That's a form
of delusional psychosis.
Rare, but does exist.
If the killer is
one of Ernie Dell's foster kids,
maybe bleach played a role
in some sort of childhood abuse.
He's getting back at the world
for what they did to him.
Well, if having bleach
in your home
is the common element
among victims...
(chuckles)
...then anyone can be next.
Did the victims use
a common cleaning service?
Not that we know of.
However,
it's not unusual for people
with these pathologies
to become vocal
toward the institutions
that they feel
propagate the trigger.
Maybe we could call
bleach manufacturing companies
and see if they've received
any hate mail.
Cross reference correspondence
with Vegas postmarks.
Might be able
to narrow down neighborhoods.
Good job, Hodges.
Really.
(sighs)
Now...
Do you mind?
Absolutely...
(objects rattling)
I... I'm sorry
if I crossed the line.
It won't happen again.