WOMAN:
It was the '70s,
it was Las Vegas,
it was the time
of Mickey Dunn...
...the legendary organized
crime figure
who ran Vegas operations
of extortion and racketeering
by day...
I love America!
...and partied on its disco
dance floors by night.
Until August 1976,
when federal authorities
linked Dunn to the murder
of a low-level mob informant.
It was the case prosecutors
were waiting for.
The arrest warrant was issued,
the party was over.
But the legend
had just begun.
Mickey Dunn and his fabled
gold Cadillac
vanished that hot summer night,
never to be seen again--
until today.
(speaking Spanish)
So you went fishing,
your line got stuck,
and you pulled
this up.
Do you know what
this might be?
Si, si... Everybody,
they know Mickey Dunn.
I'm Sally Jeffers, KRAC-TV,
Lake Mead, Nevada.
ANCHOMAN:
Thank you, Tally.
We look forward to the next
installment
of the Mickey Dunn story.
Coming through.
Crime lab, coming through.
Thank you.
MAN:
All right, we're all
hooked up-- let 'er rip.
WILLOWS:
You ready for this?
BROWN:
Ready to waste my morning
on another
Mickey Dunn sighting?
Yeah, right.
The guy's been spotted
more places than Elvis.
BROWN:
I know somewhere in hell,
Mickey and his old pal
Jimmy Hoffa
are laughing their asses off
at us poor dumb taxpayers.
WORKMAN:
Easy now.
All right,
here she comes.
Easy... easy...
What do you know.
WILLOWS:
Chainsaw.
That looks like him.
♪ 'Cause this fine old world
keeps spinning round ♪
♪ I've been a puppet,
a pauper, a pirate, a poet ♪
♪ A pawn and a king ♪
♪ I've been up, down, over and
out and I know one thing ♪
♪ Each time I find myself
laying flat on my face ♪
♪ I pick myself up
and get back in the race ♪
♪ That's life ♪
♪ That's life ♪
♪ I just can't deny it ♪
♪ Many times, I've thought
of quittin' ♪
♪ But my heart won't buy it ♪
♪ But if there's
nothin' shakin' ♪
♪ Come here, this July ♪
♪ I'm gonna roll myself up ♪
♪ In a big ball ♪
♪ And die ♪
♪ My, my. ♪
(cheering and applause)
Shut the machine off.
You can't top that.
(laughing)
Hey, whoa,
whoa, man, man.
No, no, you're not
going anywhere
until I buy you a round.
Come on.
(laughing):
That's my music!
Them that can sing it,
never heard of it,
and them who heard of it,
they can't sing it no more.
Well, there's still some
of us left.
I thought I was the last
of a dying breed.
Myers. Call me Michael.
Ken Billings.
What are you drinking?
What do you got?
Tina, Tina.
I don't remember
the last time
I closed a joint down.
You know... we gotta
do this again.
Anytime.
Now, can I give
you a hand?
Oh, no, no,
no, no.
I'm fine; I'm fine.
no problem.
♪ Riding high in April,
shot down in May... ♪
I told you, I don't
need any help.
(singing tune)
Right over there.
I thought I was drunk.
No, back there.
Back there.
Back there!
No, no, stop...
Stop! Stop!
Stop!
What are you doing?!
Stop! Stop!
Help! Help!
BRASS:
All right, fine.
Okay, all right.
Thanks.
(sighs)
At least the driver
was sober.
I can't say the same about
the boatload of high school kids
he was driving around town.
Listen to some of the
wonderful statements I got:
"We go, 'errr...'
dude goes 'aah.'
"We go bam...
Dude goes, 'Aah!'"
The wheelchair brake attachment
has been loosened.
Well, maybe it broke
on impact.
Impact was from
the left side.
But the bolts were loosened
on both sides.
Well, then... that looks
like we have
a homicide-related
road pizza.
GRISSOM:
Yeah.
Who ordered it?
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
Force of impact propelled
the body just over 47 feet.
Not a lot of spatter.
External damage,
mostly superficial.
Bet he's mashed up
on the inside.
Probably dead before he hit
the ground.
Oop... Wallet.
License...
registration...
Kenneth Billings.
Nevada resident.
Date of birth, 11-9-52.
Photo.
WOMAN:
Michael Myers.
Never seen the guy before.
Sure was the life
of the party, though.
Hmm. And the victim?
Kenny-- a regular.
He'd come in for Karaoke night.
Drink a little, go home.
You'd never notice him,
except for the wheelchair.
Well, this is
a late-night place.
It ever get rough
in here?
Sometimes.
You think it could've been
a hate crime?
It's a karaoke bar.
I don't see a lot of hate here.
Me neither.
Mike Meyers.
Here he is, Jim.
Knucklehead left us
his autograph.
So what was
our boy drinking?
The good stuff--
Well's Head Lager.
You sell much of that?
I'm lucky if I move
a case a year.
Got trash?
Mm-hmm.
Empties should give us DNA
and fingerprints.
Not that we really need them.
Mr. Meyers has already left us
his photograph
and signature.
And he sang karaoke.
Do you have video?
Tape's in the machine.
Perfect.
Boy, you got to love it when
a guy makes it easy for you.
Mickey Dunn's ride.
Well, I guess it looked
better in the '70a.
Live fast, die young...
Doubt he left
a good-looking corpse.
(grunting)
Look at this.
30 years of toxins,
pesticides, heavy metal...
maybe some decomp.
Little piece of Vegas
history right here.
You know,
in Kicks and Kisses,
Lois O'Neill wrote a whole
chapter about Mickey Dunn.
What, that he was a
thrill in the sack?
No... no, that was
Tony Constantine.
Apparently, Mickey wanted
to go down
in a barrage of bullets,
like Sonny in
The Godfather.
Quite the ego on that guy.
Even in death, he was
larger than life.
Well, sure,
but all the original
mobsters were like that.
Tony, Mickey Dunn, Sam Braun...
My father was not a Mob guy.
I wasn't comparing...
or speaking ill
of the dead.
Greg.
Now we know how Dunn-Dunn died.
♪ That's life... ♪
SIDLE:
How can we be sitting
on this much evidence
and still have nothing?
Well, I can tighten up
the image for you.
I don't think more pixels
are going to solve the problem.
You got the face.
And the name.
Plus photos,
witnesses,
DNA samples, handwriting,
prints.
There's no record
in DMV or AFIS.
He knew exactly where
the cameras were.
He played right to them.
Obviously wasn't afraid
of being identified.
Why not?
♪ ♪
Same time next week?
Sure, baby.
Okay.
Excuse me, sir?
Please, could you help
me with my bags?
I hate to bother you,
but my back...
Getting old
ain't for sissies.
(choking)
Garroted.
Wire broke the skin but,
from the discoloration,
I'd say suffocation killed him.
CURTIS: Do you know
anyone who'd want
to do this to him?
I know he wasn't
into breath-play.
Choking on purpose.
More bang for your buck.
After he left the room,
did you hear
anything-- argument,
shouting-- anything
like that?
No. Whatever happened,
happened fast.
Okay, thank you; if we
have any more questions,
I'll contact you.
I don't get it.
A john walks by,
the door may be open,
but why walk in?
Who was the room
registered to?
Well, the manager said
an older woman.
A "Pamela Voorhees."
He's got a camera in the lobby.
So we'll get a face.
I'd love an address
to go with that.
(unzipping suitcase)
Empty bags.
Empty closet.
Bags could have been a lure.
Hey, guys. Busy day.
David...
can you get us a T.O.D., please?
DAVID:
Oh...
There's something in the mouth.
Bizarre.
It's my second one today.
That guy
got hit by a limo.
I guess that makes
this a hit list.
♪ ♪
A lead .38 round-nose.
I like it.
It's kind of '70s.
You were a kid
in the '70s.
Yeah, but I was a Vegas kid,
so I grew up
on all those '70s stories.
Like the "Ghost Rider" story.
Remember that one?
No.
You never heard of
the "Ghost Rider" story?
That has everything to do
with Mickey Dunn.
August 12, 1976.
Officer Eddie Sanchez
was the real-life
motorcycle cop who radios in
the last known sighting
of Mickey Dunn's
funky, gold Cadillac.
Is this on record?
It's stuffed away
in some police file somewhere.
Know what happened
to the cop?
No one does.
Officer Sanchez
and his motorcycle
disappeared that night.
What? In a puff of smoke?
A puff of smoke--
never to be heard from again.
Legend has it that you can
still hear the Ghost Rider
gunning up and down
that highway.
My grandmother used to try
to scare me into
good behavior
with that one.
Did it work?
Not when I was six. No.
But a .38 round-nosed
lead bullet was what Nevada
Highway Patrol
used back in the day.
And I don't need to tell you
there was a lot of
dirty cops back then.
There was a lot
of dirty everything back then.
Think about this.
You're a motorcycle cop.
You pull over
a speeding
gold Cadillac.
Sitting in the driver's seat
is Mickey Dunn.
Skipping town
with a load of cash.
Bang.
Put a cap in Mickey Dunn.
So you think this motorcycle cop
killed him?
I think I'd like
to find that police file.
What, you got a better story?
I was 16.
Jaws was sold out,
so I went looking for trouble.
Found Mickey Dunn.
All he said was,
if I met him outside
at 2:00 a.m. sharp,
he'd show me
the time of my life.
No way.
You and Mickey Dunn...?
Well, I showed...
he didn't.
You were 16, hot and ready,
and he stood you up?
All I know
is that I dodged a bullet.
And he didn't.
GRISSOM:
Our killer pays in cash
to avoid identification.
Then she signs in.
GRISSOM:
Yeah-- giving us
her name.
Why?
Gentlemen... blew up
a clean copy of
our hit list photo.
Look at that.
GRISSOM:
Planted on two separate bodies
by two separate killers.
You know,
Mickey Dunn practically
owned Las Vegas--
these guys look like employees.
Busboys, waiters,
obviously at the Desert Inn.
Rumor has it that Mickey
had a percentage of the DI.
It still begs
the question:
Why are those guys
killing these guys?
Yeah. I'll get PD
to identify
the last two.
See what they have to say.
(phone rings)
Grissom.
Yeah.
Okay.
Brass just got
a call from someone claiming
that the ghost of Mickey Dunn
wants to kill him.
(doorbell rings)
Johnny D'Angelo--
Las Vegas Police.
Look, we tried you at work,
down at the chicken joint,
but no Johnny.
I'm not coming out.
Think I'm crazy?
Slow down. Take it easy.
He killed all the others,
now he's coming for me.
Take it easy.
Can't arrest him.
How do you kill a man
who's already dead?
Why don't you make it
easy on all of us
and blow off
this ghost business,
and I.D. the person
who's after you--
preferably someone living.
Okay? Now, you don't
even have to say
a name, all right?
Just point at
one of these guys.
That's the ghost
of Mickey Dunn.
Okay, Johnny, I'll bite.
Why would a dead guy
have a beef with you?
Back in the day...
Yeah?
Vegas was like...
out of some kids' book.
And Mickey Dunn was the king--
only this was real.
And, in reality,
the king has guys
who work for guys
all the way from the top
to the bottom of the barrel.
That was us:
Kenny, Mason, me and Derek.
You know how they say
nobody saw Mickey Dunn
leave Vegas that night?
Yeah.
It's true.
'Cause we saw him,
and we was nobody.
Mickey was acting
like he owned the joint.
Like he owned us.
That's when Derek got smart.
Derek explained that
we hadn't been paid in months.
We were young.
We were stupid.
But Derek...
...he was insane.
What do you got there,
nitroglycerine?
Bum ticker.
You know you just confessed
to armed robbery, right?
Least of my worries.
Now, either you
get out there
and you arrest
the ghost of Mickey Dunn
or you get the hell
off my property.
We're the cops,
not the Ghostbusters.
(camera shutter clicking)
(shutter clicking)
Excuse me?
Hello.
Who are you?
I work here,
in the, uh, lab.
No, I don't think so.
I know everybody
that works here,
and I don't know you.
I'm new.
You're lying.
Give me that camera.
Now.
All right, all right.
(grunts)
(groans)
Security!
Damn paparazzi.
Hm.
(electronic squeak)
Book that moron.
Keep the camera.
(knocking)
Iris Paul?
Yes.
Officer Mitchell,
Las Vegas Police Department.
Are you Derek's mother?
Yes, I am.
(door closes inside)
But I haven't seen Derek
in-in months, uh,
not since he got out
of prison, mm-mm.
He might be in Florida.
Florida.
Yeah.
He loves it down there.
Can you give me
a description of Derek?
Sure, sure.
Uh, he's very tall,
very, very lean,
he has very long,
dark hair that he won't cut,
no matter how
many times...
Kind of like that?
(officers shouting in distance)
(grunting)
CURTIS:
So why'd you run?
I don't like cops.
We hear you don't like
criminals, either.
Is that right?
We know you worked
for Mickey Dunn.
We know you chased him,
you ran him off the road,
you stuck a gun in his face.
That's armed robbery.
If it happened.
Johnny D'Angelo said it did.
How is old scaredy-cat?
Credible.
There were a lot of
rumors going around.
Mickey owned this,
he owned that.
He owned a piece
of the D.I.
We just happened
to work there.
A lot of us guys did.
See, I'm thinking
that's not the full story.
You're young; you don't know.
The memories,
you get up there, they...
they start getting tricky.
Well, why don't you tell me
what you do remember.
We took a little joyride,
looking for Mickey Dunn.
But we never found him--
because someone else
found him first,
and who that was, I don't
know.
Because, by the time
we got there,
whoever had killed Mickey Dunn
was already gone.
Whoosh. Like a ghost.
I don't believe in ghosts.
But we got
one scared guy,
we got two dead guys,
and we got you, Derek.
How do you feel about your
buddies getting bumped off?
I'm all torn up inside.
You ever seen them?
DEREK:
Never.
But... they look like suspects.
And I think you're fishing.
And you got no legal
right to hold me.
If you can't hold me...
you got to let me go.
(gun cocks)
(gunshot echoing)
Johnny?
Johnny D'Angelo?
(Iris sobbing)
(doorjamb cracks,
alarm blares)
Johnny D'Angelo!
Las Vegas PD!
(sighs)
Yeah, go for Brass.
CURTIS:
Scene is Code 4.
Johnny D'Angelo is not
at his house.
BRASS:
Okay, got it. Thank you.
(sniffs, groans)
(coughs)
Do you smell that?
(sniffs)
(inhales)
Phew...
(exhales)
Maybe it was the ghost
of Mickey Dunn.
(printer whirring)
(chuckles)
(whistles)
Sweet ride.
Know what makes human bones
glow in the dark?
Love?
Tetracycline.
You want to help me
with a little experiment?
Sure.
Grab that evidence bag?
Okay, let me see that.
Take this.
No go. Okay.
Looks like a match to me.
This is your experiment?
Actually, it is.
Thanks.
GRISSOM:
The victims-- Ken Billings,
Mason Carter, Derek Paul
and Johnny D'Angelo--
all murdered
in the last 24 hours.
Four victims, three killers,
no connection between them.
Johnny D'Angelo's on both lists.
BROWN:
Could be
he hired the others.
Could be.
We don't know where they are.
We don't know who they are.
Let's stick
to what we do know-- all the
victims worked for Mickey Dunn,
who's been dead for 30 years.
Well, check this out.
I've been digging through
the police files all morning,
and guess who I found.
Officer Eddie Sanchez.
The "Ghost Rider."
Now, assuming he's
alive, the officer
would be 55 today.
And he has family
down in Mexico.
So you're thinking bike cop
shoots Mickey Dunn,
dumps the car and
takes the money?
SANDERS:
And with the exchange rate,
lives like a king, south of the
border, for the last 30 years.
Fast-forward-- Mickey Dunn's car
gets discovered.
SIDLE:
By a Mexican fisherman
who would be
just about the same age
as the bike cop.
Only the discovery
was bogus.
Turns out the hood ornament
pulled from Lake Mead
is a fake.
So... the fisherman was
what, pulling off a hoax?
GRISSOM:
That or fraud-- he either
planted that derringer
at the crime scene,
or maybe someone paid him to.
BROWN:
Either way, whoever did it knew
that this car was down there.
SANDERS:
And was missing
the original hood ornament.
SIDLE:
Who could know that?
Someone who was there
the night it went down.
SANDERS:
The motorcycle cop's
looking better
every minute.
Hey, don't rule out
the ghost of Mickey Dunn.
Doc told me to tell
you: your last vic,
the one all pretzeled
up in the oven,
lividity's fixed:
dead two days.
Before the Cadillac
was found.
Yeah.
Ah, and I got
trace analysis
on the sample Phillips
collected on Chicken Johnny.
And?
Alginate and
plaster of Paris.
Combination used to
make dental impressions.
And you don't even seem to be
the teeniest bit surprised.
I'm not.
(sighs)
♪ ♪
GRISSOM:
Our Mexican fisherman
signed his television
release form "F. Kreuger."
Freddy Kreuger,
Nightmare on Elm Street.
Yeah, and the karaoke singer
was Michael Myers
from Halloween.
Parts one through nine.
JOHNSON:
Yeah, but...
who's the hotel killer now?
Who's Pamela Voorhees?
Friday the 13th.
No, that's Jason.
Jason's the sequel.
Pamela, the mother,
was the killer
in the original--
that's the question
that tripped up Drew Barrymore
in Scream.
Yeah, and look
what happened to her.
You watch slasher flicks?
(quiet, wry laugh)
With Lindsay, I... do.
They never get
the spatter right.
All I know is the master
of all scary movies
was Lon Chaney, Sr.,
the man of
a thousand faces,
and that's what
we're looking for.
The thing that really gets me
is I talked to this killer
dressed as
Johnny D'Angelo,
close enough
to smell his breath
and still he walks.
All the evidence says
he was wearing
state-of-the-art
prosthetics.
I want to see him
in an orange
jumpsuit and cuffs.
He's got the real
Johnny's wallet.
Well, if he's got
his driver's license,
he could be using it
to try and escape.
He said the vic's car
is parked in
the parking lot.
He doesn't need his car.
He's got his face.
We'll pull his credit records.
Hope he bought something nice.
(over sound system):
♪ That's life ♪
♪ That's life ♪
♪ That's what
all the people say ♪
♪ You're riding high in April,
shot down in May ♪
(sirens wailing)
♪ But I know I'm gonna
change that tune... ♪
Put your hands
on the wheel!
Put your hands on
the steering wheel now!
♪ I just can't... ♪
Shut up and get out of the car.
♪ Checking out, but my heart
won't buy it ♪
Gun on the seat.
He's clean.
D'ANGELO:
♪ And then I'd buy it ♪
I thought I was clear
on the "shut up."
♪ That's life. ♪
Pop the trunk.
(distant):
♪ And as funny
as it may seem... ♪
Chainsaw-- sound familiar?
You get to be my age,
all kinds of things ring a bell.
How about this?
Any chimes?
That's a real good-lookin' boy.
But as the poet said...
"It ain't me, babe."
Mickey Dunn.
Back from the dead.
You missed a spot.
I think I got all I need.
Just going along.
Well, keep going, Mickey.
Do you recognize him?
Could be a dead cop.
Yeah, Officer Eddie Sanchez.
He had a wife,
two kids.
He also had a skin condition
commonly known as acne
which he treated
with tetracycline.
That drug incorporated
into his bones,
making them glow
under ultraviolet light.
Helped us identify him.
BRASS:
Thing's aren't looking
too good for you, Mickey.
So now we know we got
a dead cop's body
in your old car.
So tell me
what happened.
You were skipping town
and Eddie Sanchez
pulled you over
and you shot him point-blank?
Like I told you,
you missed a spot.
You missed a big spot.
I shot a lot of guys
point-blank.
But this nosy piece
of garbage
bike cop that
you two are so teared-up
about...
I shot him from 40 feet away
with a soaking-wet
revolver.
It was one hell of a shot.
The poor dumb bastard
didn't know what hit him.
He thought he'd been trained.
They don't prepare you
for what I got.
SANCHEZ:
Stop!
Stop or I'll shoot!
I said stop!
You found the skull
had no teeth
because I bashed 'em in
with the barrel of my gun.
And all the forensics
in the world
ain't gonna show you that
when I smashed his face in...
I liked it.
You're under arrest, Mickey,
for murder.
Thank God you blew me off
when I didn't know better.
Sam Braun's daughter.
You think that I would ever
forget a face?
That face?
Meet me outside,
2:00 a.m. sharp.
Ask yourself
what force on earth
that kept me from your soft
teenage graces.
Only one:
Daddy.
Sam Braun stopped you?
Sam always said
if I ever touched you,
he'd tear me apart.
That took a big pair
to say that to me.
He said that
you were family.
Still, now he's gone.
We're here.
We could always give it a go.
You're not going anywhere.
(gasping)
(grunting)
He's having a heart attack.
Call a paramedic.
Bum ticker... right on time.
I'm dying.
Okay, take it
easy, buddy.
Take it easy.
WILLOWS:
I'll give you a hint:
you're not in Heaven.
How long you been
living with a bullet
in your chest?
Who told you?
Why God invented X rays.
You'd like
to take it out,
have a closer look.
Ah, but you can't do that,
not without killing me.
I'm guessing it's a .38...
...which matches the .38
that we took from the body
of Derek Paul,
which also matches the one
that killed Eddie Sanchez.
You like horror movies, Mickey?
You know... I love 'em.
I got one for you.
Does it got a monster in it?
(chuckles)
Yeah.
I bet you heard it.
It's strictly B-list stuff.
No-name cast, summer release.
Four Vegas punks run a monster
off the road.
They shoot him, they rob him,
they leave him for dead.
But everybody knows
that shooting the monster
and killing him
are never the same.
A young honest cop arrives
and with him
comes opportunity.
The monster changes his name,
his face...
...passes for human.
Rides off into the night.
And the legend is born.
The end.
Mickey,
you know that real horror
stories never end.
Oh, this one does.
(laughs)
It's been huge fun
coming back, trying new faces,
leading you
all around town
by the nostrils.
Setting up the big discovery.
Everybody, he know
Mickey Dunn.
I'm Sally Jeffers, KRAC-TV,
Lake Mead, Nevada.
MICKEY:
Going after Kenneth...
I'm Mickey Dunn.
(wheelchair crashes
as tires squeal)
...taking out Mason...
...and the best part of all,
the look on poor Johnny's
face.
Not the most handsome guy
in the world,
but a face worth wearing.
And the hardest part--
learning Spanish.
(chuckles)
Good times.
Why now?
Because that tiny
piece of metal
that Derek shot in my chest
has finally moved.
Doctors gave me a week,
maybe two, to live.
Figured I'd go out
with a bang,
never see the inside
of a cell.
It's really funny how
one little bullet can make
things suddenly seem so clear.
You mean this bullet?
Mob doctors
become Mob doctors because they
sucked in the first place.
But we got a licensed surgeon
that fixed you up good.
Cheer up, Mickey,
you're gonna live
another 20... 30 years.
And you'll be spending every day
in the federal penitentiary.
But only until you die.
Well, I'll still
go out a legend.
You haven't changed that.
Oh, you've been out of the game
awhile.
The homies they have in the pen
these days never heard of you.
That's impossible.
No, Mickey, that's life.
♪ That's life... ♪
♪ That's life... ♪