(sobbing):
You got the wrong guy, man!
I didn't do it.
I didn't do it, man.
(gunshot)
(distorted, dream-like):
I love you, Mikey.
(amplified heartbeat)
(heartbeat fades)
That is what I love
about this town.
They've got good eggs Benedict
24 hours a day.
Just getting off shift?
No, I'm going in early.
Thank you.
Do you ever eat dinner?
You're looking at it.
Okay, I'll see
you at the lab.
Bye.
Can I get a check please?
That guy over there
already paid and tipped.
Says he's your friend.
How's it going, Mike?
What are you doing here, Frank?
What do you want me to do?
You don't return my calls.
I tried calling you,
but I've been, uh... busy.
You didn't make it
to Amy's memorial Mass.
Yeah, I know.
I got the card
from Father Anthony.
Couldn't get away this year.
It's okay.
Dennis Graves and I decided
to come to Vegas for a few days,
blow off some steam.
You like standing? Sit down.
I can't.
Look, Frank, I got to run.
We'll get dinner later in the
week, all right? I'll call you.
Mike.
Listen, I, uh...
I'm in a bit
of a fix; I need
you to do me a favor.
I can't do it this time. Okay?
Don't ask me
to do it, Frank.
Things are just starting to...
Hey.
What are you getting
so excited about?
(chuckling):
I didn't say anything.
I'm just getting the lay
of the land here, you know?
Trying to move on.
I got it, bad timing.
You all right?
Don't you worry about it.
I'll sort it out.
Looks like it's
you and me again, Hoss.
You got a problem
with that?
No, no, I like your style.
It's just the whole
suit thing
you got to work on
a little bit.
Yeah, yeah,
what do we got?
Two gunshot victims.
Male, shot two times
in the chest.
Female shot in the back,
and her hand is missing.
Why take just
one hand?
KEPPLER:
Maybe there was
something on it he wanted.
Boxer shorts, socks.
I'm guessing this is his.
You see another
suitcase?
No, no, I did not.
Looks like she
was just visiting.
.45 automatic.
No purse...
no valuables.
Did you see a safe?
No.
No, no safe in here.
Looks like a robbery.
Hey, this guy has
a bunch of law enforcement
logo shirts
hanging up in here.
Check the Bible drawer.
Anything?
Nine millimeter service pistol?
Stamped "T.P.D."
Could be any city
starting with T.
I didn't find any nine
millimeter casing,
so this weapon was never fired.
The room is registered
to a Dennis Graves
Trenton, New Jersey.
He's a cop, Trenton, PD.
Hey, you're from Trenton.
Do you know him?
No.
Who found them?
His buddy, Frank McCarty.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
BRASS:
So what were you
two guys doing in Vegas?
Playing a little golf,
indulging in the buffets.
BRASS:
Is that all you indulged in?
We were down in the bar,
Dennis picked up a date.
Is she the date?
I didn't get a name.
Anyway, they went upstairs,
I played a little blackjack.
Then what?
Then, I pulled
some strings
and got us a tee time
at the Wynn.
Dennis didn't answer his phone.
I figured he was busy
going around the world.
After a while, I...
I knew something was wrong.
I got hotel security
to open the door.
Excuse me. Yeah?
Captain, we got press
all over the place.
Can you stick around?
I'll be right back.
Yeah, sure.
Okay.
Mr. McCarty?
If you don't mind.
You want to tell me what
I'm seeing here, Frank?
Could be anything.
Pimp went off on his whore.
Robbery gone bad.
It's a dangerous town.
Have a seat.
Yeah.
Heard we have a dead
out-of-town cop.
Yeah, Detective
Dennis Graves.
Trenton PD.
Trenton?
Yeah.
David, you got the T.O.D.?
About four hours ago.
KEPPLER:
Male was shot twice,
both frontal.
No exits.
The girl was shot
once in the back.
Did you find the hand?
I'm guessing
the killer's got it,
along with the rest
of their valuables.
Hey, Catherine, check this out.
I've got an uncapped
bottle of mouthwash here.
Probably come back
to the hooker.
Yeah, but I've got
something else,
and this is good.
There are quite a few
long, light-colored hairs
snagged in the soap dish
right there.
Not a match to either victim.
Sloppy housekeeping?
I doubt the maid
would miss this.
What appear to be
high heel shoe impressions--
I checked, again,
no match to the
working girl.
Bath towels
haven't been used.
So who was in the tub
with her shoes on?
Keppler, do
me a favor.
Go over by the
body, will you?
Yeah?
I can see you; can you see me?
Yep.
What about if I get low?
Not anymore.
So either she was
lying in wait...
Or an eyewitness tried
to hide from a killer.
Let's pull the elevator
surveillance.
Maybe we can find a blonde
who got off
on this floor.
Welcome back, Dr. Grissom.
It's good to be back, Judy.
There are no words
to describe how glad
I am you're back.
But I'm sure you'll find some.
The lab almost
went to hell
in a handbag while
you were sabbaticalling.
I'm sure you
talked to Catherine,
but just in case
you didn't...
lot of hurt feelings,
so in case you talk to Nick...
I'd rather hear it
from Catherine, thanks.
Fair enough, but,
uh, permit me to say
that the "Seasonal Behaviors of
the Walden Pond Swamp Mosquito"
was an incredibly
stimulating seminar.
And you know this how?
I took your course online.
It's free to alumni.
Oh, you're Spanky.
Seven-four-three.
I aced the final, didn't I?
(computer beeping)
Post-mortem tool marks
to the left wrist.
No vital reactions
from the tissue.
Cuts are scalloped,
definitely a serrated blade.
Not a bad job.
Anything to help us
identify her?
David printed
the right hand.
No hits on AFIS.
Lucky for you,
like many young ladies
her age,
she had some surgical work done.
Feel these.
What do you think?
Implants.
Kind of big
for my taste, really.
The other end.
Oh, they're for the butt?
KEPPLER:
Implants are serialized.
We can get an ID from those.
STOKES:
You know, I spent 12 hours
on a court bench last week.
I could have used
a pair of these bad boys.
What about C.O.D.?
ROBBINS:
Single gunshot to the back,
just to the right
of the spinal column.
Bullet severed the aorta,
lodged inside the sternum.
And the cop?
I removed these
from Detective Graves.
Large caliber, too.
I'll get those
to Ballistics.
Okay, so I'll run the serials?
Yeah.
I am an ass man.
(chuckles)
GRISSOM:
Michael Keppler.
Hi, Gil Grissom.
How's everybody
been treating you?
No complaints,
you've got a great team.
Yeah, thanks.
Does Ecklie still
have you slotted for days?
As far as I know.
I hear you're working the double
homicide at The Olympia.
What have you got?
Oh, it's uh, bullets
from Doc Robbins.
I was going
to run them through IBIS.
The dead cop was
from your hometown, huh?
Yeah. Retired.
Did you know him?
You know how many retired cops
there are in Trenton?
Well, it's great
to finally meet you.
Same.
I love you, Mikey.
Hey.
I said, "How do you feel
about butt implants?"
You don't need them?
Thank you.
I wasn't really talking
about me, but...
Oh, right.
Sorry.
You got something
on the dead cop case?
The blond hair from the tub
does match the saliva left
in the mouthwash bottle.
And it's female,
but not from the dead hooker
with the big back seat.
Second female in the room
uses mouthwash.
More than likely
another hooker.
Looks like we got a witness.
Dennis should've lived long
enough to spoil his grandkids.
He was a good man, good cop.
Good enough to spot a
hooker when he saw one?
You don't have to be a cop
to have that radar.
So tell me
about Dennis.
Did he major in French?
Maybe liked ménage à trois?
You know,
two's company,
three's a party?
'Cause there was another girl
in the room with him.
Really?
Mm-hmm.
I only saw him leave
with one girl.
So as far as you know,
there wasn't a blond
in there with him?
(chuckling):
Dennis?
He could barely handle one.
Besides, he was a little tight
with the buck.
MAN:
Hey, Brown.
I'm looking at the over-
under in the Suns game.
What do you think?
I don't bet sports
anymore.
Not what I hear.
According to Stokes, you're
at the top of your game.
Well, why don't you get
your picks from him
with his fat Texas mouth.
I'd take the over.
Hey.
Want some help?
Welcome back.
What do you got?
Well, I'm just
following a lead
off some serialized
butt implants.
I missed Las Vegas.
(laughs)
What are you doing here?
I'm avoiding the paperwork and
mail that's piled up on my desk.
Well... we got a, uh,
dead prostitute's apartment.
It's obvious that it's
been ransacked and robbed.
I'm thinking that she was
the target of the double
and the cop was collateral.
Where would you like me
to start?
You can hit the dinette.
I haven't taken that yet.
Unless you're avoiding
her paperwork, too.
There's a lot of it.
Well, she was past due
on her electric bill.
But seems to have paid
her telephone bill on time.
Telephone. Hooker's lifeline.
I'm telling you,
whoever hit this place
left a lot of prints.
I, uh, heard
there was some friction
in the lab
while I was gone.
You ever hear
of "reverse forensics"?
(phone rings)
Keppler.
MCCARTY:
There was someone else
in that hotel room.
I know.
I need a name.
I don't have one.
Don't let me down, kid.
You got to help me here;
I'm counting on you.
You okay?
Yeah.
Well, I tracked down
the plastic surgeon
that augmented
Courtney Evans' glutes.
Probably the only implants
ever paid for in cash
by, get this...
her pimp,
a guy named Eric Hong, aka...
"Precious Ricky," huh?
Yeah, that's what
my mama calls me.
Precious "Licky".
(chuckles)
Is she one of yours?
No, ain't seen her before.
You bought her
butt cheek implants.
Is that something you normally
do for girls you don't know?
Oh, see, that's
the problem.
You're showing me
the wrong end.
Okay.
So, then she is one
of yours, right?
Hey, I run an escort service.
Strictly legal.
I'm sure it is.
So what did she do, Precious?
She make you mad?
No.
No, I don't get mad, man.
I'm blissed out.
I'm a Buddhist.
I let the anger flow
right through me.
Sentient beings are numberless,
and I vow to save them.
I didn't do
nothing to her.
Nothing?
Like cut off her hand,
and you kill the cop
she was with?
We know Courtney was
with a blond last night.
Long hair.
You got anyone who matches
that description?
Jenny, Coco, Lani...
April, May and June, too.
But you know what?
The cuffs don't always
match the collars, you
know what I... (grunts)
Now, look, Ricky,
maybe you're
a nice guy, maybe you're not,
but right now I
really don't care,
because I think
you're lying to me.
And that could go very badly
for you.
(gasps)
Do you understand
what I'm saying?
Okay, okay.
They were all
on the clock last night.
It was a bachelor party.
(knock at door)
CURTIS:
Nick, Mike,
can you step out a minute?
Miss McFarland is a
baby-sitter, of sorts.
I wouldn't leave
her with my cat.
I think
she likes the pipe.
She claims that
that baby belongs
to Courtney Evans.
She had a baby? Damn.
I'm going to call
Child Services.
Yeah.
Ma'am, I'm Nick Stokes;
this is Mike Keppler.
We're with the Crime Lab.
You mind if we ask
you a few questions?
Um, look,
Courtney was supposed to come
in the morning
to pick up Lila, okay.
I got to work.
You know, real work.
Okay, look,
my own problems, okay?
Otherwise, I would have taken
her myself, but, um,
I ain't in no shape,
okay?
So, uh, you can
find her a family, right?
What about the father?
Heard he was in prison
or something like that.
I ain't never seen him.
When she left the baby with you,
was Courtney with anyone?
A friend maybe?
No, no, she ain't got
no friends.
What about enemies?
You know what?
I got to go. I can't take this.
Mm-mm,
please take her.
Thank you.
Please.
Go with her.
I got to go.
Oh.
Looks like we have
another victim, huh?
It's gonna be okay, baby.
We got to talk, Frank.
Hold on, hold on,
I'm on a streak here.
Now, do I keep the ace
or draw the inside straight?
I'm gonna draw
to the straight.
She had a kid.
Oh, God.
Why don't you tell
me about the hand?
Why?
She scratched me, Mike.
Come on, what was I
supposed to do?
I couldn't take the chance
that one of your guys
would find my DNA
under her nails.
Why, Frank?
You know why.
That was a long time ago;
Dennis never said a word.
Yeah, but he was going to.
He was about to be indicted.
Wife, three kids.
There was no way
he was doing time.
He was going down, Mikey,
and he was taking us with him.
He was a cop, Frank.
Yeah.
You told me that.
You don't do that,
not even to save
your own ass.
Yeah?
What about yours? Hey!
Give me another vodka
and tonic.
And give my boy here
a scotch.
Neat, right?
Make it a double.
We got to loosen him up.
(chuckles)
Look at her.
Just like catnip.
Don't look at me
like that, Mike.
We did the right thing,
all of us.
But do you think
the grand jury's gonna
see it like that?
They're gonna see a white cop
turned "Dirty Harry"
goes across the river
to take out some Puerto
Rican drug dealer.
Shoots him in the back.
They don't understand.
Every time we take one step
outside the box
for public safety,
they nail our asses to the wall.
Sit down, Frank.
Hey, Mikey,
there's no turning back.
You did the right thing.
If you hadn't taken care
of that evidence...
Keep your voice
down, all right?
Come on, I need some help here.
Or you're gonna lose
everything.
And that isn't
what Amy would have wanted.
She loved you.
Don't do that.
What?
Don't bring her into this.
You think
you're the only one
who cared for her?
I was her father, Mikey.
Don't ever forget that.
I would've killed
that the scumbag
who raped her with
these bare hands,
but you got
to him first.
I love you
for that.
Yeah, I made
compromises for you.
You wouldn't be here now
if it wasn't for me.
Yeah.
You're out of line, Frank.
Hey, Mikey, there is no
statute of limitations
for murder.
The kid you shot,
his mother's still crying.
And I got the gun...
with your prints
and his blood on it.
You go down now,
you take every case
you ever worked on with you.
Trenton, Philly,
Baltimore, Vegas.
All those killers go free.
All on your hands.
So, pin it on the blond
in the bathroom
or the pimp.
Just do it, I don't care how,
just do it.
(sniffs)
I don't even know Courtney
what's-her-name.
BROWN:
So how is it
that your prints ended up
all over her apartment?
I've never been
to her apartment.
Did I mention
she was dead?
What?
Yo, I don't even know
no dead person.
PJ, you know what I think?
I think you killed her.
You took her purse,
went to her apartment
and stole all her stuff.
No, no, no. I
didn't kill nobody.
Well, she's dead.
And so is the cop she was with.
That's the death penalty.
Here's what happened-- I swear,
this-- this is the truth.
I was minding my own business.
I was checking out
the Dumpsters behind,
behind the Strip,
and lo and behold,
I find this lady's purse.
Right there in the Dumpster?
Yeah, like pennies from heaven.
It had a wallet,
it had keys, it
had a cell phone.
So I checked for her
license, I got her address
and went to her house.
I was going to return
the purse, I swear.
Oh, like a Good Samaritan?
Yeah, but, when I got here,
no one was there.
So what'd you do?
I used the key.
I was going to leave
the purse inside.
But you didn't
do that, did you?
I might have taken
a couple of things.
Where was the Dumpster?
Behind the Palermo.
(phone rings)
This is Catherine.
Catherine, it's Mike.
Mike.
Where have you been?
I had to take care of something.
How's it going?
Any I.D. on the blonde yet?
No, but we got some info
from the deadbeat
who burgled the hooker's
apartment.
Claims he found her purse in
a Dumpster behind the Palermo.
I'm just off the Strip now;
I'll take care of it for you.
Mike, are you okay?
Yeah, yeah. I'm fine.
I'll see you in a little bit.
(tires screeching lightly)
♪ ♪
Hey, Mike.
Hey.
Did you get anything
from the Dumpster?
Yeah...
a bad smell.
So...
Ecklie wants you on days now
that Grissom's back, but...
I could talk to them,
get you to stay with us.
Oh, I'm sure you guys will do
just fine without me.
(chuckles)
Yeah, usually transfers
don't fit in,
but... think about it.
Catherine.
Thanks.
Keppler.
Archie found
the mystery blonde.
Before she was in
Dennis Graves' room,
she was with that cop,
Frank McCarty.
They got on in the
lobby, got off on 11.
Around the time McCarty
said Dennis picked
up his hooker.
STOKES:
Hey, he never mentioned
he had company,
and he knew we were looking
for another hooker.
Now I'm starting to think
we're looking at a dirty cop.
Who knows about this?
PD's about to.
I'm calling them right now.
JOHNSON:
You'd think a cop would
know he's on camera, huh?
CURTIS:
McCarty's phone
keeps going to voice mail.
And, according
to the receptionist,
he didn't check out.
LVPD. Open up.
Give me the card.
(sobbing fading in)
I didn't do it...
I didn't do it, man.
Come on, man;
I didn't do it.
You got the
wrong guy, man.
(gunfire)
No!
CURTIS:
It's a .45 auto.
Same caliber as the gun that
killed the cop and the hooker.
With blood stains.
STOKES:
This this is
practically gift-wrapped.
If the guy wants
to get caught so bad,
just confess, make it easy
on all of us.
I can't wait to get
this back to Ballistics.
I'll see you.
I'll finish up here.
(phone rings)
(recording):
You've reached Frank.
Leave me a message
after the tone.
(beeping)
Sara.
Hey. You're back.
Yeah.
Uh, I've-- I've been out
at a, um...
I've been at...
A garbage dump?
Yeah.
It's so obvious, isn't it?
Nice, um...
You look good.
Did you, uh, put the
cocoon in my office?
Cool, dry,
not a lot of light.
It seemed like
the right place for it.
I think you're going to be
surprised when it hatches.
I have no doubt.
I'm gonna...
go clean up now.
I'll see you later.
Yeah, you will.
McCarty's mystery blonde
knew the dead hooker.
How do you know that?
(typing)
Check out the
time code.
1:10.
We recovered the
hooker's cell phone,
thanks to a Dumpster diver.
These are all her voice mails,
the last couple hours
before she died.
At the same time the
blond was making this call,
Courtney Evans
received a voice mail.
So, I synched up
the audio to the video.
Yeah, Courty, it's me,
Suzy Q. Got your message.
What are you,
too busy to answer me back?
Uh, so anyway,
I just left my guy.
Eh, it went all right.
Usual "Call me Daddy" crap.
(laughs)
You know, he actually wanted me
to whimper. Whatever.
He kept calling me "Amy."
(woman whimpering)
KEPPLER:
Amy?
...that three-way...
I don't know, I don't know.
I think I'm gonna have to--
Do we have an I.D.
on the blonde?
Just now.
I just finished running names
off Courtney Evans'
incoming calls.
Yeah?
JOHNSON:
We're looking for Suzy Gibbons.
WILLOWS:
Here it is.
Priors for prostitution
and a last known.
Can I see that?
JOHNSON:
She knew the vic.
She's the blonde in the bathtub.
Well, if we can find Suzy,
so can a retired cop.
He needs her dead.
KEPPLER:
If she's dumb enough to
hide out in her own house,
she already is.
Mike?
Mike, where are you going?!
♪ ♪
(device beeping)
Amy?
(distorted):
Daddy said
never tell you.
(car horn honking)
Why would McCarty
have a bloody gun
with Keppler's prints on
it, in his hotel room?
Doesn't make any sense.
No.
Could Mike have touched
it when he found it?
No, no way.
I was right there.
Besides, the blood
was already dry.
You don't leave fingerprints
in dried blood.
I compared
the .45 ammo evidence
to the dead cop
and the hooker.
It's the correct make,
model and caliber,
but I'm telling you,
it's a different gun.
Maybe he's
being set up.
GRISSOM:
Why?
By whom?
Keppler told me that
he didn't know Frank McCarty.
He also said he didn't
know the victim.
Maybe he's lying
about that, too.
I'm sorry, Catherine.
I like the guy, too,
but I'm just following
the evidence here.
We should be talking
to Keppler about this.
Where is he?
He was with me in A/V.
Nobody has seen him since,
and he's not answering his cell.
STOKES:
He knows where
the eyewitness lives.
What are you saying, Nick?
I'm saying that
if he had something to do
with these two murders,
then Frank McCarty's
not the only one
we need to
worry about.
PD's on their way
to Suzy Gibbons' apartment now.
GRISSOM:
Okay, grab Sara
and go over there,
and I'll have Brass
call Trenton PD,
see who knows who.
Welcome home.
What other evidence did, uh,
Keppler handle?
STOKES:
He brought back
the three bullets
from Autopsy, which didn't match
the gun with his prints on it.
Could he have swapped
the bullets?
Anything's possible.
BROWN:
He also searched
the Dumpster
where the homeless guy found the
hooker's purse and cell phone.
He told Catherine
he didn't
find anything.
I got your DNA results,
and the blood
on the gun from
Frank McCarty's hotel room,
it doesn't match
either victim.
There were no hits in CODIS,
and the DNA print
ancestry markers
say that it's from a black male.
Keppler and McCarty
were both Jersey boys.
Expand the search
to the East Coast.
Will do.
I really hope he's clean.
We have to treat
him like a suspect.
I'll tell Ecklie.
(cell phone ringing)
Still no answer on his cell.
Hey.
Got a fix on the GPS
in his Denali.
He's near Henderson.
What's he doing there?
(beeping)
He just disabled his GPS.
Smart guy.
Guilty guy.
Try tracking his cell.
PD-issued phones
have GPS, too.
Yeah.
Got him.
(speaking Asian language)
Okay?
I'll take that.
(grunts)
Suzy Gibbons--
how do I find her?
Okay, you know what?
First off, you're gonna get
your freakin' hands off me.
I don't have time, Ricky.
Why should
I tell you?
Because if you don't...
(cocks gun)
I'm the last face
you're gonna see alive.
I don't think Suzy
works out of here.
Me, either.
(cell phone ringing)
Jim?
BRASS:
So I finally got through to
the Homicide captain in Trenton.
Anyway, here's the story.
Keppler not only knew McCarty.
Not only did he know him,
he was like a son to him.
Keppler had a close relationship
with his daughter,
and McCarty was the one who got
Keppler his job as a CSI.
And what about the victim--
Detective Graves?
Yeah, he knew him, too.
Graves was being indicted.
Seems like too many
of his suspects
were showing up dead
before the trial.
Catherine, I think
all three of them are dirty.
Okay.
You know,
some women...
live out of
their purses.
I know a lot of working girls
operate out of the Siren.
I think we just
found her office.
(cell phone ringing)
I'll see you
back at the lab?
Okay.
Hello.
It's Mike.
Where have you been?
Everybody is looking for you.
I know.
I'm sorry.
Then come back in.
I can't.
It's kind of complicated.
I... made a mistake
a long time ago.
Let me help you.
It's too late.
You're gonna end up looking
into my cases, Catherine.
(sighs)
They're clean.
I promise, every one of them.
Except the Alvarez homicide
in Philly.
If you run the ballistics again,
it'll come back
to Dennis Graves.
Your guys are smart,
they'll figure it out.
Mike, don't do anything stupid.
I got to go.
(phone beeps)
(line ringing)
McCARTY:
Hey, you've reached Frank.
Leave me a message
after the tone.
(beep)
If you still want
to fix this, Frank,
you got 20 minutes.
Blue Siren Motel,
Third, below Fremont.
(cell phone rings)
Grissom.
He just called,
sounded desperate.
Like a man with nothing
to live for and nothing to lose.
Well, he's not your priority.
Find the witness.
Yeah. I'm on my way.
Just wanted you to know.
(knock at door)
It's open.
(gasps)
Drop it, Frank.
Put the gun down.
Look, Mike...
about the bar,
you were right.
I was out of line.
You know how I get--
come on.
Put the gun down.
You're not gonna shoot me.
Suzy, I want
you to get up
and walk out of the
room, all right?
I can't let that happen.
Sit down.
(sobbing)
It's over, Frank.
I know what you did.
What are you talking about?
I know what you did to Amy.
I killed an innocent man.
Mikey,
you're talking crazy.
She was your daughter, Frank.
You watch your frickin' mouth.
All right, okay!
Put the gun down.
(Gibbons sobbing)
Shut up!
I loved her, Mike,
more than you know.
All right, okay.
I'm a dirty cop,
rotten to the core.
What do you want from me?
(siren approaching)
I want you
to tell me why, Frank.
Why you would do that
to your own daughter.
Come on, Mike.
You're all I've got.
(sobbing):
No! No!
(screaming)
Mike!
Mike.
(gunshots)
(grunting)
Mike.
Mike, hang in there.
Call the paramedics.
Dispatch,
got a Code 44.
You're gonna be okay.
Just stay with me.
I'm sorry.
I just know
they both had guns.
Move it.
Pupils still fixed and dilated.
He's moving into V-fib!
Let's go!
I'm here.
Stay with me, Mike.
Place him into the back
of the rig.
Mike?
Let's go, let's go.
Hang on, Mike.
Charging, 300.
(high-pitched electrical whine)
Two placement's good.
Clear.
(electrical thud)
No response.
Hitting him again.
(high-pitched electrical whine)
Copy. Clear.
(electrical thud)
Yeah, I've got nothing.
Still in V-fib.
Come on, come on.
(high-pitched electrical whine)
(electrical thud)
No pulse.
What?
He's gone.
BROWN:
Talk to me, Archie.
JOHNSON:
The signal's 20 yards north
of your position.
I don't see anything.
I'm dialing the phone now.
All right.
(faint cell phone ringing)
Hey, wait, wait,
wait, wait!
I got something.
I'll call you back.
(faint cell phone ringing)
(cell phone ringing)
Keppler left his phone
so we'd find the hand.
"Check under the nails.
You'll find
Frank McCarty's DNA.