♪ ♪
(garbled radio transmission)
BRASS:
A trucker driving
by saw the body,
called it in.
Easy to miss.
The coroner's tied up on
a multiple in Pahrump,
but they're
en route.
Officer Jensen was
first responding.
When he saw the
condition of the body,
he backed out of the scene,
stepping in his own footprints.
Anyway, we've been
beating the bush
looking for her personal
effects, but so far nothing.
Jane Doe it is.
♪ ♪
(camera clicking)
You must be Keppler.
Willows?
Catherine.
Sorry I'm late.
Got stuck on the Strip.
Welcome to Las Vegas.
Is that how they're doing things
in Baltimore these days?
Out here, we don't
touch the body
until the coroner releases it.
Sorry. Just...
trying to get a better look
at her face.
WILLOWS:
There's bruising around
the neck, relatively fresh.
No other obvious wounds
on the body.
This girl's barely
out of high school.
Catnip.
Excuse me?
The way they attract men
at that age;
it's like catnip.
That's a terrifying thought.
You have kids?
A daughter, 15.
You must be a hit
on career day.
I try not to bring
my work home with me.
Yeah.
How about you?
What?
Any kids?
KEPPLER:
Patchy discolorations
on the skin.
Looks like
dehydration.
White fibers.
I'm guessing cotton.
Looks like she's been
swabbed down with something
that evaporated,
maybe alcohol.
Unlike most men,
this one knows how
to clean up after himself.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me
who are you, you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
(garbled radio transmission)
(camera clicking)
So how long is this fellow
Keppler supposed to be with us?
Well, he was hired to staff
the new day shift, but...
since we're one shy
with Grissom away,
Ecklie wanted us to
break him in for a few weeks.
Got a broken fingernail.
Please tell me she got
a piece of her attacker.
WILLOWS:
If the nail had been torn off,
the break would be smooth.
It's jagged; she's a biter.
BRASS:
So flash this photo
around the Alphabets.
If she's a pro or a local,
somebody will
recognize her.
Alphabets?
Yeah, it's a neighborhood.
You know, A Street,
B Street, D Street.
Mm.
A through F is pretty bad--
homeless, junkies,
scumbags,
the hookers we chase
off the Strip.
I mean, if you're
down and out in Vegas,
sooner or later,
you're gonna end up here.
Hear you got one of
the fastest growing
murder rates in the country.
Yeah, we're very competitive.
Is that a Philly accent I hear?
Trenton, born and bred.
My condolences. I'm from Newark.
How you doing?
How are you?
Thought I heard
something familiar.
But you got to love Vegas,
isn't that right, Catherine?
My hometown.
I mean,
the pizza's terrible,
but everything else
is paradise.
So I see you've got the soil
and vegetation exemplars.
Thank you.
Three distinct locations.
Not that it's gonna
make much difference.
I get the feeling
our guy's not the type
to track away dirt
on his shoes.
Probably not.
Our best bet's
the body.
Which we're probably not
gonna get much from, either.
So is the pizza
really that bad?
I like it.
♪ ♪
No obvious traces
of semen?
No.
No visible skin
under the fingernails,
so she probably
didn't fight back.
There were no defensive wounds
on her forearms,
no ligature marks
on her wrists or ankles.
Maybe he didn't
want to mark her up.
I mean, look at her.
So young.
Innocent.
He wanted to take his time.
He drugged her.
We should expand tox
to include volatiles
and sedative hypnotics.
You got something?
WILLOWS:
Highlights and lowlights.
That's a hair process
that isn't cheap.
Nominal hair growth
is roughly
half-a-millimeter a day.
And based on the length
of her roots, it's been about
two months since
she's had it done.
Not the kind of girl who goes
missing without a report.
(camera clicking)
SANDERS:
Your vic's name is
Veronica Sorensen, age 17.
Last reported
in Victorville.
About two
months ago?
Yeah, yeah.
She's a...
Runaway?
Yeah. Parents
reported her missing.
P.D.'s already made
the notifications.
So, what's the verdict
on this Keppler guy?
What?
You're usually pretty
quick to size people up.
Jury's still out,
but he knows
what he's doing.
MAN (on TV):
In other news, local Las Vegas
police officers are still trying
to identify the body of a nude
woman found off Highway 51
early yesterday morning.
The police say they received
a call at 3:32 a.m. from a truck
driver who happened to be
driving down Highway 51
when he spotted
the young woman's body
just off the road.
Sources indicate that she had
been stripped of her...
I'm Detective Curtis.
I'm... so sorry
for your loss.
That girl on the TV,
that is not my Veronica.
They wouldn't call us
if they weren't sure.
We were able to match
her fingerprints.
Then you've made
a mistake.
The prints that we
gave to the police,
they were from a
school safe kit.
She was ten
years old.
They could've
changed, right?
Fingerprints don't change.
There was a tattoo
on her right
ankle-- an iguana.
(sobbing softly)
(sobbing):
Oh, no.
We just want to take her home.
Of course.
As soon as we've
completed the autopsy.
No.
No, you're not
gonna cut her open.
Sir, this is a homicide.
We're not giving
our permission.
CURTIS:
I'm afraid
you don't have
a choice.
(sobbing)
But I promise you, we'll treat
her with the utmost respect.
(Robbins whistling a tune)
(whistling continues)
And what can I do
for you?
Let me know
when you release the body.
It's going to be a while.
I haven't even
opened her up yet.
Well, just let me know.
(whistling a tune)
And stop whistling.
ROBBINS:
C.O.D. was asphyxiation
due to strangulation,
but it wasn't quick.
The overlapping patterns
of fours and ones
suggest multiple events.
I imaged subcutaneous bruises
under UV
from several positions
around the throat.
Killer choked and released
at least three times.
That's consistent
with sexual asphyxiation.
S.A.E. is about
what you'd expect.
Vaginal trauma,
no semen,
but traces of spermicide.
Guy used a condom.
What about tox?
Well, blood was positive
for MDMA.
Ecstasy.
That's it?
Yep.
I can't believe
that she was compliant.
Thanks, Doc.
You got it.
(exhales)
You ever see a cat playing
with a mouse?
Point isn't to kill the mouse,
just keep the game going.
I'm guessing you've got cats.
No. I just like
the metaphor.
Same game every time.
Cat goes home, leaves
its kill on the doorstep.
Our guy's done this before.
I'm with you there.
What got our cat's attention
this time?
Around puberty,
most guys fixate on a particular
body type that turns them on.
Tall, skinny, short, red hair.
Whatever floats
your boat.
It's imprinted.
Hard to let go of.
Okay.
So we know what his type is
and we know what he likes
to do with them.
Okay, we've got three
that fit the type.
The cases were
years apart.
1999, 1989...
and 1975.
Let's bring up
their photographs.
Look at the similarity
in the body positions.
They look posed,
almost as if
they were...
waving good-bye.
Jane Doe '99
was discovered naked
in a stretch of dirt
off Paradise
behind the old
Hotel Continental.
Based on
the photos,
her hair was matted with dirt,
which suggests that it was wet
when she was dumped.
It's likely
that her body was washed.
That's consistent
with the latest victim.
Any traces of alcohol
or cotton swabs?
There's nothing indicated,
but there's almost nothing
in this file.
Based on T.O.D.,
the body was found less
than four hours after death.
Yet other
than a general canvass,
not a single person
was interviewed.
The homicide detective's summary
is less than a page.
Sounds like shoddy police work.
Sounds like no police work.
After the autopsy,
C.O.D. confirmed
asphyxiation by strangulation.
There was absolutely
no follow-up whatsoever.
Well, there was a follow-up
in spades on Jane Doe '89.
She was found in a vacant lot
off 28th Street
near Boulder Highway.
Uh, stripped of her clothing.
Like the others,
several peri-mortem bruises,
but check out this hair.
Yeah, it's crimped.
I remember those days.
There's no way that
style survives a shower.
Killer didn't wash
that one down.
Methods evolve.
Practice makes perfect.
Again, the cops didn't come up
with a single suspect.
There were detailed sketches
of the crime scene,
microscopy on errant hairs
and fibers,
even ran the vic's prints
through WIN.
'89... that database was
barely on the Internet.
The guy that worked
on this case
was very thorough.
He just didn't close it.
Okay, Jane Doe '75.
Well...
she was found in an alley off
of Bridger near Fremont Street.
Based on the level of decomp,
she'd been lying there
about two days
before they found her.
Only thing about this one is,
she had her clothes on.
Might have been his first.
Or maybe the first one found.
Isolated contusions on her neck,
arms and shoulders.
C.O.D. listed
as heroin overdose.
Junkies do bruise easily.
And the "waving good-bye"
hand position is
a natural way to fall.
It's possible
that this one is
a coincidence.
It's not.
How do you know?
Because I do.
This guy pays attention
to the details.
Knows what he likes,
he doesn't mix it up.
Thing that gets me is
the discipline, though.
He's got a habit, but he seems
to be able to control it.
Only needs to kill once
every ten years or so,
and when he does,
he's got a type.
Pretty but not pricey.
And not likely to be missed.
You're a CSI,
not a profiler.
What's the difference?
Evidence.
I want leads and IDs.
Follow up on
what you've got.
MAN:
When I left this place,
it was all grey walls
and cinder blocks.
Very fancy.
What made you
transfer to Henderson?
Cost of living,
better commute.
I socked away a few bucks,
bought a nice place
in Green Valley.
Ah, I take it you're a
shortcuts kind of guy.
I guess you could say that.
I like to get to the heart
of things right away.
Any reason that you didn't get
to the heart of this?
Whoa.
October 17, 1999.
You remember the date?
Yeah.
Why is that?
Hey, I'm not sure
I like your tone.
Answer the question, Detective.
It's my son's birthday.
Day I caught the case,
my wife went into labor.
It was rough.
There were complications.
Anyway, I was out for weeks
taking care of her.
Used up all my vacation time.
When I got back, there were
a half dozen cases on my desk.
My captain told me to let it go.
Look.
We canvassed the neighborhood.
No name.
She was homeless,
hooking for drug money.
You do not know that.
You didn't even ask for tox.
We didn't need to do a test.
We found her
at Paradise and Flamingo.
What else
would she be doing there?
Okay, here we are.
Autopsy samples for Doe, Jane.
99-103.
Uh, most recent vic had
traces of E in her system.
If this one does, too,
there might be a connection.
To a drug dealer
from ten years ago?
That's kind of weak.
Weak is the best
that we have right now.
SIDLE:
Hodges ran the formalin-fixed
tissue sample
from Jane Doe '99 through GCMS.
There's no traces of Ecstasy,
but he did find
chloral hydrate.
Chloral hydrate is
a hypnotic sedative.
There were no traces
of anything like that
found in Veronica Sorensen.
Which means if our guy
still sedates his victims
before sexually
asphyxiating them,
whatever he's using now
isn't leaving a trace.
Warrick Brown.
Mike Keppler.
I know...
You trying to do a geographic
profile of your serial?
Yeah, most of these guys tend
to operate out of one place.
In theory,
as the killer gets
more and more comfortable
with each act,
the locations of the bodies
should spiral outward
from one central point.
I tell you one thing that your
dump sites do have in common.
What's that?
When the bodies were
found, the location
that they were found in
at the time had the highest
crime rate in the city.
Smart.
The crime center
sure seems
to move around pretty
quickly here, huh?
Well, in Vegas,
new is old in five years,
old is history in ten,
and nothing ever
seems to leave a mark.
Sounds refreshing.
STOKES:
'89 Jane Doe,
this was your case.
One of the first
homicides I ever worked.
Damn, I had good
handwriting.
Excuse me.
Come on, come on,
I know you got company.
Yeah, that's it.
Oh, man.
You processed a mountain
of evidence
but didn't turn up
a single suspect.
It's not my
fault, man.
I had the scumbag
dead to rights.
What are you talking about?
There's nothing here
to indicate
that you...
This is it.
That's the killer's hair.
You did note morphology
consistent with the vic.
Yeah,
but the position-
location was all wrong.
I pulled that out of her
navel, just that one hair.
It was a
sexual assault,
It had to be
from the killer.
But I couldn't prove it,
so... I didn't write it down.
This hair had a tag.
Did you run DNA?
(chuckling):
In '89?
Man, we were just
reading about DNA.
The only lab in the country
that was doing that stuff was
the FBI, and my supervisor--
he wouldn't have called them in
on a case like this.
I used to bust my ass
to keep a crime scene pristine,
and then some uniform
would wobble over,
stuffing his face,
drop a hamburger wrapper
right at my feet.
Who the hell needs that?
Man, if I had the tools
you guys do today...
...I finally would have been
a real hero.
There's your
money shot.
Damn it.
Did you preserve the hair?
Permount on a microscope slide
with a cover slip.
It should still be
in Central Property.
CLERK:
Are your sure it's really here?
As I said when you called,
we have no record.
STOKES:
Sir, I spent half the day
at Central Property
going through their records.
Now, according to the case logs,
it was transferred to this court
in late 1989 and never returned.
So, it's got to be here
somewhere, okay?
Okay.
So it is.
Excuse me, bro.
♪ ♪
HODGES:
You rang?
Yeah, I think I need
a hand here, Hodges.
Well, what is this?
It's from an '89 Jane Doe.
I'm looking for anything
probative that will help us out.
Those look like rat droppings.
That's because they are
rat droppings, man.
Are you familiar
with the hantavirus?
Carried by rodents,
transmitted to humans
when they inhale vapors
from contaminated urine,
saliva or feces.
That crap will kill you.
Hodges...
glove up.
If I start leaking blood from
my eyeballs, I'm blaming you.
SPORTSCASTER:
The home team has first and ten
in the closing minutes
of the fourth quarter.
Now the offense shifts to the
right side side for this play.
And the ball is snapped.
The quarterback
fakes a throw left,
hands off right running back.
(crowd cheering)
DR. ROBBINS:
Keppler?
SPORTSCASTER:
He's blocked well and tries
to cut through the middle.
Didn't they give you an office?
I, uh... I like the noise.
It helps me to concentrate.
I prefer things quiet myself.
Of course, I am a pathologist.
SPORTSCASTER:
Just over nine minutes
to go in this quarter.
I reviewed that Jane Doe
autopsy from '75.
That was fast.
Well, I'm sure the original
examination was, too.
M.E. was a hack
named Sam Barnard.
He, uh, retired a little
while after I started.
Once saw him do a Y with
a scalpel in one hand
and a hot dog in the other.
I take it he wasn't known
for his, uh, rigorous analysis?
He was known
for liking hot dogs.
(chuckles)
Well, that's just great.
You know, if you really want
to figure out what killed
your Jane Doe,
there's pretty much only
one thing we can do.
♪ ♪
That one's it.
(creaking)
See the sutured
cut across the
top of her head
and the Y-incision?
No.
It's because
they're not there.
So the original M.E.
didn't even do an autopsy?
What can I say?
He was a lazy bastard.
That's criminal malfeasance.
Well, if you want to tell him,
I can dig him up, too.
Ah, geez.
So what do you got?
Check out
the hyoid bone.
It's fractured.
Yeah, it doesn't take
much force to do it,
so it's possible
there were no
external marks.
But our girl was strangled.
So she is one of ours.
Gum line filling.
Silver amalgam.
On the outside
of the tooth?
That's a cheap
way to do it.
Old school.
Nowadays, most dentists
use epoxy
and other components to make it
match the enamel.
I worked a mass fatality
fire in Philly.
Learned a lot about teeth.
Well, Veronica Sorensen had
a similar filling in her mouth.
Jane Doe '99
had traces of
chloral hydrate in her system.
I read that dentists used to use
it to sedate pediatric patients.
Looks like our guy
might be a dentist.
♪ ♪
(blipping)
(beeps)
(ticking)
♪ ♪
CATHERINE:
Her name is Veronica Sorensen,
and we believe
that she might have been
a patient here.
Oh, yes...
that poor girl.
I saw her on the
news. It's terrible.
These girls, do you
recognize any of them?
Are those girls dead?
We need you to look
carefully at those, ma'am.
(sighing)
I'm sorry.
I don't recognize them.
Well, we're going to have
to see your patient files
from 1975 to '99.
Oh, well, I'm sorry.
Inactive files aren't kept
past seven years.
We just don't have the space.
Can you tell us who worked
on Veronica Sorensen?
I'll have to check.
We have several dentists
on staff.
Even a few dental
students who volunteer.
There we are.
She saw Dr. Dave.
That's Dr. David Lowry.
Everyone around here
calls him Dr. Dave.
How long has Dr. Dave
been working here?
Oh, as long as I have.
And I'm going on my 32nd year.
Could you ask him
to step out, please?
We'd like to speak with him.
It's 1:15.
He's at the Quality Cafe,
around the corner on Fremont.
Second booth
on the left
facing the counter.
The man is nothing
if not predictable.
Dr. David Lowry?
Everybody calls
me Dr. Dave.
I'm Catherine Willows.
This is Michael Keppler.
We're from the Crime Lab.
Please, join me.
Thank you.
Dr. Lowry, we'd
like to ask you about
one of your patients...
Veronica Sorensen.
Is this your work?
That was a very sad business.
She was a lovely, young girl.
(sighs)
She had a gum-line cavity.
Now, normally,
I would have used enamel resin
to match the teeth, but this
was on the inside of her mouth,
so I used amalgam to fill it
because it was less expensive,
and she was worried
about the cost, and...
her bill was never paid.
Are these your
work as well?
I have no idea-- I was...
I was seeing a lot of patients
over the years.
Do you know their names? I mean,
that might ring a bell.
No, we don't know who they are.
Do you ever use chloral hydrate?
No one uses chloral hydrate
anymore. It's too dangerous.
Hmm...
(sighs)
I just feel so awful.
Why is that?
I brightened her smile.
Perhaps that's what
attracted her predator.
Oh, well...
you'll forgive, but if you don't
have any more questions,
I really should get back
to my office.
Whoever did
your mouth...
he does lovely work.
MAN:
See you tomorrow,
Dr. Dave.
I don't know, kind of
reminds me of my Uncle Ralph.
Except for the serial
killer part, I hope.
Haven't seen him in a while.
Who knows?
♪ ♪
STOKES:
In the original photograph,
it would've looked
like a severe bruise.
But there's a lot of information
in the negative.
You know, back in the day,
they didn't have the capability
to see this stuff.
Pretty distinct impressions
of the six upper teeth.
STOKES:
Yeah.
And here, there's a small gap
between the two front teeth.
Did Dr. Dave have a space
between his teeth?
I don't remember.
But you can't go in there,
because he's with a patient.
(knocking)
Dr. Lowry,
would you
please come with us?
Euginia has been
seeing me for, um,
how many years,
my dear?
(grunting)
(chuckling)
I think it's much
longer than that.
I'd like to finish Euginia up
before the Novocain wears off.
We've got a court order
to collect a bite impression
from you.
Is this about these young girls?
KEPPLER:
I think you know what
this is about, Dr. Lowry.
You're gonna need to come down
to the crime lab with us.
Bite impression.
Couldn't we just do that here?
It'll save us all
a lot of time and trouble,
unless of course,
embarrassing me in front of
my patient is your real intent.
Fine.
Okay. Euginia?
(grunts)
I'm going to have you
wait in Exam Four,
and I'll be in there
in just a short while.
(grunting)
No, come on,
let's go.
Let's see, just...
And you know the upper
right teeth we worked on?
Well, they're looking fine.
That's too much water.
It will never set.
We've got time.
Young lady,
please, please, please,
let me do this.
I have much more practice.
Be my guest.
(chuckles)
You know...
I don't believe courts accept
bite mark evidence much anymore.
No, they'd much rather have
DNA from saliva around a wound.
I've gotten convictions
from bite marks.
Not many, I suspect.
Do you know
that our teeth
continuously migrate
through our entire life?
(chuckles)
Yes.
Dental forensics
is definitely
an inexact science.
We could probably
match four out of six.
That's not enough
for a conviction.
Has to be.
It's all we've got.
The killer's left front
incisor is misaligned.
Dr. Dave's smile is perfect.
Would you go to a dentist
with bad teeth?
BRASS:
So we're all on
the same page, right?
About giving the
names of these girls?
WILLOWS:
Yes.
So, Mike, the Viewing Room
is down the end of the hall.
Wait, why don't you
go in and I'll watch.
What makes you think
he's gonna talk to me?
Because I have
a pretty good feeling
he's not gonna talk to me.
All right.
KEPPLER:
Dr. Lowry, I'd like to show you
a bite impression
that we're using as evidence
in the Sorensen case.
There are similarities.
But I don't think
it's conclusive.
Yes.
The left front incisor
doesn't match,
and there's a sizable gap
between the two
front teeth.
But then we found these.
We subpoenaed your
personal records.
You go to a
good dentist.
KEPPLER:
In late 1989,
you had a cosmetic surgery
to repair
a sizable gap between
your two front teeth.
Diastema. It's called diastema.
We used the X-rays
taken before the procedure
to modify your dental model
so that it matched
the configuration
of your teeth in 1989.
This is the new overlay.
Very impressive.
You make a good case.
Wasn't easy, Dr. Lowry.
You cover your tracks well.
Dr. Dave, please,
call me Dr. Dave.
KEPPLER:
Jane Doe in 1975,
Jane Doe in 1989,
and Jane Doe, 1999.
Three girls
without identities.
You were the last person
to see them alive.
You know their names.
Tell us.
You have two daughters,
don't you, Dr. Lowry?
This is the most
cryptic conversation
I've had since dental school.
All right, let me
clear it up for you.
The last time you moved
as a free man
was when you walked
into this room.
When you leave here, you're
gonna be charged with murder.
So do yourself a favor,
give us the identity
of these three girls,
and you might spare
yourself the death penalty.
At my age, I'll die
before that happens.
So what do you have to lose?
I don't want to degrade
the sweetness of my memories.
My memories are all I have left.
I can't imagine that
you didn't feel something
for these girls at some point.
We're just asking you
to help us return them
to their families.
What benefit would I get
from doing this?
You might sleep better at night.
I sleep fine,
thank you very much.
I've always considered that
a key to my good health.
So none of this bothers you?
My life has been blessed.
I was married to a kind woman.
Just lost her a few years ago.
We raised two children.
One of them is an oral surgeon,
the other one is a homemaker.
And you don't care
how this might affect them?
They'll be horrified, of course.
They're not monsters.
BRASS:
Well, I'm sure the judge will
take that into consideration.
You're not listening.
I don't feel bad
about what I've done.
I feel disappointed
that I've been caught,
but I tend to take
the long view of things.
I've had
a wonderful life,
and I know that all things human
eventually must end.
♪ ♪
(speed dialing)
RECORDED VOICE:
You have seven new messages.