♪ ♪
GRISSOM:
Generally, autopsies are
performed in the morning.
Hello, David.
Hello, Grissom.
David Phillips,
everyone,
our excellent
assistant coroner
and baseball trivia expert.
And who's that?
I'll introduce you to her later.
Afternoons are usually
for paperwork and court.
♪ ♪
Hi.
I'm Rebecca.
Donna. I'm...
I was Donna.
But you know,
I don't think that
matters much anymore.
So... so we're...?
Yeah.
Huh.
Somehow... it's not quite
what I expected.
What were you expecting?
White light, puffy clouds?
My mom.
So how'd you get here,
anyway?
You know...
someone will figure it out.
BRASS:
So you're the one
who found the body?
Yeah, I pushed
the button, the
doors open,
I get this.
Right.
Do you recognize her?
No.
At any time did you step
inside the elevator?
Get closer to that?
No, thanks.
Okay. All right, thank you,
Gloria. Thank you.
Some white cotton fibers.
Probably from the towel.
Could be she was dragged
into the elevator.
From any floor except this one.
How many floors we got?
Well, no 13th.
No four and no 14.
Yeah, unlucky numbers.
Different countries,
different superstitions.
That was something
Sam taught me.
Yeah.
And we just eliminated
the one we're on.
You do the math.
33 floors.
Hey,
I'm sorry I'm late.
The wedding planner.
Hmm? Yeah. 21 days
and counting.
That's all right, David.
Why don't you help me
turn the body?
Examine her
for injuries.
Wait a second.
A rose petal.
American Beauty.
(grunts)
Oh!
I'm gonna take a wild stab
and guess drowning.
How do you drown in an elevator?
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me
who are you, you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
(elevator bell dings)
♪ ♪
What do you got?
We got a dead cop.
BRASS:
Donna Basset
out of San Francisco.
She's not
a registered guest.
San Francisco PD
lets their guys moonlight.
Do you know anyone
on this floor
needs private security?
Mr. Hsing. Robert Hsing.
He's an architect.
A pretty big deal in Hong Kong.
Which room?
Clear!
Clear.
Clear and empty.
We need to locate
Mr. Hsing.
I know these suites.
This furniture's
been moved.
Per Mr. Hsing's request.
What is this is, an
eight-sided pattern?
Feng shui?
He's exacting.
The furniture we moved
left impressions in the carpet.
We vacuumed them out.
Some numbers patterns
make elements flow.
Luck, energy, chi.
So you believe in all this
feng shui stuff?
When a guest gambles
several million dollars
per visit,
it doesn't matter
what I believe.
Now we know how
you drown in an elevator.
You don't.
Martin, could you join us?
Don't step in.
Just take a look around
and you notice
anything missing
or out of place?
There's a couple
of towels missing.
And a bath sheet.
And do all your infinity tubs
come with rose petals?
No, we did that.
When the water flows,
the money flows?
Four dozen red rose petals
exactly.
Imported bath oil.
Per Mr. Hsing's request, hmm?
(phone ringing)
This is Martin.
Great. What floor?
Who's in the room
with him?
BRASS:
You okay?
You know, I mean,
working Sam's hotel
so soon after the, you know?
I think that working helps.
I mean, you know that.
Yeah.
MARTIN:
No, stay put.
We found Mr. Hsing.
He's gambling
in a private suite downstairs.
Player has five.
Natural nine.
You win.
Close the door.
Mr. Hsing,
I'm Detective Jim Brass,
Las Vegas Police.
Your security officer,
Donna Basset,
was found dead tonight.
Murdered
in your hotel room.
I'm so sorry.
Donna's worked for me the last
12 times I've come to your city.
Have you notified
her family?
We'll take care of that.
When did you last see her?
When she escorted me here
about four hours ago.
Mm-hmm. Mr. Hsing,
when you hire security,
how much of it
is for real threat
and how much
is perceived?
Do you know what I mean?
How much is for show?
I have very real enemies.
Yeah, she drowned,
all right.
Slight petechial hemorrhaging
in both eyes.
Any chance it was
an accident?
When was the last time
you took a nap in Grissom's tub?
Take a look.
Oh, yeah.
Someone held her down.
And she...
Put up a fight.
So, you checked in
around 6:00.
Where have you been since?
Here, playing.
It's why I come to Vegas.
So you never left this room
all night?
Once, about three hours ago.
Oh, that's helpful.
Why'd you leave?
My luck was bad.
I went to change it.
(chuckles)
And how'd you swing that?
Called Detective Basset
to escort me back to my suite.
She didn't answer.
I went by myself.
I see.
You can corroborate this?
He used the hotel phone.
Okay, good,
there's a record then.
So you get back
to you suite. Then what?
I urinated.
Changed my underwear.
Came back. Kept playing.
So changing your skivvies
can change your luck?
Mr. Hsing's was down
$1.2 million.
Now he's up over $2 million.
Wow. I'll have to try that.
Well, got part
of your killer.
He knew there were cameras
in the elevators,
but not in the hallways
or the service area.
So what do you
want to do now?
His sleeve is wet.
Stop and smell the roses.
♪ ♪
You just caught me.
Mr. Hsing, I'm Catherine
Willows, from the Crime Lab,
and I need to see
the suit that you wore
last night.
You already have
my fingerprints.
Well, we can be finicky.
A rose petal
from the victim's body
was found to contain
traces of vitisvinifera--
grapeseed oil.
The kind that this hotel
puts in your tub.
We know that
the killer's shirt was wet,
so I need to see your clothes.
I'll leave you my
address in Hong Kong.
You can ship them back to me
when you're done.
Thank you.
Rose petals in the bathtub
had traces
of grapeseed oil.
Killer's sleeves
were wet.
So you get the clothes,
you get your guy.
Dry cleaner screwed us.
Did he push all the buttons?
Yeah. Enough to keep that body
moving, and leave me with
a lot of partials.
A lot?
(beeping)
You're in my water.
You're the reason I'm losing!
DONNA BASSET:
I changed his luck,
and he took my life.
Every time he came to Vegas,
he would gamble
for four hours exactly.
And, you know,
I took that bath every time.
You were murdered.
I was a cop.
Thought I could
see danger coming.
Well, not me.
I got into more train wreck
relationships than I can count.
And then I met Gavin.
And...?
He was a great guy.
And then I fell... I fell hard.
(woman groaning)
(screaming)
CURTIS:
Rebecca McGill.
She was taking a hike
with her husband Gavin.
He was taking photos.
One second she was there,
the next she was gone.
He went for help.
Hiking accident?
Maybe.
It's going to take you
some time to get down there.
It's better than
the express route she took.
BROWN:
Okay, Mr. Boy Scout.
Eagle Scout.
SANDERS:
I didn't earn a chestful
of merit badges for nothing.
You see anything
interesting up there?
Well, looks like
she bounced around a lot
up here at the top
before she caught air.
She was hot.
You pay for "hot," believe me.
It's a no-brainer.
I guess that makes me
the search party.
Oh, I see it.
You're getting warm.
Hotter by the foot.
There you go.
It's hard to crack an egg
without breaking the yolk.
That's amazing.
Don't think
she'll be needing it, but...
I found her cell phone.
It was a bald eagle,
and they're extremely rare,
and Rebecca had to have
a picture for
our Christmas card.
It's weird...
You take a picture,
and you turn back around,
and life as you know it
is forever changed.
Sir, is that the camera
that you used?
Yeah.
May I see it?
This was
supposed to be
our second honeymoon.
We fell in love
at an Internet
convention
at the Hilton.
Couldn't believe my luck.
A model...
and a guy like me.
Beauty and the geek.
What did you do after she fell?
I ran to the edge,
called down to her,
and she didn't move.
Mr. McGill,
you hiked
to the ranger station for help.
Why didn't you just
use your cell phone?
Bad reception.
You're free to go.
But stay local.
Impressive that
it remained intact.
I'd say.
So take a look at this.
The multiple
embedded small rocks
present in the neck area,
also in the parietal
and occipital scalp,
suggest she landed head first.
Extremity fractures,
rib fractures,
spine fracture--
all consistent
with a fall.
Multiple abrasions
on the arms and legs.
So I am guessing
most were sustained
before hitting the ground.
Well, I did find some blood
on the rocks
at the top of the cliff,
as well as a piece of his shirt.
Looks like it was a bumpy ride
all the way down.
Yeah. Which could
explain these abrasions.
She tore up her hands
grabbing on
to anything she could.
Severe lacerations
on the backs
of both hands
and a broken
right middle finger.
Was that sustained
during the fall...
or did someone step on her hand?
BROWN:
Tina, baby,
can you give me a call
when you get this?
Listen, I know we haven't been
spending quality time
with each other, but I was
thinking tonight we could...
Uh, Warrick--
Oh.
(whispering):
I'll come back.
Work comes first.
What's up?
Oh, uh, tox
came back.
I detected traces
of sertraline
in the vic's blood.
It's a currently
popular anti-depressant.
She had moderate levels of
alcohol, oh, six percent.
That's a dangerous
combination.
But it's not
that unusual.
Well, would you let
your wife drink
if she was on medication?
If I had a wife... no.
So let me get this straight.
You took your depressed wife
to the top of Red Rock Canyon,
shared a bottle
of wine,
and then you went
on a nature hike?
What are you implying?
Did you know she was
on anti-depressants?
She made her living
with her looks
and, lately, she'd been worried
about... losing them.
Worried enough
to kill herself?
I was going to take her
to New York and then to Paris.
We started talking
about planning a family.
Suicidal people
don't make plans.
Maybe it wasn't
a suicide,
but then again,
you're the only one left.
You can say anything you want.
Let's just say your
marriage wasn't so rosy.
Alimony's a bitch.
You get her drunk.
It's cheap just to
shove her off a cliff.
According to the coroner,
the evidence suggests
that her hands
may have been stepped on.
(strained cries)
(Rebecca screaming,
body thudding)
You're right,
Rebecca was drifting away.
She became a different person.
The meds weren't helping enough.
I thought if I took her
to Vegas, where we met,
it would snap her
out of it,
but instead, she jumped.
No, no.
(crying):
It is my fault.
I never should've
taken her out there.
Why didn't you just tell us this
in the first place?
Would you want people
to know that your wife
would rather be dead than
spend another minute with you?
Well, if he is lying,
somebody should give him
an Emmy Award.
Well, there's plenty
of physical evidence,
but it's all ambiguous.
Yeah.
Ultimately, I think
he is responsible,
whether he meant
harm or not.
Well, you know, there's
precedent for charging him
with promoting
a suicide attempt.
It's reckless
endangerment.
There was a case
in New York,
but it's hard to make
that charge stick.
Well, what if I can prove she
tried to kill herself before?
How do you do that?
Well, I have her phone.
I could go through
the most recent calls.
If I know women,
the husband's usually the
last person to know anything.
♪ ♪
(beep)
Gavin, what are you doing?
Gav... wait...
No! No!
(gasping)
Help me! Help... (yells)
We have a witness.
Why did you kill your
wife, Mr. McGill?
You try having a hot wife.
You pay for it every day.
I want a lawyer.
I finally found a guy who
liked me for my brains.
Turns out he thought
I didn't have any.
Excuse me, ladies?
Have you seen
my wife?
Her-her name's Cara.
No.
Or my little girl?
I had a beautiful
little girl.
She was only
about that big.
You ain't seen
her, have you?
Nope. Just us.
So they're not here?
(exhales)
Okay, then.
It's okay.
Anywhere but here, right?
(laughs)
So, how'd you get here?
Oh, ma'am,
I thought the war was hell
until I came to Vegas.
(tires screech, car crashes)
WOMAN:
Knucklehead just blew the stop
and ran right into
the side of my car.
STOKES:
Damn.
You're lucky-- I don't even see
any skid marks.
Didn't even try to stop!
Just dropped off my partner--
otherwise I would've
been sitting in that
passenger seat.
Hey, Linda...
you didn't touch
the outside of that
door handle, did you?
No. I know better.
Been to a couple of
forensic classes taught
by you lab guys.
Reached in through the
window to check his
vitals-- he was dead.
Paramedics pronounced; made
sure no one touched anything.
You did good.
This might take a while,
if you want to take a little
break or something.
Thanks.
(helicopter flying overhead)
ROBBINS:
Hey, Nick.
Hey, Doc.
What brings you out?
David's on a pickup,
and he's got another two
lined up after that.
He's going for some
sort of record.
Dig in.
What was going through his mind
just before he crashed
into the police cruiser?
"I want to die today
and take somebody with me"?
STOKES:
Huh?
Nothing.
Got a wallet.
Mr. Russell Caris.
He has dried blood
on his hands and on
the steering wheel but no
bleeding wounds that could
have contributed to it.
This could explain the blood.
Sophia...
Here you go.
you might want
to put out a broadcast
on Mr. Caris and his vehicle.
Possible stabbing suspect.
Well, he's definitely
good for something.
I'll include the local hospitals
in case they've had
a stab victim.
Why wouldn't he have thrown
that knife away?
He's not smart.
(laughs):
This is natural selection.
The dumb ones die.
The good ones, too.
I just found your stab victim.
CURTIS:
Patrol got a 415B call.
Man with a knife.
The paramedics rolled up
soon after they did.
The guy was
already dead.
Was he alone?
No. He was with his family.
WOMAN:
We were getting gas,
and, uh, some lunatic came up...
(crying)
...just stabbed my husband
in the chest.
(continues crying)
My baby saw Jack get stabbed.
Did your husband
know the man?
No. And Jack offered him
his wallet.
The guy just muttered something,
just... just stabbed Jack.
(crying):
And left the wallet.
Why... why did he do this?
My... my husband just met
his daughter.
Wha... what do you mean,
he just met his daughter?
He just got back
from his second tour in Iraq.
Would you recognize this guy
if you saw him again?
(baby continues crying)
Is that him right there?
That's him.
Well... is he dead?
Who is he?
Why did he kill my husband?
That's what I'm gonna find out
for you.
Why don't you go
with this officer right now.
She'll take care of you,
all right?
I'll do my best to keep you
informed, ma'am, I promise.
Um... I'll check
with the clerk,
see if his surveillance
camera was working.
Yeah, there's some-some...
oil and grease around the pump.
I'll check the tire and...
shoe impressions.
CURTIS:
Made it back from the war to die
on the streets of Las Vegas.
I'm telling you,
no place is safe anymore.
ROBBINS:
Sergeant Jack Day
was in top condition
except for the single
stab wound to his chest.
Knife entered
the fourth intercostal space,
transected the fourth
intercostal muscle, and the left
internal mammary artery.
C.O.D.'s exsanguination.
What about
the crash-test
dummy here?
Interesting case.
He has intense erythema
of the tracheal mucosa
extending down into
the main stem bronchi.
(inhales)
You don't get that from
an auto accident, do you?
No. You get it from inhalation
of some caustic poison or drug.
I sent samples to Tox.
Okay, good.
So... C.O.D.?
Well, the impact
of the accident caused
the first cervical
vertebrae to tear away
from his skull,
lacerating the brain stem.
His skull separated
from his spine.
Exactly.
Should've been wearing
a seat belt.
(computer beeping quietly)
No!
(knife stabs)
Well, why'd he stab him?
I mean, it's not like
he put up a fight.
And why does he pick
the biggest guy at the station?
You think that guy in the back
would be an easier target.
Rewind it back to this fool
getting out of the Buick.
(beeping)
STOKES:
He seems disoriented, shaky...
high on something.
ANDREWS:
He had fairly high levels
of THC in his blood.
97 nanograms
per milliliter.
THC? That's it?
Isn't that what you
were looking for?
No, I was kind of thinking there
was something else in there.
You should've seen this guy--
he was acting really...
sketched out.
Sometimes people
are just crazy.
♪ ♪
Well, you're persistent,
I'll give you that.
I tested the remaining marijuana
in the paper wrapper.
You were right.
The joint was dipped.
PCP?
No. Embalming fluid.
"Embalming fluid" is
the street name for PCP.
Yeah, but I don't use street
names when I don't mean to.
No, I mean real,
inject-into-a-dead-
person embalming fluid,
made of formaldehyde,
methanol,
ethanol, all
that bad stuff.
So this guy was smoking wet.
Well, the embalming
fluid would make the
marijuana burn slower,
giving it more chance
to be absorbed,
creating a longer lasting
high, I would imagine.
So, now, what do I tell
Sergeant Day's widow?
A retired marine who served
two tours in Iraq.
That-that all this
is about getting higher?
You got to tell her the truth.
(crying):
It-it was... it
was just random?
That's the reason I
don't have a husband?
That's why?
(continues crying)
I'm sorry.
So after all that,
how can you be happy?
You don't get it.
This is the best
week of my life.
'Cause I got to hold
my baby girl.
Oh, son of a bitch!
Let me tell you something,
you got nothing to
bitch about here.
I don't think
you can smoke in here.
Nah. Let him try.
REBECCA:
No, you guys,
we're gonna be here a long time.
Let's just try
to keep it pleasant, okay?
I'm not even supposed
to be here.
Tell me about it.
(chainsaw whirring)
(man screaming)
(chainsaw strikes
hard surface, stops)
The hot weather, the full moon,
too many people moving to Vegas.
Whatever the reason,
the natives are restless.
Scene's in the garage.
SIDLE:
Well, that's not a good sign.
GRISSOM:
Bacon and eggs?
Yeah, no, you know,
don't bother about that.
That's the water delivery boy.
He lost his breakfast,
and his bottle.
He said the house belonged
to a guy named Lou Beltran.
Is he one of the victims?
He couldn't tell.
The door's been forced.
(door creaking)
I thought this only
happened in the movies.
Life imitates art.
(camera shutter clicking)
Okay.
You first.
All right.
Kicked-in door, one bloody
chainsaw, two dead bodies.
Someone broke in,
cut up the two guys,
left the murder weapon
and split.
What about all this mess,
the furniture and appliances?
Some of the furniture looks new.
Some of it's cut-up,
some of it's not.
Maybe they were cutting it up
when the assailant came in.
That's a workable theory
for now.
You know what this
reminds me of?
The first time we met.
San Francisco.
Your lecture.
Double murder in a garage.
I'd heard you were a little dull
as a speaker,
but you can't rely
on your first blush.
That was the, uh,
subject of your talk.
I believe I said
first opinions are crucial,
but if the evidence changes,
so must the theory.
Exactly.
Hey.
Any ID on them yet?
We're still working our way in.
Well, you know,
I'm kinda stuck
until I know
who they are, so, uh...
Sara, do me a favor, will you?
Reach into that barbecue
and hand me
his wallet.
Sure.
Thank you.
This guy doesn't live here.
This is Ray Gaynor,
lives a few houses down.
Maybe the other one's Lou.
I don't know, but I'd bet my
right arm that's his left arm.
(Brass chuckles)
I'm gonna see if the one-arm man
has a wife who knows
how to operate a chainsaw.
It was a jagged,
sharp force injury
to the base of the neck
on the right side.
Wound extends
down and left laterally
from the right shoulder
to the left hip.
Wound becomes shallow
and then separates
into individual incisions.
Directionality
of the individual wounds
is from bottom to top.
All chainsaws operate
the same way, right?
Chain travels
around the bar, teeth move
away from the operator
around the top and come
back on the bottom.
Mm-hmm.
So, if our guy, Lou,
was attacked from the front,
the teeth would hit him
from a downward angle.
Leaving downward wounds
instead of
the upward wounds you see here.
So... what?
He was attacked from behind?
Guess who owns the chainsaw.
Ray Gaynor.
The neighbor.
I also found bits
of wood and metal shavings
on the inside
of the cover plate,
consistent with the furniture
and appliances.
The teeth
on the chain are dull,
probably from cutting them up.
Don't tell me Lou cut up
my mother's headboard.
Was it blue?
Sorry.
How about my dining room set?
Um...
I think there's a couple
of chairs left.
Damn that man.
Everything I asked
for in the divorce.
Did he get the
living room furniture?
No.
Figures. That was
going to be his.
Well, now it's mine.
The bastard can rot in hell.
So, Mrs. Beltran, I assume
the divorce wasn't final.
No.
Lou held it up out of spite.
Hmm. Do you know Ray Gaynor?
Decent guy. Never married.
Lots of women around, though.
Pretty handy with his tools.
Uh-huh.
Halfwit would
go over there
and Ray'd teach him
how to do things.
Too bad he never taught him
how to be more of a man.
Look, I gotta ask you this--
where were you last night?
32,000 feet over the Pacific
with 300 other people.
So you were in a plane.
I'm a flight attendant.
But go ahead and ask me
if I'm sorry he's dead.
SIDLE:
Where do you want him?
Put him under
the Lou Beltran spatter.
And load him up.
SIDLE:
Blue test paint
is not lining up
with the red known spatter.
Well, the body's in the
correct relative position.
but the angle's off.
What could throw
the angle off?
I don't know,
but it's very awkward
to try and line this up.
You know...
What if you line it up
switching hands, like this?
Ray Gaynor's killer
was left-handed.
Lou Beltran wore
his watch on his right wrist.
I bet he was left-handed.
So... Lou could have killed Ray,
cut off his arm...
...but who killed Lou?
Doc Robbins
said that the cuts on
Lou's body were made
when the chain was
traveling upwards.
Well, if I attacked you,
the chain would be
traveling downwards
when held normally by a left-
or a right-handed person.
Which means that
the top of the chain
had to be facing him.
The way that this works,
is if Lou was holding the saw.
The chain was dull
from cutting up
his wife's things.
The wife told Brass
that he wasn't very handy.
An inexperienced left-handed
operator with a dull chainsaw
certainly increases
the risk for injury.
Kickback.
You don't know
what you're doing!
I know exactly what I'm doing!
(screams)
So he chainsawed his wife's
furniture and appliances,
the metal dulled the blade,
and the kickback from the
chainsaw is what killed him.
So it was an accident.
How many of you
are right-handed?
Left-handed?
2,500 left-handed people
die each year
using products designed
for right-handed people.
Okay, but how do you know
there wasn't a third person
that killed both of them?
A third person would have left
shoe impressions in the blood,
various other sign--
there was none.
You're absolutely certain?
Part of being a CSI is learning
to work in the absence
of absolute certainty.
Each and every
case brings us
a new opportunity
to learn something.
For instance, in the case
of Donna Basset, we can see that
there is no such thing
as an insignificant detail.
Here, the evidence itself
can bear witness.
Don't just look for what you
think you're going to find.
And this one,
never impose logic
on an illogical act.
And finally,
if the evidence changes,
your theory must change as well.
Questions?
How do you deal
with the smell?
You get used to it.
I'm not sure I can do this.
Well, not everyone can.
Why do you do it?
Because the dead
can't speak for themselves.