(distant siren wailing)
(garbled radio transmission)
The vic is
Ross Neddy. Ex-con.
Spent a couple years
in Jean for
domestic assault.
Just got paroled.
Shop foreman says he's only been
working here a few days.
Out of the frying pan
into the fire.
He is a crispy critter.
I'd say the point
of origin was him.
KEPPLER:
He should have stayed in prison.
STOKES:
Mmm-hmm.
KEPPLER:
Sloppy shop.
This whole place is
a fire hazard.
Okay if I move him out?
STOKES:
Yeah, he's all yours,
Super Dave.
(device beeping)
There was a lot
of gasoline over here.
Which explains this V-pattern.
Accelerant,
a second point of origin.
Most likely arson.
Ex-con.
STOKES:
Enemies on the outside...
two points of origin...
maybe we're looking
at a little payback.
What do you
think, Keppler?
I think I'd better
head back to the body.
Hey...
you know what Grissom
would say here, don't you?
PHILLIPS:
Something ironic, I'm sure.
KEPPLER:
Looks like somebody took
a staple gun to him.
ROBBINS:
Those aren't bones.
That's bad luck, isn't it?
♪ Who...are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who...are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
ROBBINS:
PVC piping is sometimes
used to replace bones
that have been donated
for transplants.
So that the body looks right
at open casket?
ROBBINS:
Right.
They use umbrellas and
broomsticks for that, too?
ROBBINS:
Not that I've seen.
KEPPLER:
Wait a minute,
they killed the guy
and torched him;
there's no open casket.
What's the point
of stuffing the body?
Looks like the long bones
are gone...
ditto for the spine...
tendons
and cartilage...
most major veins... phew.
They took the heart valves, too.
KEPPLER:
So somebody murders an ex-con,
then commits arson to make it
look like an accident
just so that they can harvest
his bones and tissues?
That's big business--
disc replacement,
joint replacement,
bypasses, more
demand than supply.
Why leave the kidneys,
the heart
and the liver?
They're worth big money, too.
Organ donation
is heavily regulated.
Bone and tissue aren't.
C.O.D.?
ROBBINS:
At this point,
indeterminate.
All I can say right
now is based on the
level of decomp,
he's been dead at least a week.
You think I'm
selling body parts?
Come on, you're
wasting your time.
I sell refurbished engines.
I don't know jack
about body parts.
No one's looking for
a down-and-out ex-con.
It's less risky than drugs.
BOONY:
I hired Ross to weld
metal together.
Even if I killed him--
not saying I did--
but if even if I did, I'd
just burn the body as is,
not re-pipe the guy.
And I definitely
wouldn't burn him at work.
Fire station's a block away.
How do you know Ross?
You meet him in the joint?
I was out before he even
went in. I picked Ross up
with a bunch of other
guys looking for work
outside that big
hardware store
on Herrick four days ago.
When was the last time
you saw him?
Four days ago.
He'd been working nights.
Really?
'Cause the coroner said
he's been dead at least a week.
You calling me a liar?
I'd believe a dead guy
over an ex-con.
Living large.
Mm.
Place this big in
MacDonald Ranch--
what's the occupation?
That's, uh,
Bill Norton.
You know,
Dorton Homes.
Biggest
homebuilder in town.
He built mine.
Huh.
Oh, uh...
you'd better
throw on some booties.
BRASS:
Margo Dorton, age 39.
Her husband said
he returned from a business trip
and found her like this.
No sign of a forced entry.
My guys are gonna go talk
to the neighbors, see what they
say about their relationship.
What did he say?
According to him,
it was a honeymoon every day.
SIDLE:
Maybe...
she was having a honeymoon
with someone else.
That'll be good motive
for the husband.
SIDLE:
There's a void here.
Maybe someone was
sitting on the couch,
or someone
was sitting
on the floor
in front of the couch.
But then where's
the "someone else"?
I mean, why kill her
and not the lover?
BROWN:
Maybe the husband was the one
having the honeymoon and the...
the wife walks in.
He kills her,
tells his lover to beat it.
I'd buy it.
Unless the husband's
alibi checks out.
Airport. I was coming
home from the airport.
It's a business trip.
Caught an early flight
to surprise Margo.
I want your best
cops on this.
I contributed a lot
to this community.
Absolutely.
Let's establish a timeline.
What time did your plane land?
Around 10:30.
10:30.
And you
arrived here at...
Midnight.
Well, it took you an hour and
a half at that time of night
to get from McKaren to here?
A half an hour waiting
for baggage check,
(voice cracking):
and half an hour
to find my driver,
and a half an hour
to get home.
BROWN:
Look at this.
Valet ticket.
Nice purse. Nice dress.
Maybe safe to say
she went out last night.
Maybe this
will tell us where.
SIDLE:
Maybe this...
will tell us who.
I'm gonna follow
a little lead I got.
BROWN:
Well, I found a circular
blood transfer
in the bathroom about
three inches in diameter.
Champagne bottle.
Looks like it's been wiped down.
Looks like we found
our murder weapon.
♪ ♪
STOKES:
So the crispy critter
isn't Ross Neddy?
KEPPLER:
Nope.
STOKES:
Let me get this straight.
The ex-con
digs up a corpse,
scoops out a few
body parts to sell,
then fills it back up
with PVC and umbrellas,
then torches the body
where he works
to make it look like
he's the victim?
Cops don't come looking for you
if you're already dead.
If this Lapinsky guy
was already dead,
then how come the doc didn't
find traces of embalming fluid?
He's Jewish.
So what?
Observant Jews don't
believe in embalming
or donating organs.
It's part of
their faith.
They think the body should
go out the way it came in.
So, this isn't just about
desecration of the body,
but of the
family as well.
Mmm-hmm.
I'll get a court order
for the exhumation.
♪ ♪
What you got?
Well, looks like your killer
wigged out on your vic.
The pink fiber's modacrylic
with low birefringence.
Most likely made of elura.
Synthetic hair.
So much for DNA.
And the substance
you found in the toilet--
if it looks like vomit
and smells like vomit, it is.
The champagne glasses
were negative for DNA,
and Mandy found
nothing but smears
and partials on them.
And the blood
from the champagne bottle
just came back
to the vic.
Any good news?
Well, I called the phone number
on the valet stub.
It was a company
called Chariot Parking.
They operate the parking lots at
30 restaurants and nightclubs.
Oh, well, that
narrows it down.
Actually, it does.
The ticket on
Margo Dorton's key ring
came from a batch
at the Over-Under Cabaret.
(rap music playing)
Excuse me, have you
seen this man?
No. Thank you.
ANNOUNCER (over speakers):
Ladies and gentlemen,
get ready for tonight's
panty auction!
(applause)
Hello.
Have you seen this man?
For our first pair,
starting at
the low price of $50,
Cotton Candy!
Doesn't accept checks,
just cold, hard cash.
(cheering, whistling)
WARRICK:
Check out the pink wig.
Bid!
CANDY:
Come on, come on.
Why you got
to take the wig?
Wig's part of my act.
Y'all are straight
stealing from me
right now! Hello!
I'm crying for you.
Synthetic.
Same color and texture
as the one
that we collected
off the vic.
Whoa, wh...
Hey, hey, hey!
Look, look, look,
look, look.
Look, we didn't
even have sex, okay?
It was all touchy feely.
Jerky treats.
What are you
talking about?
The guy I took into V.I.P.
right before panty auction.
Look, man, all we did was touch.
Why do you think
you're being arrested?
Solicitation, right?
No, actually.
We found this hair on
this woman's dead body.
Margo?
She's dead?
And you think I killed her?
With or without the help
of her husband.
No, no, no.
Look, man, I never seen
dude in that picture.
And Margo,
yeah, I'll admit,
I slapped the ho
around last night,
but I didn't kill her.
You slapped her around?
She's always hanging out
with my fiancé.
I couldn't take it anymore,
so... yeah.
Bitch!
Get off of me!
No!
Why would Margo Dorton
be hanging out here
with your fiancé?
He works upstairs.
Upstairs?
Look, honey,
they don't call this
the Over-Under for nothing,
all right?
What's your fiancé's name?
Jesse.
WARRICK:
Take her downtown.
We're going upstairs.
Are you serious?
I didn't do anything.
(handcuffs clicking)
Come on, man.
♪ ♪
Is this a restaurant?
If it is,
I'm scared of the menu.
The bus boy looks likes
he's in charge of
stocking the champagne.
I'm gonna have
a word with him.
Okay.
Would you like
a Meet Book
or do you have a steady host?
Uh, actually,
it's my first time.
What exactly goes on here?
This is a host club,
a place where men
entertain women.
It's the first
of its kind in Las Vegas.
They started in Japan.
Take your pick.
Hosts get paid
by the bottle.
There's a two bottle
minimum.
Bottles range from $50
to $5,000.
What's a $5,000 bottle
of champagne taste like?
We only sell one brand
of champagne.
It's the host
attached to the bottle
that determines price.
Everything is legal
in Clark County.
Miss, we don't sell sex here.
What do you sell?
A relationship.
Isn't that what most women want?
I don't know.
But I know what I want.
I want Jesse.
Who doesn't?
Let me see if he's avail.
Never seen the old guy before,
but the lady, a bunch.
Last night, she got blasted on
by one of the strippers
downstairs.
Really?
(retching)
Are they doing what I think
they're doing?
Hosts get paid by the bottle.
So they drink more
than their stomachs
can handle.
Always see blood
in those toilets.
Ah, just off work, huh?
Just on, actually.
Sara Sidle,
Crime Lab.
Oh.
What can I do for you?
Do you know this woman?
Ah. Lady Dorton.
Yeah, she's one of
my relationships.
Could I ask you
a few questions about her?
Okay.
Um, I don't like to talk about
my relationships
out here.
Let's take it someplace
a little more intimate, yeah?
Okay.
STOKES:
The coffin had only been in
the ground for about a week.
Dirt and sod were
pretty loose,
so it was relatively easy
to take out and put back in.
You guys sure do a lot
of exhumations here.
As many as we have to.
Nobody home.
No surprise.
(camera clicking)
Look at this.
Lapinsky may have been burned
in this shirt,
but I doubt he was buried in it.
Dead men don't wear plaid.
Wait a minute.
Is this blood?
(fabric ripping)
Ow!
Dead men don't bleed.
(camera clicking)
How did you
meet Margo?
Uh, she picked me
from the Meet Book.
And then what?
Uh, she wanted
what most women want.
What's that?
No, thank you.
The dream.
And that's you.
50 G's
I make a month
says I am.
Who doesn't want to be
swept off their feet?
I am not sure
it's something
that I would pay for.
Yeah, but you don't
want to spend
your whole life
waiting for it either.
Right here, right now, a woman
can have a relationship
with a man who only
wants to please her--
who can make her laugh,
wipe away her tears,
give her the confidence
to be herself.
And how many
of these
relationships do you have?
I can handle about 25 at a time.
Is a woman named Cotton Candy
one of them?
Yeah.
She's been financially
worshipping me for a while.
Now, she says
that she is your fiancée.
That's good.
Means I'm doing my job.
She told me that she and Margo
had a scuffle.
Yeah.
Um... my relationships
do get jealous sometimes,
especially when one has
more money than the other
and can monopolize my time.
Is that why you're here,
because of that little catfight?
No.
Um, Margo Dorton was...
bludgeoned to death
with a bottle
of champagne.
Margo was... killed?
Yeah.
And you think Cotton Candy
killed Margo?
What do you think?
Um... I wouldn't know.
Would you know if Margo
took you home the other night?
I don't see my relationships
outside of here.
If it does happen, it marks
the end of the relationship.
I mean, by having sex with me,
a woman's reached her goal.
There's nothing more
I can give her.
Did Margo's husband
know about you?
She told me she was divorced.
Well, Jesse...
I'm, uh, sorry for your loss.
SIMS:
I ran the blood from the coffin
through CODIS,
and I got a hit,
but it's not Ross Neddy.
So he's got
a partner.
Well, DNA matches
a Heidi Sultz,
who did time
for domestic assault
and is currently
out on parole.
That's funny.
Ross Neddy did time for
domestic assault, too.
Maybe they're
sparring partners.
This is Heidi's last known.
According
to her P.O.,
she's been trying
to straighten out.
She's detoxed, got a job.
She's dumped Ross Neddy.
She may be taking
the right steps,
but she definitely
hasn't cleaned up.
(knock at door)
MITCHELL:
Las Vegas P.D.
Heidi Sultz?
What's going on?
You're under arrest.
Why?
Where's Ross?
I haven't seen
that dog in weeks.
MITCHELL:
Anyone else living
here with you?
Yeah, my baby and my new
boyfriend Charlie.
Where are they?
Out back, hanging out.
CURTIS:
Put her in the car.
Ross.
Wake up, sugar.
Hey, baby.
My name's Charlie,
Charlie Keefer.
Get on the wall.
I got I.D.
It's in my jeans.
Where'd you get this,
the dollar store?
Have a seat, Ross.
KEPPLER:
This is your third strike, pal.
Right now you're looking
at a minimum of 25 years.
You want to talk to us?
We can make sure
it doesn't get any worse.
What do you say?
(fussing)
Daddy will be right there,
sweetheart.
It's ten more
for falsifying an ID.
Fifteen for grave robbing.
Arson, that's another ten.
Desecrating a corpse, ten;
another 20
for trafficking body parts.
Body parts? No way.
I thought those
cuts were from,
like, an autopsy.
So you admit
to digging up Roger Lapinsky?
I've been out two months
and the best job I can get
is five bucks an hour
welding engine parts together.
They wouldn't even
let me flip burgers.
Heidi just had the baby.
It wasn't like
it was gonna hurt anyone.
We dug up someone my age,
took him to work.
made him look like me.
And then we torched it.
All I was looking for
was a fresh start.
Best way to make it happen
was to kill myself.
Should've stuck with
the five bucks an hour.
Whoever did this must
have been pretty angry.
Let me guess, multiple BFT?
You got it.
Fractured skull, broken nose,
cheek bones.
Take a look.
Defensive wounds consistent
with a cylindrical object.
Warrick found a bloody
champagne bottle at the scene.
That'll do the trick.
But the death blow
came in the neck area.
Impacted her Adam's apple
with so much force,
it sent a reflex arch
to the vagus nerve,
causing a stimulus
to the heart.
Bradycardia set in,
causing the heart to slow,
and eventually to stop.
BRASS:
So where'd you go
after the fight with Margo?
Back to the pole.
You're a real
workaholic, huh?
Look, man,
the more I work,
the more I can be with Jesse.
I know how hard it is
to wiggle your ass all night.
Now, why would you
want to spend
all your hard-earned money
on a guy
whose job it is to be
with you and 24 other women?
He doesn't care about them.
Now you know this is
not a real relationship.
It's a business transaction.
He's doing the same
kind of thing that you
are doing
on the pole for the guys.
Those guys, they can't see
past this, okay?
I am more than a piece
of meat to Jesse.
He-he-he doesn't judge me.
All right?
He doesn't
blow me off.
He makes me smile, you know?
He heals me,
he heals me when I'm down.
He makes me feel
like I am Mrs. Steve Wynn.
Hmm.
Now we're going to get married,
real soon.
Can you show me some
verifiable proof
of where you were
the night Margo was murdered?
I was in V.I.P.
with this pit boss,
Joe Brodsky--
works at the Olympia.
But he's married and
he'll probably deny it.
But I can prove it to you if you
give me my wallet right now.
Sure. Okay, go ahead.
There it is.
Right there.
He paid me with those.
Brand-new, straight
from the bank.
And what would you like us
to do with those?
You're a CSI.
You can take a print off
of there, easy... duh.
Hi.
What are you doing?
Just looking.
What do you think?
Meticulous.
Obsessive.
Clearly knows his way
around a modeling kit.
Grissom didn't make those.
No? Hmm.
Fits the profile.
Bugs in bottles,
the Darwin desk set.
He's a bit of a collector
of certain things.
Yeah, I knew a guy in Philly
like that.
Kept a case of thumbs
in his closet.
Friend of yours?
No, a serial killer.
Do you miss it?
What?
Philly.
No.
♪ ♪
Hey, thought you
had a deposition.
Oh, it got postponed.
So I did a little follow-up
on tissue procurement
companies in the area.
Turns out there's
only two in the state.
One is out in Summerlin.
It's called Longevity
Tissue Services.
Check this out.
That's the same
logo you found
on the umbrella
that was in Lapinsky's leg.
Yeah. It's the Chinese character
for "long life".
So, what can Longevity do
for the L.V. Police?
We need to know if your company
received tissue or bone
from a Roger Lapinsky.
What's the problem?
There might not be one.
All right.
Well, I'd be
happy to check.
Will you excuse
me, sweetie?
(computer keys tapping)
Yep, there he is.
Roger Lapinsky, 37 years old,
died of cardiac arrest.
It's tragic.
We're going to need
a copy of his records,
and we're going to need
to confiscate his parts.
And if you don't tell me
what's going on,
you're going to
need a warrant.
This is a criminal
investigation.
Those parts are evidence now.
You know, I was always
under the impression
that the body parts were to be
removed at the hospital.
Major organs have
to be removed at the hospital
and then transplanted
into the new patients
within four to six hours,
but bone and tissue
can be removed at any point
and stored for up to five years.
Who gives you access
to those parts?
I always have signed consent
from next of kin.
STOKES:
And?
Most funeral homes have tissue
recovery coordinators.
They choose who the parts go to.
If you have a good reputation,
you have a better chance
of getting the parts.
I help the dead help the living.
According to your records,
Roger Lipinsky's body parts came
from the Silver Hills Mortuary.
If that's what it says.
Hey.
So you heard Cotton Candy's
alibi checked out?
Yeah.
And Brass talked to
Mr. Dorton's limo driver.
Confirms his story,
he got home way past T.O.D.
I don't get it, Warrick.
The vic is in a good marriage,
and she's spending thousands
on a "fake" boyfriend
that she's not even
having sex with.
It doesn't make any sense.
Like this void on the sofa
for instance.
It suggests the presence
of a third person,
but we don't have
any evidence to back that up.
Maybe it's not a person.
Maybe it's a thing.
Rectangular, roughly,
what, 11 by 14 inches?
It was obviously
important enough
that the killer took it.
What if he didn't take it?
♪ ♪
SIDLE:
Whose baby is this?
Margo's.
I remember, Bill,
you telling me that
you didn't have kids.
We don't... or I don't.
She gave him up
right after we met.
She was 17.
And I didn't want any kids.
Who'd Margo give the baby to?
The biological father,
but he was a drunk.
Last we heard, the kid ran away.
She was looking
at these photos
when she was killed.
Yeah.
She started taking them out
ever since she hit menopause.
BRASS:
Wasn't she
a little young
for menopause?
They call it premature menopause
and she was having
a tough time with it.
The mood swings,
the "brain fog,"
the emotional detachment.
The finality of not having
any more children.
BRASS:
Bill...
did you know that
Margo was frequenting
um...a so-called
host club,
and paying money
to a male escort?
No. She was paying for sex?
SIDLE:
She was paying...
for companionship.
♪ Ta-da-ba-da-ba ♪
♪ Ta-da-ba-do-whop ♪
(straining)
(bone cracks)
♪ Ha-da-da-ba-da ♪
♪ Da-da-ba-do-whop ♪
(grunts)
(bone cracks)
I'm looking for
Salvatore Heinz.
You got him.
Mike Keppler,
Las Vegas Crime Lab.
Sorry if I don't shake.
I, uh, hope you don't mind
if I keep working here,
I'm kind of on a deadline.
That's mortuary humor.
I'm sure it never gets old.
We're following up
on a body that came
through here.
Roger Lapinsky.
You know, he does
look familiar.
I believe he's spending
his eternal rest
at Horizon Meadows Cemetery.
Not anymore.
Someone dug him up.
Aw, geez.
You know, sometimes I wonder
what the heck is going on
with the world these days.
His major bones, veins
and tendons were all stolen.
Recovered! Not stolen.
I'm a certified tissue
recovery coordinator.
Oh, yeah?
That where you learned how to
stuff the bodies with umbrellas?
That was a one-time thing.
I ran out of
PVC pipe, and, uh...
so I improvised.
Understandable.
Look, it was a closed
casket service, and uh...
I have a signed consent form.
Where? If you don't mind,
I'd like to take a look at that.
Sure.
Anything for LVPD.
KEPPLER:
I take it you do a lot a work
with, uh...
Longevity Tissue Services?
Some.
Those are just
promotional items.
Handy in a pinch, huh?
(cabinet drawer slams shut)
Lapinsky, Roger.
It's all yours.
I got copies.
Thanks.
HEINZ:
C.O.D., cardiac arrest.
Everything seems
to be in order here.
Like I said.
Thanks for
your time.
(cell phone rings)
Keppler.
ROBBINS:
Robbins here.
Want a C.O.D.
on your Frankenstein?
Beat you to it-- cardiac arrest.
Not according to histology.
Roger Lapinsky died of leukemia.
You want to repeat that, Doc?
Sure.
Roger Lapinksy died of leukemia.
Thanks.
If you don't mind, I'll, uh...
stick around here
till the warrant comes.
KEPPLER:
I got a copy of Roger Lapinsky's
death certificate
from Carson City.
KEPPLER:
This is the one we got
from the mortician,
that old nut job, see?
Changed the C.O.D.
It turns out, Ty Miloni...
is a bit of a hustler as well.
Those umbrellas were
a promotional gift
for a vitamin
telemarketing
company he ran
a few years back.
This guy isn't even a doctor.
He did drop out of
chiropractic school.
You're telling me that
any Tom, Dick, or Harry
with a sign can open up
a tissue bank?
Well, if you're FDA
registered, yeah.
How do you get FDA registered?
You just fill out a form.
In the last
three years,
37 of the bone and tissue donors
were from Silver Hills mortuary
that went to this
Longevity clinic.
C.O.D in 23 of those
cases was cardiac arrest.
And most of those decedents
were in their 30s and 40s.
That's a lot of young
heart attacks.
We're going to through
all these C.O.D's
and match them up against the
official death certificates.
And do more exhumations.
The only thing
I'm wondering--
is the mortician hustling
the tissue bank guy
or they're working together.
♪ ♪
Dr. Stewart, Dr. Klein,
Dr. Combs, Dr. Jones.
That's not my handwriting.
Well that's
the point of forgery,
isn't it, Mr. Heinz?
A man dies of leukemia,
and his body comes
into your mortuary,
and you decide to...
sell his spare parts
for a few extra bucks.
Only problem is, nobody wants
to buy diseased body parts,
so you make a new
death certificate,
change the C.O.D.,
sign off with a legit
doctor's signature,
and cash a check
from Ty Miloni.
MILONI:
I'm so disappointed
with Mr. Heinz.
He always seemed so honest.
Have you ever followed up
on any of the patients
who received parts
from the Silver
Hills Mortuary?
No. That's the hospital's job.
But as far as I know,
none of the recipients
have ever complained.
Maybe that's 'cause
they're not around anymore.
We followed up on several
patients who received
Silver Hills
bone and tissue
from your clinic and now
seven of them are dead.
Three from hepatitis,
three from cancer,
and one AIDS-related.
The same thing ironically
killed the donors.
One of those victims
was a 15-year-old
healthy high school
soccer player.
You gave him
a contaminated kneecap.
Oh, my God.
He came to me!
You harvested
diseased body parts
and sold them
under false pretenses.
He told me what to do.
He... he said it was safe!
But you didn't have to do it,
did you, Mr. Heinz?
You took money,
and people died.
Now, whether or not
we got him--
we got you.
You've got nothing on me.
I don't care what that...
little body snatcher tells you.
The families are going
to sue you
and your company
into bankruptcy.
They can try.
That is what signed
release forms are for.
You're reopening a very nasty,
old wound for them, now.
Uh-uh. I didn't do anything.
Because of you...
they're going to have
to rebury their mother,
their father, their son,
their daughter.
Ty...
let me tell
you something.
I'm gonna come down
to that clinic...
...and I'm going
to go through it
piece by piece by piece.
And if something
doesn't jibe,
I can assure you...
sir, I will find it.
Well, that is your job,
isn't it?
Yes, it is.
And you'll have
my full cooperation.
SIDLE:
I did a little background
on Jesse, the host.
He was in and out of 11
different foster homes.
Brass accessed
his juvie records.
He had multiple arrests
for prostitution,
and drug possession.
Kid had a hard life if
he had to take it to the
streets to make a buck.
We still need his DNA,
and if he did kill Margo,
he's not just
gonna give it up.
What about the vomit
that we found
in the toilet at
the crime scene?
What about it?
Well, the hosts drink a
lot and throw up a lot.
Busboy says he
always finds blood
in the toilets.
If Jesse's a host,
chances are he's
throwing up blood, too.
SIDLE:
Jesse, we found your DNA
in Margo Dorton's toilet.
I thought that you said
that you didn't
see your relationships
outside of the club.
Unless, of course,
the relationship is ending.
BRASS:
Oh yeah, that's a
cold word for it--
for murder.
I didn't kill her, all right?
I ended the relationship
and I bounced.
Champagne got me sick.
No, I don't think
it was the champagne, Jesse.
I think it was Margo.
She was coming to see you
for a couple of months,
spending a
lot of money,
you were running your
pro-game, you know,
doing the host thing.
Holding her hand,
touching, consoling her.
Laying on the
old Jesse magic.
But then she laid
some pretty heavy
information on you.
I want you to come home with me.
So you want to end
the relationship?
I guess you thought, you know...
here's Margo,
this cougar...
wants to take me
back to the love pit,
end the relationship.
Sexy time.
But it didn't turn out
that way, did it?
Jesse, I...
Shh...
Look, um...
I have something
I need to show you.
Okay?
This is you.
I'm your mother, Jesse.
I've waited my entire life
to tell you this.
I love you.
I'm sorry.
No!
(retching)
You look a little
pale, Jesse.
Are you getting this?
She lied to me.
Said she hired
some private investigator
to find me.
Said she'd been
building up the nerve
to tell me the truth.
Said she had
a lot to make up for.
And that, uh...
I could have her car.
And that I didn't have
to work anymore.
You thought those were lies?
Yeah, lies to get
closer to me.
All my clients
have their tactics.
But hers was... insane.
She wasn't lying to you, Jesse.
You have
13 alleles
in common.
You killed your mother.
Then take me to jail.
You know,
call me a killer...
a murderer, whatever,
but don't tell me
I have a mother...
because I don't.
I never did.
And I never will.
Hey.
Need some help?
Aren't you off shift?
Yeah. Are you?
Yeah.
Thanks.
I'll be back in a minute.
Keppler?