(grunting)
♪ ♪
(bed springs squeaking)
MAN:
Yeah. One of the gals fished him
out of the pool,
and the owner called me.
No one's touched the body since.
Where's your coroner?
Oh, couldn't get him
on the horn.
Probably out in some barn,
up to his elbows
in a cow's vagina.
Excuse me?
Oh. Yeah. Coroner's a part-time
gig here in Brime County.
He's a veterinarian.
That's his money gig.
Control,
this is CSI Sidle.
We're going to need
a coroner for that 419
out at the
Sugar Cane Ranch.
(overlapping chatter)
This is a strange crowd
for a cathouse.
MAN:
Hey, Sheriff!
Di-Did you hear about my wife?
Somebody shot my wife.
Yeah.
No, I'm telling ya,
they shot my wife.
Yeah. Okay. All right.
Okay. All right.
Settle down, Milton.
Settle down. Okay.
His wife died about
ten years ago of a stroke.
What is with all
the old-timers
out here tonight?
Oh, they live here.
Yeah, all over these hills.
Cheap rents,
abundant sunshine...
Life is good here
in Brime County.
Guy's name
is Lorenzo Morales.
"Happy" Morales.
I saw him fight LeRoi Steele
at the Sands a couple
of years ago.
Took a vicious beating.
Never touched the mat once.
Well, he's definitely
down for the count.
Listen. I want
to tell you something.
George and Doris Babinkian
own this place.
Run a real tight ship.
Never had a problem
in all the years
they've been here.
Just good people.
Pay their taxes,
provide employment,
Pillars of
the community.
You know, last month
actually, they had a...
Ned, you left this
in my room again.
Oh. Thanks. Thanks, Aimee.
She...
Look at this.
Gunshot wound?
Maybe.
He's got a contusion
over his right eye.
Could be associated
with the incident.
Well, he was a boxer.
Feels like bathwater.
It's got to be 90 degrees.
There's no way we're going
to get an accurate T.O.D.
Places like this
always keep their pools warm.
Encourages the girls
to swim topless.
It's good
for business.
So they tell me.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
♪ ♪
So when was the last time
you saw the deceased?
It was, like,
an hour ago,
when they took him
away on that cart.
(chuckling):
No, I...
you know, I meant the last time
you saw him alive.
I saw him around
noon yesterday.
Made him his
favorite meal. Meat.
Yeah. Mr. Babinkian...
Oh, you call me Binky.
Everybody call me Binky.
Okay, Binky, tell me about...
Lorenzo?
Everybody call him Happy.
Mm-hmm.
What? Does everybody
have a nickname around here?
Not me. I'm just Doris. Nut?
No, thank you, Doris.
So tell me about Happy.
BINKY:
Oh, Happy, Happy.
He was a fighter.
He was a born boxer.
He had speed,
he had skills,
he had heart,
he had... punch!
You know, four years ago, he was
a top-ranked middleweight.
That's right.
Yeah. But he... I don't know...
stumble into hard times.
Oh, yeah? What do you mean?
You know. Boompa, boompa
sniff, sniff. Like, party time.
And I... I mean,
I buy his contract,
I take him out here,
I give him a double-wide.
I build him a gym to train him,
and I train him.
I can make him a champion.
He did that.
You took a boxer
who likes to party
to a whorehouse to train?
Do you think that was smart?
Well, in hindsight,
maybe not so good idea.
So, anybody have a grudge
against Happy that you know of?
(mutters)
Everybody loved Happy.
Yes.
You...
I want you to catch
this person.
Find him, please.
And, you know...
anytime your boys need a break,
we have something here
we call a cop special.
You'll like it.
Any girl,
no charge
and one complimentary drink...
Oh, two!
Okay, two complimentary drinks.
And one appetizer
of your choice here at the bar.
Tonight, we have, uh...?
Baba ghanoush.
Yes.
Well, thank you.
Thank you very much.
You two really run
a mom-and-pop operation.
(laughing):
Oh, thank you.
And now, if you don't mind, I'd
like to talk to the hookers.
Hooking is what girls do
out on the street.
Here we prefer the term
"pleasure provider."
Ooh! Beer caps, candy wrappers,
cigarette butts, used condoms.
This is one
pool I am not
feeling a pressing need
to take a dip in.
Ugh. Me either.
This chair has
taken quite a beating,
and this cigarette
looks like
it was just left here
and burned out.
Hand me an evidence marker,
will you?
There is a stain on the filter.
Could be blood,
could be lipstick.
If this fellow was shot
through the throat,
and had a nasty lump
on the head,
could be how he ended up
face down in the pool.
Yeah, but there's no blood
by the pool.
If he was shot shot here,
you'd expect spatter.
Back-splash could
have washed it away
when he hit the water.
I kind of doubt it.
The bloodstains on his shirt
were straight up and down.
They had time to settle in.
I think
he was shot somewhere else,
and just got dumped in here.
Well, it sounds like we need
to play...
"Find the Bullet."
All right. Open up, please.
Honey, come see me later.
I can show you a better way
to get DNA.
(women laughing)
BRASS:
So did you see Lorenzo
"Happy" Morales last night?
Uh-uh.
No.
I don't think so.
No?
No.
Mm... Mm-mm.
Did you hear any gunshots?
Any shouting? Anything unusual?
No.
So what did you do last night?
A guy came in, and he brought
his 18-year-old son,
and I made him a man.
I popped his man cherry.
Oh, the usual stuff.
I had a pretty good night.
I tided a guy.
That's it?
I had a cold,
so I stayed in my room
and I read Pride and Prejudice.
(chuckles)
I have a big fat crush
on Mr. Darcy.
I had two... no, three dates.
Then I hung around the bar
and watched TV.
So, what did you think of Happy?
He was fine.
Actually, he was kind of...
Cute.
And he was...
I mean, I didn't
have nothing against him.
Let me make something
clear for you.
This is a homicide
investigation.
If you're lying to me,
even a little bit,
I'm going to come down on you
like a load of bricks.
So let me
ask you again.
What did you think of Happy?
He was messed up, man.
He took pills to get wood,
then he couldn't even finish.
Plus, he had the windy problem.
What does that mean?
He talked too much?
No. He passed gas too much.
He smelled really bad.
I mean, I know
you're not supposed
to be sensitive
in this line of work...
But that guy
could blister paint.
Wow.
What pissed me off,
he started coming around,
and he just stopped
paying for it.
He thought he could get anything
and everything for free.
So, did Doris and Binky
have a problem with this?
Binky had a big problem
with it.
You keep your hands
off my girls.
Okay?
Hey, this is a whorehouse.
That's what they're here for.
You lazy, fat bum.
Why you don't make yourself
useful around here, eh?
Look at this piece of falling
apart crap of a chair.
You pick up a tool
and fix it!
All right?
(burps)
Doris, uh... she had
a little thing for Mr. Happy,
if you know what I mean.
Did he reciprocate?
What?
Was it a
one-way thing
or a two-way thing?
I don't know what you're saying.
Did Binky know?
I don't know.
May I?
Thank you.
Mm-hmm.
These monitors
are live-feed only?
Nothing taped?
Absolutely not.
If we did that,
and word got out,
we'd be out of business
in about a week.
But I see that the rooms
are wired for sound as well.
Yeah. Well, that's
for the girls' protection.
And to make sure that
they don't short you
on their financial
transactions?
I just spot-check
from time to time.
I trust my girls.
Did you hear
anything unusual last night?
Believe me,
if I had heard anything,
you'd have known
about it already.
I want to know
what happened to that poor boy
just as much...
just as as much as anybody.
You cared about him.
Happy was a child
in a man's body, you know?
He had no family.
He had nobody.
He was scared.
His big comeback
was going nowhere.
He was finished,
and he knew it.
Happy knew it. Binky knew it.
Everybody knew it.
25 people here last
night, and nobody
sees anything.
Nice hat, honey.
So you've been to a place
like this before?
I worked a murder-suicide
at the Naughty Kitty once.
No, no, come on.
You know what I mean.
As a customer? No.
You never paid for sex?
I have not.
I find the whole idea
very... bleak.
Really?
How come?
Sex should provide
the opportunity
for human connection,
but paid sex does
the opposite of that.
To me, sex without love
is pointless.
It makes you sad.
Well, I'm pretty sure
I don't make you sad.
No. You make me happy.
Methaqualone...
benzodiazepine; antidepressants.
Anabolic steroids,
beta blockers,
high-blood-pressure meds,
Prevalis.
There's no prescription labels.
It's all written in Spanish.
Looks like a lot of this stuff
came from south of the border.
Blood drops on the floor.
Smears on the furniture
and the walls.
This might be where
they ran the opening bell.
ROBBINS:
Boxers all end up
the same,
beaten, broken
and forgotten.
BROWN:
Hmm, yeah, Joe Louis,
George Foreman,
Ali, Marciano,
Frazier, Tyson.
Who are those guys?
Whoa.
Genitals are distended
and patchy and covered
with large red welts.
Testicles are swollen,
roughly three times
the average size.
Scrotum is filled
with fluid.
It's consistent
with cardio edema or an STD.
Maybe an infection of some kind.
Either that or this guy's got
the world's ugliest Johnson.
Okay, I'll just slice
the scrotal sack
and draw out
a fluid sample.
Oh, Doc, could you wait
till I leave? Thanks.
This guy's got a nasty crack
on his head.
Yeah. Probably a fracture.
Wouldn't surprise me
if there was a hematoma
to go along with it.
There's linear markings
on the contusion.
(device beeps)
BROWN:
Looks like letters of some kind.
What is that?
I think it's backwards.
I-N-C-H.
BINKY:
Please, listen.
You make me close down my
doors, cop cars in front!
It's not good
for the business.
I know a man die here,
but dead is dead.
I lose my shirt.
Are the girls allowed
to keep any weapons
in the room
for self-defense?
No weapons.
Strictly forbidden.
Then you won't mind
if I check for myself, right?
What do you mean,
check for yourself?
How long will
this take?
As long as it takes.
(mocking):
Your mother sleep
with Azerbaijani.
(zapping)
BRASS:
Dreama Little.
Is that your real name?
♪ Stars shining
bright above you ♪
♪ Night breezes
seem to whisper "I love you" ♪
♪ Birds singing in
the sycamore tree ♪
♪ Dream a little dream of me. ♪
Do I look
like Paula Abdul to you?
My daddy gave me that name
'cause he liked that song.
All right.
Happy was hit
in the head with a crowbar
we found in your room.
You wiped off your fingerprints,
but you didn't wipe off
his blood from the grooves.
He was always...
coming up to my room,
getting all up on me.
He liked them
other girls,
but he was obsessed with me.
Look, look what he did.
He punched me right there
in the ribs
just for fun.
Stupid. Then he flipped me over
and then he started punching me
back here.
Every night, drunk, crazy,
messed up.
Whether he could get it up
or not.
Last night I was just about
to take my week off to bleed,
and I wasn't in the mood.
No!
(gasps)
grunts)
So yeah...
(groans)
...I hit him.
So what?
He deserved it.
It didn't even drop him.
He just wandered off.
I'm going to let you in
on a little secret.
You don't get to decide
whether you kill somebody
or not.
I just explained to you...
You whacked him on the side
of the head with a crowbar.
I know, but I didn't...
He came over...
That's assault
with a deadly weapon.
It doesn't matter whether
he wandered off or not.
He's bleeding from the brain.
If he dies later on,
that's murder on you.
I killed him?
You know, a jury may take into
account the fact that you
were abused,
and I hope they do.
But you're not gonna
just walk out of here.
(sobbing)
I killed him!
You know, sometimes
it helps
to write it down.
Okay.
(phone rings)
Yes.
I understand you're going
to be talking
to the girl
who crowbarred the boxer.
(whispering):
Well, yes, Doctor,
I'm actually with her right now.
Yeah, well, actually
I'm with him right now,
and that blow to the head
didn't do him much good,
but it's definitely
not what killed him.
The blow to the forehead
caused bruising
to the right frontal lobe.
It's significant,
but definitely
sub-lethal by itself.
And what are those gray spots?
Just old scar tissue.
See it on boxers
all the time.
It's impossible to know
what kind of brain damage
the guy was already living with.
So what killed him?
In addition to
the brain trauma
and the holes in his throat,
he has needle marks.
on his thighs,
arms and buttocks.
I don't know for certain
what he was shooting up.
Still waiting for tox.
Well, he was found floating
facedown in a pool,
so let's start with the obvious.
Any evidence of drowning?
His lungs were partially filled
with blood and water.
However, the neck
wound transected
the trachea below
the epiglottis.
So the air
and the water
could have entered
passively postmortem.
Well, the entry and the exit
are the same size, but...
it doesn't look like
a bullet wound to me.
No, it seems more like a
straight-through puncture.
The bruising here
is more developed
than here.
At this point, all
I can say for sure
is the neck wound occurred
before the blow to the head.
(distant police radio
transmission)
Okay.
Hey.
Catherine said we might not be
looking for a bullet anymore.
She happen to say
what we are looking for?
Not a bullet.
Well, it looks like we have
blood drops
heading towards Happy's trailer.
Mm-hmm.
MILTON:
Hey!
You kids, you caught your,
caught your guy?
No, sir.
You going to catch him?
We certainly hope so.
Well,
think this might be
of some help?
I told you,
somebody shot my wife.
Come in. I'll show you.
There is what appears
to be blood
on the shaft.
I told 'em.
I told 'em,
but would they listen?
No, no,
just an old man
running off at the mouth.
Did you see this happen?
No. Woke up
this morning and found it
like that.
I shot an arrow into the air,
and it fell to Earth
I know not where.
Oh, so swiftly it flew,
the sight could not follow it
in its flight.
Long, long...
Sir.
That's,
that's really sweet.
That's Longfellow.
(chuckling):
What do you kids know
about poetry?
Nick, arrow came in
through that window.
Yeah.
Even an idiot could see that.
♪ ♪
(whooshing)
Hey, Sara.
Found another arrow
shot in the ground
near that old tool shed.
Maybe the shooter got nervous.
Well, to work
in a brothel
you're required to register
your fingerprints, so...
I'm almost done here.
I'll catch up.
Okay.
I'll let you know
if we get lucky.
A long time afterward,
in an oak
I found the arrow,
still unbroke
And the song, from
beginning to end,
I found again in the heart
of a friend.
Keep the faith, Milton.
(beeps)
(beeping)
Connor.
Honey, are you asleep?
Hello, Doris.
Are you drunk?
No.
Not too much.
What's up, dude?
Mr. Foster, we're going to need
to talk to you
down at the police station.
Okay?
Okey-doke.
(mutters)
CONNOR:
Okay...
(voice breaking):
so I shot Happy.
I hated that guy.
But it was self-defense.
Self-defense,
really? How?
I myself was trying
to defend the girls.
They needed me to protect them.
They depended me on that.
So that's what I done.
(whispering):
This guy was a monster!
(shrieks)
(gasping, panting)
He was all puffed up...
like some big-ass...
lizard monster guy.
(grunts)
(wheezing, gasping breaths)
(groans)
(wheezing,
gasping breaths)
(whimpering)
(sighs)
So this is your idea
of an assassination attempt?
This is your Lee Harvey?
You hide behind a
tool shed and shoot him
with a crossbow, which we all
know you own-- is that it?
Yeah, but he wouldn't die.
And I'm glad he did.
And anyway,
I wasn't the one
that killed him.
(whispering):
He just...
kept coming at me.
He wouldn't lie down.
Right.
It was horrible.
Connor.
You shot a guy in the neck,
and you don't think
you killed him?
Uh-huh.
Well, how do you know
you didn't kill him?
How do you know he didn't
stagger off somewhere and...
you know, drop dead
in the pool?
I'm liking you
for Happy's murder.
I'm liking you a lot.
But I didn't kill him!
And I'd do it again
if I had a chance!
(whispering):
I killed him?
(quietly):
Yeah.
I killed him?
I killed him!
(sobs)
(phone rings)
(sobbing quietly)
Are you gonna get that?
Yeah.
Listen, I just got a confession
from the crossbow guy,
so we're all set.
Well, then I am sorry
to ruin your day,
but I certainly appreciate
the company.
Your guy might be the shooter...
but he's not the killer.
(crying)
He-he's not...
What do you mean?
I mean...
It's not him.
(loud sobbing)
ROBBINS:
Happy was on the verge
of anaphylactic shock.
His trachea was
almost completely blocked.
And then he got shot.
The arrow reopened his airway,
in essence gave him
an emergency tracheotomy.
So the guy took an arrow
through the throat,
and it prolonged
his life?
Apparently.
And what are the odds of it
not hitting a major artery?
Whatever comes
right before zero.
So C.O.D. is anaphylactic shock?
Not entirely.
The epiglottal tissues
are only slightly swollen,
which suggests
the anaphylaxis
had enough time
to subside.
(clears throat)
Not now, David.
I'm sorry,
but Happy's antigen assay
came back.
The anaphylaxis was a reaction
to shellfish.
I didn't find any seafood in
his stomach or small intestine.
Just six
and a half pounds
of undigested red meat.
Well, that explains
the flatulence.
And nothing else.
HODGES:
Anything?
SANDERS:
No shellfish yet,
but plenty of used condoms,
as well as antifungal powder,
vaginal lubricant, hair balls,
toenail clippings,
hemorrhoid cream
and lice-killing shampoo.
Somehow, the whole
brothel mystique
is wearing thin.
I found a couple
of syringes, too.
I thought these girls were
supposed to be drug-free.
Well, maybe there's a legitimate
medical reason for that.
Yeah. That's why it was stuffed
inside of a tampon applicator.
SANDERS:
You know,
I kind of feel bad
for these girls.
Don't feel too bad.
They have health
benefits, good pay.
Women get
regular checkups.
The industry is
well-regulated,
as opposed to picking
a hooker up off the street.
Does she have a disease?
Multiple diseases?
Is she crazy?
Is she gonna roll you?
Where do you go?
Do you do it in your car?
Behind a building?
Down a dark alley?
So you drive around,
scared out of your mind.
You finally get the nerve up,
pick one you like,
call her over,
she gets in-- next
thing you know,
you're down on the pavement,
cuffed,
'cause she's an undercover cop,
but luckily, you're three months
shy of your 18th birthday,
so when you call your mom
to come get you,
it doesn't go
on my permanent record.
Okay.
(like a carny):
We've got a winnah!
(beeping)
GRISSOM:
The prints on the shrimp tails
all came back
to George Babinkian,
but whoever
was eating the shrimp
was wearing lavender lipstick--
so I'm guessing
it wasn't Binky.
BRASS:
Well, that's Doris's color.
Doc was bothered there
was no sign of shellfish
in Happy's digestive tracts,
so he went back and checked
the genital area--
there are
clear indications
that the point of entry
of the anaphylaxis...
was through
the urethra.
Oh...
Yeah.
You know, when I
talked to the girls,
they told me that
Doris and Happy had a thang.
You add Binky into the mix,
and that is one nasty little
love triangle.
So, are we making progress?
Well, actually, it's a...
it's a very complicated case.
We were hoping maybe you'd
help us out a little.
Well, of course,
gentlemen, anything.
Well, apparently,
Happy was in the midst
of a life-threatening
anaphylactic collapse.
Do you know
what that means?
Um....
It's a very heavy
allergy attack...
to shellfish.
But the strange thing is,
the allergen, it seems,
was introduced
into Happy's system
through oral-genital contact.
I have no idea what
you're talking about now.
(clears throat)
DINKY:
Now...
(seething breaths)
Uh... gentlemen,
she's very hot my wife.
She was very fond of...
of this boxer.
Apparently.
Will you excuse us?
I would like to... comfort
and talk to my wife.
Well, no,
wait a minute, wait a minute.
No. I think it'll be all right.
Go ahead.
Thank you, thank you.
Take your time.
What was that about?
These rooms are all wired
for sound.
We can't use this as evidence.
They have no expectation
of privacy in those rooms.
Binky and Doris are
the ones who wired them,
and they listen to their
clients all the time.
DORIS:
That's why you did it.
That's why you
fed me the shrimp.
I feed you shrimps
because I love you.
And you love shrimp, no?
Don't play dumb
with me, George.
Somehow you figured out
that Happy was allergic.
Oh, you crazy talk, crazy.
No, it's all
clear to me now.
How long have you known?
Known about what?
About me
and Happy.
You were doing boxer?
DORIS:
Screw you, George.
You know damn well I was.
I don't care of you have
your flingy-flingys.
We're living
in America, no?
I mean everybody's
entitled
to pursuit of happy.
What's done is done, Doris.
He was turning
into big drag.
He's dead now.
May God take his soul
and rest.
You're setting me up, George.
I...
Now don't you shush me, George.
You know what?
You've pulled some really
out-to-lunch crap in your life,
George, but this...
is...
GEORGE:
What you just said...
I didn't mean it.
That was just
crazy talk.
Yeah.
I mean, nobody
would ever possibly
believe, not for a single
solitary moment,
I mean not for a single
that you, that I,
that Happy...
Oh, come here,
baby, baby, come.
Oh. I love you.
I love you.
(sobbing):
I love you, too.
And I love you both.
Let's go.
You're under arrest.
GRISSOM:
Binky used Doris
to induce Happy's allergic
reaction to shrimp
as a sort of test
her fidelity...
And Happy ends up dead.
Not bad.
Who's Brass going to charge?
Don't bother.
You can't charge either one.
ROBBINS:
On secondary examination
of the body,
I noticed a patch of necrotic
skin on the right calf.
Looked like a bite
of some kind.
So I sent blood off for
prothrombin
time and blood venom ratio.
It came back positive
for snake venom.
Smashed with a crowbar,
shot by a crossbow,
poisoned by shrimp
and now bitten by a snake?
Sort of-- Happy had Western
Diamondback Rattlesnake
venom in his system--
the real deal--
but it wasn't from a bite.
I histo-ed the wound and
checked the cross-section.
Snake bite punctures
are typically curved...
Yeah, these are straight.
And one's deeper
than the other.
Look like needle marks.
As you can see, the
tissue around the wound
was pretty badly
degraded.
Greg found this
in the trash
of one of the girls' rooms.
Which girl?
BRASS:
So I think you'll be
happy to know
that your little crowbar stunt
didn't kill Happy.
Really?
Really.
Oh, that's great.
That's like I told you.
So can I go now?
Well, don't you even
want to know how he died?
Well... yeah, okay.
You know, it was
the damnedest thing.
He had snake venom
in his system.
Huh.
A snakebite.
Isn't that a hoot?
Yeah, that's just
what it is-- a hoot.
You know, there's a bunch
of those rattlers
all up over those hills.
I bet he just...
Oh, he wasn't bitten.
No, he was injected.
Yeah. Somebody
took a syringe full
of snake venom
and injected it in his leg.
I don't know nothing about that.
Oh, we found
the syringe with
the venom in it
and your DNA on it in the tube
you hid it in.
I mean, you might
have walked on the crowbar
thing, but this is premeditated.
And that can be very,
very bad for you.
Look, I know that you
and Connor did this together.
He's already going down
for the crossbow shot.
That's probably why
he gave you up.
He-he blamed...
he blamed it on me?
He said that you cooked up
the whole thing
from top to bottom.
Mm...
Connor would never say that.
He was in love with me.
Are you saying that faking
the snakebite was his idea?
No.
Connor ain't that smart.
It was my idea.
(rattling)
My daddy was a serpent-handling
preacher.
My people all had
the holy fire.
I had it, too,
but mine came from below.
I caught and milked
that rattler.
CONNOR:
Dreama said she did it?
By herself?
That's right.
You're going to walk out
of here a free man.
And she's going to jail,
and you can visit her
every third Thursday
until she's a very old lady.
Is that the way
you want it to be?
No.
Well, that's the way
it's going to be.
Unless you can convince me
she's lying
just to save your sorry ass.
That ain't the way
it went down.
Dreama thought it up,
but I'm the one who stuck it in.
(mouthing)
HAPPY:
Come on, honey, stop...
DREAMA:
That's okay. Shh.
Go back sleep.
Later, I'll get
you later.
Okay?
It's okay.
Two holes.
Oh.
CONNOR:
And then I went
and I dumped his body
into the culvert.
Me, by myself.
Right now the D.A.'s not sure
who he's going to charge.
What he needs from us
is the most accurate
timeline we can provide.
Well, according
to Tox, the hemolytic
component of the venom
had time to break down tissue,
which means that it had to have
been in his system
at least a few hours.
So the fake snakebite
is around 1:00.
Happy's down... but not out.
Well, that gets Dreama
and Connor
for attempted murder
with conspiracy to commit.
And earlier that night,
Binky fed Doris
some jumbo tiger shrimp,
knowing that she'd eventually
find Happy for round two.
Dreama!
Oye, mamita.
I don't feel too good.
Come here, baby.
I know what you need.
I'm going to make you
feel all better.
Come to Doris, baby.
Doris administers
some very special first aid...
and Happy's little soldier
swells to battalion size.
Babinkian knew about
that shellfish allergy--
that's intent, right?
In any event, Binky and Doris
lawyered up.
They're sticking together.
How romantic.
So, now Happy is not so happy,
because he'd heading into
anaphylactic shock.
GRISSOM:
According to Narco, Happy had
epinephrine in his trailer,
which is probably what he was
trying to get to
in round two.
STOKES:
That's assault
with a deadly weapon.
GRISSOM:
But not necessarily murder.
So the field tracheotomy
buys un-Happy enough time
to get the epi.
(gasps)
At this point, you'd think he
would've just called it a night.
Watched a little TV,
hit the sack,
but no.
Dreama.
I'm going to get you,
you little bitch.
Which brings us to round four.
(groans)
The T.K.O.
You do know what a good
defense attorney
is going to say to all this,
don't you?
What?
The lawn chair did it.