(sirens blaring)
Hank Connors, Las Vegas Police.
Come out with your hands
above your head.
Come out slowly.
(automatic gunfire)
(squealing)
(screams)
Officer down!
Go back where you came from!
You're not taking me!
(screams)
OFFICER:
Circle the perimeter.
OFFICER 2:
Move in, three-two.
(Connors panting heavily)
(indistinct radio
communication)
♪ ♪
MREs, automatic
weapons, ammo, water--
this guy Connors was ready
for the end of days.
Which, in his case, was today.
Bomb squad find any booby traps?
No, he liked it mano a mano.
Any sign of Chyna De Vere?
Not yet.
(snorting)
You know, there's
some food,
you just shouldn't see
where it comes from.
Did you know that pigs
are very intelligent animals,
right behind chimps,
dolphins and elephants?
Ahead of dogs?
And certain
politicians.
(chuckles)
I don't see Connors'
truck anywhere.
Let's look in the barn.
(meowing)
There's the truck.
If this is Chyna De Vere's
blood, we're getting warmer.
(camera clicking)
Looks like he had a
hobby-- stuffed animals.
Hey, Warrick.
Yeah?
I feel like Marco Polo.
Why's that?
I just discovered Chyna.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me
who are you, you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
This is a career first.
BROWN:
A little tip for you:
The new Mrs. Phillips
doesn't need to hear about this.
Are you kidding me?
She'll want to hear
every detail.
Why do you think
I married her?
STOKES:
Come on, pretty girl,
come on.
(pigs squealing)
Come on.
Hi.
Hey.
What are you doing?
Well, I read about
this farmer in Canada
who killed a bunch of women
and fed them to his pigs.
Oh.
Yeah, their
health department
had to put out a
bulletin that said,
"Warning: your pork may be
contaminated with human."
I'm so glad I'm a vegetarian.
(pig snorting)
Get through there!
Well, no one has seen or heard
from the victim's husband,
so... I kind of figured
he may have been dessert.
I think the fat one likes you.
They always do.
SANDERS:
We went to Connors' ranch
because a week ago,
Chyna De Vere went missing.
She just separated from
her husband, got her own place.
This is a large section
of her living room carpet--
wet to the touch,
pheno confirmed a blood pool.
Well, it's certainly enough
blood to suggest foul play.
There were
also traces of
perchloroethylene, phosphates,
alcohol, ethers
and sodium
hypocholorite.
Used a steam cleaner.
Would've denatured
any DNA.
Yeah, we checked all the local
places that rent them.
Connors' name
didn't come up.
How about the husband's?
Nope.
And he's still missing.
So what's this?
That is a single,
distinct blood drop--
not from the victim,
not from the husband.
They didn't clean
the whole carpet.
Unknown female.
We also found
soil trace,
identified as scheelite,
a tungsten ore.
Apparently,
Connors' ranch
is near old tungsten mines
by McCade.
How is Connors, this pig farmer,
connected to the victim?
Oh, he's in kind of a club
with the victim's husband.
Kind of a club?
♪ ♪
Want me to take the living room?
Looks like Armageddon came
on a Thursday.
Do you believe that intelligent
life exists on other planets?
I'm not sure there's
intelligent life on this planet.
I was just in the barn.
I'll get started.
Ms. Turner.
I already went
through this a week ago.
You know, you're right.
But let's go through it again.
Chyna De Vere is dead.
And her remains were found
on your boyfriend's ranch.
Yeah, not my boyfriend--
my friend.
And furthermore,
I never knew Chyna De Vere.
She wasn't a member
of your club?
No.
If she was, I would have
known her, and I didn't.
Her husband was.
And he's MIA.
You know, the club's getting
smaller and smaller
by the minute.
This morning, Hank Connors died.
When we went up there
to arrest your friend,
he shot himself.
And I'm getting
the feeling
that you're going to be
missing a meeting, too.
Look, Shannon, you
alibied a killer.
You're already an accessory
to one murder.
If Hank Connors
killed Chyna's husband, too...
Oh.
Oh, is that
what you think happened?
Tell me where he is.
Hmm?
You know, this can work
in your favor with the D.A.
Oh, you know what?
I'm not really
worried about that.
(switch clicks,
projector whirrs)
Adam and Eve were not only
the first humans on the Earth,
they were bait...
for intelligent life forms
elsewhere in the cosmos,
refugees from planets that could
no longer sustain them.
But why Earth?
Deoxyribonucleic acid.
DNA.
The blueprint of human life
is the key to their survival.
Without it, they will perish.
(door opens)
Hi, Ms. Turner.
My name's Greg Sanders;
I'm with the crime lab.
I have a warrant to take
a sample of your DNA.
You're not touching me.
Well, ma'am,
this is standard
procedure.
I know who you are.
I'm just going to swab
the inside of...
Hey! Not!
OFFICER:
Calm down.
Get off of me!
Calm down, ma'am.
All of you,
Calm down.
get away from me!
Get him away from...!
Calm down.
No!
Let's try this again.
(screams)
Let go of his hand!
Let go of his hand, ma'am.
That bitch bit me.
I got my sample.
MAN (on film):
The first encounters
between humans
and extraterrestrials took place
over a hundred thousand years
ago in Atlantis,
and in its sister civilization
in the Pacific, Lemuria.
Ancient civilizations
on every continent
have recorded evidence
of these encounters.
These visitors
were highly advanced
and did not appear
in human form.
Now, the Mayans
called them Chanes--
people of the serpents--
and in Hebrew legend,
the snake represented knowledge.
Of course it did.
It was not human.
Not of this Earth.
Shannon sure has
a lot of books.
UFO's, alien abduction...
Chyna was a dealer
at the Palermo.
Looks like Shannon was a player.
Gold level.
Yeah, tell me they never met.
We'll check
the Palermo security.
Reptiles...
UFOs...
BRASS:
Xena, Warrior Princess.
MAN (on film):
History is replete
with stories of the heroic
destruction of serpents.
Perseus and Medusa,
St. George and the Dragon,
St. Patrick
and the Snakes of Ireland.
But these are
not merely legends...
What is this?
I think their UFO club is based
on the teachings of this guy.
...and the natural form of these
invaders is not human.
They are described
in ancient accounts
as serpents and dragons.
And man's weapon against them
is the sword.
Cut off the tail,
the serpent lives.
Cut off its head, and it dies.
So Connors cut off her head
because he thought she was
a serpent from outer space?
BRASS:
Catherine...
check this out.
Chyna De Vere's
husband Preston.
What's Shannon
doing with him?
"Chillin' in Cabo."
(cat meowing)
BRASS:
Aww.
Well, while Mommy's
in custody,
I guess the kitty's hungry;
I'll call Animal Control.
Oh, Jim...
Well, hello, Xena.
(splashing, squishing)
(drill whirring)
Oh, boy.
Look what he used
on the incision.
Duct tape?
Yeah, he used it
to close up
the laceration from
a sharp force perimortem wound.
Corresponds to the indentation
in the skull.
Could that be the fatal wound?
Give me the rest of the body
and I can tell you.
Nick's working on it.
Almost three inches,
smooth-edge blade;
you know, Catherine found--
Yeah, I heard.
A sword-- everyone's talking
about this one.
Why would anybody want
to taxidermy a human head?
I'm still working on the "how."
That, I can tell you.
Mounted one myself.
A deer-- Dad was a hunter.
First, our guy
had to separate
the head from the body.
For that, he used
a serrated-edge knife.
Dad used a carving knife, same
one we used at Thanksgiving.
When mom found out,
she almost killed
him with it.
Heartwarming.
Yeah, so then...
he had to flesh the skin away
from the underlying muscle.
Next, he would've stretched
the skin out on a board,
rubbed it with rock salt...
...then waited two days.
Then he tanned the skin
to preserve it,
hydrated it with a borax
and water solution
to keep the bugs off.
Next, he cleaned the skull,
filled the imperfections
with clay, sawdust,
anything at hand.
Popped in two glass eyes,
and then...
And he's got the best-looking
wall mount the neighborhood.
We're going to need to
process that toolmark.
Yeah, I'll get it
over to CSI.
(playful shuddering):
Oh... nice sword.
Mm-hmm!
I dated a guy on
the fencing team.
His thighs
were incredible.
Did you want to
show me something?
Yes, the, uh, tip
has been wiped clean.
Negative for blood.
But I did find
a couple of partials
on the blade
just above the hilt.
Okay.
And a couple of full prints
on the handle.
STOKES:
The femur measures
461 millimeters.
Gives us a height
for a white female of 5'6".
Exactly Chyna's height.
How about for a male?
5'7".
Preston De Vere
is too tall.
Did you measure
the head of the femur?
No, sir, I was
just about to.
41 point s...
point five millimeters.
It's a female.
You want my theory?
This little piggy
went to market.
stayed home.
This little piggy had Chyna.
Yeah.
Human teeth aren't strong enough
to leave these marks.
And it is consistent
with Connors
chopping off her head
and tossing his "girls" a bone.
Okay... go back to the ranch.
See if you can find
the rest of her.
WILLOWS:
Hey, Greg.
You up for a bite?
(forced laughter)
(pounds counter)
(continues laughing)
No.
I am on antibiotics,
I had a tetanus shot--
I'm having a pretty bad year.
Oh, it's only a bad year
if you do a bad job, Greg.
You're having a great year.
I got that gel ready for you.
♪ ♪
Voilà!
We have our weapon?
Yeah, and a mounted human head,
a suicidal pig farmer,
a missing husband,
and a bunch of UFO believers.
What could be next?
Wendy got results
back on the blood
from Connors' workbench
in the pickup truck.
It's Chyna De Vere.
Good. Come here,
take a look at this.
Hey, isn't that, uh...?
Yeah.
You can see
Dick Cheney, Al Gore,
all nine
Supreme Court Justices
shape-shift into Reptilians.
Did you know that,
for thousands of years,
creatures from the constellation
Draco have been mating
with humans to form
a super-race that includes
43 U.S. presidents,
most members of Congress,
and the entire
British royal family?
Hey, did Shannon Turner
have a cat?
Yeah.
So did Hank Connors.
See, it figures.
Cats are a natural enemy
of reptiles.
I'll keep that in mind.
The sword I found
at Shannon Turner's
made the tool marks
on the skull.
Shannon's prints were
all over the handle.
And the partials on the blade,
above the hilt--
Chyna De Vere's.
She tried to defend herself.
Did Wendy find anything on that
drop of blood on the carpet?
Came back to Shannon.
Yeah, but Brass
interviewed her last week.
She didn't have
any visible cuts.
Warrick?
Come at me with a sword.
All right, so I push
back hard enough...
bang you on the nose.
Brass wouldn't have seen that.
But what I don't understand is
if Shannon Turner
and Hank Connors
really believed
in a Reptilian conspiracy
and they felt threatened
by the political establishment,
why kill a blackjack dealer?
BROWN:
Hey, Nick!
Yeah?
I got something
over here.
Man, that looks human.
(shutter clicks)
(blows)
"To Chyna,
Love, Preston."
"To Preston, Love, Chyna."
Till death do us part.
JOHNSON:
According to the Palermo,
Shannon Turner joined
the Player's Club last month.
Whenever a player uses a
club card at a table game,
the floor man writes down
what game you played,
where you sat,
what time you started,
time you quit.
Then they estimate your average
bet, win-loss ratios...
No wonder she believed
in conspiracies.
Well, this is the first time
Shannon used her card.
SIDLE:
And the dealer
is Chyna.
(computer beeps)
JOHNSON:
A week later.
By now, she's a regular.
SIDLE:
Looks like they're
best friends.
(taps key, computer whirs)
Two weeks ago.
SIDLE:
Table's full.
She's waiting
for a seat.
Shannon only gambled
at Chyna's table.
Maybe Chyna was her lucky charm.
That depends
on how you define luck.
SIDLE:
She never walked
away a winner.
Maybe she blamed Chyna
for her losses.
She's too friendly.
I think
she was gaining her trust.
Stalking her.
Well, it's Las Vegas.
It's not a crime
to play blackjack.
You're right,
it's Las Vegas.
But it is a crime to
lie to the police.
We found your blood
in Chyna's apartment.
Then it was planted.
By whom?
How should I know?
Maybe you planted it.
Look...
...you killed Chyna,
and you got Connors
to help you move the body.
And Connors killed Preston,
because he was obsessed with you
and wanted
to eliminate the competition.
You lied about knowing Chyna,
you going to lie
about this, too?
Preston can't be killed.
His cells don't die.
He's over 4,000 years old.
Oh, 4,000.
The new 50.
You just don't know the truth
when you hear it.
Preston is a great man.
He has the wisdom of the ages.
Beyond your capacity
to understand.
Ms. Turner...
...was Chyna a Reptilian?
Who is this?
The Reptilian Athena.
Is that Chyna De Vere?
(papers rustling)
Tell me about this one.
That's the Protector of Mankind.
Is that you?
(slurping)
Hmm?
Did you slay
the Reptilian Athena?
I did what I had to do.
I have to kill you.
What?!
(blade rings)
(grunting)
It's not like
there's nothing at stake here.
Just the survival
of the human race.
Yeah, I'm just
a phone booth away
from changing into my tights
and saving the world.
(computer beeps)
Hey, Warrick,
I got something.
I was scanning
the casino footage
from the day
Chyna disappeared.
And she had a visitor.
Her husband.
She doesn't look so happy
to see him.
Well, we don't need words
to get that.
JOHNSON:
"Give me your ring.
"I really, really
hate you.
Our marriage
is over."
BROWN:
Well, that means
she was killed before she had
a chance to change her clothes.
That would explain why
we found both rings
in the ashes.
But it doesn't explain
what happened to him.
(camera clicking)
I found it embedded in this.
T-9 vertebra.
But that means
the bullet had to pass
through at least
one vital organ.
Yeah, heart, lung,
and then the dome of the liver.
That's your C.O.D.
And you're sure
these are Chyna De Vere's bones.
Yeah, pelvis is female.
No duplicate bones.
The femur's the same length
as the one
the pigs were chomping on.
It's her.
Okay. Well, we'll run this
against Connors' guns.
(people screaming)
(roaring)
(crowd screaming)
(monster roaring)
I always feel sorry
for the monster.
Then you better turn it off
before they use
the Oxygen Destroyer on him.
(monster roaring)
Hey, Bruno,
come on!
(monster roaring on TV)
GRISSOM:
I don't know why
I find it so difficult
to express my feelings to you.
Even though we're far apart,
I can see you as vividly
as if you were here with me.
I said I'll miss you,
and I do.
GRISSOM:
As Shakespeare more ably wrote
my sentiment in Sonnet 47,
"Thyself away art present
still with me;
"For thou not farther
than my thoughts canst move,
"and I am still with them,
"and they with thee.
"Or, if they sleep,
"thy picture in my sight
awakes my heart
to heart's and eye's delight."
BROWN:
Fire in the hole!
(gunshot)
You're supposed
to let me get these things on.
Hey, you were
supposed to be ready.
I don't know, man.
Maybe it would have
worked out
if Tina was someone
who did what we did.
At least
she'd understand the hours.
Oh, I don't know.
I don't think
it's a good idea
to date somebody
you work with.
You never really
get away from
work or them the way
you need to, you know?
You mean, like me
and you, baby?
Yeah, exactly, honey.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah, it looks like
the bullet that killed her came
from Connors' Walther PPK.
(crying)
(gunshot)
Captain Brass?
Jim.
Joe Vasquez.
How you doing, Joe?
I got a call from
a passing motorist.
Naked guy running
around in the desert.
That may not be so
strange where you work,
but out here, it
gets our attention.
I recognized him
from the news.
Thanks a lot, Joe.
Preston De Vere?
Very glad to be back home.
What are you doing
out here, Preston?
I was a captive,
held against my will.
From what the Sheriff tells me,
I've been gone over a week.
Feels like just seconds.
Can you describe these people
to me?
Well, yes,
but you won't believe me.
Try me.
They were very tall...
with Reptilian features;
large, almond-shaped, red eyes.
Hey, what's happening,
Lizard King?
I appreciate your skepticism.
I anticipated it.
Insight begins
with asking the right questions.
Okay, then,
when exactly were you abducted?
Nine days ago.
Oh, so you were abducted
before your wife was missing.
What do you mean Chyna
is missing?
What happened to her?
What are you trying to tell me?
You don't know
your wife is dead?
That was callous of you.
Unnecessarily cruel.
I had no idea.
(sobbing)
That sweet girl...
Stop the crocodile tears.
Come on.
Preston.
If she was so sweet,
what were you doing chillin'
in Cabo with Shannon Turner?
Are you suggesting
that was romantic?
Well, you got your pictures
on the coffee mug.
That's romantic to me.
You better come up
with an alibi--
on planet Earth--
of where you were
the night your wife was killed.
That's easy.
There's a woman, and it is
romantic, very romantic.
I was with her
when they took me.
Her name is Clarissa Niles.
MAN:
We are victims...
...and no one is listening
to us.
We're powerless
against what's going on.
We're not crazy.
If you look at who has had
contact, we're airline pilots,
professionals,
teachers, scientists.
I don't know how to get
the truth out, but we have to.
Has anyone talked to Shannon
in the last couple of days?
They've got her.
It's like we're witnessing
some form of mass hallucination.
You know,
they think
the cops are part of this
Reptilian conspiracy as well.
That's why Shannon
attacked Greg.
And why Hank Connors
shot himself.
Sorry to interrupt.
Don't make eye
contact with them.
Please, we
come in peace.
Which one of you is
Clarissa Niles?
(whispering):
Don't.
It's all right.
I'm not afraid.
SANDERS:
Got a warrant to tow in
Clarissa Niles' car.
Blue fluorescence is one of
the properties of scheelite.
Which was found in the soil
at Hank Connors' ranch.
And Preston beamed down
in the same area.
Have you looked inside yet?
I was just about to.
Preston was found naked, right?
Yeah, it's a recurrent theme
in tales of alien abduction.
I practically grew up
on The X-Files.
Preston's wallet.
Somehow I doubt
aliens would have folded his
clothes when they abducted him.
So Clarissa drove him
out there
and he left his stuff
in her car.
That's not all he left.
(chuckles)
Steam cleaner.
Just what every
estranged husband needs
to clean up
his dead wife's blood.
This case just came down
to Earth.
Yes, Preston was at my home
in Summerlin.
We were asleep and suddenly
the room turned very cold.
Freezing.
I woke up and looked over
and Preston was gone.
I... I searched
the house, outside...
It was as if he evaporated.
(weary sigh)
Come on, Clarissa, you're
a smart woman, I mean, really.
I mean,
you have a beautiful home,
you're a good citizen, you
pay your taxes, you vote,
you even play a little golf.
You got way too much on the ball
to fall for this con man.
Con man?
(laughing)
You think I'm gullible?
He's a brilliant man.
He saved my life.
When we first met,
I was very ill.
It was cancer
and he cured it.
Really?
How'd he do that?
He knows how to prevent
human cells from dying.
He has injections;
they're, they're radioactive.
Hospitals won't do it because
it would make everyone well.
It would put them
out of business.
Do you really think
he's 4,000 years old?
Here.
Let me show you
something.
Look at this.
He's 42.
He claims he's
a nutritionist.
He's not.
And look.
Look at all these
schools and labs
he said he went to.
They never heard of him.
He has no place of
business, no job.
He just preys on
vulnerable women.
He got Shannon Turner to
kill his wife for him.
Got you to
give him money.
He never asked for it.
I wanted to give it to him.
You would have done anything
for him,
whether he asked for it or not.
Do you have any idea
how beautiful you are?
I mean really, really,
really beautiful.
More so every day.
That's because you cured me.
I-I-I've never felt better
or happier.
You know, I didn't want
to alarm you,
but they put
an implant in you.
They do it
while you're sleeping
so they can manipulate
your thoughts.
My injections disabled it.
You're not only cancer-free,
you're free of their control.
Oh, my God.
How am I ever going
to be able to thank you?
You drove him
out to McCade,
you dropped him off, you
brought back his clothes.
The evidence is
all over your car.
He loved me.
He used you
just like he used everybody.
♪ ♪
If they were trying
to clean up all the blood,
they did a good job.
Steam cleaner tested
positive for blood,
but there wasn't
enough for DNA.
Did you find anything?
Funny you should ask.
Found a hair
in the brushes.
Oh.
It's on the left.
The one on the right is
Chyna De Vere's.
They're both Chyna's.
Hey.
That steam cleaner was
completely wiped down,
couldn't find
any prints.
But then I remembered this story
about a CSI down in L.A.
Nobody could find any prints
on a gas can from an arson,
but he realized that you got
to grip it underneath
in order to pour out the gas.
And you know what?
He broke the case.
So whose prints are
on the steam cleaner?
I just got an AFIS hit:
Preston De Vere.
You have a destiny.
You were chosen.
You are a Protector
of Mankind.
Have no fear.
Cut off her tail,
she lives.
Cut off her head,
she dies.
No problem.
It wasn't
a Reptilian conspiracy,
but it was a conspiracy.
Men are snakes.
BRASS:
So we checked Chyna's
bank account.
She had a tidy little
inheritance until she met you.
Chyna was sucking
the life out of me.
She deserved none
of what she wanted
and all of what she got
in the end.
I'm glad it took a long time
for her to die.
I can only imagine the pain.
You know, every time I think
about leaving this job,
a guy like you comes along
and reminds me why I can't.
(spits)
MAN (on film):
History is replete with stories
of the heroic destruction
of serpents.
Perseus and Medusa,
St. George and the Dragon,
St. Patrick
and the Snakes of Ireland.
These are not merely legends.
These are accounts of battles
for the survival
of the human race--
a battle we will lose unless
we stop killing one another
and focus on the real enemies.
They are among us.