♪ ♪
KENTNER:
Primitive people refused
to be photographed,
fearing the camera
would steal their soul.
Like any good hunter,
the photographer stalks,
takes aim, and shoots an image.
Who's to say
that when the shutter
traps that moment in time
those primitive fears
weren't well founded?
(cheering)
(camera clicks)
♪ ♪
(camera shutter clicks)
(buzzer rings)
(cheering)
(camera shutter clicks)
Megan has no reason to run away.
She's always been a happy kid
and we trust her implicitly.
Captain, this is not like her.
Of course it's no accident
they're missing together.
MAN:
Ryan has a scholarship to Duke.
He's not going to throw it away
for some chippie.
Excuse me? "Chippie"?
Your daughter's
the one
who's calling our house
25 times a day.
BRASS:
All right,
all right, all right.
This isn't helping.
The kids have been missing
since last night.
Why you'd wait till now
to report it?
We thought that Megan was
sleeping over at Sheila's.
Sheila who?
Uh, Sheila Latham,
her best friend.
When I called Megan
on her cell phone this morning,
I couldn't reach her,
so I called the house,
and, uh, she wasn't there.
And Sue Latham didn't know
anything about a sleep-over.
MAN:
Ryan doesn't
have a curfew.
But he never stays out
all night.
He's not answering his cell
phone, and his van is missing.
MAN 2:
Captain, please, find
my daughter before
she does something stupid.
Stupid I can live with.
I need to know they're okay.
BRASS:
The last place they were seen
was the parking lot
at the school after the game.
GRISSOM:
These two kids have only
been missing for 14 hours.
They could have eloped
to Mexico.
I know, but...
All right.
But you owe me one
for getting me out of bed
on a Saturday morning.
Mitch?
This is Ryan Lansco's
assigned parking spot.
His drives
a blue '72 Ford van.
It's missing.
What do you want me to test?
MITCH:
Doesn't look like
transmission fluid.
Did you have assigned parking
when you were in high school?
No. We didn't
even have cars.
Yeah, it's blood.
I hope they're in Mexico.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
STOKES:
40 may be the new 20, but...
16's the new 30,
between cars and cell phones
and the Internet.
Yeah, well, the world's become
a very small place, Nick.
All the vices
are closer to home.
Hey.
GRISSOM:
More polyfil.
Hey, Nick?
Yeah?
This looks like
arterial spraying.
Something bad happened here.
STOKES:
A little blood
in the parking lot,
a lot of blood here.
But very little in between?
Hey.
Look at that
equipment shed door.
Some kind of broken glass.
Well, this was kicked in.
♪ ♪
Sheila.
Megan told her parents she was
spending the night with you.
But first she was...
gonna hook up.
With Ryan after the game.
Do you know where?
No.
Sheila...
What? I don't know.
Excuse me? Your best
friend is missing
and you're at a police
station. Act accordingly.
And sit up straight.
Are you okay?
Yeah. Yeah, I'm fine.
I just have a headache.
Were you drinking last night?
Mom, no!
Look...
a couple of us
went out for burgers
and then I came home.
Megan was supposed to call me
on my cell...
and I was going to go downstairs
and let her in.
And did she call?
No.
And you weren't worried?
I thought it was just
an overtime make-out session.
I fell asleep.
And now I'm here.
WILLOWS:
Both kids have an ATM card.
Neither's been used
since they went missing.
No calls were placed from
either of their cell phones.
There's an APB out
on Ryan's van-- no hits.
An APB has gone out to
local hospitals-- nothing yet.
I know. It sucks.
Any calls placed
before they went missing?
(laughs):
Where do I start?
Megan and Sheila phoned each
other about a dozen times.
A handful of calls were
placed to Charlie and Bonnie.
They're both on the
cheerleading squad.
"Hair up or down?
Black socks or gold socks?"
How about Ryan?
Ryan, uh, and Megan
exchanged a few calls.
He phoned home twice.
His last call was after
the game to a Diane Kentner.
She is the photography
teacher at the high school.
Warrick is
following up and...
I'm going to collect DNA
exemplars from the kids' houses.
My favorite part.
SANDERS:
Wish I had one of these
back in high school.
What's that?
A letter jacket?
No. No, a love shack.
Back seat of my car
got real old, real fast.
I was getting so much
play my senior year,
I seriously considered
getting a hearse.
Well, I never accused you
of not being smart.
Greg, you're a little weird,
but...
a hearse?
So what's with the ropes,
Casanova?
Well, I don't think
they were working out.
Looks like what started out
as a good time went bad.
I'd know those
footsteps anywhere.
The glass you found on the track
is optical glass.
Camera lens, not spectacle.
Camera lenses have
one side that's round
and one side
that's flat
for a high
refractive index.
It bends the light more.
It also has magnesium
fluoride and calcium fluoride
coatings for anti-reflection.
You're looking for a
high-end, non-compact camera--
Nikon, Leica,
or Canon--
that's missing its lens.
Thank you, David.
Warrick Brown
from the crime lab.
Thanks for coming
in on a Saturday.
Diane Kentner.
I took these photographs
of Megan and Ryan.
I like those.
Yeah, I teach photography.
Well, that's a nice shot
right there.
Thanks.
That's Charlie Kellerman.
I try to take pictures of what
the kids are passionate about.
So I guess he's passionate
about photography.
Yeah. That and Megan.
Charlie's in love with her.
She's in love with Ryan.
Ryan's in love with his future.
Ah, high school.
Yeah.
Did you notice any drama
yesterday in class
between Megan and Ryan?
No.
I mean, if a day goes by
that a teenage girl doesn't cry
in my class, it's a rarity.
But yesterday, it wasn't Megan.
And Ryan's head was already
in the game.
He's got a lot of pressure
on him.
He's oldest of six.
His parents are already
counting the money
that he's gonna make
from his first NBA contract.
Hmm.
Ms. Kentner, what kind of
cameras do you use in class?
We have a couple of junky ones.
Students usually bring
their own.
And what about your own
personal collection?
Well, I'm old school.
I mean, I took these
with a Hasselblaad, but...
otherwise, I use a Minolta
I've had forever.
Why?
Just following up
on some evidence.
And Ryan called you
after the game last night.
Yeah, he wanted copies
of the photos
the photography club had taken.
And he called you on your cell?
Yeah, I put it on the syllabus.
You can have it if you want.
No, thanks.
I've... I've already got it.
I'm not seeing
any evidence
of other people.
It's possible that
the basketball player snapped,
killed the cheerleader,
took her body and drove off.
What about the busted door?
He starts out
the big romantic...
Oh, don't break your
million-dollar foot.
Shh.
SANDERS:
And that's when
things went south.
Ryan.
Stop. I told you
Come on.
I want to wait
till prom.
It's gonna be fun.
Stop it!
She pushes him off,
makes a run for it.
But he realizes that
an attempted rape charge
might crash a Duke scholarship,
so he chases her down
and bashes her head in.
(phone rings)
Stokes.
Oh, hey, Wendy.
Really?
Yeah, thanks.
How does your theory
account for the fact
that all the blood's Ryan's?
It doesn't.
Okay.
Let's say I'm
a Lovers Lane rapist.
I stalk them.
I want me a high school
cheerleader.
What's the first thing
I do?
You take out
the basketball player.
Grab her, take her
somewhere more private.
Why take Ryan's body?
People...
let's spiral out.
♪ ♪
(camera shutter clicking)
Greg.
Accident debris.
Broken turn
signal light.
Lots of pieces
of grille
for a physical match.
Shoes match
the description
of the sneakers Megan Cooper
was wearing last night.
So far, the only blood I found
was on the shoes.
This road has almost no traffic
at night.
Take a look at this.
GRISSOM:
Looks like
acceleration marks.
Start out heavy,
and then they fade out
as the vehicle
gains momentum.
They're in a direct line
with the accident debris.
That tells me it's probably
related to the impact.
If Megan was
hit by a car,
hard enough to knock her
out of her own shoes,
I doubt she just walked away
from this.
So far there's no reports
of anyone fitting Megan's
description being admitted
to area hospitals.
I had a friend once that got hit
by this big-ass van.
Knocked him like
200 feet in the air.
Nick!
Yeah?
Straight ahead of you
about 20 yards.
Yeah!
Yeah, I got her.
Is she still alive?
Barely.
Yeah...
Okay...
All right.
Right, yeah, yeah, hold on.
We found Megan.
She's alive.
She was found on the side
of the road
near the high school.
She's apparently victim
of a hit-and-run car accident.
She's in a very
serious condition
and has been taken
to Desert Palm
Hospital.
And what about Ryan?
We haven't found him yet.
We're still looking.
Go ahead.
Let's go.
Uniforms found the van
on patrol.
They called it in.
I cleared it, waited for you
guys to open it up.
Front end's intact.
No damage,
no paint transfer.
There's no signs of an accident.
The keys are still
in the ignition.
There's no blood
on the driver's seat.
CURTIS:
Which means Ryan
probably wasn't driving,
because his blood was
all over the field.
(camera shutter clicks)
Body dump?
Where's the body?
(camera shutter clicks)
Hospital food.
Oh.
The best I could do.
Any word?
Not yet.
You know Megan.
She's a fighter.
She'll pull through this.
Thank you, Charlie.
Thank you.
You've always been
very good to her.
Excuse me.
I'm Nick Stokes
with the Crime Lab.
Oh, Charlie, he's the one
that found Megan.
Thank you.
You're very welcome.
I left your mom
a message.
I wanted to ask you
a few questions.
You mind if I...
steal him
for a minute?
Sure.
I understand you and Megan
were pretty close, huh?
We live next door
to each other.
I drive her
to school every day,
home after
cheerleading practice.
You wait that whole time?
Don't cheerleaders
work out for, like, hours?
No, I'm, I'm on the squad.
Oh.
Oh, okay.
Cute girls, short skirts.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, I get it.
(chuckles)
Did you wait for her after
the ballgame the other night?
I don't usually see her
after Friday night games.
She catches a ride home
with Ryan.
Hey, Charlie,
since you guys
are so close
you'd know if somebody had it in
for her, wouldn't you?
The only person who was ever
rude to Megan was Ryan.
How rude?
Ryan was a dog.
And the only person that
wouldn't believe that was Megan.
High school kid
with a van.
We could have half
the senior class in here.
Yeah, a bunch of minors
that won't be in the system.
That'll be helpful.
Ryan is six feet.
Whoever was driving
must have adjusted the seat.
(grunts)
Hello.
What you got?
I got a cell phone.
(camera shutter clicks)
Battery's dead, so I don't
know who it belongs to.
But something tells me
that pink is not Ryan's color.
I don't know.
I think he might be
always thinking pink.
If these all belong
to one girl, she's got nothing
left to wear.
You know, when
I was in college,
I had this boyfriend
and I thought we were
monogamous.
And one night, during the
post-coital panty search,
he handed me a pair of
underwear that wasn't mine.
Ooh.
How'd he explain that one?
He said they belonged
to his sister.
Yeah, right.
I know.
Let's hope your taste in men
has improved since then.
There's a large
rectangular blood pool
at the center
of the sleeping bag...
with several satellite
transfers.
At each corner...
a four-plus-one pattern
consistent with transfer
from bloody hands,
indicating the body was carried
on the sleeping bag.
Between ten and 20 semen stains.
Some overlaid
with blood.
Ugh.
You okay?
Phthirus Pubis.
Yeah, crabs.
I am buying Lindsey
a chastity belt.
There's a hole
in the metal
to let the urine pass.
So theoretically,
she could still get them.
You are so creepy sometimes.
You know, the incidence of STDs
in monogamous couples is slim.
Unless one someone arrives
at the party with them.
So assuming
they both have pubic lice,
if either Megan or Ryan
were assaulted,
they would have given them
to their attacker.
A sex pervert
with an STD?
That's not going
to narrow it down.
Yeah, but once they jump
to the fresh host,
crabs contain the DNA
of the receiver and the giver.
Did the parents agree
to an SAE kit?
Yes.
You rang?
Found the owner
of that cell phone.
Megan.
Nope. Sheila Latham.
What is
Megan's best friend's cell phone
doing in the front seat
of her boyfriend's van?
♪ If that's your boyfriend,
if that's your boyfriend ♪
BOTH:
♪ He wasn't last night. ♪
Hi, hi, I'm sorry I'm late,
but, you know, the sun
goes down on missing kids
and it's news.
I know this sounds awful,
but all I keep thinking is:
thank God it wasn't Sheila.
Doesn't make you a bad person.
(coin clanking)
Oh, this, this,
this thing is so broken.
There's a trick
to it.
Ah.
I lost two dollars in there.
This is Vegas, baby.
That's nothing.
(can clatters)
Thank you.
Voila.
Let's go to my office,
okay?
Look, I know you have
questions for her, but,
you know, Sheila almost lost
her best friend yesterday
and she's still
a little out of it.
No, I get it, and I appreciate
you bringing her in.
Hey, Sheila.
See, she's exhausted.
Oh, poor baby.
Sheila, honey.
It's time to wake up.
Captain Brass is here.
Sheila?
We got a 421!
Somebody run next door
and get the squad medics.
Wake up, please.
(sobbing)
Sheila, honey.
I'll tell you
it's been a banner week
for teens and police.
Two kids disappear;
one we can't find;
one may not make it
out of surgery;
and another one ends up
dead in custody.
I mean, I don't want
to make this about me,
but I need to know
my office is not responsible.
Did you hit her over the head?
Because COD is
epidural hemorrhage
caused by a blow
to the top of the skull.
The blood clot pushed
against the brain,
which compressed
the respiratory centers.
Her brain stopped telling her
body to breathe, and she died.
How recent
was the injury?
I extracted
about 150cc's
of partially clotted blood.
Would have taken
at least a day
to form, maybe longer.
Wait, so...
Sheila suffered the blow
around the same time
that Megan and Ryan were, um...
well, whatever they were.
Did her mother
mention the injury?
Injury? No.
Well,
that's not the only secret
she was keeping.
She swallowed something
rather unusual,
and she had crabs.
Well, I can guess
where she got those
and who she
gave them to.
What is it that she swallowed?
Looks like a memory
card from a camera.
♪ ♪
Looks like the metal connectors
got pretty gacked up
by the stomach acids.
Let's see if it still downloads.
Ah, we're in luck.
I'm guessing
that's your missing
basketball player.
Yeah.
In the equipment shed.
Look, I don't even know
how I got crabs.
GIRL:
You got them from humping
everything that moved,
you big loser.
Now, read.
What are you so mad about?
Come on, guys.
It's cold in here!
You could
at least close the door.
I, Ryan Lansco...
...am a diseased subhuman
sex pervert.
If you do me, you'll go home
with a souvenir.
Your own little crab colony.
My parents
better never see this!
(scoffing):
Oh, yeah?
This is going up on YouTube,
or maybe you'd like to put it
on your FriendAgenda page.
You put everything else up
there, why not your crotch rot?
Handheld camera.
There's a light in the room.
Someone opened the door.
There's got to be more than
one person yanking his chain.
You know, hang on,
I can give you
one voice comparison
right now.
Hi, guys, this is Sheila.
Guess you missed me,
but if you leave me a message,
I'll get you back.
(voice doubled):
Hi, guys, this is Sheila.
This is going up on YouTube.
Oh, Sheila.
So does that make her a victim
or a suspect?
Maybe both.
STOKES:
Megan, listen, I know you've
already been through a lot,
but you may be the only one
that can tell us
what happened to Ryan.
Where is he?
We don't know.
Let's start with the
last thing you remember.
We were at the game...
and I did a perfect hurkey.
What's a hurkey?
It's a jump where you go...
I keep forgetting
I can't move my legs.
(sobbing)
Mom,
you're not helping.
Do you remember anything
after the game?
Anything?
We won.
Everybody was happy.
I remember being really cold.
There were lights.
And then...
Nothing.
I'm sorry.
(sobbing)
EDDIE LANSCO:
If anyone knows anything
about our son,
please contact
the Las Vegas Police.
He's a great kid,
with a bright future
ahead of him,
and we just want him
home where he belongs.
"I'm likin' basketball,
"virgin daiquiris,
and sweet,
sweet ladies."
It's Ryan Lansco's
FriendAgenda page.
What's a "Hit List"?
Well, his van was
like a hot sheets motel,
so I don't think
he's an assassin.
Wants a password.
Try "Megan."
It's too obvious.
I'll try it anyway.
(scoffs)
Men are never
as mysterious
as women wish they were.
"Sheila L.-- couldn't move it.
"Bunny B. is a honey bee.
"Diane K. taught me
a thing or two."
Diane K.
Diane Kentner is
his photography teacher.
The fingerprint results
on Ryan's van.
No hits except
on the back door handle,
came back to Diane Kentner.
She was arrested last year
at a demonstration in support
of an X-rated photography show.
Now, what's
a photography teacher doing
touching a student's van?
Maybe she wanted a ride.
Ms. Kentner, the car
that hit Megan Cooper
left a broken
turn signal light
in the road.
It's from a Saab.
Isn't that the car
that you drive?
Yeah, along with hundreds
of thousands of other Americans.
Well, we're going to need
to take a look at yours.
Get a warrant and you can.
We also found
your fingerprint
on the door handle
of the back of Ryan's van.
Could you explain to me
how that got there?
Well... Ryan helped me
move an enlarger I got
for the photo lab
for the school.
My Saab wasn't big
enough to move it.
Your name came up
on, uh, Ryan Lansco's
FriendAgenda page,
what was called
a "Hit List."
It's apparently a list
of people that he slept with.
(laughs)
Wow.
If you're under 40 years old
and you teach teenage boys,
they all want to make
you Mrs. Robinson.
It's flattering,
but it's fantasy.
So, you are denying that you had
any sexual relations
with Ryan Lansco?
I would never take advantage
of a student.
Well, we're going to need
to take a DNA sample,
and that I have a warrant for.
My parents
better never see this!
Oh, yeah?
This is going up on YouTube.
The only reflective surface
in this whole frame is
that cabinet.
What am I looking at here, Arch?
I'm thinking
it's two faces.
Only time I can see it is
when the light hits it.
Sheila.
And some dude.
Some dude named Charlie.
You can grab a cup of coffee.
I know you've waived
your right to counsel.
I appreciate you
coming in here
and talking to me, Charlie.
That means you're
ready to be honest.
That's, that's good.
Because Ryan is
still missing,
Sheila is now dead,
Megan is partially
paralyzed,
and you are digging yourself
into a pretty deep hole here,
pal.
I know you were there
that night in the
equipment shed.
I have your shoe
impressions at the scene;
I've got you on film;
and we found Sheila's cue cards
in the back of her mom's trunk.
So...
Where's Ryan?
I don't know.
You're an adult, Charlie.
There's a big difference
between going to juvie
and going to state prison.
Big difference.
Okay, I'll tell you
what I think happened.
(clears throat)
You're in love with Megan,
who's in love with Ryan,
who's a dog.
You said so yourself.
And he gives her crabs.
But does she
break up with him?
No. She goes
right back to him
after crying on your shoulder.
Man, that'd piss me off.
Don't make me
present to a jury
that you came up
with this plan,
this little prank,
and recruited Sheila--
equally afflicted by this--
and you ran that
boy's head against
a tackling sled.
Then when Megan
freaked out
and got scared,
you just ran her over
and left her for dead.
No. No, no, that's not
what happened.
Then you tell me what happened!
Okay. You're right.
It started as a prank.
Sheila and I wrote out
that speech.
Sheila brought her camera.
We went down to the field house.
We knew
they'd be there fooling around.
What the hell?!
Shut up!
No, no, no, no.
Megan! Megan!
Get off me!
Shut up!
Stop it!
We tied him up.
We got him
to read the speech.
We were just gonna post it
on YouTube.
What happened?
He got loose,
came tearing after us.
He's coming.
You two.
(soft grunt)
Give me
the camera.
This what you want?
Huh? Ah, ah, ah.
Ah, ah...
(groaning)
What the heck, man?
(Sheila gagging and coughing)
(mock coughs)
Jerk!
Ryan? Ryan!
CHARLIE:
Next thing I know, blood was
just gushing out of his neck.
I haven't slept.
I haven't eaten.
I can't stop playing it
over and over again in my head.
(sobbing)
He just went down so fast.
And-And I was
looking at him.
And it-it was like
he wasn't Ryan anymore.
(sobs)
Whatever made him Ryan was gone.
What did you do with the body?
This is where I suck.
We should have just called 911,
but we panicked.
(cloth tearing)
(groaning)
Come on.
SHEILA:
Shut up and just pull. We don't
have time to think about that.
What are you doing?
Look, let's just get him
in the van.
I'll drive; you follow.
(groans)
Move. Move!
Where is Ryan?
(sobbing):
I just told you everything
I know.
We left him in the van.
What about Megan?
The second we barged
into that field house,
she freaked out and took off.
I-I didn't even know
she was in the hospital
until her parents called.
Okay, come here
and take a look at this.
Sheila's holding the camera;
you're holding the cue cards.
Who's holding the light?
Was there somebody else there?
Uh-uh.
Hmm?
I-I was holding the light
and the cue card.
Are you sure?
It was just Sheila and me.
(sobbing):
And now, it's just me.
♪ ♪
Okay, we got quite
the smorgasbord here.
Um, the only constant
from the crabs is Ryan.
He's half the DNA
on each of the combos.
And the other contributors
were Megan, Sheila,
several unknowns,
and everybody's favorite
photography teacher,
Diane Kentner.
Certainly hope
she gave him an A.
It proves sex with a minor.
Even if we can't get her
for Megan's hit-and-run,
it's enough
for a search warrant.
(siren blaring)
(garbled radio transmission)
So, what you find
at Diane's house?
Uh, not much, but
propped up on a dresser
was a rental
agreement
to this address and a key.
Looks like
she drew us a map.
Looks like it.
(garbled radio transmission)
Diane Kentner,
open up!
Las Vegas Police!
There's our busted headlight.
(garbled radio transmission)
(door rattling open,
high-pitched whirring)
BROWN:
What the hell is that?
(clicking)
Hold it. Hold it. Hold it.
Hold it.
(click,
high-pitched whirring)
(click)
(high-pitched whirring)
(click,
high-pitched whirring)
(click, whirring)
BRASS:
Now I remember
why I don't like modern art.
I'm gonna go call
the coroner outside.
(click,
high-pitched whirring)
BROWN:
I'm slipping, Grissom.
I talked to this woman twice,
and this body was here
the whole time.
No one could have
predicted this.
(clicking)
(whirring)
She was on a daily dose
of lithium.
Bipolar.
(click,
high-pitched whirring)
What is this, Grissom,
Romeo and Juliet?
Postmortem
photography-- memento mori.
In the 19th century,
a photo
of your dead loved one
was a popular keepsake.
Death remembered.
One last look.
(high-pitched whirring, click)
Hey.
(whirring, click)
Charlie told Nick
that Sheila pushed Ryan.
BROWN:
Charlie lied...
to protect Megan.
(whirring)
How you feeling?
Okay, considering.
Oh, my parents are
in the cafeteria
if you want to wait.
Oh, no, no, I'm... I'm good.
I just wanted
to show you something.
What do you think about that?
Is that me?
What am I doing?
Oh, it looks like
you're killing your boyfriend.
You tell me.
Who took this?
Ms. Kentner.
Oh, come on. Obsess much?
Oh, so, you do remember?
No.
Not what happened that night.
I wish I could get
selective amnesia.
There's a lot in my past
I'd like to forget about.
If I did push Ryan,
and he died,
then that was wrong.
Don't you think that
I've been punished enough?
EDDIE LANSCO:
Are you telling me
you're not gonna
prosecute the girl
that killed my son?
The DA decided
not to file.
I mean, my guess is
that he probably felt
he couldn't get
a conviction.
Wh...
Where's the justice in that?
Everybody involved in this thing
has been punished in some way.
I mean, Diane
and Sheila are dead.
Charlie's probably going
to jail, and Megan...
Got away
with murder.
You trust me?
Intimately.