Hola, Cariño.
¿Todo bien?
Estan mis bebes
durmiendo como bebes?
Sí, ya se, ya se.
No me reganes mas.
Sí, sí. Comida para el bebe.
Sí, pan, leche.
Mira, Cariño, ahorita vengo.
Te quiero.
(kissing noise)
♪ Oh, darling ♪
♪ Danke scheon ♪
♪ Danke scheon, oh, darling ♪
♪ Thank you for all
the joy and pain... ♪
(keys jingle)
(loud creaking)
(indistinct radio transmission)
The vic had nothing on him
but his casino I.D.
Name is Vasco Ruiz.
He's a dishwasher here
at the Golden Sapphire.
Yeah, I guess he
got off his shift,
went to his car,
got whacked.
By what?
A blender?
Surveillance?
Not in the employee
structure.
Witnesses?
Well, we found a
Wayne Newton impersonator,
but all I could get
him to do was sing
a few bars of
"Danke Sheon".
But no wallet
no cash,
no cell phone,
no car keys.
Smells like a robbery.
Maybe it was his payday.
Even if this guy
was walking out of here
with a million dollars...
this is way more than excessive.
Personal.
Yeah, I'm gonna
go get personal
with his boss.
See what he knows.
(rings bike bell)
(screams)
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
♪ ♪
(indistinct radio transmission)
(sirens blare)
You got a name?
She's not talking.
What about ID?
He must've taken
her wallet.
Cell phone?
It's not here,
they took it.
Somebody had
to see something.
Hey.
Hi.
Well, we got a souvenir cup
that screams "tourist."
Yep.
I don't see a bar
anywhere around here.
She must've been
either going to
or coming from the Strip.
But she shouldn't have been
walking around here, Warrick.
Couldn't pick a shadier
part of town, man.
You know these tourists
don't know what they're getting
when they book
a trip to Vegas online.
They think "I got a room
on the Strip for 75 bucks.
Whoo, what a deal."
Then they mosey through
the naked city
with their thousand
dollar cameras.
Next thing you know,
we're taking their picture.
You know what,
Grissom's crime scene
is just five blocks from here.
Both victims had their wallets
and their cell phones stolen.
And they were both beaten
down in the same way.
Looks like someone's
on a little crime spree.
Uh, David, hang on.
Looks like a woman's toenail.
Well, it's not necessarily
a woman's.
(camera clicks)
Jessica...
this might hurt a little bit,
but it's going to
help us get the people
who did this to you.
(groans)
I'm sorry.
Thank you.
Do you have any other injuries?
Yeah. On my left side.
Ow.
(groans)
Could you lift your left arm
for me, please?
(crying)
Thank you.
I just got out of
a ten-year relationship.
So I decided to take
a solo trip to Vegas.
You know, try the whole
"what happens in Vegas,
stays in Vegas."
Been there.
Yeah, well, I get to take
this face back with me.
(crying)
Well, did anybody
else get hurt?
Why do you ask?
I heard them say
that I was number two.
Was there a number one?
There was.
How are they doing?
He died.
♪ ♪
All right, slick.
Now what's with the suit?
Today was my first
jury trial.
Today ended
an hour and a half ago.
Well, maybe I just
don't want the day to end.
Well, if that's the case,
why don't you help
my day end quicker
and help me isolate
some shoe treads.
Take the pants.
So...?
How'd you do on the stand?
So good the prosecutor
took me to dinner.
Female?
Yeah, she was icing.
I was just happy
to finally
see a case from the crime
scene to the courtroom.
We freakin' buried
the guy.
It was bad ass.
I dropped the hammer...
he was squirming
in his chair.
How many different patterns
you have there?
Five different patterns.
Well, I've got three different
ones on the T-shirt.
I mean, this one that looks like
an athletic shoe
sure got around.
As did this pointed toe
high-heeled one.
Check out the heel mark.
So did this work boot.
What do you know about
work boots?
I'm guessing
you haven't worked
a day of hard labor
in your life.
I wore Doc Martens
in high school.
It was the style.
Yeah, for skinheads.
Yeah, they kind of
ruined it for everyone.
You know, one of the
victims was Hispanic,
the other was Jewish.
Maybe this was a hate crime.
Sure looks like hate to me.
Vasco Ruiz was someone's
punching bag.
He suffered multiple
abrasions, lacerations,
contusions.
I found no particular patterns,
sharp edges
or tool marks from any weapons.
Do fists and feet count?
He had too many
bruises to count,
one on top of another.
And under the skin,
things get even worse.
Long bone fractures
of the fingers,
radius, ulna, humerus.
Rib fractures, flail chest.
Fractures of the vault
and base of skull.
Almost every bone in his face.
Somewhere along the way,
he took a shot to the head
that resulted in
a subdural hematoma.
COD is multiple
blunt force trauma.
Could one person have done this?
Not even Mike Tyson.
MAN:
Okay, okay, okay,
they took my good vodkas,
my single-malt whiskies,
they took vermouth,
cognac, VSOP cognac.
Am I going to get any
of the stuff back?
What are you guys
going to do about this?
Okay, slow down.
You're talking too fast.
All right, you know what? Just
let me know when you're ready.
I'm ready, sir, I just, I just
need you to talk slower.
Okay, I can do that.
These creeps
come flying in here,
they take a lot
of my good stuff.
And I chased one of them
and I snatched the sweater
right off his back.
How many did you see?
I don't know.
There was a bunch.
A bunch.
Two, five, ten?
Closer to the ten.
Any descriptions?
They had hoods on.
They were hooded.
You took the sweater
off one of them
and you didn't get to see
what he looked like?
He was on his way
out the door.
What I did see was really weird.
Anyway.
What does "weird" look like?
I don't know.
His face.
His nose was all deformed.
The whole thing creeped me out.
Thank you.
Greg...
lose the monkey suit,
you got a scene;
liquor store robbery.
Here's the address.
Related to the earlier 415s?
Could be-- Sofia's got one
of the suspect's sweaters.
I need you to seal it,
bring it back here
and anything else
you can find.
All right.
Who's my wingman?
You're a big boy, Greg.
You don't need
a wingman for this.
Primary. Nice.
(grunting)
Whoa!
Pick on somebody
you're own size.
Are you volunteering?
No.
The two scenes are related.
I found two common
treads on both vics;
an athletic shoe and a boot.
I ran them through
the Solemate database.
The athletic shoe...
is a Converse Chuck Taylor
and the boot is a Doc Martin.
Could this be a woman's shoe?
Yeah, I ran that through
the Solemate database, too.
That is a Steve Madden
Dynasti stiletto.
Open-toe shoe.
'Cause Catherine found
a broken female toenail
in the vic's mouth.
Most of the treads
are on the sides
and back of the victim's
clothing.
Which suggests that they
were on the ground
for most of the beating.
Kicked to death.
(sobbing)
How am I going to feed my boys?!
Pay the rent,
gas, car? God...
Mrs. Ruiz,
I'll do the best I can.
I'll put you in touch
with State services
that'll help you deal
with these issues, okay?
But right now
I need your help
to do my job.
I need some
information, okay?
Whatever you need.
All right. When was the last
time you talked to Vasco?
Midnight.
He calls me every night
after work.
Did he have any enemies
that you know of?
No.
He was a good man with
a good heart.
No one disliked him.
Okay. Did he carry a wallet
or a cell phone?
He had both.
I want you to write down
his cell phone number
on this piece of paper, okay?
I need to access
his records.
Hey, guys,
this officer's
going to take you
and your mom home,
make sure you all
get home safe, okay?
Thank you.
REPORTER:
I'm standing across
from the Holiday Motel
where a brutal beating
just occurred a few hours ago.
We have the footage
which was recorded
by an anonymous bystander's
cell phone.
Although the quality is poor,
you can see several images
assaulting the lone
female victim.
Anyone living near the strip
is being told to stay at home
until the assailant is caught.
For anyone who has any
information,
please call 555-0155.
Get this reporter on the phone.
Control, Control,
this is CSI Sanders.
I need some help.
Control, go with your
information.
Okay, I got an assault
in progress one alley south
of Casino Central Drive,
cross street Shane.
How many suspects involved?
Multiple suspects.
Could be the guys who've
been doing it all night.
The closest unit
has a five-minute ETA.
Rolling Code Three.
Are they armed?
I don't know. I don't know.
Ma'am, please, listen.
You got to get here quicker
than this.
Copy that. We'll roll two
additional units ASAP.
Wait for backup.
(beeping horn)
(horn blaring)
Move!
(thugs shouting)
Get out of here!
(horn blares)
(glass shatters)
(grunting)
(girlish laughter)
(man laughs)
WOMAN:
Please, let me see
Demetrius.
I just want to talk to him.
I'm sorry.
It's a crime scene.
I can't let you pass.
I'm sorry.
He's not dead,
is he?
He's been badly injured,
but he's being attended
to, I promise you.
Hey.
Why isn't there
a medic on Greg?
He's been stabilized.
Sara, he's going
to be okay.
(faintly):
Sara...
I didn't think you could see me.
I can't...
but I know that Sidle scent.
I'm going to take that
as a compliment.
I scratched
one of them.
And you should
check my vest.
I think the same guy
spit on me.
And one of their cars
crashed into the Denali.
I guarantee
there's transfer on it.
You should process
the scene now.
Me later.
I came here for you, Greg.
BRASS:
So how long you been
in town, Mr. Tanner?
About 20 hours, man.
You on vacation?
Straight from Union City,
Tennessee.
Okay, tell me what happened.
Well, I was cutting
through that alley
trying to find a taxi
off one of them side streets.
Next thing I know
I'm on the ground
just getting pounded
all to hell.
I thought
I was gonna die.
Even give it up to the Man.
Then I heard that horn honking
and engine revving toward me.
Can you give me
any descriptions?
Okay.
All right. You take it easy.
Could you do me a favor?
Sure, I'll do my best.
The man that saved my life,
I'd like to meet him,
give him a thank you.
His name is Greg Sanders.
And I'm sure he'd appreciate it.
I'll tell him.
(inaudible police radio
transmission)
(camera shutter clicking)
I think I just found
a piece of Sanders' hair.
MAN:
So what, did somebody else
get a beat down?
You bitches haven't caught
them cats yet?
Excuse me?
You fellas want
to keep it moving?
We're trying to work here.
You call that working?
Why is there an ass-whupping
on every other block?
There's about to be an
ass-whupping on this block.
Is that right?
That's right.
BROWN:
Hey, Nick...
Man, you're weak,
weak, weak, weak.
Come on, man.
You can't do this.
MAN:
I'm sorry,
I'll say
what I want.
you're not weak.
Nick.
Nick...
You're a joke.
BROWN:
Nick.
Come on!
Anybody get that on video?
Man, I'll take a picture myself.
That's a nice phone
you got there, man.
Real nice phone.
Wonder how many
drug dealers' numbers you got
on this phone here.
Feel like going
to jail tonight?
Listen, I'm sorry
about the little spill
you had earlier,
but that's why we got
the crime tape up,
so you could see it.
Watch where you're going
next time.
Get you home safely.
What are you doing?
We beating people up now?
I'm sick of
these punks, man.
I'm serious,
I'm sick of it.
Then you're
in the wrong town.
Maybe.
(woman speaking indistinctly
over P.A. system)
Greg?
Grissom.
Just another day
at the office, huh?
Well, at least I can see now.
The guy they beat up...
how is he?
He's gonna be fine.
What about the other guy?
The guy I hit.
His name is Demitrius James.
He's in surgery.
Is he, like,
a gangbanger or something?
Actually...
he's a student
at the university.
He gonna be okay?
I don't know.
(sighs)
Has someone called your parents?
We should let them know.
(sighs):
Mm.
What's the matter?
They still think I'm in the lab.
Why do they think that?
When I was in high school...
I never played any sports.
No football, no basketball.
Definitely no hockey.
I never would've guessed.
Well, it wasn't
by choice.
My mom wanted four kids.
Ended up with only one.
She always made sure
I stayed close.
If I got a nosebleed,
she'd take me to the E.R.
(chuckles weakly)
Well...
now would be the
time to come clean.
My mom's gonna freak.
You tell her that
you risked your life
to save someone else's...
and I think
she'll be very proud of you.
(crying quietly)
Hey.
Doctor found these
on Demitrius James.
Contact lenses.
Special kind.
They're called Halloween lenses.
They're wearing costumes.
Great.
Just a game to them.
WILLOWS:
Is that your number, Cha Cha?
Yeah, that's my number.
So tell me...
what does a dead guy
sound like?
(suppressed laughing)
Oh, is that funny?
Oh, man, I mean,
isn't it supposed to be?
Someone called you
from his phone-- who was it?
(exhales):
When'd they call again?
12:33 a.m.,
last night.
Man, you know how many people
blow me up at that time?
Shoot, that's
like prime time.
Finding-the-right-party time.
Half my calls go to voice mail
my line's so busy.
Who's this guy?
(sighs)
M-Maybe I seen him before,
I don't know.
Farami, huh?
Yeah.
You like?
If it was real, I might.
Whatever.
Can I go now? Damn.
When I swab that knockoff
Farami buckle and I find
this tourist's DNA on it,
you're going down
for murder.
(scoffs):
She didn't die.
No, but Mr. Ruiz did.
And you were the last person
that he called.
That connects you
to both crimes.
(sighs)
Tara, okay?
Tara called me.
It's funny, 'cause
the only reason
I picked up my phone is 'cause
I didn't know the number.
Thought it was this hot boy.
And what did Tara want?
(exhales)
Her boyfriend Pig invited her
to a party at a motel.
She invited me, so I rolled.
(indistinct shouts)
Go get a piece.
It's fun.
(punches landing)
Is that your idea of a party?
Man, everyone loves
a good fannysmackin' session.
A what?
Beating up fannypackers.
You know, tourists.
Why would you want to do that?
Nothing else to do.
And you do this all the time?
Yeah, but this was
the first time
I ever heard of anyone dying.
What is Pig's name?
I just know "Pig."
So if... fannysmackin'
is all about tourists,
why'd you go after a dishwasher
at the Golden Sapphire?
I don't know.
Maybe he was just practice.
So, you think we're
out of the woods yet?
Well, beatings were
occurring every hour,
and it's been three hours
since the last one, so maybe.
MAN:
Do I look like
I want to sign in?
I want to talk to cop, okay?
Somebody get me a cop!
I want to talk
to a cop now!
He's a cop.
She's a cop.
Hey, my friend,
he got beat up and robbed.
I can see that.
Where?
On the corner
of Decatur and Jones.
They-they took the ten G's
that I had on me,
they took my watch,
they took my
cell phone.
And look at his face.
They beat him up, too.
Did you get a good look at 'em?
Not really--
they were wearing hoodies.
Processed the sweater
found at the liquor store.
Found blood.
Sent it to DNA.
Wendy found two types,
matched both to your vics.
She also ran saliva
on Greg's jacket.
Came back unknown male.
Same unknown male
that Greg scratched.
Nice map.
What do you see?
My old neighborhood.
Inconsistency.
In what?
The dishwasher, both
tourists and Greg
were attacked
near the Strip.
Dean Harden claims
that he was attacked
all the way over here
in Southwest Las Vegas.
Swarms don't backtrack.
We're talking about
humans here, not bugs.
Humans have always adapted
strategies from insects.
Swarming is
an ancient military tactic.
You surround your enemies,
then attack
from all directions
simultaneously.
Alexander the Great pioneered
the maneuver 2,000 years ago.
Although swarms consist
of several individuals,
they must be treated
as a single entity,
which lives,
thinks and moves as one,
built with an internal logic
to continue forward,
gain momentum
and never backtrack.
So this guy Dean probably
was not a victim of this swarm,
or he's lying.
Take a look at these clothes.
In contrast
to the other beatings,
I found only one type of shoe
tread on Dean's clothing.
The print matches a size 12
Nike Air.
And this shoe is...
his own.
He swarmed himself?
I owe my Uncle Lenny
ten G's.
and I don't got it,
all right?
Am I supposed to know
who Uncle Lenny is?
Uncle Lenny? Lenny G.
The famous sports
handicapper.
Yeah, it's not
ringing any bells.
He's blackbooked
from the casinos.
But he still likes to bet.
And you bet for him.
Yeah, he gave me five dimes to
bet the Eagles this past Sunday.
You see, me and Ant,
we're hurting
for cash right now.
We didn't think
the Eagles had a chance,
so we thought we would
just pocket the cash.
But they won and now you owe
Uncle Lenny G. ten G's.
Yeah. And when we saw
these beatings on TV and...
just thought
it was a great idea.
Don't go near the package.
Why am I going to go
near your package?
All right.
It'll be like Pesci did it
to DeNiro in Raging Bull.
Remember that?
Yeah, all right,
just do it, man, come on.
Okay.
All right, just
do it, man!
I'm doing it!
(yells, groans)
What, are you crying?
Shut up, man!
It's not funny, all right?!
I figured if Dean said
we got beat up and robbed,
we wouldn't have to pay up.
Yeah, well, now you're
eleven G's in the hole.
The ten thousand
you owe Uncle Lenny for the bet,
and the thousand you owe us for
filing a false police report.
(beeping)
Hey, Catherine.
I think I'm on to something.
Check this out.
WILLOWS:
Oh... the King Swine.
Now, "y'all" is plural.
Believe me, I used
the word a lot,
so I have a feeling he sent
that to more than one person.
Could be a mass text.
Lindsey once sent everyone
in her phonebook
the same message
at the same time.
I got stuck with a $300 bill.
Hmm, we got this punk's
phone number.
All we have to do is
subpoena his phone records.
We'll get every one he
sent the message to.
We'll text him, we'll tell
him to meet us somewhere.
From Tara's phone?
They'll know it's us.
No, from Pig's phone.
We don't have Pig's phone.
Don't need it.
When you text
from a computer,
you put in the number
that you're calling from.
We'll just use Miss Piggy's.
Okay, but how do we get the Pig?
BRASS:
Look, I'm not going
to play you, Tara.
So let's not waste
each other's time.
I have enough evidence
to try you for first
degree murder.
But I'm greedy.
I want the rest of
the Mickey Mouse Club.
So you have a choice.
You can either spend a very,
very long time in jail
or you can help me out.
I'm not saying nothing.
You don't have to sayanything.
Write a text message.
Something Pig
would send to his buddies
to gather them all up for
another fannysmackin' party.
Look, Tara,
I don't think
that beating these
people up was your idea,
so why should you and
Cha Cha take the fall?
These guys don't care about you.
I mean, let's face it.
You're just
a piece of tail to them.
Right?
So what's it
going to be?
Are you going to let a guy
with the colorful but
unfortunate name of "Pig"
run free while
you go to jail?
You know, it's
funky in there.
No Posh Spice.
No parties,
no purses or pedicures
or pasta primavera.
So you decide.
Decide.
(rap music playing)
Pig text you?
Yeah.
Hey, Pig, thanks for that text.
I'm ready for
some smackin'.
I didn't text you.
You didn't?
Nah. Did you text me.
I didn't text you.
(sirens blaring)
(weapons clicking)
BRASS (over bullhorn):
Everybody out of the car, now.
Get out of the car.
Let's see those hands.
Put them on the top
of the car.
(cocks shotgun)
Turn off the truck.
Get out.
And put your hands
above your head.
BRASS (over bull horn):
Get out of the car.
You're going to jail.
Free shower, free food,
free sleep.
(chuckles)
Let me in there.
This little piggy went, "Wee,
wee, wee," all the way home.
(snorts)
(indistinct PA announcement)
NURSE:
I think this
is the room, sir.
There he is.
Mr. Sanders?
Hey. How you doing?
Better than dead.
Get me over here, Lizzy, where
I can shake this man's hand.
You're a brave man.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Home, Elizabeth.
I cook some mean barbeque,
If you ever get yourself
to Union City, Tennessee.
I'll look you up.
You do that.
(woman hysterically sobbing)
(hysterical sobbing continues)
I am going to pick up
some Roberto's,
take it over to Greg.
I'm sure he's sick
of that hospital food--
anybody want to come?
I'll take a ride with you,
but I'm going to pass
on the Mexican food
at 10:00 in the morning.
No, I'd like to see Greg.
I'm definitely in, yeah.
Pig and the piglets
are in the pig pen.
It's about time.
Finally, some good news.
Did you know that Pig,
aka Cole Trit,
was the only adult.
The rest of them
were under 18.
One was 14.
Are you kidding?
Who raises these kids?
I mean, they weren't
all delinquents.
Demitrius James was
a college student.
Hanging out with the wrong
crowd in the wrong town.
I'm telling you,
a fake ID
in Las Vegas is like having
a free ticket
on the hell train.
Sex, drugs, gambling,
no adult supervision, 24/7.
By the time they're 21,
they've done and seen it all.
Make me slit my wrists,
why don't you?
I'm raising a teenager here.
Oh, you're doing a great job.
Lindsey's gonna turn out
to be a beautiful
young woman.
Besides, I grew up in Vegas,
I didn't turn out so bad, did I?
Yeah, that was
pre-Mirage,
back when you were
a little squirt
going to the casino
playing the arcade games.
No, Vegas is a different
animal now.
BROWN:
Yeah, these kids
need to beat people on
the street to be entertained.
They just need
some good discipline.
They need their
grandmother
whupping their ass
like, like I had.
Yeah, a good slap.
You know, it kind of sounds like
your guys are blaming everybody
but these kids.
I mean, you don't get a bye
just 'cause you grew up here
or your parents are on drugs.
Those kids are
perfectly capable
of telling the difference
between a wild night out and...
beating somebody to death.
The truth is...
a moral compass can only point
you in the right direction,
can't make you go there.
Our culture preaches that, uh,
you shouldn't be ashamed of
anything you do anymore.
And unfortunately, this city
was built on the principle
that there's
no such thing as guilt.
"Do whatever you want,
we won't tell."
So without a conscience,
there's nothing to stop you
from killing someone.
And evidently,
you don't even
have to feel bad about it.