(distorted, indistinct,
overlapping voices)
WOMAN (distant):
There's an Amber Alert
this evening in Clark County
for two missing boys.
Okay, we have two
missing criticals--
Jason Crowley, age ten--
black, male, four-foot-six.
Lucas Hanson--
age ten, Caucasian,
male, five feet.
Now, uh,
the boys were last seen at this
location at 15:30 hours--
Jason Crowley's house.
Jason lives with his
grandfather, Terrance Crowley.
The address is on your handouts.
Terrance Crowley
assumed
that they were staying
at Lucas' house.
Dawn Hanson,
Lucas's mother,
returned home from work
at 21:00 hours.
She assumed they were
at Terrance Crowley's house.
She reported them
missing at 24:00 hours.
Now, we searched the schools,
playgrounds, basketball courts.
Found nothing.
Canine is on the scene.
Neither of the boys carried
cell phones or pagers.
Now, any
questions?
Boys ever run
away before?
No, and, uh,
we interviewed the teachers
at the school,
and according to them,
they're both good kids.
(cell phone chimes)
MAN:
Any, uh, distinguishing
features or marks?
BRASS:
Well, as you can see,
Jason wears glasses,
but that's it. Yeah?
MAN 2:
Did Amber Alerts go
out to any other states?
BRASS:
Amber Alerts
have gone out
to the states of
Utah, California...
(siren blaring)
Okay, so what does your arson
have to do with my missing kids?
Upon initial search
of the premises,
farmer located one adult male
unconscious
on the living room floor.
His name's Carl Fisher.
Paramedics have him
on the bumper now.
Once he came around,
he started claiming
every time there's
an Amber Alert,
somebody tries to kill him.
Child molester.
Tier Two,
by his own admission.
Excuse me,
Mr. Fisher?
My name's Gil Grissom.
I'm with the Crime Lab.
What happened
to your shoes?
They're in the house.
I was asleep.
Are you familiar with the names
Lucas Hanson or Jason Crowley?
The kids from the Amber Alert?
No, sir.
I'm a convicted pedophile.
That would be a violation
of my parole.
Which is it-- boys or girls?
Boys.
Preteen.
I know what you're thinking.
No, you don't.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
(coughing)
FISHER:
Don't know what woke me up,
the smoke or the fire.
(coughs and groans)
Next thing I remember,
I was outside,
looking up at
the paramedics.
Hold out your hands, please.
(camera shutter clicking)
Turn them over.
So, uh, can you account for your
whereabouts the last 24 hours?
I worked from 6:00
until 2:00 p.m.,
and then I went
straight home.
BRASS:
Where do you work?
At the feed lot off Highway 111.
I've got a Masters
in English Literature.
I used to teach high school.
Let me guess--
the kids loved you.
Someone set fire to my house.
I almost died.
Why don't you ask me
about that?
Okay.
Who would want to barbecue you?
My neighbors make it clear
every day how they feel
about me.
I would start
with Mr. Hamilton.
He threw a rock through
my window a few months back
when a little
girl went missing.
Hamilton... he barely
finished high school.
He has a lot of displaced anger.
Hmm.
You're not writing
any of this down.
I have a good memory.
Listen, I've called you guys
half a dozen times
in the past two years.
I've had my house graffitied,
my windows broken,
my tires slashed.
Well, you know, Carl,
sometimes bad things happen
to bad people.
But I'll tell you what--
(cell phone chimes)
I'll let you file
a formal complaint
down at the police station.
I got to go.
You all right here?
I'm almost done.
I've been living right
the past five years
since I got
out of prison.
I haven't gone
near a child.
I go to a support group
every week.
I've even lectured
social workers
on how to recognize
sexual predators.
Ask my parole
officer.
Doesn't that count
for something?
I don't know.
But it doesn't change anything,
does it?
WOMAN (on TV):
Police have no new clues
in the disappearance
of ten-year-old Lucas Hanson
and 11-year-old Jason Crowley.
Teachers and classmates
are planning a six p.m. vigil
at Rockwater Elementary...
Mrs. Hanson, I got your message.
You said it was urgent.
You told me to go home
and look around.
That's what I did.
My ex took 'em.
BRASS:
I thought you told me that
your ex-husband wasn't involved
in Lucas' life.
He doesn't care
about Lucas.
He barely uses his visitation,
and then, six months ago,
I don't know, he-he got
into some kind of trouble.
He started coming around
when Lucas was home alone.
He'd gone
through my mail, my checkbook.
He-He stole our TVs.
Daddy, please.
Mama said she's gonna
call the cops.
Put it back.
Your mom can do
whatever she wants.
I paid for this.
It's mine.
(engine starting)
So I told Lucas that he couldn't
be home alone anymore,
and I took his key.
You locked your son
out of his own house?
I made arrangements
with Jason's grandpa.
The hide-a-key is
for emergencies only.
So it's possible
that Lucas took the key.
(voice breaking):
Lucas...
Lucas always drops his book bag
in the hallway
and turns on the TV.
I bought him a new one.
I'm positive
he didn't came home.
Okay, all
right, all right.
Give me an address
for your ex-husband.
(crying)
225-IHG.
That sounds
like a license plate.
Yeah, well,
he moves around a lot.
Practically lives
out of his car.
He... He runs
a stripper circuit on I-15.
Have you ever seen this man?
No. Why?
Uh, he's a person of interest.
Lucas knows better than that.
You don't talk to strangers.
Ah, it's okay. Uh, yeah.
Put out a broadcast
on Perry Hanson.
MAN:
Look, Jason and Lucas probably
just ran away.
They're at that age.
You know what I'm saying?
Well, kids with no money
and no place to go
usually come home quickly.
Do you know how hard it would be
to catch them?
Lucas is a big boy.
And Jason...
(chuckles):
Jason is fast.
The red one is Jason's.
Your grandson's
into sports, huh?
Yeah, you'd think.
Plays them damn video games.
That's all he wants to do.
I told him I don't allow
that stuff in my house.
Boys need fresh
air and sunshine.
CURTIS:
Uh, we haven't
been able to reach
Jason's father.
Have you spoken to him?
You know, my son fell apart
when his wife died.
Quit his job.
I was basically
taking care of both of them.
And then he got
a great opportunity in Houston.
Couldn't get Jason
into a school until
next semester, so I said
I'd keep him until then.
(dog barking)
How do those dogs find people?
(laughs)
WILLOWS:
Just like the movies,
they sniff them out.
Bet it's expensive, huh?
You worried about the money?
Let me tell you something.
Boys are gonna walk
right in here
just like that runaway bride.
And you people
are gonna be
handing me a bill
for all the looking, you watch.
(siren whoops in distance)
(device beeps quietly)
(trilling)
Hey.
I talked with
the neighbors.
A Mrs. Hamilton says
she walked her dogs
around 6:00 last night.
She saw Carl watering
his outside plants.
He was alone.
She also said that after dark,
everyone locks up their doors,
and the kids stay inside.
And let me guess.
Nobody saw
or heard anything, right?
Right.
What do you got?
Based on the burn pattern,
the origin
of the fire was definitely here.
I detected an accelerant
on the front
of the car, and on the ground,
both consistent with gasoline.
Now, the back seat's
still intact, so I figure
the fire jumped from the car
to the house and fast.
Check this out.
(indistinct radio communication
in distance)
Full shoe impression
on the concrete.
STOKES:
Someone stepped
in the accelerant
before the car was lit.
Treads lead toward the street.
Could've been
a neighbor.
Could've been anybody.
(camera shutter clicking
and beeping)
(indistinct radio communication
in distance)
(camera shutter clicking
and beeping)
Well, so far,
the only prints I found
in the bedroom
are Carl Fisher's.
No semen stains
in the bed.
And nothing
to indicate children.
SIDLE:
Well, there's tons of these.
What's that?
Spencer's Last Straw,
Wiz Kids, Mayhem and McCabe,
Secret City.
Guy lives in a trailer.
He drives an old Mercury.
He has a ton of expensive DVDs
and video games.
There's gummi bears and chips
on the floor.
House might as well be made
out of gingerbread.
(siren sounds)
Vehicle matched
the description.
Went to pull him over,
he tried to split on us.
Perry Hanson?
So, Mr. Hanson,
where are the boys?
Which boys?
Lucas and Jason.
My kid, Lucas?
What, did he ditch school
or something?
No, he's missing,
and so is his best friend.
You mean, you didn't hear
the Amber Alert,
or check your messages?
You don't have to talk
to him, okay, Perry?
See, I know the
frickin' Constitution.
I bet you do.
Somebody get Ben Franklin
out of here.
Don't...
You didn't have to cuff us,
you know?
It's not like
we're frickin' terrorists.
(indistinct radio
communication in distance)
♪ ♪
BRASS:
You want to tell me
what Jason Crowley's
baseball glove is
doing in your car?
Lucas must've
left it there.
I don't know, man, kids are
always taking each other's crap.
Yeah, well,
I'm not taking any more
of yours. You're under arrest.
(dog barking)
Got something here.
WILLOWS:
Lucas was last seen
wearing khaki-colored
board shorts.
I've had calls here before.
A lot of these
houses are vacant.
Perfect place
for a little
privacy.
Okay, let's get
around this fence.
Okay, let's hear it.
You know my ex
is crazy, right?
Always been
a drama queen.
She probably told you
that I stole the TV.
I don't care about the TV.
When was the last time
you were in your house?
Day I left--
I've never been back.
I found this in your car.
Guess whose front door it opens?
Look...
my ex will hardly
even let me see my kid.
You know, not until I pay up
on the vaginamony that I owe.
And that's illegal.
She doesn't care.
Yesterday, I-I just
wanted to see my boy.
You know? So I went over
there and he wasn't home.
I guess I forgot
to leave the key.
Another sad,
suffering single dad.
You better find my kid.
And if I were you, I'd start
with Dawn's boyfriends.
Oh, if you were me.
She only dates scumbags
and bottom-feeders.
At least I never
been in prison.
Well, that can change.
MAN:
LVPD.
(dog barking)
MAN:
Kitchen's clear.
Clear!
Closet's clear.
Check the rest of the house.
It's the door itself,
not what's inside.
There was a struggle here.
I've got blood...
and short dark hairs
caught in the wood.
Could be Jason's.
We've got tags.
Blood smear.
That's far enough
away from the door.
It's possibly
a separate event.
Toys and candy.
Somebody's kids
were playing here.
Sofia...
A dental bridge.
Two premolars.
Grandpa lied through his teeth.
Recognize these?
You brought me way down here to
show me a picture of my teeth?
Huh?
The least you could do is
give 'em back.
Remember those dogs...
you were so interested in?
Well, they led us to
an abandoned house,
not far from where you live,
and that's where
we found your teeth.
We also
found physical evidence--
blood evidence--
that tells us that your
grandson and Lucas--
You think you're
real smart, lady.
Don't you?
Before I start thinking
you killed those boys,
why don't you tell
me what happened.
I was defending myself.
Against a pair of sixth graders?
You're damn right.
Two boys can cause
a lot of damages.
Especially that Lucas.
Hey, hey, hey!
Dinner was at 5:00,
now it's cold-- let's go!
We don't want your food.
We're going to eat at my house.
My dad said I could stay
with Lucas and his mom.
I like it better there.
Don't you lie to me, boy.
I'm not lying.
I wish you weren't
my grandpa.
Don't talk to me
like that again.
(Terrance grunts)
They had it coming.
Those boys have no respect.
They're punks.
Now, I love my son,
but he didn't do right by Jason.
So you thought you'd
beat respect into him.
I don't need a lecture about
how to discipline my grandson.
That's the trouble
with parents today,
they're afraid of
their own kids.
Sounds like they were
afraid of you.
That's the way
it's supposed to be.
What happened
after the altercation?
They ran off.
You don't want to eat,
you go hungry.
That's how you learn.
Why didn't you tell us
this before?
I told you
what was important, lady.
Now those boys are
going to be fine.
What they're trying to do,
they're trying to punish me.
That's what they're
trying to do.
And you'll see,
they'll be back.
And then I will sit down
and I will talk to Jason.
Now, what about my teeth?
They're evidence.
We'll give them back to you
when we're done.
It was self-defense
and you can't charge me.
Okay, I'll let you go.
Until we find the boys.
Well, how am I
supposed to get home?
You took my car, too.
There's a bus stop
down the street.
Where is he?
What did you do?
You better watch your tone.
You swore you wouldn't
lay a hand on him.
You better
get out of my face boy.
Are you Gerald Crowley?
Jason's dad?
Yes, ma'am.
Did you know this
man is a bully?
Big college football
coach until
he got caught abusing
his own players.
Almost got thrown
in jail.
You just had to take care
of him for a few months.
What the hell is wrong with you?
Okay,
let's go talk some place.
I swear...
If you hurt Jason...
I will kill you.
♪ ♪
It's a gas
container.
Yeah.
I found it melted
to the floorboard.
People are so predictable.
Lucky for us.
You want me to go
to the station,
and repeat all the
facts I already told you.
If you want
to file a formal complaint
to make it official, yes.
Oh, is that a Red
Cross voucher?
I'll call and make a hotel
reservation for you.
I got to go
to the bathroom.
You want me to
leave the door open?
I'm too old
for you.
(phone line rings)
Grissom.
Yeah, Gil, yeah.
He's agreed to come to the PD.
But I can't keep him there long,
so let's ratchet it up a notch
and get something
to hold him on, all right?
Carl Fisher's on his
way in to the station
to sign off on
his arson claim.
Brass needs something
from us to hold him.
Yeah, if he's got
those kids stashed somewhere,
he could try
to take them out of
state.
Or worse.
I wish I had more.
The burned shoe impression
was a size 11.
Carl Fisher wears
a size 11.
But none of the
patterns match up.
And the shoes that Sara
found near the sofa...
I can't even
identify a brand.
Sorry.
(rock music blasting)
Didn't we talk about
this once before, Greg?
I'm the one who
turned the music on.
GRISSOM:
What have you found?
A gas container.
As the heat melted
the plastic,
it formed pockets,
trapping the gasoline inside.
And if Hodges can
isolate any unique
compounds from the gas,
you know, like, gas DNA.
Gasoline comparisons
are only credible if
you have pure samples.
Otherwise, there's
too many variables.
I know that, Grissom.
What I've extracted was never
exposed directly
to the fire.
So, if we can identify
either a dye,
or a unique compound,
and match it to
a particular station,
then we might be able to prove
whether Carl set the fire.
I'll get this to Hodges.
Greg's got the Coroner's
Inquest coming up.
He's been under a lot of stress.
Maybe you could
be a little nicer
to him.
I just want to find these boys.
Okay.
Carl Fisher, apparently...
...eats and drinks in
the backseat of his car.
I found it in
a seat pocket.
Fruit punch?
Or a mixer.
Whiskey-- I did not
find the bottle.
And... so?
Mushrooms, picked off
a cheese pizza.
I found it stuffed
between the cushions
in the backseat
of the car.
If you're an adult, and
you don't like mushrooms,
you don't order them.
Oh, did I tell you, you
can't check into the hotel
till after 4:00.
I'll find something to do.
Well, I'm wondering
if you might hang out
and volunteer
your services here.
Isn't that what you do?
Talk to groups about
sexual deviancy?
You want me to help
you do your job?
Help you find those
missing kids?
Yeah, that's what I want.
So you going to
help us out or what?
I may be able to
offer some insights.
But only if I can talk
to the other guy.
I'm a victim of abuse.
My older brother.
I was eight.
He was much older-- 16.
He was jealous and angry.
He wanted to destroy me.
It's not offered
as an excuse,
but it might explain
why I'm here
with you right now.
These are known child
molesters living
within our
search radius.
I met him in prison.
He's an environmental offender.
Situational.
Only molests members
of his own family.
Small world--
he's in my support group.
Your boys are too ripe for him.
He likes toddlers.
A couple of these guys
are mysopeds--
aggressive pedophiles.
Some of their pleasures derive
from physical violence.
They like to molest,
then beat, and sometimes
kill their victims.
But these guys aren't killers.
Who said the boys were dead?
They've been gone a long time.
(cell phone chimes)
Bad news?
OFFICER:
Sir, you're gonna
have to stand back.
You're gonna have to
stand back, ma'am.
(screams)
There's a scrape
on his left cheek.
Yeah, there's some
minor bruising
on the knuckles
of his right hand.
Probably
a defensive wound.
Catherine found some
brown fabric on a fence nearby.
I bet it's from these shorts.
Hey, super, you didn't
leave this shirt inside out
when you took it
off the body,
did you?
No.
Could be a redress.
Yeah. Yeah, it could.
Okay...
Well, SAE kit should tell us
whether or not
he was molested.
Sometimes this job gets to me.
Yeah, me, too, buddy.
Me, too.
Grandpa play golf?
I think golf's a little
too rich for his blood.
Doesn't mean he didn't
follow them here.
A killer wouldn't
take time
to bury him that way,
it was too nice.
It suggests
whoever killed him
cared about him,
knew him, you know?
Well, my money's still
on the pedophile.
A ten-year old could
fit in there, huh?
Jason's a skinny kid.
(indistinct police radio
communication in distance)
I didn't see this boy
at the pizza place,
but I remember the little guy.
He had a fat lip.
I asked him where he got it.
What did he tell you?
He said his
grandfather was a bully.
I started to walk out
with him and I was worried.
But he swore he was safe.
With friends.
Did you see who
he was with?
Some white guy.
It was pretty dark.
And there was no
one else with him?
Not that I saw.
But they ordered
an extra-large
with everything--
and that's 18 slices-- and
a full liter of cherry soda.
If it matters, they sat
in the parking lot
for a while.
Is there anything you can
remember about the car?
Make? Color?
It was a Mercury Marquis.
Are you positive?
Yeah.
My boyfriend's a street...
uh, he's into cars, so...
I know cars.
No sand in his nasal
passages or lungs.
He was dead before
he was buried.
Are those palm prints
on his sternum?
Consistent in position
and pressure with CPR.
Also found air in his stomach.
If you don't tilt
the head back,
the trachea doesn't open.
It forces air into the stomach
instead of the lungs
and that's bad CPR.
Now, what kind of a killer
performs CPR
on their victim?
Well, maybe he didn't
mean to kill him.
His pupils were dilated.
I found a
subdural hematoma
in the left
frontal lobe.
That's your preliminary
cause of death.
I sent samples to
Tox, of course.
Catherine found
blood smear
on the floor
where he was playing.
He has a laceration
on his cheek.
And the grandpa admits
he pushed Lucas down
when he hit his head.
Except that, by itself,
the head injury wouldn't
have been immediately fatal
or necessarily
incapacitating.
But, yeah, he would've
had a headache.
Hey, got some gasoline
samples for you.
Thanks, Greg. It's gonna
take a little while
to fill my tank.
Why don't I get
you a funnel?
Kidding.
You think your arson case
has something to do
with these missing kids?
Well, Carl Fisher lives
in the neighborhood,
but, so far,
his alibi checks out.
I don't know why pedophiles
just don't kill themselves.
Who knows,
he might have tried.
I collected these
from service stations
closest to his house.
Did you consider...
That he might have filled up
on his way to work
or anywhere else in Vegas?
Yes-- that's why
I wanted to get you
started on these
before I hit the other
stations on the list.
Good job, gas-hopper.
Okay, then...
...what would you do
if you were going
to take those boys?
I would be studying them.
Do they like sports?
Comic books?
Do they skip school?
Have any friends?
Good parents,
or are they neglected?
Unhappy? Angry?
And then?
What do you do
when you like a woman?
It's a game of seduction.
Once you know what they like,
you make contact.
You start slowly, play it cool.
Especially with boys.
It's about building trust.
Like you're doing with me.
Do you like mushrooms, Carl?
I like all
the nightshade vegetables.
Are you going to buy me dinner?
We found mushrooms
in the backseat of your car.
Is this turning
into an interrogation?
You're free to leave.
On the night the
boys disappeared,
witnesses said they saw
them sitting in a car
with a man,
eating pizza.
You take a date out
to a nice steak dinner.
Kids would rather have
hamburgers or pizza.
Did you take the kids
out for pizza?
No, I'm talking hypothetically.
You must be desperate
for a suspect,
or a scapegoat.
Do you need to give the press
something to chew on?
We just found
Lucas Hanson's dead body.
They're chewing on that.
What about the other boy?
He's still missing.
In my opinion,
if someone killed one boy...
...he'd kill them both.
So, we're working on a couple
of Jason sightings.
Camper in Red Rock
spotted a kid
that looks like Jason,
so I sent Vega.
And Sofia is on her way
to Bullhead City, Arizona.
A woman on a bus
called the cops.
She swears that Jason's
sitting next to her.
That's what I've got.
Any luck with Carl Fisher?
I don't know.
He wants something from me...
or he wouldn't still be here.
♪ ♪
(machine whirs)
SANDERS (on phone):
Sanders?
You can stop gassing up.
I've got a match.
AvCon on Buffalo Canyon.
Pump six.
Where did he board?
Vegas depot.
Was he with anyone?
I'm not gonna
report you.
You can tell me the truth.
Children aren't supposed
to travel alone,
but it was a full bus
when I took off today.
I couldn't tell you.
He was definitely
by himself.
I saw this, I
knew it was him.
DRIVER:
I radioed my dispatcher.
She told me to pullover
at the next town,
make sure he doesn't get off,
and wait for you.
Thank you for your help.
Can you tell me
where he's sitting?
Back row.
Hey.
My name's Sofia. Are you Jason?
There's nothing to be
afraid of, Jason.
You're not in trouble.
I just want to help you.
You're on your way
to Texas to see
your dad, right?
It's just...
well, went you went missing,
your dad flew to Las Vegas
to find you.
He's waiting for you.
Can I take you to him?
BROWN:
Is that the tox report
for Lucas Hanson?
His blood alcohol--
point one six.
Geez. It's a drunk kid.
And Sara found a whiskey cap
in Carl Fisher's car.
Oh, perfect way
to loosen up a little boy--
give him pizza and whiskey.
Yeah, well, listen to this.
According to the report,
Lucas also had 98 micrograms
per milliliter of salicylates
in his system.
Well, I guess
he took the aspirin
after he hit his head.
Wonder who gave him that.
Probably the same
responsible adult
that gave him the whiskey.
FISHER:
So, you think I got
the boys drunk,
and then killed them?
Not exactly.
We found Jason Crowley.
Alive.
On a bus headed
for Houston.
One of the lucky ones.
It's okay, Jason.
Daddy's here, boy.
Daddy's here.
That bus ticket costs $95
for a child under 12.
Jason's grandfather
doesn't keep any cash
in the house, and he doesn't
give him an allowance,
so where do you think
Jason got the cash?
Maybe he stole it.
From whom?
I don't know.
Why don't you ask him?
I will.
Do you get a lot
of migraines, Gil?
You should ask your doctor for
a prescription of sumatriptan.
Works for me.
Captain Brass wants
to put you in a lineup.
If you'll agree to it,
then I think
this will all be over with.
Then let's do it.
(light switch clacks)
SOFIA:
Do you recognize
anyone, Jason?
Which number?
Number two?
Yes.
Was he the man
who kidnapped you and Lucas?
Jason,
remember, you can see him,
but he can't see you.
Did number two
hurt Lucas?
MAN (distant, distorted):
I'll kill your dad
if you tell...
No, ma'am.
The gas DNA panned out.
It did?
Yeah. Hodges and I traced
the gas back
to a service station
near Fisher's house.
Station had security cameras.
Got him filling up
the night of the fire, so I went
through the electronic receipts.
All of them.
Carl Fisher purchased
16 gallons.
And?
His Mercury Marquis
only holds 14,
so, where did he put the extra
two gallons?
In a plastic gas can?
All of which he paid for
with his ATM.
Not the same as cash.
Thanks, Greg.
No one has told me
why I'm being detained.
Arson is a felony.
You torched your own car.
We have video
surveillance
and electronic records
that show you purchasing gas
and a gas can.
I was trying
to scam my insurance company.
I needed the money.
You were destroying evidence
of Lucas Hanson
and Jason Crowley in your car.
And I think
you helped kill Lucas.
No, I didn't.
And you're not charging me
for that, so I'm guessing
Jason didn't pick me
out of the lineup.
He told us he knew you.
Kill one, kill both, remember?
If I had killed Lucas,
I would have killed Jason.
(sighs)
Lucas was looking for a father.
His real one was an accident
of biology.
His mother was limited,
always working.
He was lonely.
He found me.
LUCAS:
I see you every day.
You play a lot, huh?
Maybe we can play sometime.
My best friend's
always grounded.
How about tomorrow?
Did you know
that most parents spend less
than 20 minutes a day
of quality time
with their kids?
Lucas was starved
for attention.
All his mother did
was complain about his father
and how he'd abandoned them.
Do you know
what that does to a child?
It doesn't kill them.
Okay, Carl,
just tell me what happened.
(sighs)
Lucas and Jason had gotten
into it
with Jason's grandfather.
He knocked
the boys around.
They ran to Lucas' house,
but couldn't get in,
so they came to me.
(knocking)
(crickets chirping)
I explained to them
that hitting wasn't okay.
I said Jason needed
to call his father
and tell him what was going on.
Did you let them
use your phone?
But they were too upset.
When the grandfather
pushed Lucas, he hit his head.
I gave him a couple
of aspirin.
Well, if he didn't want
to call his mother,
why didn't you call her?
I couldn't risk it.
She might have turned me in.
So, instead,
you took them for pizza?
I didn't touch him.
I didn't want to hurt him.
You gave him liquor.
I stopped and bought
some whiskey before we picked up
the pizza-- I was nervous about
them being in the car with me.
I didn't want
to go back to prison.
And you wanted
to get them drunk.
They... They just wanted
to try it.
I gave them a taste.
GRISSOM:
It was more than a taste, Carl.
Lucas' blood alcohol level
was point one six.
That's twice the legal limit
for an adult.
Why didn't you take them home?
They didn't want to go home.
They wanted an adventure.
I promised them a dollar
for every golf ball
they brought back.
Lucas wasn't feeling well, so
he stayed in the car with me.
GRISSOM:
And you knew that Jason
wanted money, so he could go
to Texas and see his dad,
so you bribed him in order
to be alone
with Lucas.
I didn't molest him.
Who took his shirt off?
He was hot.
What were you
gonna do to him
once his shirt was off?
It was innocent.
He wasn't feeling well.
He laid
his head in my lap.
I touched his hair.
I didn't want to...
I loved him.
I loved Lucas,
and he loved me.
Is that what you think?
Then why didn't
you help him?
He told you he hit his head.
He was in pain.
He had a concussion, Carl.
You must have
known that.
I'm sure he was dizzy,
probably had no appetite.
Maybe he was even
slurring his words,
but you didn't
care about that,
because you wanted
what you wanted.
(panting)
Lucas?!
GRISSOM:
His brain was bleeding.
Now, most kids won't die
from that,
because someone
who really loves them
takes them to the hospital,
but instead, you gave him
alcohol and aspirin,
a lethal combination
for his head injury.
It prevented his
blood from clotting.
You killed him, Carl.
And you would have killed
Jason, too,
except he ran away from you
and crawled into a drain pipe.
Hey.
(panting)
Hey, what are you
doing in there?
You're not listening to me.
I didn't want to hurt anyone.
I need you to believe me.
I don't.
You had choices.
You made the wrong ones.
And now this little boy is gone.
BRASS:
So I talked Voris
into violating parole,
and we're adding the charges
of negligent homicide.
You're not gonna see
Carl for a long time.
Also, we, uh...
we've arrested
the grandpa, Terrance
Crowley, for child abuse.
Everybody wins.
Except Lucas.
You're gonna fry.
You drove him
right to it...!
You did this!
I'll kill you!
MARGARET FINN:
Where is Carl Fisher?
You can't take
him to County...
Mr. Crowley's
civil rights were violated.
This department
is racist.
FINN:
Excuse me! I
was here first.
My client has been
detained illegally.
LEWIS:
You cannot
charge Mister...
(faint, indistinct voices
and laughter in the distance)
(sighs)