(quiet, eerie tones
and rhythms playing)
♪ ♪
(eerie tones and rhythms
slowly fade)
Mr. and Mrs. Decomp?
Till death do
they centrifuge.
Yeah, I do know how
to read a calendar.
I know when you're due in court.
I just have a backlog
of my own here.
Well, when Riley left, it just
kind of took us all by surprise.
She just left us
with a hundred open cases,
and we're shorthanded.
But I'll get to yours
as soon as I can.
(snaps phone shut)
(sighs)
(clunk)
What is this for?
I am training myself to...
identify different knife wounds.
Do you know how much
ballistics gel costs?
Don't worry.
I'm gonna melt it down
and reuse it.
You've had quite
the busy summer.
"Advanced Non-Invasive
Tissue Imaging."
"Raman Microspectroscopy."
You're already two courses
over your training allotment
for the whole year.
Yes, which is why I paid
for them myself, and...
took my vacation time...
to do them.
I know.
I like the attitude.
You're now officially a CSI-2.
Congratulations.
(phone ringing)
BRASS:
Well, this one'll put you
off driving for a while.
We've got one fatality,
and another circling the drain.
The driver of the SUV's
from L.A.-- prior DUI.
Why the red flag?
Yeah, it's a lot of press
for a traffic accident.
They're here for her.
Oh, man!
That's Olivia Hamilton.
The actress?
Yeah.
I just saw her
in that pool hustler movie
with Robert Downey, Jr.
I liked her.
MAN (in distance):
No! No! Move! Move!
Olivia!
Sir, wait here.
No!
I have to see her!
No traffic cameras.
Typical for this part of town.
What is it, Ray?
Pulverized rubber.
Tire dust.
The driver of the SUV
kept his foot on the gas
after he crashed
into the other vehicle.
MAN:
We got a pulse.
This is one lucky
son of a gun.
Let's get him
out of here stat.
(wheezing)
STOKES:
Looks we may have an eyewitness.
That should add to the circus.
Doesn't really matter
what he has to say.
Everything we need to know...
is right here in front of us.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you, are you!
I'm still learning
About myself, my craft.
I guess with every new role,
I try and stretch myself
a little bit more
because...
I think the minute
you stop learning...
you're dead.
♪ ♪
(camera shutter clicking)
WILLOWS:
There's no scoring
and no horizontal
scrape marks on her car.
Hey, come on, people!
Stay back!
Back behind the line!
Let's go!
And there are none
on the bumper of the SUV, so...
she was stopped when he hit her.
(camera clicking)
(helicopter flies over,
siren wails in distance)
LANGSTON:
These yaw marks indicate
a gradual turn
through the intersection.
There's no fresh
braking marks, man.
This SUV didn't
even try to stop.
(whoosh, then crash)
Maybe he passed out,
lost control
of the vehicle.
If he did that, then how'd
he keep his foot on the gas?
(phone rings)
Busy morning.
We've got a possible 420
at a weekly on...
Boulder Highway.
Greg, you take it.
Are you serious?
You're sending me on a trash run
to a fleabag motel?
What's the problem?
Why me? I mean, there are
people here with less seniority.
Present and
accounted for.
It's all right.
I'm happy to do it.
STOKES: No, no, that's
not the point, Ray.
When your supervisor
assigns you a case,
you don't whine about it,
you take it; he knows that.
Who asked you?
Nick, I need you over here.
You know better than that.
Greg, why don't
you go around the other
side of the vehicle.
Fine.
Captain, I'm Tom O'Neill.
I handle Denny's security
when he's here in the States.
I know who you are.
You mind waiting outside?
Actually,
I'd prefer to stay
with my client.
It won't take long.
(quietly):
All right.
So, uh, Denny...
looks like you hit it pretty
hard at the club last night.
You want something
for that hangover?
Coffee, water,
or anything?
(exhales)
You want to tell me what
Olivia was doing on that road
at 4:00 in the morning?
She was on her way to the set.
She was making a movie.
I see.
Olivia and I,
we've been together,
it would've been a year
this weekend.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry for your loss.
You know, if there's
something we can do...
You can put a bullet in the head
of the guy who killed her.
Mr. Ocampo, let me
give you some advice, okay?
Your father owns a casino.
He probably has
a lot of enemies,
so do yourself a favor:
don't make statements
like that in public.
It'll only come
back to hurt you.
TV NEWSWOMAN:
The film world is reeling
from the untimely death
of Olivia Hamilton.
Her life was cut short
by a car crash
early this morning.
It happened on
an otherwise empty street,
and the lack of eyewitnesses
is slowing down
the police investigation.
One cannot overestimate...
Is the sock
still in it?
Yeah.
No wallet, no I.D.
Was probably robbed
after the murder.
SANDERS: He's been dead
two days, minimum.
Half the department gets
to work a dead hot movie star
in front of the national media,
but we end up on the
wrong side of town
in a scumbag incubator
that's good for at least
a couple of these every week,
wasting our time on a...
On what?
An old man who gets
tossed around this dump
fighting for his life till
he gets his skull smashed in?
Whoever would do this
is worth getting off the street.
Don't you think?
Yeah.
Definitely.
Sorry.
♪ ♪
Seven Hills Mortuary?
Yep, this one's yours.
That's quite the ghoulish hobby
you got there, Doc.
I'm quite the ghoul.
She had a bit part in a
Sex and the City I saw.
Even then, I could tell
she was going to be a star.
Well, now,
she'll never grow old.
C.O.D. was internal hemorrhage
from a transection
of the descending aorta.
Classic for a side impact.
Tox?
Preliminary's clean.
She was pregnant.
Fetus measured
19 millimeters.
Eighth week.
That's long enough
for her to know.
Thank you.
MAN:
It's just not fair.
A loser like that taking the
life of a talented young woman.
I'd be stunned if his BAC
came back under point one.
I could smell the booze
on his clothes.
Is he going
to make it?
Ah, he's not dead yet, which is
a minor miracle in itself.
His C-2 vertebra was crushed.
Hangman's fracture.
Classic hyperextension injury.
Paramedics said he wasn't
wearing his safety belt.
So the airbag probably
hit the side of his face,
twisting the neck.
(bones crackle)
Hmm. And somehow the drunk
manages to survive.
ECKLIE:
Heard from some uniforms
that you guys
had a little dust-up
at the scene.
It was just a spirited debate
among colleagues.
My team's very passionate
about their work.
Yeah, they're also understaffed
and have been for a while,
which is why I'm adding
another CSI to your shift.
Ugh, Conrad.
I don't have time
to train anybody new.
Don't worry. This one's
been around the block.
You're going to
get along just fine.
ANDREWS:
Richard Wilkes had
a blood alcohol level
of point one-eight;
he also had GHB
in his system to the tune
of 60 milligrams per liter.
Guy obviously
liked to party.
Copy that.
Think it's safe to say
his judgment was impaired.
This could be the culprit.
Henry...
find out what that is
for me, please.
LANGSTON:
According to the SMDs,
Wilkes traveled 3.2 miles
from his last engine stop.
Now, how do you drive
that far, that wasted,
and still stay on the road?
Individual tolerances vary.
Just ask Keith Richards.
Want to take a
look at this?
Yes.
"Dearest Richard,
thank you for your letter.
"It was so sweet and so real.
Love, always, Olivia."
This wasn't some random drunk
accidentally slamming
into a famous actress.
He was stalking her.
The call sheet that we found
in Olivia Hamilton's car
indicates the time that she was
due on the movie set,
along with a map from her hotel
to the location.
The same information was
on Richard Wilkes' computer.
We think he hacked
into the film company's
virtual production office.
He knew where she was gonna be
and when she was gonna be there.
In other words, he ambushed her.
Mm-hmm.
Maybe.
There are some inconsistencies.
Like what?
The duct tape, the rope,
the knife we found--
all these things suggest that
Wilkes was thinking to
kidnap Olivia, that he wanted
to possess her.
His crashing his car
into hers without
wearing a seat belt
makes it seem like
he was suicidal.
The man was intoxicated.
Well, celebrity stalkers
who kill are driven by
an overwhelming desire
to achieve fame
by murdering someone
who's famous.
If he killed himself
at the same time as Olivia,
he would've missed his chance
to bask in the limelight.
ECKLIE:
All right, look, guys,
I got a press conference
in an hour,
and I'd rather not say something
I'll have to backtrack on
later on.
Did Wilkes intentionally
kill Olivia Hamilton?
I'd say so.
I doubt it.
Maybe you should cancel
the press conference.
(insistent beeping)
Well, looks like we got someone
who can clear things up.
Richard...
Hey, Richard.
My name is Jim Brass.
Oh...
I'm a detective.
Do you know why you're here?
I killed Olivia.
Yeah, you did.
How'd that happen?
We spoke with the people
Olivia works with.
They said you went by the set
the day before,
asking to see her.
She got you booted off the set.
So you get mad and...
you went to an intersection
where you knew she would be.
She rolls up,
stops at a light.
"Love always...
Olivia."
What?
Her letter.
She loved herself.
Yeah, right.
STOKES:
This angle is looking
straight down Bridger.
Unfortunately,
the crash site itself
is obscured, but I figured,
you know, see what we can see.
And where did
this come from?
A patrolman noticed
a camera on a warehouse
about a quarter-mile
from the intersection.
Okay, this is about
the time the accident
was reported to 911.
I'll roll it back.
Dr. Langston, these
just came for you.
Shooting Review Board?
Yeah.
(sighs)
They cleared me.
Good.
Kill or be killed, Ray.
It's a terrible situation
to be in, man.
Don't let it bother you.
It hasn't been bothering me.
And that's what's been
bothering me.
LANGSTON:
That's Olivia's car.
(taps key)
That's her, all right.
I'll roll it forward.
Now she's approaching the
intersection at Hasbrook.
Damn, if that camera were
just a couple feet higher,
we could see
the crash.
Light turns red,
she stops at the intersection.
That puts the crash time at
3:27 a.m.
Yeah...
but look at all
the lights on Bridger.
They're all green,
except for hers.
So?
So I know that street
pretty well.
Those traffic signals
are synced.
Her light should be green,
like the rest of them.
What's the white light
on the traffic signal?
That's a confirmation light
for a traffic signal preemption.
Looks like somebody overrode
the normal timing,
forcing Olivia's light
to turn red.
Making her a sitting duck.
HODGES: Tom O'Neill,
Guardian of the Stars?
Hey.
David Hodges.
Uh, w-we met at Lavo.
The CineVegas after-party.
You were parting the seas
for Tarantino.
Uh...
Actually, it was, uh,
outside of Lavo.
I couldn't get past the rope.
Next time,
you flash this.
That'll get you inside.
Thanks.
Always glad to help
a brother in blue.
Where are we at with Wilkes?
Oh, uh, yeah, he confessed.
But we're not sold on it.
Something just doesn't add up.
Denny, you okay?
Hi.
(nervous laugh)
Gentlemen.
They're ready downstairs.
WILLOWS:
David.
Sorry, we are
really backed up.
STOKES:
The only way
anybody could change
Olivia's traffic light
is with
an infrared emitter.
LVPD and fire department
emitters
are coded for identification.
Uncoded emitters
are against the law.
D.O.T. records confirm
that at 3:27 a.m., an uncoded
MIRT infrared emitter
preempted the signal
at Bridger and Hasbrook.
(tires screech)
If Wilkes was using
an illegal emitter,
why didn't we find it
in his car or at the scene?
What are you thinking, Ray?
I'll tell you if I can prove it.
Are you a reporter?
I'm from the crime lab.
Oh.
I heard there are a lot
of reporters out there.
They're all here
to talk to me, you know?
Everybody wants
to talk to me now.
They've even been bothering
the poor nurses.
I feel so exploited.
They're not interested
in discovering
who I really am.
They just want
to make money off me.
I watched a segment
on TV la...
Your O2 sat is very low,
Mr. Wilkes.
Oh. Oh...
Now you're in perfectly good
hands. I am a doctor.
I mean, I was a doctor
until I was forced
out of my profession.
It was one of those angel
of death things, you know?
Huh?
You see, no one really
understood the real me.
A-And what...?
Would you close
your eyes for me?
(laser beeps)
And try to relax.
Oh, wait a minute.
Shh. This will be over
in just a moment.
ALS revealed subcutaneous
bruising on Wilkes' torso.
STOKES:
Looks like a seat belt injury.
First responder said
he wasn't wearing a seat belt.
I know.
Look, the bruising runs
from his right shoulder
to his left hip.
That means Wilkes
was in the passenger seat.
He wasn't
driving the car.
The real driver crashes into
Olivia Hamilton, killing her.
I don't think the crash
broke Wilkes' neck.
I think the killer moved
a drugged-out Wilkes
behind the wheel,
then snapped his neck.
Killer leaves the scene.
The headline is,
"Stalker Kills Actress."
Which suggests that the killer
knew that Wilkes was a stalker.
Well, he certainly picked
the right nut job.
Even though Wilkes survived,
he still confessed to the crime.
Can Wilkes corroborate
any of this?
Oh, he won't.
He's too happy being
the new Mark David Chapman.
I really hope you're referring
to Richard Wilkes.
I wasn't.
Where'd they get
this from?
I don't know. You tell me.
I don't know.
It's your job to know,
Catherine.
Nobody in this lab
should be talking
to anybody in the media
about an open investigation,
let alone one
of this profile.
Hey, take it easy,
Ecklie.
I'm sure she's not the leak.
I can defend myself.
This is a discipline problem,
Catherine.
Just get a grip on your people.
I'm beginning to think
Riley was right about you.
What is that supposed
to mean?
You didn't read
her exit interview.
I put it on your desk.
What?
Just read it.
Uh, hi, guys.
This a bad time?
LANGSTON:
Nice to meet you,
and I look forward
to working with you.
Thanks. Me, too.
STOKES:
I'll see you
later, yeah?
Yeah.
So let's grab a bite
after the shift.
Okay.
Sara!
What are you doing here?
You tired of being
happy and married?
No, Grissom is guest-lecturing
at the Sorbonne
while we're waiting for our
research grant to get funded,
and Ecklie called;
he said the team was down a man
and he wondered if I could
recommend anyone.
And you know,
as much as I love Paris,
and my French is
actually pretty good right now,
I realized I miss you guys.
Well, we miss you, too.
So, uh, how's the world
treating you?
Oh, you know, still being
treated like the lab tech
with the crazy hair.
(sighs)
(man clears throat)
It has ten percent of the FDA's
daily requirement for vitamin C.
If you don't have
your health,
you don't have anything.
Hodges, who did you blab to?
Nobody in the media,
(scoffs)
but I did mention something
to Tom O'Neill.
But only in passing
and implicitly in confidence.
I would point out that I had
not been explicitly forbidden
from discussing
the case
with law enforcement community.
Uh, memo from my supervisor
to that effect
would have been helpful,
not that I'm
blaming you.
Don't ever do anything
like that ever again.
Thank you.
STOKES:
I know Richard Wilkes
stayed here. You remember him?
Uh, you know, I guess
I recognize him.
You know, he looks like
a lot of guys that stay here.
Sir, please, it's important.
Think a little bit harder.
Are you sure you didn't see him
with anybody else?
No. All I can say for sure
is that he checked out
two nights ago around
midnight. Paid cash.
All right, thanks.
Sure.
Hey.
Eye-in-the-sky guys delivered
some surveillance video.
Good. 'Cause the manager
confirmed Wilkes stayed here,
but that's about it.
Hey, looks like he managed
to make himself a friend.
STOKES:
Is that...?
That's Tom O'Neill.
Talking to Olivia Hamilton's
stalker
a little over three hours
before she died.
It's funny
he didn't manage
to mention that
to anybody.
STOKES:
Little lie, big lie.
What if O'Neill
was the driver?
If O'Neill was driving,
then how come he didn't get
so much as a scratch
from the airbag opening up
in his face?
BRASS:
Well, rolling the dice.
That's a, that's
a different way to grieve.
He has the right to grieve
any way he wants.
Now if there's
any more questions...
Actually,
I have questions for you.
Sure, no problem.
Hang in there, kid.
Did you know
that Olivia was pregnant?
Yes.
You didn't mention that before.
It's none of your business.
We spoke to Olivia's
production office,
and they told us
that you would ride
to the set with her
nearly every morning.
Why not that morning?
I wish I had.
I was gonna give her this.
(trilling)
(beeping)
When I heard about the incident
on Olivia's set,
I put a tail on Wilkes.
I found where
he was staying.
Olivia Hamilton
wasn't your client.
A threat to her
was a threat to Denny.
So I went and had a little chat
with Wilkes.
If you don't leave
Olivia Hamilton alone,
I'm gonna go
to that aerospace plant
where you polish the floors
and I'm gonna show Mr. Segal.
That's right.
I know your boss's name.
I'll show Mr. Segal my card,
and I'll tell him to fire you.
He'll ask me why.
And I'll say because you're
a stalker and a psycho.
And then he'll fire you.
Then I'll go to my cop friends,
and I'll get
a restraining order.
And when you violate it--
because sooner or later
you will--
I'm gonna throw your ass
in jail.
I impressed him
with my sincerity,
and he agreed to leave town.
I walked him back
to his room.
I helped him pack,
and I put him in his car
and I followed him
to the I-15 on-ramp.
Watched him get back
on the road to L.A.
Apparently not for long.
You can understand
why I didn't tell you
all this before.
No, I understand.
You lean on a guy,
the guy flips out,
kills your client's girlfriend.
That can't look good
on your resumé.
I-I couldn't afford the hit.
I got six hungry bookies
to feed.
Oh, yeah, sure.
Hey...
what's in the bag?
Workout stuff.
I was at the gym.
11:30 at night?
Crazy hours I pull,
you grab a little cardio
whenever you can.
Well, let's just see
if that's true.
I assume you had a warrant
for that?
Oh, sure, we're professionals.
Mr. O'Neill,
I have to say
that your hotel suite
was very impressive.
The Ocampo family
clearly values your services.
Now why are you carrying around
this helmet?
I use that for a tactical
driving course I teach.
And can you tell me what
that white powdery substance is?
Uh-uh.
We are testing it, of course.
Here's my prediction.
It's airbag dust.
Tactical driving,
you bump into things.
Airbags go off.
They also go off when you ram
a young woman's car
and crush her
to death.
Now, maybe Denny loved Olivia.
I don't know.
But I bet
his father in Macao didn't.
Not with Denny's record.
Another pregnant bimbo,
another multimillion-dollar
settlement.
Mr. Ocampo, who pays your
salary, who finances your...
Flamboyant.
...lifestyle,
I think he asked you
to find a more
cost-effective way
of dealing with the situation,
and so you did.
Too bad for you
Wilkes already confessed.
I want a lawyer.
LANGSTON:
Hodges confirmed
that the dust we found
in the helmet
was airbag talc.
Which only puts O'Neill in half
of all cars with airbags.
He's guilty, Catherine.
Okay, how are we
gonna prove it?
I don't know yet,
but we will.
I like his attitude.
Reminds you of you?
I checked companies
that sell Murray emitters
against O'Neill's
credit card statements.
No joy. He could
have his own emitter.
The old ones aren't coded.
So what's next?
(sighs)
Sara, I know that you walked
into some fireworks
in the break room.
What, Ecklie? Please.
No, I just read
Riley's exit interview.
She had some harsh things
to say about my leadership;
that the team's
fractured;
that it lacks cohesion
because of me
because of my
managerial style.
I don't know. I-I admit it.
I admit that things are
different since Grissom left.
Well... it's like...
when a great baseball team
loses its clean-up hitter,
suddenly everybody's
swinging for the fences
and nobody's playing small ball.
You're using a baseball analogy.
Apparently,
part of being married
is attempting to share
in your spouse's interests.
(chuckles)
Okay.
That's a weird side of you.
I know.
Look, you still have
a lot of great players
and some new talent.
Maybe you just need
to reshuffle your lineup.
English, please.
You are a great CSI, Catherine,
and you know
how to manage your team.
The only thing Grissom had
that you don't...
is you.
Oh, God.
Hey, who are you?
Hello? Excuse me, excuse me.
Hey, hey, stop!
What the hell
is going on here?!
(speaking Russian)
Security!
(yelling indistinctly)
(gunfire)
You okay?
Are you okay?
(indistinct radio transmission)
On your feet!
Settle down!
The doctor said both of
our people are stable.
SIDLE:
Good.
Okay, I got the van's plate
number out on broadcast
and Ecklie's handling the press.
Any idea who they were?
Well, they're not morticians,
no matter what their IDs say,
and these...
are Russian mob tattoos.
BRASS:
Which means we're going to get
a lot more out of him
than we will out
of any of the survivors.
The IDs looked legit
so the security guard let them
in through the loading dock.
They snatched the body.
When they tried to leave
the same way they came in,
they found the doors blocked
by a double-parked truck.
So they found
another way out, okay.
But why risk breaking
into a lab filled with cops
to steal Olivia Hamilton's body?
They didn't take
Olivia Hamilton.
They took my bum?
But we don't even
know who he is.
Well, clearly they do.
Hey, guys, you're not
going to believe this.
The DNA from
your John Doe
just came back with a parental
match to an open case.
That bum is
Olivia Hamilton's father.
DISPATCH:
All units be advised,
suspect vehicle
in the lab break-in
was recovered on Westcroft Drive
at mile marker 214,
Mount Charleston.
Hey.
Oh, no.
This doesn't look good.
(flies buzzing)
STOKES: Well, so much
for Olivia Hamilton's father.
Ugh.
It might not be him.
SIDLE:
Mmm. (coughs, clears throat)
You, uh, care to rethink that?
SANDERS:
According to James Hamilton's
medical records,
he was a diagnosed schizophrenic
prone to violent outbursts.
Olivia Hamilton
was his only child,
and she did the best she could
taking care of him,
but he was in and out
of institutions
and on and off the streets
for years.
Now from what I can tell,
their relationship
was never made public.
It's a minor miracle she was
able to keep it out of the tabs.
That might have been
about to change.
We found these shots
on O'Neill's camera.
Recovered JPEGs
from the SD card.
They were taken
in front of the weekly
where James Hamilton
was living
two days before
Olivia Hamilton's death.
We got O'Neill's financials.
Like we figured, Denny's father,
Mr. Moneybags from Macau,
pays his salary.
One week ago,
O'Neill receives
an unusually large deposit--
a hundred grand--
wired from an Asian bank.
Maybe paying him to break up
Denny's latest romance.
O'Neill shadows Olivia,
trying to dig up some dirt.
Follows her to the weekly
where she meets up with
this very strange old man.
He could be a drug dealer.
Who knows?
But it looks like the perfect
material to incite a break-up.
So he takes a couple shots
of them.
But he's curious.
So he goes to the room
to talk to the guy
and see what the story is.
Hamilton freaks out.
They fight and O'Neill
ends up killing him.
Now O'Neill's a murderer--
under stress.
And a delusional stalker
provides him
with the perfect way
to get Olivia out
of Denny's life permanently.
It's reasonable.
But it's just speculation.
We can't nail O'Neill
for either death.
The only reason O'Neill
would risk stealing the body
is if he believed
it could somehow implicate him,
which means there has to be
evidence on the body
or in the body.
(sighs)
(sniffs)
Ugh.
Oh.
(chuckles)
James Hamilton swallowed
something
when O'Neill beat him
to death.
Greg found clothing fibers
in his teeth.
We're looking for this cufflink.
If O'Neill knew
what happened,
why not take the body
right then and there?
WILLOWS:
He didn't know,
not until he came here
and saw James Hamilton's body.
STOKES:
We've been separating
metals and inorganics.
So... Here, this may be it.
We got him.
WOMAN:
Las Vegas Police have arrested
Tom O'Neill,
a bodyguard
often seen protecting
the biggest celebrities,
including Denny Ocampo.
Funny thing is,
the father's death
was probably an accident.
But Olivia was
premeditated.
Irritates me that we weren't
able to get him for that.
But you know what?
We know what he did
and so does he,
and he can spend
the next 20 years
of his life
dreaming of his
perfect crime.
Think of it like busting
Al Capone for tax evasion.
(cricket chirping)
How did you now he was
going to be hungry?
It doesn't
really matter.
They go after crickets
no matter what.
I think the chirping
annoys them.
That's not my spider, dude.
Seriously?
Seriously.
Is that...?
Little Stevie?
Oh, he's been missing for years.
I'll have to let Sara know
so she can tell her...
husband.
Husband.
WILLOWS:
Hey, Nicky.
Yeah.
You got a sec?
What's up?
Oh, something
that's long overdue.
I don't tell you enough, Nicky,
but I couldn't do this job
without you.
Okay.
Love you too, Catherine.
I am promoting you.
You are now assistant
supervisor on grave.
All right. Thanks.
Please have these FI reviews
on my desk
by tomorrow night.
What's up, Doc?
Well, just business as usual,
I'm delighted to say.
This gentleman has been in
the cooler for a couple days.
Joseph Bigelow.
No known address.
Apparently, spent most of his
time downtown in the streets.
No signs of trauma.
My guess is his ticker probably
decided to call it quits.
Whoa.
What the hell is that?
I was hoping
you'd tell me.