You guys, ready?
(women laughing)
(man laughing)
Yes!
(coins clattering)
(indistinct chattering)
Seven.
Yes!
(cheering)
Yes. Yes.
Pay it. Pay it.
(laughter)
I already ejected the guest
from the show.
You don't need to do anything.
Just send him down.
Tell him to meet me
at the front desk.
(elevator bell dings)
MAN:
What's your floor, honey?
WILLOWS:
17.
Who gets thrown out
of a lingerie show
in Vegas?
I mean, what is the point
of having live girls
if you can't touch them?
I flew all the
way from Omaha.
Hi.
Hey.
(laughs)
MAN:
Well, everybody's
getting lucky tonight.
(door closes)
Sorry, close call.
Too close.
Where's the setup?
It's in here.
Our first suspect,
Everett Edwards,
decided to bring the
party back to the room.
Had to get our guys
out of there fast.
I passed Greg
and Archie in the hall.
They got out of
there just in time.
But they didn't finish.
WOMAN:
Ooh. Hi.
(door opening)
Wow, look at this place.
Oh. No bathroom cam.
Here's the second suspect,
Bellermine Quisk.
Goes by Bell.
These two guys are the
biggest suppliers of Ecstasy
in the Southwest.
When did they get here?
Everett checked in
around 2:00.
Bell, about an hour ago.
Since then, it's been
all booze and hookers.
Well, there's no chemicals
or apparatus visible.
(woman laughing)
Probably still
in the luggage.
(phone ringing)
Hey, Greg.
SANDERS:
Bathroom cam malfunctioned.
Tell her we can get
a lipstick cam in
the tissue box.
Just need a
little time.
Did you hear that?
Yeah.
But I think the boys
are in for the night.
SANDERS:
Okay.
I'll send Archie back
to the lab.
I'm gonna stick around
in case you need me.
Thanks.
So you get to kick it with
the babes in the casino,
and I get Hodges
at the lab.
Yup.
Sorry.
(phone beeps)
(beeps)
(cries out)
(grunts)
(groaning)
Oh! Oh.
Oh.
Catherine, I think
I got a dead body here.
Uh, there's a-a woman down.
Archie, where exactly are you?
The loading dock.
Her head's bleeding. Uh...
WILLOWS:
Okay, listen to me.
This is what you're going to do.
Stay with the body, don't
let anybody come or go,
and don't touch anything.
Got it.
I don't believe this.
We got a 419
down at the loading dock.
Well... we can't have
a big police presence here.
I'll call it in.
The last thing we need tonight
is a crime scene.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
MAN:
Her name was Sasha Katsaros.
She was one
of our event planners.
Outstanding employee.
You know, everybody loved her.
She'd always go
that extra mile.
What kind of
security do you have
in the, uh, employee
areas, Mr. Thomas?
Call me Finn, please.
Sure.
Well, no cameras, but,
uh, access is restricted
to employees,
key card only.
We're gonna need a list
of all the employees who were
on duty
tonight.
Absolutely.
Did you see
or speak to Miss Katsaros
at any point today?
Yeah. Yeah. Uh, the last time
I saw her was at... 10:00 p.m.
All right, Finn,
can you tell me, uh,
who she was going
that extra mile for?
Yes.
FINN:
His name is Lon Rose.
He's hosting a private
lingerie show in the casino.
And I should mention
that Sasha sometimes brought
angry guests back here
to calm them down.
Thanks.
I want everyone
behind the crime tape
until we finish
processing the scene.
Anything you need,
you know where to find me.
Thank you.
(indistinct radio transmission)
STOKES:
Dried blood on the stairs.
It looks like she took a tumble.
Archie said her body
was still warm?
LANGSTON: Head of security
said he saw her at 10:00 p.m.
Archie called
Catherine at 11:15.
That gives us a 75-minute
window for time of death.
PHILLIPS:
Hey.
He's looking
kind of green.
SANDERS:
How you doing, man?
First DB's the hardest.
(indistinct radio transmission)
PHILLIPS:
Huh.
Neck feels broken.
She's got a four plus one
on the left forearm.
STOKES: Yeah, same thing
on the other arm.
Thumbs on the inside,
fingers on the outside.
Stop!
Whoever grabbed her
was facing her.
Hey. I, uh, told Archie
to go to the lab
and check in his clothes
and then head to the station
and give his statement.
He's, uh, a little
shook up, but
he'll be okay.
He did have one
unusual observation.
David,
can you please confirm
if the vic
has, uh... gone commando?
Sure.
(indistinct radio transmission)
No underwear.
Why was he looking
up her skirt to begin with?
He was just being thorough.
LANGSTON:
The killer might have taken
the panties as a souvenir,
which means
this wasn't an accident.
Okay.
Be sure and collect
an SAE kit, huh, Super?
I know. Just make sure
that no one enters the casino
with vests, radios or uniforms.
We can't have any mistakes.
STOKES: Copy that.
How's the stakeout going?
Well, so far,
it's like watching bad porn.
All right, talk to you later.
Keep me in the loop, Nicky.
Will do.
I just don't get
these two idiots.
They're born
into money.
They graduated
good schools.
Their daddies
paid for it all.
Sounds like you've got an issue
with rich people.
No.
I got an issue with
rich kids killing
poor kids.
These guys were
in Tahoe last week.
They were peddling bunny tabs
laced with DXM.
Cough suppressant.
Causes hallucinations,
inhibits sweating,
raises body temperature.
You add E and a hot dance party,
you got yourself
a heart attack before
you're old enough to vote.
And with their
background,
they probably didn't cut the E
to save money.
Trying to
distinguish their product,
make it a stronger trip.
And Bell, his profile
is even more disturbing.
This kid,
he gets off on anything taboo.
He is a crazy bastard.
And what makes you guys think
they cook in hotels?
Tahoe PD found
an empty can of ether
and some broken glassware
in their hotel room,
but that's not enough
to bust them.
So we got to catch
them in the act?
Just... not that act.
(moaning on video)
Nothing on surveillance.
Did you find anything
in the vic's files?
Yes. She noted an incident
with an angry guest
at the lingerie show,
but no details.
STOKES:
Well, it's a private show.
There has to be a guest list.
Let's get a name.
(Stokes signs)
How do you want
to do this?
Nick!
Hmm?
How do you want
to do this?
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, I'm sorry.
Cheerleaders are my weakness.
I noticed.
Let's find the host
of this shindig.
Divide and conquer.
Yeah.
(sighs):
Oh.
Excuse me, ma'am.
Hi.
Do you know where I could find
a guy named Lon Rose?
It's Brenda.
Brenda?
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
I haven't seen him in a while.
No?
Mm-mm.
Okay.
What do you think about these?
I slept in them all night.
I don't know what to think,
to be honest with you.
I'll take them.
♪ ♪
You looking for
sweet or sour?
Sweet or sour?
(chuckles)
Well, you must be a musk man.
Have I got the perfect
model for you.
You must be Lon Rose.
Yes.
Hi.
I haven't seen you before.
You find us online?
No, my name's Langston.
Langston.
Ray Langston.
I'm with
the Vegas Crime Lab.
I need to speak with you,
Mr. Rose,
about, uh,
a woman named Sasha Katsaros.
You gotta be kidding me.
Pudder called you guys?
Ms. Katsaros was
only doing her job.
Mr. Pudder was out of line.
And who is Mr. Pudder?
A buyer.
See, he started
pawing one of the models
and when he wouldn't stop,
I asked Sasha to eject him.
He tried to sneak
back in, I sent him
downstairs to her and
she took care of it.
Hey. Hey.
You open it,
you own it, pal.
Yeah, I see you.
Uh, I'm happy
to talk to you all night.
Just, uh, let me
take care of business.
Very well.
Okay.
Hey, check it out.
Two grand
for a pair of underwear.
Can you believe that?
Why would you want
to vacuum pack panties?
Well, the vacuum process
removes oxygen, which
preserves the shelf life
and quality of things.
But that's typically food.
(inhales deeply)
"By any other name..."
Get it?
"Would smell as sweet."
Oh!
(inhales deeply)
Oh...
Oh.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
(music playing)
WILLOWS:
He just turned down the AC.
Must be getting
ready to cook.
(light snoring)
Dude...
girl won't quit snoring.
You don't pay hookers for sex,
buddy, you pay them to leave.
Get her out of here.
(knocking on door)
VARTANN:
We got a situation.
Somebody's at the door.
Both suspects have
at least one gun each.
Looks like Everett
has a .357.
And Bell is packing a Colt .45.
BRASS (over radio):
Copy that.
It's a room service waiter
pushing a cart. Looks legit.
More room service?
(groaning)
I forgot, yeah.
You can order online here.
I was craving
cheeseburgers, man.
Don't let him in the room.
We needed more
ice anyway.
Should I
bring it in?
Yeah, I got this.
(door closes)
Hurry up, we got beans to cook.
This isn't a freaking vacation.
That's confirmation.
BELL:
You want a coffee?
Back in college the girls
would always complain
about their underwear being
stolen from the laundry room.
It does give
a whole new meaning
to the term "panty raid."
You know, I spent a
lot of time in Japan.
They actually have,
um, vending machines
filled with used panties.
Vending machines?
Seriously?
I've seen them.
Okay, all right,
so, this guy, Lon Rose,
hosts a fetish show
for men who enjoy
the scent of women's
used underwear?
Right.
And because his clients
are so hardcore,
he vacuum packs them because
it's all about that first whiff.
(chuckling)
Look, we smell with our
brains, not our noses.
Every time we inhale
through our nostrils,
air enters the nasal cavity
which contains millions
of olfactory receptor neurons,
and when scent molecules
lock into the cilia,
it creates an electrical signal
that tells the brain
how to interpret the smell.
We follow our noses.
Exactly.
Odors help us choose our mates,
impacts our sex drive,
alters our hormone levels,
even triggers memories.
For example,
any time I smell nail polish,
I think about my first
girlfriend, Michelle.
It's a long way
from vending machines.
(phone chirps)
They picked up Pudder.
Mr. Pudder, you've got
quite a collection
of women's panties
in your hotel room.
Did you buy all
those at the show?
Yes. And I would've bought more.
That's why I came to Vegas.
Well, you must've been
angry...
when Sasha Katsaros
kicked you out.
She had no right.
Yeah, is that why
you killed her?
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Someone killed
Sasha Katsaros, Mr. Pudder.
Whoever did it took her panties.
You better hope we don't
find her underwear
in your little collection.
I would never go
to a loading dock.
Those places smell horrible.
And anyway,
Miss K... not my type.
So, what is your, um,
your type?
(snickers)
Well...
When it comes to the,
uh, chamber of Venus,
I have a very
sophisticated palate.
You know,
a woman's aroma is...
(inhaling deeply)
(moans)
It's complex,
you know?
And when all of the conditions
are just right...
...there's nothing to compare.
(clearing throat)
Look, why don't you just talk
to that charlatan Lon Rose?
He'll tell you.
I only bought off
of one model.
Brenda.
After all the money
I dropped on her last year,
I slipped a pair
off of her last night--
I'd earned it.
Can you tell us what you did
after you had been
ejected for the
second time?
I hooked up with another buyer,
paid him to buy up
Brenda's whole table.
He dropped off the
merchandise around 11:00...
...and I blissed out in my room
for the rest of the night.
Holed up in your hotel room
with a bunch of women's panties
is not an alibi.
(low chuckle)
If you'd ever tried it,
you'd know it was.
(chuckling)
We're gonna need a sample
of your fingerprints
and your DNA.
Right hand, please.
Is that thing clean?
I hope so.
(beeping)
Sticks.
BELL:
Okay, it's show time.
EVERETT:
Just get the stuff
we need for now.
How long does it take
to make Ecstasy?
(sighing)
Well, let's see.
We could go shoot some craps,
play a little blackjack,
have a long lunch,
go shopping.
Or you could take me
to the new Cirque show.
Maybe dinner.
And... maybe about halfway done.
Wow.
You're not a cheap date.
Not anymore.
No.
(laughing)
Seriously, it all depends
on the recipe
and the, uh, skill of the cook.
Well, it's noon now.
Intel says that it's a surge
that starts at 10:00,
they just don't know where.
I'm assuming surge
is another term for a rave?
The underground scene
uses different terms.
"Surge" is slang
for an inside party.
A "doof" is outside.
Surge because of the feeling
you get from E,
but "doof"?
Doof, it's the sound
that the bass makes
when there are no walls
to reverberate off of.
You know, "doof, doof,
doof, doof."
Yeah, I get it.
(phone chirps)
(clears throat)
Is that a text
from your daughter?
(sighing)
Lindsey wants to visit
a friend at USC.
I said no way,
and she just won't drop it.
She graduates
this year, right?
Well, you'll miss
the fights some day.
Yeah, I know.
I even miss my son's
horrible techno music.
You've never talked
about your son.
Um, Jake.
He just, uh, turned 21.
Yeah, my ex got custody,
but, uh, he was a handful,
so he ended up living with me
for high school.
I always thought
that I was...
you know, better alone,
you know?
But I miss having someone
to come home to.
I didn't mean
to put you on the spot.
Just wanted you to know.
(helicopter blades whirring)
My uncle was obsessed
with the smell
of chocolate chip cookies.
One day my aunt came home
and found him with his head
in the oven,
thought he was
committing suicide.
She realized at that instant
the secret to a happy marriage--
fresh-baked cookies every day.
You're really
kind of freaky, Doc.
(laughs)
Coming from you, I'll take that
as a compliment.
You're welcome.
I found a contusion on her back
and, uh, a couple
of fractured ribs.
It's a partial shoe impression.
David found
a corresponding
mark on her jacket.
No distinguishing
features.
Hmm. So,
our victim
was grabbed
and then kicked.
Let me go! Oh.
(yells)
That would explain
the broken neck
and the, uh,
scalp lacerations.
Vascular birthmark
shaped like a strawberry.
You know, in Arabic
they're called Wiham.
That translates to "wishes,"
and believed to be a sign
of a mother's
unfulfilled dreams.
SIMMS:
Hey.
So, I just finished analyzing
your victim's SAE kit.
Yeah?
I found one plus spermatozoa,
but no indication of trauma.
Okay. She had sex,
but she wasn't raped.
Right.
We know whose it is?
Yeah. It was an unknown male.
It wasn't Pudder.
Is that the bra
she was wearing when she died?
Yeah.
I don't think Pudder
took her panties.
Based on what?
Based on the fact
that I didn't receive
any black underwear like that
with pink satin trim
in any of the lingerie
that was retrieved
from Pudder's room.
And...?
Okay, stay with me.
That right there
is an Amatore bra.
Now, it's really nice,
it's really expensive,
and if a woman buys a bra
like that,
then one, she always buys
the matching underwear,
and two, she wears them
together as a set.
It's a thing.
Maybe it was in the wash.
Yeah. No. She would never put
underwear like that
in a washing machine.
Why not?
Just trust me.
I'm an expert.
WILLOWS: So Bell just
brought in more ice.
They're probably bathing
the condensate.
It's the most dangerous part.
If I'm right,
they just completed
the Wacker oxidation stage
to keep the temperature down.
The chemical reaction
is exothermic,
it gives off a lot of heat.
From this point on,
they've got to keep the mixture
below 40 degrees Celsius
at all times.
Or what? It goes bad?
No.
It explodes.
How you holding up?
Finding that woman's body
was pretty intense.
But... (laughs)
You know, these bodies here
are making that memory
fade pretty fast.
It's all right, Archie.
It gets easier.
(mutters)
I've been going over
Rose's sales
for the last 24 hours.
Quite an inventory.
Let me tell you,
this is one
recession-proof industry.
Enlarge and enhance
this photo for me.
I want a look
at her clavicle.
Yeah.
Our victim had a
strawberry-shaped birthmark.
That is Sasha Katsaros.
Oh, I... I thought she worked
at the hotel.
Apparently, she wasn't making
enough money at her day job.
I'll see you guys
tomorrow, okay?
Mr. Rose?
(clears throat)
There's been a
development
in Sasha Katsaros' case.
Oh, good news.
You caught the guy.
LANGSTON:
We're circling him.
Why didn't you tell us that
Sasha was one of your models?
Well, you didn't ask.
You didn't think
that's important
in a murder investigation?
Look,
she, uh, made me promise.
She loved her job here
at the hotel.
That's... that's why
she never did live modeling.
That's her table, isn't it?
Yeah.
My biggest seller.
Guys went crazy
over her scent.
You guys think my business
is for undersexed husbands
or losers who can't get any?
Yeah, something
like that, yeah.
Well, I might have thought that,
too, if I hadn't met Sasha.
You see, she was my inspiration
for starting the business.
I fell in love
with the way she smelled.
Well, her killer
liked her smell, too.
So much so that he took a pair
of her panties as a souvenir.
This is for you.
There's an officer
outside who will
escort you downtown.
Yeah, we're just going to sniff
around, if you don't mind.
Sasha gave them to me yesterday.
Sasha, darling,
they can't get enough.
I need more product.
(chuckles)
Well, I can't go home.
I'm working.
Well, what about the ones
you're wearing?
I could sell those as fresh.
Get a premium.
(sighs)
Ah.
Oh.
Look, I swear I didn't
kill Sasha. I loved her.
We're going to need
a sample of your DNA.
You think I had sex with her?
Did you?
I would never
have sex with Sasha.
That'd be like scribbling
on the Mona Lisa.
It would kill my business.
And these-- turns out
they're worthless.
Yeah, well, they're not yours
anymore; they're ours now.
Give them to me.
Sex changes a woman's
body chemistry,
which alters the fragrance.
Look, she should've
known better.
But the nose knows.
BELL:
No, no, no, no, l-listen to me.
I don't... no, no, I don't care
how big her boobs are. I...
Oh, I'm so tired
of white chicks. Um...
Give me...
give me an Asian chick.
No, you know what?
Make that two
Asian chicks.
I want...
(phone beeps off)
No more hookers.
Whoa!
We've got to finish.
We only got three hours.
Ev, you've got to relax.
We're the sole suppliers
for this event.
We don't deliver,
they don't roll.
Dude, what's going to happen
if we're five minutes late?
You on a suicide mission, Bell?
We ruin this guy's
surge, we're dead.
He won't care how rich
your daddy is.
Hey, no.
Hey, uh-uh. Don't talk to me
like that, okay?
You owe me. I'm the one
that got us out of the
mess in Tahoe, pal.
You're the one that got us
in the mess...
Oh, come on, no.
Don't put that on me, all right?
You cooked the beans.
You're the one
that screwed up the ratio.
Yeah, 'cause you lied to me
about what you put...
(shouts)
Shut up.
Shut up, Ev.
Shut up, or I will shoot you.
(knocking on door)
If that's room service,
I'm going to shoot you.
Who's at the door?
They are friends of mine.
It is a private sale.
Get rid of them.
I paid for the room,
so just back off.
Belly Bell!
Mmm, Jilly-Jill.
You are looking good.
(Jill giggling)
How you
doing, baby?
Who are you?
You the BF?
We need a hook-up.
Well...
She's obviously trippin' balls,
so you're out of luck.
We're, uh, we're
not ready yet.
I can feel your energy, Belly.
It's, like, ice cream.
I love your soul.
Get off her, man.
(groaning)
Oh, my God, this is amazing.
Get up, Jill.
This is like
the softest thing on Earth.
Now!
Come on, Jill.
Hey!
You're not going anywhere,
except hell.
All right, we got a possible
444 developing here.
Entry team stand by.
(Bell and Jill's boyfriend
speaking indistinctly)
Hey, buddy, you
looking for these?
Yeah.
But first I'm going
to kill your boy here.
Oh, you gotta know, I'm not
going to let that happen.
Besides, we start shooting,
whole place goes boom.
Take them.
On the house.
Ooh, I'll take them.
Grab your lady and bounce.
Babe.
Do you guys want to come?
Get out.
Or not.
VARTANN:
Okay, stand down, stand down.
Whoo!
As soon as you can,
grab the male and female.
The guy's armed.
He's got a revolver
inside his jacket.
Hold them
until I get there.
BELL: We only got a couple more
hours. Let's go.
Hey, uh,
you want me to send
one of my guys
up here, keep you company?
I'm solid.
I'll leave the radio.
Wendy.
Hmm?
Here's Lon Rose's exemplar.
I need you to compare it
to the male contribution found
in the victim's SAE kit.
Okay.
And... victim's underwear.
I was right.
Yes.
You were.
Thanks for the insight.
JOHNSON: Hey, Nick.
Yeah?
You're going to want
to see this.
I was reviewing the victim's
key card history for you.
According to the hotel's
security card database,
somebody's
currently using it.
That's impossible.
Sasha's key card is
still in evidence.
Let me see that thing.
(beeping)
Didn't see that coming.
Just wrapped up.
We didn't get anything
from the boyfriend,
but we did get
a location
for the surge from
the E-tard girl, Jill.
It's an abandoned building
just west of Red Rock.
I've been to parties there.
Well, I used to be
down with PLUR.
It's an acronym for
"Peace, Love,
Unity, Respect."
It's like the, uh, rave motto.
Anyways, it was a long time ago,
but I know the scene.
You pass your drug tests?
Of course.
Consider yourself recruited.
Okay, the
surveillance team
that's in place at the casino--
they'll follow Everett and Bell
when they leave.
I'll keep the backup units
at a distance.
Do you want to pick them up
before they get to the party,
or after they distribute?
No, I want them
for distribution to minors.
Give the DA something
rock solid to deal with,
something they can't skate on.
All set?
I'll head back upstairs.
Mr. Thomas.
Oh, hey.
Gentlemen, can
I help you?
Yeah, I hope so.
Sasha's key card
is still active.
What, you mean
somebody's using it?
Probably her killer.
But, you see,
the thing is
we already found a card
in her jacket.
Oh.
May I see
your key card, please?
Yes, absolutely.
(chuckles)
Uh, you know what?
I, uh, I think
I left it at my desk.
This is embarrassing.
I'll be right back.
No, no,
no, no, no.
We'll just check
your pockets right here.
(beeping)
LANGSTON: How do you
explain that, Mr. Thomas?
Look, when I met Sasha,
I knew she was special.
Hell, after the third date,
I wanted to marry her.
Then she booked that...
that lingerie job.
It made me sick
to think of her sharing
herself with all those...
perverts.
So we had it out,
she promised to quit.
She lied.
Wait a minute.
You're going to choose
a bunch of perverts over me?
They're not perverts.
They're fans--
they're my fans.
You shouldn't be jealous.
Are you kidding me here?
Look, Finn,
if you can't accept
my lifestyle,
we're over.
Wait, wait a minute.
What is wrong with you?!
Hey!
(screams)
You don't know Sasha.
You don't understand.
She was everything to me.
I couldn't live without her.
No, Mr. Thomas, you couldn't
let her live without you.
Let's go.
(sighs)
Are they finished?
They've been in the
bathroom for over an hour.
There's no more
ice coming in.
It's almost 10:00.
BELL:
Here we go.
We've got movement.
Okay, let's lay 'em out.
WILLOWS: Final step in the
process-- brand your goods.
♪ ♪
VARTANN:
All right,
they're leaving the room.
Both suspects are armed.
Let me know
when they hit the lobby.
I'm going to need
a uni with me
when I disable and
process the lab.
You're looking at him.
BRASS (over radio):
Suspects are at the valet.
Game on. Let's not lose them.
♪ ♪
Suspects' vehicle is leaving
the front entrance,
turning north
on Las Vegas Boulevard.
I'm in the number one position.
Units three and four,
stand by to take over.
Turning east on Flamingo.
WILLOWS:
Well, there's open chemicals
and spilled chemicals--
I don't know what they are.
You're not suited up,
Lou.
Stay in the living room.
Okay, I'll search
for finished product.
Suspects are two blocks
from the warehouse.
UC officers and Sanders
are in position.
(techno music playing)
(dancers shouting)
♪ ♪
BRASS: We've got Sanders inside
with three officers.
When I get a text,
I'll give the word.
Black-and-whites move up,
and standby units move in.
One for you, pretty lady...
and for you.
♪ ♪
(garbled police radio
transmission)
(sizzling fizz)
How's it going?
(jar clatters, Willows coughs)
(muffled):
Slow.
(techno plays)
Bell, let's go, man.
I'm good.
No, come on, let's go.
(laughs)
Whoo! Whoo!
(mutters)
Hey, uh, can I get another roll?
I lost the other one.
Thanks, man.
(gun hammer cocks)
Don't move.
Don't even twitch, or this
will be your last party.
Stay right there.
You're under arrest.
OFFICER:
Let's go, pal.
The party's over.
What's the 20 on Bell?
He was back there
a minute ago,
but he's gone.
(indistinct radio transmission)
(camera shutter snaps)
Hey, they
arrested Everett.
They're still searching
for Bell in the crowd.
Almost done.
The chemicals are sealed and
secure, HazMat's on their way,
and we'll need to pack up
those suitcases
and take them with us.
Okay, you got it.
DISPATCHER: ...in or out of any
exits at this time.
OFFICER:
Adam 2-2, copy that.
We are currently in the back
alleyway of the Diamond Dust.
(door opens)
BELL:
No, dude, I snuck out
a side door.
Yeah.
No, the cop... the cops don't...
they don't know where I am.
I don't know what
happened to Ev.
Just... just come get me.
Just-just come get me...
DISPATCHER:
Confirm suspects are in custody.
BRASS: We do not have
the second suspect in custody.
Repeat, we do not have
DISPATCHER:
Copy that.
Confirm that the suspect
is still at large.
(gun hammer cocks)
(soft rustling)
(garbled radio transmissions)
(grunts, sniffles)
DISPATCHER: Any available units
to Diamond Dust Hotel.
OFFICER:
...1-2, yeah, stand by
and we'll check with the watch
commander in your area.
(grunts)
(grunts continue)
(gunshot)
(panting)