(jazzy Vegas show music playing)
(applause)
MAN:
I'll tell you why.
It's my mom's fault
I'm still single.
What do you mean,
it's your mom's fault?
She hates every
girl I bring home.
Listen, you little
nuck-nuck,
some girls you just don't
bring home to Mom.
For instance, if a girl's
ever told you to hurry up
before somebody
takes her corner,
that's not a girl
you take home to Mom.
And you say to a girl
you're gonna take her
to a football game,
and at the halftime,
the band comes
on the field
and-and spells out
her phone number.
That's not a girl
you take home to Mom.
No, you don't
take her home to Mom.
Right. Now if
you find a girl
who thinks
shooting the breeze
means wearing a mini-
skirt without undies,
oh-ho, don't take
her home to Mom.
Take her home to Dad.
And if her tattoos,
her tattoos are misspelled,
man, oh, man,
you don't try to bring
that... you-you...
You-you don't try...
You don't-you don't...
Oh! Am I running this
through the shredder.
What is... Uh...
"You don't take her home."
This is funny stuff, ladies.
30 years ago, your parents
were peeing themselves
in the TV room.
30 years ago, you were saying
the right lines.
I'm distracted
by these lovelies.
They probably all got
boyfriends, husbands.
And you,
you got that beautiful wife,
your Terpsie.
I got nobody, Knuckles.
Never did.
Nobody loves me.
I love you.
Come on. Come on.
Come on.
Everybody loves Knuckles.
Nobody loves Nash.
Ten minutes.
Ten minutes!
Ten minutes, girls.
See you at the party.
(showgirls conversing
indistinctly)
Ten minutes, Mr. Nash!
Mr. Nash?
It's me-- Bingo.
Is everything okay?
SANDERS:
It was the Rat Pack
at the Sands in '62,
Elvis at the Hilton in '69,
and Knuckles &amp; Nash
at the Rampart in '74.
This was supposed
to be their first reunion
in 30 years.
And I bet you
had a ticket.
Saturday night, front row.
(Stokes laughs)
What's the story, Doc?
No obvious trauma.
Jaw's slack,
dead no more than two hours.
Could be a natural.
Blemishes,
enlarged blood vessels
on his skin.
It's consistent with long-term
alcohol abuse.
Legend is,
Nash was such a boozer,
PD kept a cell waiting for him
every time they played town.
What do you think?
Open bottle of vodka,
used glass.
One last drink?
One last laugh.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
(distant siren wailing)
(siren whooping)
AKERS: Hey. So, a Sanitation
Department worker
noticed the tarp
when he was making a pickup.
Nobody's laid a finger on it.
Let's take a look.
Ooh...
Human Swiss cheese.
AKERS:
Holy...!
Man!
LANGSTON:
Hands blown off,
feet blown off.
With what? Bazooka?
Well, that might not be
an exaggeration.
WILLOWS:
If Holey Man was shot here,
we'd have more evidence of it,
not to mention
someone in the neighborhood
would've heard.
We'll canvass the block.
There's white trace
on the body as well
as the tarp.
You usually see
this level of violence
down around the border.
Could be spillover from Mexico.
We're definitely in gangland.
This is how cartels kill people.
I.D.-less,
no face, no hands.
I'm assuming no wallet.
Nothing.
Gun on him.
Gun in him.
When a man is dead,
a man is dead.
Why keep killing him?
Either you're very angry
or you're having too much fun
to stop.
Tox just came in
for Bernie Nash.
BAC was .11.
He had a reputation as
a gold-medal drinker.
How's this for a chaser?
Henry also found higher than
therapeutic levels of oxycodone.
Really?
Well, you know,
if he'd just been drinking,
I would think
he died of natural causes.
I mean, he was an old comic
facing an audience
after decades.
You add in
the drugs...
So he over-medicated?
It wouldn't surprise me.
I, uh, I need to roll him here.
(Robbins grunts)
STOKES:
Bruises and abrasions.
Appear to be perimortem.
Yeah, alcohol abusers
bruise easily.
There's some trace
in these scratches.
Gold flecks.
He had a whole lot
of party going on.
Those are love scratches.
(young woman laughs,
Bernie groans)
It appears old Bernie
wasn't alone when he died.
KNUCKLES:
Well, Bernie had the most
creative comic mind
in the business.
Brilliant, really was.
He was my friend for 40 years,
partner, brother I never had,
you know?
I was nothing without him.
I-I was just this hippie comic
with a dirty T-shirt
telling bad jokes,
getting no laughs.
And all of a sudden,
Bernie sees the act
and says, "Hey. Hmm?"
So he gets me a haircut,
tuxedo,
puts me on his left side,
bang, we're big stars.
You know the stage
manager-- Bingo?
Uh-huh.
He said that you rehearsed
up till 4:00 p.m.
Is that right?
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, we did.
Uh, but look, if you haven't
got a pulse by now,
I'm gonna be doing
a double with Bernie
over at Forest Lawn,
all right? Huh?
Uh, did Mr. Nash
appear ill at any time?
WOMAN:
He was a nervous wreck
every rehearsal this week.
Yeah, yeah, well,
you know,
it takes a whileto get
your stage legs back
under you after 30 years.
Oh, sure.
Come on in, Greg.
This is CSI Sanders.
He may have
a few questions.
Huh?
Did you see Mr. Nash
after the rehearsal?
No, no, he wanted
to, uh, take a nap,
so he went back to his room.
Which is French for
"hoisting a couple."
(clears throat)
Uh, sweetheart,
I'll-I'll handle this.
Right.
KNUCKLES: A lot of comics
will knock one back
before the show,
you know, kinda relax 'em.
SANDERS: Excuse me,
Captain, but
wasn't it his drinking
that broke up the act?
Yeah. (chuckles)
How could you possibly
know that?
That-that was before
you were even born.
Hey, look,
we were a couple
of poor kids
who made a pile of money,
but Bernie didn't have
any time to play with it,
so, huh-huh,
he quits.
Was it amicable?
I thought I was through,
you know?
As it turned out, it
opened some other doors.
I did TV shows.
Two hit TV
shows I had.
Very successful.
And I-I did, uh, movies.
Had movies.
And Mr. Nash?
He-He played with his money,
yeah.
Racehorses,
real estate, women.
Pretty soon,
he's busted again,
so he needed a comeback.
He asked me...
Begged you.
Begged...
And, uh,
how could I say no?
We believe that someone
was with him when he died.
KNUCKLES:
Oh?
A woman.
Aha, ha, ha...
Yeah, those-those are good.
Cherchez la...
showgirl--
that's-that's French.
Do you have a name?
Did he ever get a name?
KNUCKLES:
No, no, but...
good for Bernie.
Went out with his shorts down.
(chuckles)
...97, 98,
99, 100...
101...
Over 100 bullet holes,
and still counting.
I take it that's why
Catherine kicked me over
to help.
There are bullet holes
on top of bullet holes.
through bullet holes.
Plenty of bullets
in his body,
and one bullet
in his mouth.
Fast-track that frag
to Ballistics.
(squishing)
Looks like he left us
some kind of I.D.
(computer trilling, beeping)
(rapid beeping)
LANGSTON:
Kurtis Torse.
Ten Most Wanted list.
SIDLE:
I know him.
He blew up an abortion clinic
in Seattle last year.
This was a dangerous man.
He's been on the
run for a year.
That's a long time.
It's not every day
you get a hit
on a Top-Tener.
Yes, but who got him?
(door opening)
Hey, Doc. I left you
a breakfast burrito
in the other fridge.
Thanks.
So is that another picture
for your Death-styles
of the Rich and Famous book?
The death of Bernie Nash
is a book-worthy mystery
of its own, my boy.
A locked dressing
room mystery.
So you're saying he did not
die of natural causes?
Nothing natural about it.
I found a fair amount
of fluid in
his pharynx--
suggested laryngospasm.
(gurgling)
His esophageal sphincter
closed off the pathway.
He couldn't swallow
or breathe.
Take a look at the lungs.
Pulmonary edema is
the body's response
to heart failure when
he stopped breathing.
But there's one more thing--
I aspirated this fluid
from the sphenoid sinuses.
They were full of it.
Pulmonary edema,
laryngospasm,
his pharynx and sinuses
were filled with fluid?
Are you trying to tell me
this guy drowned?
That's exactly
what it looked like.
At least from
where I'm standing.
The closest body of water
was a toilet 12 feet away.
Told you it was
a great mystery.
WILLOWS:
Mrs. Torse, when was the last
time you saw your husband?
Does it matter?
He's dead.
Whoever killed him
did you a favor.
We prefer to find
our suspects alive.
Well, that wasn't gonna happen.
He's too smart.
Think about it.
He got all the way from Seattle
to Las Vegas on foot,
and no one heard a peep.
WILLOWS:
Did he ever contact you?
MRS. TORSE:
Feds had my phones tapped
and two guys on my tail.
You know he didn't.
The day the police found out
Kurt did the bombing
was the last day I saw him.
He just walked out the front
door and he didn't look back.
I know you have two children.
It's hard to not
look back at them.
No secret visits?
Kurt's beliefs meant more
to him than his family.
Kurt always talked about
going off the grid some day.
How going out in public,
taking the bus, driving a car
could get him got.
WILLOWS:
Any idea who got him?
How do I know you cops didn't?
How do I know you didn't?
27 people died in that clinic.
They all had families.
They all wanted Kurt dead.
They want me dead.
So why don't you start
harassing them?
Why don't you start
giving me names?
Got no names.
Sorry.
I just...
I'd just catch them
following me around.
They even called the house.
I take phone numbers, too.
I don't call people
who are trying to kill me.
Well, once you give me
your phone records,
I can do that for you.
LANGSTON:
Porcupine man.
It's like he was
stuck on a spit
and put in front
of a firing squad.
C.O.D. was GSWs
to the everything.
Robbins found these in
the body at autopsy.
.50 calibers,
.30-06's, nine millimeters.
Lucky for us he left us an eye.
Vitreous potassium puts
T.O.D. at one to four hours
before you found him.
All right, that's between
midnight and 3:00 a.m.
David counted 127 bullet holes--
37 of which were blackened.
You know, at first
I thought that was GSR
from close shots, but histo
revealed that they were singed.
Tracers or incendiary rounds
could cause this kind
of burning.
When I was a kid,
my dad and his army buddies
would get drunk and fire tracer
rounds at night on the base,
tell me they
were fireworks.
And they are a kind
of firework.
Tracers are modified
with a pyrotechnic charge
in the base. thereby allowing
the machine gun shooter
to correct his aim
vis-à-vis the target.
But incendiaries and tracers
are designed for use
on the battlefield.
Fully automatic firearms
and surplus ammo
are pretty widely available
in Nevada.
They're illegally sold
to recreational shooters.
For target practice.
He certainly looks like
a human target.
SANDERS:
It's hard to get a hair in your
throat without intimate contact.
But I guess
you're never too old.
Especially with
the blue pill.
Heck, I know guys my age
who are using it.
Guys who, you know,
need the boost.
Other guys.
Take a look.
The pigment of most hair is
concentrated on the outer
edges of the cuticle.
Only red hair has a
central concentration
of pigment like that.
So, cherchez la
redheaded showgirl.
I really appreciate you
volunteering to do this.
Yeah, the only other thing
we had to do today was
file for unemployment.
Well, I just need
a few hair samples
from each of you.
Well, the drapes are hanging
but the carpet's Brazilian.
(nervous chuckle)
Uh...
a few from your head
should do it.
So did you see Mr. Nash
after rehearsal?
We hightailed it out of there
before he and Knuckles
got offstage.
Showgirls-- we're moving targets
to Bernie Nash.
What about Knuckles?
Oh, he'll corner you, too,
if he gets the chance.
Bettina darling,
Well, looking
mighty fine.
Say, how'd you like to play
a little King Kong?
You know, I'll be
the gorilla,
you be the Empire
State Building.
Knuckles!
Whoa. Cheese it, the wife.
What are you doing
without your pants?
I, mm, uh... Oh!
(clears throat)
Uh, well, actually,
I was doing pretty good
till you showed up.
BETTINA:
All Knuckles forces
on you is jokes.
Until his wife
yanks the leash.
DAWSON:
So those bullet frags
from Torse's mouth
came from a lead-
free frangible,
composed of
sintered copper,
meant to disintegrate
on impact,
which is why frangibles
are used in shooting ranges.
Maybe Kurtis Torse was killed
at a range.
Shot with multiple calibers...
means lots of different guns.
And Vegas has the least
restrictive gun laws
in the country.
I mean, anyone with a valid I.D.
can shoot a machine gun
in an indoor range.
I'll have Brass pass
his photo around.
Wait, hang on.
I can save him
some shoe leather.
Come here.
So your brand of frangible
is Crate City Arsenal.
Now, unless the killer
ordered them online,
there's only one shooting range
in town that has those.
And I'm pretty certain
you've heard of it.
I have only been
to PD's shooting range.
The tourists in town
are ditching Manilow
to shoot at this place.
The ads are everywhere.
Oh, come on.
Now, you had to
have seen this.
Hey, lady, grab
a Blast Away coupon.
WOMAN (over bullhorn):
Come on in, folks!
Come on in and experience
the thrill of freedom!
Exercise your
Second Amendment right
and experience what
real freedom feels like.
Come on in, folks.
Come right now.
And ladies,
first 50 rounds are free.
(clearing throat)
Biz license, F.F.L.,
proof of secure gun
storage, Class-3 license.
This is not an
enforcement check.
Do you recognize him?
A thousand people come
through here every day.
Yes, but this man
was murdered.
Uh...
(nervous chuckle)
I didn't make
eight mill last year
because I kill people.
Do you see those big-ass dudes?
Anyone tries
anything,
one of them
takes care of it.
We found a Crate City bullet
where his two front teeth
used to be.
You are the
only place
in town that sells those.
I don't sell bullets.
Ammo's included
with the rentals.
Nothing comes in
or out of this place
without me knowing.
We'd like to take a look
at your surveillance video.
We'd also like
to take a look around.
Fine.
What are you looking for?
Blood.
(gunfire blasting)
WOMAN (over P.A.):
Attention shooters, stop firing.
Make your guns safe,
step back from the line.
(repeating announcement
in foreign language)
(sighs)
This place hasn't been cleaned.
There's at least a week's worth
of debris here.
I'm not seeing a stitch
of blood.
Torse wasn't shot here.
WILLOWS: Mrs. Torse's
phone records show
that you had called her
25 times in January.
She changed her number
in March,
following which, you phoned her
another 30 times.
Her husband killed my mom
and my dad and my baby sister.
Anyone I ever cared about.
I'm truly sorry for your loss.
You know,
my mom had preeclampsia.
She, uh, had to get
the procedure
or she was going to die.
We found an AK
in your apartment.
You've also been to
the Blast Away Gun
Alley a dozen times
in the last month.
What were you doing there,
practicing?
You think I did something
to that scumbag's wife,
you're wrong.
No, I think you did something
to the scumbag.
He was murdered.
He was shot so many times
you could see through him.
Yes!
(whoops)
(laughing)
I didn't kill him,
but I would've.
I would've taken the needle
to taste that sweet revenge.
I mean,
murder is wrong,
but killing your enemies,
that's all through
the Old Testament.
That's pretty much
the same reason
that Torse bombed that clinic.
I didn't cast the first stone.
I'm gonna need your prints,
your DNA,
and those boots.
You got it. They're all yours.
And, miss, thank you for giving
me the best news of my life.
HODGES:
All the hairs from the showgirls
were dyed,
no pigment concentration.
And I always thought that
those girls were all natural.
However, the hair
that was found
in Bernie Nash's throat
is from a natural redhead.
So, it wasn't one of the
showgirls who was with Nash.
What about
the trace in the scratches
on his back?
Ah, believe it or not,
there's gold in them
thar scratches.
No, really, it's actual gold.
Along with traces
of camphor, ethyl acetate,
and tosylamide-
formaldehyde resin.
All common ingredients
in fingernail polish.
We're not looking
for a showgirl.
We're looking for a gold digger.
I was just trying
to protect my marriage.
Believe it or not,
I really do love my Knuckles.
My little hamster.
Then how do you explain
the traces
of your fingernail polish
on Bernie Nash's back?
Huh?
Remember we found you
trying to remove it
when we questioned you?
(sighs)
Bernie made a pass at
me the day we met,
right in front
of Knuckles.
And all these
years since,
every time we saw him,
he was always grabbing
and squeezing
and whispering
dirty talk.
And always, I told
him, "Get lost."
And then one day he happened
to catch me in a...
compromising position.
How'd you get
the funny name?
By doing this.
Bingo! (chuckles)
(moaning)
Anybody here
got a cough drop?
Um, do you have
a cough drop?
Bernie said he would tell
Knuckles unless...
So, anyway,
after rehearsal,
I went to his
dressing room and...
Mm, yeah.
But Bernie
couldn't do zilch.
(both laugh)
Come on!
(grunts)
Well, you gave it
the 120-proof try.
Bernie?
You need a doctor?
I need a stiff drink.
Vodka rocks.
You need a stiff something,
that's for sure.
I gave him his
drink, I left,
and then he died.
I guess I was
just too much
for his old heart to handle.
(both laugh)
But that-that's not breaking
any laws, is it?
Well, doping his drink
with enough oxycodone
to take out Rhode Island is.
What?
No, I didn't, I didn't.
I don't even have any oxy.
Oh, come on.
And believe me,
I could use it.
Dancing for 20 years,
I got gravel for cartilage
and back pain like you
wouldn't believe.
What I do believe...
is that you could never let Nash
tell your little hamster
about what was going on
between you and Bingo.
It wasn't Nash's heart
that made him a dud Casanova,
it was the fact
that he was loaded up on dope.
That's what did it.
That's ridiculous.
The last thing you could get
Bernie to drink was water.
Look, I was there
five minutes, tops.
And when I left,
he was alive.
Well, now he's dead.
And you're not going
anywhere.
Oh, uh, no-no, no-no.
The straw
and razor blade
are for an experiment
that I'm working on.
And the white stuff?
Uh, the white stuff.
Yes, that's magnesite,
aka magnesium carbonate.
It's the white residue
that was found
on the tarp
that your victim was
wrapped up in.
It was also found on
Daniel Peidre's boots.
Where does one find a lot
of magnesite around here?
You want to guess where
the largest magnesite mine
in the U.S. is?
Not really.
I'll tell you anyway.
It's in the lovely town
of Gabbs, Nevada.
About two 250 miles
outside of Vegas.
You know, my mother
took me there
for my 15th birthday.
She's a bit
of a rock hound.
Every store in town sells
magnesite souvenirs.
There's clocks,
key chains, pens...
Maybe the killer killed
Torse in Gabbs.
All right, T.O.D.
was between 12:00 a.m.
and 3:00 a.m.
Which means the killer would've
had to have shot Torse
127 times in Gabbs,
then drove 250 miles
to Vegas to dump the body.
All under four hours.
I don't buy that.
But I bet there's
plenty of magnesite
washing down from that mine.
Koral, Nevada.
Just 50 miles outside of Vegas.
More like it.
Mm-hmm.
MAN:
Light 'em up!
Excuse me!
Hey, y'all lookin' for passes?!
LVPD usually
shoots here for free!
We're not here to shoot!
We need everybody
to stop shooting-- now!
Okay.
(whistles)
(air horn blows,
gunfire stops)
MAN (over P.A.):
Okay, folks, sorry about that.
MAN:
Hey, what's going on?
(over P.A.):
Uh, local authorities have got
a little something to do here
for a few minutes.
Why don't you visit
the tables...
Now first off,
let me just say
I'm a huge supporter
of law enforcement.
I respect the badge.
But this here,
it's not a firing range.
It's a shootout.
I don't need a permit.
I own the land.
All right. I see
you're shooting an M2.
And I noticed
a grenade launcher
on the way in,
a hydraulic cannon as well
as a flamethrower.
Yes, sir, pretty cool.
All registered and legal.
Doesn't mean you
should be shooting
them for fun, does it?
Sure. Why not?
This here-- it's a festival,
celebrating gun ownership.
A place where
law-abiding Americans
can dust off weapons
they normally couldn't use
anywhere else.
Want to try the ol' Ma Deuce?
She's a lot of fun.
I'm sure she is.
Do you recognize
this man?
Negative.
We think he might have been
killed on your property.
Ma'am, I've been doing this
for a lot of years.
Never had any accidents.
We didn't say
it was an accident.
What about him?
Have you ever seen him before?
Yeah.
Yeah, yeah, he was
shooting down here
the other night.
Well, as a big supporter
of law enforcement,
would you mind if we
took a look around?
Not at all.
(whirrs, beeps)
What if Terpsie Pratt
is telling the truth,
and she didn't
kill Nash?
She's not a redhead.
It's possible.
So, somebody must have been
in the dressing room
after she left.
Yeah, but the hair I found
didn't come from
any of the people
that we know were backstage.
And we still don't know where
the oxycodone came from.
Water, water everywhere,
including Bernie Nash's lungs.
Good. Salt water?
Tap water? Glacial melt? What?
Fresh water,
indeterminate source.
But it did contain minute
particles of ferric oxide.
Iron rust. That usually comes
from old pipes.
That's why nearly all water
lines are copper now.
We can probably
rule out
Terpsie's bottled water.
And the samples that
you collected
from the dressing room sink,
toilet and shower
had no iron particles.
So the water Nash drowned in
came from somewhere else.
And it doesn't add up.
We gotta go back
to the crime scene.
Dressing rooms were
completely renovated
a year ago.
Including the plumbing?
Yeah, all new.
Believe me,
no expense spared.
All right, thanks, Bingo.
Lines are all copper.
Water did not come from here.
(man and woman arguing
in distance)
MAN:
Get out of here!
Come on.
WOMAN:
Give it to me!
Hey! Come here!
Give me that!
Let go!
Are you crazy?
STOKES: Hey, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa.
What's going on here?
He took my bag.
Hey, hey, hey!
Give me my bag!
It's my bag.
Give it back!
All right, enough, enough!
You're under arrest
for assault.
Which gives me the right
to search your bag.
Cuff him.
Aw, come on.
There's nothing
in there.
(handcuffs clicking)
What's this?
(pills rattle)
Looks like oxycodone to me.
Where did that come from?
That's illegal
possession,
sale of a Schedule II
controlled substance
and homicide.
Looks like we got
ourselves a Bingo.
Get him out of here.
Oh, I got something
over here.
(flies buzzing)
Whew!
Well, Torse was missing
both of his feet.
Directionality of the
blood is heading this way.
I got a finger.
(camera clicks twice)
(Langston sighs)
Looks like this is
where it started.
(flies buzzing)
MAN:
That's what I'm talkin' about!
MAN 2:
Here we go, boys!
(men shouting,
whooping in distance)
(gunfire blasting)
(grunting)
(groans)
SIDLE: So you said that Daniel
Peidre was at your shootout.
Yeah.
What was he shooting?
Same thing
we were all shooting.
The mountain.
Look, the kid didn't do
this by himself, all right?
You want to play
dumb with us,
we'll just charge
you for murder, too.
Look, I didn't kill anybody.
We found his
body wrapped in
one of your blue tarps
off an alley on 28th Street,
where it was dumped.
It's your land,
it's your shootout,
it's your responsibility.
So what happened?
Daniel catches himself
a famous fugitive,
he brings him down here,
you guys decide
to have a whole lot of fun,
use him for target practice...
No, no, no, no.
No, that's not what happened.
Then what did happen?
Because that is the story
that we're gonna give the D.A.
He was already dead
when I found him.
We sweep the range before
and after every night shoot,
make sure it's clear
of animals.
Never expected to see
a body out there.
My family's owned this land
for over a hundred years.
I figured you guys find
a dead body out here,
you'd probably take it from me.
Most people take their bodies
from Vegas out to the desert,
not the other way around.
Well, I'm just not real
experienced on killing people.
Look, I was just trying to get
the scent away from my land.
All right,
we dropped him in Northtown
thinking you guys would think
it was some sort of gang thing.
I'm telling you,
we sweep this range
at last light.
He had to have snuck in
after that to camp out.
It's so dark out there.
We didn't know about him.
He sure as hell
didn't know about us.
Not till we started shooting.
So, you're saying
that this was an accident?
Ma'am, I'm telling you that
everybody on that firing line
probably put at least
one bullet in him.
Including me.
That kid-- he didn't have
anything to do with it.
Well, the dead guy,
Kurtis Torse, he blew up
an abortion clinic.
He killed 27 people.
If you had just
called the cops,
you'd be a hero
right now.
LANGSTON:
Instead, you tried
to cover it up.
Which makes you a criminal, too.
Bingo's the oxy connection.
He's involved
with Terpsie Pratt,
which gave her access
to the drugs.
And Nash's death would have
kept their affair secret.
But how did
they drown him?
(ice clattering)
Old model.
You thinking what
I'm thinking?
I was, but it's
another copper line.
Let's get this panel off.
The line's got a leak--
check it out.
And it's dripping onto
that rusty panel.
It's dripping into the ice bin.
Nash drowned in ice cubes?
Well, the vodka and the oxy
would have induced
respiratory depression.
Blood flow to the brain
would've been reduced.
He was probably
unable to realize
what was happening to him,
much less how to stop it.
No prints.
Weapon just melts away.
Looks like natural causes.
It's the perfect murder.
Yeah, but where'd
the red hair come from?
It's not the showgirl's--
hers was dyed.
And Terpsie's a brunette.
Knuckles wears a toupee.
So what?
It's brown.
Well, having
dabbled in the art
of discreet hair
coloration myself
in my younger, more
experimental days,
I know a thing or two about
the calibration of highlights
and lowlights required to
obtain certain effects.
To wit, human hair both absorbs
and reflects light.
So, a brown toupee could also
contain lighter shades,
such as light brown,
blonde or even red.
I guarantee you,
we are going to find
red hairs in Knuckles' rug.
Should've taken
that toupee off a long time ago.
It's been molting for years.
(chuckles)
No, I-I-I did.
I killed Bernie.
Well, why?
Was it jealousy because
they were having an affair?
Oh, no; no, no.
No, if a light in Vegas
went out every time
Terpsie banged a guy...
(chuckles)
you'd have to be a bat
to find your way home at night.
That wasn't it.
You see... what we do
out on that stage,
it's kind of like
life and death.
I mean, you do a good show
and you come off and you go,
"Boy, I killed 'em."
(chuckles)
But, uh, you don't
get any laughs,
oh, boy, you say,
"Whew, I died."
Yeah.
Yeah, and that's not
just an expression.
You know, when Bernie and I
were rehearsing
last week, um... well,
he couldn't remember any of
the new material, you know.
He couldn't even remember
the old material, so, just...
Drive me kind of crazy,
but he lost his funny.
And when a comic
loses his funny...
that's the end.
(slurring):
Cancel? Are you nuts!
Give back a
million bucks?
You don't want
to open, fine.
I done a single before,
and I'll do it again.
KNUCKLES:
I couldn't let him go out
in front of that audience
on opening night.
I figure I...
I just killed him
before they did.
And I did it because...
I loved him.
And he'd have done
the same for me.
Where did you get the OxyContin?
Swiped it from Terpsie.
You know, she's got
a little trouble
with the pills, you know.
(chuckles)
Yeah, she tries to hide that
stuff from me, but I find it.
You know,
it's a little game we play.
And how'd you come up with
the ice cube gag?
Oh, y-yeah... Oh, that was
a good one. Yeah, yeah.
See, I did a show with Angela
Lansbury one time, you know.
And, uh, Angie says to me--
I called her Angie--
she says to me,
"That's the perfect murder."
And I say, "Well, it would
have been perfect,
if you hadn't decided
to come to town."
(laughs)
Eh, got a pretty big laugh.
Yeah.
Nuh, maybe I lost
my funny, too, huh?
But I'll tell you
something.
It was beautiful
while we were there.
Yes, sirree.
And we were both there,
right on top, you know.
Vegas was Mount Olympus.
And we were gods.
♪ We've come to the last dance ♪
♪ And save me the first dance
♪ In your dreams tonight.