ROBBINS:
Victim's name is Trevor Beck.
Caucasian male, age 17.
Five foot, 11.
154 pounds.
Senior at Sagebrush
Valley High.
Appears to be well nourished
and in overall good health,
without any abnormal skin
coloring or pigmentation.
♪ ♪
There are several
light abrasions
and contusions on the knuckles
of his right hand,
consistent
with a recent scuffle.
(no audible dialogue)
(indistinct yelling)
But there do not
appear to be any
external wounds consistent
with severe trauma.
Internal organs appear healthy.
No signs of trauma or disease.
Heart muscle...
...is free of scarring
and necrosis.
And there's no evidence
of any cardiac event.
(sighs)
Healthy young men like this
don't simply drop dead
for no reason.
I concur, which is
why I am still looking.
Whoa!
(Langston exclaims)
Oh!
That is one massive
cerebral edema.
The meninges don't
appear to be
discolored or inflamed,
so I think we can safely
rule out meningitis.
Did he suffer any
blows to the head?
There's no evidence
of any injuries to support that.
According to the police report,
he was shoved at school
this morning and collapsed.
And even if he
sustained a blow
during the altercation,
that's not nearly enough time
to cause this much swelling.
And what does
that leave us with?
Drugs? Toxins?
Or a prior injury
we don't know about.
Not yet.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
Mrs. Beck,
please sit down.
(sniffling):
Okay.
Just-just a few things I have
to ask you, all right?
Was Trevor injured recently?
"Injured"? How?
You know, uh...
a bang in the head.
Even a little bump? Anything?
MRS. BECK:
No. No, I mean,
not that I know of.
BRASS:
No? Was he complaining
of, uh, headaches
or blurred vision, nausea--
anything like that?
I-- you mean, he's been
a little grumpy lately.
I mean, this morning,
he couldn't find his car keys,
and he... he threw a fit.
And then, he realized
he'd left them in the car.
But, um, I think that's
just 'cause he's,
he's not getting enough sleep,
you know?
He's... he's a teenager.
Sure. Sure.
Sure, we all do that.
I understand.
(Mrs. Beck sniffles)
Was he in a fight recently?
Trevor doesn't fight.
He's a, um...
he was a good kid.
Well, even good kids
have bad days.
Did somebody do something
to Trevor...
that, that killed him?
We can't say
anything definitive.
We're just looking
at possibilities.
But it would be helpful
to have a diary of Trevor's
comings and goings
in the last week.
That would be good.
How do you know anything
about a kid at his age? I...
BRASS:
Well, we could
ask his friends.
You know, maybe
they could help.
MRS. BECK:
He didn't have
a lot of friends.
You know, when Trevor
wasn't doing his schoolwork,
he was, he was
working on his car.
You know, he always
said that he was going
to be an artist.
I mean, I thought
that would be
like a, you know,
a painter or sculptor
or something, you know?
Not a gearhead.
But he said
that a car was art
that could move.
(computer beeping)
He started seeing a girl.
Cindy. About a week ago.
She came home
with him last night.
Yeah? What time was that?
Let's see, they went up
to Trevor's room about 9:00.
But, um, there was
no sleeping over,
so she left
about, uh, 11:00, I think.
But I-I didn't
see her go.
Do you have her phone number?
No. I don't.
It's okay.
It's all right.
We can find that.
That's easy for us.
(line ringing)
CINDY (on recording):
Hey! If you want Cindy,
well, too bad,
'cause you can't have her.
(giggles, voice mail beeps)
(phone beeps off)
(music plays over headphones)
You don't look
nearly busy enough.
(music stops)
Well, thank you.
It is my gift to look relaxed
while doing many things.
Unlike Hodges,
who has the ability
to look overwhelmed
while really doing
nothing at all.
I'm waiting on
an A.G. waiver
on a cell phone for...
WILLOWS:
Cindy Warner.
It just came through.
Start "relaxing."
You got it. Okay.
You know,
I heard the victim's
brain kind of exploded
in his head.
Kind of.
What does this girl have
to do with that?
No one's
seen her since the night
before Trevor Beck died.
She lives
with her brother,
a construction worker
out of town on a job.
I sent some unis
over to their apartment
for a welfare check
and she wasn't there.
I mean, her boyfriend drops dead
in front of the whole school,
and she's nowhere to be found.
That qualifies
as suspicious to me.
Hmm.
(computer beeps)
Oh, okay.
Her cell is
registered
and active at a tower
on Washington Boulevard
between Oak and Maple.
Sagebrush Valley High.
Well, it is a school day.
According to the office,
Cindy was not in her
homeroom this morning.
WILLOWS (on phone):
Well, according to my daughter,
some kids just go to school
to hang out.
Never set foot in a classroom.
Oh, I have her schedule.
I will beat the bushes
and see what turns up.
Bye.
Cindy?
Sorry?
This is
Cindy Warner's locker.
Yeah and mine.
We share.
Oh, uh, well,
I'm Sara Sidle.
I'm with the crime lab.
What's your name?
Renata Clarke.
I'm going to need
to get in there, Renata.
Like the teachers say
"no expectation of privacy."
So did Cindy do
something wrong?
Have you seen her today?
No.
I mean, not since
the other night.
Actually, before what
happened with Trevor.
And I've been texting
her like crazy
and Cindy's my biff.
We always talk
before bed.
She text you back?
And you're not worried
about her at all?
Of course
I'm worried about her.
Her boyfriend, like, died.
But I mean, half the school
went home after that
and I figured
Cindy did, too.
She just wasn't ready to talk.
And I can't even imagine
how she was feeling.
You think Cindy
ran away or something?
We don't know.
(school bell rings)
Well, I'm going to be
late for class.
Oh, uh, no problem.
Go ahead.
But, um, could
you do me a favor?
If Cindy does get in touch
with you, could you
call me please?
Sure.
Thanks.
(indistinct chatter)
Hey!
STOKES:
Hi.
What are you doing here?
I called Impound for this.
Yeah, they're
still sorting out
a multi-car pileup
on the 15.
Thought I'd save
them some trouble.
Take care of this
one in the field.
Nobody mentioned
it was electric.
So?
So this is
a 1958 Porsche Speedster.
So?
So, it's a classic.
James Dean had
one of these.
Putting an electric motor
in this is sacrilegious.
Not to polar bears.
Did you process
the interior?
No, no, not yet.
Uh-oh.
Looks like we've got
some more blasphemy here.
Yeah.
I saw that fresh
yellow paint scrape
passenger's side door.
Already collected for trace.
Hmm.
You know, these EVs
have diagnostic
modules up the wazoo.
They log
range, speed, acceleration,
state of charge--
all that stuff.
Well, I guess the electric
motor's good for us, too.
Phenelzine.
Antidepressant.
Sadly, very popular
with the high school set.
(beeping)
Got a pink cell here.
Cindy Warner's phone.
They say the only way
to get a teenage girl
away from her cell phone
is to pry it
from her cold, dead hand.
Well, whoever "they" are,
let's hope they're wrong.
(computer beeps and whirs)
♪ ♪
Ow!
Let go!
What are you doing?!
What's the matter with you?
Stop it!
CINDY:
Stop!
Come on, man.
♪ ♪
Miyamoto Takahashi?
(sighs) Nah, man.
It's after 3:00.
I'm not a truant.
Oh...
Wouldn't that be
your lucky day?
I'm a homicide detective, man.
How'd you get that shiner?
(iPhone beeps, video plays)
This'll help.
CINDY: Ow!
TREVOR: Let go!
What are you doing?!
What's the matter with you?
Stop it!
CINDY: Stop!
BOY: Come on, man!
(video stops)
Looks pretty self-explanatory.
Boy, I don't know
what's going on today,
but everybody's
giving me attitude.
Hey, you know what?
I'm the victim, man.
You're not the victim
when the guy who did that,
17 hours later, ended up dead.
The gentleman in question
died at school.
Probably bored to death.
So what was your
beef with Trevor?
No beef, man.
Amateur got in my face.
I let him slide.
A tough guy like you
didn't hit back?
Come on.
Let who's ever up decide.
You know, for such
a man of peace,
you have a funny way
of showing it.
You know what I think happened?
I think it all had
to do with Cindy Warner.
I'm perplexed.
(chuckles)
An educated guy like you?
Come on.
Cindy used to be my lady.
Then she started keeping
his passenger seat warm.
But you never know
when history's
going to repeat itself--
that's the way I saw it.
The way I see it is, uh,
you get in a fight with Trevor
to win Cindy back,
and then Trevor kicked your ass.
17 hours later, he ends up dead
and Cindy goes missing.
She's missing?
Yeah.
Where is she?
If we knew where she was,
she wouldn't be missing.
Now, where did you go
after Trevor decked you?
Back here.
Look, I swear.
Ask my boss.
I was helping with inventory.
When was the last you saw Cindy?
You're looking at it.
STOKES:
It looks like his brain stem
has been jammed into his spine.
Essentially it has.
It's a rare condition known
as Chiari malformation.
It's a deformity of the skull
that displaces
the cerebellum
and the brain stem
into the spinal canal.
Most people don't even
realize they have it
until they've experienced
some kind of trauma
or vigorous
neck flexion.
Like a blow to the head?
Exactly.
If that happens,
the condition creates swelling,
edema, resulting in massive
intracranial pressure.
The headaches can be
excruciating.
WILLOWS:
According to the mother,
Trevor had been irritable.
And wasn't sleeping very well.
It's got to be hard
to sleep when your brain's
blowing up in your skull
like that, huh?
SIDLE:
Trevor was also taking
antidepressants,
MAO inhibitors.
I know they spike
blood pressure,
but wouldn't they have worsened
the swelling?
LANGSTON:
Definitely.
The existing Chiari,
the antidepressants,
and whatever struck his head,
all combined to create
an acute hypertensive crisis--
a perfect storm.
So whoever gave him the drugs
was also contributing
to his death.
Yes.
WILLOWS:
We still don't know
what hit him or who
or where it happened.
Well, the diagnostic modules
in Trevor's Franken-Porsche
did give us
a little something there.
On the night before his
last drive from home
to school,
Trevor drove
about 14 miles in the course
of an hour and a half
without turning his engine off.
That's seven miles out,
seven miles back...
Seven mile search radius.
And just before
he made that trip
is the last time that
Cindy Warner was seen.
I've got a bad feeling
about this.
♪ ♪
Guys, she's pretty
messed up.
And it's not just
from the tree.
Compound fractures
of both shins.
A lot of internal injuries.
And her uniform
is missing
the skirt, which could
suggest sexual assault.
Possible body dump.
You know, I haven't seen
any blood in the vicinity
or footprints,
other than ours.
Or any sign of a struggle.
No, if this is a body dump,
and Trevor's death
was some sort of twisted
karmic retribution,
then why didn't he try to hide
the body any better than this?
There's no tire treads
coming off the road,
no signs of another vehicle
even being out here,
much less another person.
It's like she just...
fell from the sky.
HODGES:
What do you think?
Kids head out
to the desert for
a little sneaky-touchy.
Things start getting
hot and heavy,
clothing is removed...
Then things go
terribly, terribly wrong.
Definitely wrong.
That is not what happened.
Do you see how the tibia
is snapped clean?
The X-ray shows
the posterior
is beveled.
This is a pedestrian fracture.
She was hit by a car.
David said that there was no
evidence of that at the scene.
Maybe not in the immediate
vicinity of the body,
but if you take a car
traveling at highway speed
and hit someone just right...
A girl this size
and this weight--
she could fly the length
of a football field.
We need to widen our search.
♪ ♪
♪ So you... don't talk,
don't mock, don't squawk ♪
♪ So close to me ♪
♪ And you... don't push,
don't pull, don't be a fool ♪
♪ So close ♪
♪ To me ♪
♪ On call, on edge, on point ♪
♪ But don't point
that close to me ♪
(engines revving)
(Cindy screaming)
♪ You're livin'
on nothin' but drive ♪
♪ You can wail out
as much as you like ♪
♪ It's your day in the sun,
so walk right ♪
♪ Walk right, walk right... ♪
(shutter clicks)
STOKES:
There were yaw marks
up and down the road,
but no clear tread marks,
so I obliquely photographed
areas where I thought
tread marks might be
by using a light source
at different angles,
different contrast...
Each angle revealed portions
of otherwise invisible treads.
By layering the shots,
I was able
to come up with a complete set
of tread mark impressions.
Very impressive,
smarty-pants.
(chuckles)
Two distinct sets.
Both originating
in the same general vicinity...
here.
The yellow scrapes
and blood on the road
appear to be from Cindy's
point of impact,
which was
roughly 1,300 feet
from the starting point.
We found her body 300 feet
from where she was hit.
Two cars, dead of night,
a girl on a lonely stretch
of quarter-mile straightaway.
This was a drag race.
(muted cheering)
(tires screeching)
(screaming)
With Cindy at the finish line...
in every sense of the word.
The treads
on the left are
a thin five-bar tire
that's consistent
with the ones on Trevor's car.
The treads on the right
are from his
mystery opponent.
They're 17-inch,
Goodyear Eagles
with a wheel width
of approximately 70 inches.
STOKES:
A lot of cars
on the road today
that fit that
description.
Hodges was able
to I.D. the yellow flakes
in Cindy's wounds
and the point of impact.
It's Flatz uranium number two.
And it is the same
paint as the yellow
scrape that we found
on Trevor's door.
Okay, so...
the two cars race,
one swipes the other.
The yellow car loses control
and takes out Cindy.
That would explain
why there was no damage
to the front-end
of Trevor's car.
So we're looking for
a yellow street racer
in Las Vegas? Great.
That should
narrow it down to just
a few hundred suspects.
Well, maybe Trevor's
drug dealer can help
us out with that.
I tracked the lot number
on the phenelzine
pack you found.
It's from a local pharmacy.
I called the owner.
His son works as a stock boy
and he goes
to Trevor's school.
BOY:
A drug dealer?
Me?
Do I look like
Tony Montoya to you?
Damn it, Rishi,
stop messing around.
That's good advice.
We know that you're dealing.
I never took any cash
from Trevor.
We were in auto shop together.
He was like a genius,
and I have this mental blockage
when it comes to things
mechanical,
so I exchanged
my goods for his services.
Tutoring.
All this and you're failing
auto shop, too?
That's right, Dad!
I'm never going
to be an engineer.
Strip me of my Indian.
The night before he died...
who was Trevor racing?
No one.
Come on.
I'm telling you,
Trevor wasn't a racer.
Tell the police the truth!
He wasn't a racer!
Not as far I know.
That car was like his baby.
Well, racing
is what a car like that
is built for.
We know that Trevor was
out in the desert drag racing
a yellow car,
which killed Cindy Warner.
Do you know somebody
with a yellow car?
I don't think you're aware
of what's going on here.
The pills that you gave Trevor
helped kill him.
No-no-no, he...
he asked me for the painkillers.
But that stuff's addictive,
so I gave him the uppers.
Which are
controlled substances.
Trafficking them is a felony.
Hey, I'm still a minor.
But your father isn't.
He's responsible for
those medications.
And if he's found
criminally liable,
he could lose his store.
Oh, my God.
Rishi, what have you done?
The yellow car...
it's got to be a Demon.
They're a gang.
Their color's yellow.
That's all I know.
I swear.
I'm sorry, Dad.
I'm sorry.
BRASS:
The Demons have been
around for awhile.
They're a legitimate car club,
but they've diversified
into distribution
of narcotics, chop shops,
protection rackets--
things like that.
Well, we can't exactly
round up every Demon in town
who's driving
a yellow car, can we?
Well, maybe
we don't have to.
I know where a lot
of Demons are going
to hang out tonight.
♪ ♪
SIDLE:
"Street Rumble"?
That's catchy.
Brass says the department
sets this thing up
to keep racers
off the streets.
Ten dollars buys
anyone into a race,
and it's all legal.
Well, it looks
like it's working.
Yeah, it does,
actually.
Well, at least one
day a week anyway.
(man speaking indistinctly
over P.A.)
Here we go.
Check it out.
Pretty nice ride
you got here.
17-inch rims?
Ooh, look at that.
The lady can appreciate
the finer things in life.
Nissan 350Z.
This is a race car.
You can't keep it caged up.
You got to let a canary sing.
Ask Sergeant Jenkins.
This is the ride that beat
his ass here last week.
Bumper looks a little
beat up, though.
This baby's pristine.
You know Officer O'Malley?
Got smoked two weeks ago
on Las Vegas...
On the track.
Your old Crown Vic's
just no matchup.
Hey, no disrespect, but any
scratches get on that shine,
there's going to be
problems, man.
No, there's not.
Besides, I was just
admiring the color.
Weren't you, Sara?
The color is nice.
What is it?
Uh, Flatz uranium number two?
Don't know.
Is this your car?
I'm watching it for a friend.
What's this about?
What's your friend's name?
Don't know.
You don't know the guy's name,
but he lets you baby-sit
his car? Why is that?
What can I say?
I got a trustworthy face.
No, you don't.
We're looking for
a yellow car in
connection with a murder.
SARA:
Mitch!
Johnnie! We got a runner!
Stop, LVPD!
Stop now!
Step aside! Please!
LVPD! Stop!
Get out of the way!
SIDLE: Back it up!
Get down on the ground!
Now!
Get down.
Get your arm back.
Get down!
Back it up!
Maybe in your car
you would've had a chance.
(grunts)
You're under arrest.
Get him up.
Let's go.
Oh...
What is it, Greg?
I was just thinking about
the time I went joyriding.
You? Really?
I was 12.
My Papa Olaf bought
a red 280-ZX.
Man, it was love at first sight.
And I have no idea what made me
think I could get away with it.
But when Papa O went down
for his afternoon nap,
I swiped the keys
and took it for a spin.
Where'd you go?
Around the block-- twice.
And when I was rolling it
back into the driveway,
I almost ran over my foot.
Papa Olaf woke up,
had no idea.
He never found out.
Hmm... you're
a little car thief.
Yeah, guess I am.
So, listen,
Miyamoto lawyered up.
But according to the guys
in the gang unit,
he's been involved in stuff
like this before.
He got busted in a chop shop
raid last summer,
but since he was a juvee,
and not principally involved,
they turned him loose.
I'm pretty sure
he's involved in this, too.
Well, unfortunately,
his car isn't.
Well, his wheel
width matches,
so do the tires.
And Hodges confirmed the paint--
Flatz uranium number two.
That may be so,
but while at the crime scene,
I collected broken glass
associated with the impact.
It turned out to be
headlight glass.
These headlights are plastic.
There is no way that this glass
came from that car.
♪ ♪
(indistinct chatter from video)
WILLOWS:
Is that Trevor?
Looks like he was more
of a racer than people thought.
Where did you get to this?
Well, that photo
was on Cindy's phone.
It was taken
at the winner's circle
of Street Rumble,
so I searched their site
and this came up.
It's from nine days ago.
WILLOWS:
Check out that paint job
on the other car.
Yellow flames.
How much do you want to bet
it's Flatz uranium number two?
(tires screeching)
WILLOWS:
Ouch.
He got whiplashed
in that spinout.
That's probably what
setoff his Chiari.
Which means
that his death
was probably an accident.
Yeah.
Wait a minute.
That is Renata Clarke.
Cindy Warner's best friend.
So, Trevor smokes Renata
in an organized race.
Maybe the desert was a rematch.
(engine revs, ticks)
All right, you hear that
light ticking sound?
That's the hot solid lifter cam.
The valves need adjusting.
Shut it down.
See, if you listen,
your car will tell you
everything.
There's no guesswork.
Unlike your girlfriend,
she'll tell you exactly
what she means,
but you have
to listen, because...
If you don't, your car's
just a noisy heap of metal.
So take care
of those valves.
Okay, Gus.
Hi. Can I help you?
Hi there. Mr. Davis?
Yes.
We're with the crime lab.
I understand that
you're Renata's legal guardian.
I am. I'm her uncle
and her shop teacher.
We're going to need to take
a look at her car.
Sure. Uh, yeah,
it's right over here,
only it's not for sale.
Renata? Come on out.
Uh, these people want
to take a look at the car.
What's this all about, Gus?
I don't know.
No signs of blood spatter
or body damage.
Even the tires look clean.
But the headlights are glass.
Well, the wheel width is right.
SIDLE:
There's no way we're
off base on this.
Maybe we're not.
Check it out.
Yellow paint overspray.
This area's been recently
repaired and repainted.
What are you looking for?
Renata...
where were you the night
that Cindy went missing?
Um, I went to Giant Burger
to meet up with some
friends for dinner.
When the fries got cold,
I came home.
Studied calc and fell
asleep on my textbook.
True story.
What were you calling
Cindy about at 1:00
in the morning?
Around midnight, I woke up,
ink on my face and everything.
I watched
the Gossip Girl I DVR'd
and called Cindy to go
over the pertinent details.
Did you made plans to meet up?
"Meet up"?
There's no meeting up.
Cindy and I talk every night.
This is nothing
out of the ordinary.
Wait.
You couldn't possibly think
I was there when Cindy...
When Cindy what?
You think I killed her?
Cindy was my best friend!
I would never hurt her!
Never!
Renata.
What's this all about?
Evidence consistent
with this car
was collected at
a crime scene, Mr. Davis.
This vehicle
will now be impounded.
Impound? What? Because of some
stupid measuring tape?
You can't take it!
You can't let them take my car!
You don't
actually have a choice
in the matter.
Okay. Fine. Look.
She was at home.
I was with her.
And we're done talking.
Okay, you guys are
looking for fibers
blood, hair-- any transfer
that would confirm
this is the vehicle that struck
and killed Cindy Warner, okay?
The suspect hides the murder
weapon in plain sight,
in her auto shop class.
That's pretty sophisticated
for a high school girl.
Right.
She's definitely more
sophisticated than the ones
you chat with on
the Twilight message boards.
Wait, wait.
So, I'm guessing
that about
a million grubby
teenagers probably
pawed their way
all around this thing.
So how exactly do we put
Renata behind the wheel
when Cindy was killed?
By going over it
with a fine-tooth comb.
If we can rule out
other drivers,
then we can build
a pretty good case.
Right.
What if the other driver
was wearing gloves?
Helping or hindering, Wendy,
which one's it going to be?
I am helping.
Attagirl. Thanks.
(shutter clicks)
SIMMS:
What do you got there?
Kids.
Gross.
SIDLE:
There are only two ways
to get to the drag
where Cindy was killed.
One is an exit
off the 95.
Mm-hmm.
And the other's a turn
off Blue Diamond Road,
which is the way to get
there from Henderson.
And where both Trevor
and Renata live.
Is there a traffic camera
or video surveillance
at the Blue Diamond
intersection?
I am just going
to check that out.
Good. PDs doing
their part.
Somebody's bound
to get lucky.
This is a 1933 Ford Roadster.
It was involved
in a street race that resulted
in the death of a teenage girl.
Now, we have reason to believe
that the street gang known
as the Demons
aided the driver
by chopping the
parts of this car
immediately after the incident.
Now, the gang unit has supplied
you with a list of the known
Demon chop shops,
several of which are fronted
by legitimate businesses.
Now, the job is
to locate and recover
any and all parts
from this vehicle.
And when you do so,
give CSI a call.
♪ ♪
Cindy Warner's
sweater made quite
the impression
on the hood of Renata's car.
(screaming)
There was so much
kinetic energy transferred
in the collision that when
the fabric came into contact
with the hood, it actually
deformed the clear coat
and the paint.
After that, she takes
the car to the Demons
who replace the parts and
paint everything to match.
And she pretends
the whole thing didn't happen.
Were there any other prints
besides hers
on the steering wheel?
No. No, we got her
as good as we can.
You know, there's one thing
that I still don't get.
So, Renata loses to Trevor
in a legal, organized race,
and then a week later,
they have a rematch
at an illegal drag
in the desert.
Why not just wait
until the next Rumble?
Racer mentality
runs in her family.
Her guardian
was on the stock car
circuit in the '70s.
Made a bit of a name
for himself.
Back then, guys used
to build their own cars
and race them for pink slips.
He obviously passed
the bug on to Renata.
Uh, guys, we got
a problem.
These were taken
by a traffic camera
on Blue Diamond Road
the night of Cindy's death.
STOKES:
That's Trevor's Porsche
with Renata
behind the wheel.
That doesn't
make any sense.
It blows up
our whole theory.
Trevor wasn't in the desert.
It wasn't a rematch.
So then what-- he let
Renata borrow his car
to... what?
Race who?
Her car was
already there.
STOKES:
We're missing something.
SIDLE: Okay, but what?
I think I know.
(gum rattles)
Want a piece of gum?
Piece of gum, Gus?
We know you didn't
race Trevor in the
desert, Renata.
Finally. It was starting
to feel like harassment.
You were racing each other.
We found a wad
of chewing gum stuck
on the back of the steering
wheel of Renata's car.
I know you're a fan of
Chuck Yeager's. So am I.
Chuck used to snag
a stick of Beeman
from his mechanic before
he did a test flight.
And then he'd take
the gum, right?
And he'd place it...
right on the cockpit.
So it'd be there
on his safe return home.
And I guess that in your
racing days, you'd leave
a wad of gum on
the steering wheel?
Just like Chuck.
Well, once we match
your DNA to that
chewing gum,
it's like the checkered flag
for us.
So, I chew gum.
Renata and I work together
on that car
all the time.
That doesn't prove anything.
The morning that Trevor died,
he couldn't find his car keys,
but he said found them
later inside his car.
So I think that you
got your BFF Cindy
to steal the car and
bring it out the desert
so you could race it.
And after Cindy
got killed,
you drove the car back
into Trevor's house
and left the keys
inside the car.
He...
We, we didn't mean to...
We didn't do
anything.
And we're leaving.
No, you're not leaving.
Well, wait a minute.
Actually, you can leave.
But you're going to stay.
You're under arrest.
Cuff her.
Read her her rights.
Charge is felony murder.
She were there.
You want to give her a hug,
buddy, now's a good time.
No, wait. N-now stop!
RENATA:
It's okay, Gus.
I'm going to be okay.
No.
Don't.
It's my fault.
Don't!
It was my fault.
(cheering)
What the hell
happened out there?
That guy's never raced
a day in his life
and he beat you?!
His car runs like
it's on jet fuel.
There's no beating that.
You were slow
on your gear changes.
If you had the guts
of a real racer
you would've beat him!
His car is better
than ours, Gus.
Get over it!
I saw Trevor's little toaster
all the time in class.
It's not about what's
under the hood.
And I had to show
Renata that what matters most
is the heart behind the wheel.
Cindy was dating Trevor.
I got Renata to convince Cindy
to steal Trevor's car.
so I could prove my point.
I don't know what came over me.
I just never liked
to lose to anyone.
(Cindy screaming)
RENATA:
Cindy!
Get in the car!
(panting, crying)
No! We have to find her!
All right, I will,
but I want you out of here.
Take Trevor's car
back and go home.
I tried.
I tried to find her,
but I couldn't.
But I felt that hit.
There was nothing
I could do for her.
I gave that Miyamoto
kid 500 bucks
to make the car
like new overnight.
This is on me.
RENATA (crying):
No.
It was my fault.
If I hadn't had Cindy
steal Trevor's car,
she never would have been out
there in the first place.
You did.
She was.
Who won?
WILLOWS:
Brass said the D.A.'s
going to charge
them both.
STOKES:
There you go--
two lives ruined,
two dead kids
and for what?
So some old-time race car
driver could show off?
It's a shame.
When you're young,
you think you're immortal.
And when you get older,
you just want to remember
how that felt.
Driving crazy fast
on an open road.
We're not getting
that old, are we?
(chuckles)
Good night, Nicky.
Good night, Catherine.
I'll see you tomorrow.