♪ ♪
PHILLIPS:
Lividity is fixed,
consistent
with her body position.
No apparent
discoloration.
Puts T.O.D. around 24
to 48 hours ago.
Brass said
the Dumpster diver
that called it in hadn't been
down this way in a few days.
SANDERS:
Four-plus-one impressions
on her throat.
Manual strangulation.
There's also a thin abrasion.
Killer swapped her necklace
for a choker?
(gasps, choking)
Where's the source
of that blood?
It's a V-shaped wound.
Doesn't look too deep.
Maybe incidental
to the strangulation?
Blood flow defies gravity.
She bled in an upright position
and was moved after death.
I think she might
have been dumped here.
There is some
yellow trace in the wound.
I got a purse.
(garbled radio transmission)
Heidi Custer.
New York, New York.
Business cards.
Just her name
and a 212 phone number.
No cash.
Maybe a robbery gone bad.
Cell phone.
Room key from the Luxor.
Joey Bigelow?
Hey, uh, guys...
she's carrying photos
of all of Jekyll's victims.
Multiple copies.
She a cop?
No badge or creds.
So, what was her interest
in the Jekyll case?
And did he have any interest
in her?
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
The Lone Ranger returns.
Lately, you've
had more solos
than a Lynyrd
Skynyrd concert.
I don't mind working alone.
Uh, I wanted to speak with you
about something else, actually.
Um, Heidi Custer.
The woman found
in the alley?
Yes.
I knew her.
Really?
She was a reporter.
She covered the Angel
of Death murders
at Delaware General
while I was there.
We spent quite a bit of
time talking back then.
You talk to her
recently?
No, it's been years.
But she was a
great reporter.
Fierce, tenacious.
Well, Brass reached her husband,
who's also the editor
of the magazine she writes for.
He's been in L.A. all week,
and confirmed
that she was working on a story
about Jekyll.
Do we know when she got
into town?
Monday.
How much could she discover
in three days?
Reporter like
Heidi wouldn't have come
out here without a good lead.
It's possible that she turned up
something that we didn't.
Well, Nick is heading to her
hotel room. You should join him.
All right.
No signs of a
struggle, no blood.
This doesn't look
like the primary.
And according to Heidi's
credit card records,
she had a rented
Malibu, which is
still M.I.A.
Yeah.
Where's her work?
Where are her notes and...
her research?
There's a camera charger here
and a laptop power cord.
But she could have the camera
and the computer in her car.
Right, or it could be in
the hands of her killer.
Yeah.
Blue Aces Casino
Player's Club Card here.
It's a locals only type place.
I know.
Jack Herson clocked
some credit card debt there.
It's also along Joey Bigelow's
panhandling route.
And why don't I remember
any of that?
I've been following up
on some of the Jekyll leads
in my spare time.
Oh, you have?
Yeah, I've been talking
to victims' families
and friends.
Trying to get a feel
for their habits.
Trying to get a feel for Jekyll.
Ray...
this job will eat you alive
if you take it home with you.
Okay, so, two victims
connected to the Jekyll case,
and a reporter
who was investigating it
all visited
the same little casino.
If Heidi used that
player's card anywhere,
we should be able
to find her on surveillance.
Right.
What about that?
That looks exactly
like the letter L.
Could be a message
from Jekyll. L for...
David, those are two
surgical screws,
implanted at a
90-degree angle
as part of a knee
operation, documented
in her medical records
as having been performed
three years ago
by a doctor whose name was
distinctly not Jekyll.
Let it go.
Hey, David, Doc.
What do we have?
C.O.D.'s no surprise.
Asphyxiation via manual
strangulation.
Broken hyoid.
Superficial
head wound clotted.
Later reopened around
the time of death.
As for the question
of whether
she was a Jekyll victim--
I performed a thorough
examination for puncture wounds,
laparoscopic entry points,
and despite David's imaginative
analysis...
Greg, tell me that does not look
exactly like a smiley face.
There was nothing
out of the ordinary.
No unaccounted for objects
or organs inside her.
So, Heidi Custer could be
another victim
like Lily Xiaoping--
a spur-of-the-moment,
unplanned kill
by a cornered Jekyll
who was simply trying
to avoid capture.
Hey, Archie, I brought
you that blinky thing
from the beepy
no-working thing
you told me you'd
take a look at.
Is that...?
Yeah.
Anything on the Blue Aces
surveillance, Archie?
Actually, there is.
(surveillance video rewinding)
3:30 p.m. Monday.
Heidi Custer goes
into the casino bar.
Okay.
30 seconds before that...
(video rewinding)
WILLOWS:
Langston goes into the bar.
There's no surveillance
inside the bar.
But 20 minutes later,
Langston leaves.
15 seconds
after that...
Heidi leaves.
Did he say anything about
meeting her for a drink?
Thanks.
MAN:
Afghanistan, Liberia,
Iraq.
Of all the places
she went for stories,
I never-- I never thought Vegas
would be the one that got her.
You see this mark
around her neck?
Did your wife
wear a necklace?
(gags)
Amber pendant.
Well, gift
from a Congolese rebel.
I was never able to get her
to wear her wedding ring, but...
she never took
that damn thing off.
I always knew I came
second to her work.
But she was worth it.
Yeah, I heard she was
a hell of a reporter.
A colleague of
mine knew her.
Ray Langston.
Ray Langston's a cop?
No, he's a CSI.
Ray Langston is a murderer.
About five years ago,
my wife was writing a piece
on the Angel of Death
at Delaware General Hospital.
27 patients were murdered by
injection of ethylene glycol
into their IVs.
Langston was a pathologist
at the hospital...
and a very helpful source
to Heidi.
At first.
HEIDI:
If the tragedy
at Delaware General
is ever granted the full
autopsy it deserves,
a haunting truth will
be revealed
in the harsh morgue light.
When the primary suspect,
Dr. Michael Webb
killed himself,
the same way
he killed his patients,
the police and hospital
quickly closed the case.
Even though there was
compelling evidence
that Dr. Webb did not
act alone.
Death by ethylene glycol
does not arrive unheralded.
Distinct crystals
of calcium oxalate
accumulate in the tubules
of the kidney.
And yet, with the evidence
of Dr. Webb's murders
literally glittering
before him,
Delaware General's pathologist,
Raymond Langston,
claimed to have seen
nothing unusual.
27 times over, he saw nothing
and allowed Dr. Webb's
sinister work to continue.
Well, I talked
to CSI Langston.
He had nothing but admiration
for your wife.
He never mentioned
her article.
That's because
we never published it.
It never passed
the fact-checking process.
So, her accusations
were false?
I didn't say that.
We kill stories
all the time...
because reporters rely
too heavily on unnamed sources.
And the only reason
that this story got spiked
was because a bunch of lawyers
were too afraid
the magazine was
gonna get sued.
But my wife was right.
He helped Dr. Webb,
and now he's helping
Dr. Jekyll.
CSI Langston has been relentless
in his pursuit of Dr. Jekyll.
He was personally assaulted
by the suspect.
(groans)
AARON:
And you saw this happen?
The gash in his head--
that told the story.
Giving himself
a bump on the head--
nice touch
of authenticity.
Raymond Langston hid
behind a lab coat,
and now he's hiding
behind a badge.
HODGES:
It's a lovely shade
of saffron, no?
Just got my annual
trace metals report.
Hmm, my mercury is as high
as the Baker thermometer.
Guess I should lay
off that tuna sushi.
Otherwise, I'm facing
chelation therapy.
The trace we found
in Heidi Custer's head wound
was lead paint.
My lead levels are well
within the normal range.
The weapon could have
been any tool or implement
with a 90-degree angle
and old enough
to have lead paint.
Or a super fun new toy
from China.
Ray.
Yes.
My office.
Right.
She came at me in disguise,
Catherine.
She pretended
to value my insights,
and the whole time
Heidi was investigating me.
Ray...
This article of hers
is full of junk science.
That's not the issue
here.
I examined samples that
I received from other doctors.
Dr. Webb wasn't just
going to send me
evidence of his murders,
and when his mortality rates
became suspicious,
I was the one
that bucked protocol.
I started autopsying
the bodies myself.
We're not here about the article
or your feelings, Ray.
You met with a homicide victim
shortly before she died.
What are you talking about?
And then withheld
that information
from your supervisor.
I was at the Blue Aces,
but I was there on my own time,
and I swear,
Catherine,
I never saw her there.
Conrad... you know what
a casino floor is like.
It's a maze of slot
machines and gaming tables.
(scoffs)
You know, I admire you guys for
sticking together, I really do.
I'm not saying I don't believe
you, Ray-- I'm struggling to--
but when we catch
Heidi's killer,
12 members of a jury
aren't going to be
as understanding as Catherine
when it comes
to coincidence.
They're just going to
see an over-involved CSI
who had a conflict
of interest.
So... it's hands off.
You can't work this one.
(computer beeping)
(typing)
Ray,
Catherine just told me
what happened with Ecklie.
What are you doing
in here?
Take a look at this.
Heidi Custer
used her credit card at the
Blue Aces when I was there.
Then she used it again
to park at WLVU
Medical School.
I was there--
same place, same time.
Heidi Custer
was following me.
Why would she do
something like that?
Because she thought
I was connected
to the Jekyll murders.
I'm investigating Jekyll,
she's investigating me.
All right, all right,
if anybody asks, though,
I found this,
you didn't.
Now, you got to get out
of here-- I think you're up next
for call-outs.
I may have led her to Jekyll.
I may have gotten her killed.
You don't know that.
I was going to
all the places
that Jekyll's
victims went to,
places that Jekyll may
have gone to himself.
Heidi was there
asking questions about Jekyll,
She asked the wrong person
the wrong question.
I need to go out there.
I need to retrace my steps.
No, no, we'll go back out,
as a team.
You need to stay off this case
and trust us.
We'll handle it.
I'm going to get you my notes.
All right.
He's off the Heidi Custer case.
I want to tell you something,
but you cannot tell
anybody else.
You know me.
Okay, this time I swear.
I promise.
Do you remember
the Botanica case?
Langston had palpated some
grout with his bare hands.
So I asked him for
a control DNA sample
because I wanted
to exclude him, right?
Well, in that case, I just need
a sample of your DNA
and I will exclude you.
You're going to have to put
in your report that I said no.
He refused.
Well, after seeing Gattaca,
you can't hardly blame him.
We all have privacy issues.
Okay, that's a valid point,
but a couple months before that,
he was in the break room,
and he was reading somebody's
genetic report
about M.A.O.A. deficiency.
You know, that specific
mutation right there
has actually been linked
to violent behavior.
M.A.O.A. deficiency
doesn't make you violent.
Just 'cause something might
happen, doesn't mean it will.
It's genetics,
it's not destiny.
HODGES:
I see your need
for the cone of silence.
First his hospital, his
classroom and now here.
The man does seem to be a magnet
for serial killers.
I understand not wanting
to share the details
of your personal life
with your coworkers.
But when you don't share
the fruits
of your investigative work...
No, he will
from now on.
He wasn't purposely
shutting us out.
Look, I really like Ray.
I think he's a great CSI.
But if he doesn't trust us,
how can we have his back?
And how can he have ours?
Hey, Heidi Custer used her
credit card Wednesday night
at 7:05 p.m. to get gas.
I called the station.
I got a surveillance photo
of her at the pump.
Now, that narrows down time
of death to Wednesday night.
It does something
else, too.
It gives Langston an alibi
for Heidi's murder.
At 7:05 p.m.,
he was already at work.
Solo burglary.
He was gone a couple of hours.
Well, it's easy enough to
confirm he was there, right?
Crime scene photos
are all time coded.
7:20.
24.
7:32... and the last one's
at 7:40.
So, he obviously
photoed first.
Three latent prints
in two hours?
That's all he collected?
What else was Langston doing?
OFFICER:
Parking control spotted
Heidi Custer's vehicle.
SANDERS:
Let's start a canvass.
See if anybody recognizes her
or saw who parked the car.
Will do.
SIDLE: Thanks.
Well, she wouldn't have
walked away
and left the keys
in the ignition.
No laptop, no camera.
Nothing in here either.
So, the killer dumps Heidi
in the alley
a couple miles away,
drives over here
and walks away with
the camera and the laptop.
A private lot
like this
is rarely patrolled
by police or parking control.
Dumping the car here
indicates the perp
may have some knowledge
of law enforcement.
Well, if they were banking on us
not finding the car,
maybe there's something
inside it.
(camera shutter clicking)
Bloody print
on the steering wheel.
SANDERS:
More blood over here.
LANGSTON:
I was going to all the places
that Jekyll's victims went to.
Places that Jekyll may
have gone to himself.
I need to go out there.
I need to retrace my steps.
STOKES:
You need to stay off this case
and trust us.
LANGSTON:
I may have led her to Jekyll.
I may have gotten her killed.
(tires screeching)
Hello. My name's Ray Langston.
I'm with the Vegas Crime Lab.
I came in here the other day
and showed you
some pictures.
You remember?
Oh, yeah, I remember.
Um, I have one more
photograph to show you.
Do you recognize this woman?
No. I don't make eye contact
with the customers.
It only encourages
them to yell.
I'm trying to find out
if she came in here
shortly after I did
the other day.
Maybe she spoke
with someone else?
Uh, a white male,
average build?
I've never seen her.
But I know we got surveillance,
'cause the night shift
gets robbed all the time.
All right, I'll, uh,
come back with a warrant.
Thank you.
You son of a bitch,
you killed my wife!
You killed my wife,
you son of a bitch!
(sobbing):
You son... you killed my wife!
AARON:
You just, you're gonna
let him go?
Just let him walk away?
This guy's a murderer!
I'm telling you
he's a murderer!
LANGSTON:
He blindsided me,
Catherine
Yeah, I know
the feeling.
What are you
doing here?
I was on my way
to a 406 on Riviera.
And you decided to
stop for a soda and
the Jekyll Killer
special, is that it?
Ray, you got to quit
playing detective,
you know?
'Cause I don't have
time to keep getting
your ass out of jams
that you shouldn't be in
in the first place.
(indistinct radio transmission)
So this is why
it took you two hours
to lift three points
at your last 406?
You're running your
own investigation.
Catherine, listen...
Right. It's a lot
harder to blindside a guy
if he follows the playbook
and trusts his team.
I was honestly on my way
to my scene. I passed...
You're not going to your scene
anymore. You're going home.
You're suspending me?
No, I'm diagnosing you.
You got the whatever virus.
Take a sick day.
(knocking)
Hey.
Come on in.
Catherine send you
to take my temperature?
No. No,
I'm not a doctor.
Maybe if I was,
I could decipher your
chicken-scratch handwriting.
(dry chuckle)
Nice place.
Thank you.
Single-malt.
Boy, that's good stuff.
Dr. Robbins brought it by
last week.
Care for a snort?
I'm, I'm good.
Sure?
Good stuff.
I'm sure it is.
(sighs)
We can work back there.
All right.
You've been, uh, busy, huh?
Just a little bit.
What, uh, what happened
over here?
Those are leads
I decided to eliminate;
crackpot theories mostly.
Tinfoil-hat ramblings,
some of which
are not even my own.
You know how it is, Nick.
You listen to any piece
of music long enough,
it starts to sound good.
We found
Heidi's rental car.
Unknown fingerprint
on the steering wheel.
Heidi's blood on the interior
of the passenger-side door.
The car went off the road
at some point.
Did you have any places
of interest out
in the desert,
off the beaten path?
Sure. A dump where Jack Herson
used to salvage scrap metal,
an airstrip where Bernard
Higgins used to charter jets.
Half a dozen
other places,
You think she could have
homed in on some of your leads
going out here
on her own?
I didn't go out
to any of those places while
she was following me, but...
sure, I suppose it's possible.
Ecklie's not gonna like us
running around
all over the place.
Us?
Yeah, man,
we're a team. Come on.
Okay?
Now, who's this
on the back wall
over here?
Ah... yes.
My family.
The great mystery: my father.
A man
with a very violent temper.
I sometimes wonder if my
affinity for Chicago blues
isn't the only thing
that I inherited from him.
You know, I think everybody
has a violent streak in 'em.
I know I do.
But it's how we deal with it
that determines who we are
as men.
(knocking)
We brought soup,
bagels...
And bat feces.
I'd prefer cream cheese.
Come on in.
SANDERS:
Hodges analyzed
the trace recovered
from the Malibu's
tires-- bat guano.
And based on
the insect matter,
the little morsels were the
work of the free-tailed bat.
Considering the large amount
of the sample,
the car must've been driven
near a bat roosting spot.
Mines, caves.
There are a lot of those
around Clark County.
But we can eliminate
most of them.
The Malibu's tires were clean
when Heidi filled up
at 7:05 p.m.
She started
with a full tank of gas.
Malibus can get, you know,
up to 34 miles to the gallon.
We found the car with a half
a gallon consumed, which means
she drove up to 17 miles
after she filled up.
Maximum 8.5 miles out,
8.5 miles back.
There are only
a handful of caves and mines
within 8.5 miles
of that gas station.
We marked them here.
LANGSTON:
Huh, Lobo Flats.
STOKES:
Were you out there?
Mm-hmm.
What was the lead?
A fairy tale.
That's why I tore it down.
A couple of weeks ago,
I was out at WLVU
Medical School.
A man approached me, a coffee
server named Vince Grady.
Badge lover.
He said he was interested
in what I was working on.
Dr. Langston?
You're still investigating
the Dr. Jekyll case, right?
Yes.
I saw something this weekend.
Why don't you
have a seat.
I was out near Lobo Flats
looking for arrowheads.
Valuable stuff out there
if you've got the eyes for it.
That's where I saw him.
There was blood
all over his scrubs.
So I went out there with Vince.
At first, I thought,
"Why would he be way out here?"
But if you think about it,
it's the perfect place.
Nobody could hear
his victims scream.
Who knows how many victims
he's chalked up by this point.
Could have bodies buried
all around here.
Might consider bringing out
some cadaver dogs
or ground-penetrating radar.
LANGSTON:
Place wasn't even locked.
Hardly the fastidious work
of a killer like Jekyll.
And what I found inside
did nothing
to assuage those doubts.
He's good.
Not a drop of
blood anywhere.
The guy's a genius.
I'll be sure to integrate
this lead
into our
investigation.
Is this the place?
LANGSTON:
Yes.
(sirens wailing)
(sirens stop)
OFFICER:
It's all clear.
All right, Ray, I'm heading in.
Copy that.
I got a stain on the floor
in here.
Blood?
LANGSTON:
Nick, you there?
Nick, you there?!
Yeah.
Yeah, and so was someone else.
Got a toolbox here.
Yellow paint like we found
in Heidi's head wound.
And some of the paint's
been knocked
off one of the corners.
(screaming and yelling)
(toolbox clattering)
I may even have
a partial palm print.
(computer trilling)
(indistinct radio transmission)
The bloody fingerprints from
the fridge are Heidi Custer's.
LANGSTON (over phone):
Well, what about the palm print
from the toolbox?
STOKES:
Running it right now.
(typing)
(computer trilling)
No match.
And no way to tell if it's
from the same contributor
as the bloody fingerprint
from the steering wheel
in Heidi's car.
That means Heidi was in
the building and alive
at least long enough
to have left her prints.
Ray,
if you haven't been back out
to this place
since she came to town,
how did she learn about it?
Perhaps from the same person
who led me out there.
(grunting)
Happy to aid you
with the Jekyll investigation.
Has Dr. Langston
been following up on my lead?
Mr. Grady,
you recognize her?
Yes, ma'am.
She-she's dead?
Mm-hmm.
(sighs)
Nev-never should have taken her
out there.
She said that she had seen me
talking to Dr. Langston.
Gave him a big lead
in the Dr. Jekyll investigation.
It was integrated.
Oh.
What was the lead?
Well, that's
police business.
Really don't want
to compromise the investigation.
Sure. Um, well, I'm
working on a story
for a big national
news magazine.
Think a $100 latte
might be the fix I need?
GRADY:
Hey, Lou, cover for me.
The key with a
killer like Jekyll
is to put yourself into
his twisted mindset.
It's a chess game, really.
Every move Jekyll
makes is calculated,
and guys like
Langston and I
have to anticipate
his deadly gambits.
Location like this fits
my profile of Jekyll.
I'm thinking there may
be a secret passageway
to an underground
operating room.
(gasps)
Ow.
Geez!
WILLOWS:
Toolbox just happened
to fall on her head?
GRADY:
That's what happened. I swear.
So, tell me more about
the secret passageway theory.
WILLOWS:
I'm not buying it, Mr. Grady.
And I don't think Heidi was,
either.
I think Heidi realized
that there was nothing
in that building but a story
and a pathetic little man
who had spun it
for some attention.
She called you out on it--
she humiliated you--
so you attacked her.
You smashed her head
into that toolbox,
grabbed her by the throat...
No.
No. No.
Uh, no, no, no, no, no.
Okay, yeah,
maybe she wasn't thrilled
about the head wound
and some of my theories,
but I certainly
did not touch her.
She gave me a ride
back to the medical school.
She was alive
when she dropped me off.
And I was not lying.
We never should
have breached Jekyll's lair.
But we did--
he tasted her blood,
he hunted her down,
and he finished her.
Where's Dr. Langston?
Excuse me?
I need to speak to Dr. Langston.
He understands the kind
of criminal mastermind
that we're after.
(knocking on glass)
The palm print
on the toolbox is Vince's,
but the bloody print
on Heidi's steering wheel
is definitely not.
Still unknown.
Well, it's consistent
with the goofball's story.
Guy's delusional,
but I don't think he killed her.
And we don't have
any other suspects.
But we do have another theory.
Langston's.
STOKES:
If Langston was right
and he led Heidi to Jekyll,
we might find him
somewhere
in this Blue Aces
surveillance footage.
JOHNSON:
Well, I've looked
through it all.
She didn't talk to anybody.
She just follows Langston
through the casino,
into the bar,
and then out again.
Besides, aside
from a guy
playing keno in
his bloody scrubs,
how are we even going to be able
to identify Jekyll?
Some random
five-foot-ten white dude?
Check out this guy.
He's playing a penny machine
near Langston and Heidi,
but when they were on
the other side of the casino...
...the same guy is playing
ten dollar slots,
and again right by
the two of them.
Now, nobody who plays pennies
starts yanking
ten dollars a spin like that.
Well, maybe I can get
some other angles on this guy.
Yeah, but first,
give me a surveillance still
of Jekyll
from the St. Sebastian's
Hospital supply room.
Biometric comparison?
Yeah, exactly.
All right.
WILLOWS:
So, Heidi's following Langston
and Jekyll is following one--
or both-- of them.
Yep.
And somewhere along the
way, Heidi meets Jekyll,
and he kills her.
It's looking very possible.
JOHNSON:
Okay.
There are no more angles
on this guy.
No.
He's good. He ducks the cameras.
(cell phone ringing)
Hey, Jim.
So, we picked up a guy
who was trying to pawn
Heidi Custer's amber pendant,
and her laptop and camera.
And his print matches
the bloody print
we found on the rental car.
Jim, it's got to be him--
Dr. Jekyll.
No, this kid
is no Doogie Howser.
Been spilling his guts
for the past two hours.
Name is Lou Brennan.
He's a busboy at the loony-tune
coffeemaker Vince's place,
and he was tweaked
on more than a macchiato.
Said he saw Heidi talking
to Vincent at the coffee stand.
HEIDI:
Well, I'm working
on a story
for a big national
news magazine.
BRASS:
Saw her flashing
a lot of green.
Think a $100 latte
might be the fix I need?
BRASS:
After Lou closed up,
he waited for Heidi and Vince
to come back.
What the hell?
Heard you give money
to people who know stuff.
I know stuff
about all kinds of stuff.
You know what?
I have had a belly full of crap
from losers today.
I am not giving you any money.
You don't think I know stuff?
You mop the floors for a guy
who knows nothing, so no.
Now, get out of my car.
(grunting)
(gasps)
BRASS:
Claims he didn't mean
to kill her,
just accidentally strangled her
for four and a half minutes.
Then, had to get rid
of his mess.
WILLOWS:
So, Heidi's murder
had nothing to do
with Dr. Jekyll.
It was a simple crime
of opportunity.
My big question is,
if Jekyll wasn't after Heidi,
what was he doing
at the Blue Aces?
He was following me.
The man stole my I.D. badge.
He knows my face.
He could have followed me
from the lab to that casino.
He could have followed me home.
He could have followed me here.
I can talk to Brass to get a
protection detail for you.
You should think
about wearing a gun again.
Jekyll's had plenty
of opportunities to hurt me.
I don't think
that's what he wants.
SIDLE:
Don't be so sure.
Jekyll's meticulous,
takes his time.
He might be planning
something special for you.
(cell phone ringing)
Thanks.
Excuse me.
This is Langston.
MAN:
It's been a while, Professor.
Who is this?
Did I come up on your phone
as "unknown"?
And you answered anyway.
It's nice to know you haven't
lost your faith
in your fellow man.
How's the real world
been treating you?
Ever get nostalgic
for our school days?
Nate Haskell.
That's right.
Your favorite serial killer.
I'm calling with an exciting
limited-time offer.
What do you want, Nate?
That's the wrong question,
Professor.
This isn't about what I want.
This is about what you want.
Or rather... who you want.
I know who Dr. Jekyll is.