(panting, grunting)
(screams)
(grunting, gagging)
(punches landing)
(coughing)
(groans)
(screaming)
STOKES:
What's his status?
He has multiple contusions
and severe lacerations.
You know, I should follow
and process this kid.
I'll be back soon as I can.
Still be here.
All right.
WOMAN:
I swear.
I swear on the
Bible, the Koran
and a whole stack
of police badges,
I ain't do
nothing wrong.
Then what are you
doing in the alley?
Looking for my kitty.
She's lost.
What's your cat's name?
Pussy cat.
Yeah, now why
didn't I know that?
Okay, the victim's name
is Tommy Baker.
He's a local kid.
Somebody beat the crap
out of him.
WILLOWS:
Business deal gone wrong?
What's with all the blood?
Don't take that tone
with me, Blondie.
This is the blood
on an innocent Samaritan.
BRASS:
Oh, yeah, we got a special
on Samaritans.
We're arresting
them tonight.
That's you,
your pimp...
Hey-hey-hey-hey-
hey-hey-hey-hey.
I got to work tonight,
so here's the straight.
I was in the alley
with my boyfriend.
I got some
good stuff for you.
Oh, oh.
Oh, Lord Almighty.
Honey, honey?
Are you okay?
It looked like somebody
put him in a blender
or something.
Where'd your boyfriend go?
He ran off.
I don't know.
Didn't even scrape me off a tip,
but that's okay,
because I got
his number.
(chuckles):
Okay.
Excuse me. I'm looking
for Tommy Baker.
Yeah, right down there.
Thanks.
Excuse me.
Hey, are you with
the crime lab?
Yes, sir.
Hey, I'm Mark.
I'm Tommy's older brother.
Nick Stokes.
He's pretty whacked out.
It's hard to look at
his face, you know?
Hey, excuse me.
When are we gonna
be able to see a doctor?
Nobody will
talk to me.
Doctor hasn't even been
in to see Tommy yet.
You look like
you could use a break.
There's a pretty decent vending
machine down the hallway.
Why don't you go grab something?
I'll stay
with your brother.
All right.
Okay?
Yeah.
Mr. Baker.
I'm Nick Stokes.
I'm a crime scene
investigator.
I'm here to photograph your
injuries, collect trace and...
later, I'll take your
clothes from you.
I'm sure you want to catch
whoever did this to you.
Can you tell me
what happened?
Do you know who
did this to you?
(Tommy screaming)
Get the hell out of here!
Huh?!
Leave me the hell alone!
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
Hey.
That was fast.
Yeah, I think we might
have a P-Paul.
Victim won't cooperate?
Mr. Baker went a little nuts,
busted my camera.
Is he on something?
Nah, I think
he's just traumatized.
I'm gonna have
the hospital call me
after the doctors
examine him.
What is going on here?
I found five separate
bloodletting incidents.
Blood spatter, blood
spray, drag marks.
Whew.
How come all the blood
over here is still wet,
but this blood's dry?
Well, this wasn't
a hit-and-run,
this went on
for a while.
I found some
semen here.
Hooker alley.
You'd think I
would've found more.
Mm-hmm.
Are you done taking overalls?
Yeah, all clear.
A Saint Christopher medal
with blood on it?
Could belong to the victim.
Yeah, it didn't do him
much good, did it?
That's because he's
the patron saint of travel.
Eddie always used to have one
hanging on his rear-view.
Didn't help him much, either.
Yup. No, I'm staring
at it right now.
No. All right,
sprinklers are off.
Thank you.
Fire department finally tracked
down the main water line.
Okay, KQUT traffic chopper
spotted smoke
on their morning flyover
around 8:00.
Store doesn't open till 9:00.
Did you happen
to notice
whether or not this was the fire
department's handiwork here?
You mean the evidence
eradication crew.
VARTANN:
They never checked to see
if it was unlocked.
They said that there was
so much smoke
that they had to do
a hatchet job on it anyway.
I'm going to canvass the
neighborhood, see if anybody
saw anything.
Excuse me.
Think we have a camera
in the ceiling down here.
Victim's only lightly toasted.
If someone was trying
to burn this place down,
they didn't do
a very good job.
And a seasoned arsonist would've
disabled the sprinklers.
The fire was probably
an afterthought,
just an attempt to
destroy any evidence.
Hmm.
This camera's
not just a live feed,
it's a surveillance camera.
Means there's
got to be a console
around here somewhere.
I think I found it.
Tape's missing.
How surprising.
Hey. I'm so sorry I'm late.
Just drove in from Pahrump.
Sara's got a
quintuple in a motel.
She's gonna be there for days.
(chuckles)
Your vic's only been dead
a couple of hours.
Oh.
We got two GSWs
to the upper torso.
Not through-and-throughs.
SANDERS:
Wayne Smith, 26.
Lives in the area.
Wayne Smith, proprietor.
So Wayne's here
getting ready to open up
the store, somebody comes in.
Or somebody's here already.
(doorbell chimes)
Botched burglary?
Guess it's more than the economy
that's killing
small business owners.
(sighs softly)
Hi.
I help you?
Uh, yes, ma'am.
LVPD. I'm looking
for Tommy Baker.
(sighs)
(slurred):
That's my son.
I'm his mom.
Can I get you a drink?
Uh... no.
No, I'm good.
Thanks.
Did you know your son
checked himself out
of the hospital against
doctor's orders last night,
refused treatment?
(dishes clattering loudly)
You okay?
When was he in the hospital?
Last night.
You do know your son was
assaulted last night, don't you?
Really?
(scoffs)
That boy's always
had a temper!
I hope that he
kicked some ass!
Well, he didn't.
Is he around?
I really need to talk to him.
Hey.
Mama, what are you doing here?
How'd you get in?
Hey, honey!
Did you know that Tommy was
in a fight last night?
Mark, I'm sorry
to barge in on you
like this,
but I still need to get
your brother's statement,
process him, you know?
Yeah, sure,
of course.
But, uh...
Tommy's asleep.
I'm on my break.
I came by to check on him.
Oh, okay.
I'll get him.
No. Mama, you need to go,
all right?
Get your hands
off of me!
You know you're
not welcome here.
Let's go.
I want to see my baby!
Outside!
Take it easy, okay?
All right, just
give me a minute.
Just take it easy.
Okay, just give me
some money, because...
Outside!
Take it easy!
Outside, Mom!
Let's go.
That's a police officer,
you know?!
You are a
piece of work!
That is an officer
of the law!
You don't touch
your mama like that!
I am your mother!
You're supposed
to respect me!
(knocking)
(shouting continues faintly)
MARK:
Hey, excuse me.
I didn't say you could
go into my room.
It's not your room,
it's Tommy's.
Where is he?
I don't know.
He came home, he took a shower,
he didn't feel like talking,
then he left
a little before 6:00.
Figured he went
to his girlfriend's,
but he's not
answering his cell.
Look, Mr. Stokes,
I'm sorry about your camera.
I'm not really worried
about the camera.
But, believe it or not,
there are other cases
that could use
my attention.
You know what I mean?
I'm not gonna run
all over town
playing hide and seek
with your brother.
You have him call me.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Cash register's cleaned out,
but there's a .22 in here.
Most likely belonged
to the victim.
Two fired cartridges.
The vic had two gunshot wounds,
so he probably pulled it out
to defend himself,
and then got overpowered.
But why'd the killer put
the gun back in the register?
Langston?
Ray?
I can answer my own question.
"You see, Greg, cop pulls you
over and finds cash on you,
"no big deal.
"Finds a gun,
then you're going to jail.
Want to bet it's wiped down?"
Well, looky here.
Got a serial number on the
bottom of the cash drawer.
Lots of mom-and-pops
will record the serial number
off a 20 and keep it
in the drawer as bait money.
That way,
in case they get robbed,
cops have a way to match it.
"Thanks, Greg."
No, thank you.
Back door's dead-bolted.
Window's unlocked.
Sometimes when God closes
a door, Satan opens a window.
(grate creaks)
I'm glad to
hear I'm not
the only one who talks
to himself.
I think I found a point
of entry here.
Really?
Can I help?
You can start processing
what's on that side
of the room.
All right.
I got a bag here with what
appears to be blood on it.
Looks like Jack
Sparrow's been here.
I don't think our vic
was making his living
from just selling TVs.
I don't think this was
a random hit.
Killer knew his way
in and out.
Also knew
about the surveillance.
I'm thinking that our suspect
either knew the victim
or at the very least
knew about his operation.
Then why'd he take all the cash
and leave the good stuff?
Do you know
who killed my brother?
I mean, do you, do you have
any suspects?
No, none yet.
Hey, don't worry, okay?
We're gonna
catch the guy.
So Wayne lived
at home
with you and
your parents?
No, it's just us.
Our folks died when I was 13.
Wayne had to quit school
to keep the store going.
When's the last time
you saw him?
He was heading out
when I got up.
It was around 6:00.
Wayne opens
during the week
when I'm in school.
So you work at the store, too?
Did he empty the cash register
every night?
No. He only goes to the bank
once a week.
Can I go now?
Actually, CSI will need
to get your fingerprints
just to exclude
you, okay?
And then I can give
you a ride home.
Ran a background on Tommy Baker.
Got his juvie record.
He was a runaway.
A drunk mother.
Oh, I met her.
Still drunk.
Did a stint
for punching a cop,
another for
petty theft.
He's no angel.
I'm thinking that
he picked up a hooker...
That's 50 bucks
extra, baby.
Hey-hey-hey-hey-
hey-hey-hey!
You think you're gonna get
some of this sweet stuff
without paying?
...and her management
beat him up.
He seems embarrassed about it.
I think he just wants it
to go away.
It could be the
same hooker
who called 911.
Guilty conscience.
I'll have Brass
pick her up.
Maybe she'll roll
on her pimp.
Won't do any good
if Baker won't testify.
Hey, guys, I just got
the DNA results from the alley.
All the blood came
from one unknown male.
I'm assuming that's
probably your victim.
Reasonable assumption.
But the fluid was actually
a mixture.
It was semen and blood.
So I separated out
the swimmers,
and a profile came back
to a second unknown male.
The blood was
actually a match
to the rest of the blood
at the scene.
So we got the victim's blood
plus an unknown male's semen.
Maybe the semen was
already there
and the blood
dropped onto it.
No, there was
no visible blood on
or near the stain.
You said that Tommy got violent
when you tried to process him?
Yeah.
He refused medical treatment,
he went home
and showered,
and according to his brother,
he wouldn't talk
about what happened.
If this were a woman,
what would you think?
I'd think she was raped.
WILLOWS:
Excuse me. I'd like to speak
with the nurse
that admitted
Tommy Baker last night.
I admitted Mr. Baker.
Uh, checked the
paparamedicsmedics'
intake sheet;
nothing life threatening
so I stuck him
in a room.
Did he say anything?
Just that he got jumped
after leaving a bar.
And did the paramedics draw
any blood?
They suspected
drug use, so they pulled
a sample.
Do you still have that?
Thank you.
(knocking)
Miss Martin,
Nick Stokes, CSI.
I got your name
from Captain Brass.
Who cares if I'm in the middle
of lunch, right?
I can come back later.
Mm-mm.
We never get CSI
in Victim Services.
Wouldn't want you to waste
a trip. What is it?
I have a victim who may have
been sexually assaulted, but he
isn't really in
the mood to talk.
"Sexually assaulted,"
as in raped?
Yeah.
Men almost never
report it.
People think
it's a prison thing,
but it's just as likely
to happen on the outside.
This your first?
Yeah. Yeah, that's why I'm here,
looking for some insight.
Your victim was
raped in an alley
My experience, it means
he probably didn't have
a strong connection
to his attacker.
Either they didn't know
each other
or the connection
was casual.
And don't be surprised
if Mr. Baker never admits
he was raped.
Odds are you'll probably close
the case on lack of cooperation
and then make fun of him
around the office.
Have a nice day,
Mr. Stokes.
What is your problem?
I'm just trying
to do my job here.
I've watched you guys
stand over dead bodies
and crack jokes.
I still see
a human being
when all you see
is evidence.
Which might make you
a good investigator,
but it also makes you
cold, hard people.
So you can feel compassion
for dead people, but you can't
feel it for someone who's
alive wearing a badge
trying to help?
Good luck with that.
Enjoy your sandwich.
Best way to get Mr. Baker
to talk
is to let him know
that you want to help him,
that it's not just a job.
Give him my card.
He might feel more
comfortable talking
to a woman.
Keep the other one in case
you have any more questions.
Okay. Thanks.
Out with it, Simms.
What is up with Ecklie?
Excuse me?
He said he's not
gonna let anybody else
pull a Sanders.
I don't get to go out
in the field.
Ah.
And the thing
that really
pisses me off about this...
I have recommendation letters
from Grissom, Catherine
and Nick in my file.
It didn't make
any difference to him.
I mean,
this is ridiculous.
It's supposed
to be a meritocracy.
Since when?
Et tu, Hodges?
It's a bureaucracy.
Just keeping it real.
You want me to talk
to Conrad for you?
Yeah, no.
I can talk to him myself.
You sure?
We're in book club
together,
and Conrad respects
my opinion.
At least where
Pride and Prejudice
and Zombies
is concerned.
I thought you were
against me going
from lab rat to field mouse?
I just want you to be happy.
ROBBINS:
Victim from the electronics
store was shot twice.
Both bullets entered
front to back,
but this one's
your killer.
Did a little samba
around the lung and heart.
(gunshot)
Bullet entered the left lung,
hit the anterior aspect
of the spine, then ricocheted
down into the ascending aorta.
.22s will do that.
Yeah.
You find any soot
in his larynx?
Well, if you're wondering
whether Mr. Smith was breathing
when the fire started, he was.
Thank you, Doctor.
Show ain't over yet.
Glasses?
I found this under the soot.
Bruise is perimortem.
Could have occurred any
time between one minute
and a couple hours
prior to death
Judging from color and shape,
I'd say someone slapped him
pretty hard.
Maybe the killer.
(claps twice)
Or it could be
unrelated.
The zipper on his pants
was down,
so I swabbed his penis;
found a vaginal contribution.
He had sex shortly
before death.
So you're thinking it's a woman.
A little slap and tickle?
Most men don't slap, they punch.
Now the show's over.
Not quite yet.
SANDERS:
Uh, yeah, connect me
to pawnshop detail, please.
Hi. This is CSI Sanders.
I need you
to run some serial numbers
against your database.
The first one is
a Patek Phillipe watch.
Serial number is
Edward-6-Victor-5-Lincoln-2.
All right, next one is
a diamond ring--
5-Victor-7-2-1.
Pam Harris.
Grrlz Club?
MAN:
One, two, three, four.
(rock music playing)
♪ ♪
I'm Pam.
You're looking for me?
Miss Harris,
I'm Detective Vartann, LVPD
This is Greg Sanders
from the crime lab.
You reported
a ring missing?
My engagement ring.
If you guys got it,
drinks are on me,
all night.
We wish we could
take you up on that.
So you caught the guy?
Do you recognize this man?
Wayne?
Are you kidding me?
Angela, get your
ass over here.
These guys
want to know
about Wayne.
I told you not
to date customers.
Wayne's my boyfriend.
He's not in any trouble, is he?
Did you know Wayne
was fencing stolen goods?
No way. He sells TV's.
But I lost my
sapphire necklace
just last week, and Wayne
kept telling me it must be
in my apartment.
That dirtbag!
I'll tell you where he lives,
and I'll press charges.
Well, that
won't be necessary.
He's dead.
Oh, my God.
I ran this three times,
and I kept getting
exactly the same results.
I think I cross-contaminated
your samples.
(clears throat):
All right...
first of all,
what are your results?
Well, the fluid from the alley
came back as a mixture
of Tommy Baker's blood
mixed with Wayne
Smith's semen.
Wayne Smith?
That's our victim.
Right. And
then the blood
from the bag that you
two found at the store
came back as
Tommy Baker.
That's our victim
from the alley.
Not a mixture,
just a single profile?
Yeah. That's why
I confirmed it in triplicate.
Okay, so if there was
cross-contamination
or commingling,
there'd be a mixture
of profiles
on the bag, too.
Unless it's an additional
lab error, and it's from
a third, unrelated case?
Knowing Wendy's process
and lab procedure,
with only one case
open at a time,
I'd say that's... impossible.
WILLOWS:
So if there's
no cross-contamination,
then there's a connection.
It means
that Wayne Smith
sexually assaulted Tommy Baker.
(punches landing, grunting)
Which gave Tommy motive
to kill the bastard.
If I were Tommy,
I would've killed him, too.
Hey, look.
I found a Franken-Blob.
That could be our missing
surveillance tape.
Mm, it's pretty destroyed.
Archie's gonna have
a hard time with this one.
Hmm.
We didn't find any evidence
of accelerant at the scene,
but these could be
our ignition source.
Maybe you can
pull DNA.
I knew you were taking
a lot of classes--
I didn't realize
you knew all
about DNA.
No, I don't know
all about it... yet.
(laughs)
But I did learn
that burn materials
used to be collected
in paint cans
and plastic bags, which
preserves accelerant
but destroys DNA,
which, until recently, no one
knew could survive fire damage.
I take it you passed.
You take it right.
Mm, the stems are limp;
that means they got wet.
Unfortunately, DNA can't survive
on burn material once it's wet.
Well...
Wendy,
these babies look dry.
Where have you been?
I was dialoguing with Conrad.
What else have
you been touching?
Have you run the trace
from my cash tray?
Dust bunnies?
Comprised of dirt,
pollen, metal shavings
from copper wiring
and fecal matter.
Did you know that most dust
contains trace amounts of poop?
Even in hospitals.
What about the white fragment?
Eh, still in the works.
All right, I know
you're dying to know,
so I'm just gonna tell you.
I was talking to Onrad-Cay
about Endy-Way
and an ansfer-tray
to the ield-fay.
I... need the trace.
Ow-nay.
Oser-lay.
Ey-hay.
LANGSTON:
The edges of the security tape
were melted,
but this section
survived.
It's from the night
before Smith was shot.
Check out the bag.
Now, it looks like
the one that we found,
but it doesn't have
Tommy's blood on it yet.
I think this is Tommy.
Seems to be avoiding
the camera.
Does have on
similar clothing.
The night that Greg and
I processed the store,
we were under the assumption
that it was one event.
Wayne interrupted
a burglary,
the suspect shot him
and torched the place.
But this proves there
were two events.
The botched burglary
on Thursday night...
WAYNE:
Bastard! I'm gonna kill you!
...the shooting on
Friday morning.
That time code
says 10:16 p.m.
Wayne assaulted
Tommy in the alley
a few minutes later.
You know...
that electronics store
was only five blocks away.
So... there was
a chain of events,
assuming that Tommy
is our killer.
Okay, let it run.
All right.
What did he just take there?
There?
That's a St. Christopher medal.
You know, I found
one of those at
my crime scene.
Then how did he
know it was there,
and why did he take it?
(sighs)
What is it, Nick?
Wayne had a stripper girlfriend.
He had sex with a female
just moments before he died.
Every indication is,
this guy was a hetero.
So?
So, you catch a guy
burgling your store,
you want to teach him a lesson--
I get it, you beat him,
you stab him, you shoot him--
but do you have to rape him?
Greek warriors in ancient times
would sodomize their enemies
after a battle to humiliate
them, take their manhood.
Yeah, yeah, I understand
the concept of humiliation--
rape isn't about sex,
it's about violence.
But this is a little excessive,
don't you think?
Well...
for some men...
violence is their sex.
BRASS:
Do you recognize that man?
WILLOWS:
He was in the store
Thursday night.
We have him
on surveillance.
No. I've never
seen him before.
We think he's the one
who killed your brother.
No, he didn't.
How do you know that?
Because I killed Wayne.
JESS:
I hated him.
Wayne treated me like property.
Had all these rules.
I couldn't wear short skirts.
I had a 10:00 curfew.
He would hack into my email.
I couldn't sleep over
at friends or...
or get my own car.
He threatened any guy
who asked me out.
And that's why
you shot him?
No.
I shot him because he liked
to hit me when he got mad.
Why don't you
tell me about that?
The first time he hit me
was eighth grade,
because I wore makeup to school.
Wayne said I looked like
a whore, and he would know.
He was such a hypocrite.
Sleeping around, partying,
stealing stuff.
BRASS:
I'm just trying to understand.
Did Wayne, uh,
do anything else to you?
JESS:
Isn't that enough?
So no one ever noticed?
You know, a doctor, a teacher,
a friend or anyone?
I got real good
at hiding it.
This is the last thing
he gave me.
I tried to run away.
He always found me.
'He thought I was
his baby sister,
and he wanted
to keep it that way.
I'm 18 years old.
He was never going to let me
have my own life.
(beep)
Oh. Now, that looks
like you know him.
You know, I think
I get it now.
Your brother, Wayne Smith,
caught your boyfriend,
Tommy Baker,
stealing from his store
and assaulted him.
And then Tommy came back
later and shot Wayne.
And then in order to
cover up for Tommy,
you made up
this whole...
sequence of lies.
No.
We were going to get married.
We needed money
to get out of town.
So I came up
with this plan
to rob the store.
But I left my
St. Christopher medal, and...
I couldn't leave without it.
It was my mom's.
That's how Tommy ended up
on the surveillance.
That's the least
of his problems.
I already told you.
I shot my brother.
Tommy had nothing to do with it.
OFFICER:
Don't run!
Tommy, stop!
On the ground!
Hold it right there!
(cops shouting, Tommy yelling)
What is this?
It's the number of someone
who might be able
to help you.
Listen, Tom, I know
what happened to you
in that alley.
What are you talking about?
Hey, rape
is a horrible thing,
no matter who it happens to.
This young lady will...
will better understand
what it is you might
be going through, help
keep your manhood intact.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Nothing happened.
Look, W-Wayne beat me up.
Okay? He didn't
make me some...
some bitch.
We talked
to your girlfriend,
Jess-- she claims she's
the one that did it.
Did... did what?
Shot Wayne.
I did it.
I killed Wayne.
Everything was
my idea.
Well, we found her prints on the
unlocked window at the scene.
That's conspiracy.
I'm telling you right now,
Jess had nothing to do
with that, okay?
I staked that place out
for three weeks.
And after the robbery
went south,
after the alley, I went
back into the store.
And I knew right then that
he would never let me
see Jess again.
Son of a bitch!
I want to cooperate
with you, Mr. Stokes,
100%, but you got to leave
Jess out of this.
I can't do that, Tom.
Not if the evidence
shows me she was involved.
So what, you got him here?
Mr. Stokes.
Yeah?
Hey, I just got a call.
Tommy's been arrested?
(phone ringing)
I don't understand.
You brother just confessed
to killing the man
who assaulted him.
What?
I'm sorry, Mark,
I got to take this.
Tommy's lying.
I shot Wayne Smith.
Come again?
Then I torched the store
to cover it up.
This is for my brother.
BRASS:
So you shot him
with a Colt .45?
That's right.
What did you do
with the revolver?
I tossed it in a Dumpster
by my house.
And you did this because
Wayne Smith assaulted
your brother--
Tommy Baker?
It was more than assault.
He raped my brother.
Tommy tell you that?
I, uh...
I figured it out.
When I saw the blood,
I don't know, I felt sick.
What did he do to you, Tommy?
You know, you could have just
called the police
and had Wayne arrested.
That would have been
the easy
thing to do.
Then the whole world
would know what happened.
Tommy would have never been able
to live that down.
The truth is,
it would have been better off
if that bastard had just
killed Tommy.
So we've got three confessions
and three suspects.
Jess Smith, Tommy Baker,
Mark Baker.
The DNA evidence
on the matchbook
puts Mark at the scene.
Which proves
that he set the fire.
But he claims
he used a .45.
Murder weapon
was a .22.
Yeah, he's lying about that,
but not about the fire.
STOKES:
Yeah, he knew Tommy ran
out of the house
and he assumed
his brother did it.
He was trying to cover it up
to protect him.
Grabbed the surveillance tape,
tossed it in the box,
set the fire.
What do we have on Tommy?
STOKES:
Motive, opportunity,
but no physical evidence
putting him in the store
at the time of the shooting.
Have we considered
the possibility
that Tommy confessed
for the same reason
his brother Mark did?
To protect the person he loved.
Jess-- who has her own reasons
for killing Wayne.
Could have been Tommy,
could have been Jess,
could have been both.
Okay, maybe we can
come at this from a
different direction.
Whoever shot Wayne,
most likely stole the cash
from the register.
Well, I didn't find any cash
in Jess' house.
And I searched the Baker boys'
apartment and their vehicles.
Nada.
Then again, the mother could
have helped herself to it.
WOMAN (over P.A.):
CSI Stokes. Stokes,
please come to reception.
Now what?
Ms. Martin.
What can I do for you.
I just came
from Tommy's jail cell.
I didn't know
Victim's Services
was allowed to talk
to suspects.
He's still a victim.
You're the one who gave him
my card.
Tommy asked me to pass on a
message to his brother Mark.
Who is also now in jail.
What's the message?
You know I'm bound
by confidentiality.
Come on. Why'd you
come down here then?
I've read Tommy's confession,
and the police report.
There is no way that kid
was brave enough to confront
his attacker unarmed.
It's very atypical.
Like everything
in this case.
Look, I know you think
I'm just a bleeding heart,
but I can read victims
like you can read fingerprints.
Tommy Baker is not a killer.
Okay.
Okay, I'll keep that
under consideration.
I don't think you're
a bleeding heart.
I appreciate the help.
Your white fragment.
Ran MICRO-FTIR.
Came back synthetic.
More specifically acrylic.
With a layer of "Snow White"
nail polish on top.
French tips.
My mother wears acrylics...
♪ ♪
Hey, Ms. Paulson.
Hey, officers.
Did you find my necklace?
No, but we think
we found out
who killed your
boyfriend Wayne.
Really? Who was it?
You.
This is a search warrant.
I'll take that,
thank you.
Same serial number
as the bait money.
Stop!
Why don't you tell me
that you love it, huh?
Don't! I don't want to!
I got to get to work.
What? I'm not man
enough for you?
Just give me my money.
I want my cut for all
the stuff I stole.
That's for the dress
I bought you.
You owe me for the trip.
That was a gift you ass!
(gun cocking)
Get that thing out of my face!
(gunshot)
You're under arrest
for the murder of Wayne Smith.
It wasn't my fault.
I wiped off the gun
and took what he owed me.
It was self-defense.
Keep still, ma'am, please.
Thank you.
WILLOWS:
You're free to go.
They're just finishing
up some paperwork.
But I need
to ask you...
How did Wayne know that Tommy
would be at the store?
He didn't.
Wayne was supposed
to be at home with me.
This whole thing
was my fault.
My brother was
obsessed with me
staying a virgin.
He had no clue Tommy
and I were having sex.
Tommy would always come over
when Wayne was at work.
No, wait, no.
Oh, I ripped your shirt.
I'm sorry.
(both laughing)
I didn't even
think about it
when my shirt ripped that night.
Then Wayne came home...
What the hell
happened to you?
Nothing.
It must have ripped
on something.
I'm-I'm fine.
You had sex, didn't you?!
No.
No, Wayne, no.
I wouldn't.
It wasn't like that.
It wasn't.
It was that Baker kid,
wasn't it? Huh?
He forced you, didn't he?
Didn't he?
JESS:
He went crazy.
Took my cell and locked
me in my room.
I knew Tommy was at the store
and Wayne was going there
to get his gun, but...
I had no way to warn him.
So what's going to happen
to my brother?
D.A.'s gonna charge
him with manslaughter.
Wayne was still alive
when Mark set that fire.
Listen, Tommy,
I know you've been traumatized.
And I want to tell
you that, uh...
Hey, look at me.
(sniffs)
If there's
anything you need,
you call me.
Here, take this.
Back-back in the alley
uh...
he said something.
I'm going to ruin you
like you ruined my sister!
It really worked.
Because I can't even think
about Jess now,
without seeing his face.
I didn't even fight back.
I just froze up, you know.
I didn't-- Why couldn't I
at least just fight back?
It wasn't your fault.
Look, Jess doesn't know
what happened,
and I'm sure not going
to say anything.
And if you
don't want to,
that's up to you.
But if you really love her
and she really loves you,
this isn't going
to make a difference.
Tommy?
Tommy...