(cheering, applause)
Whoo! Yeah!
ANNOUNCER:
Unbelieveable!
All X's, baby.
All X's all the time.
ANNOUNCER:
I'll tell you what, he
is a cocky young man,
that Kevin "X-Man" Chatts.
Look at him out there
playing to the camera.
ANNOUNCER 2:
What an ego, huh?
Yeah.
I'll tell you though...
Look at this.
Oh, man.
The crowd's loving it.
The fans love him.
Chevy Cigs has always
had his number though.
They've met
12 times on tour--
Chevy has 12 trophies.
X has zero.
ANNOUNCER 2:
Well, Chevy needs to
clear the rack here,
he'll make it 13.
All right.
Here's the determination.
This is the closest
they've ever been.
Here it goes.
Oh.
Oh, my goodness!
Hah! Yeah!
That's right, the
X's are all mine!
Seven-ten split.
The dreaded
field goal.
How many times has this been
done, J.T., in history?
ANNOUNCER 2:
Three times.
Only three times.
Three times,
national TV.
Chevy Cigs has got
to pick them both up
to make this
a win for him.
If not, X-Man wins
and becomes the new champion.
(rumbling)
Oh, my God!
(crowd gasping,
screaming)
(camera shutter clicking)
This head used to be attached
to the body Ronald Tobin.
He works here at
the rental desk.
That's his girlfriend
over there.
She works here, too.
Cocktail waitress.
Understandably
in shock.
What do you mean
you don't know
when the match
is gonna resume?
I'm going back
to Omaha tomorrow.
It's my son's birthday.
MAN:
I'm sorry,
there's nothing I can do.
You got to be kidding me.
Hey, can you speed this up?
I was beating this guy
straight up!
You haven't won
anything yet, kid.
We're not even letting him
wash his hands.
Do you think we're going
to let you bowl?
Look, I wasn't talking to you.
Hey, hey, hey.
Come with me.
Let's go. Come on.
This isn't over yet.
See you soon.
SANDERS:
All right,
that's it, I'm done.
Just make sure to give
your contact info
before you leave.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa!
You cannot touch that
ball; it's evidence.
I've thrown with that ball
for ten years.
It's my go-to ball.
You'll get it back.
Eventually.
OFFICER:
Please follow me, sir.
Right this way.
When did bowling
become so serious?
You know, it
doesn't take
an expert to know,
if the head came out the return,
it went in
behind the lane.
Maybe that's where
the rest of the vic is.
♪ ♪
(cell phone ringing)
Yeah?
SANDERS:
Yeah, I didn't find
a body back here.
But I did find an empty bowling
ball bag with blood in it.
Bag without a ball,
head without a body.
At least we know
what we're looking for.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
(camera shutter clicking)
Man, this is more complicated
than I thought.
You know, at the turn
of the century,
this was all done by hand.
Really?
Yeah.
Ten-year-old kids called
pin boys would run around
clearing and resetting
all the pins,
returning the balls
to the bowlers.
Too bad they're not
around anymore.
We might have some suspects.
Looks like the head
rolled through there, huh?
Yeah, this is the tower section
of the ball return
conveyor system.
The killer had to start there.
It's the only way in.
The head went into the pit...
(ball striking pins)
...through the ball door.
Up the tower, under the lanes,
through the accelerator...
...and out the return.
You sure do know
a lot about bowling.
Uh, mechanical engineering
class in college.
We took a field trip
to a bowling alley.
Every Saturday night,
family league.
Yeah?
You any good?
I'm not bad.
Okay.
Photo, mark and sample.
I have the victim's
vehicle registration.
I'm gonna go see
if his car's in the parking lot.
Too bad the only surveillance
is at the register
and front entrance, huh?
I knew that field trip
would come in handy.
♪ ♪
(groans)
LVPD. Out of the car.
Come on.
Hands, hands.
Let me see
some hands.
Put them
on the car.
Don't move.
(whistles)
What are you
doing in there?
I was sleeping, man.
Do you know
who this car belongs to?
Yeah, Ron Ron.
He's been letting me crash here
till I got my own digs.
I know he's dead.
I'd seen his head come
rolling out of that thing
and all that.
I'm still pretty wigged out
about it.
But you're still sleeping
in his car?
It's a lot more comfortable
than the concrete bedsprings
I'm used to.
I'm homeless.
How do you
know him?
We're from the same hood.
I've been down in the dumps,
and Ron Ron was helping me out,
money-wise.
Even got me a stock boy gig
over at the SSB.
Yeah, what's the SSB?
It's the Silver State
Bowling Supply.
Duh.
What about all
this bowling gear?
Wouldn't happen to
be stolen, would it?
Man, I don't know donkey
about bowling.
That's Ron Ron's thing.
You just told me you work at
the bowling supply company.
I just started there.
And like I said,
that's Ron Ron's thing.
Yeah, so is this car.
You're moving out today, buddy.
Get out of
there. Come on.
Man, what are y'all
doing up so early?
Get out of there.
MAN:
Carla always swore
she was innocent.
LANGSTON:
And you believed her?
MAN:
As a Public Defender, I believe
she was innocent
until proven guilty.
LANGSTON:
Well, based on what's here,
that shouldn't be a problem.
But looking at it,
13 months ago,
Carla York
and her husband James
got into a heated argument,
which got a little more heated.
PUBLIC DEFENDER:
Carla and James had
a pretty volatile relationship.
He liked to play around, there
were allegations of affairs,
they fought all the time.
And Carla had served
on the National Guard.
(gunshot)
LANGSTON:
So, she was trained to shoot.
The revolver was found
in the bushes-- a .38.
It was registered
to the husband.
It was usually kept in the
master bedroom nightstand.
This was confirmed
by Ferrotrace.
Bullets matched the gun.
Now, what was your defense?
The usual.
Ah. Attack the evidence.
There was no GSR on the wife.
Day shift found the shower
still wet,
so she obviously cleaned up.
She was heavily intoxicated--
BAC 0.18.
She claims she didn't remember
anything that night.
How many innocent clients
have you heard that from?
She had no history
of violence.
Well, a lot
of domestic murderers don't.
According to the
police report,
the sister named Hannah
was staying with them.
(gunshot)
Then she heard the shot,
found the body, called 911.
Was the sister
ever a suspect?
Unfortunately, no.
She'd been on a date
earlier that evening,
with a movie ticket
stub to prove it.
Taxi dropped her
off at the house.
Cabbie confirmed
angry voices inside.
Sister claims
she was out back
trying to get away
from the noise.
Are you certain there was
no one else in the house?
Just the vic's
11-month-old daughter
in the master
bedroom crib.
I tried to get
Carla to plead out.
She just wouldn't do it.
Jury came back guilty
in five hours.
She was dead five
hours after that.
Why are you so interested
in the original case?
This woman hung herself
over the verdict.
I would like to know why.
You're thorough.
I heard that about you.
Is there anything else
you need from me?
No. No, thanks.
Take care.
You know, I brought
Carla's kid to the jail
a few times to visit her
while she was awaiting trial.
She always used to tell her,
her dad was on vacation
and that he loved her very much.
It's kind of sad, huh?
Ah, just in time
for the headtopsy.
I heard someone
was using this one
as a bowling ball.
Well, his head is
very spherical.
My father had bowling alleys
in every one of his casinos.
I liked everything
about them but the bowling.
Rented shoes
that you have to disinfect
before you put them on.
Not for me.
This looks like
manual saw strokes.
Probably a handsaw
or a box saw.
Multiple cuts
from multiple angles,
hesitation marks.
Whoever did this
wasn't skilled.
Lack of hemorrhagic
tissue suggests
decapitation was postmortem.
What do you think this is?
Has an alveolar texture.
Lung tissue?
Mm-hmm.
How'd it end up in his nose?
Maybe the vic suffered
some kind of traumatic injury
to the chest, like a gunshot.
(gunshot)
Could be C.O.D.
We found this guy
in Ronny's car,
and he has a pretty
long rap sheet.
Oh, yeah,
that's Vitas.
He was going through
some really hard times,
and Ronny was
helping him out.
Do you think
he killed Ronny?
We don't know.
When was the last time
that you saw Ronny alive?
Earlier today; he was working.
You know, before...
his-his head...
You know.
Did he have any enemies
that you know of?
Just himself.
He wanted to be pro,
but he ended up
being the shoe boy,
and it really started
getting to him.
So he gave up on his dream.
No, his dream
gave up on him.
He definitely had
the physical ability.
I don't know anyone
that could throw
a harder ball.
He even beat the X-Man
the other day in a pickup game.
I-I know this is weird
to say after what
just happened...
...but he just didn't really
have it all up here.
You know, it takes
more than skill to bag
ten in a row
five days in a row.
You really have to have
a level head.
♪ ♪
(trilling, beeping)
Yep, it's my two-ball roller.
What makes you so sure?
It was made for me.
The company sponsors me.
You know, those
are my colors.
Where'd you find it?
Back of the bowling alley
with the victim's blood on it.
Why don't you have a seat?
You know you should be talking
to the guy
who snaked it
from my dressing room
first day of the competition.
I've been using
my spare.
Sit down.
(firmly):
(sighs)
So, do you know
the victim?
Not really.
Well, according to twitterverse,
you know him pretty well.
I don't have a Twitter.
You fans do, critics do.
I do. I tweet.
Listen to this.
"Kevin X gets beat
by local Vegas putz."
Do you know what a "putz" is?
"Shoe boy makes X-Man
look like an amateur."
"X-Man should put down
the bottle before
he loses to his self."
(chuckles)
Ooh, that's-that's harsh.
This is like a whole
wealth of information.
This is a detective's dream.
(chuckles)
Okay. Yeah... we played.
Hey, guy,
hook me up with a lane.
Sorry, we're all full up
right now.
You're full?!
Yeah.
Do you know who I am?
I don't care who you are.
Okay, look, let's just say
that I'm the best bowler
in the place, all right?
I doubt that.
He challenged me, I couldn't
disappoint the ladies.
Right.
And you were drunk and you think
highly of yourself.
Yeah.
(spectators murmuring)
Come on...
(cheering)
I'll admit he wasn't bad.
That must have pissed you off.
It didn't piss me off
enough to kill him,
if that's where
you're going.
It's physically impossible
for me to have tossed that head
in the ball return, okay?
I can't be in two places
at once.
I'm a bowler, okay?
I'm not Criss Angel.
Maybe you had a partner.
All right,
let's go to motive.
Tell me about you
and Chevy Cigs.
He's, uh, he's old school.
I'm new.
He uses a three-finger grip,
I use a no-finger grip.
He's a hook guy,
I'm a straight roller.
I'm a freewheeler,
he's a... technician.
But he's the only guy
you never beat on the tour.
You know,
I did some research
'cause bowling's
not my thing,
but I found out
that the old school
is always kicking
new school's ass.
So maybe you thought
the only way to beat Chevy
is to mess with his head...
...with a head.
You gonna let me go now
or should I ask for my lawyer?
No, you can go.
(PDA beeps)
Just don't leave town.
♪ ♪
Fire in one!
You got the same
entry wound path
from two different
shooting angles.
Uh-huh.
How?
(chuckles)
A bullet hitting
a slanted surface
should deflect up, right?
Not always.
Not when they're hollow points.
One theory is because
the lower lip
of the hollow point strikes
the glass first,
the unbalanced force
on the bullet
deflects it down, sometimes
as much as ten to 15 degrees.
If you didn't
account for it,
you might conclude that a shot
came from a second-story window
when really, it was fired
from level ground.
Was this a day shift case?
Those lazy, incompetent
bastards...
Look, it means
that the victim's wife
didn't shoot him.
You just exonerated her.
Like my daddy
used to say,
"A day late and a dollar short."
STOKES: Where'd you
get these images?
The bowling alley
has pinsetter cameras.
Really?
Yeah.
Near the end of the lane,
the ball breaks the infrared
sensor, which initiates
the pinsetter control unit.
After the ball hits,
a CCD camera snaps an image,
activating the sensors
in the pinsetter,
telling it which pins
have been knocked down
and which need
to be picked up.
The sensors then relay
that information
to the automatic scoring system.
That is Chevy's last toss.
The dreaded seven-ten split.
SANDERS:
But check this out.
The victim's head in
the killer's hands,
moments before
the head rolled out.
Now, according to Brass,
our vic played Kevin X
the night before.
So, I went through
those photos
and I found this.
STOKES:
Hey, I know that guy.
Know where he works, too.
BRASS:
We're looking for Vitas Ling.
MAN:
Back there.
WILLOWS:
You recognize that smell?
Hey, Cheech.
BRASS:
Got your hands on a little
chronic, eh, hombre?
Whoa, all right?
Everybody just
calm down, okay?
It's medicinal.
I got a bad back, all right?
I got it at a dispensary.
I got my card in my wallet
right here.
Keep your hands
where we can see them.
Okay.
This is Nevada, pal.
You want to play that,
go back to Cali.
STOKES:
"Going Back to Cali."
That's a good
rap song.
BRASS:
Yeah, I'm channeling
Notorious B.I.G.,
can't you tell?
Hey, Jim, go ahead
and take "High Times"
back to the station.
Nick and I are gonna get a
little familiar with this place.
Oh, come on!
I've got a box saw over here.
It's the same type of saw used
to cut off the victim's head.
I think we just found
the victim's head remover.
Got some more blood over here.
Trail looks like
it goes outside.
STOKES:
See that... right there?
Then it kind of stops.
Positive for blood.
C.O.D.
is gunshot to the chest.
This could be where
Ronald Tobin was killed.
STOKES:
Medium velocity spatter.
Could be from
an exiting bullet.
Nine millimeter.
Remington Golden Saber.
There's a trail
of wood splinters.
Somebody was dragging
something made of wood.
(groans softly)
You recognize that smell?
Yes, ma'am.
Unfortunately.
Staphylinidae beetles.
Clean up crew.
BRASS:
Who's that?
That you?
Can you see through
those slits, buddy?
Yeah, man.
I was knocking over pins
for Ron Ron.
He called me up, said he was
bowling against some pro
and he needed
my help.
So, you were cheating for him?
Yeah.
20 bucks a pin.
I knocked over, like,
ten that night.
(clicks tongue)
It's easy money.
It was easy money
for your drug dealer.
'Cause everything you get
goes to him.
Right?
Unless, Ron Ron
wasn't breaking you off
with your paycheck on time?
Of course he did.
He was a stand-up dude.
Stand-up dudes don't cheat.
He only was doing this
to impress his girl Shea.
Stand-up dudes don't steal.
He only stole that stuff
because he was a fan.
I never seen him sell any of it.
Well, maybe you were selling it,
and you didn't cut him in
on his action.
You... you think I killed him?
You were caught sleeping
in Ronald's car.
He was shot,
he had his head cut off.
He was thrown away
like a piece of garbage,
and all this happened
at your place of employment.
And you're telling me you didn't
know anything about it?
No, I didn't.
Look, I may be a-a-a broke,
homeless druggie,
but I ain't no killer.
Okay.
That should do it.
This is the bullet's
true path.
Shot came from
the backyard.
Yes.
And with any luck,
this overhang
will have protected this area
from the elements.
Maybe we can still get GSR.
Don't you put your hands on me!
That's enough!
Well, the sister told the truth
about one thing--
she was exactly
where she said she was.
Autopsy confirms that the victim
died of a single gunshot wound
through the left lung.
All of the blood at the scene
was from our victim.
No hits on the bullet
and no prints on the saw.
There were two sets of prints
on the bloody roller bag--
the victim's and
Kevin X's.
Kevin X.
Okay, we know
that the victim
and his pal Vitas
were partners in crime,
stealing whatever
they could get their hands on.
But if these two guys
are the best we got,
I'm a little worried.
Both of them were
at the front of the lanes
when Ronald's head popped out--
Kevin was bowling,
Vitas was
in the crowd.
I mean, how could
either one of them
have put the head
in the ball pit?
You're right about Kevin--
he was bowling the whole time,
and we have the footage
to prove it.
Which leaves Vitas.
Is it possible
that he put the head
in the ball pit
and made it around
to the front of the lanes
in time?
And obviously it's going
to take a little longer
for a ball to make it back
to the return
if it's pushing a human head.
It also depends
on the pinsetter.
Some are faster than others.
The automated scoring
computer clocked
Chevy's first throw of the
tenth frame at 8:47.
The head appeared in the return
just 18 seconds later.
So, you're telling me
that Vitas
dropped the head in the ball pit
and then made it all the way
back around to the front
of Chevy's lane in 18 seconds?
I don't know if weed head
could've pulled that off.
I mean, look at him.
Well, there's only one way
to find out.
Are you ready?
It's in.
13 seconds.
(panting)
Good job.
It's five seconds faster
than the pinsetter.
I don't know, man.
Add in the crowd, it's doable.
Even for Vitas.
SIDLE:
This is the raw broadcast
footage of the tournament.
We have all the camera angles.
So, this is the moment that
Ronald's head appeared.
And there's Vitas.
Back it up.
Let's see
where he came from.
This is a few
moments prior.
And Vitas doesn't move.
He stayed there
the entire time.
But the vic's
girlfriend is moving.
Do you have a wider angle?
Can you zoom in,
track her movement?
Yep.
She's coming
from the back side
of the lanes.
And apparently
she's one hell of an actress.
WOMAN:
So are you sure you're going
to be okay with her?
Oh, yeah. I love them
when they're this age.
Hello. Hey, you want
to be in CODIS?
(little girl gibbering)
Let's go play with CODIS.
Okay, we can play...
Right this way.
Go ahead
and have a seat.
So?
You said you had some
information about my sister.
Actually, it's about
your sister's husband,
James York.
We were able to determine
that she didn't kill him.
What good is that going to do
her now? There's no point.
You killed him.
Didn't you, Hannah?
James York liked to play around.
I suspect that he was playing
around with you.
And maybe you didn't
intend to kill him,
but after you shot him,
you never thought your sister
would go down for it.
Now, we know you didn't
try to frame her.
That was just an accident
of bullets and geometry.
The D.A. is going
to press charges.
Just come clean now.
Thank you.
Hannah...
...spare yourself the trouble
and the pain
of going through another trial.
Would it make any difference
if you knew that James York
was a piece of garbage?
I wouldn't have touched him
with a ten foot pole.
You know he had three
other children
with other women.
Sweet little kids he'd already
managed to screw up.
I loved my sister,
but she was never very bright.
And she was an idiot to
stay with a man like that.
Their daughter...
my daughter...
is two years old now.
And I tell her that I love her
every day.
And she knows I really mean it.
Whoever killed James York
did her a favor.
(voice breaking):
That should make a difference.
It's not for me to judge.
You're going to have to go
with this officer now.
Did you go behind the lanes
the night that
Ronald was killed?
Mm-mmm.
Oh. That.
That was
when I ran to my car
to get my birth
control pills.
And you were running because...?
Well, because I didn't want
to miss the match.
I wanted to find out
who won.
(door opens)
Ms. Lammet,
I found this
in your apartment.
This is the hot designer
bag of the moment.
Every woman wants one,
including me, but...
we just don't make
that kind of money.
What's your secret, Shea?
It was a gift.
From Ronny?
Your boyfriend makes less
than you do.
WILLOWS:
Oh, but you know, it could
be from his side biz.
Except...
this bag has been
slashed with a razor,
and totally ruined.
No woman I know would do this
to this bag.
And if a guy is splurging
on something like this,
he's not going to destroy it.
Who did you get it from?
Chevy Cigs
gave it to me.
You know,
the famous bowler.
Yeah.
Yeah, we know him.
How did you meet him?
I served him at the alley
a couple times.
He lives in the area,
so he would come in to practice.
You started dating?
We fell in love, actually.
So, what happened, Chev?
So, you meet cute little Shea
at the bowling alley, right?
And you're itching to roll
your balls down another lane.
You know what I mean?
So, you wine her,
you dine her, you buy her.
Then the boyfriend finds out,
and he slices up
the purse you gave her,
so the boyfriend's got to go?
Hey, I didn't kill anybody.
You're the only one
with a registered nine
millimeter in the bowling alley.
Now, you know
we searched your house.
We didn't find the weapon,
but we found
a box of Remington
Golden Sabers,
the same ammo used
to kill Ronald Tobin.
So, where's the gun?
She must have
stolen it from me.
So you're saying
that Shea killed Ronald?
She had to, right?
Did she tell you
that she killed Ronald?
No.
Look,
I broke up with her
because Ronald found out.
And I guess she was thinking,
with Ronald gone,
maybe I'd get back together
with her.
You're telling me
that Shea killed Ronald
and cut his head off
just to mess up your game?
She did that
because she's nuts.
Because I didn't get
back together with her,
and I guess it's
her idea of revenge.
That's the truth.
I got nothing to hide.
I got a big match tonight.
Can I go now?
SIDLE:
If Chevy's telling the truth...
then Shea did
everything by herself.
It doesn't add up.
Let's see.
She shoots him,
cuts off his head,
picks him up,
tosses him in a crate,
then drags the crate
across a parking lot.
And I think Ronald weighed
about 180 pounds,
minus his head.
Add the crate.
I'd say it's unlikely.
She must have had help.
♪ ♪
(computer trilling,
then beeps twice)
SIMMS:
The blood in the finger
holes came from the victim.
The blood in the head
was already dried
by the time it was
tossed into the ball pit.
Which means that
it couldn't have splashed
or spilled in there.
Right.
So we've got the victim's
blood on Chevy's hands.
I think it came
from his fingertips.
And I think
that the smears were minute
because he washed his hands.
I think he accidentally left
blood under his nails, but...
did Chevy ever actually
touch the bowling ball
after he touched the head?
No, so, at the very least, we
know that Chevy was involved.
It's just so weird,
because you didn't find
blood on any
of his personal effects.
Not his shoes, clothes,
towel, gloves, just nothing.
He had to have tossed
everything.
I mean, clothes are replaceable.
His lucky ball isn't.
ANNOUNCER 2: Well, it's been
a crazy turn of events,
but we're finally gonna find out
who wins this tournament.
Final frame, final throw,
for the championship.
Yeah, Chevy needs to
knock this field goal down
for the win, J.T.
If he misses, X-Man takes
his first against Chevy.
Here we go.
Look at the
determination.
All comes down
to this, folks.
He needs a miracle.
Chevy, you're
under arrest.
Drop the ball.
Oh, this cannot be happening.
Come on.
Get on your knees.
(cheering)
Yes!
(applause, cheering
and whistling)
(sighs)
You just lost.
BRASS:
So did you.
How's it feel to be ratted out
by your own bowling ball?
What the hell am I still
doing here?
I've told you everything I know.
No, you didn't, but Chevy did.
Sit.
What did he tell you?
That you killed Ronald,
decapitated him
and threw his head
in the ball pit.
That's what he said.
No, he didn't.
Shea,
this is your life.
Sit down.
If Chevy's lying,
you need to tell me.
Otherwise, he's going
to continue
to win bowling titles
while you rot in a cell.
Look, I didn't shoot Ronald.
Then who did?
When Ronny found out
about Chevy,
he got a gun,
and he forced me
to lure Chevy to SSB.
He said he was just
trying to scare him,
but I didn't know.
I got completely freaked.
So, I just did what he wanted,
and I told Chevy
that I was stranded.
Hey, bro, get out
of the truck.
Get that gun out of my face.
Get out of
the truck!
Ronny, don't!
You're gonna get
out of the truck,
I'm gonna call
your wife,
and you're gonna tell her
what a scumbag you are,
and how you been banging
my chick.
SHEA:
Ronny, put the gun down.
Shut up.
No.
(crying):
Oh, my God!
Oh, my God, Chevy!
You set me up!
I ought to kill you, too!
I'm sorry, Chevy.
I'm sorry.
We got to get rid of this body.
So, come on, pick him up.
Come on, come on, come on.
(crying):
Okay, okay.
Come on, lift higher.
Come on, push!
We're over.
(gasping sob)
Say a word, and
we both go down.
(sobbing):
Oh, my God...
Ronny promised me
that he was gonna marry me.
15 years later,
I still have the same last name.
Chevy promised me
the same thing,
just so he could
keep getting laid.
I was just fed up.
I wanted to give Chevy something
that he would never forget.
(sighs)
(sudden squish)
It's shocking enough
to find a human head
in the ball rack...
...but when it's the head
of someone that you killed--
unforgettable.
So, um,
what are we looking at here?
Jail-time-wise? What...?
What am I looking at?
I mean, I didn't actually
kill anybody.
No, but cutting the head off
of your dead boyfriend
is not going
to get you a lot of sympathy
from a jury.
Right, yeah.
But I mean,
I'll get out some day, right?
And Chevy--
it was just self-defense.
He could get out
even before I do.
You might be right about that.
By then, I mean,
he could have forgiven me.
Maybe we'll get to be
together after all.
MAN:
Ooh!
(people groaning)
I had it. I almost had it
and I hate this.
I hate it.
Happens every single time.
No more.
Aw, come on.
You know,
don't be afraid to rock
the granny roll, Cath.
Always works for me.
Are you coming?
The party's
already started.
(over phone):
You better hurry.
You're coming up soon.
Yeah, Sara, I'm here, I'm here.
I'm just getting my shoes.
Size 13 and a half, please.
Wait. Hold on. Hold on.
Hold on.
HODGES: My granny
taught me that.
Uh-huh...
Langston's here,
everybody.
Sara, that pin
is flipping you off.
Nothing but
strikes, Doc!
Nice hook.
(everyone shouting
encouragement)
(cheering and whistling)
He's the sexiest.
STOKES: There he is.
Time for a toast.
Cold one?
Yo, bowling
is a family sport.
I would like to raise a glass
to our CSI family.
STOKES:
Cheers.
ALL:
Cheers! Yeah!
Cheers.
But unfortunately,
it's time to give the family
a little ass whooping.
Ouch!
Oh, really!
All of us?
Just pay attention, Nick.
Be careful you don't let
your mouth write a check
that your ass can't cash.
(everyone laughing)
Ooh!
Oh! Nice!
(cheering, whooping,
applause)
Wow. All right.
WILLOWS:
Yeah!
(laughs)
He's on my team.
I told them 13 and a half.
Wrong size.
Be right back.
Hurry up.
Hey, sorry I'm late.
I couldn't find my ball.
You have
a ball?
Yeah.
And a bag.
It's a purse!
(laughter)
Check it out!
Did your grandmother
give you that bag?
Time out. I thought
you weren't gonna bowl.
Yeah, I changed my mind.
Somebody's rearview mirror's
a little lighter.
STOKES:
Is that legal?!
Don't be scared.
(cheering and applause)
I owe you nothing.
Oh, all right,
it's on, it's on.
All right... so what was that
about an ass whooping?