(players shouting, calling plays
distantly, echoing)
(heart beating very slowly)
(distant, echoing shouts
and slow heartbeat continue)
(fading in):
Green 30!
Green 30.
Sweep right!
Watch the backs!
Set! Hut!
(spectators cheering)
ANNOUNCER: Burns is tackled...
he's goin' for it!
Oh!
He's hit by the Aztec safety.
Time-out! Time-out!
(whistle blows)
Give me a time-out! Kayle!
(air horn blows)
All right, look, this is it.
This is it.
Just stay focused, son.
It's our will versus their will.
Run 2-22 Strike.
(air horn blasting)
(quarterback calling play)
ANNOUNCER:
Nice snap, dropping back...
He's got a man open downfield!
Oh! He got it! Touchdown!
(whistle blows, cheering)
(cheering wildly)
(shrill beeping)
(beeping continues)
(water running)
(alarm blaring)
(alarm continues)
Coach?
Coach, you okay?
You know the Mustangs
were 7 and oh this season?
On their way
to winning their
third consecutive
Silver State Bowl.
Didn't realize you
were a fan, David.
My father took me to my first
game when I was seven.
And it was Coach Miller's
first game, too.
My father loved this man.
♪ ♪
Spatter is concentrated on
the pillow, the headboard;
there's cast-off on the
ceiling and the wall.
(thudding, squishing)
Looks like he was attacked
while he was sleeping.
A large blood pool
under his head.
Looks like he laid there
for hours, bleeding.
And still managed
to get out of bed
when his alarm went
off at 6:00 a.m.
I turned it off.
There wasn't any blood
on any of the phones.
But he still had
the wherewithal
to pour himself a cup
of coffee and a bowl of cereal,
but not call 911.
You know how it is
with head wounds.
Yeah.
All right. I got a couple
shoe impressions.
Coach Miller was barefoot,
so this has got
to belong to the killer.
I spoke to
the home security company.
The system was triggered
at 6:04 a.m.
So, the security system
was on last night?
Suggests the killer
knew the code,
otherwise, how would they
get in and out of here
without setting it off?
LANGSTON:
I was teaching at WLVU
when Coach Miller won his
second conference title.
Everybody loved him,
treated him like a god.
Even gods have enemies.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
(winch whirring)
Did you find Nemo?
Not unless
Nemo was a Beemo.
Some kids spotted the car
over the weekend.
Couldn't get a crane here
until this morning.
Ran the tags.
Fleet vehicle
from Vegas Legacy Motors.
Reported stolen
about six months ago.
(sniffs)
Phew! She's been down
there a while.
This window's
rolled down,
that one's broken.
She had two escape routes.
It looks like she might've
gotten stuck in her seat belt.
"Paige Hammer, 19."
North Dakota license.
Possibly a tourist
or a new resident.
SIDLE:
Both airbags are deployed.
The airbags only go off if
someone's sitting in the seat.
She wasn't alone.
Guess we're looking for the one
who got away.
So, did you see anyone else
when you pulled up?
SECURITY OFFICER:
No, sir, just Coach.
And I usually keep an extra
eye out for his house.
You know, he spends a
lot of time on the road,
so I take in his
newspaper and his mail.
Then I guess you're the one
who turned off the alarm?
Was that bad?
Yeah.
So, is it just you
who knows the code
or everyone
in the department?
Pretty much
the whole department.
Everybody loves Coach M
and the Mustangs.
Okay, I'm gonna need a list
of everyone.
MAN: I got 'em
right here.
Put that on for
Coach, all right?
Did everybody get one?
Did everybody get an armband?
Yeah, I got one.
Did you get an armband?
Did everybody get one?
She needs one.
I'm sorry for your loss.
It's more than a loss.
It's a tragedy.
Coach took a third-rate team
with players
no other school wanted,
turned them into champions
with real futures,
real degrees.
He was one of a kind.
I'm Catherine Willows
with the Crime Lab.
And you are...?
I'm Pal Arnold.
I'm president of
the Booster Club.
Did you know Coach Miller well?
Like a blood brother.
Did he have any family?
A wife, any kids?
Yeah, about 85 of 'em;
the whole roster.
Coach always said, "Your
team is your family."
Am I right?
That's right.
His wife passed on
about ten years ago,
and they had no kids.
So he lived alone?
I wouldn't say that.
House was always full.
It's the way
he liked it.
Would you happen to know
if any of his extended family
had a key to the house?
They kind of all did.
What do you mean by that?
Let me show you, can I...?
No, no, just tell me.
Um... you see those three
rocks there in front?
Uh, there's a small rock,
uh, on the left-hand side.
That's the
one, right...
Right... your right.
That's it.
C.O.D.'s exsanguination
due to both sharp force
and blunt force trauma.
Coach was struck
at least a dozen times.
Lot of rage here.
Agreed.
The multiple impacts
crushed his skull
and drove bone fragments
into the brain,
causing catastrophic
hemorrhaging.
It's like when you
push your finger
into a hard-boiled egg--
the shell cracks,
but the pieces stay in place.
Thanks for ruining
another breakfast for me.
It's what I do.
What about the weapon?
Well, you're looking
for a wide,
flat object with
narrow sharp edges.
I can't be any more
specific than that.
Okay.
Come on. You're not gonna ask me
about the zombie thing?
You're obviously eager
to tell me.
Well, damage was predominantly
on the right side
of the brain to the neocortex
which controls thought,
language and reason.
It was almost completely
destroyed.
But the paleocortex,
which lies beneath it,
remained intact.
The paleocortex controls
learned instinct and rituals,
which explains why the victim
was able to brush his teeth
and eat his breakfast
without noticing
that he was bleeding to death.
They never seem to get
that right in zombie movies.
Most of the mud and
silt is over here.
Tells me the car settled
driver's-side down
on the lake bed.
Yeah, which
eliminates using
the driver's-side window
as an escape route.
Lots of diced glass.
Must be from the broken window.
It is not easy
to break one of these.
I wonder how she did it.
Hey, Sara...
Hmm?
Got a .38 Smith &amp; Wesson.
What? We got to open it up
right now
and get the cartridge cases out
before the gun totally rusts.
(phone chirps)
Mandy, we just recovered a .38
revolver that's been in water.
We need a rush on
getting it processed.
MANDY (over phone):
Okay, got it.
It's a five-shot.
Four live rounds.
One cartridge has been fired.
This is the most
excitement I've had in weeks.
Oh, okay.
Well, the prints for this
are gonna be a long shot,
but we'll give it a try.
(door slides open,
then closed)
That's a lot of computing power
for a football coach.
LANGSTON:
It's a complex game.
Two teams, 11 players,
each play crafted with
multiple levels of redundancy.
And yet, most academics and
intellectuals prefer baseball.
I suppose for the poetry.
I just like to watch the guys
hit each other.
And I like their butts.
Check out this photo.
LANGSTON:
Okay, in the photograph,
there are two trophies
and a football
on the top shelf.
The Coach of the Year trophy
and the football are missing.
The remaining trophy
has been moved.
What do you think?
Think it might be a burglary
gone bad.
The cover-up always
leaves behind more evidence.
BRASS:
See, one of the downsides
to working
in law enforcement
is that your fingerprints
are on file.
So when you break the
law, you're screwed.
Okay, listen, I...
Like I said before,
I'm a huge Mustang fan,
and while I was waiting for your
guys to arrive at the scene,
I... may have touched
one of Coach M's trophies.
(wry laugh)
Oh, you did more than touch.
I don't know
anything about that.
Are you sure?
'Cause look at the big bid
I just put on BarterBarrel.com.
Captain, do you know
how much the university
pays campus security?
Well, I know that prison inmates
make 15 cents an hour.
Is it less than that?
Look, here's what I
think happened.
I think you broke into
Coach Miller's house--
you already admitted to
having the alarm code--
you snatched up
some valuable memorabilia.
You went upstairs
hunting for some more.
Coach Miller wakes up,
you panic, and you grease him.
No, no.
I loved Coach Miller, all right?
Don't go around saying that.
All right, I'll cop
to stealing the football.
Okay, what about the big trophy,
the Coach of the Year?
No, I only stole the football.
I mean, the trophy
would've been tempting,
but... I don't even
remember it being there.
C.O.D. should come as no
surprise; she drowned.
One of my greatest
fears, by the way.
Can't definitively tell you if
she engaged in sexual activity
immediately
prior to death,
but I did find this
wedged between
her central
and lateral incisors.
Oh, pubic hair.
I'll get it to Wendy.
I also found something
in her right main stem bronchi.
Tempered auto glass.
ROBBINS: She aspirated it
while drowning.
Glass particles wash
down the trachea,
eventually wedging
in a pathway
of the main-stem bronchi.
Confirms that
the passenger window was broken
after the car was submerged.
ROBBINS:
Mm-hmm.
Thanks, Doc.
Hey, Sara.
Ooh. How's it going?
I'm, uh, kind of
underwater on this one.
Yeah, looks like it.
Have fun on campus.
Will do.
Hey, Doc, are these the casts
from Coach Miller's head wounds?
Yeah. You got a
weapon to compare?
No... No, just a hunch.
WILLOWS:
So Coach Miller was killed
with his Coach of
the Year trophy.
Mm-hmm.
That can't be a coincidence.
No, I think Coach
knew his killer.
And given his penchant for
treating everyone like family,
that narrows our
suspect pool down to...
The entire university.
Yeah.
Bloody shoe impression
you found in the bedroom
is a size 12 Jupiter
Athletic Gear
Galaxy One.
Last year's model.
Mine's current.
And I'm sure this is
leading somewhere.
Yeah, to the gross
overcommercialization
and corruption
of college athletics.
See, uh, Jupiter sponsors
WLVU football.
Yeah, I contacted the
Mustang's equipment manager.
And he said that
Jupiter did donate
a pair of Galaxy Ones to
every player on the team.
How many of them wore size 12s?
Five. Four of which have
gone on to graduate,
which is not unusual for
Coach Miller's players.
Which leaves us with the star
running back Calvin Crook.
Is Mr. MVP
living up to his name?
Where's Archie?
He's at a technical conference
in Sioux City, Iowa.
How can I help you?
I'm interested in any e-mails
between Coach M
and Calvin Crook.
Coach had two separate
e-mail accounts.
One was an ".edu"
through the university,
the other was personal.
I found an e-mail trail
between
the two of them
back in April.
April?
Yeah, got a little heated.
That's around the time
of the NFL draft.
Rumor had it that
Calvin was gonna skip out
on his senior year
and enter the draft early.
Money, money, money.
But he stayed.
Yeah, and he lost
some of his magic.
Wasn't being played as often,
and he was playing for free.
Most of their back and forth
was on the university account,
the majority of which
was between the coach
and Calvin's reps.
But... check these out.
LANGSTON:
"Coach, Agents are blowing
up my cell saying I can
"enter the draft now and sign
for three years, five mil.
Calvin."
Now comes the tough love.
"The Mustangs are
family, Calvin,
"and that has more
value than money.
"Money waits
for talent.
"Finish your education,
"not just for the team
but for yourself
"so you'll have a career
after football.
Coach M."
Five minutes later, the
Coach sends Calvin a link
to this Las Vegas Globe
article.
22-year-old restaurant
worker found in the lake.
Single gunshot wound.
Andrew Jimenez.
Calvin never mentions
the draft again.
Because of this article?
Well, something made him
walk away from five million.
CALVIN:
I know you're hurting.
I'm hurting.
But we have to remember
what Coach M taught us.
What he expected
from each of us.
We play in that game
on Saturday
and we play hard.
And we honor Coach M
by drilling
the Cougars into the ground.
What did he always tell us?
"God didn't put us on
this Earth to be losers."
So what are we going to do?!
ALL:
Win!
That's right!
Calvin...
I'm Nick Stokes.
This is Ray Langston,
we're with the Crime Lab.
We need to ask you
a few questions, okay?
Sure, sure.
Yeah, ask away.
Last season you received
some Jupiter Athletic Gear,
specifically a pair
of Galaxy Ones.
Yeah.
We need to examine them.
Well, I don't know what that
has to do with anything.
And I'd love to help you
guys out, but I tossed
those months back.
The more expensive
the kicks, the quicker
they wear out
I guess, huh?
Hey, what can you tell us
about Andrew Jimenez?
I'm sorry, who?
Andrew Jimenez.
He was a waiter
at Lakeside Pizza.
Coach Miller
sent you an article
on him back in April,
didn't he?
(sighs)
That's it.
I forgot his name.
Uh, shot coming
home from work.
LANGSTON:
So you two weren't friends?
No, no, no.
I never met him.
See, Coach used to do stuff
like that all the time.
You know, he'd send me stories
to keep my head straight.
I was thinking about
entering the draft, but...
that guy's death just reminded
me how short life can be.
So it was a life lesson?
"Our decisions
define who we are."
If I were to
die tomorrow,
would I want to be the
guy who turned his back
on his team for
some quick cash
or the guy who stayed
loyal and led the Mustangs
to another victory?
The decision
was easy after that.
You know what?
Save it.
Where were you yesterday between
1:00 and 6:00 a.m.?
I was asleep.
In my bed.
Hey, guys, if you
don't mind, I got to
get back to practice.
Sure.
Thanks.
SANDERS:
Firing two!
♪ ♪
Hey, that, uh, .38
revolver Sara and I found
got a hit on IBIS.
It was used in a six-month-old
unsolved homicide.
And get this-- the victim
died of a single
gunshot wound.
The gun had one expended round.
Yeah, and there's more.
Bobby Dawson
found fragments
of tempered auto glass
on the tip of the bullet
that killed the vic.
He couldn't explain it.
I think that the bullet
shattered the passenger window
and then went
into his chest.
He could be our
missing driver.
Well, and Doc Robbins
found glass fragments
in Paige Hammer's bronchi,
along with a lot of water.
I think that the gun
was fired underwater.
What's your theory?
SIDLE:
She's trapped by her seat belt
and he realizes
that the only way to save her
is to save himself.
So, he escapes
out the window...
the car's already listing...
and she thinks that
he's abandoned her.
SANDERS:
There's a gun in the car,
not sure whose.
The only way out is
through the passenger window,
so she shoots it out
(gunshot)
not realizing
he's on the other side.
SIDLE:
And he becomes a dead hero.
Well, it says here
that your vic was found
without the shoes, jacket
or bicycle he left work with.
Do you even have any evidence
that he was inside the car?
No, but that
doesn't necessarily mean
he wasn't the driver.
All right, just to be safe,
let's go back
to the lake and canvass the
area where we found the car.
Okay, but in the meantime,
assuming your theory is correct,
is it even possible for a bullet
fired underwater through glass
to actually kill somebody?
Andrew Jimenez.
That's just really weird.
His name popped up
in Coach Miller's homicide.
Prove your theory.
We gotta find out
what the hell's going on here.
He's Andrew.
And this is the car window.
We fire the gun
through the glass
and see if it was possible
to shoot him underwater.
Firing one!
Wound has a depth of two inches.
According to the file,
Andrew Jimenez had
a shallow penetrating wound
of approximately
two inches.
Paige Hammer shot
Andrew Jimenez,
most likely by accident.
So we know that Coach Miller
was murdered the day after
the BMW surfaced.
But was he murdered
because the BMW surfaced?
Was there any direct connection
between Coach Miller
and Andrew Jimenez?
We haven't been
able to find one.
Andrew had no ties to WLVU.
High school dropout,
didn't go to college.
Never played sports.
Could they be indirectly
connected through your
female victim?
Ah, Paige Hammer.
Was new to Vegas,
no known address.
She was arrested for
solicitation six months ago.
A hooker doesn't really jibe
with Coach Miller's
good-guy reputation.
According to Andrew's
co-workers, it didn't
fit his rep either.
What about the gun that
you found in the car?
SANDERS:
Unregistered. Untraceable.
No prints so far.
Mandy's processing
the ammo.
Okay, this is a bit
of a stretch,
but your car was a BMW, right?
Indeed.
Coach Miller drove a Beemer
as well-- M5.
Oh, ours was a sedan
fleet vehicle
from Vegas Legacy Motors.
Coach Miller's was also
from Legacy.
LANGSTON:
Car dealerships
are typically
big supporters
of college football.
Look at this guy.
I pulled up this site
earlier.
WILLOWS:
I know him.
He was at the crime scene.
President of the
team's Booster Club.
SANDERS:
"Pal Arnold.
You can always trust your Pal."
All right, I'll call Brass,
check him out.
♪ ♪
Welcome, gentlemen.
You're just in time for burgers.
Grab a brew.
I won't tell.
We're still working.
Mr. Arnold, we found
something that--
Everybody calls me Pal,
even my ex-wife.
Both of them.
(laughing)
Mr. Arnold, we found
something that belongs to you,
just down the street,
past the golf course,
at the bottom of
Lake Henderson.
A silver BMW?
You're kidding me.
You found my Beemer?
Good work, boys.
When you reported it stolen,
did you know there was
a dead girl inside?
Well, it came fully loaded,
but a dead girl
wasn't part of the package.
Do you recognize her?
Kind of.
I don't know her name.
Last spring,
just before the draft,
I held a little soirée
for the team.
Red-blooded boys
never come empty-handed.
This girl
was a professional.
None of my business.
I don't tell them how to run
the ball or who to sleep with.
Who did she come with?
She moved around the room,
if you know what I mean.
(laughs)
My gut is always right.
I figured she jacked my car.
How'd your gut figure that?
Never saw her before,
haven't seen her since.
I don't like to get
my boys in trouble.
Oh, somebody's
already in trouble.
It was your car, your party.
I don't like your attitude.
Yeah, I get that a lot.
Calvin, come here.
Show him the picture.
Calvin... tell them how
you know the girl.
Your burgers are burning.
I don't think I should be
talking to you without
an attorney.
Okay, you we can call him
from the police station.
You see that?
Our guy worked
at Lakeside Pizza.
(sniffing)
Possibly pizza sauce?
Negative for blood.
If Andrew Jimenez
was in the car underwater,
wouldn't most of the pizza
sauce have washed off?
You'd think so.
His shoes never did
get in the water.
Because he took them off
before he got in--
he wasn't the driver.
PAIGE:
Help! Somebody help me!
Help!
Whoever was driving
gets out,
Andrew dives in to save Paige,
gets shot,
floats to the surface,
which most likely
freaks the driver out.
He ditches Andrew's clothes
in the bushes and takes off.
Right place, wrong time
for Andrew.
"No good deed..."
ATTORNEY: He's not
giving you his DNA.
Then we'll compel it.
Look, Calvin, I'm gonna
be straight with you.
You're in a tight
spot here, man.
We already found one of your
hairs on the dead girl,
so we know you
were with her.
If that's true,
why do you need his DNA?
We know you were at Pal Arnold's
house on April 15 with her.
Here, let me show you
a picture of her.
This is what
she looks like now.
No, go on, Calvin,
take a look.
Come on.
We know you left the party in
Pal's BMW, drove to the lake,
and then what?
What happened?
How did the car
get underwater?
You obviously
saved yourself.
Were you too much of a
coward to save her, too?
I mean, that's gotta
be eating you...
No, that never happened.
Andrew Jimenez wasn't
a coward, was he?
He was a Good Samaritan,
trying to help.
I know you already
told me about him,
but you weren't
telling me the truth.
Which brings us
to Coach Miller.
Who found out about
you and Paige
and was gonna blow
your chances to go pro.
So you killed him.
Hmm?
I got to tell the truth here.
You need to keep
your mouth shut.
Come on, Calvin.
Get this off your chest.
This is not who I am
and that's not what happened.
I loved Coach M.
I'd give my life
for his right now.
I admit
I was at the party.
I admit I was with that girl.
It was a lapse of judgment.
I did get in the car with her.
But we never even
left Pal's driveway.
Coach M showed up.
He didn't yell,
he didn't scream.
It'd probably
been easier if he had.
I'm not angry at you.
But I am disappointed.
If you want to screw
around with your life,
that's your decision.
But you cannot do that
and play football for me.
That goes for the
rest of you, too!
Now pull up your pants,
put down the beers and get
your asses back to campus!
YOUNG MAN:
Yes, sir.
Pal...
you never were
what these boys are.
And you never will be.
Stop trying.
I can tell you that...
it was a lot harder
than being caught
by my old man, you know?
I looked up to Coach.
Then what happened?
When Coach M tells you
to do something, you do it.
I went back to campus.
The next few days
were brutal.
You know, I had agents
trying to sign me,
fly me everywhere
for meetings.
Coach M was giving me
the silent treatment.
And then I got the e-mail.
So, this did have
something to do with Paige?
I didn't know anything
had happened to her.
I mean, didn't even connect
the e-mail to her.
I thought this was about me
and being at Pal's
lake house and goofing off.
So I decided to play for
the Mustangs one last season.
I swear to you,
Mr. Stokes, if I'd have
been in that sinking car,
I'd have done everything I could
to save that girl's life.
Hey, Ray.
You got a second?
Yeah.
Did you ever play football?
Yes, um,
the real football.
You know, tok-tok,
tok-tok-tok,
with your feet.
Soccer.
Well, I never
called it that.
I was born in Seoul,
South Korea,
and my dad was career
military man.
I grew up on bases
all over the world,
and we just always
called it football.
What about you?
I'm... I'm from Austin.
I grew up playing football.
You know,
I feel like
I understand football players,
but I don't know
about this Calvin Crook kid.
At first I thought
he was lying to us,
but he really came clean
with me, man.
And now I'm
not so sure.
Well, what is the
evidence telling you?
There's no physical
evidence connecting him
to Coach Miller's murder
or to the drowning.
So where does
that leave us?
If Calvin's telling the truth,
which I think he is,
then Paige Hammer
was still alive
after Calvin and the rest of
the team left Pal's party.
Pal didn't leave the party.
It was Pal's house, his car.
He had to be one of the last
people to see her alive.
Maybe the last.
And if he was the driver,
Coach Miller knew about it,
that would be motive
enough for murder.
Can we put him in the car
with Paige?
I'll check with Mandy,
but the gun's the only
evidence outstanding.
Wait a minute.
If we want to catch
Coach Miller's killer,
we gotta find the murder weapon,
right, boss?
I need...
a couple of volunteers.
Okay, I'm in.
He would love to.
Thanks.
Can I at least hear
what I'm volunteering for,
considering I've just
been drafted?
Campus police always circled
Coach Miller's house.
They would have noticed
a parked car.
I'm thinking the killer
approached on foot.
And since the killer
was most likely associated
with the university,
that means that
he would have walked
back to his place on campus...
Ditching the murder weapon
and blood evidence
along the way.
It's all very
Mission: Impossible.
What are you talking about?
It's a great theory.
Thank you. Can we go?
I'm eating.
There's plenty of food
where we're going.
You know what this is?
Looks like a fingerprint.
Yeah. Yours.
Found on your .38 caliber
Smith &amp; Wesson
in your car
with a dead hooker
at the bottom
of a lake.
Sounds like you're
accusing me of something.
I'm not accusing
you of anything.
I'm charging your
with vehicular manslaughter
and negligent homicide.
Well, why don't you
charge me with
the JFK assassination
while you're at it?
No, I'm gonna let you slide
on that one.
But I could add in
a first degree murder
of Coach Miller.
Now that's not funny.
I lose my sense of humor
when it comes to murder.
Tell me about Paige Hammer.
It was an accident.
She was hot.
The boys had already
had some on my dime.
My turn.
You didn't have
to drive me home.
Thought you might be interested
in a little... overtime.
Strictly cash and carry.
(chuckles)
(tires squeal)
Next thing I know, airbag was
exploding in my face.
PAIGE:
I can't get out!
I said three hallelujahs
when that window rolled down.
You can't leave me!
Let go of me!
Please! Help!
"You can always trust
your Pal."
I'm not a brave man.
When I was safe, I wouldn't have
gone back for my own mother.
But that doesn't make me
a bad guy.
It just makes me human.
And when that kid showed up,
I thought he'd save my ass.
Hey, you okay?
There's somebody...
(coughs)
There's a girl in there.
You gotta help her.
(Pal coughing)
(coughing)
(muffled gunshot)
Then his body floated up...
and I got
the hell out of there.
Tossed his clothes
along the way.
BRASS:
So this kid dies
saving your girlfriend...
...and you didn't even call 911?
I was... I was scared.
I wasn't thinking.
You were thinking clear enough
to hide his clothes
in the bushes,
cover up the evidence.
It's better to be a live coward
than a dead hero.
Tell me something.
How did Coach Miller
fit into this whole deal?
Just my luck he'd come back.
I guess he hadn't finished
chewing me out.
I was soaking wet.
I had to tell him
what had happened.
He wanted to call the cops.
I convinced him of the
consequences for the team:
the parties, the booze,
the girls.
And now two bodies deep-sixed.
You weren't going down alone.
You know, it's the only time
he ever compromised his values.
And even then,
he did it for the team.
So when that car bubbled up,
so did Coach Miller's conscience
and he finally figured out
that he better do
the right thing, but you
couldn't let that happen,
so you killed him.
(scoffs)
Excuse me.
My name is Ray Langston.
I'm with the Las Vegas
Crime Lab.
We're gonna need you
to dump your garbage.
Really?
♪ ♪
(laughs)
Touchdown!
SIMMS (sighs):
Nicely done.
You know, I'm not
a CSI by choice.
Hey, Hodges?
Yep?
It's probably
for the best.
ATTORNEY:
I'm advising my client
not to say anything.
Then he can just listen.
We found your fingerprint in
blood on the murder weapon.
We also found
your Jupiter Galaxy Ones.
You told us you had
tossed them months ago.
In fact, it was just
the other night.
They matched the bloody
shoe impression we found
next to Coach Miller's bed.
You killed Coach Miller, Calvin.
We're not clear on why,
but it doesn't matter.
No, it matters
to me.
Calvin...
Look, you heard the man;
I'm screwed.
Mr. Langston...
all I've ever known,
all I've ever been good at
is playing football.
I love the game,
and it loved me back.
And what about Coach Miller?
Coach M's head
was buried in the past.
He was naive.
Nobody's cutting you
a fat check
for team loyalty.
Not anymore.
"Calvin, you want to be the guy
who turned his back
"on his team
for some quick cash,
"or the man who stayed loyal
and helped lead the Mustangs
to one last victory?"
Hell, yeah, I wanted
to get paid to play.
Are you kidding me? I busted
my ass. I was entitled.
Then what made you stay?
That night at Pal's.
The dead girl.
I didn't even know she was dead.
She was just a hooker.
I'd forgotten her name by the
time she stepped out of the car.
I was drunk,
stoned, whoring.
Coach M had everything
he needed to bury me.
So I gave him
what he wanted:
one last season.
He was blackmailing you?
Yeah, in so many words.
Then why did you kill him?
Because he didn't live up
to his end of the bargain.
He stopped playing me
when it mattered;
when I had a chance to shine.
ANNOUNCER:
He's goin' for it!
Oh!
Time-out!
Give me a time-out, ref.
Coach, let me run
2-22 Strike.
Sit down.
But the scouts are here.
I need this.
Back off.
Kayle!
Run 2-22 Strike.
Yes, Coach.
All right, get it.
ANNOUNCER:
Oh! He got it!
(cheering)
CALVIN:
He was punishing me
for letting him down.
Scouts had stopped calling.
I could feel my future
slipping away.
"God didn't put us on
this Earth to be losers."
Well, he didn't put us here
to be suckers, either,
so I did what I had to do.
Did you never stop to think
that maybe
it wasn't about
you, Calvin?
Paige Hammer
and Andrew Jimenez died.
Pal was responsible.
Coach knew about that.
That had nothing to do with me.
Didn't it? Carrying a secret
around like that
couldn't have been easy
for a man like Coach Miller.
And I think that every time
he looked at you,
he was reminded
of his own hypocrisy.
I was looking out for myself,
doing what was best for me,
and I'm not gonna apologize
for that.
But if Coach M were here,
he'd say, "Calvin,
you need to take responsibility
for your actions."
So that's what I'm doing.
I owe him that much.
Then you did learn something.