♪ ♪
(gunshot, glass shatters)
Hey!
Mom, get down!
I got you covered!
Ow!
You son of a bitch!
(entry bell jingles)
(siren whoops)
Looks like he took
a John Wayne shot.
John Wayne shot?
Yeah, the Duke would
take one to the shoulder
in all his movies, then
he'd just shake it off
like it was a
mosquito bite.
Well, this was more like
a spaghetti Western.
Involving Italians,
lots of blood.
BRASS:
By the way, the guy they
wheeled out of here?
That's Hank Rinaldi.
He and his mother
run the place.
A lot of cops like
to hang out here.
Camera's up there.
We'll get tape.
And this must be
where Hank went down?
BRASS:
That's where we found him,
curled around his Glock.
(cell phone rings)
Guessing this is Mom?
BRASS:
Yeah, that's Dolores Rinaldi.
One tough mother.
Go ahead.
SANDERS:
Multiple gun shot wounds.
.45 still gripped.
(camera shutter clicking)
She went down fighting.
Shooting at him,
I'm assuming.
Three gunshot wounds
to the torso, one to the head.
Edward Smith, 40.
Local address.
He's got a fat wad
of hundreds in here.
Must be at least five grand.
(cash register bell dings)
Drawer's stocked with cash.
There's lots of antiques here.
Lugers, Tokarevs, Old Colts.
Some good stuff here.
Doesn't look like robbery.
Maybe he was a customer,
in here to make a big purchase.
(camera shutter clicks)
I might've found part
of his shopping list.
"101 SW."
Smith &amp; Wesson?
What about
these rogue footprints?
With the blood here?
There must have been
someone else here.
Look like a
small men's size.
Nine?
Sneakers.
If he walked
through the blood pool,
he had to have been
standing right here.
Guy stands in the middle
of a three-way shootout
and strolls out alive?
(shots firing)
Was he just lucky?
Or bulletproof?
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
(police sirens wailing)
(garbled police radio
transmission)
Hey.
Catherine.
Thanks.
You're welcome.
Body's over here.
A couple of teenagers were
cutting through the park
and spotted her.
Thought she was sleeping.
Snug as a bug in a rug.
Well, there's a path
of displaced gravel
coming down
the embankment.
High-speed body dump?
Well, if it is, then
this quilt is awfully clean.
So, how'd it get here?
Covered up after the fact?
There's road rash
under the blanket.
(tires squeal)
(heavy thud)
VARTANN:
Suspect made no attempt
to hide her.
WILLOWS:
Yet he made an effort
to tuck her in.
It's oddly tender, huh?
For a body dump.
Act of remorse?
Maybe our killer
has a conscience.
I was in the
back room.
I heard them
arguing,
Ma and this guy.
It's the guy
in the baseball cap, right?
No, no. Not him.
The other one.
The one in
the red shirt.
(muffled arguing)
I didn't get
a good look at him.
I just started shooting.
No!
Had to defend my mother.
Not that she's ever
been a sissy.
And this customer,
he starts unloading
at the crazy guy, too.
So, this "guy in a red shirt"
he takes out you,
your mother
and a customer?
One against three?
Sir, there were a lot
of bullets flying.
I don't know who hit who.
♪ ♪
SANDERS: Okay. Here
go the lights.
The red lasers are
customer Ed's shots.
(gunshot)
These are Delores's shots.
And these are Hank's shots.
(gunshot)
And according to Hank,
the man in the red shirt
was everyone's target.
Which is consistent with
everyone's trajectories,
assuming he was
a moving target.
But where are
Red Shirt's bullets?
Well, all of these shots
are misses.
Maybe he fired and didn't miss.
(cell phone ringing)
Langston's out of Autopsy.
Ed's ammo killed Dolores.
A combination of Dolores'
and Hank's ammo killed Ed.
And the surgeon pulled
one of Ed's nine mils
out of Hank's shoulder.
Well, that answers
that question.
The man in the red
shirt never fired.
So, all three shooters
missed him
and only hit each other?
Warrick and I worked a case once
where two guys were shooting
at each other in an elevator.
Zero out of 25 were hits.
But the math is off.
Customer Ed put four
of his nine mils into Dolores,
one into Hank,
and ten into the back wall here.
That's 15 shots.
And we collected
16 nine mil cases.
So, we're missing a bullet.
All of Ed's shots missed
in this direction.
And unless
it's in Red Shirt,
it's got to be
in this back wall.
Got it.
Straight through the wall
and into the stock room.
Huh. Ed's nine mil.
All projectiles
now accounted for,
which means
Red Shirt wasn't hit.
It's hard to believe.
(rattling)
Doesn't sound like gun oil.
This can top's been doctored.
At least ten grand here.
It's probably
the Rinaldis' 401AK.
Full-auto sears.
SANDERS:
You insert these
into the lower receiver
of a semi-auto rifle,
and you've got yourself
a fully automatic machine gun.
(shots firing rapidly)
Which is why they're illegal,
and fetch a mint
on the black market.
Two excellent reasons
for hiding them.
ROBBINS:
Ran her prints.
Still a Jane Doe.
Suffered multiple traumatic
events before she died.
C.O.D. is
no surprise.
Disarticulation of the
atlantooccipital junction.
Consistent with her impact
into the rock.
This, however, is the result
of a separate incident.
Superficial bullet wound.
She was shot?
Sodium rhodizonate test
was positive for lead.
The extent of the blood clotting
indicates it was antemortem.
Shot at least an hour
prior to death.
So, he shoots her
but doesn't kill her.
Then dumps her out
of a car an hour later,
which does kill her.
Why didn't he
just shoot her again?
Well, I saw
the crime scene photos.
It's only luck of the draw
that she hit that rock.
Not much logic to it.
Gun shop's camera
was out of focus,
only took intermittent
still shots
and was on
an oscillating pattern.
It's hard to choreograph
a less useful record of events.
However, there were
two helpful frames
before the camera was
knocked out by a stray shot.
This one shows
Ed Smith and Red Shirt
walking into the
store together.
You can't see
Red Shirt's face.
But it does look
like they're together.
All right.
Now check this out.
Hank blasting away at Ed.
Red Shirt is in front of Mom.
Not even in Hank's
line of fire.
STOKES:
He told Brass he was
shooting at Red Shirt.
Red Shirt is clearly
not Hank's target.
Which isn't
the only thing Hank lied about.
He told Brass that Ed was just
a random, well-armed customer.
Ed was another
customer all right.
His prints
were all over
the cash
with the full-auto sears.
Which explains the five grand
we found in his wallet.
He was there
to purchase more sears.
From Hank.
Whose prints were on both
the cash and the sears.
So, Hank's about
to make another big sale.
Why shoot such a good customer?
Get too greedy
for the green stuff,
you can get yourself hurt.
We know about your little
side business there, Hank,
selling the full-auto sears.
Which is a federal offense
in itself.
You pile on the fact
that you lied to the cops
about killing Ed Smith...
He was robbing us!
I was... I was afraid
if I told you,
you'd take a
closer look at him,
find out about the sears.
Honestly, I was just
defending our store.
(Mom arguing)
HANK: I come out of the back,
and Ed's got my ma at gunpoint.
And not just him. He brought
some partner with him.
So I did what
my mother taught me.
Hey! (fires gun)
Guy kills your mom,
you're okay saying he died
trying to defend her?
Make him out to be a hero?
The truth wasn't going
to bring her back.
And I didn't want
to go to jail.
(sighs)
So, you caught him, right?
Ed's wing man, the
guy in the red shirt.
You caught him, right?
That's how you
learned all this?
Well, actually...
But we're getting close.
Oh, God.
What?
He's still out there?
You got to find him.
That guy, the way he
was just standing there
with those bullets
flying all around?
He was not human.
(shots firing)
He was like the Terminator.
A machine.
I've seen my share of crazies.
But this guy?
Wasn't his first time
at the death dance.
As long as he's out there,
I'm staying right here.
(camera shutter clicks)
Hey.
Car was parked in
a loading zone off Industrial.
The ticketing officer
saw the blood and towed it in.
I'm hoping it's related
to our body dump.
R.O. is a Carrie Warren
of Noelle Lane, Las Vegas.
WILLOWS:
Is that an I.D. badge?
It's our Jane Doe
from the ditch.
She was dumped from her own car.
Clearly, she wasn't driving.
So, uh...
what's going on
with you and Vartann?
I am a trained observer,
you know.
(chuckles)
Okay. I see it's still in its,
uh, early investigative stages.
No comment.
Huh.
Same pattern as the quilt
she was wrapped in.
Key's still in the ignition.
(key turns, chime sounds)
Out of gas.
Explains why the killer
left the murder mobile
in plain sight.
(removes key from ignition)
Looks like we have
her house keys.
LVPD!
Anybody home?
WILLOWS:
How's it look?
No sign of
forced entry.
All Carrie Warren.
Looks like
she lived alone.
SIDLE:
I got a blood trail.
It's all clear.
You're not going to like
what you find in the bedroom.
I'm going to check
the perimeter.
Blood spatter on the wall.
This is
where she was shot.
(shutter clicks)
Sheets match the quilt
she was wrapped in.
There's no photos
of any humans.
But she sure had some love
for this German Shepard.
Yeah. Roscoe.
Oh, my God.
It's Roscoe.
(sighs)
He was shot.
Blood trail ends in the garage.
So, killer's in the bedroom.
(dog barking)
Shoots the dog.
(Carrie screaming)
Shoots Carrie.
Takes Carrie and the quilt,
and takes her car.
Control, this is 802 Charlie,
Detective Vartann.
I need Animal Control
to transport
a dead dog.
Carrie's tidy.
Strange that she'd leave
food trash in the bedroom.
Maybe the killer
likes milk.
Stain on the bed skirt.
Milky vomit.
I'll get it to DNA.
Maybe we'll get lucky
on some epithelials.
There's no pictures
of any boyfriends,
yet she's got a drawer full
of tokens
of someone's affections.
Hmm. She doesn't want
to look at them anymore,
but she can't bring herself
to throw them away.
Maybe Roscoe wasn't
the only man in her life.
PHILLIPS:
Backed over by a car.
Fell down a well.
Attacked by coyotes.
Poisoned by a spider.
Lost in a cave.
Traded for a Mike Schmidt
rookie baseball card.
And my favorite,
given to a farm.
Allegedly.
The tragic fates of the
Phillips family dogs.
Oh.
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
I'm sorry.
I-I extracted a bullet
from his dorsal lumbar.
Shallow penetration.
Lack of vital response
in the surrounding tissue
indicates he was
shot postmortem.
Oh, accounts for the lack
of blood at the scene.
No blood pressure, no bleeding.
C.O.D.?
Undetermined at this point.
Huh.
Medium caliber bullet
flattened on two sides.
Double ricochet explains
the shallow penetration.
And the fact
that we have two wounds
but just one bullet.
I bought my first
Ruger 1022 from Rinaldi's.
Oh, sweet.
Colt Single Action
Army. Beautiful.
Aw, this baby's a
shooter, not a collector.
Dang it.
Hey, guys.
I know you're slammed.
This is the round
that we pulled
from our female victim's
German Shepherd.
You're looking for the
"Truth About Gats and Dogs"?
(both chuckle)
A little bit of ballistics
humor there for you.
See, 7.62 by 25 mil.
Only a few rare old makes
of gun use this ammo.
Mauser, Tokarev,
Norinco.
Hold on. We collected
a Tokarev from the gun shop.
Here it is.
(casing clatters)
Whoa.
The case was stuck
in the chamber.
You were supposed to clear
that at the scene, Greg.
I know, but I got it out of
a shattered merchandise case.
Guns for sale are supposed
to be unloaded by law.
It's clear.
Hey, y'all, there's a
piece of somebody in here.
Must've blocked the
slide with their hand.
Now, there is no way
Rinaldi's would sell a gun
with an expended case
in the chamber
and a hunk of skin in the slide.
Maybe it wasn't for sale.
Wait a sec.
If your vic was shot
with that gun earlier today,
and it wasn't
for sale at Rinaldi's,
then it stands to reason that
your killer brought it there.
There were four players
in the shootout,
and only three known guns.
Maybe the Tokarev belongs
to the Man In The Red Shirt.
Who's the Man In The Red Shirt?
Some guy on a crime spree.
Bobby, can you run
the serial number?
Then we need to compare
my bullet with your gun.
(typing)
R.O. is a John Rakow.
Guy lives...
Right behind Carrie Warren.
Mr. Rakow, I see from your file
you served in the military.
And you have a Tokarev
automatic registered to you?
Yeah. I brought
that back from 'Nam.
That gun saved my ass
more than once.
Thank you for your
service, Mr. Rakow.
You're welcome.
Where is the Tokarev now?
I gave it to a friend.
What's the friend's name?
It's a neighbor. Why?
Carrie Warren?
Yeah.
You guys get along?
Well, I ain't
particularly crazy
about that
yappy mutt of hers,
but we worked that out.
Mr. Rakow, do you
make it a point
to arm your entire
neighborhood,
or just the pretty girls?
I had a daughter once.
She was about the age of Carrie.
She moved to New York.
Young girl all alone
in the big city.
I wish somebody had
looked out after her.
So I look out after Carrie;
I protect her.
Protect her from what?
This armpit
of a city.
You know, when
seconds count,
you-- you cops
are minutes away.
So you've got a
crazy-ass boyfriend,
got some screws loose.
She's always
breaking up with him,
and he's always begging
to come back.
So how do you fit
into all this?
I chased him off a couple
times, but I couldn't
watch her for 24-7,
so I gave her the Tokarev
and taught her how to use it.
Something happen to Carrie?
She's dead.
Someone shot her and her
yappy mutt with your gun.
I'm done talking.
BRASS:
Okay, let's talk about
something else, then.
What about the boyfriend?
Has he got a name?
Dirtbag.
And I can't recall
his last name.
The man is wearing
boots as big
as all of Texas.
There's no way he could cram
those dogs
into size-nine sneakers.
Plus, I observed his hands;
there's no slide bite.
He didn't shoot Carrie.
He wasn't in the gun shop.
He's not the man
in the red shirt.
ANDREWS:
I got Roscoe's tox panel.
Your German Shepherd
was poisoned.
High concentrations of lorazepam
and diazepam in his blood.
Found the same
anti-anxiety drugs
in the milk you collected
from the bedroom.
So, based on
his stomach contents,
Carrie's dog drank
the poison milk.
What about Carrie's tox?
She was clean.
Stomach was empty.
No milk.
We didn't find any
prescriptions at Carrie's house.
Red Shirt had to have
brought the drugs with him.
So he dissolved them in milk
and feeds them to the dog?
The dog apparently regurgitated
some of the mixture
onto the bedskirt, but not
enough to save his life.
The killer premeditates
the dog's murder,
but not Carrie's?
Not necessarily.
He poisons the dog
to shut it up.
Waits for her to come home,
then shoots her
with her own gun.
Well, if that's true,
he knew her. He knew her dog.
He knew where she kept the gun.
No signs of forced entry.
He had to have a key.
Obvious question--
she have a boyfriend?
Oh, yeah.
And I'm betting
he has a red shirt.
I mean, is this what
women really want?
It's what men think
women want.
Like candy.
It's sweet and hard to resist,
but sooner or later, we just
want some meat and potatoes.
(gravelly voice):
All the women I take out
just order a salad.
(laughs)
God, I used to have drawers
full of this crap from guys.
Now I just want a man
I can count on.
"My eternal love is yours
in life and in death.
Forever, Sam."
That sure sounds
like a boyfriend.
Although I never wrote
a love poem
to a girl that included
the word "death."
There's something
under that label.
Sam gift-lifted this book
from a public library
and gave it
to his beloved.
Classy.
Call the library and find out
who the last borrower was.
♪ ♪
(knocking)
Las Vegas Police.
Anybody home?
(football game playing on TV)
Go, go, go, go, go.
Hold.
Who are you?
I'm Detective Jim Brass,
Las Vegas Police.
We're looking for Sam Trent.
Who are you?
I'm Paul Trent, his father.
He's not home.
What happened
here, Mr. Trent?
It was an accident.
BRASS:
Any idea where Sam is?
My son's 27. I don't interfere
with his personal life.
Well, we do. We have a warrant
to search your house.
What's this about?
An overdue library book.
Mr. Trent, I need you
to come with me.
Another accident.
Mm-hmm.
SIDLE:
Styron, Plath, Sexton.
Looks like a reading
list from Morbid 101.
Taste in cinema appears
to be much lighter.
These are all
romantic comedies.
SIDLE: With the kind of guy
who never gives up
until he wins the heart
of his dream girl?
Of course, Sam's dream girl
is dead.
A photograph
of Sam and Carrie.
Proves they
were together.
Mm-hmm.
Does this look like
it was taken from the
top of the Stratosphere to you?
No, it's not
high enough.
It's got to be
the Ivory Tower Skydeck.
It's kind of a dumpy
old tourist trap
with a nice view
of the methadone clinic
across the street.
I'll take you there sometime.
Gee, thanks.
I have...
at least a dozen ticket stubs
to the Skydeck.
Maybe it was Sam and Carrie's
favorite place.
Eight bucks a pop.
What do you have?
Letters.
"Sam, meeting
you up there,
the city sprawling
below us, changed my life."
This is five days later.
"Sam, I'm sorry, but I can't
be with you anymore."
And then a few days after that.
"I can't stop thinking
about you."
"I need you.
You're the best thing
that ever happened to me."
"Sam, I hope we can
always be friends."
Light-switch romance.
On and off.
Well, this is from last week.
"You need to respect
my boundaries, Sam.
It's over. Leave me alone, or my
neighbor will kick your ass."
Good neighbor John Rakow?
Diazepam.
Lorazepam.
Both scripts written last week.
Both empty.
That's what killed Carrie's dog.
Mm.
Some other...
letters here.
This one...
written two days ago.
From Sam to Carrie.
Looks like
an early draft.
"Carrie, we have
talked about this.
"I know talking is easier
than going through with it.
"But after the darkness
comes the light.
"In a painless moment we
can be together forever."
That sounds like an invitation
to a suicide pact.
She's dead.
Did he change his mind?
You have the results from
the Carrie Warren scene?
I do.
There was DNA on the lip
of the tainted milk bottle.
And I just matched it
to Sam Trent's toothbrush
that was sent over
from his house.
Sam drank the
poisoned milk?
Yeah.
Which is why
I then ran the vomit,
and it turns out it wasn't
actually the dog's.
The mucosal cells
were a match to Sam.
Sam tried to commit suicide
in Carrie's bedroom but failed?
Mm-hmm.
(sighs)
What about the tissue
from the gun?
(machine beeps)
Just came up.
It's Carrie Warren.
You're joking.
She shot herself?
The physical evidence
now supports
the suicide pact theory.
Only Sam didn't die
from the poison,
and Carrie didn't die
from the gunshot.
Okay, check this out.
This is Carrie's house.
This is where we
found the body.
This is where you found her car.
And this is Rinaldi's
Gun &amp; Ammo.
I think that Sam took
the gun and Carrie,
got in her car, and I think he
was headed for the gun shop.
The gun was jammed.
It wasn't his gun, so maybe
he thought it ran out of ammo.
He needed more bullets, so he
could finish them both off.
Okay, so why did he dump her
on the side of the road
on the way to the gun shop?
Well, Carrie was dumped
at the apex of a hairpin turn.
And a piece of the quilt
was in the passenger
door latch,
which could have prevented
the door from fully closing.
(tires screeching)
I mean, an accident
would explain
why he wrapped her in a quilt.
Nothing was going
according to plan.
She's dead,
he's not.
He's probably feeling
left behind.
Yeah, and now
he really needs
to get to that gun shop.
So when the car runs
out of gas,
he just walks
the rest of the way.
Suicidal guy enters
a gun shop,
desperate for another bullet
to pop into his Tokarev.
If they're not going
to give one to him,
maybe they'll shoot one at him.
Mm. So somehow,
Sam triggered the gunfight.
Just his luck, he's the only one
that walks out of there
unscathed.
(door rattling)
Sara...
the closet door's
been kicked in.
I don't think
Sam did this.
Does that look
like a cowboy boot to you?
Texas-sized.
Mr. Trent, if you want
to try to help us
save your son's life,
you've got to tell me
what happened in your house.
There was a knock at the door.
I barely heard it over the TV.
When I went to answer it...
(football game playing on TV)
(door banging)
(glass shattering)
Sam Trent, where is he?
Where is he?!
(gun cocks)
Sam, you son of a bitch!
When he didn't find Sam,
he trashed the place
and stormed out.
A couple minutes later,
Sammy came home.
Sammy... Sammy,
what happened?
Are you in trouble?
There was a man here.
I... I almost called the police.
No police, Dad.
Everything's gonna be fine.
Take my car.
The guy had a gun.
Go on, t-take my keys,
grab-grab my wallet.
Take what you need.
Thanks, Dad.
Sam only wanted eight dollars
from his father?
The price of an Ivory Tower
Skydeck ticket.
Hey, you-you
can't park here.
I just received
Carrie Warren's
medical records.
She had a history
of bipolar disorder
for which she was
recently was being
treated at
St. Anthony's Hospital,
101 Southwest
Harmony Avenue.
101 S.W.
The shopping list
from the gun shop.
Yeah.
It was an address.
Uh-huh.
We just assumed
that he was driving
Carrie to the gun shop.
This is her house...
body, car.
There's the gun shop.
And just to the west
of it...
St. Anthony's.
He was headed for the hospital.
Sam was trying to save her life.
(lively chatter)
(wind whistling)
(vehicles passing below)
(distant car alarm blaring)
(sirens wailing)
(siren whoops)
Control, officers are moving
into position
(cell phone rings)
at the Ivory Tower.
I need a full rescue-
team response.
Detective Vartann and a police
officer are already up there.
You're free to go up.
I don't want any
heroes up there.
Can you hear me, Catherine?
You son of a bitch!
You're a dead man, Sam Trent!
(grunts)
(gasping):
One would think.
(gun cocks)
Police, drop the weapon!
Drop it!
John, Sam didn't
shoot Carrie.
You're lying!
We found her skin
in the Tokarev slide.
John, you know
what that means?
I know you do.
Carrie shot herself.
No, you're lying.
She wouldn't do that.
John, Carrie was bipolar.
She'd attempted
suicide before.
You told me that
Carrie needed protection,
but it wasn't from Sam,
it was from herself.
That's not true,
John. I killed her.
You shut up!
I put the gun to her head.
I brushed away...
LANGSTON:
Sam stop.
I brushed away her hair,
I looked into her eyes...
and I just...
LANGSTON:
John, after Carrie
shot herself, Sam took her
to the hospital.
No, that's not true!
I killed her, John.
We found a note
with the address
to St. Anthony's on it.
SARA:
Sam, you loved Carrie.
You tried
to save her.
(uncocks gun)
Sam!
You don't have to die today!
This is meant to be.
You don't have to die today.
The last two people who tried
to stop me ended up dead.
Just give me one bullet, okay?
Just one bullet.
Whatever this takes!
(laughs)
Just give me one bullet!
No...
(gunshots)
Hey!
This is where Carrie and I met.
And this is where it's
destined to end.
It doesn't have
to end here.
We know about the pact.
We know you tried to save her.
And Carrie,
she would want us to save you.
Okay, but I have
one question.
Was it me or the dog?
What do you mean?
It wasn't, I mean, it wasn't
technically a pact.
I wanted her to come home
and find me.
My whole being
rendered solemn valentine.
(dog whining)
(gunshot)
There was milk all over
its snout.
Carrie loved that dog.
And when she came home
and found him,
was it the sight of me
or the dog
that made her pull the trigger?
It was you, Sam.
I'm sure it was you.
So nice of you to say that.
SIDLE:
Sam!
(sirens wailing)
Situation is Code Four.
One in custody.