(upbeat music playing)
(women cheering)
(cork pops)
Whoo!
(laughter)
♪ ♪
Slam it, slam it!
Whoo!
Okay, 39 hours
and you're an old
married bitch!
(all yelling)
I'm not married yet
and you're the bitch!
Whoo!
No, n-no, n-no,
you're driving,
I'm drinking.
Brenda,
flash the trucker.
Flash the trucker,
flash the trucker!
flash him!
(all whooping and chattering)
(horn honking)
Uh-oh!
(laughter
and cheering)
(horn blowing)
(shouting)
(laughter
and cheering)
Hey, yo, there's a car!
(tires screeching)
(screaming)
STOKES:
Look, sir, it's just
standard operating
procedure.
TRUCKER:
Hey, I told you I
wasn't drinking,
but those girls, they must
have been on something.
What about the pedestrian that was hit?
Did you see where she came from?
I didn't see her
till she was
on the ground.
Girls were screaming.
I'm the one
that called 911.
LANGSTON:
Thank you.
OFFICER:
All right, calm down.
Tell me what happened
before you hit that lady.
WOMAN:
We didn't hit her.
She hit us.
Shut up, Claire.
You girls
been drinking tonight?
Is that woman going to die?
I don't know.
Which one of you was driving?
All right, Mitch,
Breathalyzers and sobriety tests
times three.
Got you.
But I'm getting
married this weekend.
And if he loves you,
he'll wait.
Julie was driving.
Julie?
I'm not going to miss
my wedding for you.
(vomits)
You got a whole desert here.
LANGSTON:
Hey, Nick, what do you got?
Why can't people just wait
till they get to Vegas
to start partying?
Is that so difficult?
Well, it is
for some people.
You know
what they say--
beer before wine,
you'll be fine.
Yeah, wine after
liquor, never sicker.
Hmm.
Which is probably
the case here.
Right front tire is flat
and as you can see,
this front bumper
is just shredded.
Yeah, that looks
like the point of impact.
Paramedic said he found
the victim over there.
I'm still trying to figure out
what she was doing
out here all by herself
in the middle of nowhere.
(monitor beeping)
We moved her from
critical to stable,
but it's going to be a while
before you can talk to her.
Okay, thank you.
Okay.
Hey, Jim.
Hey.
Greg found
an abandoned vehicle
about a mile
from the scene.
It could be
the victim's.
Keys and wallet were under
the seat, Nevada license.
Her name is
Janet Marie Marsh.
She lives in
Seven Hills.
She's a friend.
About three years ago,
her husband and two kids
went missing.
We found his abandoned SUV
with blood inside on the I-15.
She was hit
near mile marker 41.
It's the same
stretch of road.
She lost
her whole family.
She was looking for them.
She's looking for ghosts.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
BRASS: There's always a case
that just won't let you go.
I carried this around
in my wallet for three years.
This is the husband,
Mike Marsh,
and the two kids--
that's Andy, age nine,
and Emily,
age 15.
Hmm, how did it
all go down?
Well, Janet got out of work
a little after midnight.
Comes home, nobody's there,
you know.
So she calls her husband,
she calls her daughter--
no answer.
She, uh, calls her brother
who lives nearby.
He doesn't know anything
about it, so calls the hospital
and then
she calls us.
We put out
a broadcast.
Around 6:00 a.m.,
Highway Patrol found
an abandoned SUV on I-15 North.
Inside we find the husband
and the daughter's blood
in the backseat and a bloody
pajama top of the young boy.
Not enough blood
to confirm death,
but it was certainly enough
to suspect serious injury.
That's all the evidence
we recovered.
Case went cold.
And she just keeps going
back out to the
crime scene?
Yeah.
(camera shutter clicks)
You know, I usually work
scenes like this solo--
deserted stretches
of highway,
nothing around but coyotes.
I used to consider it
punishment, but now
I enjoy the quiet.
(sighs)
I can leave if you like.
(both chuckle)
Looks like the
convertible
bottomed out here.
Yeah, this dip
probably caused the car
to bleed off
a lot of speed.
It's probably
why the victim is still alive.
Something in
the bushes.
I got a flashlight...
with what appears
to be fresh blood on the grip.
Could've belonged to the victim.
And you didn't have
any suspects?
I kinda liked the brother.
Name is Bill Cornwell.
He has
a construction business.
He was in
partnership
with Mike Marsh.
There's a lot of debt,
a lot of insurance.
That's motive right there, Jim.
We brought him in,
we interrogated him,
you know?
He didn't give me a straight
answer. He was very cagey.
I just didn't like his face.
I felt he was lying.
But he had
an airtight alibi.
DOCTOR:
Captain, she has a concussion.
Her left ulna's fractured
in two different places.
There's no
internal bleeding.
She got lucky. I'm going to keep
her under observation
for a few more hours.
That's great news.
Thank you, Doctor.
Okay.
Thanks for your help.
Thanks.
Mm-hmm.
Would you mind
if I just...?
Give me a minute?
No, please.
Thanks.
Go ahead.
(monitor beeping rhythmically)
I thought we had a deal.
No more
moonlight hikes.
What happened out there?
How are the girls?
Did their parents
get notified?
Come on, Detective.
Don't do my job for me.
Okay.
(knocking on door)
This is CSI Nick Stokes.
He's got to do
a little work, okay?
Mrs. Marsh, I'm here
to, um, document your injuries
and collect
your clothing, okay?
Janet, they're gonna
release you
in about two hours.
I'm gonna come back
and give you
a ride home, okay?
Ooh!
(groans)
How many stitches
did they give you?
You're wasting your time.
I'm not going to press charges.
Well, that's up
to the D.A.,
but I'll put it
in my report.
Jim told you all about me,
didn't he?
I can tell by the
look in your eyes
you pity the poor crazy lady
who lost her family.
No.
Yes.
No, I don't.
Listen,
I don't pity you.
Honestly,
I completely understand.
If I lost my whole family
like that,
I would never stop
looking for them
until I got some answers.
No matter what.
Can you remember anything
about the car accident?
BOY (low and distant):
Mommy, Mommy, I'm here!
He was calling me.
BOY:
Mommy, Mommy,
I'm here!
Mommy, I'm here!
(women screaming)
Sometimes I get lost
in my thoughts.
Is that what happened
last night?
You got lost in your thoughts?
No. I was out following a lead
on the case.
And did you tell Captain Brass
about that lead?
Uh-uh.
Because the lead came
from a psychic.
A reputable one
who's worked
with the LAPD.
Jim thinks it's all hocus-pocus.
You probably do, too.
(chuckles):
No, ma'am. I've learned
to keep an open mind.
This job will
do that to you, you know?
This psychic...
she's sure that Andy is dry,
yet near water.
Did you know that
Vegas is built
on some underground springs?
Yeah.
Well, I got a map.
And there's a spring
in the desert
right under where they
found Mike's Jeep.
See-- dry, yet near water.
Mommy, Mommy, help me.
Help me!
Mommy, please...
Please help me.
(voice breaking):
Andy's so close.
He wants me to find him.
I feel him
all around me still.
(sobs)
What about your husband
and your daughter?
Never.
Isn't that terrible?
No.
(computer trilling, beeping)
Hey, Greg.
you gotta come take
a look at this.
I was just processing
the fresh blood
from the grip,
and I noticed old
blood and tissue
in this ring
around the lens.
Old blood?
Yeah.
So it can't be casual transfer
from the vic.
Has to be from an earlier event.
Right.
And that impact
had to be significant enough
to actually damage tissue.
Plus those are hair fragments
right there,
which tells me that
somebody was whacked
on the head.
So, uh, Wendy got a hit
on the blood and tissue
from Janet Marsh's flashlight.
Familial match
to her son Andy.
We could be looking
at our murder weapon.
So this woman's been searching
for her son all these years
with the exact same flashlight
that was used to kill him?
If Janet Marsh
was in possession
of the murder weapon,
that makes her the only suspect.
Wait a minute now.
I've met the woman.
It's very tough to fake grief
like that.
Well, guilt can masquerade
as grief.
And there's a lot of people
who express remorse
after committing
a homicide.
If this were the father
that we were talking about
and not the mother,
what would we be thinking then?
"Lock him up"?
And, ordinarily,
we'd be right,
but this is by no means
an ordinary case.
(knocking on door)
Hi.
How you feeling,
Janet?
Better?
I'm okay.
Good.
So, what brings you here?
We found
some new evidence.
It concerns Andy.
You found my son?
Uh, no, ma'am,
but with your help,
we may be able to.
Okay.
Come on in.
So, what can I do?
How can I help?
You had a flashlight with you
last night.
Yes.
Where did you get that?
It was in the car.
Okay, so it's yours.
Yes.
Oh. And where do you
keep that, in the car?
In the kitchen.
How long have
had the flashlight?
Uh, ten years.
Since we bought the house.
(chuckles)
Why are they asking
about the flashlight?
We found Andy's blood on it.
Well, how can that be?
You all searched
the house already.
When we searched
Mike's Jeep,
that became our
crime scene.
Mrs. Marsh, we'd
like permission
to process your house.
Of course.
Kitchen's that way.
MAN (over radio):
Control, 257 Adam, copy.
Responding at three.
WOMAN:
252 Boy, Control.
Respond to a 417
at 273 Adams Street.
Informant will meet you
in front of the house.
(scoffs)
When did you get
the police scanner?
Oh, I hardly listen
to that thing anymore.
It's in the kitchen.
Yeah. Let-let me show you
where I keep the...
No, no. You can just point it
out for me, if you don't mind.
I keep it in the last drawer.
(indistinct radio transmission)
Come on, Janet.
I'll buy you lunch.
All right, I got a
police report here
with a supplemental
in Brass' handwriting.
Time cards substantiate
that Janet Marsh was working
at Wellington's Market
from 4:00 p.m.
to midnight the night
her family went missing.
She had an alibi.
But she didn't
call 911
until almost 4:00 a.m.
Which would've given
Janet Marsh time
to kill her family,
to clean up,
to dispose of the bodies
and to dump
the bloody truck,
which gave her a diversion
and took us 23 miles away
from the house.
That's a lot
for one person to do.
So, if she did it,
she had to have help.
If a stranger committed
these murders,
he would've brought
his own weapon.
And if he didn't,
he would've done
a quick search
of the room
and grabbed one
of these knives.
Why would he pick
a flashlight?
And why put it back
in the drawer?
Maybe force of habit.
Or the killer thought
he cleaned it off
and put it back
where it belonged.
Either way, it suggests
we're looking
at a family member
or a friend.
Janet admitted to Brass
that her marriage was rocky.
A lot of marriages end
because of infidelity.
Maybe she was seeing someone.
Brass checked
her phone records.
There was
no unusual calls.
Looks like she talked to her
brother at least twice a day.
Let's say Janet snapped,
killed her family,
calls brother Bill.
He helps her
cover it up.
Well, Brass' gut told him
that the brother was involved,
but the guy had
a ironclad alibi.
He was questioned
a dozen times.
Searched his home,
his office, his car.
Still, Janet told Nick
that she had hallucinations
about her dead son.
It sounds like
she was experiencing
some kind
of dissociative episode.
Her personality splintered
because of the guilt.
This is why she wanders
the highway at night.
She's being tormented
by her own conscience.
Or she's a cold-blooded murderer
who's still playing out
her diversion
to keep the suspicion away.
♪ ♪
Hey,
check this out.
This is the latest issue
of this magazine.
Janet Marsh never canceled
her son's subscription.
You know. it looks
to me like she just quit
living the night
her family disappeared.
And she's not going to live
again until
she gets some answers.
What's that?
Her daughter
had a diary.
Listen to this.
"He gave me
the coolest bracelet today
"and told me how special I am.
"He's the only one
who understands me,
"especially since my mom
only cares about Andy,
"and my dad's never home.
"I love him, and
I wish he could
take me away from here.
Maybe someday."
Did Brass interview
the boyfriend?
Brass never mentioned
a boyfriend.
Well, this is the last entry,
five months before
her disappearance.
She wrote in this journal
every day for a year,
and then just stopped.
There must have been something
going on,
especially at that age.
Maybe a significant event
with a significant other?
A boyfriend could've known
his way around the house.
What's his name?
We'll have Brass round him up.
She doesn't even mention
his name.
Not even an initial.
Ah, that's weird.
Maybe it was someone
her parents didn't approve of.
You think they're
dead, don't you?
It's just that
I always had this feeling
that somehow Andy got away.
What about
your daughter?
Could you ever
give up on Ellie?
(children giggling)
Actually, I think
in some ways
Ellie gave up on me.
You never stop
loving your kids.
There's a difference
between giving up
and letting go.
Janet,
you got to learn to let go.
(car door closes)
Can I help you?
What's going on here?
This is a police investigation.
Who are you?
Bill Cornwell.
This is my sister's house.
Let me see some I.D.
Okay.
You're not an organ donor?
Look, Janet came home
from the hospital this morning.
She should be resting.
Where is she?
Your sister's fine,
Mr. Cornwell.
My sister hasn't been fine
in a long time.
That's why I have
to come by every day;
pay her bills,
make sure she eats.
Is there something going on
with the case?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I know.
You can't talk about it.
I just miss them, you know?
Andy and Emily
were great kids.
Hey, Bill, while
we're talking,
have you ever met
any of Emily's boyfriends?
If she did have any,
she didn't bring them home.
Yeah? Why's that?
Mike was pretty protective
of his little girl.
And Em and Janet,
you know,
they had
a pretty stormy relationship.
Thanks for stopping by.
Yeah, I hope you
come up with
something again.
We'll do the best we can.
Thanks.
You're welcome.
(engine starting)
Hey.
Janet's brother.
Heard you could use
an extra hand.
Yeah. Yeah, thanks, Ray.
Greg's finishing up
with the luminol inside,
but so far, there's no evidence
of any killing
that took place here.
Let's check the garage.
It's frozen in time.
Just like the rest of the house.
Let's go to work.
The luminol's reacting
with the detergent.
Yeah, and the bleach.
Nick.
Hmm?
I've got something over here,
and it ain't bleach.
No, sir.
We need to get up there.
LANGSTON:
That's the stain that seeped
through into the garage.
A trail of fluid leads
back to...
this footlocker here.
U.S. Army standard issue.
A psychic told Janet that her
son was dry but near water.
Oh.
LANGSTON:
Andy was wearing pajamas
the night he disappeared.
(sighs)
BRASS:
Where exactly?
Have they recovered
anything else?
Okay, keep me posted, Nick.
Jim, what is it?
What? Did they
find something?
Tell me.
They found Andy's body.
At the house?
No.
Oh, he was with me all the time!
(sobbing):
He was with me!
Come on.
No! No! No!
(sighs)
You know, Doc...
I'm against the death penalty...
...except when it comes
to people who kill children.
I think they should
be tortured first
and then guillotined.
ROBBINS:
Every layer of friction ridged
skin was eaten away by bugs,
so I can't get prints.
Tissue sample should be able
to confirm
his identity through DNA.
Well, I confirmed
the remains as male.
Femur measured
11 inches.
That's consistent with an
average nine-year-old.
The decay was consistent
with a boy
who's been dead
approximately three years.
What about C.O.D.?
Blunt force trauma
to the temporal bone.
Single blow?
As far as
I can tell.
The wound appears compatible
of an object the size and shape
of that flashlight I saw.
And there were bone fragments
inside what was left his brain.
I can't tell you
what Andy was feeling
in the final moments
of his life...
...but I do know
he didn't suffer long.
He shouldn't have suffered
at all.
(sobbing)
Her son's body
was found in her garage.
She was in possession
of the murder weapon.
That makes Janet Marsh
suspect number one.
We're taking her
into custody, Jim.
The woman has been through hell.
She just found out
that she's been living
with her kid's corpse.
Yeah, a corpse that was
never in her husband's vehicle.
Which means that her son's
bloody pajama top was
planted there,
which brings us back
to your friend Janet.
She didn't kill her family.
Jim, I know you're
trying to do your job,
but you have a personal
relationship with this woman.
Okay?
And that's not going
to look good.
Don't go there, Conrad, okay?
Jim, we're going
to do this by the book.
I'm not taking you
off the case,
but I want to interview her.
She knows me.
She trusts me.
Let's just see what she'll say
when she's talking to someone
she doesn't know.
Mrs. Marsh,
my name's Conrad Ecklie.
I'm the undersheriff.
We need to ask you
some questions.
First, I need to make sure
this waiver of attorney we
have on file still applies.
Do you waive your right
to have an attorney present?
Yes or no, please?
Yes.
I waive my right
to have an attorney present.
Janet, you remember me, yeah?
We've talked before.
Yes.
Guess we'll talk a little bit
again here.
Um, what can you tell me
about the footlocker
in the crawl space
above the garage?
Oh, my God.
Was he in there?
Stay with me now, Janet.
How long has it been there?
Since Mike got back
from Desert Storm.
So it was your husband's
footlocker?
Yes.
But we kept Andy's camping stuff
in it.
He loved to camp.
STOKES:
And how long has it been
since you opened it?
JANET:
We took a camping trip
to Cathedral Gorge that summer.
The kids, Mike, Bill and me.
And Bill is...?
My brother.
He spent more time with the kids
than their own father.
Taught Andy
to fish.
Uh, Emily was being difficult,
so I brought her home.
I'm pretty sure they put the
locker away when they got back.
You think I killed
my little boy?
My daughter? My husband?
I can't move because I'm afraid
if they come back,
they won't be able to find me.
I can't sleep, and so I go
looking for them on the highway.
It's all I do!
Why can't you people
understand that?
I hire psychics to help me,
and then people think I'm crazy.
This is making me crazy!
And it's got to stop!
It's got to stop!
LANGSTON:
I collected 16 prints.
Six were identifiable.
Five were on the bottom panel
of the footlocker.
Position suggests that someone
was trying to pick it up.
All five were a match
to Mike Marsh.
Identified by an old work card.
Construction contract
at the Eclipse.
This one...
is unknown.
Did you check it
against the brother?
Yes. Everyone's money
is on Uncle Bill,
but no match.
Print could belong
to one of the kids.
David Phillips was unable
to get any fingerprints
off the boy's body.
And there were
no exemplars
from Andy or Emily in the file.
♪ ♪
LANGSTON:
What made you collect this?
Emily's room was full of
stuff that belonged to her,
but this was actually
a part of her.
No hit on your lid print.
It was a long-shot,
but we had to play it.
Wait a sec.
That's impossible.
There were no exemplars.
She can't be in AFIS.
What did Emily's
print hit on?
Current work card--
Hope Wilson,
Reno, Nevada.
Date of birth,
September 2, 1992.
It's a different name,
but it's the same birthday.
That is Emily Marsh.
MAN:
Suspect's vehicle
is approaching.
Let's go.
Emily Marsh,
step out of the vehicle.
Emily Marsh?
My name is Hope Wilson.
Put your weapons away.
Mommy.
There's a child
in the backseat.
Call Child Services.
Get an ambulance,
get the kid
back to Vegas.
Emily Marsh, you're under
arrest. Come with me.
My name is Hope Wilson.
Please don't hurt my son.
He'll be fine.
Oh, Conner,
don't be sad.
Everything's cool.
Hey, I got something for
you. You want to see?
Pick one.
Green.
Green?
Are you sure?
The red's really good.
Uh-uh.
I'll make
you a deal.
You try the red one,
and if you don't like it,
I'll give you the green one.
Okay.
There you go.
(chuckles)
You don't like it?
Okay. All right, the
green one it is then.
There you go.
Good?
Good.
How old are you?
Three? No way.
You're a big boy.
You like that one?
I got to get me a green one.
WILLOWS:
We know who you are.
You're Emily Marsh.
Your fingerprints
confirm it.
Emily,
we've been looking
for you for three years.
We're still looking
for your father.
Can you tell me
what happened?
I'm going to need
to take your DNA
to confirm
you're the mother of Conner.
I am.
Who's the father?
Open up please.
How's it going
in here, Ray?
Looks like we're
back to square two.
You know her neighbors
in Reno said that Emily was
living with her husband--
an older guy.
LANGSTON:
Conner's father,
Doug Wilson.
D.O.B. September 14, 1967.
Age...
Forty-three.
Mike Marsh would have been 43.
People on the run
are desperate.
They're not thinking straight.
They change their names,
but they forget to change
their date of birth.
(typing)
(computer trilling)
LANGSTON:
Doug Wilson.
That's the same face.
Father and daughter
living as husband and wife.
Connor was three.
Emily was pregnant
before she disappeared.
Her father's the father.
I want to see Emily now.
It's gonna be a while.
We haven't finished
talking to her yet.
Why? What's the matter?
Emily is safe.
So keep that in the front
of your mind, okay?
But things are
unraveling very quickly,
and there've been some
unexpected developments.
Mike is alive.
Emily has a child.
What?
He's three years old.
How...? No, no, that can't be.
How could that be?
Captain.
Yeah?
There's a Doug Wilson
at the Reception.
Wants to talk to you.
Okay.
I'm gonna send someone
home with you, okay?
And I'll call you later.
(quietly):
As soon as I take
him to Interrogation,
get her out of here.
Yeah.
Oh, my...
(sobs):
Oh, my God.
Mike Marsh.
Have you arrested him?
Yes, Captain.
That's why I'm here.
I'm the guy you want,
not my daughter.
Emily didn't do anything wrong.
We're gonna talk about that.
Let's go.
I made the decision to run!
I took her with me.
Let Emily and her son go!
She didn't have
anything to do
with Andy's death!
I killed him!
It was an accident.
It was all me.
Did you hear
what I said?
It was all my fault.
I killed my son.
(screams)
You sick bastard!
You were supposed
to protect our children!
Get down!
Dad?
Dad!
(sobbing):
Daddy!
(sobbing)
Daddy, what happened?
What happened?
Daddy.
No!
(sighs)
A man murders his son,
impregnates his daughter.
Why turn yourself in?
I mean, he ran once,
why not run again?
Maybe he thought,
in his own sick,
twisted way,
that he was really
in love with her.
And then he found out
that she and their son
we're in custody?
He wanted to protect
the both of them.
DNA results on Connor Wilson
came back.
He shares more than 20 alleles
with Emily.
Because Connor's mother and
father were father and daughter.
The extra alleles come
from the maternal DNA.
Say again?
Mike Marsh is not
Connor Wilson's father.
His father shares
seven alleles
with Janet Marsh.
Janet's brother?
Uncle Bill.
I told my mom I didn't want
Uncle Bill to come over anymore.
She said I was
ungrateful,
and it was her house.
This whole thing is her fault!
Everything is her fault!
When did your dad find out?
That night.
My dad was still at work.
Uncle Bill let himself in.
I thought since I was pregnant,
he would leave me alone,
but he didn't.
Andy should've been in bed.
(Bill speaking indistinctly)
(Emily sobbing)
When Uncle Bill left,
I went to find Andy.
I didn't even know what to say.
But the way he looked at me...
He started yelling,
"I'm gonna tell Mom!
I'm gonna tell Mom!
I'm gonna tell Mom!"
She would have blamed me!
I just wanted him to shut up!
I'm gonna tell Mom!
Quit it!
You're not gonna tell Mom!
Yes, I am!
Get that thing
out of my face!
You're gonna be
in so much trouble!
Shut up!
When my dad came home and found
us, I told him everything.
Emmy, what happened?
(sobbing)
I'm sorry.
He said it wasn't my fault,
that he'd make it all better.
My dad said we'd come back
someday and bury him.
My dad was just trying
to protect me.
He didn't do anything wrong.
(sobbing)
I loved my brother.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry!
(sobbing)
The D.A. has decided not to file
charges against Emily.
She'll be a much better mother
than I ever was.
I never could
talk with Emily...
even when she was little.
Andy was different.
He was so easy to love.
This all happened
because they knew I could
never forgive her.
I hope one day
she can learn to forgive me.
Okay.
(sighs)
♪ ♪
Okay, there's your mom.
It's time to go.
But before you leave,
how about...
a green one for the road?
All right,
you're a good boy.
Go on,
you little CSI.
Mom!
Hey.
Hi.
Mommy.
How are you?
Are you okay?
Yeah.
Yeah?
I missed you.
Let me see you.