(dog barking)
(barking continues outside)
Try "extrapolate."
(barking continues)
(chuckles)
You want to do me
another favor?
Uh-uh.
Get Rocket to
stop barking?
It's your turn
to bring him in.
Hmm.
(barking continues)
I bet he's harassing
that poor little possum again.
(barking stops)
(barking resumes)
(window creaking)
(dog barking)
(gunshot, dog whimpers)
(barking stops)
(door opening)
(glass breaking)
(woman screaming)
Lisa!
(thudding)
(Lisa screaming)
Lisa!
(gunshot)
(gasping)
(wind whistling)
What the hell is wrong
with you?
Now you're really in trouble.
MAN:
Lisa!
(gunshot)
(camera shutter clicking)
(distant siren wailing)
MAN:
As soon as I saw their dog,
I knew something was wrong.
Then I saw the door open
and Ms. Layman inside.
You touch anything?
No, sir.
I just called 911.
No shell casings.
None here either.
Weapon was probably a revolver.
Wife hears the commotion,
comes out...
She struggles with the killer.
He drops her.
Lisa, honey, what's wrong?!
(three gunshots, man groans)
(camera shutter clicking)
SIDLE:
Got a partial shoe impression.
Generic worker boot.
Roughly 10 to 13.
WILLOWS:
We'll put a broadcast out
on the daughter.
That's about all we can do
for now.
Yeah, that's the one thing
I hate most about this job.
(gunshot, man groans)
Daddy! Daddy!
(screaming)
(three gunshots)
(gunman panting)
(indistinct police
radio chatter)
There's a wallet
and a purse
in the master bedroom,
both filled with
cash and cards,
so this wasn't
a home invasion robbery.
And looks like they came
for Gracie.
Mm-hmm.
Tom Layman was a pit boss
at the Palermo.
Lisa was working here at home
as a freelance
technical writer.
They were a regular
middle-class family,
not typical targets
for kidnappers.
I don't see any blood.
There's a crawl trail here.
See that?
Green fluorescence--
urine.
(screaming)
Gracie. Gracie,
it's okay.
My name's Nick.
I'm with the police department.
You're safe now.
Come here, honey.
Oh, baby, it's all right.
Come here. It's okay.
Aw.
It's okay.
Oh...
(crying)
I got you, honey.
(sobbing)
It's okay.
I got you.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
(tapping)
Hey, Sara, I found
some fresh tool marks
on the windowsill.
Looks like somebody jimmied it.
Well, the shooter definitely
came in through the back door.
But maybe he did
a little recon first.
In L.A., the Manson family
used to do "creepy crawls."
They would break into a house
while the people were asleep
and sneak around inside.
Knowing they
had the power
to end people's lives
like that
must have been a real turn-on
for them.
Got a print.
(grunting and panting)
(gunman straining)
(soft beep)
SANDERS:
Mandy got a hit off that print
on the windowsill.
STOKES:
The gardener?
He's just going to say
he left it
when he was working
around the house.
Yeah, well, I'm more interested
in what the little girl
has to say.
(sighs)
Child witness--
that's not a lot
to hang your hat on.
We got anything else?
Just some metallic trace
in the killer's bootprint
and on the wife's robe.
All right.
I'll let you know how it goes.
Later.
(phone beeps off and flips shut)
(television playing softly)
Hey, Gracie.
You remember me?
Yeah?
Can I sit here with you?
I've got some
good news for you.
Your Aunt Maggie's flying in
from Boston to see you.
She's going to be here
real soon.
But hey, listen,
I'm stuck,
and I need some help.
It's very important.
You want to help me?
Hmm?
Okay.
(phone beeps on)
You know who he is?
He's our gardener.
Is he the guy
you saw last night?
(gunshot, man groans)
Daddy!
(screaming)
(three gunshots)
(panting)
(door creaking)
(wind whistling)
(gun cocking)
(sobbing quietly)
(screaming furiously)
It was really dark, and...
I really couldn't see anything.
I'm sorry.
Hey, don't be scared, honey.
You're safe now.
Nobody's going to get you.
You can tell me:
Is this the guy
who hurt your parents?
It was him, right?
I'm glad you're feeling better.
So maybe I leaned
against the window
while trimming the bushes.
So what?
So you're a convicted felon,
that's what.
So you got a record, right?
B&amp;E, assault,
grand larceny.
The gang unit tells me
you were a member of the
L.V. Marrones back in the day.
They also tell me
three weeks ago,
you were hanging
at Jackson and K.
That's where the Marrones
deal heroin.
But you know that anyway, right?
I'm not on probation anymore.
Yeah.
Every once in a while I go by
the old neighborhood,
say hi to the homies.
Sure, I understand.
You want to go by
the clubhouse,
kick it, chill,
drink some 40s,
smoke some herb,
watch football...
and plan some robberies
and murders.
I don't run with those guys,
and I didn't touch the Laymans.
I got a wife and a kid,
and I've been doing it straight
for nine years.
You guys just don't lay off
a guy's ass,
just hoping he's gonna screw up.
What's your shoe size?
Why?
Because I asked you.
That's why.
Eleven.
You said the magic word.
Give me your shoes.
Now you want to give them to me
or you want me
to get some professional in here
to take them off you?
Look, I was never in that house.
Are you sure about that, homes?
Are you absolutely sure
about that?
Because if I toss
your place and I find
one eensy-bitsy piece of swag
from the Laymans...
Okay, fine.
I snuck in that window...
not last night, last week.
I looked inside,
and I saw their kid playing
with a brand-new
video game box.
The old one was just sitting
there on the shelf.
So I waited till they went out,
I went inside,
And I took it.
I make $60 a day pulling weeds
and shoveling dog crap.
How do you think it feels?
I can't even afford
to buy my kid one game.
I didn't kill anyone, I swear.
Gardener's boots had
the same tread pattern
as the crime scene
impression,
but there was no
characteristic match.
And apparently,
they're negative for blood.
There was no metallic
trace on them either.
Any luck in Ballistics?
Well, the bullets
we recovered were all .22s
fired from
the same gun.
Nothing in IBIS,
so no real luck at all.
Luck is where opportunity
meets preparation.
The metallic dust
was a titanium alloy
consisting of 4% vanadium
and 6% aluminum.
That's an odd material
to find in a garden.
Definitely. Titanium is
widely used in aerospace
and high-end tooling.
Based on
the particle size
and uniformity, my guess is,
they came from a machine shop.
Titanium dust on the killer's
boots and hands?
Maybe we're looking
for an industrial worker?
You know, if there was dust
on the inside of the house...
(wind whistling)
(gate creaking)
OFFICER:
Thought you guys
checked this house.
STOKES:
Twice. Both times, nobody home.
SIDLE:
I got a blood smear.
(doorknob jiggles)
STOKES:
It's unlocked.
Vegas Police!
Call for backup.
(static crackles)
OFFICER: Control. Akers.
Two additional units backup
at my location.
DISPATCHER:
Copy, Akers, 105.
(static crackles)
(whispers):
.22s.
(wind whistling, dull thud)
(water running)
(door creaking)
(radio playing music softly)
(soft, repetitive
mechanical humming)
(repetitive mechanical humming
grows louder)
(mill humming)
(electronic beep)
(computer beeps)
Nick!
LVPD tell 8 News Now
that they want
to talk to retired machinist
Jack Herson.
Herson, in his 50s,
is a person of interest
in the violent home invasion
that shattered the calm
in that normally quiet
neighborhood.
Well, I'm pretty darn sure
he hated that dog.
Furry bastard was always
tearing up flower beds,
chasing cats,
barking at all hours.
Enough to drive anybody
to murder.
(indistinct radio transmission)
(camera shutter clicks)
Jack Herson owns a 12-shot
.22-caliber revolver
with the same GRCs
as the murder bullets.
Any sign of the gun?
Hasn't turned up.
After what he did,
he'd probably
be keeping that with him.
We anywhere on his contacts?
His Internet service provider
gave us access
to all of his accounts.
There are hundreds of e-mails,
hundreds of phone numbers.
The few with the same
last names are relatives,
and we know they're
are all back east.
As for his friends...
it's gonna take a while
to round up
even the local ones.
LANGSTON:
Hey.
Hey. I just got off
the phone with Brass.
We're not gonna find Herson
by trapping his plastic.
According to his
credit card company,
he's been maxed out
for months.
Great.
So, at this point,
we seem to be dealing
with a nice,
retired machinist
who suddenly goes
on a killing spree
because he's behind
on his bills.
Well, one day,
the wrong synapse fires,
and a dam bursts.
No one can truly know
what goes on
inside another man's mind.
No.
Nick, come take a look at this.
I'm assuming that's not
just another machine part.
It's a surgical tool.
According to the witness,
it was a straight-up
hit-and-run.
Started as a fender-bender.
One driver got out pissed;
the pickup ran him
over and split.
When the responding officer
called in the tags,
it came up as Herson.
Injured driver's in stable
condition at Desert Palm.
Ah, he was lucky.
South Turkson at Blue Diamond
three hours ago.
Where was Herson going?
These are pieces of a prototype
stereotactic frame.
It's what a machinist makes
in order to ensure
his design works
before he mills a real one.
SIDLE:
Out of titanium,
I'm guessing.
Yeah.
What's it for?
Neurosurgery.
The surgeon locks it
onto the patient's skull,
and then uses
the calibration marks
to precisely position
instruments
for operating on the brain.
(squishing)
You think Jack Herson
is Dr. Jekyll.
SIDLE:
Why would a methodical killer
like Jekyll
suddenly go ballistic and kill
his next-door neighbor?
Maybe the Laymans
saw something.
Figured out what Herson
was doing down here.
Jekyll's killed a witness
out of panic before.
To perform surgery, you...
you need a operating table,
don't you, Doctor?
That's a lot of blood.
All right. I'll see
what I can find out.
Hey. Nick and Dr. Ray
are finishing up
at the Herson place.
I figured I might be able
to help out here.
Highway Patrol
just found Herson's car
overheated and abandoned
off the 160, outside of Pahrump.
Any idea who...
(computer beeps)
(typing)
(sighs)
I take it you're
playing a hunch?
Uh-huh.
What is the mascot for
Pahrump Nye County High School?
Uh, the bulldog.
I thought so.
Herson knows a woman
in West Pahrump.
The residence
is number 28128...
I can't see the street.
Well, there can't be too many
houses in that district
with that number.
No, there can't.
WOMAN (distorted):
Those men outside,
they're going to hurt you
if you don't do what they say.
You-you've always been
a good boy, Jackie, and I...
I know that whatever you did,
you-you must have had a reason.
Mr. Herson, we've got
the place surrounded.
You know there's no way
you can escape.
Why don't you pick up the phone
and talk to us?
Stupid dog.
I understand.
HERSON:
Stupid dog!
Sir, the house belongs
to Nell Porter,
a retired schoolteacher
and Herson's aunt.
Yeah. There's something
wrong with that guy.
HERSON:
Barking! Barking!
No kidding, sir.
No, no.
I mean his behavior.
Look at that.
He just kept barking
and barking and barking.
Hold on a second.
What is it?
The radiator
plug's missing.
So?
So, if you turned on the heat,
you'd flood the whole place.
Somewhat imprecise for
a precision machinist.
Hang on to that.
Fresh tool marks.
This has been
wrenched off recently.
Hang on a sec.
The last time Jekyll killed,
he took a souvenir
from the victim's house.
And he left...
Oh, please put the gun down!
(crying):
Oh, please put the gun down,
Jackie.
HERSON:
There's something wrong
with my head.
OFFICER:
Mr. Herson, please.
Why don't you let your aunt
come on out?
(gunshot)
(screams)
Go, go, go, go.
OFFICER: We have a go.
(static crackles)
Move! Move it!
(keypad beeping)
Gita.
11:32.
Go! Let's go!
It's a passage
from the Bhagavad Gita.
OFFICER:
Let me see the hands.
Get the hands up, sir!
The words that went through
Robert Oppenheimer's mind
after he witnessed
the first atomic bomb test.
Stop moving now!
"Now I am become Death,
the Destroyer of Worlds."
Herson isn't Jekyll.
No.
He's another victim.
STOKES:
Dr. Jekyll performed
his first operation
on an already dead
street performer
by inserting a laparoscope
into the corpse
and tying his intestines
into a bow around his spleen.
WILLOWS:
However, his second victim
was very much alive
when Jekyll sewed
a septic appendix
to his ascending colon.
In both cases,
Jekyll gave his victim
something and then took
a similar souvenir.
Joey Bigelow got
a bow-tied intestine,
and then Jekyll took
his actual bow tie.
STOKES:
And Bernard Higgins
received an extra appendix
in exchange for a word
from the appendix of his book.
And now it appears
that Dr. Jekyll has taken
Jack Herson's radiator plug.
Mm-hmm.
But in exchange for what?
What do you know?
Oh...
He's wearing a rug.
Oh.
Human hair hand-tied
to a fine lace front
to hide the hair line.
Quality carpet.
LANGSTON:
He's got stitches.
PHILLIPS:
They look fresh.
They are.
What is that?
It's super-bright.
May be a bullet.
Give me another view.
I can't even see any edges.
And the image
isn't moving at all.
Could it be radiating energy?
Radiator.
It's radioactive.
(Geiger counter clicking
rapidly)
(saw buzzing)
ROBBINS:
Looks like Dr. Jekyll
drilled a hole
in the top of Herson's skull,
inserted a hollow needle
between the brain hemispheres
and into the septum pellucidum,
and then shoved
radioactive material in
like peas through a straw.
They're radiation seeds.
Don't worry.
It's a lead-infused acrylic.
STOKES:
Yeah, I've heard of these.
They're used
to treat cancer.
Herson didn't have cancer.
No.
The radiation severely damaged
the area of the brain
that's involved
with mood changes,
sexual gratification and rage.
LANGSTON:
In the 1950s,
researchers induced
similar lesions in rats.
It produced
"septal rage."
These creatures
would attack each other savagely
with the slightest provocation.
Are we saying that Herson isn't
responsible for his murders?
No. But he might not have
been aware of what he was doing.
I'll bet he didn't even realize
he'd been operated on.
Jekyll's anesthetic
of choice is ketamine.
Herson would've come to
with his rug back in place,
disoriented, and unable
to remember what happened.
SIDLE:
According to his medical
records, he called his HMO,
complaining
of severe headaches.
They said that they couldn't
schedule an appointment
until next week.
He threw a tantrum.
They said
that he sounded drunk.
(grunting angrily)
(dog barking)
(barking grows louder)
LANGSTON:
Maybe the dog barking
was the final straw.
(panting nervously)
(gun cocking)
I'm sorry.
(agonized groans)
STOKES:
And not killing Gracie
was the last shred
of humanity he could muster.
WILLOWS:
Three weeks ago,
Jack Herson made
a cash deposit of $5,000.
The very next day,
he drew up plans
for the stereotactic unit
and placed an order
for medical-grade titanium.
So, Jekyll
gives Herson the money
to build the device,
and then, when it's finished,
he turns around and
uses it on its maker?
I've seen my share of sickos,
but this is severely twisted.
Dr. Jekyll is a classic sadist.
He designs
his operations
so his victims suffer
slow, agonizing deaths.
Well, we have Herson's contacts
and emails.
I know it's brute force,
but if we can figure out
where or how Herson and Jekyll
could have crossed paths,
it could lead us to him.
This is Jekyll's
third time at bat.
He doesn't seem to be
getting any sloppier.
Well, he did leave these.
(radioactive beads pulsing
photons of gamma radiation)
(Geiger counter clicking)
(clicking continues)
Why did I just receive 17 pages
of federal forms to fill out
with your name on it?
Have you ever tried to locate
a high-purity germanium
gamma ray detector at 4:00
on a Friday
in Las Vegas?
WILLOWS:
No.
I assumed you wanted the
analysis as quickly as possible,
and I'm happy to tell you
that the implants
showed gamma spikes
characteristic of iridium 192.
Iridium 192?
That's used in high dose rate
cancer therapy.
It also has half-life
of 73.827 days,
which means that a simple
decay rate calculation
can accurately determine
when it was manufactured.
I take it you've performed
this calculation?
Of course.
But there's more...
This gamma signature
indicates that the pellet
also contained gold.
The only commercially
available iridium pellets
with gold substrates
are from Nosumi BioMed,
which manufactured these seeds
13 days ago for delivery
to Saint Sebastian's Hospital,
in care of a Dr. William Burke.
I'll tell you what he says.
Well done, David Hodges.
And, uh, you can tell
Homeland Security
that the quantity
of radioactive material in this
is infinitesimal
and poses no threat.
Oh, you can tell them.
Hang on a second. No.
If-if the radiation source
is infinitesimal,
why are you wearing
three lead aprons?
Despite my aversion
to children,
sperm count.
Gentlemen, it, uh...
seems you're correct.
We received 40 iridium seeds
from the manufacturer last week.
My physicist just
counted them
in the storage room, and...
we are ten short.
Do you know what
happened to them?
Not yet,
but I promise you we will.
It's possible
it's a clerical error.
It's also possible
someone stole them.
What for?
You can't make a dirty bomb
out of them,
and they won't get you high.
Have we met?
No, I don't believe we have.
Why are a homicide detective
and a CSI investigating
a discrepancy in our inventory?
Your iridium seeds
were used by a killer.
A person with sophisticated
surgical skills.
Sounds like a modern-day
Jack the Ripper.
The perpetrator's not
a simple cutter.
Two days ago, he used
a custom-built
stereotactic device
to insert your pellets
into a man's septum.
The ensuing brain damage
caused the victim
to kill three people
before he died himself.
You're kidding.
No, I'm not.
Dr. Burke,
we're gonna need
a detailed account
of your whereabouts in
the last several days.
Mostly here.
Am I a suspect?
We're just following
our leads, Doc.
Actually, we're trying
to rule you out.
Right.
My secretary can give you
that information.
If you'll excuse me,
I have a patient
with prostate cancer.
I have to tell him that
his surgery has
been delayed.
I got it.
Raymond Langston--
you wrote that book
about the Angel of Death
at Delaware General.
(chuckles):
Oh, yeah!
You'd love it if
I was the killer.
Then you could
write a sequel
about another psychopathic
doctor murdering his patients,
and use it as an
excuse to indict
the entire medical
establishment again.
Well, obviously, you didn't read
very clearly or carefully.
I was examining my own
failures in the book.
Interesting how
your soul-searching
managed to imply
that everyone else
was incompetent.
You took one rogue surgeon
and vilified
an entire profession.
I saw their mistakes
in the morgue, Doctor.
I wrote what I saw.
I don't suffer the illusion
that all surgeons walk on water.
You know, Ray,
I think were not needed here.
I think we're all done.
Thanks for your time, Doctor.
Mm-hmm.
Let's go.
Uh, you sound a
little envious.
Why is that?
Because you didn't
have what it takes
to cut into a living,
breathing human being
and try and save
their lives?
Being a pathologist is easier.
Your patients are already dead.
It's kind of like being a CSI,
I guess, right?
You're perfect for the job.
(loud bang)
Aah!
(groans in pain, pants)
Now you've got a problem.
(groans)
So, the good doctor
saw the light,
and he's agreed not
to press charges for assault.
I convinced him that
a very public investigation
into how he lost potentially
dangerous radioactive material
may impact negatively
on his insurance liability,
both for him and his hospital.
So he calmed down and...
actually became
kind of reasonable.
So I said we'll chalk
it up to an accident.
It was an accident, right?
Yeah. Look, Ray, I mean,
I've known you long enough
to know that you don't
like to get any advice,
but I'm gonna give you
some anyway, okay?
You know, if this song-and-dance
here that you did was
because you're frustrated
about the Jekyll killer,
I understand that.
I get it.
But if it has to do
with something...
from the past, some old,
unfinished business,
something from way back when...
I suggest you drop it,
'cause it's not working for you.
That's all I'm gonna say.
SECURITY DIRECTOR:
All of the restricted areas in
the hospital have keypad locks.
To gain access,
I assume all your people
have to enter their
personal code.
Exactly.
Our system tracks
every time and place
one of those codes is used.
Now, these surveillance photos
were taken at the door
to the nuclear medicine
storage room.
That's where we keep
those radioactive seeds.
STOKES:
Mm-hmm. And these are
the people who entered
during the time period
the seeds went missing?
SECURITY DIRECTOR:
Mm-hmm.
(typing)
Hmm.
Huh, what is it?
This man used
Dr. Davis's I.D. code.
Only one problem:
Dr. Davis is a five-foot-two
African-American woman,
and she's in Hawaii.
Has that code been used anywhere
else in the hospital since then?
Uh, searching.
(typing)
(computer beeps)
It was used
four minutes ago.
Where?
A surgical supply locker
on the fifth floor.
Get on the phone,
lock down the building.
Lock it down!
Hey, what's going on?
Dr. Jekyll's here--
fifth floor.
Control, this is
Charlie 03 Stokes.
I need four units containment,
Saint Sebastian Hospital.
You sure he's
in the building?
Yeah, he was in a lab coat
and a surgical mask.
So are half of
the people in here.
(both panting)
You go east; I'll go west.
Yeah.
STOKES:
Excuse me.
Everyone, I'm a crime scene
investigator with the Vegas PD.
I need everyone to remove
their masks for me, please.
Are you out of your mind?
This is a sterile area!
And I'm in pursuit
of a murder suspect.
Take it off.
Take if off!
That goes for
the rest of you, too.
Get them off.
Identify each other.
WOMAN:
We're all here.
There's nobody
that shouldn't be.
(panting)
What the hell
is your problem?
(startled chattering)
MAN: Hey, straight ahead.
(shouting)
MAN:
Marcie, call security!
Hold it right there!
I'm a CSI.
(panting)
(door closes behind Langston)
(door opening)
(heart monitor beeping)
(door closes behind Langston)
♪ ♪
(indistinct chatter)
Did you see a doctor
come through here?
Anyone?
A doctor?
A man dressed...
as a doctor?
A man in a white coat
with a doctor's mask
come through here?
A man dressed
like a doctor!
Has he come through?
Which way did he go?
Nick, Jekyll just
went through the kitchen.
I'm on my way.
STOKES:
Where's the kitchen?
MAN:
Back there.