This is Langston.
Yeah, I need you back here
as soon as possible, Ray.
We're holding down
the fort tonight.
I just collected the last finger
on my 4-20.
I'll be on my way after that.
Okay.
Good night,
Catherine.
Thank you
for the time off.
Go, before
I change my mind.
Good night, John.
(car remote chirps)
Hey! What the...?!
Look, buddy, you got the
wrong guy! That hurt! Ow! Ow!
MAN:
Hit it! All clear. Get moving.
What the hell?!
My arm!
Shut up!
ANDREWS: Look, what do
you want from me?
You know what we want.
ANDREWS: I don't.
I swear to God.
I don't know anything.
That's not what
Harry says.
ANDREWS:
Who's Harry?
(chuckling)
Don't be stupid, Henry.
Now's no time to play dumb.
'Cause Harry don't like it
when people play dumb.
Understand?
Please, look, if you
just give me a hint,
I'll tell you anything
you want to know.
Oh, my God!
(gasping):
No...
Happy birthday, Henry.
What?
(all laugh)
Happy birthday!
Hey, man!
You scared the crap out of me!
What's the matter
with you idiots?!
Hey, hey, come on!
I'm driving!
It was all for a laugh!
God!
Henry, my friend, you are
about to have the best birthday
of your life,
because we are taking you
to the one,
the only, Harry's Hog Hideout.
Yeah!
What's a hog hideout?
It's only the best barbecue
known to mankind.
It's a little bit
of a drive,
but don't worry.
Greg knows where it is.
SANDERS:
I thought you said
you knew where it is.
(country music playing
over radio)
It's just a bit
of a drive, y'all.
ANDREWS:
Look, if this place,
if it's so great,
then how come
I've never heard of it?
Come on, man.
A little trust, baby.
Come on.
It's your birthday.
Yeah.
I hate my birthdays.
They always suck.
Oh, great, we got
a full moon tonight, too,
so every nut job
in the state will be out.
I'm surprised at you, Henry.
There's absolutely no
statistical evidence linking
lunar cycles to an increase
in irrational,
careless, or criminal behavior.
(horn honking)
Are you sure about that?
(all yelling)
(yells)
(yelling)
(grunting)
Ow!
(groaning)
Everybody okay? Huh?
You got a little
something.
What?
ANDREWS:
Aah, I think
I sprained my ankle.
Damn!
I rolled that bad boy,
didn't I?
(all laugh)
SANDERS:
I'd say.
Anybody got cell
phone service?
Nope.
Uh-uh.
No.
Doesn't really matter.
Harry's is about a mile
up that way, I think.
We can walk it.
Whoo!
Gee...
Thanks.
Here you go.
Thanks, brother.
Okay. Okay.
Let's go.
Ow!
♪ ♪
(satisfied chuckling)
Gentlemen,
we've arrived.
ANDREWS: Doesn't look
real open, does it?
"Notice:
"Closed by the Board of Health.
"Suspected point of origin:
a hepatitis B outbreak.
Date of closure: 7-3-09."
Oops.
That's five
months ago.
Nice. You were gonna
give me hepatitis
for my birthday.
Thanks.
Still got no reception.
All right, maybe
there's a working phone inside.
Let's take a look around.
Happy birthday.
I think we got a dead body
here, boys.
Best birthday ever.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
ANDREWS:
It appears this man
has a large raccoon sticking
to his face.
Ah. Procyon lotor.
The common
North American raccoon.
This is quite
a specimen, too.
Bet that sucker weighs
at least 30 pounds.
.357 in his hand.
No blood pool around the body.
No apparent entry wounds.
No signs of decomp.
This is a recent
event, fellas.
The entire upper half
of his body
looks like it was singed.
Hey. Let's roll him.
Oh, no, I... I'm not a coroner.
Greg, help me
out here.
Take a look back there.
No apparent entry wounds
on the posterior aspect, either.
Okay.
Maybe the raccoon leapt
through that window
ninja-style,
and before this guy
could shoot it,
it landed on him
and chewed his face off.
Well, I guess we should
call it in, huh?
Oh, that's right.
We've got no reception.
Well, it looks
like something
propelled them both
through that window
at a high velocity.
All right, I tell you what.
Greg, you and Hodges
take a look around outside.
I'm going to clear
this building,
see if I can
find a phone.
Henry...
stay with the body.
My pleasure.
(groans, sighs)
You come here often?
MALE OPERATOR:
911 operator. What
is your emergency?
WOMAN:
Please help me!
He's trying
to kill me!
Ma'am, please try
and remain calm.
Try to get to a
safe place, but stay
on the line with me.
Do you understand?
Ma'am? Ma'am?
Are you still
with me?
Dispatch, possible
person in distress.
917 Villacoté Circle.
Please respond.
♪ ♪
(over radio): Got one body--
female in the bathroom.
No pulse. I'll call it in.
Roger that. I'm still clearing
the first floor.
(woman screaming)
(on radio): I'm checking
the other rooms.
(muffled screaming)
WOMAN:
Somebody help!
(muffled screaming)
MAN (over TV):
But when help arrived,
it was too late.
The victim lay dead
on the floor,
and the killer had vanished.
(air pumping rhythmically)
Sir, you need to wake up.
(fading):
Sir, Las Vegas
Police Department.
(faint):
You need to wake up, sir.
Hey, Mr. Higgins, wake up.
OFFICER COLLINS: He just keeps
nodding off, sir.
Come on, man.
Bernard, come on!
What...?
Why are you guys in my house?!
Because there's a dead girl
in your bathroom.
What?!
(camera shutter clicking)
There's a pattern of reddish
abrasions ringing her neck,
consistent with somebody
forcing her head underwater.
With her fighting back,
that's a noisy way to go.
I'm gonna see what's up
with sleeping beauty
in the other room.
All right.
David, anchors aweigh.
Okay, ready?
Yep.
Cath?
There's something
in her arm.
Looks like a
broken hypodermic.
In other words,
she might've been drugged.
Her name is Lily.
Lily Chow Ping.
What was your relationship
to her?
Girlfriend,
I guess you could say.
She was just gonna take a bath
and wake me up in an hour.
We were gonna
go for dinner.
So you're telling me you slept
through the whole attack?
Attack?!
(sobbing):
Oh, God, there was an attack...
I have apnea.
Which means I have
a chronic sleep deficit.
When I put on the machine,
I'm dead to the world.
Who would want
to kill Lily?
Well, that's what
we're here to find out.
Look... (groaning)
You o... you okay?
(groaning)
I have Crohn's disease.
HIGGINS:
You know what that is?
Yes, an inflammatory disorder
of undetermined
etiology.
It ulcerates
the intestine.
It can be very painful.
HIGGINS: You can't get
rid of it, which is why
I feel like my guts
are on fire all the time.
Well, do you need
medical attention?
No.
Not at the moment.
Okay, then come with us.
We have some
more questions.
(groaning)
Oh, Lily, God.
(sniffling)
A woman was attacked
and violently drowned
in his own bathroom
and he says he slept
through the whole thing?
Well, being connected
to a CPAP is kind of like
being connected
to a ventilator.
It's a noisy machine,
and it's a reasonable alibi.
And Mr. Higgins knows a lot
about reasonable alibis.
He's a big fan
of true crime.
Compressed ethylene gas.
(scoffs)
Used book of matches.
Somebody's been playing
with fire.
Gee, I wonder who.
Gnawed bones and trash
at the bottom of a barrel.
Raccoon bait.
Really?
You know, I had a hat
like that when I was a kid.
Except I wore it
on the back of my head.
The other kids
would make fun of me
and occasionally beat me up,
but I didn't care,
'cause I was...
♪ Davy, Davy Crockett ♪
♪ King of the wild frontier ♪
(cocking gun)
Hold it right there.
Geez!
I'll unload both
barrels on you
and I'll turn you
into a pink mist.
Don't you think I won't.
Did you kill my friend?
Well, I go away and come back.
He's dead and you're here.
Put that gun down
on the floor.
And end up like Gomez?
I don't think so.
You think I'm crazy?
Calm down.
Yes, please calm down.
You calm down!
Hey, we're law enforcement.
Put that gun down
right now!
No!
Look, you may get a shot off.
You may even kill
my young friend there.
But then I will
unload on you.
I can't miss from here
and you don't wanna be
dead, now, do you?
You're a cop.
That's right.
Mystery solved, gentlemen,
courtesy of the A-Team--
Whoa! Who the hell are you?!
I just work in the lab.
We're crime scene investigators.
I'm gonna reach in my pocket
and I'm gonna show you my badge.
Lookie here.
See that?
That's legit.
There you go.
Nobody has to get hurt.
Yeah, tell that to Gomez.
Give me that shotgun.
You all cops?
STOKES:
Here you go.
Yeah, yeah, yeah,
good man.
Uh, sir, I think
we can explain
what happened
to your friend.
You see, it looks like
he baited the pipe out back
to lure the raccoons,
filled it with ethylene gas
and then tried to ignite it.
HODGES: Unfortunately,
he didn't realize that
the gas was pooling
at the bottom
so, when he resorted
to other methods...
(chattering)
(gunshot)
It was an accident.
That's Raccoonzilla.
In life, he and Gomez
was locked into a hatred
that surpasseth understanding.
Uh... Raccoonzilla?
Well, that's the meanest,
vilest rodent that ever
strode the planet.
Technically, not a rodent.
What?
You're book-smart.
Gomez...
he was a good man.
You kept to yourself,
but you always had a smile
and a helping hand for others.
You're gonna be missed.
(sighing)
I saw him alive
less than an hour ago.
How in the hell did you boys
get here so fast?
We're off duty.
We came for the ribs.
And the hepatitis.
What are you doing here?
I'm the handyman.
Well, I was the handyman.
I'm the night watchman now.
Do you have a car?
Uh-uh, no.
A buddy dropped me off.
(car approaching)
Somebody's coming.
That'd be Shirley,
Harry's wife.
Where is Harry anyway?
I'd better let
Shirley tell you.
(tires screeching, crashing)
(sighing)
Damn it all to hell!
Who put that pig there?
Who are these assclowns?
Gomez was an artist.
He was a genius with
the flesh of a pig.
Kept all his
recipes locked up secret
inside his head.
Now, why did you have to go do
that to yourself, you dumbass?
Now we are never gonna
get this place reopened.
You can always
hire another chef.
No...
No one cooks swine
like Gomez did.
He's the heartbeat
of this place.
I thought Harry was.
He was nothing
but the front man.
Yeah, where is Harry?
Bastard cleared out
the accounts,
took off
six months ago.
A month later,
Board of Health shut us down.
Wouldn't surprise me
if Harry had something
to do with that, too.
If I ever catch up to him,
I'm gonna wring his ass dry.
At least I've got
the martini olives.
So, Greg says
that the car is toast.
And reeking of alcohol.
I think that this is the same
broad that ran us off the road.
Yeah, that's what
we just said.
All right, we gotta find a way
to get some backup out here.
Hey, is there not a working
phone in here anywhere?
No.
There's a ham radio
buried in the back.
Keep an eye on her.
(device beeps)
That broken needle
in the victim's arm
contained ketamine.
Party drug.
Prelim tox
on the victim
shows no traces of ketamine
in her system.
Maybe the party
hadn't gotten started.
According to your measurements,
the fragment we extracted
from the victim
was part of a 16-gauge needle.
Right.
The only needles we found
at Bernard Higgins' house
were 31-gauge.
He could've had
a different kit
for his recreational stuff.
What about this bloody
piece of metal
that was found on the floor
under the recliner?
It's high-grade
stainless steel,
probably from a hand tool.
Maybe scissors
or a pair of snips.
I'm running the blood for DNA.
Well, if it comes
back the vic's,
Bernard's got a serious problem.
You have to believe me.
I would never hurt Lily.
We, we loved each other.
(sighs)
I wouldn't expect
a man like you to understand
how this petite,
exquisite creature
could love a man like me,
but I...
Our hearts touched.
She used to call me...
(speaking Mandarin)
It's Mandarin
for "bountiful panda."
Sounds a lot sexier in Mandarin.
Listen,
I'm just not seeing it that way.
In fact, I think she came
to tell you that it was over.
She was tired
of banging Sasquatch.
So you kind of
got all jammed up.
You roughed her up.
You roofed her
with ketamine.
That didn't work.
She ran away.
She called 911.
So you had to kill her.
You've got it all wrong.
I'm a very sick man.
You have to
believe me...
(snoring)
Cut the crap, Bernie.
Come on.
Sorry.
I'm a narcoleptic.
It's a very
serious disease.
But it never stopped me from
making a success of myself.
When I'm under stress,
it gets worse.
Tell me about
the beautiful friend Lily.
She comes to Vegas once
in a while on a layover.
Oh.
She was an international
flight attendant.
And, yes, all right,
I would pay her expenses
when she was in town.
Show her a good time...
(snoring)
You know, Bernie...
you're beginning to try
my patience a little bit.
Come on.
(bangs loudly)
Bernie.
Stick with me now.
Call my doctor if you don't
believe me, all right?
I can't sleep.
I just drop off when
I'm under... stre...
Bernie.
Bernie!
Hey. Bountiful!
Bountiful Panda...
Uh-oh.
Ooh.
There's a radio
here somewhere.
I know that, uh...
Lift it up...
(straining):
Ah. Here.
Be careful.
(imitates mouse squeaking)
(chuckles)
Oh, that's a...
That's just
a walk-in.
No radio in there.
I-I wouldn't go in there,
if I was you.
You don't move, Slick.
I mean it. Just freeze.
I'm froze.
It's rubber!
(laughing)
Yeah, yeah.
Harry used to make Shirley
give first-timers the tour.
Never failed to scare
the crap out of them.
Should've seen
the look on your face.
Yeah, you got me.
Eh, that's the kind
of guy Harry was.
Always good
for a laugh.
Yeah, let's find that radio.
You think I don't know what
you see when you look at us?
Bunch of ignorant,
drunk crackers.
Shiftless peckerwoods.
Let me tell you something.
We built this place
out of nothing
with our hands and our sweat
and our determination.
Mayor of Vegas
used to eat here.
All right-- if I can't find a
phone, I'm going to make one.
Keep an eye on her.
We had politicians, celebrities,
rubbing up elbows
with the common man.
Some nights, we had eight, ten
limos stacked out up front.
Then Harry took off.
(whispers):
All went to hell.
He didn't care who he hurt.
Are you sure, though,
that I can't fix you
boys one of these?
You know, uh, I could use
a little boys' room.
Yeah. Yeah.
Toilets is all stuffed up.
There's one in the basement.
But you don't want
to use that one, believe me.
There's like, a million
black widow spiders down there.
It's like black widow convention
is what it is.
You know, you just puff up
and die, so...
Use the bushes.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
What am I supposed to do?
You heard Greg.
Keep an eye on her.
You...
are going to drink a man drink.
Just like that.
(chuckles nervously)
Really?
♪ ♪
Moonshine.
(electronic tones
buzz and oscillate)
Hello? Hello?
Is anybody out there?
MAN:
Earthlings, your days
are numbered.
The Imperial Armada
will arrive on...
(crackles, tones fade)
(sighs)
Well, maybe you could fix it.
Well, that depends.
You got any spare vacuum tubes
laying around?
Got a vacuum cleaner.
This place was a gold mine.
That man...
he walked away
with $250,000.
All I got...
was a postcard.
Just to rub it my face in.
(sighs)
"Shirley,
"by the time you read this,
I will be sippin' piña coladas
"on a island
somewheres far away
"with the new love
of my life,
"who is much younger
than you.
"Don't come
looking for me
'cause I'm all gone.
Good-bye. Harry."
You ever hear anything so mean
in all your life?
(sniffling)
No, ma'am.
You're real cute.
You know that?
Now, what'd you say
y'all come out here for again?
It's my birthday.
(gasps)
Well...
why don't you
come over here
and give your auntie
Shirley some sugar?
Oh, (chuckles)
uh, no, I can't.
I'm-I'm engaged...
I'm married, actually.
Uh, I have syphilis.
Perfect. Me, too.
What?
(whimpering)
You ever see a really advanced
case of Crohn's disease?
Only tissue sections
on microscope slides.
Gross.
Oh.
LANGSTON:
Yeah.
It's kind of amazing
he lasted
as long as he did.
Well, he was on heavy doses
of broad-spectrum antibiotics.
It may have helped.
ROBBINS:
C.O.D.'s coronary infarction
with complicating factors
of widely disseminated sepsis.
(device beeps)
(phone rings)
Hello, Catherine.
I found an errant
shoe impression
in Bernard's bathroom.
It doesn't belong to the cops,
and it appears to be
a size 13...
Bernie was a ten.
There was somebody else
in this bathroom.
So Bernie may have been
telling the truth.
I'll let you know
if I find anything else.
All right, thank you.
What's the plural of "appendix"?
"Appendices"?
That's what's at the end
of a book.
"Appendixes" doesn't quite
sound right, does it?
Then "appendixes" it is,
because this is definitely
not right.
This man has two appendixes.
One's healthy;
the other's clearly septic.
Is it possible that
this is a natural condition?
Well, genetically,
I suppose it could happen.
The septic appendix
has been sutured
to the intestine.
He has a scar
in his navel.
It's consistent
with laparoscopic surgery.
There's only one guy
who does this kind of work.
Dr. Jekyll.
He's back.
♪ ♪
It's about time.
Where's Nick and Greg?
Outside.
Wha... come on!
Go fish.
It's rummy.
It's gin rummy.
Forget it.
You think you can
make it work?
Yeah, all we gotta do
is go up the pole
and clip these taps
into the main line.
All right, on three.
One, two, three.
(groans)
HODGES:
So, I, uh, found an
ethylene gas
processing plant
down in the
basement.
Old Slick and Shirley
are running a distillery.
Of course they are.
WOMAN (over phone line):
And I told him,
that's your baby.
I didn't make
that baby by myself,
and I need some money!
Uh, Excuse me.
Uh, this is an emergency.
That's what I told him!
And you're never going to
believe what he said back to me.
That rat...
(dial tone)
(keypad beeping)
(line ringing)
Willows.
Oh, Catherine.
Hey, it's Greg.
You're not going to believe
what happened.
So everything's been called in.
Highway patrol and a coroner
are on their way.
But listen, you two are going to
have to come down to the station
and answer a few
questions, okay?
That's-that's routine.
This should all be
cleared up soon.
It's a good thing, too.
That guy is getting pretty ripe.
I'm sure, he wasn't too good
in real life either, but now...
(sniffing)
I need to wash up.
HODGES:
Hey, see if you can find
an air freshener.
(clattering, glass shattering)
Aah! Oh, my God!
What happened?
Aah!
It's sulfuric acid! Aah!
All right, put your hand
under cold water.
(groaning)
(Andrews groaning
in pain)
Ow! Aah!
Here, here.
The charcoal will
neutralize the acid.
(sighs loudly)
Yeah. Ah.
(Andrews groaning)
ANDREWS:
More. More charcoal!
SANDERS:
Just keep it underwater.
(Andrews groans)
Whoa!
What do we
have here?
Check it out, guys.
Y'all want to tell me
who this is?
Who?
Well, I don't know.
You tell me, Shirley.
I got no idea.
Slick?
I don't know.
(sirens approaching)
You know what?
That's okay.
Just sit tight.
(cocks gun)
We're gonna figure this out.
LANGSTON:
All right, the sutures
had started to dissolve,
which means
that the septic appendix
was inserted into his body
about four to seven days ago.
The blood on
the piece of steel I found
was not Lily's;
it was Bernie's,
and it was most likely from
a laparoscopic scissor.
Dr. Jekyll has moved on
to living victims, Catherine.
He is escalating.
Okay.
Joseph Bigelow,
about two months ago,
was found with his intestines
tied into a bow.
Operated on postmortem.
What does he have in common
with Bernard Higgins?
Joseph Bigelow:
lounge piano player,
homeless.
Bernard Higgins:
self-help real estate guru.
Different ages,
different social circles,
different
physical types.
Nothing leaps to mind.
We'll run DNA
on the septic appendix.
If the donor's in CODIS,
it might give us a lead.
We can check hospital records...
There are almost
200 appendectomies
that are performed
in Las Vegas every month.
If the appendix
was stored
in formaldehyde
and flushed prior to surgery,
it could've been in storage
for years.
Right, which means it could've
come from just about anywhere.
Bernie was a narcoleptic,
the perfect victim for a surgeon
who doesn't want his patients to
know they'd been operated on.
Right.
WILLOWS:
And Jekyll performed
the surgery
in Bernie's home.
All of which suggests
that Jekyll knew him.
But maybe not as well
as he thought.
Bernie was so full of meds
that I suspect
the appendix didn't kill him
as quickly as Jekyll planned.
Well, say Jekyll saw Bernie
somewhere, up and about,
after he was supposed
to be dead.
Wouldn't that piss him off?
And like many serial killers,
it might have compelled him
to finish what he started.
So Jekyll goes back
to the house,
packing ketamine to subdue
Bernie, and he
surprises Lily.
LANGSTON:
She runs. She calls 911.
He chases her,
tries to inject her, but fails.
He hears the sirens,
and he leaves before
he can finish Bernie off.
And all we have of him, maybe,
is a size 13 shoe.
LANGSTON:
Well, if Bernie
and Jekyll
did know each other,
then maybe there's
something that connects them
back at the house.
PHILLIPS:
Poor guy.
SANDERS:
Gomez?
I meant the raccoon.
I got Harry's medical records
and dental X-rays here.
Number three, M.O.L. amalgam.
Number 30, full gold crown.
You know, I'm no
forensic odontologist,
but that's Harry.
You will be missed.
Not by pigs.
Look what we got here.
Gomez has got a record.
SANDERS:
Busted for forgery
in San Antonio 13 years ago.
Jumped bail
while awaiting trial.
Whereabouts unknown.
Until now.
A little help?
(grunting)
Oh! Oh.
Oh, way to go, little guy.
This guy's ribs
are completely missing.
It looks like they were cut
along the sternum
and spine.
The restaurant was closed,
due to a hepatitis outbreak,
a month after
Harry disappeared.
Harry had hepatitis B.
Which has an incubation period
of roughly four weeks.
You know what that means,
don't you?
(man laughing, chattering)
Mmm. I have always
loved Harry's ribs.
Where is Harry tonight?
You know, honey,
I'm not sure
where he got off to.
I'm sure he's here in spirit.
I just can't believe
Harry's dead.
I never killed nobody.
I ain't that kind of woman.
Anyway, I loved the man
until the day he disappeared.
Now, if you ask me...
it was Slick.
Now, why would he
do that?
'Cause... before Harry
came to town, I was...
You was what?
Slick's fiancée.
Oh.
Harry swept me
off my feet.
I am not proud
of what I did.
So you dumped Slick for Harry?
Yes, sir.
I broke Slick's heart.
And then,
after Harry disappeared,
I was in the vulnerable state,
and Slick forgave me.
He took me back, but I think
that he bumped Harry off,
get him out of the way,
so he could have me all
to his self once again.
What man wouldn't?
I'm not one
to cast aspersions,
but Harry and Shirley were
at each other's throats
night and day.
Shirley's what
you might call a, uh, uh, uh...
a first-class bitch on wheels.
She told me she dumped you
and ran off with Harry
and broke your heart.
She said that?
Yeah.
I'm the one kicked
that tramp out,
and she went crawling
on her belly back to Harry.
Oh, she spun her feminine wiles,
but he grew... he grew wise
to her trampy ways.
You know,
I thought he got out
while the getting was good,
but I will bet you
dollars to donuts,
it was that whore
that barbecued his ass.
STOKES:
They both had motive,
and they're both accusing
each other of killing Harry.
So far, we have
no evidence
that suggests either
of them actually did it.
Could be either one
or both,
or-- or-- it could be
somebody else altogether.
(groans) My money is
on someone else altogether.
Hey, Hop-Along.
What do you got there?
A postcard Harry sent Shirley
after he was dead,
which is why I had Mandy
print it-- and get this:
She got a hit for Gomez's
mother, a 60-year-old
truck-stop hooker in Boca Raton.
So I ran the handwriting
through Q.D.
It was an excellent forgery.
It was good enough
to fool Shirley, kite a check
and empty
their bank accounts.
But, wait,
where did you get...
An exemplar of
Harry's handwriting?
From his bank.
Time out. Let me
get this straight.
Gomez, a convicted forger,
wrote the postcard,
sent it
to his mother,
who then mailed it back
to Shirley all the way
from Florida?
Yes! See,
it's a deliberate attempt
to obscure the details
of Harry's death.
See, I think Shirley really
believed Harry ran out on her.
But why?
Why would Gomez...
Kill Harry?
Yeah.
I don't know.
I bet Harry knew
Gomez was on the lam,
and was using it to keep him
under his thumb.
STOKES:
One day Gomez just
got sick and tired of it.
Huh.
You know, this birthday
didn't suck after all.
(laughs)
Oh! Aah!
Ow.
WILLOWS:
We got Bernie's
computers, Rolodex and
personal correspondence.
Everything that we collected
will go into storage, in case...
In case Jekyll
strikes again?
He will, you know.
Well, this is what's
been bugging me.
With Joey Bigelow,
Jekyll took
the man's bow tie
and then left another
bow tie, so to speak,
inside his body.
But with Bernie, Jekyll
gave him another appendix.
I'm just wondering,
what did he take?