NARRATOR (on TV):
...primarily on medium-
to large-size rodents.
(lock beeps,
buzzes, clicks)
...they will generally eat
any meat that is available...
(loud slurping)
(narration continues
on TV as wolves howl)
(elevator bell dings,
doors open)
(laughter, whooping,
hooting)
MAN:
I can't believe that, man.
(nature documentary
continues indistinctly on TV)
(slot machines beeping)
NARRATOR:
...a wolf's feeding requirements
is 1.5 tons of meat.
(wolf howls on TV,
then narration continues)
(gasping)
Oh, my God.
Oh, man. Oh, man.
Security, we've got an emergency
in the-the west garden.
Send help, please. Hurry.
My supervisor's, uh, going
through all the video feeds.
If we got her face
on one of our cameras,
uh, you guys
are going to have it.
You better pray
that she doesn't
have a family that's
going to sue you
and this whole joint
for gross negligence.
Take a hike.
Go with him.
LANGSTON (recorded):
Hello, this is Dr. Langston.
Leave a message.
Yeah, hey, Ray.
It's Jim Brass.
Weren't you supposed to be here
at my 420 about an hour ago?
Where the hell are you?
Have you seen
this woman, sir?
No, I haven't.
How about you?
Have you seen this woman?
No.
How about you, ladies?
Hey, big fella.
You want to party?
I'm looking for this woman.
Her name is Madeline Briggs.
Cop.
I'm not a cop.
I'm not here
to arrest anyone.
I just want to know if you've
seen this woman.
I seen lots of people.
What about her?
Have you seen her?
Sorry. She's too pretty
to be a track ho.
Um, you think you could
spare some frog skins?
I ain't eaten
since yesterday.
That's a pretty bad
rash you have.
I work at a clinic.
(siren chirps)
It's not too far from here.
If you want to come over
and have that looked at...
Dr. Ray.
Yeah?
You got your phone?
Yeah, yeah. Right here.
Did you forget
how to use it?
You were nonresponsive.
I thought you were
in trouble, man.
Don't scare me like that.
I'm sorry.
That's okay, but if you
really want to hide out,
you gotta ditch
the department cell.
They all have GPS.
What are you
doing out here?
That's what I'm
doing out here.
STOKES:
Madeline Briggs?
LANGSTON:
Madeline Briggs, yeah.
STOKES:
You been back for ten days.
Is this what you've
been doing every night?
I thought the trail went cold
in New York.
LANGSTON:
It did.
This picture was taken a week
ago at Pecos Bill Casino.
Security trespassed her off
the property for soliciting.
She's here, Nick.
She's hooking.
Have you been
in contact with her mother?
Not since New York,
but I told this woman
I would do everything
I could to find her daughter.
So... here I am.
All right, tell you what.
Let's take care
of the call-out first.
Then after shift, hey, I'll
come back out here with you.
We'll pass out some pictures
together, okay?
Okay.
Okay. Come on.
(siren whoops)
Okay, boys,
what's happening?
I mean, you know...
I don't know.
Is everybody moving
in slow-motion?
The coroner's
not even here yet.
Sorry. We, uh, we got
held up. What's going on?
BRASS:
We got a dead woman,
no I.D. in her purse,
$40 in cash,
half a dozen condoms, a few
roofies, and some baby wipes.
What does that tell you?
Standard hooker tool kit.
$20 for cab fare, $20 for the
bartender to look the other way.
Which means she probably
hasn't tricked yet.
Well, it looks like
word's already gotten
out on the ho-vine.
The "ho-vine"?
Yeah, you know,
when the hookers get wind
the cops are here,
they start texting
each other like mad
and then they, they book out
of here like a shot.
So I'm going to go
catch up with them,
see if I can get
some information.
I'm out.
All right.
Okay.
Throat is cut clean, linear.
My guess would be
a straight razor
severed the common carotid.
There're a lot of ways
in and out of here.
Killer could have come
from any direction.
Arterial spurt like this,
usually they at least get
some blood on their shoes.
I don't see
any tread marks.
PHILLIPS:
Hey, guys.
I'm so sorry I'm late.
I was on that biker shoot-out
up in Pahrump.
Lots of gurney work.
It's all right, David.
Whoa!
This is Dede Chase.
Who?
Dede Chase. She's the, uh,
meteorologist on Channel 27
in Barstow.
You sure about that?
Definitely.
Why do you watch the weather
in Barstow?
Dede always made me laugh.
She was kind of
daffy, you know?
What's a weather girl
from Barstow doing
turning tricks in Las Vegas?
These days...
seems like everybody
has a second job.
Captioning sponsored by
CBS, C.S.I. PRODUCTIONS,
and
TOYOTA. Moving Forward.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
SANDERS: Took a lot of makeup
to cover these bruises.
I collected the SAE kit.
There were vaginal abrasions
at 3:00 and 4:00 to 8:00,
consistent with
violent sexual activity.
And the wet mount
was negative,
so no DNA on whoever
she was with.
Lots of purplish-blue
contusions.
Somebody worked her over
pretty good,
most likely
within the last day or two.
Tat is still fresh, too.
Skin's still inflamed.
Ink can't be more
than 48 hours old.
Guys, take a look at this.
Oh, we have a fabulous weekend
ahead of us
with highs in the upper 70s,
lows in the mid-40s, though,
so bring a jacket
if you'll be staying out late.
I know I will be.
That's your high desert weather.
I'm Dede Kase. Chase.
D... Dede Chase.
Wow, of all the things to screw
up, I choose my own name.
I'm Dede... Chase.
(on video):
I think.
I'm sorry,
but I don't believe
Dede was a hooker.
Maybe she just liked things
a little dangerous.
WILLOWS: Well, certainly
wouldn't be the first
time a good girl
starts looking for love
in all the wrong places.
There is blood
on this earring.
But I only saw blood on
that side of her face.
Well, straight razors
are hard to handle.
People cut themselves
with them all the time.
So, this blood could
be the killer's.
Mmm. Swab it.
LANGSTON: There's no image
of the killer.
The camera
is completely blocked.
Can we see how
she got there?
Yes.
Tangiers surveillance
was very cooperative.
STOKES:
We know who that is?
Now, don't
get excited.
He's on surveillance
playing roulette
at the time of the murder.
He's a hotel guest.
Brass took his
statement.
He said he picked
the girl up at the bar,
they went upstairs,
and she split.
Now, this is
the earliest
we can put Dede Chase
in the hotel.
Okay...
so she meets a guy in the bar,
they head up to his room.
Right. There's no sign
of violence, no argument,
nothing inconsistent with
a woman out for a fling.
That elevator is in
the south tower.
She came down
the elevator
in the north tower.
Means she ran
all the way across the hotel
just to leave?
But if she got
cold feet,
why not just take
the next car down?
That's a good question.
You know, maybe
this pickup in the
bar was a cover.
Maybe she was running
from somebody.
Somebody who was already
down there waiting for her.
If you're going to have me
keep doing Archie's job,
I'm going to
need a raise.
Let me know
what Ecklie says to that.
I was hoping you'd ask,
Herr Supervisor.
Yeah, well, it's
good to, uh...
it's good to
hope for things.
Here's the dump
on your vic's cell phone.
In the three days
prior to her death,
she received 28 phone
calls from a cell phone
out of Barstow, registered
to one Brett McDowell.
I wonder if he's
the jealous, violent type.
Well, shouldn't be hard
to find out.
I trapped his plastic.
His credit card was just run
at the Four Kings.
He's in town.
Enjoying your time in Vegas,
Mr. McDowell?
Uh, yeah, I guess.
What is this about?
What's your relationship
to Dede Chase?
We're colleagues.
I'm her producer.
Were you banging her?
(scoffs)
Excuse me?
Listen to this.
Dede, damn it,
you do not call my house.
You do it ever again,
and I promise you
there will be consequences.
There's a lot more
like this on this tape.
Now, I see that you've, uh,
taken off
your wedding ring
recently.
So, you're married.
Does your wife know
about these phone calls?
Okay. Okay.
Look, uh, Dede and I
were having an affair.
That's a good place to start.
We came to Vegas to
resolve a few issues.
She wanted me to
get a divorce,
and, you know, I couldn't
afford that, so...
When was the last time
you saw her?
Three nights ago.
Where was that?
On the street.
DEDE: Yeah.
BRETT: Yeah? Great.
This is what I want.
I want you out now.
Oh! Well, why don't you
just go to hell!
Just go to hell
while you're at it!
Why don't you just do that?
(engine revving)
She told me to go to hell,
so I drove back to Barstow.
So, you left her
on a street corner in
a strange town, all by herself?
That's why I came back.
I got worried, you know.
She didn't show up to work,
and she wasn't returning
any of my calls.
Well, she had a good reason.
You thought she
was going to make good
on her threat
and send your marriage
and half your assets
down the toilet,
so you decided
to cut your losses
along with her throat--
is that what you did?
I would never do anything
like that. I swear.
I'm going to need
your DNA.
I'm going to need a list
of all the people
you met when you were here
and all the places
you went.
That means bars,
restaurants, hotels,
tattoo parlors, clubs.
Tattoo parlors?
What are you talking about?
Well, there is some evidence
that she got a tattoo
in the last two days.
She hated tattoos.
She thought they made women
look cheap.
Ray.
Yeah?
I think you need
to see this.
What is it?
The DNA from the blood
on the weather girl's earring--
it wasn't hers,
it wasn't Brett McDowell's.
It's Madeline Briggs.
Okay, Madeline Briggs and Dede
Chase-- what's the connection?
Madeline Briggs fell prey
to an interstate
human trafficking ring.
Took her from Miami
to New York
to Las Vegas,
where she was probably forced
into prostitution.
SANDERS:
Her blood was found
on an earring worn
by Dede Chase,
a TV weather girl
from Barstow.
Who ended up with
her throat slit
in the Tangiers
garden,
sporting a new tattoo associated
with known prostitutes.
So, how did she cross
paths with Madeline?
Well, you said
that the earring
belonged to Madeline, right?
Right.
Well, if she
and Dede
were sharing jewelry,
it suggests they
were living together.
So, maybe they
had the same pimp.
Possibly, but the Vice tattoo
database didn't I.D. the pimp.
What's today's date?
The 15th.
Why?
I think I know
where we can find a lot
of pimps tonight.
(hip-hop playing)
By all means, LVPD,
feel free to look around.
But we ain't got none
of them real-life,
lawbreaking kind of pimps
in here.
This here
is DJ Tall-K's PlayerCon.
No, right, I understand.
This is, uh--
technically speaking--
just an elaborate costume party.
WOMAN (over P.A.):
...peoples, it's my honor
to present the Golden Pimp Award
to DJ Slickbone!
(crowd whistling, applauding)
All right, y'all, give it up
for Daddy of the Year!
SLICKBONE: Winning the Golden
Pimp as Daddy of the Year,
is a honor for DJ Slickbone,
'cause pimping ain't just
about sex and bling.
It's about standing up
to The Man
and shaking off
that slave mentality.
Touch.
(hip-hop playing)
Nah, baby, baby, listen.
See, I'm what you call...
(clears throat)
a life improvement coach.
It ain't all
about business with me.
I love my wifeys.
Back in my
dancing days,
pimps would come into
the club to recruit.
They just have a gift
for sniffing out the
damaged and needy.
That's what it's
all about: love.
And I'm getting
a vibe from you
that you haven't
always got enough,
especially from
your father.
Am I right?
Mm-hmm.
♪ ♪
Americans
are so puritanical.
You need to open your mind.
This is a Dionysian festival,
a celebration of life
that stretches back
thousands of years.
The ancient Greeks
greeted the spring...
Well, we talked to
a few of the girls
with the heart and
diamond tattoos,
but nobody
knows nothin'
about pimps or hos
in this place.
Well, we could just haul
the whole lot of them in
for questioning.
BRASS:
No, that won't work.
These girls are used
to being rousted,
plus we have
no leverage.
I don't know-- maybe we do.
I've got an idea.
That's one of our
tattoo ladies.
Let's go talk to that
girl onstage, Jim.
Las Vegas Police, ma'am.
We have reason
to believe that you
are holding
a controlled substance.
Oh, no, not me, sir.
(chuckles)
STOKES:
You know what I love
about science?
It doesn't lie.
Hey, I earned that.
I don't mind
paying a ho-tax
on a straight-up bust,
but this is bogus.
Look at that--
positive for cocaine.
BRASS:
I guess this means
you're under arrest.
Come with us.
Hello, Mrs. Briggs.
Why didn't you let me know
that Madeline
had been photographed
in one of your casinos?
Mrs. Briggs, what
are you doing here?
You said you would let me know
if there were any developments.
Do... Do you think I'm just
sitting at home
waiting by the phone?
I have been on every
law enforcement Web site
and Listserv across the country.
I know how to network.
I understand, and I apologize.
I should have let you know.
We have some evidence
that Madeline
was in Las Vegas.
It was about a week ago.
It may no longer be the
case, you understand?
This is not something that
you can pin your hopes to.
Okay, just don't decide
what information
I am capable of handling,
all right?
She's...
She's with a cop.
They would have
let her call me.
Why didn't she call me?
I would have come.
I would have...
brought her back home.
Oh, God,
I don't care what she's done.
I just want
to bring my Maddy home.
This was recorded at the
Clark County Detention Center
about an hour ago.
Go ahead and play it.
WOMAN:
I'm so, so sorry
to bug you, Daddy.
It's just, I'm really scared.
MAN:
Bitch, I told you never
to call me from in there.
They hear everything we say.
They said that my money
tested positive for coke.
They said that
that means hard time.
Every bill in America
has cocaine on it.
Stupid bitch!
(click, dial tone)
So, did you trace the call?
(cell phone beeping)
It went to a disposable cell.
There was no address.
Someone just came in here
to post
Diane Jasper's bail.
Oh. Daddy sent someone
to bring wifey home.
Must really love her.
(camera shutter clicking)
SANDERS (over radio):
The woman who posted bail
is Susan Samuels.
Career prostitute.
Busts for narcotics
and solicitation
spanning over three decades,
but nothing recent.
The house belongs to her.
She has a son, Anthony, 28.
No criminal record.
And, apart from a brief stint
in the food service industry,
no employment history, either.
Best guess is mom retired
and left Anthony
the family business.
We need to get into that house.
I know.
LANGSTON:
Any judges owe you favors, Jim?
BRASS:
Everybody owes me a favor.
But we gotta sit
on this place
until we can get enough probable
cause for a warrant.
SANDERS:
I think I've got something.
He's wearing
Madeline Briggs' earring.
OFFICER:
You! Get up!
Stand up!
Las Vegas Police!
Remain calm.
We have a warrant to
search the premises.
OFFICER:
Put the bottle down.
All right,yo, yo, yo, yo.
Let me see your hands!
Get 'em up!
Everybody be cool, okay?
This is my mom's house.
I'm just visiting.
OFFICER: Clear!
You gonna let me
put my shirt on?
No.
No? That's what's up?
Put your hands up.
(woman moaning and groaning)
We need the paramedics
in here.
We have an injured woman
on the first floor.
Can you say
your name?
Diane.
LANGSTON:
We're looking for this woman.
Her name is
Madeline Briggs.
Now, if any of you
have seen her,
we want to know.
It might make things
easier on you.
That's right, ladies.
You help out the cops
in any way you can.
OFFICER:
Get back in line!
(dog barking in distance)
♪ ♪
(camera shutter clicking)
You know, you and I have
a lot more in common
than you may think.
Both of us are in the
family business, right?
I mean, look at me,
my uncle was a cop,
my older brother became a cop
and then me.
If I were in your family,
I'd be a sorry-ass
sleazeball pimp, like you.
I'm not a pimp.
Oh, come on, playa, you live
with a bunch of prostitutes.
Hey, playa,
that's just who I am.
I like bangin'
strippers and whores.
You like to beat
them up, too, right?
Like Diane Jasper.
I had nothing
to do with that.
Oh, come on...
Them other bitches did it,
man, they crazy.
They always doing
crap like that.
Your fingerprints are all over
the baseball bat.
We got a lot of
goodies on you, man.
You know what we found
in your barbecue?
67 G's in cash!
You got 13 G's
in chips in there.
I mean, there goes
the defense fund.
We also found
Dede Chase's driver's license.
How did that get in there?
Dede partied with my girls
for a couple days.
Oh, yeah.
Asked me to hold on
to her valuables
while she went clubbing.
Did she also ask you
to beat her, rape her
and slit her throat?
Hey, hey, hey, hey, whoa.
Huh?
I was at Tall-K's PlayerCon
the night she got killed,
a'ight?
A lot of people saw me.
They saw you
wearing an earring
that belonged to
Madeline Briggs.
She one of your girls?
Nah...
I, uh...
I think Mom brought her by.
You know, Mom's always
bringing in strays.
They crash for a couple days
and then they move on.
They give me stuff.
Do you know where she is?
Okay, let me tell you something.
If that is her blood
in your place,
you're in such
deep trouble.
Give me a lawyer.
WILLOWS:
Diane...
Diane, we need your help.
No.
Don't want more trouble.
We want to put
Anthony Samuels away
so he can't hurt you
or anybody else ever again.
My fault.
I shouldn't have
called from jail.
Now, I have to earn
back my hair.
How am I gonna earn like this?
Diane,
you don't have to.
We're gonna help you
get out of the game.
You can go back to school.
You can get a straight job.
Will you help Anthony, too?
Diane.
Anthony's a sociopath.
We believe that
he murdered Dede Chase.
He'd never do
anything like that.
You don't know him.
Diane,
he almost killed you.
Anthony risked his life for me.
That Russian could've put him
in a hole in the desert.
That Russian has a lot
of holes for people
who cross him,
but Anthony didn't care.
He fought for me!
Okay, who's the Russian?
Before you joined
Anthony's family,
did you work for somebody else?
No, I was solo.
I was a renegade.
Please go.
Let me see your tattoo.
Don't touch me!
Nurse, nurse!
Get away!
Nurse!
Get away from me!
I don't want you in here!
Get out of here!
Get out of here.
You're messing everything up.
Anthony...
He loves me.
Thanks.
Nick.
Help me roll her over.
This tattoo,
it's larger than the ones
on Anthony's
other girls.
Yeah, what's that tell you?
Usually, when a girl
leaves her pimp,
the new daddy gets rid of
the old one's brand.
Either with, I don't know,
a hot iron
or battery acid
or a cheese grater.
There's no evidence of
anything like that here.
That's right.
Which makes me believe that
Anthony just covered it up.
Since tattoo inks
vary among artists,
they should fluoresce
differently under different
wavelengths of light.
You know...
pimps treat these girls
like livestock.
Back in the Old West,
if another rancher
stole another man's cattle
and tried to rebrand them,
it'd start a range war.
SIMMS: The samples that you took
from these satellite stains
came from one contributor.
Madeline Briggs.
Yeah, it's exactly
what you thought.
But then this large
stain right here,
it was actually from
two contributors,
so, I subtracted out
Madeline's profile from the mix,
and I got this.
13 alleles in common.
That's a parent-child
relationship.
CSI New York discovered
that Madeline was pregnant.
That blood is from
a miscarriage?
Anthony Samuels buys Madeline
from the Miami-New York
traffickers.
According to Vice,
the going price
is ten grand.
That's a serious investment.
Then he discovers
she's pregnant.
He realizes she's not going to
make him a lot of money
in that condition.
So he feels ripped off.
And then he
takes it out on her.
Do you think she
could've survived?
The bloodstain on the mattress
is consistent with about
a pint of blood.
The covers were replaced.
There's no way to know how
much blood was really there.
There's just no way to tell.
BRASS:
So, we matched
the butterfly tattoo
to about a dozen prostitutes
in town,
all of whom receive
regular visits from that guy.
Dimitri Sadesky.
Diane's scary Russian.
And Vice thinks
he's taking a piece
of their action.
You know where
to find him?
Yeah, but you
won't believe it.
SADESKY:
Do we not all harbor
covert passions
that society tells us
is inappropriate?
See?
Shana knows what
I'm talking about.
It's facile to dismiss
a middle-aged literature
professor as a deviant
for deflowering...
a 12-year-old nymphette.
I mean, is he really so
different from the rest of us?
Are you sure you want to learn
about Nabokov from a pimp, miss?
SADESKY:
More unsupported accusations
from LVPD Vice.
It sounds like a
bad TV show, huh?
Oh, I don't know
anything about that.
I'm a Homicide detective.
Okay, everybody.
Class dismissed.
BRASS:
Thank you.
So, Professor, you
recognize these girls?
Diane Jasper, used
to wear your brand
until she was rustled
by Anthony Samuels.
I think you have me
confused with someone else.
So, how's it work
in the pimp world, huh?
To discourage poaching,
if he takes one of your girls,
you take one of his?
I'm sure I don't know,
but I wonder,
what has become of loyalty, hmm?
An organization invests time
and money training an employee,
and the moment they get
the better offer, they bolt.
How are we ever going to
dig our way
out of this recession
with work ethic like this, huh?
That's very poetic,
but it's not an answer.
Hey...
This is my car.
What are you doing
with my car?
This is my car!
Hey!
I want to see your warrant.
This vehicle is
parked in plain view
in a public area, sir.
We don't need a warrant.
Well... that's
a nice car, Dimitri.
You know, Vice told me
that five years ago,
you were handing out flyers
outside a strip club.
Now here you are
living like a king
up in 10,000 square feet
in Sunrise Mountain.
That's pretty good
for an old Soviet lit professor
who came to this country
with his hat in his hand.
Wouldn't you say, Ray?
I embraced
the entrepreneurial spirit
that is the American Dream.
Perhaps you've heard of this.
You been doing
any off-roading
in the desert lately,
Mr. Sadesky?
Sometimes I drive up there
to-to collect butterflies.
Yeah, and put young girls
into holes
in the ground.
SADESKY:
What are you doing?
What is this?
This?
Geiger counter.
You know, like the one
used at Chernobyl.
(imitates accent):
Perhaps you've heard of this.
Let me share
something with you.
Something I have
learned about women.
Inside, they're all whores.
They all love to hear
the things that
they want to believe.
That they are so beautiful,
so fascinating.
So special that they deserve
the best of everything--
the finest clothes, champagne,
and jewels-- that money can buy.
And you know how you get
the whore to emerge, huh?
(counter clicking)
You tell her
there's an easy way
to get all of this,
and watch her lick her lips
and ask you how.
These levels are consistent
with residue
on a dismembered leg we found
in Miami, with your butterfly
tattoo on it.
We're going to impound
your vehicle, Mr. Sadesky.
Don't worry.
We'll give you a ride.
LANGSTON:
Nick.
Yeah?
We're holding Dimitri,
but he's already lawyered up.
Okay, so we gotta find something
that connects him to Dede Chase.
Or Madeline Briggs.
Or both.
All right.
(computer blipping)
♪ ♪
(spray hissing)
WILLOWS:
We found the purse
in Anthony's house
along with your clothes.
You had it
at the Tangiers
the night that
Dede Chase was killed.
And security footage...
confirms that you
were following her.
BRASS:
If the DNA on that blood
comes back Dede's,
you're all wrapped up
in murder one.
So, if Anthony Samuels
forced you
to participate in this murder
in any way,
now is the time
to tell us, okay?
Knew I should've dumped
that purse.
I just couldn't.
It was the first thing
that Anthony gave me
when we were dating.
Dating?
Yeah, he courted me.
When I was working for Dimitri.
Said that he loved me.
He'd write me these
little poems.
Said he was going to marry me.
So, that's why you left
Dimitri?
He said that the other wifeys
would be working for us.
And he was saving up so me
and him could retire in Hawaii
and raise a family.
That all changed the night
we picked up Dede.
Anthony needed another wifey
to up the cash flow.
DIANE:
Hey, honey.
You look lost.
Do you want a ride?
It's okay.
Okay.
(laughs)
DEDE:
Thanks.
I'm staying
at the Four Kings.
I really appreciate this.
Took a couple of days,
but he wore her down.
Take it like a ho.
(Anthony moans)
You are one...
dynamite piece of ass.
Matter of fact, I'm
about to make you
my bottom bitch.
These other wifeys,
they're gonna work for us.
A couple years,
we'll retire to Hawaii.
You're gonna love it.
Sounds great to me, Daddy.
He thought he
broke her.
That girl was cagey.
She pretended to dig it.
And Anthony...
Anthony fell for it.
Tell me what happened
at the Tangiers.
WILLOWS: That was the first
night that she was to earn?
Wasn't it? And you were there
to turn her out?
Yeah.
And when her trick
came down alone
five minutes after they went up,
I knew she was gonna bolt.
Where do you think
you're going?
Where do you think?
You can't leave Anthony.
Come with me.
I... I-I can't.
You want to be
with him?
Are you insane?
What the hell are
you thinking?
(gasps, screams)
Anthony told me he loved me.
Nobody had ever said that
to me before.
It seems an odd place
to look for butterflies.
But a great place
to hide a body.
We have DNA from the blood
we found
in the Russian's SUV.
It is Madeline's.
(slow, rhythmic beeping)
(rapid beeping)
♪ ♪
LANGSTON:
We found four mummified
female DB's
at a location that was in the
GPS memory of your vehicle.
The palm on one of the bodies
had a cigarette burn.
Wasn't enough
for you to kill them.
You had to
torture them, too, right?
But the desert preserves
DNA, Dimitri.
My client has information
the D.A. and the FBI
would be very interested in.
And he's willing to cooperate.
Well, if he wants to avoid
the death penalty,
then your client better do that.
You can start by
telling me what you did
with Madeline Briggs,
Dimitri.
These bodies we found have been
in the ground a long time.
Too long to be Madeline.
The girl meant something
to you, huh?
Dimitri...
I can see that.
Fine.
As a token of
my good faith,
I'll tell you what
I did with her.
I'm listening.
Nothing.
Her blood was in your car.
How do you explain that?
She was a peace offering
from Anthony,
in exchange for stealing
Diane from me.
I accepted this.
But... only to save face.
I could see he had destroyed
her commercial value.
She knew nothing of me
or my operation,
so, easiest thing to do...
was let her go.
So... I'm not such a
hard-hearted guy, huh?
(chuckles)
WILLOWS:
Well, well, well.
HODGES:
It's not Christmas yet.
Aren't we lucky?
What is this stuff?
Uh, Langston sent us
some souvenirs
from Miami
and New York.
Oh.
WILLOWS:
I was kind of hoping for
a little somethin'-somethin'
from Bergdorf's.
SIMMS:
I love this.
How do I look?
SANDERS:
Bitchin'.
Oh... ridiculous.
LANGSTON: The names Dimitri
gave us are going to help Miami
and New York roll up most of
the human trafficking syndicate.
Oh, so we did some good.
Not good enough.
Look, if Dimitri
really set her free,
then why didn't
Madeline go home?
Well, a lot of girls that try
to get out of that life
come out feeling so
degraded and ashamed,
they feel like, sometimes,
nobody will ever
want them again.
You know what I mean?
Yeah.
What are you doing?
Using the ho-vine.
The phones we recovered
in Anthony's house
all had the same numbers
programmed into them.
He must've given one of
them to each of his girls.
You think Madeline
still has hers.
It's good to hope
for things, right?
♪ ♪
Madeline.
(voice breaking):
You're Langston?
Yes.
How can I go back after
everything that's happened?
(sniffling)
All you have to do is...
walk through the door.
Come on.
(crying)
It's all right.