(crickets chirping)
(yelling)
(yelling wildly)
Hiker spotted the body
from that rise just after dawn.
(camera shutter clicks)
LANGSTON:
Whoever did this
put a lot more effort
into the killing
than the concealing.
Looks like it might have been
spur-of-the-moment.
Or he didn't care if the victim
was found, either way.
Go ahead and roll him, Dave.
STOKES:
If the killer's smart,
he's already out of town,
laying
on a beach somewhere,
drinking a margarita.
LANGSTON:
Well, let's hope he's not
all that smart, then.
Any I.D. on him?
PHILLIPS:
Mmm. There's no wallet,
there's no cell, and
there's no keys,
unless you want to count
this bicycle lock thingy.
Body is just going
into rigor.
LANGSTON:
So, probably killed
late last night.
STOKES:
Those look like
defensive wounds
on the wrist.
LANGSTON:
Multiple head wounds,
any of which
could have been fatal.
STOKES:
He pissed somebody off,
didn't he?
What's the angriest
you've ever been?
I've been mad enough
to kill somebody.
Didn't do it.
What about you?
High threshold.
Short fuse.
PHILLIPS:
Me, too. In high school,
I vented my frustrations
by devising elaborate tortures
for my classmates.
In comic book form, of course.
Well, whether the killer
woke up this morning intending
to beat this guy to death
or not,
right now, he's a new man
with a new plan.
And a big, fat secret.
LANGSTON:
Secrets are hard to keep.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
(coyote yips, howls)
(camera shutter clicking)
Tire tracks head
out to the road.
They're fresh and deep.
Driver must have floored it.
But, then again,
he had a good reason
to be in a hurry.
I have two different sets
of shoe impressions here,
in mud.
It hasn't rained out here
for weeks.
Could be melted ice
from a cooler.
Locals sometimes use these woods
to get drunk,
have target practice.
No, this isn't alcohol.
And he wasn't shot;
he was bludgeoned.
ROBBINS:
Victim's male Caucasian,
five-foot-ten,
155 pounds,
probably in his mid-20s,
with multiple BFTs
to the head and back,
as well as severe
lacerations
to the left wrist.
Lack of hemorrhagic tissue
indicates the wound
is postmortem.
Wound tract: approximately
two centimeters deep,
atypical for a defensive wound.
Which suggests the killer...
...was trying to dig...
something... out.
This looks like
an implantable RFID.
Radio Frequency
Identification chip.
I know. They're used for
tracking inventory at Wal-Mart.
But unless the 13th Amendment
got repealed
while I wasn't looking,
that's not inventory.
Implantable RFIDs
are pretty new.
There's some high-end
nightclubs
that give them to their VIPs
to make it easier for them
to run up a tab.
(chuckling):
Oh, yeah.
Having a chip surgically
implanted in your body
is so much more convenient
than putting a credit card
in your pocket.
Well, not everything I wear out
has pockets.
I'll buy you a purse.
All right.
The chip itself looks intact.
If I can get my hands
on a scanner,
I might be able to tell
who this belongs to.
MAN:
No batteries required.
Just a little movement
in a magnetic field
to energize the circuit,
which transmits a code,
which gets sent
to the access database,
and...
(buzzing and clicking)
(sighs)
Just like magic.
That's impressive.
So, do you have
any other tricks
up your, um, arm?
MAN:
Belinda?
I have those TPS reports...
Jason, this is Paulie Krill,
facilities
management.
Paulie, this
is Jason Devereaux,
our new I.T. guru.
I.T. geek-- it's
okay to say it.
I had an RFID surgically
implanted in my wrist.
It's, uh, practically
the definition.
Did it hurt?
No, it was, uh...
it was a little like
getting a vaccination.
Without the autism.
Actually,
that's anecdotal.
I read in...
I tell most people
that it was a
suicide attempt.
It makes me appear
dark and tormented.
I bet the ladies
love that.
You tell me.
(clearing throat):
Lombard.
Sounds to me like your
computer has a virus.
BELINDA: Oh, that's
what I was afraid of.
Ah, well, come with me.
That's why we call
it the Help Desk.
WOMAN: What?
Sorry.
(beep, buzz)
(door handle clicking)
(beep, buzz,
rattling handle)
(beeping, buzzing)
(groans)
Where the hell
is Devereaux?
I haven't seen him today.
Something wrong?
Yeah.
It's, uh...
Something is, uh...
very wrong.
Come here.
No, come here, you...
you've got something in your,
something
in your hair.
There, there,
there, there...
There.
Got it.
Thank you.
What are you looking at?
A sexual harassment suit.
(raspy, snorting laugh)
You're a very funny guy.
Hey.
Tell, uh, little Jason
that I want that
fixed ASAP.
From now on, this is no longer
the Help Desk.
It's just... the desk.
Thanks.
You're welcome.
You ever think that some people
would be better off dead?
What's gotten into you today?
I don't know.
Whatever it is,
I like it.
So, they say people have
a good side and a bad side.
What's the verdict?
I don't seem to have a bad side.
What do you
have there?
Metal fragment
from my crime scene.
LANGSTON:
Mandy was able to pull
a few small partials
and some smudges,
but, uh...
nothing with enough detail
to run through AFIS.
It's magnetic,
which means it's ferrous,
probably a steel alloy.
Layered steel.
Very high strength.
That fine line pattern
looks like ferning.
HODGES:
Material deformation resulting
from explosive force.
Yeah, possibly.
You see that kind of
thing in a pipe bomb.
Is that what this is from?
I don't know.
(trilling, beeping)
Come on, damn it.
(beeping)
(gasps)
Yes.
You sound happy.
What's going on?
I just got the
vic's name.
Jason Devereaux.
STOKES:
Nice.
I'll track down
his phone records.
He lives at 1120
Marapasa Parkway,
apartment number one.
STOKES: And he drives
a Ford Ranger.
That's consistent with
the tire treads at the scene.
Kill a man, take his car.
Mmm. Bonus.
STOKES:
Man, that's three messages
I've left for
the property manager now.
Maybe he's got
better things to do
than cooperate
with the law.
Wait, wait.
Hold up a sec.
That's the victim's truck
right there.
And trust me...
he was in no condition
to drive it home.
SANDERS:
Key's in the ignition.
Door's unlocked.
I'll check for prints.
Looks like everything's
been wiped clean.
Maybe not everything.
Dispatch, this is
Charlie-Zero-Six Sanders.
We need backup and tow
at 1120 Marapasa Parkway.
DISPATCHER:
Copy that, Charlie-Zero-Six.
Officers are already at
that location, responding 406.
We came in on the other
side of the complex.
That's why we
missed each other.
Regular maid service
entered the apartment
a few hours ago.
Found the place trashed,
called it in.
The unit's
right back here.
Most of the electronics
are gone.
TV was probably too big
to carry out.
Security cable's been cut.
Killer didn't have a key.
It was on the victim's belt.
So, the killer comes back
to the vic's apartment.
Why?
Maybe to get something that
ties him to the murder.
A computer,
from the looks of it.
That suggests that
the killer
had a prior relationship
with the vic--
family, friend, coworker.
Mm-hmm.
Which means this...
is a pretty good place
to start.
Hey!
Everybody shut up!
And stop trying to look busy
for a minute,
and give your attention
down here.
BRASS:
Good afternoon.
I'm, uh, Captain Jim Brass.
I'm a detective
with the Las Vegas
Police Department.
I'm sorry to break up
your day like this,
but I'm here about
Jason Devereaux.
BELINDA:
He's not in yet.
What is this about?
Mr. Devereaux
is the subject of an active
investigation.
I'll be talking to all of you
individually.
These officers will pick up
your contact information.
I promise it won't
take too long.
Thank you in advance
for your cooperation.
(staffers murmuring)
He's a hacker.
Bet it's
a hacker thing.
Probably some high-tech
black market credit card scam.
I read about it
in Wired.
Some people,
you just can't tell.
Well, all I know is the kid
was here yesterday,
he wasn't here today.
And since he didn't
bother calling,
he's also fired,
so you know.
That's the least
of his problems.
LOMBARD:
Well, I got just the
place for you.
You pull the blinds, it's
totally private and quiet.
You can pull out the
rubber hose, nobody
will even know.
You know, I'm curious, uh,
do have you any problems with
disgruntled employees lately?
(scoffs)
No more than usual.
I mean, come on, you know
what we do here.
Yeah, I can read
the sign.
You're a support operations
for the Tangiers.
Which mean we laminate badges,
distribute uniforms,
and issue parking permits.
We are the testicles of the
casino business, my friend.
If you're working here,
it's not 'cause
you want to be.
(camera shutter clicking)
Action figures and anime
for the computer guy.
It's almost a cliché.
Let me guess,
you were a GI Joe man?
No, but... my dad was.
Hey, Nick, we're
finished up here.
Want me to help Barnes?
All right, go ahead.
LANGSTON: Nick, what do
you make of this?
Looks like a long portrait.
They're big on
photo-sharing sites.
Video art.
With a little narcissism.
Well, one's not much
without the other.
So, all electronic data
goes back to the lab.
I'll do the honors.
Yeah, hold on there, Doctor,
I'll save you the hassle.
I've got a drive duplicator
in my truck.
I'll go grab it.
All right.
According to Mr. Devereaux's
phone records,
the two of you called each
other several times last night.
I'm his direct supervisor;
we talk all the time.
Most of the calls were
after 11:00 p.m.
Jason said he was
dealing with some sort
of mail server glitch.
I.T.'s always dealing
with something.
(wry chuckle)
I thought it takes,
like, 48 hours
to report someone missing,
so this can't be about him
not showing up for work.
You seem
more concerned about him
than the rest of
your colleagues.
We're friends.
I just want to know...
He's dead.
I'm going to be informing
the rest of your coworkers,
individually,
about that fact.
Please don't discuss it
with anybody, okay?
(whirring, blipping)
Hmm.
There are virtually no personal
files on his computer.
Yeah, what do you
make of that?
Some people
take their privacy seriously.
STOKES: His files have
to be somewhere.
This thing's set up to remotely
access another machine.
How much you want to
bet it's the laptop
stolen from his apartment?
Killed?
My God,
that's... terrible.
Where were you last night,
Mr. Krill?
Nowhere.
I... I got off work
and went home as usual.
Do you have a wife or anybody
who can verify that?
No. I live alone.
How would you describe your
relationship to Mr. Devereaux?
I don't like your tone,
Detective.
You don't
like my tone?
One of your coworkers
was just killed.
You don't seem to be too upset
by it-- why is that?
I didn't like him.
Jason was always
trying to get people
to do his work for him.
And because he was
good-looking and charming,
I guess they did.
You do your job...
and you work hard.
That's how you get
what you deserve in life.
At least
that's the way I was raised.
Hmm.
Ooh, monoamine
oxidase A.
Ask me anything.
What do you want to know?
What do you know about it?
Kind of a lot.
My research group
in grad school developed
a protocol
to synthesize the gene.
What's the case?
It's just something
I'm working on.
You know, that specific mutation
right there
has actually been linked
to violent behavior.
For example,
there was this Dutch family,
and all the males
in the family
who had that were rapists
and arsonists.
And then mice without
the MAOA gene
all exhibited highly
aggressive behavior.
MAOA deficiency
doesn't make you violent.
I didn't say it did.
Just 'cause something
might happen
doesn't mean it will.
It's genetics,
it's not destiny.
(blipping, chiming)
The vic's laptop
is online there.
That's the victim's
apartment building.
Can you isolate the unit?
Let's see.
His computer was configured
for remote screen access.
So, that means I might
be able to access
the computer directly.
Got him.
That's what's on his machine
right now.
This guy's
a gamer, huh?
Mm-hmm.
But so am I.
Check this.
Laptop cam on.
(computer game
weapons firing)
Okay...
Say cheese, dirtbag.
(camera shutter clicking)
(nervous chuckle)
Look, I-I didn't kill nobody,
I don't know nothing
about nobody
getting killed.
And here you are
with a dead guy's laptop
in your possession.
Okay, yeah, sure,
okay, I can admit to that.
(nervous chuckle)
I-I was heading
outta my crib
and I walked by this apartment.
See, the door was
just wide open.
All this high-end gear in there,
it's just sitting there,
unattended.
Yeah, all locked up
with security cables, right?
Well, well, yeah, that's why I
go back, get the bolt cutters.
You know, what with Christmas
coming up and all.
Yeah.
Write it down.
LANGSTON:
He's nothing.
He's just a random
petty thief.
The killer probably left
the apartment door open
to make it look like a robbery.
Well, Jason Devereaux
had a juvee record.
I had it unsealed.
A lot of antisocial
tendencies in there.
He also did time on a work farm
for peddling Ritalin
in high school.
You think it's a drug thing?
His tox came back positive
for methamphetamine.
Point-oh-two mikes per mil.
That's a party dose.
Maybe.
But it wouldn't be
the first time
that a regular guy with
a steady job threw it all away
for the great taste of meth.
(typing, computer beeps)
Desi?
Lucy?
(chuckles)
You're doing Desorption
Electrospray Ionization--
DESI-- a spray of
electrically charged water
dissolves compounds
in the fingerprints,
which creates a thin film
that gets scattered back
to the mass-spec
identifying what
the suspect touched.
I know how it works.
I'm doing it.
Yes.
But it was a lucid and
entertaining explanation
of the process.
You know, um, I did
process that metal
and there was no unusual
residue on the surface.
Are you expecting to find
something in the prints?
I was at a DEA seminar
last month, uh,
they were discussing
making "one-pot" meth.
You mix the chemicals
in a container
which you leave in the woods
to vent and cure.
But if someone comes along
and disturbs it at the wrong
moment in the reaction...
Kaboom.
So it's a drug thing.
That's what everyone
seems to think.
Homeland Security
was missing out
on a real asset
with Jason Devereaux.
His laptop was loaded
with keyloggers
and corporate spyware set up
to copy e-mails and files
from a dozen people
in his office.
There's gigabytes
of stuff here.
He was spying on
everybody he worked with.
Maybe he read something
he shouldn't have.
Something worth
killing him for.
This isn't
a drug thing.
Traces of RDX
in the fingerprints--
high explosive.
That's disturbing.
Terrorism comes to mind.
It certainly does.
♪ ♪
I know what you're
up to, Paulie.
And I want to help.
What are you talking about?
What are you doing?
I haven't been here long, but
I can see the way things are.
People putting you down,
day after day, in little ways,
making you feel
like you're nothing.
"Hey, Paulie,
you're going to have to
stay late and do inventory."
"Hey, Paulie, we're out of
coffee again, would you mind?"
"Hey, Paulie,
love the shirt."
I know what it feels like
to be on the outside.
And I know
you want to make them pay.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
How did you...
How did you do that?
Your life's an open
book to me, Paulie.
I know what you really
want to do to this place,
deep down in your heart,
when it feels like
Lombard and this job
are grinding you down.
I've got an uncle that works
in the mining business.
I could get a brick of RDX
with one phone call.
No questions asked.
I can make all your dreams
come true, Paulie.
All you gotta do is let me.
Okay, these are
the colleagues whose trust
Jason Devereaux was violating.
Knowing the deep,
dark secrets of your coworkers
is a slippery slope.
There was a time in my life
that would've come in handy.
I used to work alongside
an angel of death, remember?
Hmm.
It's mostly online shopping
and DVD rentals.
I take it the office
firewalls porn?
Don't they all.
STOKES:
But if the victim was poking
into everyone's
private life,
this could've been
an extortion scheme
gone bad, a crime of passion.
Wouldn't explain the
explosives we found
on the metal fragment.
SANDERS:
Archie and I did
global searches for words
like "explosives,"
and unless Mr. Lombard's
recent bout of diarrhea
counts, we struck out.
Brass ran scent dogs
through this whole office.
The only thing found
were traces of RDX
in Jason's cubicle.
Well, his uncle
runs a mining company
and according
to Jason's juvee record,
he enjoyed blowing
things up as a child.
Maybe he was just pursuing
his hobby into adulthood.
LANGSTON: Well, if there's
an explanation in there,
it looks like we're
going to have to find it
the old-fashioned way
and read the lot of them.
Split it up by individual,
starting with the day
of the murder and
work your way back.
Okay.
Oh, hey, George.
Mr. Lombard wanted me
to bring him the new swatches
Oh, yeah.
for the bellman uniforms.
Looking for Ms. Mayfield, but...
Yeah, sure, fine, whatever.
Okay?
Thanks.
(sports broadcast plays
faintly over earpiece)
So, how'd you know this
thing was even in here?
I found it logging inventory
a few months back,
so I contacted
the City Planning...
City Planning Department,
that's right, I remember.
They, uh, they e-mailed you
the building plans.
Yeah.
Okay, coast is clear.
This was an electrical conduit.
It goes about 150 feet
outside the building,
comes up on the other side
of the security fence.
Okay.
Get in.
What?
Go all the way out
and then come back.
You said this was
your exit strategy.
I just want to be sure
that it works.
Go ahead, I'm gonna,
I'm gonna stand guard.
Jason, it's totally
dark in there.
I don't even
have a flashlight.
Hey, there's an app for that.
(sneezing, spitting)
(anxious gasping)
(rapid breathing)
(grunting)
(ringtone blaring,
echoing)
Hello?
Okay, okay.
(ringtone blaring,
echoing)
GEORGE (in distance):
What are you doing down here?
JASON: Oh, hey, there, George!
Good to see you again.
Where's Paulie?
I'm sorry?
You know, I don't know.
He was just here.
I'm calling Lombard!
Whoa!
George, George,
calm down a second!
I don't know-- Paulie's
gonna be back in a second.
Hey, George,
I can explain.
(laughing)
That phone has
outstanding reception.
Wait, that was a joke?
You were joking?
Always expect the unexpected.
Are you kidding me?!
Relax, I'm just
toughening you up.
You're gonna thank me later.
Did you get all the way out?
That conduit isn't
going to do us any good
if you're just counting on
old George to be there...
(blipping,
lock buzzes and clicks)
We don't need him.
You're not authorized
to be in this...
How did you,
how did you...?
Never underestimate the power
of a sexy geek...
with a Flash drive.
I got
all the access codes we need.
LOMBARD:
Right over here,
Ms. Devereaux.
Um...
they said I could
collect my son's things.
Personal effects
only, ma'am.
And write down
whatever you take.
Excuse me, are you
Jason's mom?
I'm Paulie Krill;
my condolences.
You look like you could
use some help.
That'd be nice.
Were you friends with Jase?
Um, work friends mostly.
You didn't really
know him then?
PAULIE:
No, not really.
I always figured things
would turn out bad for him.
Jase was a difficult boy.
High-spirited.
That's rough when
there's no dad around.
Sometimes I think I took
extra shifts at work
so I wouldn't have to go home.
Here you go.
I hope he wasn't
awful to you.
Don't blame yourself.
Ray.
Highway Patrol just
brought this in.
They found it on the side of
the road near Mount Charleston,
about a mile away
from your crime scene.
Metal's consistent with the
exploded fragment you found.
And there's blood on the edge.
Which I sampled
with a high-quality
Lynn-Peavey integra swab
to compare with the vic's.
It could be what made the
impact wound on his back.
It could be our murder weapon.
Whatever it is.
Stokes.
Hey, Nick, it's Wendy.
I got the DNA results for the
semen stain in the victim's car.
Hey.
You okay?
Yeah. Clearly.
Thanks.
You're welcome.
Belinda, I know
you liked Jason.
But he was obviously into
some pretty bad stuff.
Maybe he wasn't as nice
a guy as you think he was.
They never are.
Yeah.
Look, it's about time
to get out of here.
You up for a drink?
(sniffles)
Or ten?
Just us?
Yeah.
It's been a weird day.
What the hell.
Let's make it a weird night.
Sure.
Ms. Mayfield, I need you
to come to the police station.
Why?
Do you mind?
No, he doesn't have...
I already talked with you.
You didn't talk to me about
what your DNA was doing
in the victim's car,
unless you want
to deny sleeping with him.
Go with this officer.
You know what
the weird part of this is,
I mean, at least
from your point of view.
The only reason we have your DNA
in our system is because
you gave it to us
three years ago,
when you filed charges
against your scumbag ex-husband
for domestic abuse.
Believe me, I remember that.
Oh, I'm sure you do.
And I'm not telling you
something you don't know,
but you've got a history
of picking the wrong guy.
I mean, I have statements
from your coworkers.
Jason Devereaux was banging
half the women in your office.
So, what do they say
about a woman scorned?
SANDERS:
We found Jason's Flash drive
in her purse, filled with
passwords, account information,
and RFID access codes
to nearly every secure area
in that building.
That screams
white collar crime to me.
What's the scam?
I mean, what is
there to steal?
That place isn't
exactly a bank.
I don't know, but Jason had
an E-ticket on Pacific Vista
departing for Cabo
tomorrow morning.
What?!
Yeah, so,
unless he just happened
to be planning a vacation...
More like trying
to skip town.
Let's see if anybody else
from his work went with him.
BRASS:
I hear Cabo's very
romantic this time of year.
We were just going away
for the weekend.
No, you were going away
for good.
We have your access codes
on Jason's Flash drive.
I gave him that
so he could reprogram
my boss' access card,
so it wouldn't work.
(buzzing)
Something wrong?
It was a joke.
BRASS:
It was a plan.
You and Jason were cooking up
some scheme in the office,
things went bad,
and one working stiff makes
another worker stiff.
I had a fling with him.
That was it!
I didn't kill him.
The piece that Highway Patrol
brought in is part
of the inside cover
of a Traeger GR-7 jewelry safe.
So Jason and
whoever killed him
were out in the woods
blowing up a safe?
Apparently.
All of which suggests
they were planning
an old-fashioned robbery.
You know that my dad was
a casino boss, right?
Well, every few weeks,
he had to collect the
revenue from all of his
low-end, low-volume operations.
Nickel slots from bars
and mini-marts,
grocery store Keno,
that sort of thing?
We're not talking
small potatoes, either.
Quarter mil, easy,
even on a bad month.
An armored truck would go
around town
making the pickups,
but when they were done,
the bank would be closed.
So, they would drive
to Sam's business office
where he kept a big,
old vault
in a room all by itself.
Sam loved showing it off to me
as the sacks of coins and
bricks of cash went into it.
Anyway, the money would go
into the vault and stay there
until the next morning,
when the armored car guys would
return and take it to the bank.
I think we need to find out
if there's a safe
on the premises.
Oh, hi, there.
I'm David Hodges.
Welcome to Lynn-Peavey
Corporation's
Wonderful World of Forensics.
Today on our show--
the scintillating
science of swabbing.
BRASS (over phone):
I don't think
the girl
had anything to do with it.
I think she's more of a victim
than a killer.
Okay. What about his safe?
No, not yet.
Tangiers Corporate
doesn't want
to talk about how and where
they keep their money
until they get the okay
from their bosses
in New York,
and back East,
they're still in bed,
so I'm working up a warrant.
Thanks, Jim.
You know how to find me.
What are you doing?
Proof of principle.
Mythbusters style.
When you landed on the idea that
there might be a safe involved,
we had Archie and Greg search
Jason's files for the term.
It turns out that
both the victim
and another employee,
Paulie Krill,
had been doing a lot of Web
searches on safecracking.
LANGSTON:
That is a Traeger GR-7
jewelry safe,
same model as the one
that we found evidence of
in the woods.
We bought it from
the one local store
that carries them.
And the last one they sold was
to Paulie Krill.
I take it the fact that
you're both still here means
there's a broadcast out?
Yes.
Paulie Krill is
not at home.
His office is
closed for the night.
In any event,
this safe features what's known
as a glass re-locker.
When someone attempts
to drill the door,
a glass plate
inside the safe breaks,
activating additional
locking bolts,
which render the safe
practically impervious.
(phone chimes)
There's a Traeger GR-17 safe
in the vic's office.
That is the big brother
to this model,
but the physics is the same.
These guys were also renting
heist movies,
among them The Score,
which is not
a bad film.
I liked it.
Safecracker cuts a hole
in the top of the safe,
fills it with water,
and then drops in
a high explosive depth charge.
There was water in
the vic's truck.
LANGSTON:
And mud at the scene.
Water is
an incompressible fluid,
so it transfers the force
of the explosion to the door
before the glass re-locker
can activate.
That was their plan.
(explosion)
That... was... awesome.
(laughs)
Now all we got to do
is hang loose
for a couple of days
until the money comes in,
and then we cash out.
Yo hablo español, mi amigo.
(laughs)
I hope you do, too.
I can't go through with it.
What?
No, no, no, no, no.
No, no, not now.
No, you are not backing out
of this now, man.
Not now.
It wasn't real!
It was just a game.
It was... It was a secret.
Nobody was even supposed
to know about it.
Hey, hey!
For 20 years, all you do
is fill in the space
in that lousy little cubicle,
and still, you somehow manage
to come up with
the perfect plan to rip off
all of the losers
that you work for
that make you feel
like crap day after day.
I give you the thing that
you need to make it all go boom,
and-and you don't want
to go through with it?
No.
I can't. I can't.
Yes, you can, Paul.
For once in your life,
you're actually going
to do something,
something big.
You want this,
I know you do!
I've seen it in your eyes.
Staring at all those things
that you can't get--
money, respect, Belinda.
No!
I don't care!
I'm not doing it.
I can't! That's it!
I am out!
Fine!
You want out, you're out!
I don't need you to carry
this off any more, anyway.
Breathe a word of this
to anyone anywhere,
and I will hunt you down and
put a bullet in your head.
I swear.
Empty space.
That's all you are.
(screaming)
Mr. Krill!
LVPD! Open up!
Paulie, drop it!
Open this door!
Open up!
(beep)
(banging, shouting)
Mr. Krill!
Hey! Don't do it, Paulie!
(sirens wailing
in distance)
(sirens approaching)
(gasps)
(banging on door,
indistinct shouting)
Can't get it open!
Paulie!
(pounding on door)
Get the door open!
Let's go!
GEORGE:
I can't find my card.
Try harder!
Oh, wait.
I found it.
(weak panting)
(groaning)
Call it in.
(grunts)
(gasps)
(panting)
(coughs)
I knew...
it would work.