GARY LEVOX:
Las Vegas, are you ready
for one more?
Let's go!
(audience cheering)
(band playing "Unstoppable"
intro)
♪ Hey... ♪
♪ Oh, oh ♪
♪ So... ♪
♪ So you made
a lot of mistakes ♪
♪ Walk down the road
a little sideways ♪
♪ Cracked a brick
when you hit the wall ♪
♪ Yeah, you've had a pocket
full of regrets ♪
♪ Pull you down faster
than a sunset ♪
♪ Hey, it happens to us all ♪
♪ When the cold, hard rain
just won't quit ♪
♪ And you can't see your way
out of it ♪
♪ You find your faith
has been lost and shaken ♪
♪ You take back
what's been taken ♪
♪ Get on your knees
and dig down deep ♪
♪ You can do what you think
is impossible ♪
♪ Keep on believin',
don't give in ♪
♪ It'll come and make you
whole again ♪
♪ It always will,
it always does ♪
♪ Love is unstoppable ♪
♪ Love... ♪
♪ It can weather any storm ♪
♪ Bring you back to being born ♪
♪ Again ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Helpin' hand ♪
♪ It's a helpin' hand
when you need it most ♪
♪ A lighthouse shinin'
on the coast ♪
♪ That never goes dim ♪
♪ When your heart
is full of doubt ♪
♪ And you think that
there's no way out ♪
♪ You find your faith
has been lost and shaken ♪
(electricity buzzing)
♪ You take back
what's been taken ♪
(electricity crackling)
♪ Get on your knees
and dig down... ♪
Hey, Bucky, get out there.
Get out there.
(shocked murmuring)
♪ Somebody say hey! ♪
AUDIENCE:
Hey!
♪ Oh... ♪
♪ Oh... ♪
♪ Yeah... ♪
♪ Yeah... ♪
♪ Got a man down ♪
♪ Got a man down... ♪
(music continues in background)
Pupils are dilated
but unresponsive.
(distant):
Baby?
Good breath sounds...
Hey.
♪ Say oh... ♪
Jay. Hey, Jay.
Excuse me.
Miss?
Miss, I'm gonna need
you to stand back.
Miss, I told you
to get back.
His pulse rate
is 120 and rising.
We need to get him
to an ER.
(woman gasps)
Okay, you know all our
songs, you go out there.
No.
Come on, Travis.
Come on, give him a bass.
Come on, Travis,
get out there!
Here you go.
♪ Somebody say hey! ♪
♪ Say oh... ♪
♪ Hey, hey ♪
JOE DON:
Looks like Jay's
gonna be okay.
Guy'll do anything
to get off work early.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the oldest living bass tech
in show business,
Mr. Travis Murray.
(audience cheering)
♪ When your heart
is full of doubt ♪
♪ And you think that
there's no way out ♪
♪ You find your faith
has been lost and shaken ♪
♪ You take back
what's been taken ♪
♪ Get on your knees
and dig down deep ♪
♪ You can do what you think
is impossible ♪
♪ Keep on believin',
don't give in ♪
♪ It'll come and make you
whole again ♪
♪ It always will,
it always does ♪
♪ Love is unstoppable... ♪
I was just working
in the garage, man,
and something blew
up in my hand.
You think they can put
my fingers back on?
Well, the good news is,
you brought them with you.
So, what was it
that exploded?
A volcano...
They're not getting my fingers.
Mr. DeMarcus?
Huh?
I need to examine
your injuries.
Okay.
Do you remember
the accident on stage?
No, no.
You received an electrical shock
from your guitar.
No.
May I see your hands?
You can see whatever
you want to.
You're gorgeous.
And you're married.
I'm not married; I'm
not the marrying kind.
You want to kiss me, don't you?
Uh, Catherine?
Is the guy from Rascal Flatts
hitting on you?
Mmm.
I've only seen
Lichtenberg figures
on electric and
phone company workers.
You can't get ferning
from 110 volts.
This was no accident.
Where did you put
my pants, honey?
Jay. Dude, what happened?
You scared us to death.
Jay, it's us.
Joe Don and-and Gary.
Sorry about the fight,
all right?
Should've never happened,
but, you know,
it's always just been
the three of us.
("Unstoppable" ringtone playing)
What the hell is that noise?
(music stops)
Oh, noise?
Dude, you wrote that song.
I hate country music.
I was feeling bad for you.
Man, you just won't
let it go, will you?
Dude, I don't even know
who you are.
WILLOWS:
I think he means it.
A neurologist is on the way.
I'm Catherine Willows
from the crime lab.
I need to finish
processing him.
We can talk later?
(hip-hop ringtone plays)
That's more like it.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
(indistinct police radio
transmissions)
Spotted the body
on a routine patrol.
He was caught in the reeds;
figured I shouldn't touch him.
Judging from the bloating,
he's been in the water
at least 24 hours.
There is a deep
horizontal laceration
approximately five inches long
just above his right ear.
SIDLE: Fishing vest,
fishing pants.
Boating accident?
Hit his head?
Uh, usually there's an empty
boat to go along with that.
Uh, no boat or
fishing equipment.
No wallet.
Silver cigar case.
Cuban cigar.
Lighter.
He may have been military.
Special Forces guys in Vietnam
really went in
for this kind
of gruesome imagery.
It's an interesting watch.
"Luftwaffe."
Nazi Air Force.
That's an iron cross.
"Kampfgeschwader."
Geschwader.
Oh, flight squadron.
This watch could've been worn
by a German pilot
during the second World War.
Maybe he's a tourist.
LANGSTON:
Somehow, I doubt it,
unless his initials are CIA.
Are you guys with, uh,
occupational security
hazard, whatever it is?
No, we're with
the crime lab.
Yeah, we're here to
collect Jay's guitar.
Well, I-I called OSHA,
and they're supposed to be
sending somebody out to
check for faulty wiring
in this building.
That's the only way he
could've been shocked.
And why would you think
something like that?
I'm Travis Murray;
I'm Jay's bass tech.
I take care of his equipment.
I do a shock test
before every concert.
Oh, okay.
Yeah, that's
why the wiring
in this building's
got to be jacked.
It fried most of our wireless
equipment before the show,
and that's why
we had to cable Jay.
Then zap! Huh.
Where is Jay's guitar?
Ma'am, I'm not authorized
to give that up.
Th-that's Buddy's call.
Who's Buddy?
He's the band manager.
Buddy?
(whistles)
I'm not a waitress, Travis.
It's OSHA.
What took you
folks so long?
No, you know,
actually it's not OSHA.
They're, uh,
they're cops.
She was at the, uh,
the hospital last night.
Gentlemen, we're here
to collect Jay's guitar,
his amp, his mic,
his rack, all that.
Well, this doesn't
sound very good.
Jay's injuries are not
consistent with an accident.
What are they consistent with?
Intentional electrocution.
You're saying
that somebody actually
tried to hurt Jay on purpose?
Why don't you tell us
about the fight you guys had?
I mean, what's there to tell?
Families fight.
That's just something
that happens.
You know, at least once a tour.
(grunts)
It's no big deal.
And did you have one of
those fights last night?
That's none of your business.
Well, I'm making it
my business, how about that?
WILLOWS:
All right,
uh...
Joe Don, why don't you tell us?
Well, uh, Jay wants to do
his own project, you know?
He told us, uh,
he wanted to take
a little time away from the band
and threw it on us last night.
And we didn't think it was very
cool, so we tried to kill him.
Dude, they're cops.
Okay, how about you give us
Jay's equipment?
Uh...
Yes, yes.
You give these folks
whatever they need
and none of your damn lip.
Buddy, lighten up a little bit.
You know what,
we're all Rascal Flatts here,
you know, even though
Jay can't remember.
COD?
Got a laundry list
of what didn't kill him.
No water on the lungs,
no water on the stomach.
He didn't drown.
Head wound was severe
but not fatal.
This man had cancer.
Prostate, stage four.
It migrated
to his liver,
colon and stomach.
But it's not COD.
Nope, it's undetermined
pending tox.
Let's start clipping.
♪ ♪
HODGES:
My father liked to fish.
he never took
me with him.
Maybe he felt
you were crowding him.
Hmm, not true.
I think he just liked
his alone time.
My mother and I
would bake cookies.
Your father ever
take you fishing?
Fishing?
No.
Hey, head wound
wasn't accidental.
Gravitational
blood on the shirt
indicates that he was standing
when he was hit.
(grunts)
(groans)
There was no blood
on the outside of the vest,
only transfer on the inside.
He was dressed after the event.
Someone wants us to think
it was an accident.
(phone ringing)
Willows.
It's Craig Halliday.
Associate Director,
Central Intelligence Agency.
That's right, CIA.
I heard the pause.
Listen, I'm sitting here
in my office,
and I just happened to notice
that CSI Raymond Langston
is running the fingerprints
of former deputy director
of operations Vance Colton.
(chuckling)
That old goat didn't get caught
with trick dice, did he?
Before I give you
any information,
I'll need to verify
your identity.
Good job.
You'd be surprised
how many people don't ask.
You call Langley,
they'll route you through to me.
Headquarters is expecting
your call.
(dial tone)
(cell phone ringing)
(phone beeps on)
Hi, Catherine.
So, you were saying?
My team is investigating
a floater
recovered from Lake Mead
early this morning.
A floater, huh?
Like a dead fish?
As in a dead human being.
Male Caucasian, 70s.
Does that sound
like your Vance Colton?
Well, Catherine,
this falls under
National Security protocols,
meaning I'm taking the body
and all logs, reports, evidence
and whatnot
that your team has collected.
If the victim
is Deputy Director Colton,
his body is the property
of the Clark County coroner.
You will need to contact them.
As for the "whatnot," you'll
need to put it in writing to me.
(laughing)
Whoa, there, yikes.
Uh, Catherine, I'm not trying
to dance on anybody's feet here.
How about a collaboration?
In exchange
for helping your government,
how about I give you something
you won't get otherwise?
I've seen access denied,
but access restricted?
Denied is "get
lost."
Restricted-- that's like
a fence you want to climb over.
That fence surrounds the CIA.
Your floater's name
is Vance Colton.
That would explain
the pocket full of memories.
SIDLE:
Oh, here he is.
Vance Colton,
Deputy Director of Operations.
Central Intelligence Agency,
1976 to 1983.
"As Deputy Director,
"he oversaw covert operations
on four continents.
"High point of his career
was Operation Blackwood.
"Colton conceived
and successfully conducted
Operation Blackwood
against the East German Stasi."
East German Stasi?
Bad guys.
Well, the CIA
is taking the body
and all our evidence, so...
we made copies
of everything.
Do we get anything in return?
Colton's home address.
And maybe the primary.
(buzzing)
Put down the saw!
(motor winding down)
Step away from
the guitar.
You were about to commit murder
on an immaculate '62 Fender
jazz bass with the original
factory paint.
So, what?
For someone from the
great state of Texas,
you show very little respect
for a true American art form.
Hey, just 'cause I'm from Texas
doesn't mean
I like country music.
This, Nick, is a
solid body guitar.
Do you mind?
Please.
What you see is what you get.
(sensor beeps intermittently)
You ever hear of the Yardbirds?
Oh, come on, Clapton,
Page, Beck, Relf?
Of course I have.
Back in 1976,
(sensor beeps)
practicing for a reunion
in his basement,
Keith Relf did not properly
ground his guitar,
and he killed himself.
If this guitar was sabotaged,
we'd see shaved wires.
Well, if it was just a short,
these two pot resistors
would show residue
from the ozone flash.
There's not even any burned skin
to the strings.
I think we're doing
a guitar-topsy on the
wrong guitar, buddy.
One of those Rascal Flatts boys
is jerking us around.
Dr. Langston.
And, uh,
Catherine?
Sara.
Sidle.
Oh, CSI three,
and a very good one.
Craig Halliday,
Associate Director, CIA,
but you know that.
And how do you know me?
Sorry. They beat it into us
from day one of training.
You never meet any stranger
you don't already know.
Agent Halliday...
Actually,
we recruit agents;
we're called officers.
Your officers
are corrupting
a potential crime scene.
Catherine told me
DDO Colton drowned.
She didn't tell you that.
We are investigating his death
as a probable homicide.
Aw, hell.
Oh... offer a favor
and I screw it up, huh?
You can fix it
by pulling back your officers.
Well, I would if I could,
but you see,
federal statute demands
that any investigation
of the death of one of our own,
the crime scene be turned over
to the agency for 24 hours
in order to secure
any and all whatnot
pertaining to National Security.
But 24 hours is for slowpokes.
I'm out of your way
in less than two.
Since when is a mattress
National Security?
(camera shutter clicking)
Travis, why'd you give
the man the wrong guitar?
I gave him the guitar case.
I-I thought Jay's bass was in it
because I put it there
after I finished playing
with y'all.
Okay, so which one
of these shocked him?
None of them.
I put that one in the case.
Okay, so where is Jay's guitar?
Is it missing or what?
I don't know what to tell you.
Well, you better
tell me something.
You know, this is
starting to look a lot like
a conspiracy to me, fellas.
Don't look at me like that.
Like what?
I'm not even looking
at you, man.
Yeah, then why am I sweating?
You tell me.
Look, our security team
would've stopped somebody
leaving with Jay's guitar.
Look, guys, if you want
to can me, I get it.
You're not
going anywhere.
We got a concert tonight and Jay
still doesn't know who he is.
Look, we have no show
without Jay.
Figure it out, boys.
I'm going to talk
to security.
I wonder what this
place would look like
if they weren't
cooperating with us.
If Vance Colton was murdered,
why would the CIA
want to cover it up?
Maybe they were looking
for something
here in the house.
Something...
they thought
the killer was after.
If they were looking
for something specific,
why not just take it?
I mean, we would
never know.
They took everything.
They either didn't know
what they were looking for,
or they didn't want anyone
to know what they were taking.
LANGSTON:
One canoe missing,
one paddle missing.
Colton was dressed
to go out on the water.
Could be the primary.
Freshly split logs,
no axe.
Got green-painted
plastic fragments,
possibly polyethylene.
Same color and composition
as these two canoes.
If these are from
the missing canoe,
then it has a hole in it.
(tapping)
An ax could put
a hole in this,
in which case both the ax
and the canoe are probably
at the bottom of the lake.
Maybe not, actually.
Canoes today are made with
flotation devices on each end.
Grissom and I take canoe trips.
We went looking for bugs
in a canoe on our honeymoon.
(clears throat)
Uh, point is
that, um, canoes today
don't always sink.
I got drag marks here.
Green paint transfer.
(spraying)
Why would a guy like Colton
drag his canoe to the dock
every time he used it?
And if he did do that,
wouldn't there be
a lot more drag
marks here?
(spraying)
Negative.
All right, what if Colton
was in the canoe before
it was dragged to the water?
SIDLE:
Killer launches him
from the dock,
assuming that he'll drift away
and sink, leaving no evidence.
SANDERS:
Just got off the phone
with the head porter
at the Palermo Center.
One of his guys
saw some crazy groupie chick
Dumpster-diving last night.
Thought the Web site
on her T-shirt was pretty funny.
RascalFlattsPsychoBitch.com.
(chuckling):
That is pretty funny.
Yeah. I checked the site,
she's been blogging
about Jay's guitar.
(knocking on door)
Are you Marta Petrovich?
Yeah.
We have a warrant
to search your apartment.
Well, what are you looking for?
Uh, we heard
about your guitar.
We'd really love to see it.
Oh! Well, you don't need
no warrant for that.
I'd love to show it off.
Come on, come on.
Come on.
(squealing)
Okay...
(humming)
Wow.
So nice.
Yeah.
Ah!
When I found it in the Dumpster,
I just about died.
I love them so much.
The problem is that
guitar is evidence
in an attempted murder
investigation.
Yeah, and you know,
you could be a hero,
helping to solve
a really big case
involving Rascal Flatts.
Yeah, and I'm sure the
band would be happy
to reward it to you
when we're done.
Yeah, do you, uh, mind
if I step on your couch?
Uh, I-I guess so...
J-J-Just look, don't touch!
I mean, Jay's fingers
are still on it.
Oh, boy, yeah, I hope so.
Don't you, Greg?
Mm-hmm.
Hmm-hmm.
I hate to break it
to you, sweetie,
but, uh, this guitar
is coming with us.
No, no, no, no, it's mine.
Yeah, I'm really sorry.
I found it!
No, you can't do this!
Maybe we can get you
an autograph.
(door opens)
(whimpering)
(door closes)
(sighing)
But I already have
their autographs.
(whining)
HALLIDAY:
At our headquarters,
we have a whole food court
in the basement.
I always get a kick
out of the idea that the girl
serving the burgers
has to have security clearance.
Craig Halliday,
Associate Director.
You're Jim Brass.
That's right.
So, uh, what do you need
from me, Mr. Halliday?
Well, I think that you need
something from me.
Oh, yeah?
An apology.
I offered CSI
my full cooperation,
and I hate always being
the bad guy.
Ah, don't worry about it, I'm
always the bad guy around here.
Oh, yeah?
So, anything else
you want to get
off your chest?
Captain, Larry Colton
to see you.
No, I've achieved
what I came for.
Your father was a great patriot.
I'm here to sign whatever
there is to sign and go home.
You know, I don't think I'm
gonna let you see the body.
It's, uh, it's not
a good idea really.
I haven't seen my father in
20 years, I couldn't care less.
Mmm, I know
that he loved you very much.
My father hated me.
You know that;
it's in my file.
Just by sitting here, he's
already started a file on you.
So, besides you,
any other haters?
All five of his wives.
The thousands of people he had
killed and everyone in between.
Ah, if only we could kill them
by the thousands.
The problem
with killing our enemies
is that you can't spy on them
after that.
Just want to let the family
know, the agency is behind you.
Hmm, your way of saying that
you're sharpening the daggers,
screwing on the silencers
and that the foreign flunky
who took out my father is
about to get capped as payback.
Executive order 11-905
forbids the agency
from engaging in assassination.
Okay, on that note,
have you seen
what you needed?
Because, uh, I think I
can handle it from here.
Captain Brass.
Good-bye, Mr. Halliday.
Tire tracks look like
they were made
by Suburbans.
Three of them.
SIDLE:
Two miles from the house,
a mile from where
we found the body.
And look, green paint transfer.
Colton's canoe washed up here.
LANGSTON:
Halliday beat us here.
SIDLE:
Halliday spooks?
That's not a Suburban.
I'll call it in.
(dialing)
Can I help you with something?
(speaking German)
Gun!
I'm reaching
for my identification.
This doesn't have to be
an international incident.
You're with the
German consulate.
As consulate officials,
we are protected
by diplomatic immunity.
Why don't you be diplomatic
and toss the guns out?
This car is German soil.
You have no jurisdiction
inside of it,
including us.
My passport.
This is a bunch of crap.
Yes, but he's telling the truth.
For your information, gentlemen,
it's illegal to shoot fish
in the state of Nevada.
Auf Wiedersehen.
(printer whirring)
(whirring continues)
So, even though
we're on a secure network,
someone hacked
Hodges' computer.
Why me?
Well, maybe it's because
you like to surf
more outside sites
than anyone else in the lab.
It's all research.
Archie, can't you just
trace the source of the hack?
With enough time.
Well, if I'm not needed,
I need to go delete
some personal files.
The book certainly starts off
with a bang.
A word-for-word transcript
of a telephone conversation
between the East German secret
police and Nettie Moller.
She's like their German Obama.
They say she's gonna win
the election by a landslide.
Well, she won't
if this gets out.
During the 1970s,
Moller was a double agent,
recruiting agents for the CIA
and betraying them
to the East German Stasi
for execution.
You know, if we have
a copy of this memoir,
it's not a stretch
to think that the Germans
and the CIA
had it first.
You can say anything
you want to say in a book,
but Colton had to be working
from a tape when he wrote this.
Halliday, the house,
the Germans.
The tape is what
they were looking for.
A tape worth killing for.
Yes.
Well, it's a decent theory
for a spy novel.
What do we have in the way
of evidence?
COD?
Nothing yet.
Still waiting for tox.
Pots are fried,
but no shaved wires.
This is the right guitar
but not the source of the shock.
If it's not his guitar,
then it's gotta be
his mic or his amp.
Well, yee-haw.
The ground on the amp
has been removed.
Without grounds,
the circuit breaker's
not gonna pop, you are.
Yeah, but that alone's not
enough to cause electrocution.
Well, the power comes
from the amp into the guitar
and through Jay to his mic,
where Jay's lips
close the circuit.
XLR plug's been singed.
This is part of the circuit
that shocked Jay.
But there's not enough voltage
from a 110
to leave fern patterns
on his arms like that.
220 had to come
from somewhere.
Well, the venue
runs on 220.
All somebody had to do
was sabotage a 110 box
so 220 could run
through it.
Here you go,
this is 220 right here.
Once whoever did this linked
the 220 to the sabotaged 110,
it sent the 220
directly into Jay.
And without a breaker
to protect him,
as soon as his lips
touch the mic,
Jay fries.
♪ When your heart
is full of doubt ♪
♪ And you think that
there's no way out ♪
(electricity crackling)
♪ You find your faith
has been lost and shaken... ♪
So, wait a minute,
why didn't Jay get zapped
when the concert started?
When his lips
first touched that mic?
I don't know.
But whoever's responsible
for this had to rig this box.
So maybe there's some
prints on the inside.
If we get an ID,
we'll ask him ourselves.
Henry, what do you have for me?
Well, I ran an expanded
tox panel on Vance Colton,
all the normal drugs of abuse
and poisons were negative.
Not even the cancer drugs.
No, he wasn't taking
any medications.
The man had stage four cancer.
Then he must've
stopped treatment.
(sighing)
All right, try these.
Aconitine, succinylcholine,
fluphenazine and sarin.
I've never heard of aconitine.
Fluphenazine is a psychotropic.
Sarin's a binary
chemical weapon.
Saddam used it against
the Kurds in the '80s.
But I thought the United Nations
banned production
and stockpiling
of all chemical weapons.
Correct, but all four compounds
are mentioned here
in Colton's memoir.
Tools of the spy trade.
(computer beeping and chirping)
(typing)
Okay, backed the last zombie
to the source.
Hodges' printer was hacked here,
in Vegas.
German Consulate
or Halliday's office?
(keys tapping)
Coffee shop
at the Blue Siren Motel.
That's not very 007.
(TV playing indistinctly)
I mean, it figures the
Colton kid was lying to us.
He's been registered
here for four nights.
SIDLE:
Which means he checked in a day
before his father was killed.
(TV playing indistinctly)
(silenced gunshots)
Yeah, the manager says
he may still be in his room.
The door is open.
He's dead.
(indistinct radio transmission)
Well, they
tossed the room,
probably looking
for that tape.
And his computer's gone.
Control, this is
Captain Brass.
We have a 419
down at the Blue Siren Motel.
Send backup...
and the coroner's wagon.
The Germans want us to know
they didn't kill Vance Colton.
And they also want us to know
they killed his son.
You call my mother
a whore in print,
you say I'm a bastard.
It's just more
of your lies.
She was a whore,
you don't exist, and
I'm going fishing.
(grunts)
(groans)
LANGSTON:
Larry died believing
he'd killed his father.
He sent us the manuscript
to deflect suspicion
from himself onto the Germans.
From Colton's vest,
we always assumed
that Colton was on the dock
because he was going fishing.
But there's no
fishing equipment here.
Colton took down the canoe.
So, he planned
to go out on the water
before Larry put him there.
But if Larry
hadn't been there,
what was going to happen next?
Vance Colton was going to die
anyway.
By whose hand?
That's what's bothering me.
I bet if we dug
a little deeper,
we'd find out that
when Larry was a boy,
he wanted to be
just like his father,
even though he hated him.
You always see something of
both parents in yourself.
Even if it's more than
you'd like to admit.
Hey, I got your COD,
and it's right
out of James Bond.
Just call me "H."
You get it? 'Cause
"M" and the "H"...
"H," "Q,"
Yeah.
special branch-- I get it.
Right, I-I tested all the
poisons from the memoir,
and you're negative
on the first three.
Which leaves sarin.
It was first created
by the Germans
as a super pesticide
until World War II
when they discovered it was very
effective at killing people.
Back to the Germans.
These levels of sarin
you found in Vance Colton
should have killed
him instantly.
Which suggests the poison
was administered
when he was already
in the canoe.
Yeah, but out on the
lake and out cold?
Why didn't they
just shoot him?
That's a good point.
Henry, is there a way
to make sarin
not instantaneously lethal?
Well, it's a clear liquid,
so I suppose it's possible
to put it in a capsule.
Which means it would
take some time to dissolve
before it entered the system,
so he could've
ingested it before
he was out on the dock.
This doesn't make any sense.
Yes, but Catherine
asked for COD.
That she did.
I'll tell her.
ANDREWS:
Dr. Ray? You think
I could read
the rest of Colton's book?
I love spy thrillers.
No. I'm going to return this
to its author.
(indistinct chatter, jazz music
playing in background)
I'd offer to buy you a drink,
but you already got one.
Can I have a scotch?
Okay.
It needs to be a new bottle
Sure.
with the seal unbroken.
You got it.
Seriously?
(chuckles):
I'm just kidding.
Thanks for calling me and...
and bringing me this.
Sometimes old men forget
the promises they made,
and secrets must
remain just that.
I think Colton
kept his promises,
which is why you gave him
exactly what he wanted.
What was it that he wanted?
His way out of this world.
Yeah, drowning sure
is a tough way to go.
So is cancer.
So is blunt force trauma.
With sons like that,
who needs enemies, huh?
Cheers.
We both know what killed him
was the sarin you gave him.
Sarin?
They don't even make
that stuff anymore.
Germans still make it.
Hmm.
You put Colton
back in business.
You had him write the memoir.
You provided the Moller tape.
If there ever was a Moller tape.
If someone believes
there's a tape, there's a tape.
I believe that Colton
posted the manuscript
on the Internet,
knowing that the Germans
would read it.
No, I don't think so,
because Colton was retired.
He was dying of cancer.
I doubt that he cared
about German politics.
He cared about his legacy.
He didn't want to come in
from the cold and die
a sick, old man.
He wanted to go out a hero,
poisoned by his old enemies
fighting for his country.
So you helped an old friend
commit suicide.
Well, Dr. Langston,
you like the...
extra spin around the block,
uh, goes beyond the cut-and-dry
microscoped answer from
the green paint chips of life.
You know where I work,
that block
has an unlimited horizon.
Are you offering me a job?
Have you found one yet
that fits?
Well, my mistake.
Thanks for the drink.
Did your father ever talk to you
about his time in Vietnam?
It was an odd place
to take leave
with a war staring us
in the face.
Or maybe you two
weren't that close?
(indistinct chatter)
STOKES:
There he is right there.
Just hang on a second.
How's it going, fellas?
Mr. Murray?
I think you know
why I'm here.
Man, we got
a show to do.
Yeah, not with him,
you're not.
He's the one that sabotaged
Jay's equipment.
What?!
GARY:
Travis?
Why would you do something
like that?
I just meant to give him
a little jolt
so I... so I could do
the one song.
Travis, all you had
to do was ask.
I... Don't-don't you guys see?
I'm getting old.
Th-th-the show was over
(handcuffs clicking)
after this tour for me.
JOE DON: Jay.
GARY: Hey, Jay!
Jay, I...
I didn't mean for this
to get so out of control.
Man, you lit me up like
a Christmas tree,
and you smoked
my best guitar.
Why would you do that?
I'm sorry, man.
What did I do to you?
I'm sorry.
Are you back?
Look at me.
You recognize me?
A face like yours, as ugly
as it is, it's hard to forget.
GARY:
Oh, yeah, laugh if you
want to,
but I'm the one that's
sitting there been covering
for you this entire time.
Hey, right back at you, big boy.
JAY:
Hey, guys.
I wrote a new song
while I was in the hospital.
It's a little bit different.
You're gonna have to follow me.
You guys stick around.
We're going to have
some fun tonight.
BUDDY:
Okay.
Enjoy yourselves tonight.
(cheering and applause)
Hey, Las Vegas!
How y'all feeling?
(cheering and applause
continues)
As most of you know,
Cousin Jay got a little shocked
last night on stage.
And, um... he's feeling better.
He doesn't look any better
but he's feeling better.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Jay DeMarcus. He's back!
(cheering)
Thank you.
I got a little song
I wrote for you.
You guys just follow
along, we'll do this.
Y'all ready?
(cheering)
Okay. Here we go.
Kick it off.
(bass beat plays)
(rapping):
♪ See, I thought Rascal Flatts
was unstoppable ♪
♪ That's before
I became shockable ♪
♪ But now I'm back ♪
♪ That makes us unshockable ♪
♪ Saw my whole life ♪
♪ Flash before my eyes ♪
♪ The ups, the downs ♪
♪ The lows, the highs ♪
♪ My mom, my dad,
the kids, the wife ♪
♪ And then I snapped
right back into life, yeah ♪
Whoo!
(audience cheering)
(band playing "Unstoppable")
♪ Hey... ♪
♪ So... ♪
♪ So you made
a lot of mistakes ♪
♪ Walked down the road
a little sideways ♪
♪ Cracked a brick
when you hit the wall ♪
♪ Yeah, you got a pocket
full of regrets ♪
♪ Pull you down faster
than a sunset ♪
♪ Hey, it happens to us all ♪
♪ When the cold, hard rain
just won't quit ♪
♪ And you can't see your way
out of it... ♪