BOY:
This is the part
where it gets scary.
This is the part where
everybody's panicking
because the bad guys are coming.
BOY 2:
Wait, where'd you
see this movie?
It's not a movie, okay,
it's a book.
But anyways, everybody is
scared, except for one boy.
He is the bravest one.
So can I go ahead
and open it?
WOMAN:
Yes.
Oh, Mom, this is exactly
the one I wanted!
WOMAN:
Is that
the good one?
Where did you get this?
Oh, my gosh.
Come here.
Stop.
(laughing)
This is the best
mom in the world.
Ah, I love you, baby.
Love you, too.
I have legal proof now.
I'm the best mom.
(car door closes)
(flies buzzing)
(indistinct radio transmission)
BRASS:
At 6:47 a.m., an anonymous
phone call was made
from a pay phone on the I-15
by an adult male.
The caller said he drove by
and saw the body.
Sunrise was at 6:54 a.m.
this morning.
Would have been too dark
for even an eagle-eyed passerby
to spot the body
from that distance.
Have one of your guys
dust that pay phone for prints.
We might get
something off it.
I'm gonna check with
missing persons. Good luck.
Yeah, I'll handle it.
Thanks, Jim.
Morning, Doc.
Nick.
What's going on?
Well, he's been dead
about four to eight hours
based on liver temp.
Depressed skull fracture
with a laceration
to the overlying scalp.
C.O.D. is most likely
contusion
of the brain
and a subdural hemorrhage.
The breadth of the depression
suggests impact
with a wide, flat surface.
A wound like that
with no blood pool?
Nope.
A body dump.
Dried blood underneath
his fingernails.
I'll bag his hands,
preserve any evidence
for transport.
Okay, if I check
his pockets?
Go for it.
Compass, pocket knife.
Music.
Food rations.
Possible runaway.
A flashlight
with "East Las Vegas
High School" on it.
Well, if he was a student, he
had to be at least 14 years old.
He's kind of small
for that age.
I'll get a photo
over to the school.
You know, I was really small
when I was 14.
Yeah?
Yeah. Made me ambitious.
So what did you want to be
when you were 14?
Probably the same thing
he most wanted to be--
fifteen.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
(thunder rumbling)
WILLOWS:
When was the last time
you saw your son?
I didn't even look in
Will's room last night
when I got home from work.
Didn't check on him.
And when did
you get home?
(sniffs)
Uh, club closed at 2:00.
Cashed out, divided up my tips
with the other waitresses.
It was-- it was about 3:00.
I thought I was letting him
sleep in this morning,
till I got the call.
Ms. Sutter, do
you have any idea
where he might have been
going last night?
Who he might have been with?
He knows not to open the door
for anyone,
or-or leave without calling me.
A million times
we've gone over it.
And where's
his father?
He's not in Will's life.
WILLOWS:
Do you know if Will
had tried to contact him?
Because a boy Will's age
starting to think about
growing up, manhood--
sometimes they seek
out a mentor.
SUTTER:
Will's father
is no mentor.
He's hardly a man.
I will still need
to be in touch with him.
His name's Billy Melvoy.
Your line of work--
you're more likely
to bump into him than I will.
What about Will's friends?
Were any of them driving yet?
No.
No, he's-- he's got
two best friends.
They're 14, too.
Mason and Steve.
They live down the street.
They've all grown up together.
So they spent a lot
of time with Will?
More than I ever got to.
(camera shutter clicking)
♪ ♪
Found a small crack
in the front window,
but no prints.
Other than that,
the perimeter's clean.
No sign of forced entry.
That's not surprising
when you consider
how much equipment
Will had in his pockets.
It's clear he wasn't
dragged out of his bed
in the middle of the night.
He was prepared for something.
He's got the whole universe
and all of human
history here.
So what was he out
in search of?
Or... what was he
running away from?
Right.
Got his recent
online activity here.
E-mail,
encyclopedia,
some comic book site.
Open this one, please.
Article of tribal
coming-of-age rituals.
"Only through a solitary
"and trying journey
into a literal
"or metaphysical wilderness,
"can a young boy gain
new acceptance
"as a man amongst
the members
of his tribe
or village."
You must be
Mason Ward.
Yeah.
Yeah, hi, I'm Nick Stokes.
I'm with the crime lab.
I'm going to be asking
you a few questions.
Go ahead and
have a seat.
Okay.
Now do you want a soda
or something to eat
before we
get started?
Nah. The vending machines
here suck.
Yeah, yeah, I'd have
to agree with that.
Now how do you know
something like that?
You come here often?
My dad's a cop.
I've been around.
Oh, okay.
Then you know how
important it is
that you help me
figure out what happened
to your friend
last night.
Right.
Will wasn't
really my friend anymore.
Steve, Will's mom said
that you and Mason
are Will's best friends.
Yeah, we were.
It's just
different now.
How so?
Will would still ask us
to, like, ride bikes
or look for lizards
in the park,
but we're not
into that anymore.
What are you into now?
MASON:
Girls.
You know, getting serious
about working out.
And, you know, other stuff.
Do you have any idea what might
have happened to him last night?
No clue.
When was the last time
that you saw Will?
I saw him yesterday
at school, but that's it.
Did you talk to him?
No.
Steve, you don't look so good.
Are you feeling okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
Look, I know what you mean
about moving on to other things.
When I was
your age,
I couldn't get
there quick enough.
I started to wish there was some
magic potion I could swallow
to make myself older,
cooler.
Turned out
there was.
The downside was,
the next day,
I would feel awful.
My mouth would be dry,
my head would be pounding
and I could just
smell this...
sweet sugary poison
seeping out of my pores.
You're a tequila
man, huh, Steve?
HODGES:
There were two different fibers
found on Will Sutter.
This one's a standard trilobal
nylon polypropylene fiber.
Widely used in
the manufacture
of upholstered
furniture and bedding.
This other fiber
that Nick found
on the boy,
is significantly more specific.
It's an 80-20 rayon-nylon
with an emerald hue, used,
as far as my research shows,
exclusively to carpet
1970's green Cadillacs.
Not a popular seller.
And in addition
to carpeting the interior,
this same material was also used
to line the vehicle's trunk.
You know, I read
something a while back.
Said that the distance from home
that the average parent
would allow their nine-year-old
to wander had shrunk to a tenth
of what it was
when I was a kid.
The world's a scarier place,
that's for sure.
Oh, I was terrified back then.
But a boy who
ventures out
thinking the world isn't
a place to hide from,
shouldn't be proven wrong.
JOHNSON:
Will Sutter was exchanging
emails with someone
screen-named "BlackChipCraig."
Correspondence
was mostly about
historic sites, ghost
towns, old mines.
So, one day...
(typing)
BlackChip suggests they
go check out one of
the old mines.
Sounds like innocent geek fun.
Except...
a check of BlackChip's
static I.P. address
and a quick Web search
reveal him to be
Craig Lifford,
40-year-old librarian
from Henderson.
So a 40-year-old man
invites a 14-year-old boy
to a secluded location.
Could be more than just
innocent geek fun.
Mr. Lifford.
I see you're a history buff.
You like old things--
vintage clothes, vintage cars.
Well, I-I drive a hybrid, but...
What is this about?
Can you tell
me how you got
the scratches on
your left wrist?
Um, yeah.
I have a new kitten.
A new kitten?
So you like some newer things,
younger things.
Should I have a lawyer here?
Younger things
like, um,
Will Sutter.
The young man
you invited
on a trip
to the Crowley Silver Mine.
Remember him?
Yeah?
What the hell is this?
No.
No, no, no, no, no.
Yes.
I-I work in a library.
Among children.
This has been my
life's passion.
And if someone got in that
boy's ear and egged him into
thinking that my
communication with him
was something
that it was not...
Tell me about what happened
between you and Will.
Um, we met online, um,
in a forum
on a history Web site.
His intellect,
his-his bearing--
I assumed he was an adult.
When I found out
that he was a young man...
You continued to contact him.
About Nevada mining history!
I suggested a few
historic sites
that his parents
should take him to.
When he explained that he could
not, that that was not possible,
I guess, yeah, I-I volunteered--
forgetting
for one moment
the implicit nefariousness
of an adult male
taking a young boy's
academic curiosity seriously.
But we didn't
go to the mine,
I never met him.
I didn't even know
his last name.
I need to take
a sample of your DNA.
Absolutely.
Open your mouth, please.
So is Will really claiming
that something happened?
Mr. Lifford, Will is dead.
Hey.
I got your text.
What exactly am I
not gonna believe?
(clears throat)
That blood that was
under Will Sutter's nails
was a hit to somebody
already in CODIS.
One of Sara's old cases.
And, before you look at this,
I promise you,
I triple-checked this;
it's absolutely accurate.
Okay.
Simon Rose?
I know. I don't know
what to tell you.
It's impossible,
but it's true.
Yeah, but he's been in
prison for the last...
Two and a half years.
Exactly.
So how does his blood end up
under the nails of a dead kid?
Since the morning
of January 1, 2006,
when his wife Samantha was found
murdered in their home,
I have stood by
my client Simon Rose.
I was at his side
while he grieved over his loss,
while he endured trial,
mistrial and the retrial
that wrongfully
convicted him of a crime
he did not commit.
My belief in Simon Rose
has never faltered.
And this morning's development
has vindicated my belief.
The discovery of this blood
under the dead child's nails
is evidence that there is
someone in Las Vegas--
a child murderer--
who has the same DNA profile
as my incarcerated
but innocent client Simon Rose.
Mr. Rose must be released
and the real murderer of both
Will Sutter and Samantha Rose
brought to justice.
Thank you.
(reporters clamoring)
SIDLE:
This is Simon Rose's blood
all over his wife.
He choked her to death,
left her on the kitchen floor,
and then claimed
to have been
upstairs asleep
when she was attacked.
Well, if he choked her,
then how did his blood
wind up on her?
SIDLE:
Well, because for once,
she fought back.
She broke his nose,
scratched his face.
She couldn't stop him.
And I guarantee that he took her
halfway there
a dozen times before.
STOKES:
And there were
police call-outs
for domestic but no convictions.
SIDLE:
The house told
the story.
Punched-in walls
covered up with paintings.
Broken vases
glued back together.
He's rich and handsome,
he always got away with it,
and he almost got away
with killing her, too.
The mistrial?
STOKES:
The prosecution had
a slam dunk going,
but there was juror misconduct.
Couple of weeks
into the trial,
two jurors got
their hands on
a bottle of gin
and got tanked at lunch.
SIDLE:
Other jurors said
that they saw one
of Lynn Stecker's associates
bringing the booze to them.
Yeah, but nobody can prove that.
They have tried everything
to get this guy off,
and they're still trying.
By planting blood
under a dead kid's nails?
I got to say,
I wouldn't put it past them.
Okay.
So, where did Rose's blood
come from?
There were no preservatives
in the sample,
which means it wasn't blood
drawn from Rose and
stored in a blood bank.
SIDLE:
If Rose did
plan this,
he could have had blood drawn
and stored without preservative
before going to prison.
We're only dealing
with a minute amount.
He could've snuck some
blood out of prison
via mail or a
bribed guard.
Be tough to track that one down.
LANGSTON:
Well, if Rose
cut himself to draw blood,
he might still have a wound.
I'd like to examine him.
As long as you're just looking
and not questioning,
he doesn't have a right
to an attorney.
So make that happen.
Any other possible
sources for the blood?
Samantha's dress
with Rose's blood on it.
It's in permanent storage
at the Central Evidence Vault.
All right, why don't the three
of you focus on those angles,
Greg and I will
look at something else.
A boy was killed.
Simon Rose didn't do it.
We need to find out who did.
STECKER:
Jim, at this firm,
we are the Lakers,
not the Globetrotters.
We don't rely
on tricks.
Oh, I've seen you
pass the ball behind your back
quite a few times
over the years, Lynn.
We've been pressing to get an
appeal for nearly two years.
This morning's
discovery
will merely serve as one
more piece to present
in the evidentiary
hearing--
a chance to get real
justice for my client.
This morning's discovery?
We're talking about a dead boy.
Don't give me justice for
your client; don't give me that.
Samantha Rose was covered
in your client's blood.
Funny how that works.
I argue in trial that one of
Mr. Rose's many powerful enemies
could easily have drugged
and wounded Mr. Rose,
killed his wife and then planted
Mr. Rose's blood on his wife,
and the prosecution, the media,
treat that theory
like it was a joke.
And yet, in this
new case, some vast
blood-plant conspiracy is
the only viable explanation.
Fitting that it should be
blood we're talking about,
because isn't the stuff supposed
to smell kind of iron-y?
That's cute, Lynn.
But I'm telling you,
and I want you to hear this.
If you know anything about this
dead boy or the manipulation
of evidence, you have a lot more
to lose than just an appeal.
Does it get old, Jim?
Being sent as the
sheriff's messenger?
Because when
you're ready
to join a new team, you call me.
Yeah, I know a lot of guys
who worked P.I. for you.
Financially, it's great.
Ethically, it's not so great.
By the way,
your theory's flawed.
Oh?
If someone wanted
to plant blood,
they could do it
in any crime scene.
What kind of a monster would
kill a kid to accomplish that?
The same kind of monster
who couldn't just divorce
Samantha Rose.
ANDERSON:
Yeah, I-I remember you
on this case.
W-When Rose got off that first
time round on that mistrial,
must have driven you nuts.
Drove me toward some
brochures about Costa Rica.
You're smart
to get away like that.
'Cause I remember,
when I was wearing that vest,
I always told myself
I'd do the same.
(sighs)
Little fishing lodge,
Ely, Minnesota.
(chuckles)
Clear all of it out.
But... just didn't
happen that way.
You ever get out of
town now, George?
Oh, nah.
This-this here,
this is my castle.
Let me see here.
Yeah.
Samantha Rose.
When was the last time
this evidence was taken out
by the defense
for independent examination?
Let's see.
November 4, 2006.
Returned two days later.
Right before the trial started.
Sealed, signed
and dated by yours truly.
Here you go.
Thank you.
Okay.
LANGSTON:
I'm going to need to see
Simon Rose's
visitation records.
Yes, sir.
And I'd also like to
speak with his cell mate.
Well, his cell mate was
paroled three days ago.
But I can get you
his P.O.'s contact info.
All right.
You Ray Langston?
Yes.
Nate Haskell says hello.
Trustee!
Get back to work!
Step to the center
of the cell.
LANGSTON:
Hello, Mr. Rose.
My name is Ray Langston,
I work with the crime lab,
and I'm here
to examine you today.
Notice you have a cut there
on your neck.
Can't help but breed
a few enemies in here.
You just hope that they come
at you with spoons not knives.
Breakfast,
couple days ago.
Infirmary already shot photos,
documented the wound,
wrote up a report.
Mm-hmm.
Take your shirt off, please.
(chuckles)
I know how you guys
are feeling.
Wake up one day
and everything's upside down.
Suddenly, what you know to be
impossible is the only thing
anyone else will believe,
because it's written in blood.
Turn around.
You know, when I was framed...
I kept telling myself...
if everything could be upended
in one morning like that,
maybe someday
I'll wake up another day
and everything gets flipped back
the way it should be
just as suddenly.
It took a thousand
mornings for that to
finally happen, Doctor.
I wouldn't count on that
if I were you.
Now shut up and drop your pants.
What sort of
physical evidence
do you guys have?
Anything, uh, interesting
from the dump site?
Well, we're working on it.
Well, what about
that pay phone where
the guy phoned it in?
Sometimes you luck out
with a camera, fingerprints...
Sorry.
(laughs)
Listen to me.
You still have the
instincts, huh, George?
Take care of
yourself, okay?
You, too.
Good to see you.
George?
Hmm?
Whose Cadillac is this?
That's mine-- uh, thing
barely runs anymore.
I just...
I just can't bring
myself to junk it.
I'm gonna need you
to open the trunk for me...
please.
(sighs)
Step over there
for me, please.
What is that?
That's a piece of
a candy bar wrapper.
Same brand Will Sutter
was eating.
I was the only one left
in the building last night.
I was closing up
the vault...
a little after midnight.
Turning off the lights.
Hey!
(Will gasps, thuds to ground)
He was dead.
And I was afraid that
him being inside there
could jeopardize
the evidence.
George, why didn't
you just call it in?
Why didn't you just
let us know about it?
That vault...
is mine to protect.
I keep the records.
I watch over the evidence.
If someone gets inside that's
not supposed to get inside...
that intrusion
can compromise
all the evidence,
can threaten
every conviction.
I was not going
to let that happen.
I put all the Rose
evidence in a new box,
I... signed and
redated the seals
and placed it back
on its spot on the shelf.
I drove out to the vacant lot,
cleaned out
the trunk afterwards...
then called 911.
I didn't want to leave him out
there any longer than I had to.
Well, it looks like this is
where Will Sutter bled out.
It's consistent
with George's story.
What was that kid doing in here?
Take a look at this.
"5-4-A-
0-0-2-8-A."
That's the evidence number
for the Rose case.
With someone's algebra homework
on the back?
I'm guessing... Will Sutter's.
He knew what he
was looking for.
Yeah.
How did he get
this number?
Well, Rose's attorneys
would have it in
their case files.
But anybody in law enforcement
can look that up
on the C-Track
Database.
So what are we saying, that...
Simon Rose
didn't kill Will Sutter
and have his blood
planted on him,
but one of Rose's
associates sent Will
in here to steal evidence?
It looks good
for Rose's appeal
if the prosecution lost
all the evidence.
Yes, but why send a kid?
He's 14 years old,
he's smart,
he follows
instructions well,
and if he gets caught,
he's a juvie--
they just chalk it up to a...
youthful misadventure.
That sounds right,
but why Will Sutter?
What is his connection
to Simon Rose?
MAN (recorded):
Whoever's looking
at Will Sutter's death,
here's your tip: kid's dead,
boy's mother cashes in.
You look at her bank account.
Strange how that happens--
he's dead and she's rich.
(beep)
It came in
as an anonymous tip.
That's Will's dad.
You told me that
he wasn't in your life.
He isn't.
You used to work
at the Shade Club.
Simon Rose was
a silent partner
in that club, spent
a lot of time there.
I served him drinks.
And last week
you deposited
$10,000 into your bank account.
Are you actually
accusing me of something.
Your son broke in
to the police
evidence vault.
He died while trying
to steal evidence
from the Samantha Rose
murder case.
Somebody sent him
on that mission.
Now, between the money
and your affiliation
with Simon Rose, it says
that that somebody was you.
Look, that...
The money?
Will's dad came by last week.
He'd hit some parlay
at the sports book: $50,000.
He was drunk and generous--
gave me $10,000.
I took the money.
God knows he owes me twice
that in child support.
Why is he calling us?
He probably sobered up
when he found out
what happened to Will
and-and got pissed
that I'd still have the money...
all to myself.
What a deal for me, huh?
Look, if you're
gonna arrest me,
then-then do it.
I'm not here to...
Then get the hell
out of my house.
I still can't figure out
how Will got inside the vault.
On the night of his death, the
only thing that enters the vault
are the evidence custodians...
and the evidence.
Wait, go back a little bit.
That's good. Hold it.
Bring up camera three.
You know, I found some beige
microfibers in Will's hair.
Hodges I.D.'d them
as the same type
used in upholstered furniture.
Hand me that evidence
entry list again, please.
Thanks.
"A woman walking her dog
spotted the bloody sofa
"sitting under a streetlight
in a park at 10:30 p.m.
"Evidence custodians were
sent out to retrieve the sofa,
"and it was brought back
to the vault for holding
pending further investigation."
Give me a hand
here, will you?
Cloth has been...
slit along the seam.
Stapled shut at the top.
Open at the bottom.
(chuckles)
Check it out.
LANGSTON:
Trojan horse.
Trojan sofa.
STOKES:
Must have been
pretty terrifying, huh?
All hunkered down,
alone in there in the dark.
LANGSTON:
Brave kid wasted
on a fool's errand.
Will wasn't bleeding when
he came into the vault.
Then where did
that blood come from?
Right.
Yeah. Smells
a little fishy.
Does it?
Yeah, it does.
(sighs):
Hematrace.
Yeah.
Not human.
Blood was just the bait.
Smeared on the sofa
to draw attention.
Sacrificial sea bass
to bless the Trojan voyage.
Captain, you wanted to see me
about the Sutter case?
Sit down.
Will... was actually a
friend of my son, Mason.
But CSI, they've
already talked to him.
Two days ago, you looked up
the Samantha Rose case
on the C-Track
database. Why?
No, I didn't.
Your computer,
4:00 p.m.
Two days ago, 4:00 p.m.,
I would've been...
doing paperwork in my office.
My son stopped by to hang out.
Do some homework.
Was Mason in your office?
Yeah, he said his mom
was bugging him at home,
so I said he
could hang out.
Did he have access
to your computer?
Well... for a minute,
yeah, I guess.
Do you recognize
this sofa?
This looks like
an old one
we got out
in the garage.
Is that blood?
Mason?
Get out here. Now.
(sighs)
(whispers):
My God!
Control, this is
Captain Brass--
we have a 421
Oh, my God!
with head wounds.
Easy, buddy.
Send paramedics
to my location.
Easy, Mason.
Mason must have written down
the Rose evidence number
and given it to Will.
The kid might have miscalculated
more than his algebra.
Found the weapon.
(loud crack)
With a bloody print
on the handle.
You know, either this
assailant's sloppy
and disorganized,
or really, really bold.
SANDERS:
They didn't just
leave a print--
they left a card.
Lynn Stecker, Attorney at Law.
You're lucky
this was on my route
between appointments, Jim.
And whatever you want
to show me better be
earth-shattering.
BRASS:
Do you know him--
Officer Ward?
He one of the guys
on your team?
Never seen him before.
I know you know
his son Mason.
I know you know him,
because we found your
business card in his bedroom.
How dare you.
He's going in and out
of consciousness.
He hasn't said much-- yet.
Yes, I met the kid
earlier today.
He tried to ambush me
in the firm's parking garage.
I say you on TV, and I
know you're trying to get
Simon Rose out of jail,
because nobody knows how his
blood got on that dead kid,
but I do know how.
Look, kid, I don't know
what you're doing here...
Will snuck in the evidence vault
on a dare, all right?
I know how he got in,
and I know how he got
Simon Rose's blood on him.
And if you don't give me $5,000,
I'm gonna tell the cops.
And Simon Rose will
stay in prison forever.
He tried to extort you
and you didn't report it?
I'm reporting it now.
You pay him,
or do you know someone
who plays baseball?
I gave him cab fare.
Told him to get lost.
How much?
I don't know-- whatever
was in my pocket-- $200.
That's like
cab fare to Reno.
A bold and creative
kid like that--
he reminded me of some
of my best interns.
I gave him my card, told him
to call me in a few years.
Let's let him make it
through the night first.
Good luck on that appeal.
So I heard that Mandy matched
the bloody print from the bat
to another crime scene.
Yeah, a swing shift case
from the night before
Will Sutter died.
LANGSTON:
Swing shift CSIs responded
to an extinguished house fire
at 494 Harris Street.
Just northwest of Will Sutter
and Mason Ward's homes.
LANGSTON:
The house had
stood vacant
for the past three months,
but upon entering it,
the CSIs discovered
the following items.
Lighter--
peace pipe...
And the print on that bong
matches a print on the bat.
So somebody parties
in a vacant house,
sets it on fire
and then three days later
attempts to kill Mason Ward?
STOKES:
Yeah, in the meantime,
Mason helps Will sneak
into the evidence vault.
There's got to be
a connection there.
Rose.
The burnt house
was at the corner
of Harris Street
and Rose Street.
Mason must have thought
the address was on Rose Street.
He wanted to retrieve
the evidence.
So Mason went
to his dad's office.
He looked up Rose Street
in the C Track database,
but mistakenly wrote down
the evidence number
for Rose, Samantha.
But we don't have any evidence
of Will being in
that burnt house.
There was no THC
in his tox results.
So he wasn't
partying.
Why did he go in
to get the evidence?
Maybe so he'd be invited
to the next party.
This is a bottle of tequila.
We need to find Steve Reppling.
(knocking)
BRASS:
Las Vegas Police. Open up.
Mr. and Mrs. Reppling,
we need to talk
to your son. Open up.
Anything we can do?
BRASS:
There's nobody home.
I'll be back with a unit--
we'll break down the door.
Call me if you need me.
Copy that, Captain.
Dr. Ray.
Yes?
Something's burning over there.
Wouldn't that be
right around...
The corner of Harris and Rose.
Patrol, this is
Charlie-Zero-Four Sidle.
402 fire, single-family
residence
at the corner
of Harris and Rose Street.
His bike's here.
Steven, where are you?
(coughs)
Steve, we saw
your bicycle outside.
We know you're in here.
There he is.
Get him out of here.
Dr. Ray, come on!
I'll be right behind you.
Let's go!
(distant sirens)
Sara,
we've got, uh,
apparent kindling for the blaze.
SIDLE:
Lynn Stecker gave
Mason Ward $200.
STEVE:
He deserved it.
Excuse me?
Mason deserved to die.
Mason started
everything that night.
He bought some weed
off a sophomore.
Snuck a few bottles
from his dad.
We'd been hanging out
in that house.
Mason...
Wha...?
What did you do?!
I was just messing around
with the lighter,
and then the whole...
I'm gone.
STEVE:
We needed help.
We knew Will
could figure something out.
(knocking)
So we went back over,
and the firemen had
put the fire out,
but the CSIs were bringing out
all the stuff we left in there.
What kind of stuff?
Uh...
Look, Will, you got to help us.
Okay, that stuff is evidence.
They're gonna trace it
and lock us up.
You're the smart one--
you can come up with something.
Just please.
Please.
Come on, man.
All right. Just let me
think for a minute.
Will was smarter, braver,
he was better than both of us.
Two Benjamins.
And I think I can get
even more out of the lady
if I just...
Will died!
Trying to save us.
And what, you're just going
to make money off of that?
All right, you can
have $50 of it, okay?
You got change?
It was blood money,
and I needed to see it burn.
I didn't even care
if I went with it.
We let Will down.
He's the one who deserved
to grow up.
♪ ♪
WILL:
Oh, Mom, this is exactly
the one I wanted!
SUTTER:
That the good one?
Stop.
This is the best
mom in the world.
Ah, I love you, baby.
I love you, too.
I have legal proof now.
I am the best mom.
WILL:
Wow.
Check this out.
We can pop wheelies
right here.
All right.
SUTTER:
Okay, guys, get in
for a group shot.
Hi.