PILOT:
Control, Air 12.
I'm Code Four.
Another quiet night
in the wilderness.
Nothing stirring
but a pack of coyotes.
CONTROL (over radio):
Copy, Air 12.
Whoa. Looks like
they've got company.
Stand by, One.
(helicopter whirring)
PILOT:
I have a visual.
(tires screeching)
Bogey in a blue pickup.
Half mile west of Quadrant Six.
CONTROL:
Copy, Air 12.
I'll alert ground units.
Suspect vehicle westbound
on Paiute Logging Road.
Suspect doubling back,
doubling back.
Eastbound, Paiute Logging Road.
CONTROL:
Two ground units approaching.
Suspect turning southbound.
Suspect turning south.
CONTROL:
Copy, Air 12.
(siren whooping)
PILOT:
Subject heading westbound.
CONTROL:
Park rangers have a visual.
They're in pursuit.
(sirens wailing)
(tires squealing)
PILOT:
Suspect vehicle crashed.
He's on foot.
Control,
situation is Code Four.
Park service notified us.
This is a federal
wildlife refuge.
Nobody should be out here.
That's Juan Ramirez,
suspect, Boulder City.
Buenas noches, Juan.
LANGSTON:
What was he doing out here?
CAVALIERE:
He was dumping trash,
which is what
you guys are here for.
(siren whoops in distance)
(indistinct background
radio communication)
Surgical waste?!
And human organs.
Spleen,
gallbladder
and a finger.
And these cuts--
they're surgically precise.
Hey, guys, we need a tarp
on the ground over here, please.
Nick.
It's just a kid.
Betadine.
This boy was prepped
for surgery.
What are the chances
there's another guy in Vegas
cutting out human organs
on the DL?
No, this is Dr. Jekyll's work.
I never would've expected
him to look like Juan.
Nah.
That's not him.
Hey, Dr. Frankenstein had Igor.
Maybe Dr. Jekyll has Juan.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
(elevator bell dings)
Room service found her
just after 4:00 a.m.
There's no cameras
in the hallway,
and I'm waiting
on the elevator
surveillance.
WILLOWS:
What about the stairs?
Well, hotel
security tells me
that the door
monitoring system
hasn't been triggered
in the last 12 hours.
David.
What have you got?
White marks on the neck,
but they don't go
all the way around,
and there's no indentations
on the skin.
Means she probably
wasn't strangled.
Possible asphyxiation.
Possible.
We have no abrasions
on her legs.
Nothing on her back.
She must have been dead when
the killer dragged her out here.
BRASS: Which means
she was probably killed
in a room on this floor.
Here's her purse.
Smooth skin.
Very little body hair.
Makes her a perfect
candidate for Super Glue.
Call Robbins, have him turn
the thermostat down in autopsy.
And, David,
get the body back stat.
Disturb her as little
as possible.
I'll leave
her clothes on.
SANDERS:
Hey, Don, it's Greg.
WILLOWS:
Karen Jones.
23 from Phoenix.
Yeah, hi, this is Captain Brass.
I'm upstairs.
Do you have a Karen Jones
registered as
a hotel guest?
MAN: No, sir,we don't.
Thank you.
She's not registered.
This might be.
I found some empty bottles
of prescription meds over here:
Fluoxetine, atorvastatin calcium
and Prevalis.
And this shipping order for
herbs and vitamins
from a store
called Botanica Ventura.
You want to bet that Botanica
sells more than just herbs?
That's a good bet.
STOKES:
What about this blood?
It's human.
The fresh drops
are still gummy.
Older ones are flaky.
Multiple events.
This wasn't Igor's
first trash run.
(speaking Japanese)
WILLOWS:
Excuse me.
Did either of you hear
or see anything last night?
(speaking Japanese)
(yelling in Japanese)
Uh, just get a Japanese
officer over here to F.I. them.
Thank you. Arigato.
SANDERS:
So you haven't
slept last night?
I don't know...
Where did those come from?
I-I-I mean, I think I remember
some, like, stripper chicks,
like, trying to grind
up on me, you know?
I don't know, dude.
I was so faded.
(coughs)
I think I'm still drunk.
All right, dude, well,
we need to get your statement,
but first,
you need to brush your teeth.
WILLOWS:
Mr. Crowley, just calm down.
I'm going to miss my plane.
So you're not spending
the weekend?
I'm an actuary.
It was our
annual meeting.
Where were you last night?
A group of us went to dinner
and a show.
(phone rings)
I'm going to need their names.
Well, keep knocking on doors,
'cause we're all on this floor.
Thank you for your help.
Jim, I'm getting a lot
of no answers.
So get a list of all the guests
on 19 including checkouts.
Yeah, I'm on it.
We've been showing Karen Jones'
picture around everywhere.
Somebody had to see her.
Listen, something
may be breaking now.
I'll get back to you.
What do you got, Joe?
Bartender recognized
the photo.
She was here last two nights
with a girlfriend.
With a prostitute girlfriend?
Hard to tell, but they had guys
dripping off them
so if they were working girls,
they were off duty.
Can you describe
the other woman?
Smoking body. Brunette.
I don't remember names. Sorry.
But I do remember that last
night, the girls got into it.
BRASS:
What do you mean?
BARTENDER:
Well, the blonde asked me
to quit serving the brunette;
got a little heated.
Have to say, the girl-fight--
kind of hot.
Okay.
All right, thanks, thanks.
WILLOWS:
We got no eyewitnesses on 19.
Found some white fibers
in her nostril.
Hotel's bedding and towels
were all white.
WILLOWS:
Maybe the killer used what
was available to suffocate her.
68 on the extremities.
70 on the abs.
She's chill.
All right,
that's our test print.
Let's go camping.
♪ ♪
(beeping)
Cansado estoy de esto.
Cansado y sabes
que estas mentiendo.
Estas mentiendo!
¿Que estaba haciendo
en la montaña, pues?
¿Que estaba haciendo allá?
¿Ah? Tenemos
la basura!
Y para salir de aqui...
hay que hablar!
Some guy paid me
to take the trash out there.
Which guy?
I don't know.
I-I was in the parking lot
on Turkson... looking for work.
Guy comes up, gives me $20
if I take the trash up
in the mountains and bury it.
Who killed that little boy?
Did you do it?
You like little boys, huh?
You know what happens to guys
like you in la prisión, hmm?
Give me a name!
El doctor.
He's talking to
you, isn't he?
Yes.
Sometimes I wish
they would tell me more.
they'd just shut up.
What are you hearing?
Well, the blood in his nostrils
and the petechial dots
on his skin tell me
that he was
some kind of bleeder.
His hands are raw
from detergents
or cleansers
of some kind--
tells me he worked hard.
And his teeth, see,
they're worn down by grinding.
Tells me he was probably
in constant pain,
but I don't think it was
a problem with the spleen.
You nailed it.
The splenectomy was a last-ditch
effort to save his life.
The purpose
of this surgery
was to remove this.
Supersized cyst.
It was still in situ.
Which means the surgeon
was unable to remove it
because
he was a bleeder.
Histology showed disseminated
platelet-fibrin
and microvascular thrombi.
Idiopathic thrombocytopenia
purpura.
This boy's immune system
was destroying
his blood platelets,
inhibiting clotting.
So the moment
the incision was made,
the bleeding would have been
unstoppable and the surgeon
probably panicked.
And because platelet destruction
occurs in the spleen,
the surgeon would have hoped
once it was removed,
new platelets would form
and his blood would start
clotting again.
Four months ago,
our Dr. Jekyll made a bow tie
with Joey Bigelow's intestines.
A month ago, he implanted
a superfluous appendix
into Bernard Higgins.
Cystectomy
and splenectomy are...
routine procedures.
If he did this, he's not
limiting himself to perversity.
He's operating both inside
and outside the norm.
A true Jekyll and Hyde.
I went through all
the camera footage
from the casino bar.
Karen Jones and her friend
got there
around 8:00 last night.
Well, now we know
what she's wearing:
Sequined dress,
silver stilettos.
What about all
these guys?
Lots of approaches,
no landings.
The bartender was right.
There was an altercation
between the girls.
Nothing to write
Penthouse about.
Picked up Karen
at a casino ATM camera
about an hour later.
She's working him.
He's not interested.
Probably didn't want
to pay for it.
Can't blame a girl
for trying, though.
He's obviously
got cash.
Exit camera picked her up
leaving the casino
at 10:37 p.m. solo.
What time did she come back?
Around 3:30 a.m.
Got her going up
the elevator
at 3:33, in a hurry.
Got off on 19.
So her john
had to be on that floor.
Probably checked
out by now.
So what we need to do
is find that girl
in the blue dress.
WILLOWS: Have Brass show
her picture around.
(PDA beeping)
My body's done.
Smurf's up.
♪ ♪
(camera shutter clicks)
LANGSTON:
So what do we have
on the pickup truck?
ADAMS: First priority
is an I.D. on the bleeder.
Now, he wasn't in CODIS,
but I did get a familial hit.
This is Carlos Gomez.
He's doing time for assault,
and he I.D.'d the victim's
autopsy photo
as his son Eduardo.
It turns out Eduardo was working
as a night janitor at a motel
on Bonanza and Albert.
That's only a couple of blocks
from where Joey Bigelow
was found.
Anything on the body
parts or blood evidence?
Well, the spleen
was the victim's.
The gallbladder and the fingers
were from
unrelated donors.
And as far as the rest,
I'm working on it.
What about the surgical
evidence we found
in the trash bags?
The syringes
all contained
2% lidocaine solution.
Local anesthetic
for minor surgeries.
And analysis of the
tubing confirmed
intravenous diazepam--
a Schedule IV
Controlled Substance;
probably used
to twilight patients.
All the empty bottles
of pharmaceuticals
were from Mexico;
prescription-only,
here and there.
So maybe Dr. Jekyll
has a Mexico connection.
Yeah, it could be this
Botanica Ventura place.
What do we know about it?
It's a storefront leased
by a guy named
Jeffrey Hughes.
Now there were
good clean
prints on those
drug bottles,
I just can't confirm
they're his.
No AFIS hits.
So we're gonna go check him out.
Warrant's on its way.
I want to be there.
(siren wails)
You two stay here.
You two come with me.
¿Allá?
¿Aqui, ah?
(quiet conversation
in Spanish)
CAVALIERE:
Jeffrey Hughes?
Yes?
Yeah, we have a warrant
to search the premises.
So if everybody
could please get up.
Afuera, por favor!
¿Que debo hacer, doctor?
Yo me encargo de esto.
El doctor.
I'm not a doctor.
I'm an herbalist.
All we sell is herbs,
vitamins, supplements.
Does that include
prescription drugs?
You've seen my customers.
Their ancestors were the Maya.
The Mayans believe that wellness
resides in a balance
of body and spirit;
man and God.
We're not here
for a history lesson.
Man has always been imperfect.
I do what I can.
That warrant
includes your prints.
I'd like to take
those now.
Give me your hand, please.
LANGSTON:
Does "doing all that you can"
include procedures
or surgeries?
Like I said, I am not a doctor.
What's back there?
Just a storeroom.
(beeps)
Mr. Hughes, your prints were
found on crime scene evidence.
You're under arrest.
Come with me.
CAVALIERE:
Escort this young lady
to a car, as well.
STOKES:
No table.
No surgical equipment
lying around.
LANGSTON: Suppose it would've
been easier if we'd walked in
and found a laparoscope.
Hmm.
But Dr. Jekyll or no, he
had to have some tools.
STOKES:
We'll get a warrant
for his house.
Eduardo Gomez lost
a lot of blood.
If there was an
operating table in here,
it would have been
in the middle of the room.
And he would have needed
some light.
All right, that's bright enough
for surgery.
The boy's blood
would've dripped down here
off the table.
STOKES:
Could've used bleach
to clean it up.
Bleach only cleans
the surface.
Unless you really saturate it,
it's not gonna get down
to the grout.
Nick, the grout
in these two areas is
two different shades.
Yep, the tiles on this floor
have been regrouted, Nick.
The difference is subtle,
but I can feel it.
Well, I can only think
of one reason you'd
bleach and regrout.
LANGSTON:
We have blood.
If it belonged
to Eduardo Gomez...
it means he died here.
BRASS:
Karen Jones' bank account shows
that she paid for three nights,
using her debit card.
Anybody with her?
No. She checked in
two nights ago.
She was alone.
What do you got?
Room's all clear,
Captain.
Not bad
for Fremont Street.
BRASS:
Got some luggage.
Looks like she
didn't check out.
Do you smell that?
Hasn't ripened into decomp yet.
♪ ♪
The girl in the blue dress.
BRASS: She's definitely
not sleeping it off.
♪ ♪
(beep)
SANDERS:
Hey, Catherine.
I found two suitcases
in Karen Jones' motel room,
and one of them belongs to a...
Jillian Rose from Phoenix.
(over phone):
Gotta be the girl
in the blue dress.
Great.
Have Brass run her.
(phone beeps off)
Meet Jillian Rose.
Oh. Ms. Rose has got
quite a few contusions.
WILLOWS:
Yeah. Defensive wounds.
Nasty lump on her forehead.
No internal hemorrhaging,
not fatal but
probably happened
during the struggle.
What's C.O.D.?
Petechial hemorrhaging
in the eyes and lips...
white marks, but...
no indentations in the neck.
Just like her friend--
she was asphyxiated.
Uh, didn't find any trace
in her nose or esophagus.
She was suffocated
before she was put
into that box spring.
Any indication
what time she died?
Ballpark: Sometime
between midnight
and 4:00 a.m.
Karen Jones and Jillian Rose,
friends from the same town,
sharing the same room,
killed in a similar manner
around the same time.
But their bodies were found
in two different locations.
Are we looking
for two killers?
My gut says that we're not.
Well, if just one guy did this,
she had to have
been killed first.
So the blood in the truck bed
and the trash bags
came from multiple donors,
both male and female.
Including Eduardo Gomez?
And you were right--
that was his blood
in the grout.
But I also found a second
contributor in the grout sample.
It was an unknown male.
They're probably
my epithelials.
I had to palpate the
grout-- you can't do
that with gloves on.
Well, in that case, I just
need a sample of your DNA,
and I will exclude you.
My DNA-- which would
go into a database.
Your fingerprints are already
in AFIS-- what's the difference?
There's a big difference.
You're gonna have to put
in your report that I said no.
Mrs. Hughes.
We have a warrant
to search the premises.
(slaps folder down)
LANGSTON:
All right, Mr. Hughes,
Eduardo Gomez died
in your operating room.
I don't have
an operating room.
But you knew him.
I knew his whole family.
His mother was a loyal customer.
Did you tell his mother
that you dumped him
with the rest of the trash
from your other surgeries?
I mean, it must have
been a busy night.
You, um, removed
a gallbladder;
you amputated a
gangrenous finger;
you attempted to remove
Eduardo's abdominal cyst.
So tell me, where
did you train, Doctor?
I graduated premed
at Harvard,
and celebrated in Cozumel,
where I fell in love
with a local girl.
So I, uh,
went to medical school
in Guadalajara
and trained at a hospital
in Monterey.
LANGSTON:
And are you licensed
to practice
in the United States?
HUGHES:
You know the answer to that.
LANGSTON:
Yes, I do.
So you were
smuggling drugs,
you were practicing
without a license in
unsafe conditions,
all of which cost
Eduardo Gomez his life.
I was trying to save his life!
He is the sole support
of his mother
and his newborn sister.
They're here
without documentation.
No insurance.
He was in so much pain,
he couldn't travel
to Mexico for surgery.
I couldn't turn him away.
Eduardo presented
with obvious signs of ITP.
I misdiagnosed.
By the time I knew what was
going on, it was too late.
His mother was there.
She made the decision
to dispose of the body.
She doesn't blame me.
I delivered her baby!
Her perfectly healthy infant.
Eduardo was the first patient
ever to die in my care.
Well, what about
Joey Bigelow
and Bernard Higgins?
Hmm?
What about them?
I don't know these men.
This isn't medicine.
Look, I don't run
a practice to get rich.
I... help those
the system ignores.
The nanny whose gallbladder
is inflamed,
the gardener who risks his life
for a gangrenous finger.
There are clinics,
social services
for that kind of thing.
Reform health care all you want.
My patients are always
gonna be left out.
Had the casino send over
some more surveillance footage,
this time tracking our
second victim, Jillian Rose.
Started with Karen
and Jillian at the bar,
and I noticed something.
A few minutes after
their little argument,
Karen and Jillian went
on the hunt-- separately.
That's when I found this.
WILLOWS: Oh, she landed
the ATM guy.
The one that Karen couldn't.
They got off on 19.
STOKES: Six minutes later,
she's texting, coming down.
That's not even enough time
for a quickie.
And why would
two hookers go after
the same john?
'Cause maybe
they aren't hookers.
And I don't think
this is about sex.
Karen Jones and Jillian Rose
were running a con.
One of them would steal
the guy's PIN number,
the other would steal
his credit card.
Who am I looking at?
Their mark.
That's Karen with
him at the ATM,
and an hour later,
Jillian went up to his room
on the 19th floor.
We never talked to him,
so he's got to be one
of the checkouts.
Let's go back
to the Mediterranean.
BRASS:
So, the room is registered
to Donald Fiore.
He works as an actuary;
he's here for the convention.
The maid I.D.'d him
from a photo.
She said she saw nothing unusual
when she cleaned up, so...
SANDERS:
We're only three doors down
from where we found
Karen Jones' body.
When did Fiore check out?
Well, he didn't.
He left his key in the room,
and the hotel automatically
checks him out at noon.
Right, so he could've
checked out anytime.
Fiore lives
in Salt Lake City--
I spoke to the local cops.
(phone rings)
They said they'd
keep an eye on him,
but they weren't
gonna arrest him
until we provided them
with more evidence.
I gotta take this.
Good luck.
Brass. Talk to me.
(door shuts)
Okay. So...
the maid would have vacuumed,
emptied the trash,
cleaned the bathroom,
changed the towels...
And the sheets, too.
Hotel laundry will
all be commingled.
And if he threw her clothes
in the trash, well...
that's like looking for a needle
inside a stack of needles,
so... what part
of the room remains
from guest to guest?
(door opens)
♪ ♪
STOKES: Looks like somebody
messed with this vent.
Oh...
Got a pair of shoes.
No dress, though.
Karen Jones...
had silver stilettos.
They're all wet.
I didn't see any condensation
in the vent.
Heels have been
snapped off.
And the soles
are... are bent.
I mean... this didn't
happen during the struggle.
He was trying
to get rid of these.
(sighs)
He flushed the dress,
but he couldn't get
the shoes to go down.
SANDERS: If the dress
is still in this pipe,
then the toilet
would be backed up.
And you know
what rolls downhill.
Okay. We're ready.
(flushing)
Greg, stop.
We've got something.
How may feet of cable
do you have out?
Uh, about 20.
About ten feet per floor.
So, that's...
Two floors below.
1721.
(power saw grinding)
(groans)
I think that's enough
to compel a warrant.
I didn't realize I was set up
until I was in the shower.
Oh, God, your body
is unbelievable!
And you'll get to
taste all of it.
(moans)
As soon as you shower.
I'll be right here,
thinking about what
I'm going to do to you.
(shower running)
FIORE:
She stole my wallet.
I should have known.
She was...
too beautiful
to be a hooker.
I called my bank,
found out that they had
used my credit
card and PIN,
took a $2,000 cash advance.
That's a $50 bank charge,
accrues at 28% interest.
Why didn't you just report it?
Well, if I called the cops
and you found them,
then there would be reports
saying that I had brought
a girl back to my room,
and I couldn't take the risk
of my wife finding out.
She's an heiress.
Has all the money.
Simple cost-benefit analysis.
How does that analysis work?
Their lives for your wallet?
The solve rates
for murders, for homicides
in Clark County?
62%.
My wife finds out
that I'm philandering?
That's a 100% chance of divorce.
But since
you didn't cheat,
you figured
that she would be okay
with you murdering
Karen and Jillian?
I never saw Jillian again.
As far as her friend goes,
she came looking for me.
(door closes)
You want it back?
It's gonna cost you.
Just-Just give it to me,
and I'll forget the whole thing.
I don't think so.
FIORE:
I saw that the safety
was still on, so...
I took my chances.
Prostitutes are 60 to
100 times more likely
to be murdered than
non-prostitutes.
So I flushed the dress, and I
pulled her out into the hallway.
I calculated the likelihood
that you would think
that she was a hooker
and wouldn't be a priority.
You calculated wrong.
Regardless, I acted
in self-defense.
Yeah, right up until
you suffocated her.
Well, acquittal rates
for self-defense claims
are very high-- jurors
tend to judge the motives
of a beautiful con woman
much more harshly
than an overworked actuary.
♪ ♪
Hodges.
Yeah?
I need you to tell me
what this is.
Gray fibers.
Maybe a recycled
synthetic.
Oh, yeah.
It's polyester
polyfill fiber.
Commonly used in
box spring padding.
Don't you have to do
an FTIR to confirm that?
Just did one.
On your motel girl;
the one stuffed into
the box spring.
Are you saying this fiber
is from the same box spring?
I'm just saying that it's
the same type of material.
Your two victims
shared the room.
What are the chances that
it's not from that box spring?
Karen had to have come into
contact with the box spring
after it was cut open.
Which puts her in the room
after Jillian was dead.
Or after Karen killed her.
I'd hate to think Fiore's
telling the truth.
Okay, so, there were no fibers
in Jillian's nose or throat.
So Karen had to have used
something non-textile
to asphyxiate her.
Shower curtain was intact.
Plastic laundry bags were
clean and folded in the closet.
Trash can liner.
STOKES:
There was nothing in it,
so I didn't collect it.
You had no reason to.
STOKES: Looks like
a lipstick smudge to me.
Who kisses a trash bag?
Maybe a girl fighting
for her life.
Those are carpal prints.
WILLOWS: No way those
are Karen's prints.
They're too big.
Karen didn't kill her.
(Karen gasps, screams)
SANDERS:
She came back to the room
and found Jillian dead.
Then Karen hid Jillian
inside the box spring
to buy herself some time.
WILLOWS:
She then...
took the wallet over
to the hotel room
and tried to extort money
from Fiore.
Live by the con,
die by the con.
Mr. Fiore.
There's been a development.
We need your
major case prints.
I already gave you my prints.
And I admitted to killing
Karen Jones in self-defense.
That was a standard ten-card.
Give me your right hand.
And if I refuse?
Then I'm going to get six
of the biggest deputies
you've ever seen
to come in here and assist you.
(scanner whirrs)
(rapid electronic trilling)
Jillian Rose
was suffocated with a trash
liner from her motel room,
and your prints are on it.
How did you find out
where she was staying?
I wanted my wallet back.
FIORE:
I went out looking for Jillian,
and I saw her
at the casino next door.
She jumped into a cab,
and I followed her.
(lock clicks, door opens,
then shuts)
(knocking on door)
Open up or I'll call the police.
Give me my wallet,
you bitch!
I don't have it!
Give me my wallet!
I swear!
I want my wallet!
(muffled screams)
It was
a mathematical certainty
that a woman like that
would report the assault
or she would blackmail me
for the rest of my life.
The only logical thing
to do was to kill her.
And you applied
that same logic
when Karen Jones showed up
at your door?
(chuckles)
You know what that
stupid girl did?
She-She pointed a gun at me,
and she demanded
that I give her $50,000
for her friend's funeral.
Well, according to my math,
the $50,000 that you saved
is going to cost you
20 years to life.
W-Wait...
Look, I-I am a good man.
I work hard.
I love my wife.
I contribute to society.
I mean, these people,
you deal with them all the time.
And those girls?
They were just... they were
just worthless criminals.
No, they were human beings.
You're the worthless criminal.
Okay, I'll come by your place.
No, no, it's cool.
I have tomorrow off.
Hey, Nick?
STOKES:
I'll call you back.
Listen, I need
to talk to you.
Uh, I had Wendy
run the markers
for race on the appendix
implanted in Bernard Higgins.
It was
non-Hispanic Caucasian.
Now, all the body parts we found
in the truck were Hispanic.
I don't think Hughes
is Dr. Jekyll.
Regardless, we-we got him
for drug trafficking.
We got him for practicing
without a license
and Eduardo Gomez's death.
Yeah. Yeah.
He's not going anywhere.
Agreed.
I need a favor.
I think your Spanish is a
little better than mine.
Would you take a look
at that for me, please?
(clears throat)
"Clinica gratis."
Okay. Free clinic.
"Pedíatra, emergencias,
medicina general."
I thought I was the only one
trying to save the world.
(chuckles)
I don't approve of the
way Hughes went about it,
but he had the right idea.
This clinic I volunteer at,
it's safe, it's free,
it's legal.
I just want to
spread the word.
What do you think? Claro?
Sí, claro.
Thanks, Nick.
De nada.