(siren wails)
(sighs)
I am not ready for this.
Yeah, you are.
Besides, you got to be.
Dr. Ray's still on leave
from the concussion.
We're all tapped out.
I got a multiple
in Northtown.
Call me if you need
anything, okay?
(indistinct chatter)
(garbled police radio
transmission)
♪ ♪
(flashbulb pops)
(coughing)
Damn it, Derrick, you're
screwing up my one-to-ones.
DERRICK:
Sorry.
This stuff is giving me
the desire for pancakes.
WOMAN: Yeah, me, too.
(laughter)
(groans)
Kids.
Okay,
crime cadets, this is
serious crime-fighting business,
so... back to
being dead,
please.
Excuse me, CSI Hodges?
Yes.
CSI Hodges,
th-that's me.
Katy Cypress.
Nice to meet you.
Look, I know
that this is just a program
for wannabe CSIs.
And this exercise does test
observational and
evidence-collection skills.
Yes.
Is it at least based
on a real case?
No.
This is just
brute-force rote work.
I couldn't agree with you more.
The real fun
is nailing bad guys.
And that's about
interpreting the evidence
and solving
a real mystery.
That's what... you do,
and that's what I want to do.
Okay.
I'll tell you what.
Let's finish up here,
and then you
grab a couple
of your cadet buddies
and meet me at the Crime Lab
for a real challenge--
if you're
up to it.
Oh, I am up to it.
Guillermo.
He'd love to do it.
(laughs):
He has no life.
I collect spores,
molds and fungi.
You, too, Derrick--
it'll be fun.
(beeping)
Grab a seat.
(laughs)
Are we waiting on Derrick?
Uh, no. He's not coming.
He has video-game
issues.
Ah.
These files
are from a case we investigated
four months ago.
You said you wanted
to match wits with real CSIs.
Now's your chance.
Among the many
consequences
of a construction boom
are structures
that are thrown together
with little regard
for building codes.
The fire department
responded quickly.
But even so,
the lower three levels
of this apartment building were
almost completely consumed.
The firemen, or,
as we like to call them,
the "Evidence
Eradication Crew,"
got the blaze under control.
But they were
utterly unprepared
for the astonishing sight
waiting there to greet them.
Oh, boy, do I
remember that one.
It was an
incredible case.
I mean, like, you would never
even believe it was possible
unless you saw
the evidence yourself.
Yeah, which is why
I was about to show it to them.
Oh.
Hey. I'm Wendy.
And you are...?
Crime cadets.
Guillermo.
KATY:
Could we see the
body already,
please?
Yeah. Okay.
Hey.
I tell it better
than you.
Trust me, you guys
are really gonna
enjoy this.
What used to be
the parking garage
was filled with the contents
of a dozen apartments,
everything charred
virtually beyond recognition...
with one incredible exception.
The CSIs had never seen
anything like it.
I've never seen
There's barely a mark on her.
Given the amount of available
fuel consumed by this fire,
I'd say we
should be looking
at a pile of roasted
flesh and bone.
The body must have been put here
after the fire was extinguished.
There were a dozen cops
and two dozen
firefighters
on the scene.
The likelihood of anyone
carrying a body into this
and getting out unseen
is... slim to none.
HODGES:
That's when I said...
It's as if...
the fire refused to touch her.
Excuse me?
And then Wendy said...
HODGES:
The question is,
is it miracle or murder?
Uh, please familiarize yourself
with this evidence report.
(quietly): That's what you're
doing, you're lying to children?
It's a teaching exercise.
It's an exercise in self-love.
Just play along
and be a role model, please?
Uh, no. Why would
I play along with you?
Because if you
can't even imagine yourself
out in the field, how
will you ever expect Ecklie to?
(loudly):
Okay, so there we were.
The question is,
is it miracle...
or murder?
Either way, she tried as best
as she could to survive.
(laughs)
Sounds like something
I would say.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
STOKES:
You look like you've dropped
a few pounds there, Barclay.
You been working out
or something?
Yeah, new diet.
No more donuts or sugary snacks,
just-just pure protein.
All beef, all day.
Trading the diabetes
for a heart attack.
(phone rings)
Good call.
Yeah, what's up, Cath?
I'm in Mega-Lo-Mattress hell.
Found another DB in a quilt.
I'll be here a while.
Oh, that's okay-- I just
wrapped up
my 419, I'll hold down the f...
(man clears throat)
(retching)
(laughter)
Nicky?
(laughs)
WOMAN:
Oh, my God!
(loud retching)
Nicky? You there?
Yeah, yeah, I'm here.
(retching)
Yeah, it looks like
I'm gonna be tied up
for a little while longer
here, Catherine.
BARCLAY: Need paramedics and
HazMat down to the squad.
GUILLERMO:
Okay, I see it.
The concrete around the furnace
is pitted and chipped,
most likely from
rapid thermal expansion.
It's called "spalling."
Now, take a look
at the vent pipes.
What do they
tell you?
They're rusty.
And since fire is essentially
a rapid oxidation reaction...
It means that
the furnace
is most likely
where the fire started.
Very good.
This has got to be arson.
What makes you say that?
Most fires are
either started
because of insurance fraud or
to cover up evidence of a crime.
GUILLERMO:
And that certainly is a crime.
Were all
the tenants
accounted for?
And were any able to
identify the victim?
Good questions...
for a detective.
So, all the tenants
have been accounted for.
I showed her picture
around, but, uh,
no one recognized her.
Or so they say.
Thanks, Captain.
We'll, uh,
let you know
what we come up with.
(chuckles)
That's great.
You know what?
Nobody gives a damn
about life or death.
That's the truth.
So why should I?
Why should you?
(slurring):
Do you know what the
best thing to do is?
Is to just to go home...
and cuddle up
with someone you love...
and just...
forget...
...just forget about
all this-this...
madness.
(Hodges exhales)
But that would let them all
off the hook, wouldn't it?
So, you know what
I'm gonna do?
I'm gonna go home,
I'm gonna get painted up,
put on some Kevlar,
go on a five-state
shooting spree
and take out these scumbags
one at a time. Screw 'em.
And then let
copper-jacketed
justice take its
sweet release.
Ooh, ouch.
(chuckles) What?
(laughing)
What?!
What the heck? No.
(laughs): No, I'm not going
to do that, all right?
(sputters)
No, I choose life.
Keep me apprised.
HODGES:
FYI, the alcoholism rate
among police officers
is double the national average.
Suicide rate's triple.
Really?
KATY:
Hey, uh, wait a second.
That tub-- where's it from?
It's, uh, from apartment 2B,
second floor.
SIMMS:
Whose tenant just happened
to be out of town
right before the fire.
Does he have a record?
No, but he wasn't exactly
a model citizen, either.
He'd had run-ins
with the landlord before
over illegal sublets.
Okay.
Check this out...
off-the-books sublet girl
was in the tub
when the fire breaks out.
She dies of carbon monoxide
poisoning,
leaving no marks on the body.
She was still in the tub
when the flames
torched the floor
and it all came tumbling down.
So, the bath oil
on her skin acts
like a shield
long enough to protect her
from the flames until
she is discovered.
That's not a bad theory.
And for a while,
it was our theory.
It was also
the wrong theory.
HODGES:
Most essential oils
in bath gels
have a flash point
of under 250 degrees.
With a fire that hot,
it would've actually
drawn the flames to her,
not protect her.
All right.
Well, since
we know it's arson,
if we identify
the victim,
it could lead us
to the arsonist.
Yeah.
What'd you get
from Autopsy?
For that, you'll need a coroner.
And, uh, luckily,
I happen to know where we
can find one.
Take five.
ANDREWS:
Hey, Hodges.
Oh, hey, Henry.
Yes?
Remember that time
you said that thing
about your having
a higher commitment
to the lab
and the pursuit of justice?
Yeah, I've probably
said that more than once.
Yeah, you have.
For the record,
I find it admirable
and Wendy does, too.
She does?
Yeah.
We were chatting about it last
weekend at the blood bank.
We donate together.
Oh.
No, B-positive.
Actually, Wendy
and I have
a lot in common.
We dabble in
calligraphy,
we're both
passionate
about French neoclassical
architecture,
and we are both
allergic to eggplant.
Look, I was just thinking
that I should ask her out
on a date, and I assume that
you'd be cool with that,
due to your admirable
commitment to the lab.
So are you
cool with that?
Totally.
Great.
Great, yes, see?
That is awesome.
Thank you, you're
a man of principle.
(chuckles)
Uh, Wendy.
SIMMS: Hey.
ANDREWS: Hello.
What's up?
Good.
How are you? Hi.
Um, I was wondering if you want
to go out to eat tonight
after work.
Yeah.
Yeah?
Okay.
All right, yeah,
I'm just gonna...
(Simms chuckling)
MAN (over P.A.):
Attention, all personnel...
quarantine is still in effect
until further notice.
Continue to observe all
class-four protocol.
(devices beeping)
No anthrax, no ricin,
no botulinum.
And no plague and no tularemia.
We're good, people.
Area's clear.
(sighs)
Well, if it's not in the air
or a contact toxin,
it has to be something
they ate or drank.
Wouldn't be the first
time a bunch of cops
cheaped out on a dinner
and ended up
spewing out
of both ends.
You're a CSI.
It's not your problem.
I think I'm making it
mine tonight.
SANDERS:
Have you
encountered
any cases recently
with similar symptoms?
Projectile vomit,
sweats, diarrhea?
I mean, it could be
almost anything thing.
You know, there's
a lot of stuff
going around.
This town is a petri dish.
(grunting)
Hey, Jenkins...
how you doing?
(moans)
I will get out of here
in a second to let you
get back to sleep.
But I need you to tell me
everything you had to eat
or drink today.
(muttering)
(retching)
Uh, nurse?
Hey, kids, you know,
a lot of people
believe that all a coroner
does is determine
cause, manner,
and time of death.
And in a case like this,
there is so much more
to discover.
All you have to do is look.
Her prints weren't
in the system.
And no bodies matching
her description
were in missing persons.
The condition of her...
...area is consistent
with recent sexual activity.
But her wet mount
came back negative
for, uh...
Semen?
Thank you.
I believe this woman had
safe sex before she died.
GUILLERMO:
Could we get
to the C.O.D. please?
Not so fast.
You'll miss it.
The victim had
very poor dental hygiene:
plaque with numerous cavities,
crowns made of white gold--
a substance not commonly used
in the United States.
All of which led me to conclude
that the victim was Russian...
GUILLERMO:
Russian or Eastern European.
Obviously.
This is, uh,
"Vokovushka,"
the Russian Mighty Mouse.
Perhaps she was
a tourist?
What are these
glossy patches on her skin?
I-I don't know.
I sent samples to Trace.
Talk to Trace.
Actually, Trace loves to talk.
I'd suggest carving out
a couple hours
and taking snacks.
C.O.D.?
Right.
There's no soot
in the trachea.
(cat meowing, man laughs nearby)
Lung tissue color
is normal.
(laughing)
(laughter, meowing continue)
There's no sign
of carbon monoxide
pink at all.
(meowing)
Meow.
(phone ringing)
(sighs)
Hello, Morgue.
Of course.
I'm always ready.
Right.
All right, the CSIs are
on their way down.
She didn't inhale smoke.
Give me your notes.
Get out!
(clears throat)
PHILLIPS:
You see, tox
revealed a BAC
of .30 with several
benzodiazepine sedatives,
along with zolpidem
in her system.
Now, while the individual levels
were sublethal...
The combination was...
Deadly. That's right.
C.O.D. was multiple drug
overdose.
The victim was dead
before the fire.
I was about
to say that.
Too bad I said it first.
STOKES:
Here you go.
Now, we're starting off small.
This is only the
stuff from the desks
of the officers who
actually got sick.
This is starting small?
Yep.
And you better get the
GCMS fired up, boss.
Greg's bringing in vomit,
blood and fecals.
(slapping)
(tapping rhythmically)
Get it going.
SIMMS:
In an arson investigation,
after you find the area
of origin,
the next thing you look for
is any sort
of incendiary device,
faulty wiring,
flammable fluid--
basically any ignition source
in the general vicinity.
Hey, Wendy.
Come take a look at this.
It's a natural gas line.
It's uncapped.
There's no tarnish
on these tool marks.
This was done recently.
Yeah.
Did you find the gas cap
at the scene?
Hodges.
Hmm?
Uh, no.
And we sifted
through a ton of char.
KATY:
I'm sure you're still
finding soot in places
you don't want to talk about.
Well, no gas cap
means no accident.
That proves that, uh,
we're right about arson.
So it would seem.
(grinding)
SIMMS:
We removed
a section of the pipe
to preserve the tool marks.
But what we didn't know
was that
this crime scene--
it very well
could have been our last.
(grinding)
(clattering)
No!
(sighs)
SIMMS:
Shortly thereafter, the city
declared the building
structurally unsound, and...
that was the last time
CSI was allowed in.
He saved my life.
He saved the evidence, too.
SANDERS (sighs):
You got to be kidding me.
What do you mean,
the GCMS run isn't done yet?
It was supposed to be done
an hour ago.
I don't know what's going on.
Well, I have a bunch
of sick cops
who need answers,
and if you have
to pull another shift
to get it done,
you're going
to have to.
Let me look at this.
(sighs)
Henry,
the run cycle's been altered.
You set it to
perform a cleaning
and test cycle
after each sample.
No, I didn't set it like that.
I swear.
Well, maybe a power interruption
could have reset it
to a default.
There you go.
Problem solved.
You lucked out.
Yeah.
♪ ♪
The uncapped gas line
was the fuel.
What else do you
need to make a fire?
A spark.
That's right.
And I've got a whole box
full of sparks right over here.
Take a look.
According
to this maintenance record,
this breaker box was serviced
the same day as the fire.
GUILLERMO: And it looks
like the same company
maintains the gas lines.
HODGES:
They do.
The police questioned
the maintenance man,
but the CSIs found this
in his van.
KATY:
The pipe cap?
The arsonist kept evidence
of the crime on him?
Serial killers often
keep souvenirs.
The maintenance man
told the cops that he had gone
to the apartment building
to service the gas line
and removed the cap,
which had become corroded.
But when he returned
to his van
to find a replacement,
he found he didn't have one,
so he left.
He left the gas line uncapped?
He said he forgot.
He thought he closed
the gas line completely, but he
must have left a slow leak,
which he didn't notice
because he was losing
his sense of smell--
or so he claimed.
His medical records
confirmed that.
GUILLERMO:
So, natural gas
gradually filled the room...
KATY:
Until there was enough,
so that when the furnace
clicked on...
(clicking)
Whoosh.
Indeed.
It was an accident.
Which means that it wasn't set
to destroy the victim's body.
Our theory was completely wrong.
HODGES:
You said you
wanted a challenge.
ANDREWS:
Wendy!
Hey.
Hi.
Uh, I got great news.
I had to call in a couple
of favors, but I got us
a reservation
at the Eiffel Tower Restaurant.
It's, like,
the best view in Vegas.
Wow.
ANDREWS:
That's cool, right?
SIMMS: It-it's, uh...
a little more
fancy-pants
than the cop diner
that I'd been picturing.
(chuckling):
No. I, um... I was going
to surprise you,
but then I thought, you know,
the gentlemanly thing to do
would be to let you know,
so you could dress
appropriately
for the occasion.
I'm going to go home on
my lunch break and get my suit.
You're wearing a suit?
Ce sera parfaît.
It means, "It will be perfect."
SIMMS:
Um...
(chuckling)
STOKES:
According to Henry,
there were no drugs,
poisons or toxins in any
of the food or drink samples
I collected.
We'll just have to test
every consumable in the station.
It's shigella.
Positive?
I called in a favor
at the hospital's microbio lab.
We just did cultures
on each of the sick unis.
They all have it.
Okay, well,
shigella is food-borne.
It typically vectors through
unsanitary handling practices.
Yeah, but something
doesn't make sense.
According to what the unis
told me between pukes...
(man clears throat)
...none of them ate any
of the same things today,
so how did they all come down
with the same
bacterial infection?
STOKES:
I might be able to answer that.
I'll call you back.
Hey, Nick. What's up?
Hold out your hands, Metcalf.
And, uh, don't touch me,
please.
So, basically, we have
an accidental fire
and a victim whose body
managed to remain
unburned in it.
GUILLERMO:
These patches on her skin,
did you guys get
anything useful from Trace?
You always get
something from Trace.
CSI Hodges.
Trace Tech Langston.
What do you have for me?
The question, CSI Hodges,
is what don't I have for you?
I used, uh, polarized light
microscopy to identify
the glossy patches
on your victim's skin.
And not to sound corny, but I
think you'll find the results
a-maize-ing.
Starch molecules.
Vaporized cornstarch,
to be precise.
Did you know the word
"cornstarch" is derived
from the Middle English
"sterchen"
meaning "to stiffen,"
which is apropos
to the condition of your vic.
(laughs) Langston, the way
that your rapier wit
envelopes critical information,
is just so...
Thrilling?
That's exactly
what I was going to say.
Now, you say you derived
these results
from a simple
polarized light test?
Lesser men would have
resorted to using the GCMS.
Why use a sledgehammer
to kill a fly?
I bow to the master.
Nonsense.
"You are great.
I am great."
M-5.
The Ultimate Computer.
Star Trek, the original series.
Is there any other?
It's like you're inside my head.
(both laughing)
That Trace tech
sounds kinda...
Obsequious.
Misunderstood.
You look concerned.
I am.
How does somebody get coated
in vaporized cornstarch?
Body powder?
SIMMS:
It's a health-conscious
alternative to talc.
I doubt that powder would be
thick enough to account for...
Peanuts.
Cornstarch peanuts.
Packing material.
She was killed and packed
in the box with the peanuts.
The cardboard and the
cornstarch acted as insulation,
to protect the body
from the flames.
Until the firemen arrived,
blasting everything
with their hoses,
which separated
her from whatever
remained of the box.
Congratulations.
You have just matched
wits with the CSIs.
SIMMS:
Nicely done.
Hmm!
Okay, so what's next?
Based on what we have here,
nothing.
That's as far we got.
But we never
ID'd the body.
Or the killer.
Neither did we.
What?
That sucks.
HODGES: Yes.
But what doesn't suck
is that yesterday,
the city declared the building
structurally sound.
So, after you have
your parents fax me
their written permission
indemnifying
the Crime Lab for any
injuries you may sustain,
we're going on a field trip.
So, my suit's done then?
Great. No, I'm on my way.
You didn't crease the pants
though, did you, Mom?
'Cause there is nothing
worse than...
(rattling, hissing)
Huh?
Oh, no. No, no, no.
I'll call you back.
No, no-no-no.
Not today.
♪ ♪
What?
Ow.
(coughing)
Ah! No!
Car trouble?
Yeah, no kidding.
This ruins my whole
lunch break,
and I had things to do.
You know, Henry, maybe
you should stay out
of parking garages.
Bad things seem
to happen to you there.
(music plays over stereo)
WILLOWS:
Henry?
Hmm?
I don't mind taking
time out of my day
to check out your radiator hose,
'cause, clearly,
it means a lot to you.
But you need to back off.
You are ripe.
Sorry.
My car's been spending
a lot of time in the shop.
I just wanted to know
what's wrong before I
take it in again.
Well...
I can tell you one thing.
This is not defective.
These holes are straight
and uniform,
which suggests they were
mechanically introduced
from the outside in.
Somebody poked my hose.
(whispers):
Sorry.
Sure, yeah, you could
have a shady mechanic,
but as far as car sabotage
goes, this is amateur hour.
I mean, you really
want to do some damage,
you pop out a spark plug
and throw rocks
into the cylinder.
Radiator hose--
third grade stuff.
You been pissing off a lot
of third graders lately?
Hodges! (groans)
You know, when you told me
to join you for some fun,
I really didn't realize
it was going to be
as wonderful as this.
As your humble tech, I would
like to thank you very much
for entrusting me
with such an important job.
Listen, just remember
to label all
bindled evidence.
Chain of custody is not just
a suggestion, you know.
Don't push it, Hodges.
Okay.
All right.
Hey.
Did I miss anything?
Thanks for texting me, K.
Sure, I mean, the team
isn't the same without...
Oh!
(both laughing)
Okay.
Oh.
Yes.
(laughing)
(coughs) Fire scenes
always smell this bad?
Yes.
KATY: Just let me
know if you find
anything that matches the burn
pattern that we found earlier.
Why do you feel
compelled to lie to us?
About what, exactly?
You don't have to be
a real CSI to know that
you and Hodges are not.
I suspect Hodges
is a Trace tech,
because I doubt any real
CSI would wax so rhapsodic
about that
particular specialty.
And, clearly, that man
does not relish being outdoors.
(splutters)
That, and the fact
that you two
obviously spend
an inordinate amount
of time with each other,
would suggest that you're
most likely a lab tech, too.
I'm DNA.
So, why lie?
I guess I'm afraid
that maybe I'm going
to wake up one morning
and I'm going to think
that I spent most of life
fighting crime in a test tube.
Just because something
is the size of a molecule
doesn't mean that it can't be
filled with intrigue
and excitement.
CSIs gather
the evidence,
but analysis is really
what gives it meaning.
You need both
to find the truth.
DERRICK:
Found some crispy-ass denim.
WEBSTER:
They look like men's jeans.
A quarter and two pennies.
Dinner's on me.
Dead girl's a blonde, right?
KATY: That's her.
"Stacia Borsala."
Hungarian passport.
Looks like I've got what's left
of a blister pack of...
"Zolpidem."
This is so warped,
I doubt I'm going to get
any prints off of it.
The victim had
zolpidem in her system.
We did it.
We ID'd the vic.
I'm sorry, who?
In your face, CSIs.
(laughter)
Techs and
crime cadets, we rule.
Hello.
Metcalf doesn't have
shigella on his hands.
Oh, that's surprising.
A bit of a relief, actually.
(over phone):
Yeah, but get this.
The bacteria that infected
the squad room,
turns out to be the same strain
that closed down
a day care center
in Summerlin last week.
Hold on.
A day care center, huh?
Yep, half a dozen preschoolers.
Must've been quite a mess.
I don't think
that's a coincidence.
STOKES:
The stuff that got 'em sick came
from your pastry box.
What's the deal, bud? Hmm?
You get tired of the
guys in the station
stealing your food,
so you thought
you'd lace a few of your
goodies with some shigella,
teach 'em a lesson?
No.
Yes, the guys steal my food,
although those lowlifes
would never admit it.
But, look,
I would never...
Wh-What's shi-wha?
Shigella-- it's a bacteria, man.
Come on, now. Don't make this
any harder on yourself.
What'd you do?
Did you get
the sample from your
kid's day care center?
I don't know where the pastries
came from, all right?
I stopped eating
sugary snacks, remember?
Oh, and this isn't my kid's,
it's my-my girlfriend's kid.
My-My ex-girlfriend,
we just broke up.
But I got nothing
against the kid.
You know, it's a good drawing,
he's talented.
Was it a nasty break-up?
Is there a pretty kind?
Where can I find her?
STOKES: So in revenge
for breaking up with you,
you decide to give
Sergeant Barclay some
delicious, homemade baked goods
tainted with your
child's shigella.
What did you do,
save a diarrhea diaper
and lace some
in with the icing?
No.
Well, what you
didn't know was
that Sarge had just gone
on a little post-break-up diet.
Too bad for the cops
who stole his food.
Your prints were on it.
It was a gift.
I left it
for Barky as a
peace offering.
Without telling him?
The worst
you can do is have me
reprimanded for bad hygiene.
You can't prove
malicious intent.
That will be up to the D.A.
You caused a disruption
at a police station,
which could've cost lives.
You're looking
at a class-B felony.
Would it help if I said
I was really, really sorry?
WILLOWS:
I have to say I'm impressed
with the initiative. I mean,
this case had kind
of fallen off the radar.
What made you
follow up on it?
It was...
you know, for the children.
No, really, why?
SIMMS:
I have sex stains
right here.
Anything usable?
Maybe.
I'm going to try
magnetic bead separation.
It works best
for getting results
from inhibited surfaces.
If the inhibited surface
is a negative,
then it needs
a strong positive
to draw it out.
Yeah, it also needs an outside
agent to activate
the... attraction.
Couldn't the outside agent
contaminate the entire process?
No, it's not strong enough.
In fact, it's really
only there to get
things started.
Sounds like a delicate process.
Hmm, it is.
One that requires
a lot of patience.
It's worth it,
because...
once the two
are bound together,
everything else is left behind.
Okay.
Let me know
how it turns out.
(sighs)
Hey! I know what
you're doing,
and I know why
you're doing it.
You're trying to ruin
my date with Wendy.
Well, it's not gonna happen.
I followed protocol.
I asked you if it was
cool, and you said "yes."
Henry, I understand
you're having a bad day,
but I really don't see
how I factor into any of it.
Oh, fine, then I'll
spell it out for you.
First, you monkeyed
with my GCMS,
and when that didn't work,
you took it to the next level.
But that didn't
work, either.
Our date is still on.
I hired a limo.
That's kind of flashy
for a first date.
Stay out of my lab and stay
out of my life, or else.
Or else what?
Back off, man.
I'm a toxicologist.
I know every
odorless, colorless,
vomit-inducing
liquid known to man.
You think about that
the next time you eat lunch.
SIMMS:
When the metal beads are added
to a sample of the stain from
the jeans, the DNA actually
binds to sites on the metal.
And then in the magnetic field,
the beads with the DNA
are separated from the rest
of the soup.
Now, this particular
sample came back
as a mixture,
so we just
subtract out
the victim's profile.
And we get...
An unknown male.
All we've got to do
is match it to a tenant
in the building.
You just made denim
speak for the dead.
BRASS:
I'm sure
you'll all be willing to give us
a DNA sample to assist
in our investigation.
There's a bunch of other people
whose apartments burned up.
Why are we the only ones here?
You just got lucky,
I guess.
Fine, just show me
the cup to pee in
or take my blood or whatever,
but I gotta be at my job
in 20 minutes,
so can we get this done?
That's the attitude.
Let's go.
All right.
Hey, uh, look,
giving DNA to cops... uh...
The way I see it, that's
an invasion of my privacy,
so I'm going to decline.
You know,
just on principle.
Sure, I respect your rights.
What's your name?
Melvin Dodge.
Apartment 3C.
I just have a few
things to follow up on,
so why don't we have a chat?
Just you and me.
Okay, okay.
According to the landlord,
you moved in
three days before the fire.
Boy, that's a tough break.
Has the town been treating
you any better since?
Yeah, I got a job dealing craps
over at the Palermo.
They let me go, though.
Layoffs.
There is a recession going on.
Maybe that's not
the best time to move.
Three days
before the fire,
that's barely enough
time to unpack.
Yeah, I was totally
living out
of boxes.
Boxes?
You know what I
hate about boxes?
The stuff they put in them-- the
peanuts-- they get everywhere.
I learned
something about them.
You know, they're not
made out of Styrofoam.
To be friendly to the
environment, they're made
out of cornstarch.
They keep things from
getting crushed, and also,
keeps a dead girl
from going up in flames.
Look, I can get your DNA
in about ten seconds.
Tell me what happened
right now,
and maybe we can
knock the charge
down to involuntary
manslaughter.
That's a break for you.
I didn't know
she was going to die.
I met her at Haze.
She was new in town, too.
She didn't know
anybody, either.
We started drinking. A lot.
She got flirty. She asked me
if I had any drugs.
I told her I had
zolpidem back at my place.
She starts talking about all
the dirty things we can do
if we popped a couple.
15 minutes later,
she's doing things to me
I've only seen online.
Then I woke up
the next morning...
Babe?
And there she was.
Hey, come on.
Hey, wake up.
Dead.
I don't know what happened.
She said that she had
done it before.
I guess I just wasn't
thinking straight.
So you put her body
in one of your boxes, figured
you'd throw it
in a Dumpster later?
Was that the plan?
I guess so.
But then, I got home that night
and I saw that the whole place
was going up in flames.
The fireman came up
and he told me that
my apartment had been
completely destroyed.
I kind of felt like
I got lucky again.
How do you feel now?
Let's do some
writing.
This guy's life
is totally over.
How do you deal with this
day after day?
It's good work when you know
you're on the right side.
Captain Brass?
I just want to say that
I think it's awesome
the way you've pulled
your life back together.
Did you get
into a program?
Who are you?
And what's he been telling you?
♪ ♪
What?
Oh, come on...
Oh, no way.
This isn't funny!
What the...?!
(grunting)
(exclaims)
(whimpers):
Help. My face...
Help.
(banging)
Lab tech down! Aah!
Wait, is that acetone?
Ah...
It is the best way to
dissolve cyanoacrylate, Henry.
Yeah-- ah!
That's toxic.
Well, not so much, if you
keep your mouth closed
and cover your
eyes with that.
Okay.
Lucky for you,
I was feeling better and decided
to come to work today.
There's no telling how long
you could've been stuck here.
Obviously,
someone has not been adhering to
lab policy against pranks,
which is strange because we're
usually such a cohesive group.
Please stop.
I think it's a terrible
injustice, because you...
(groans)
...are the glue
that holds this
whole place together.
Let's see.
Mm-hmm. Looks like someone
shimmed the lock, then
applied contact adhesive
to the interior surfaces
of your locker.
Yeah, well,
I have a very good idea who.
Stick it to him, Henry.
Hey. I saw you and Henry
in the hall before...
Look, I haven't been
messing with Henry.
I'm not trying to spoil
your date, and I hope that
you guys have
a very nice life together.
I really wasn't trying
to blame you for anything.
I was just checking in.
Why are your hands
in your pockets?
Because I'm
socially awkward,
and it gives me
a sense of security.
You know,
after Henry accused me,
I began to suspect
that someone was trying
to pin their
practical jokes on me.
So I mixed up
a little something called
"detection spray" and I put
it all over the surfaces
that I felt that Henry would be
most vulnerable to pranks,
including his locker.
It's essentially
a ninhydrin solution,
which goes on clear,
then reacts
with the amino salts
in perspiration,
leaving a stain on anyone
who touches it.
And the more that the perp
tries to wash it off,
the more the stain spreads.
That's really fascinating.
I should go.
It can last up
to five days.
You may want to wear a dress
with pockets tonight.
I'm not proud of this.
Then why
did you do it?
Because, originally,
I really wanted
to go out with Henry.
Because he's everything that
I know I should be looking for.
He's adorable
and charming and funny and
sweet and nice to me...
Okay, I get it.
He's peachy.
But then, I realized
that what
I'm supposed to want...
isn't what I do want.
So...
basically,
I did the mature thing
and I tortured the poor guy
with practical jokes all day,
thinking that it might make him
cancel the date.
That does sound like
something I'd do.
All right, Hodges,
Henry tells me that you
reprogrammed the GCMS.
And glued my face to my locker
and poked my hose.
WILLOWS:
Whatever. If this is
true, you're looking
at a formal reprimand and
days off. Did you do it?
SIMMS:
Can I just say something?
I am so sorry...
That you didn't
stop me earlier.
You see, Wendy
suspected what I was up to, and
she was urging me to come clean.
I swear,
it'll never happen again.
Mea culpa.
Can you forgive me?
This is going to go on
your permanent record.
You got your
confession-- happy?
Hmm.
Nobody likes a snitch.
(whimpers)
(Hodges clears throat)
Henry, I am so, so sorry.
I guess this means
our date's off?
Oh, yeah.
I guess I need some time
for my face to heal!
Can I get a rain check?
Mmm!
It's never going to happen.