(indistinct radio transmission)
MAN:
I was the driver on patrol.
Heard gunfire,
called it in, responded.
Saw the suspect with a gun
firing in a southwest direction.
Told my partner
to call for backup.
Fearing for someone's life,
I exited the vehicle
and engaged the suspect.
I fired three rounds.
Suspect went down.
I approached,
kicked the gun away,
handcuffed him.
Okay.
(chuckles wryly):
25 years on the job, Jim.
First time I ever had
to fire my weapon.
What was your partner's name?
Donna Grayson.
First week on patrol.
Officer Grayson, we're ready
to take you
downtown now.
We're gonna need your
statement, too, Danny.
Yeah, I know the drill.
Okay.
Hey.
We've been getting
way too much business
out of this
neighborhood, Jim.
Well, if the gangs in L.A.
would stay in L.A.,
life in the ghetto
would be beautiful again.
What does it
look like, David?
We got three GSWs:
one to the left kidney area;
one to the left thigh;
and one to the
upper torso.
LANGSTON:
At least one of them
was a through-and-through.
A nine-millimeter hollow-point.
This looks like our duty issue.
Smith &amp; Wesson Model 60.
.38 Special.
Suspect fired four rounds.
Well, that's consistent
with Officer Finn's statement.
Hey, brother!
Let me talk to you!
That's right.
I'm talking to you.
Damn cop shot him
after he was down.
(crowd clamoring)
Plain murder.
Murder!
She's speaking the truth!
It was murder!
Murder!
Would they be crying "murder"
if he was a white guy?
It's not about this guy.
It's never about one guy.
We'll be taking all their
statements. Let's keep going.
David, would you go ahead
and roll him, please?
(crowd clamoring)
We have another
nine-mil hollow-point.
Well, there are a lot of ways
a bullet could end up
under his body.
I can only think of two:
shot from a distance
through-and-through,
bullet got caught
in his clothing,
fell out when
he went down;
or...
the suspect was shot
after he was down,
like the young lady said.
Coup de grâce.
Sounds like you already
made up your mind.
You already made up yours?
Ray.
Jim?
Yeah?
This man is a cop.
Oh, no.
LANGSTON:
Sergeant Scott Johnson.
Lives in Seven Hills.
(groans)
What are you doing
down here, my man?
BRASS:
I'll find out.
First I have to notify Ecklie.
Conrad, Jim Brass.
(Brass continues indistinctly)
Eyes are gonna be
on every move we make.
They already are.
Tired of this!
Shot him in the back!
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
♪ ♪
FINN:
Hey, you know as well as I do--
if there's one gun,
there's two; if there's
two guys, there's three.
It's how I was trained;
it's how I train the rookies.
You don't have
to defend your actions.
I'm just here to document them
for the record.
(door opens)
CSI Willows has
entered the room.
She is here
to collect and document
your service weapon.
WILLOWS:
Actually, I'd like to ask
a few questions first.
This is a sketch of the...
900 block of Adams Street,
where the shooting took place.
Officer Finn, could you indicate
the position of the suspect
and where you were
when you fired?
Suspect was...
here.
For the record,
Officer Finn has indicated
that the suspect was
in the parking lot
of White House Burgers,
south of the building.
I parked my vehicle here.
I fired behind
the driver's door.
Also in the parking lot,
north of the suspect.
And you never fired
from any other position?
No, I fired three.
From behind my door.
(two gunshots)
WILLOWS:
When did the suspect go down?
FINN:
On the third shot.
WILLOWS:
At what point
did you approach the suspect?
FINN:
When I felt the suspect
was no longer a threat.
When he was down.
FINN:
Somebody saying
something different?
BRASS:
Well, preliminary
eyewitness reports suggest...
that the suspect was shot
in the back after he was down.
So far the physical evidence
doesn't disprove it.
Well, it didn't happen.
Ask my partner.
You gonna tell me
what's going on here?
Did you recognize him?
No.
Did you I.D. yourself to him?
I don't know. Maybe.
Did you give him a chance
to I.D. himself to you?
Hell, no. Why would I?
Because he was a cop.
Sergeant
Scott Johnson.
That's it.
I'm not saying another word
until my union attorney
gets here.
STOKES:
If Finn fired three shots
from behind his door
in that direction,
cartridge cases would have
ejected right... and rear.
They should be
around here somewhere.
LANGSTON:
I think I got one.
Make that two.
One to go.
WOMAN:
He shot out of there
like a bolt of lightning.
SANDERS:
So you saw him
leave the restaurant?
I'm saying, where's
that other guy,
the one I was talking to
in the parking lot?
You know who I mean.
Well, you got me.
(sighs) Did you, uh,
see anybody on the street?
Anything unusual?
Not till all that
gunfire started,
and that's not
all that unusual.
Okay.
What happened
when you heard the shots?
I grabbed my baby,
and I hit the ground.
Your baby?
My boy, Avery.
Six years old.
Bring him with me to work.
Sitters cost too much.
Could you see who was shooting?
I saw the floor.
And when did you go outside?
When it got quiet.
Can you show me
where you were standing?
Right here.
Right outside the door.
What did you see?
I saw the brother murdered.
Here. The cop was standing
over him, and he shot him.
But you just said
that you waited
until the shooting stopped
before you went outside.
I know what I saw
and what I heard.
There was a whole bunch
of guns going off.
Then it got quiet.
Then one last shot,
and that cop was standing
over that poor man.
I saw a murder.
(gunshot)
Well, if that's what happened,
Officer Finn's gun would have
been pointed at the ground.
That cartridge case...
ejected.
(whistles)
Nine-millimeter
cartridge case.
Consistent with
witness statements.
And inconsistent with
the officer's statement.
Sara, glad to see you back.
Ecklie.
How was your
week off in Paris?
Dr. Grissom sends
his regards.
Were you able to
make notification?
Well, Johnson's
only next-of-kin is his father.
Looks like he's out of town.
Any word on what Johnson
was doing down there?
Well, according
to Johnson's captain,
he was off duty; Adams Street
isn't in his district;
he wasn't working undercover;
and he had no informants.
So no official reason
to be there.
Which is why you are here.
Maybe Sergeant Johnson
was just looking
for a good burger.
I doubt it.
Take a look at his body fat.
Not the usual
yellow-orange color.
It's white.
He was a vegetarian.
So what was he doing
in a burger joint?
Do you have the third bullet?
Nine-mil.
Lodged in his left kidney,
not immediately fatal.
Same as the one
shot through his left thigh.
This one's your COD.
Back-to-front.
Penetrated the
interventricular septum
near the base of the heart.
That's the area concerned
with its electrical conduction.
(heart beating,
electrical buzzing)
Kind of like flipping
the main breaker.
Heart would have
stopped immediately.
So it must have been
the final shot.
Does the trajectory tell you
if he was standing or prone?
That is the question
of the night,
and I can't give you an answer.
You know,
in ancient times,
a coup de grâce
was considered an act of mercy--
a quick blow
to end the suffering
of a comrade wounded in battle.
Whatever this was,
it was no act of mercy.
♪ ♪
How's the House of Meat?
Sergeant Johnson ordered
two burgers, two drinks,
and a salad.
Burgers were not for him.
He was a vegetarian.
According to the witnesses,
he entered alone.
So he must have been
meeting someone.
Okay. Who?
And why haven't
they come forward?
Officer Grayson,
could you see
who Sergeant Johnson
was shooting at?
I don't think so.
It was all so fast.
I should have seen more.
I didn't.
Can we do this a little later?
A officer lost his life
last night.
We owe it to him
to get past ourselves
and do what we
have to do.
If you want to pound nails
in your head, do it tomorrow.
Now, show me your position.
Um, I was right there,
calling for backup.
And while you were
on the radio,
could you see
Sergeant Johnson?
No.
Could you see your partner?
Yes.
FINN:
Grayson, get the hell down.
Call for backup now.
Control, this is 3 David 34.
We have a 444 in progress,
900 block of Adams.
(two gunshots)
Damn it. Damn it. Damn it.
Requesting backup
and paramedics.
(gunshot)
DISPATCH:
3 David 3-4, copy that.
Will advise.
All units, vicinity
of 900 block of Adams,
be advised we have a 444 in
progress. Officer involved.
So you didn't actually see
Officer Finn
fire the third shot?
I heard it.
It was close.
But by the time
that I looked up...
Where was Officer Finn
when you looked up?
Over the body.
Do you have the dispatch calls
from Officer Finn's
patrol car yet?
Is there a problem?
Deputy?
No, ma'am.
But Officer Finn's mic was stuck
in the open position.
Happens all the time.
Might be helpful.
Let's hear it.
FINN:
Grayson, get the hell down!
Call for backup now!
GRAYSON:
Control, this is 3 David 34.
We have a 444 in progress.
(two gunshots)
FINN:
I'm taking him down.
Black son of a bitch.
(gunshot)
Jim, we need to
talk about the...
Jim!
I put my credibility
on the line for you.
CSI said excessive force.
I said, "No way."
That's right.
Oh, really?
(audio device beeps on)
FINN (on recording):
I'm taking him down.
Black son of a bitch.
(shot fires, device beeps off)
Look, I don't remember
saying that.
I'm advising you not to speak.
Not until we hear
the complete recording
and check
the witness statements.
What, you think
I'm racist?
ATTORNEY: Again, officer,
I'm telling you...
I don't remember. If
I said he was black,
I was describing
the suspect.
I was so focused on what
the gun was doing, I...
Did you see his face?
No, it was dark out.
Are you telling me you didn't
recognize Scott Johnson?
He was a trainee.
He rode with you.
He was your damn partner
for four months.
You spent eight hours a day
in the car together.
You saw more of him
than you did of your wife.
This was over five years ago.
So, you're telling me that
you didn't recognize the guy
who put a formal complaint
in your file
for racial discrimination?
Let me read
this to you.
"Frequent and excessive use
of racial epithets,
including the 'N' word."
First of all, no,
I didn't recognize Johnson.
And second, yeah, sure, I use
street talk with the trainees.
Come on, you know
that doesn't fly anymore.
But believe me,
whatever they get from me
is nothing
compared to what they're going
to get from the real gorillas
in the jungle.
That's a poor choice of words.
I am training them
for the real world.
And of the dozens and dozens
of people that I have trained--
and that is every color
of the rainbow, pal--
that hard-ass was the only one
who ever complained.
The only one.
He's the racist, not me.
WILLOWS:
Ready, set, go.
Four seconds.
(groans)
Could have run it in two.
Except we're timing
a 53-year-old guy
who's packing
about 30 pounds of gear.
So, the distance from Finn's car
to Johnson's body was 40 feet?
And according
to the dispatch recording,
there was 5.4 seconds
that elapsed between
the second and third shots.
SIDLE:
Greg just proved
that that's time enough
for Finn to have delivered
the final shot over the body.
(gunshot)
Brass found out Finn put in for
a promotion about a year ago.
It was denied.
A couple of weeks later,
Finn saw Johnson at another
officer's retirement party,
took a swing at him.
Finn probably thought
he deserved a desk job
and a bigger pension
and he blamed Johnson
for not getting it.
Would Finn have delivered
that coup de grâce,
if that guy hadn't been Johnson?
But it was, and when
Finn recognized him,
his resentment
probably took over.
Racially motivated, you think?
Well, obviously, race is
a hot-button issue for the guy.
When I heard
the dispatch recording,
I hated what I heard.
I thought, "The guy's a racist."
But it may not be that simple.
I mean, it was
a stress situation.
And people say things
they would never, ever say
in a normal setting.
Don't we?
(liquid pouring)
LANGSTON:
You know, there was a study
done back in Michigan
about a year or so ago.
It, uh, examined
an officer's response
to situations
involving deadly force
and whether race is a factor.
It found that an officer has
less than a third of a second
to decide
whether to use his gun.
That's not much time.
It's enough for
an instinctive response.
Yes, but the study showed,
overwhelmingly,
that the most important factor
in an officer's response
is the suspect's actions,
not race.
I'm not talking
about racial profiling.
That's a whole other
box of crayons.
I'm talking about
that third of a second
when a threat jumps out at you.
(bangs loudly)
Look...
when I had a gun
pulled on me,
I didn't check for skin color
before I pulled the trigger.
(phone beeps)
Finn's motives are not
what we're after.
Just the evidence that's going
to tell us about his actions.
WILLOWS:
We got a 420
at an abandoned school
on Madison, north of Fifth.
I'll take it.
Okay.
And life goes on.
If I need to call you,
I'm going to. That's cool?
Thanks.
Moreno.
Sara.
Skater found the body.
It looks like a
gang execution.
The victim's just a kid.
(groans)
Body's in full rigor.
TOD was about 16 hours ago.
10:00 last night.
It was a busy hour
in the neighborhood.
This was why my parents
moved from L.A. to Vegas.
So I wouldn't end up like that.
GSW to the neck.
It's a through-and-through.
Got a bullet here.
Nine-mil.
Everybody
loves their nines, huh?
Good guys, bad guys. My mom.
I don't see any cartridge
casings.
Homeboys are catching finally on
and policing their brass.
He's missing a finger.
When you get him on the table,
look in his rectum.
You'll find his finger there.
So that's what gangs are doing
to snitches these days?
How do you know he's a snitch?
He got shot through the throat.
Trajectory was upwards,
front to back.
David, can I see the entry?
Yeah.
(sobbing):
No, please.
No! No!
Please! I'll stop!
I'll stop! Please, no!
No! No!
Hmm.
Supplying or buying?
Got sneaker prints in blood.
Ball to toe.
They were running.
The tread detail is still sharp.
Sneakers were fairly new.
Probably just lifted them
at the mall.
Blood drops traveling
in the same direction.
Your suspect was wounded.
♪ ♪
You know, I can't help
but wonder
how Officer Finn
just happened to roll up
on the very guy
he had a beef with.
Yeah, who just happened to be
in the middle of the hood,
miles from home and
shooting at something.
Presenting Finn with the perfect
opportunity to exact revenge.
What do you think? You think
it could have been a setup?
I don't know. I mean, he
called in "shots fired"
before he could even see
that it was Johnson.
But if he planned it,
he knew Johnson was there.
And his unwitting partner
would give him credibility.
All right, so, what puts
Johnson on Adams Street
in the first place?
Well, his last call
was to someone
named "Anthony" at 9:59 pm.
Dispatch logged
"shots fired" at 10:07 p.m.
Looks like Johnson and this guy
called each other
several times
over the last couple days.
All right, so maybe
that's who he was meeting.
Could run the number
on an AG warrant.
Or we could call him.
(dialing)
(camera shutter clicking)
(cell phone vibrating)
(phone beeps)
Hello?
STOKES:
Sara?
This is Nick.
Whose phone is this?
My John Doe's--
the dead kid.
His name's Anthony.
SIDLE:
Victim's name
was Anthony Lopez.
He lived with his mom
in an apartment on Garfield.
She I.D.'d the body.
She said he wasn't
involved with gangs.
Don't they all?
What did she say about
the drugs he was carrying?
She said he never used,
and his tox came back clean.
Did the mother know
Sergeant Johnson?
No. And Johnson
wasn't working gangs.
And Lopez did not
have a record.
Sorry, Mom, this has gangs
written all over it.
PD has a trial
on some new gang software.
Call Detective Moreno
and give it a try.
Yeah, okay.
All right, keep them out.
OFFICER:
All right, folks, you heard
the man. Stay behind the tape.
(sighs)
Okay, Danny,
this is
the standard
after-shooting walk-through.
I'm CSI Stokes.
I'm going to be asking you
a few questions, okay?
Why not?
Everybody else is.
When you arrived on the scene,
according to your statement,
Officer Johnson had his gun
drawn and was shooting.
Is that correct?
Yeah, that's right.
Could you see
what he was shooting at?
I could not see his target.
I could not see his face.
But I saw the gun,
and I saw him firing.
And that was, uh, that was
in this direction, right?
No.
Turn to your right.
More.
That's it.
So he was facing away from you?
Why'd you make the decision
to shoot?
Screw you.
What?
Hey, hey, hey.
No, I am so sick
of everybody
and their kid brother
second-guessing me.
Hey, I'm not
second-guessing you!
You know what?
If you knew anything,
you'd know that a guy with a gun
in this neighborhood...
ITHACA:
Watch it.
What?!
It's a black neighborhood.
Look at their faces.
Tell me I'm wrong.
(crowd murmurs)
Don't go there.
It's you people
I was trying to save!
All right, shut up!
Mitch, get him
out of here.
I put my life on the line
every day for you people!
What have you ever
done for me, huh?
You got
a death wish, buddy?
And you know what?!
Every bad thing
that happened to you people,
it's not my fault.
Got it?!
It's not my fault!
Let's go.
Let go of me!
I can't defend this guy.
All right, all right, all right.
He's kind of prickly, isn't he?
Well, let's cut him
some slack.
He's under a lot of pressure.
You know.
Well, at least now we know
where Johnson was shooting.
And I'm thinking
it was Anthony Lopez
that Johnson
was meeting here.
And Johnson was shooting
at whoever killed Anthony.
I got what looks like
a bullet hole here, Jim.
BRASS:
Missing hubcaps,
flat tire.
You don't park in
this neighborhood
unless your car's
not worth stealing.
Look at that.
.38 expanded hollow-point,
with what looks like traces
of blood and tissue.
We'll find out.
Well, Johnson
was shooting a .38.
Hey, Nick.
Yeah?
I got a trail.
Yep.
Right here.
It's blood.
Whatever Johnson was
shooting at, he hit.
All right, this program
links evidence
from gang-related crimes
in a fraction of the time
it used to take us to do it.
We input all the
evidence we've got
and compare it
against the database,
starting with ballistics.
Each dot represents a crime
involving firearms.
And that, that's
just the last year.
Wow. I leave town for a while
and all hell
breaks loose.
(trilling beeps)
Pretty cool.
Showing you guys something new.
Let's hope it works.
Oh, it works.
You see?
Four gangs favor
jacketed hollow-point
nine-mils.
All right, let's input
the sneaker print.
"Cause and manner of death:
exsanguination
due to GSWs."
All right, we're down
to two possible gangs.
Let's input the location
where we found the victim--
Madison and Fifth.
(typing)
D-Street Killers.
They run Garfield Street,
where Lopez lived.
Adams is outside
of their territory.
So, Anthony Lopez and Sergeant
Johnson probably thought
they were meeting
somewhere safe.
Do you have a log of all
the known D-Street Killers
in the database?
Except the ones that are
dead or incarcerated.
Yeah.
I'll round them up.
♪ ♪
HODGES:
I analyzed the bullet
that you found here,
under Sergeant Johnson's body.
It had manufacturer's
petroleum sealant on the base.
That's not uncommon.
It keeps moisture from
getting into the cartridge.
Right, but I did not
find any sealant
on any of Finn's other bullets.
Which also is not uncommon.
Manufacturers often mix
different batches of ammo.
Did you find sealant
on any of the cartridge cases?
Bear with me, wise one.
There was no sealant
on the cartridge case Nick found
under the fence.
However, I did find sealant
on one cartridge case:
the cartridge case
that you found
in the windshield
of the patrol car.
STOKES:
So the bullet we thought
was the coup de grâce
was fired from the cartridge
case on the patrol car?
40 feet from Johnson.
That's not a coup de grâce.
HODGES:
And in addition
to the sealant, there were
denim fibers in the nose
of the bullet
found under Johnson.
He was wearing jeans.
(gunshot)
He landed on top of the bullet
that went through his leg.
LANGSTON:
The first bullet
I found
was the one that went
through his back.
STOKES:
We can't be sure.
Without
corresponding trace,
we can't match bullets
to cartridge cases.
There was trace
on the cartridge case
near the fence.
And this is where
it gets really sticky.
STOKES:
"Grape juice, corn syrup,
fruit pectin,
citric acid, sodium citrate."
It had grape jelly on it?
Yes.
And there was a fingerprint.
Mandy ran it-- no hits.
If there was jelly on the
cartridge before it was fired,
it would have burned off
in the chamber.
So somebody had to have
touched it after it was fired.
Which means somebody
moved the evidence.
The scene was secure
within minutes.
The only people
that were there
were Officers Finn
and Grayson
and the witnesses
at the burger joint.
Which doesn't
serve breakfast--
only burgers, fries,
and ice cream.
No jelly in the kitchen
or on the menu.
But check this out.
There's a
jelly packet.
Right by the toy truck.
I know who touched
the cartridge case.
I like French fries
with jelly.
Puts grape jelly on everything--
macaroni, eggs, carrots.
I take those jelly packs
from breakfast spots,
so I always have some handy.
Else-wise, baby
won't eat at all.
Avery, last night,
when everybody ran outside,
did you touch anything?
WOMAN:
He didn't touch
anything.
It was all I could do
to keep him
from having to see that...
that man that was sick
in the parking lot.
I'd like your consent
to run his fingerprints.
Could help us clear up
a critical part
of our investigation.
Avery,
can you do this
with your finger?
Put it right there.
All right, that's good.
(beeping)
He did find something.
(sirens blaring)
What you doing?
Put that down.
He didn't know
what he was doing.
He's not in any trouble, ma'am.
But he did help us prove
that Officer Finn didn't hurt
Sergeant Johnson after
he was already down.
Witnesses often
merge what they actually saw
with prior assumptions.
Well, good news is,
CSIs proved you didn't
commit a coup de grâce.
The bad news?
Excuse me.
You're still on
administrative leave.
Because of your
recent outburst,
they aren't gonna issue you
a replacement weapon
until you get cleared
by a department shrink.
When you shot a cop,
is that what you did, Jim?
Did you cry on some couch
to a shrink?
Come on, Danny.
Come on.
I know the deal.
I know the depression.
But you know, you should
look at the bright side.
You're on paid leave,
so why don't you go somewhere?
Take a vacation. Go to a beach.
Go play golf.
Go make love to your wife
in the afternoon.
(chuckles)
That's what I'll do.
And then Johnson won't be dead
anymore.
Hey, hey, come on,
come on. Hey, listen.
Listen to me. I'll give
it to you straight.
The lawsuits
and the investigation
are gonna take, like, forever,
all right?
So why don't you do yourself
a favor?
You got many years in this job.
Why don't you think
about retirement?
This could be
the time to get out.
And get out clean.
Would you be telling me to quit
if Johnson had been white?
So, it wasn't that long ago
that my wife died
and Scott moved
back home with me.
Said he didn't want me...
he didn't want me
to be alone.
That white cop...
This was revenge.
The elevators are this way,
Mr. Johnson.
He was in that
neighborhood
last night trying
to save a kid's life.
Spanish kid.
Got caught shoplifting
in a jewelry store.
Part of some kind
of gang initiation.
He only did it
because he didn't think
he had a choice.
My Scotty got the owner
not to press charges.
Told him he would be
a mentor to the boy.
Gave him his phone number and
he checked with him every day.
He was a good man.
We have all of Scott's
personal effects downstairs.
♪ ♪
Wait, Mr. Johnson.
I'll meet you in the lobby.
(gunshot)
Open your mouth, please.
Open your mouth.
Delinquente...
delinquente...
Si tu no hagas lo que quiere,
tu no sales de aqui, okay?
Can I see the bottom
of your shoes, please?
Hágalo.
(suspect gasps in pain)
Eso duele!
Oh.
Let go of my leg!
(groaning)
SIDLE:
What's wrong
with your leg?
None of your business.
Let the rest of them go.
Actually, run 'em for warrants.
(all groaning and complaining)
SIDLE:
Drop your pants.
If there's a bullet in his ass,
his ass is evidence.
It's killing me, man.
Get it out.
First you tell us
what Anthony Lopez did
to piss you off.
Anthony who?
(screams)
Answer the question.
Punk thought by muling
some crank he'd make me think
he wasn't snitching.
I knew better.
The snitch was gonna talk
to that cop.
No way I was
letting that happen.
Next thing I know,
cop's shooting at me.
Cop got his.
I got out of there.
That's it, I swear.
Just don't hit me no more.
PHILLIPS:
They say a suicide attempt
is a cry for help,
but from the size of this hole,
I'd say we have an admission
of guilt.
Have you ever been
with someone
at the moment
they died, David?
Actually... no.
Well, my eyes were the last ones
that he looked into.
I just wonder...
David, have you seen
these bruises?
Yeah, they look just like
my grandmother's knees.
She is always bumping
into things.
♪ ♪
(saw whirring)
Nick, would you go stand
where Sergeant Johnson
was shooting, please?
Yes, sir.
We've already proved
there was no coup de grâce.
What is this gonna show us?
We still haven't determined
whether or not
Officer Finn recognized
Sergeant Johnson
when he shot him.
Nick, go ahead and assume
a shooting stance, please,
Take this, put it
up to your eyes
and look at Nick.
I noticed multiple bruises
in various stages
of healing
on Officer Finn's legs
right about
coffee table height.
I also noticed
there were
a lot of dings on his car
when I went to the garage.
PHILLIPS:
Now that you mention it,
the left front fender
of his patrol car had a dent.
So, post-mortem on his eyes
revealed hyperplastic formations
in the mid-peripheral retina.
His vision was
severely impaired
by retinitis
pigmentosa.
It's like seeing the world
through a straw.
And it's progressive.
Vision in both eyes
slowly irises
down over time.
No way he should have been
working patrol then.
That's for sure.
Probably too proud to go out
on a disability,
even though
it's a better pension.
I have to say he was a pretty
good shot for a blind guy.
Ironically, because his vision
was so constrained,
he was able to focus on
the immediate threat.
And there's
one more thing.
Officer Finn's
patrol car was parked
at an angle where his headlights
wouldn't have picked up Johnson,
which means that that light
put him in silhouette.
It's like the
perfect storm:
his condition, at night
with this lighting.
Finn couldn't have known
it was Johnson.
Finn took action
in the line of duty,
and Johnson was trying
to help a kid at risk.
So where's the bad guy in this?
You tell me.