♪ ♪
BRASS:
What's going on? You bring in
a high-risk psychopath
into my department
and you don't even
bother to call me?
I mean, were you two gonna
fly this over my head?
Haskell reached out
from prison,
said he had something to offer
in the Dr. Jekyll case.
The man called me.
Yeah, and he hung up on you.
Why didn't you
just call him back?
You don't have
to send a limo for him
like Paul freakin' McCartney.
The last time we gave him
a stage, somebody got killed.
WILLOWS: This was my
decision, Jim.
I called the governor,
and the governor
cleared it through the sheriff.
Both friends of Daddy.
You know, it's amazing,
but Sam Braun
has more clout dead than
most of us do alive.
WILLOWS:
My team is working
a serial killer case.
We've got zippo leads,
and the bodies are piling up.
What do you think I'm doing,
writing parking tickets?
Hey, last time I checked,
CSI worked for me.
And have you been doing lately
on the case, Jim?
You develop any better leads?
Are you saying
I'm not doing my job?
WILLOWS: We're all
doing our jobs.
And if Nate Haskell
knows anything,
we should hear
what he has to say.
If he starts screwing
with us, we just ship
him back to Ely
and weld his cage shut.
(siren whoops)
Las Vegas.
Hands up.
This is a stun belt.
My own private
electric fence.
That's exciting.
(mooing, bleating)
Let's go.
HASKELL:
Hiya. Glad to be back here.
Nice to be here.
Oh. I hear crime
is down three quarters
in a row.
Good work.
Hey, keep that up.
Let's be careful
out there.
WILLOWS:
Well, Ray,
he's all yours.
Wait a minute. What? What?
Ray's the one he wants to talk
to-- they have the connection.
BRASS:
Hold on.
Nobody's going in there
without me.
Do it, Officer,
press the button.
I hear it's better
than sex with your wife.
One more word, I'll have sparks
coming out of your ears,
you son of a bitch.
Oh, looky.
Hate to start this off
with a complaint,
but on the way in, there
was no food service,
I didn't get
a window seat,
and the
stewardesses all had
assault rifles.
Plus they're... really ugly.
I thought you
wanted to talk,
and then you hung up on me.
Were your feelings hurt?
Tell me what happened to
the unsettled, bearded fellow.
Griswald?
Gristle?
He's pursuing
other things.
So that means
you've taken his place?
Isn't that a bit of
a comedown, Professor?
Although...
I suppose who better for a
low-level job in law enforcement
than a doctor who allowed
27 people to die
before his watchful eyes.
BRASS:
Shut up, Haskell.
You were brought here
because you said
you had information
about the Jekyll murders.
Start talking.
Which is it,
shut up or start talking?
I don't think I like you.
I don't want to play
with you at all.
Nate, you said you had
information about Dr. Jekyll--
let's have it.
Okay. After I was arrested,
when the police confiscated
my belongings,
they took something from my
dresser drawer, top right.
You'll find it in evidence.
Oh, I'm sure you've got
boxes and boxes...
Nick, get all of Haskell's
evidence out of storage,
and bring it to the lab.
Obviously, the coppers
didn't realize its significance,
and frankly, when I was
given this beautiful gift...
I didn't, either.
I felt, at the time,
it was more like a...
promise.
A talisman from
a like-minded soul.
But...
given recent events, uh...
I kept it in
a beautiful lacquer box,
adorned with a dragon,
which I had picked up on a trip
down the Yangtze River.
Actually, I bought it
in Chinatown, but...
I do have a weakness
for embellishment.
I think I got it.
Pasta?
Weird.
Bow-tie pasta...
tied with a spaghetti bow.
They're identical.
Haskell's telling
the truth.
He knows who Jekyll is.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
A monster like Haskell
kills 19 people,
and you see him up
close and personal,
he looks just like
everybody else.
Mm-hmm.
You got a lot of guts
bringing him down here.
But that's what
I like about you.
Now I know why you got up
so early this morning.
I wish I'd stayed in bed.
VARTANN:
Well...
me, too.
Here you go.
Why am I always the
last to know? Hm?
Call Hodges, see what
he can do with that.
It's so funny how
you cops come up
with your nicknames
for serial killers.
(chuckles) The...
the Night Stalker,
the Hillside Strangler,
the Iceman.
I'm the Dick and
Jane Killer.
Kind of makes me sound
so... immature.
How do you know Jekyll?
Dr. Jekyll, Mr. Hyde?
Do you guys even read?
Robert Louis Stevenson? Hello?
Jekyll was the good guy?
Well, why don't you
be the good guy
and give us a name?
(sighs)
How do you know Jekyll?
Well... since you ask,
I met him in a restaurant.
All of his victims were there.
Before he was Jekyll,
of course.
That was, oh...
heavens, ten, no...
11 years ago.
(chuckles)
My, how time crawls.
He hadn't discovered his...
potential yet, back then,
back when I was free to be me.
It was so... unexpected.
So captivating.
I knew there was
genius behind it.
Come on-- pasta?
I asked if I could
meet the chef.
What do you call this?
I'll take it back
if you like.
No, no, I like it,
I like it a lot.
You're very talented. Sit.
I spoke to him.
I liked him, Dr. Langston.
He was mad as a hatter.
What is that mess?
What's the matter
with you?
Nobody wants to see that crap
floating in their food.
Get back in
the kitchen.
Excuse me.
I'm sorry if he
bothered you, sir.
I'll get you another
plate of pasta.
This is good.
I'll keep this...
No, please, let me
get some more pasta...
Leave it!
Dr. Langston,
choosing a partner--
it's intuitive.
It comes from a place
deep inside of you.
What, like your colon?
Could we get a private room?
There's a fly buzzing in here.
Take this psychopath,
send him back to Hell
and throw away the key.
Jim...
(imitates a fly buzzing)
Could I have a few
minutes with him?
BRASS: Take all the
time you want.
(angry sigh)
Nice bad-cop routine.
Yeah, well,
I wasn't acting.
I need a name.
And I'm just so bad with names.
I did talk to him,
though, Dr. Langston.
And he opened up to me.
The right ones
always do.
He's a late bloomer,
but...
he seems to be making
quite a splash now.
What was the name
of the restaurant?
All this food talk is
making me so hungry.
I wonder whether a nice steak
dinner would jog my memory.
I'll have the rib eye,
(over speaker):
rare, baked potato, sour cream,
chives; for dessert,
berry pie--
if it's in season--
and I'll have it á la mode.
If you want to get something...
you have to give me something.
(whispers):
Let's be perfectly clear--
you need me,
and I need you.
I'm gonna die in prison,
so I'm gonna have some fun.
If you don't like it,
send me back to Ely.
Let the good doctor
continue his work.
I want my steak bloody.
So, the sheriff
has given us 48 hours,
then he ships Haskell back.
Haskell said he was
in a restaurant
that serves pasta
with a piano bar.
Jekyll was there, so were
three of his victims.
All in the same place
at the same time.
Oh, that's convenient.
I don't believe it.
He's lying for fresh air.
Yeah. But there is the pasta.
Haskell's not a magician,
right, and we had that
in evidence way before
Joey Bigelow's surgery.
He likes to mix
the truth with lies.
Let's run down
this restaurant--
if it exists--
see which is which.
Joey Bigelow may have been
playing some gigs back then,
so there could be tax records,
pay stubs...
Joey had an agent.
His name was, um,
Marty Felnick.
I know Marty.
I sat on his lap a few times,
back in the day.
When you were a little girl?
No, when I was a big girl.
So, if he's
still alive,
I'll find him.
STOKES:
Okay, we should get
credit card receipts
for Jekyll's victims,
see if there was an
overlap 11 years ago.
I'll take Higgins.
I got Herson.
And I'll call Reno PD,
get Haskell's financials.
Thank you.
Mr. Felnick?
I'm Catherine Willows.
I'm with the crime lab.
I was wondering
when you guys would show up.
Hmm.
This is about Joe-Joe, right?
Yes. Yes, sir, it is.
I heard that you were with him
from the beginning.
From before the beginning,
young lady.
Now it's after the end,
isn't it?
Whew.
The man had such talent.
He drank, though.
But I mean, from the bottom
of the bottle-- he drank.
Dumb bastard--
he threw it all away.
Do you recall if Joey was
playing any restaurant gigs
about ten or 11 years ago?
You know,
you're a very attractive woman.
Did anybody ever tell you that?
Thank you.
But one time,
I do remember
he came to me.
I remember this time,
he wanted me
to come see him play.
It was like a comeback,
you know?
It was only a one-night thing
in some kind of joint.
He not only lost his touch...
(laughs)
...he stiffed me for dinner.
Do you remember the name
of the place?
No, but I remember
the $150 he took from me.
(laughs)
That I remember.
The joint-- it was...
It was west of the 15,
as driving,
and south of the 95.
That's where it was.
Could you show me where,
on this map?
You got a map?
Mm-hmm.
Hm-hm!
Huh.
Somewhere around here.
Sweetheart,
you are very familiar.
We knew each other,
something.
I bet you say that
to all the cops.
(laughs)
Haskell's never filed
an income tax form in his life.
He's never had a job
there's any record of.
He's very smart.
He made himself invisible.
I talked to Marty Felnick.
Joey played piano
in a restaurant
in roughly the vicinity
where we found his body.
I didn't get the name, though.
I found this picture
in Herson's evidence.
His shirt is from Venetti's.
Which is on that side of town.
Bernie Higgins ate out
breakfast, lunch and dinner.
And he went to Venetti's
at least once a week.
(sighs heavily)
We're here.
Let's have a look around.
I'll get it.
What do you know?
Farfalle--
homemade bow tie pasta.
Found their business license.
Expired five years ago.
Joe-Joe Bigelow--
he's on the wall.
Bernard Higgins here.
STOKES:
Yeah, Herson...
is here, as well.
Looks like
Haskell was telling the truth.
I'd like to be the one
to tell Brass.
ANDREWS: Catherine, hey,
I got the information
you asked for.
I called the Clark
County Assessor
and got the names of the
three co-owners of Venetti's.
Oh, great.
I'll call them.
Yeah, uh, they're dead.
Two of them were
low-level Italian mobsters.
They're brothers.
Apparently, they got sent
through a wood chipper
in Brime County
a few years back.
Okay.
The third is
a Hasidic bookie.
According to Vice,
the last thing they saw
of his before he vanished
were the charred remains
of his bookie receipts
and a yarmulke on the roof
of the, uh, Silver Vista
Athletic Club.
Elroy Wax?
How did you know?
My father used to
place bets with him
all the time.
Hell, I placed a few myself.
Uncle Elroy? He's dead?
Sorry.
Here--
I also got a list
of the restaurant's employees
from the IRS.
If we're to believe Haskell,
one of these guys
has got to be Jekyll.
Jekyll's forehead
wasn't that big.
You said bulging.
I said prominent.
Make it wider, flatter.
Chin is too weak.
Where did you learn
to draw, my dear--
"Sketch Bambi" contest?
(wry, mocking laugh)
It's better, but the
eyes more wide-set,
and jaw more square,
more patrician.
Do you know what
that means? Patrician?
That's perfect.
Do you like it,
Dr. Langston?
I made it for you.
You can go.
Mm.
Bye, my dear.
Do you, uh,
recognize this place?
It looks familiar.
It's come on hard
times, hasn't it?
Things are so tough out there;
everybody out of work.
That's the thing about
two consecutive life sentences.
Mortgage is paid.
Three hots and a cot.
Must be hard for you to indulge
your hobbies from inside.
When you consider
Dr. Jekyll is out there,
free to continue his practice.
You don't get
that many opportunities
to, uh, "Dick and Jane" around,
do you?
Mm.
We confirmed
that all of
Dr. Jekyll's victims
did visit this restaurant,
this, uh, Venetti's.
Venetti's.
Yes.
Good work, Ray.
So you saw the Wall of Fame?
This is working great.
I give you good information,
you give me a good steak.
I have a list
of names here, Nate.
I wonder...
if you see the young man's name
on this list?
Oh, yeah, I see it.
What is his name?
Ray...
you know this is
a barter system.
You gave me good steak,
I got you to the place.
Now, I need
a little something else.
(sighs)
You know that we are
running down these names,
which means that
your information
won't be very valuable
for very long.
Maybe long enough
for someone to die.
Be careful, Doctor.
You might be
the next victim.
Is that a game you want to play?
♪ ♪
She's for Haskell.
(sultry dance music
playing on boom box)
That's enough,
thank you.
I need a name, Nate.
You're interrupting
a performance! It's very rude!
Yes-- I need
his name, Nate.
Carlo Parini.
You sure?
OFFICER:
Haskell, get back!
Enjoy yourself.
Carlo Parini.
Let's see if we
can find this guy.
I'm betting he's got a sheet.
See? What did I tell you?
Carlo Parini--
he's in Ely, finishing
up a five-year stint
for hit-and-run manslaughter.
So, your friend Haskell
has got himself
a free lap dance in jail.
Look, Haskell
is smart enough to know
that we were going
to come at him
with this list.
If he gives us nothing,
the game's over.
He gets nothing.
There's got to be
something here, Jim.
He's making us work for it.
Dr. Ray?
Yes.
Yeah. Uh, I accepted
a package for you.
It was marked perishable, so I
put it in the lunch fridge.
Thank you.
It's from a
James Langston.
Is that a relative
of yours?
My dad.
Oh, that's nice.
He's been dead for ten years.
We lived in Delaware
for a while,
when I was a kid.
Maybe it's some
kind of sick joke.
Or something worse.
ROBBINS:
Hmm. No batteries,
no switches,
no timers.
It doesn't look
like a bomb,
or any body part.
LANGSTON:
Well...
let's take a look.
See what we can see.
LANGSTON:
Hmm. It's my old I.D. badge.
Jekyll's come out to play.
(grunts)
ROBBINS:
Whoa.
Looks like homemade
beef jerky.
Or homemade people jerky.
ROBBINS:
You can't tell by looking at it.
LANGSTON:
That's da Vinci's Vitruvian man.
Looks to be hand-drawn,
with great precision.
STOKES:
Tattooed on meat?
LANGSTON:
"NAYL"?
That's text speak
for "in a while."
I have no idea what that is.
It appears to be a propeller
of some kind.
WILLOWS:
An angel.
That number's a John Doe.
ROBBINS:
David?
John Does are over here.
Uh, help Nick move
these bodies, would you?
JD-09-1157.
Day shift case.
December 2, 2009.
It's a typical body dump.
Okay, that's a couple of
months after Joey Bigelow,
and a couple of days
before Bernard Higgins
was worked on.
What was C.O.D.?
Uh, exsanguination
due to a stab wound.
Stab wound?
"An unusual sharp-force injury,
"wider at the entrance,
consistent with a typical,
"single-edged knife wound
for the first three inches.
"then extending
another three inches
"is a roughly circular,
eighth-inch-diameter
"wound track, which appears
to have perforated
the appendicular
artery."
And eighth-inch-diameter
wound that deep
would be consistent...
with a laparoscopic penetration.
And the appendicular
artery--
Jekyll surgically implanted
a septic appendix
into Bernie Higgins.
STOKES: Maybe the appendix
was meant for this guy
and Jekyll botched it.
He knew the guy
was gonna bleed out,
so he tried to cover
his mistake with a knife wound.
Why would he cover it up
back then,
and hand it to us
on a platter now?
Jekyll's getting
cocky, boys.
That's good for us.
(camera clicks)
Door's been open recently.
If you have a key
to the place, you could
come and go
as you please.
SANDERS:
Got blood.
But then again,
this is
where they prepared the food.
I'll test it.
(phone rings)
Hey, Nick?
I got a photo and a name:
Yuri Grishenko.
He's with another man
who appears
in a lot of the pictures
on the wall.
Sara, blood on the
table's human.
We just found
Jekyll's operating room.
SANDERS:
We got the DNA back from
the blood at the restaurant.
Two donors:
Joey Bigelow and the John Doe,
who we now know
as Yuri Grishenko.
He was a Ukranian businessman,
made his fortune
in gas and oil,
spent his winters
in Vegas gambling.
No family.
When his body was recovered,
his passport and wallet
were gone.
No one reported him missing,
and he fell
through the cracks.
So how did Jekyll
get Grishenko's
John Doe number?
WILLOWS: Probably called
the Coroner's Office,
used Ray's badge number
to get the information.
You see that mark...
on the leg?
That "X" is not a part
of da Vinci's original drawing.
And a mark like that
could imply surgical incision
through the groin.
None of his previous victims
had an injury there,
so this could be a present
or future victim.
Right.
I think that I...
saw something like this
in Herson's evidence box.
Like some sort of claw.
This is an IVC filter.
It's used to collect
clotted blood
in venous thrombosis patients,
and it's inserted
laparoscopically
through the groin.
So this... is a drawing
of an IVC filter.
All right.
"NAYL."
No... There's...
a partial horizontal break
in the stem of the "Y."
"Navel"?
"Navel."
A pneumonic
acronym taught
to medical students
to teach them how to locate
the femoral artery.
Nerve, Artery, Vein, Lymphatic.
It's the order in which
these anatomical structures
are positioned in the leg.
So if he meant N-A-V-L,
why did he use a "Y"?
Because he's a wordsmith.
He likes double entendres,
even triple entendres.
The "Y" could represent
the inferior vena cava, which is
the large forking vein
that carries blood
from the lower half of the body
up into the heart,
which is typically
where an IVC filter
is placed.
Jekyll is telling us
that "in a while"
he is going to insert
an IVC filter into the inferior
vena cava of his next victim.
(Sanders sighs)
So what's that propeller for?
It looks...
as if it was designed to fit
perfectly inside the filter.
If this device was inserted
into the inferior vena cava...
blood flow would cause
the propeller to turn,
which would cause the legs
of the filter itself
to expand out, pushing against
the interior wall of the vein.
How long could someone survive
with that thing inside them?
LANGSTON:
It's hard to say,
but it would work very slowly,
it would create
excruciating pain,
and eventually, the vein
would burst from the pressure,
and the victim would die.
(slowly, taunting):
♪ Barclay ♪
♪ Barclay... ♪
(sighs)
♪ Barclay ♪
♪ Barclay... ♪
Oh, my God!
Shut up!
Told you to shut the hell up.
My God!
♪ Barclay ♪
♪ Barclay... ♪
(annoyed sigh)
Uh, we're just
about finished.
Just give me what you got.
Well, the meat is definitely
not human; it's pork.
HODGES: In fact, it's
prosciutto di Parma.
Common prosciutto is cured
with garlic and spices--
cinnamon, cloves, nutmeg--
but prosciutto di Parma
is cured with sea salt
and then larded
and packed with cracked pepper,
allowing for the superior flavor
of the meat to come through.
So maybe Jekyll is moving up
in the culinary world.
DNA?
Well, there's definitely no
touch DNA-- that was negative.
But because it's prosciutto,
that means it was dehydrated.
And not cooked.
Right.
So we think it might
still contain some
embedded epithelial DNA,
if Jekyll wasn't
wearing gloves when
he made the jerky
in the first place.
How's it going?
Oh, we've been
cross-referencing
employees from
the old restaurant
with people who are
still in the industry.
Well, I can narrow down the
list-- we're only interested
in employees who are
now working at high-end
Italian restaurants.
Well, we've got
a handful of those.
Let's hit the streets.
There's a couple
cars in the lot.
Somebody's here.
Excuse me, sir?
Sorry, fellas,
kitchen's closed.
I'm Nick Stokes.
This is Ray Langston.
We're with
the crime lab.
We'd like to ask you a few
questions, if you got a minute.
Hey... it's always
an honor to help out
the Las Vegas
Police Department,
the greatest
in the world.
I'm Giovanni.
Everybody calls me Papa.
Thank you.
Have a seat.
All right, thanks.
Papa...
did you used to work at a
restaurant called Venetti's,
on the north side of town?
I managed the place.
Worked my way up
from dishwasher.
It was old-school, you know.
A red sauce joint, but...
a lot of great men--
important men-- ate there.
Do you manage
this place?
Come on.
(chuckles):
I own it.
DiMasa, that's me.
Papa DiMasa.
Hey, how about a glass of wine?
Aw, that's very
kind of you...
Come on,
come on, come on,
who's gonna know?
A glass of wine's
good for the heart.
Hey, Charlie, yo!
A good Barolo and three glasses.
We're looking for all the guys
who used to work
at Venetti's that
work here now, you
know what I mean?
DiMASA:
Yeah. Oh...
so this is Charlie--
he's the cook.
STOKES:
Charlie.
Gentlemen.
Yeah, I brought
a lot of the boys.
All good guys.
(gasping breaths)
Are you all right?
Whew! (wry laugh)
Being an owner.
Lot of stress.
Yeah, I'd like to take a look
at your employee list,
if you don't mind.
Yeah, sure.
Don't get up, Dad.
I'll get it.
How long have you
been experiencing
this pain, sir?
I don't know, a day or two.
Aw, don't worry
about me, I'm fine.
Do you have some kind
of heart condition?
Me? Nah.
Come on... I got
a heart like a lion,
like all the DiMasa men.
(gasps, groans quietly)
I just... I just got to...
lay off the Bolognese sauce,
you know?
(phone ringing)
Excuse me.
Stokes.
I just got the DNA results
from the meat cards.
Whoever made the prosciutto
is a filial match
to the septic appendix
we found in Bernard Higgins.
So that appendix either belonged
to Jekyll's father or...
Or his son.
Thanks, Catherine.
Mr. DiMasa, did you recently
have your appendix removed?
What are you, a mind reader?
Yeah. A couple of days
before Thanksgiving.
(groans)
STOKES:
Go back there and see what
that guy's doing.
Get him out of here, Ray.
Mr. DiMasa, we're gonna
take you to the hospital.
It's-It's okay.
I'm-I'm a doctor.
Oh... my son wanted
to be a doctor.
Yes...
(gunshot blasts)
LANGSTON: Come with me.
This way, sir.
STOKES: Shotgun!
Clark! Clark!
Situation! Clark!
CONTROL (over radio):
Three-David-34, Control.
Officer Clark, respond.
Charlie-oh-three-Stokes,
Control. Respond.
Control, Langston.
Shots fired.
Two officers down.
CHARLIE:
Got here too early, Ray,
but you're not gonna
spoil my fun.
Repeat. Shots fired.
Two officers down.
Armed suspect with a shotgun
in the restaurant.
CHARLIE:
Sure. Call 'em all.
Nothing the old man likes better
than an audience.
Isn't that so, Papa?!
What-What-What... What
are you talking about?
What?
Put your weapon down!
I don't want
to have to shoot you!
What do I care?
I'm a cop killer
twice over.
I just want
to see my father die.
You try and stop me,
and I'll blow you away!
PAPA: What, are
you crazy?
Are you out of
your mind?! (groans)
Mr. DiMasa-- slow, controlled,
even breaths, please.
HASKELL:
Don't you ever get tired
of standing
on your feet all day?
Man, I hear
that's what they do
to those guys down in Gitmo
to make them talk.
I can sit down,
if I want to.
Why don't you, man?
Maybe I don't want to.
Thing is, I could
make you a hero, Barclay.
I...
guess I could make you famous.
I've been screwing
with these other guys.
You know that, right?
But I could just give you
the whole head of cabbage.
You must know
people at Ely, right?
Maybe.
Mr. DiMasa, you have something
implanted in your chest.
You have to remain calm.
(groaning)
I hope it's tearing you up like
a thousand
knives inside.
I did that to you, Papa.
(Papa groaning loudly)
(yells, grunts)
That's the sound I want to hear.
Keep that strong DiMasa
heart pumping, Papa.
It's a drumbeat
right to the grave.
I wanted to be a doctor, Papa!
What stopped you, Charlie?
He did!
Look what I built.
For-For you, Charlie.
I never wanted it!
I could have been a great man.
A doctor, Papa.
But you had to wreck my life!
LANGSTON:
Do what a doctor would do.
Let him live.
I'm not asking
for the world here, man. I...
It's just,
my life there sucks.
All I want is an extra
half hour in the yard,
maybe some smokes
once in a while,
but... nothing illegal, man.
Screw you.
I know I got to give up
Jekyll's name to somebody,
while it's still
worth something.
Might as well be you.
Barclay, I like you a lot, man.
You have a light finger
on that button.
If it was me,
I'd be mashing
that thing just
to watch me dance. I...
But you are good people, man.
But I guess I'd see you
on the 6:00 news, right?
You'd be getting
a medal on your chest.
I don't know.
Would it help you
make detective, Barclay?
You'd strut around
like those guys.
You could probably
get laid, Barclay.
I mean, you'd probably
get laid a lot.
Who is he?
Dr. Jekyll is your mother.
What?
And she banged every one of 'em
before she killed them.
(croaks)
(electrical crackling)
(groaning in pain)
(gasps)
Sergeant Barclay.
I need medical in
the holding cells.
I got an inmate down.
LANGSTON:
Charlie, I understand
you wanting to kill
your old man, I do.
But why Higgins?
Why Herson?
Why all the others?
You killed all those men,
Charlie? You did that?!
Yeah... I killed
your friends, Pop.
Your heroes.
Great men who were
what I could never be.
Never good enough.
I got through three
years of medical school,
and then Mama died.
And you used that to suck me
back in, didn't you, Papa?
I need, I needed
you, Charlie.
CHARLIE:
To serve your heroes!
I should have been your hero!
I was lonely.
I-I... I needed you, Charlie.
Charlie, listen to me.
I wished my old man dead
a thousand times over.
He was a drunk, you
know? A real bad drunk.
One night, he'd
been out fighting.
A neighbor brought him home,
blind drunk.
Someone had beaten him
so terribly,
he had a bruise on his throat
the size of a baseball.
I pulled him up
on the porch
and watched him try
and catch his breath
while he was
gargling blood.
I was so tired
of taking him
to the emergency room,
I just left him there.
Figured he'd
sleep it off.
When I came down
in the morning,
he was laying in a patch
of winter sunshine,
and he was
stone-cold dead
where I left him.
How'd that make you feel?
Not the way you think it's gonna
make you feel, Charlie.
I just want to see him die.
Shouldn't be much longer now.
Let me tell you something,
Charlie.
Even when the old man dies,
you're not gonna stop
being his son.
You become
the son of a ghost.
The pain doesn't go away.
The rage doesn't go away.
So, come on, put your gun down,
walk out of here, be a man.
I will.
Soon as he's dead.
I can't let
that happen, Charlie.
I'm going
to stand up now.
I'm standing up, Charlie.
I'm going to walk into the back,
get some ice.
Slow your father's
heart rate.
(heavy sigh)
(siren approaching)
STOKES:
Y'all better get out of here
before there's a crime
scene to investigate.
You scared
the hell out of us, Nicky.
Ah... I'll be all right.
LANGSTON:
Papa DiMasa made it
through surgery.
The doctors were able to remove
the filter and stent the vein.
He's going to make it.
The Jekyll case is closed.
On to the next one, right?
Unfortunately,
there's always a next one.
Mm.
I'll see you soon.
All right.
I'll be back
to give you a lift home?
(groaning):
Oh, no way.
You're a terrible driver.
(Sidle and Stokes laugh)
STOKES:
Ray?
Yeah?
That story you told
about your father--
did you really just
let him die like that?
I should have let the son
of a bitch die, but...
I loved him.
I took a knife,
I opened his trachea,
saved his life.
Watched him die of
lung cancer two years later.
Hey, you feel better.
I play dead good, don't I?
You should've been an actor.
(laughs)
Thanks, Cath.
Nick's going to be okay.
(sighs)
That's great.
HODGES:
Okay. Thanks.
How is he?
I'm assuming he's okay,
because he wants us
to bring him a pizza,
or he's gonna kick our asses.
(quiet laugh)
Do you want to
come with us?
No, thanks.
Uh... just tell him
I'm glad he's all right.
Jim.
Come on, I'll buy you
a drink at PJ's.
Listen, uh, give me a minute.
I'll catch up to you.
Officer, give us
a little room, will you?
Hello, Nate.
I came to tell
you that...
You killed Jekyll.
All the urgency's gone out
of your eyes, Doctor.
All the tension's out
of your body.
You look like you came out
of it relatively unscathed.
You know what they say,
"Whatever doesn't kill you..."
I knew you
and Charlie would get along.
Daddy issues.
And the irony is, Doctor,
he didn't kill nearly
as many people
as he would've,
if he'd followed his dream
and become, you know,
your average surgeon.
Am I right?
Good-bye, Nate.