(upbeat music plays)
(music continues playing)
(music continues,
playing on radio)
♪ ♪
(gasping)
(shower running)
Killer forgot
we're in a drought.
LANGSTON:
What the hell is that?
Well, this didn't
occur naturally.
Oh, what tipped you off?
The two half hitches
and a bow?
No,
the fact that the
small intestine
is tied around the spleen.
It's red and green
and looks like a
Christmas present.
All right, the case was in
backlog pending autopsy.
Joseph Bigelow
was found in an alley
off of Charleston and Avert.
There were no signs
of foul play.
Typical dead bum case.
Autopsy was pro forma.
Joseph Bigelow.
I've heard
that name before.
Well, I bet you've never seen
this before.
WILLOWS:
Okay.
Not so typical
dead bum case.
Is that C.O.D.?
ROBBINS:
No, blood vessels
are occluded.
He died of natural causes.
Myocardial infarct
due to atherosclerosis.
I'd have a heart attack, too,
if someone did that to me.
Intestines show no vital
tissue reaction.
No signs of peritonitis.
He was mutilated postmortem.
So, he died,
then someone cut into him
and gift-wrapped his guts?
Only he wasn't cut into.
There are no visible incisions
on his body.
LANGSTON:
One thing's for sure.
He didn't do this to himself.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
WOMAN:
Can't I just go?
I want to get out of here.
BRASS: Just want ask a few
questions, all right?
Just a few questions.
Okay?
(sirens chirping
intermittently)
(voice breaking):
I just want to go home.
How did you know Ryan Lester?
He-He was my boss.
He was your boss.
What kind of work
do you do?
Entertainment.
So, did you and Ryan have a
relationship outside of work?
We hooked up a few times.
Okay...
But that... that was
a long time ago.
At least a couple of weeks.
All right,
so tell me what happened.
I was taking
a hot shower.
I was gonna go
home and study.
(gasping)
Ryan.
Not funny.
What?
Get out.
The view is "def" better
from this angle.
Ew.
BRASS: Okay, so he got
in the shower with you
with his clothes on?
Yeah, he was freaky like that.
And there was no fight?
There was no struggle?
I've learned to deal
with Ryan's "assitude,"
as long as I get a fat check
at the end of the week.
All right, keep going.
What else?
I went into the bedroom
to get changed.
(thudding in distance)
Ryan?
The power's out again.
WOMAN:
I thought he fell or something,
so I went in to check on him.
(screaming)
Help!
Somebody help! Help!
Stop!
Stop, please help!
(sobbing):
Help!
Are you all right?
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Easy, easy...
And if... if that guy
hadn't seen me...
...then I'd probably
be dead, too.
Well, you're lucky.
You're okay.
Now, the CSI is going to want
to take your clothes.
You're okay with that, right?
Yeah.
Okay, now just
wait right here.
Stay right there.
Uh, Mr. Wincroft?
Wincroft, yes.
Wincroft, right.
Okay, so, the CSI's gonna
want to take your clothes, too.
You're all right
with that, right?
Oh, yeah.
You're the one who called 911?
Uh, yeah, I'm the
Neighborhood Watch captain.
Mm-hmm.
Here, let me give you these.
No, no, no.
Keep your shirt
on, captain.
We're gonna do it
down at the station.
(indistinct background
radio communication)
(siren wailing into distance)
Hey, give me some light here,
will you?
(radio chirps)
Hey, somebody turned
the power off.
I think I might've pulled
a partial off the main breaker.
I'm turning the power
back on now.
(camera shutter clicking)
What is going on in here?
Sorry I'm late.
The freezer is
still on the fritz
from when those ROC
goons tore up the place.
It's not like we can
hang a "closed" sign
on the door or anything.
Hey, what kind of a house
has a sign-in board, man?
I don't know.
Where am I going?
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, sorry, Super Dave.
Follow me.
End of the hallway.
I wonder if the bedroom
across the hall
has a Webcam, too.
Uh, I'm pretty
sure it does.
How would you know
something like that?
Nick, could I tell you
something personal?
Maybe.
Mrs. Phillips and I
occasionally enjoy
a little... live stimulation
to get us in the mood.
What I'm saying is,
uh, I'm intimately familiar
with this
particular bedroom.
I subscribe to the Web site.
Well, try and maintain
your objectivity.
Of course.
(sighs)
(camera shutter clicks)
After you.
David. I missed
your face.
Aw, it's good
to see you.
How's your wife?
Good. Great. Why?
What have you heard?
The, um, back door is broken.
It's probably the killer's
entrance and exit point.
Looks like
a men's size ten to 12.
There's not much detail
in these impressions.
STOKES:
Not much?
There's no detail.
It's kind of weird,
actually.
SIDLE: Maybe his shoes
had smooth soles.
Or maybe he was doing
what we do.
Which means
he planned this out.
Great.
PHILLIPS:
Hey, guys.
We've got a single laceration
here, left to right.
Sliced the
carotid-jugular complex.
This guy didn't
cut too deep.
Just deep enough, actually.
Efficient.
ROBBINS:
You're in a room,
no doors, no windows.
How do you get out?
Same way you got in.
(chuckles)
Mm, I heard it this way.
You're in a room with
no doors, no windows,
there's a chain saw
and a table.
How do you get out?
I give up.
You cut the table in half
with the chain saw.
Two halves make a...?
"Hole."
Out you go.
Brother.
(laughing)
Well, whoever did this
had to get in and out
through a "hole."
Well, think it was
a natural opening
or did he make one?
Either way,
he had to use an endoscope
or a laparoscope.
Well...
here at the navel, that could
be a laparoscopic opening.
Oh, yeah.
Mm-hmm.
Hmm... Internally...
the incision is open,
but externally, it's fused.
I don't see any sutures,
so probably used
surgical glue.
Whoever did this had to have
access to medical equipment.
A doctor, med student,
surgical nurse.
This isn't medicine.
So, I hear you're the
Neighborhood Watch captain,
is that right?
Yeah.
Well, since the
housing crash, you know,
I've had to really
step up my patrols.
You know, the banks nowadays--
they're selling,
and renting out
these houses
to anyone
who has a dime.
Yeah, tell me about it.
I got the same problem
in my neighborhood.
Obviously, I could've
done a better job,
being that someone was killed.
Well, the girl wasn't.
She claims you saved her life.
Well, I do my best.
You know,
I pick up my flashlight
the minute I come home
from work.
Good man.
Here, have a seat.
Oh, sure.
So, tell me,
how well did you know
Ryan Lester?
Not really. Uh, I mean,
I've seen him coming
and going.
You know,
the Greene family
owned that house before him--
good friends--
until they lost
their jobs
and had to foreclose.
Yeah, man,
everybody's feeling it.
I'm so underwater in my house,
I should be wearing scuba gear
in there, you
know what I mean?
And neighborhoods aren't
neighborhoods anymore.
Yeah.
You know, we even got a peeper
in our neighborhood.
Really?
Yeah.
I mean,
I haven't seen him yet,
but a few of the neighbors,
you know, that are left,
they said they saw him
lurking around.
Do you think, uh, anybody could
give me description?
Well, the minute I get
something, you're my first call.
Can you hold out your index
finger for me, please?
(electronic blipping)
Why is your print on the circuit
breaker at Ryan's house?
Because I'm always
turning it back on.
I told that cop earlier--
the lights are always
going out.
With all the Webcams,
curling irons,
and blow-dryers,
the thing overloads.
Can you hold out
your hands for me?
Ryan's too cheap
to call an electrician.
Did you touch the switch
last night?
No. I don't do anything at night
except go to my car.
There's a Peeping Tom
in the neighborhood.
Have you seen him?
No.
If I had, he'd have my Mace
in his face.
Ryan said he's seen him
running from the house.
Did Ryan happen to tell you
what this peeper looked like?
You ever seen Marilyn Manson?
SANDERS:
So, I've been scanning
through this Webcam footage
for the past couple hours.
It's a tough job.
I manage.
By the way, congrats on your
new gig, supervisor.
You deserve it.
Thanks, Greg.
So, the, uh,
Webcam girls turn off
their cameras
at the end of their shift.
So Marnie's camera was off
when Ryan bit it.
Check this out.
The curtains moved.
I don't see
any hands.
So, unless it was
the AC, what is it?
A ghost?
Looks like there's something
behind the curtain,
covering the windows.
Probably to keep the light out.
And anybody
from looking in.
Not so sure
about that.
Maybe it is a ghost.
Ray.
I remember how I know
this Bigelow guy.
Years ago, I used to catch
this lounge act at the Riv.
Joey-- "Joe Joe" Bigelow
was always there.
Sitting in the back
with his dirty tux on,
playing air piano
to every tune.
Mm-hmm.
The rumor is that he...
he really did play
piano for Dean Martin.
All the old-timers knew him.
Wow.
Every day,
Joe Joe would walk
from the Nugget
to the Mandalay
and back again.
Just looking for
some ivories
to tickle, chasing
the dream.
I guess he hadn't heard
that live piano players went
the way of the dollar martini.
Well, my point is,
is that he was on the streets,
sleeping in different alleys,
but always within spitting
distance of the Strip.
Here's Las Vegas
Boulevard.
Here's where
the body was found.
So?
Joe Joe was
a Strip snob.
He wouldn't be caught dead west
of the 15.
But he was caught dead there.
Which suggests
that that is where his surgeon
works or lives.
It also suggests that...
he didn't know Joey.
And that he selected him
at random.
STOKES:
Now, looks like the peeper
jimmied the window open.
Cut himself a handy little flap
in the cardboard.
Yeah, so he could see
the ladies in action.
Closed...
never really noticed it.
But open...
I can see everything.
There's some white trace
around the peephole.
Kind of looks like makeup.
Marnie Bennett said
that the peeper
looked like Marilyn Manson.
He wears a lot of makeup.
I'll swab it.
Hey, now what do you see?
Nothing.
He would've had to...
move the curtains
to the side
to enjoy the show.
Which is what we
saw on the Webcam.
Aha!
The old wire hanger
through the peephole trick.
(chuckling):
Yeah.
And I have a pretty good idea
where this old wire hanger
came from.
Hey, Jim, this is Charlie-05.
I need a warrant for Diamond
Star Cleaners, please, sir.
(doorbell rings)
This is the only household
in the development
that uses Diamond Star Cleaners.
Faith Mason?
Yes.
Ma'am,
is there anyone else inside?
What's this about?
It's a warrant
to search your house.
Uh, my son is upstairs.
I'll get him.
STOKES:
No, no.
That's all right,
Mrs. Mason.
We'll get him. What's his name?
Craig.
Craig. Okay.
Come on, Sara.
(black metal music
blasting in distance)
grows louder)
♪ ♪
(knocking on door)
Craig!
Las Vegas Police.
(music blaring)
Craig!
Get up! Las Vegas Police!
(loud music continues)
(music stops)
Craig!
Craig, come on, buddy!
Time to wake up!
Don't touch me.
Las Vegas Police.
We need you
to step outside.
(scoffs)
You aren't the police.
Yeah, that's
all right,
we brought one with us.
Get your ass up.
I said get up!
Jeepers creepers.
Does anybody
believe in sunlight
in this neighborhood?
(click, beep)
Hey, Sara.
Ten and a halves.
Same size as the
show impressions
at the scene.
I have seen this
mask before.
Is it from a horror movie
or something?
This job is a
horror movie.
I don't even watch them anymore.
Hey.
I think we're in
the right place.
(Sidle groans)
(clears throat)
What is it?
It's, um...
(groans)
Satanists have been known
to collect dead crows,
to keep the smell of death
around them.
How do you know that?
Grissom?
Ozzy Osbourne.
I loved Black Sabbath.
For a summer.
Well, in that case,
I guess we're lucky
the head's still on it.
Sara.
Did Ozzy, uh, say anything
about collecting dead bodies?
(chuckles)
What?
(sighs)
Scary masks.
Rubber hands.
Arts and crafts.
What's this kid's name again?
Craig Mason.
As in Judge Mason?
Aka Paul Millander.
WILLOWS:
You're never going to believe
who Judge Mason's
fingerprints match.
GRISSOM:
His real name
is Paul Millander.
He's a serial killer
with a split personality.
This is our best-seller-- even
used my own hand for the mold.
MRS. MASON:
I'd like you to meet
our son Craig.
You'll be safe now.
Craig Mason is Paul Millander's
adopted son.
Son of Millander.
Nature or nurture--
you choose.
Either way,
this kid Mason's a freak.
And not very
cooperative.
The only thing he hates
worse than cops is CSIs.
He even mentioned Grissom's name
a few times.
Well, then I won't mention
that I'm Mrs. Grissom.
Oh, you took his last name?
Uh, no.
Uh, turns out we do not have
a murder weapon.
According to Wendy, the blood
on Craig's straightedge
does not belong
to Ryan Lester.
Well, maybe there was
more than one knife.
I'll call Canine,
have them meet them
at the scene.
Thank you.
My son didn't do
anything wrong.
Mrs. Mason, I am only here
to collect evidence.
I married a judge.
Craig's father was a judge,
not a serial killer.
This is not about
Craig's father.
You know damn well it is.
Craig shouldn't be punished
for Paul Millander's sins.
I can assure you
he will only be punished
if he has broken the law.
Now, if you'll please
excuse me.
Craig.
Hi.
I need your clothes
and a DNA sample.
Look, don't force me to
do this the hard way.
Can you sit
up, please?
I know you've had a
hard childhood, and
you've probably been scrutinized
at every school
that you've been to,
and to you, I'm just
another one of those
people who wants
to put you under a
microscope, but...
Just shut up
and take my DNA.
(sniffing)
(dog whining, panting)
(dog barks)
STOKES: Where's he goin'?
This is the Mason house.
I don't know!
Get that dog back.
Clear it, Mitch.
His throat's slit
just like Ryan Lester's.
SANDERS:
Dried blood, fixed lividity.
Been here
at least 24 hours.
MITCH:
Code four.
You're going to want
to see this.
Whoa-ho-ho!
The plot thickens.
Porn house,
drug house.
Millander house
in between.
They must throw one hell
of a block party.
ROBBINS:
A drug dealer
named Kilo, 25.
I compared his neck wound
to Ryan Lester's.
They're virtually identical.
Both incised wounds
about an inch deep.
Result of an extremely
sharp, thin blade.
But there's something additional
with Mr. Kilo.
Parallel abrasions
on both sides of the incision.
Murder weapon was probably
a utility knife
or box cutter.
STOKES:
If the same weapon was used
on both victims,
then why didn't we find
similar abrasions
on Ryan Lester here?
Might be a matter of pressure.
Killer pressed harder
on Mr. Kilo.
He jammed the body
of the weapon
right up against his neck.
T.O.D.'s?
Both men were killed
between 10:00 p.m. and 2:00 a.m.
I can't tell you
who was first.
Well, either way,
we've got ourselves
a spree killer.
ANCHORWOMAN:
This afternoon while
investigators were at the scene
of the Ryan Lester homicide,
a police dog lead them
to a second murder victim
located several houses down.
Police have a suspect
in custody
related to the murder
of Ryan Lester,
who was attacked and killed
in his own home last night.
Officials have not confirmed
a connection
between the two murders.
(door opening)
And police are asking
the public to please
contact the Las Vegas
Police Department with any...
Where are you
taking him?
CCDC.
Uh, we have evidence
placing your son
at the scene
of the first murder.
For the moment,
we're holding him
under NRS-200.603.
It's peeping.
Did you really do that?
Did you look
into other people's homes?
Yeah.
But I didn't kill anyone.
I was just looking
at the girls.
That's why they do it.
I just wasn't paying.
Mom, just bail me out, okay?
Mom?
Mom, you-you believe me,
don't you?
Mom!
Mom! Mom!
Mom, I didn't do it!
Your son's going
to need a lawyer.
(stifled sobbing)
(door opening)
I'm learning
when I can't find you,
I should look down here.
This is very
difficult.
It's like attempting to tie
a cherry stem
into a knot
with your tongue.
I can do that...
after a few drinks.
(sighing)
Our Dr. Jekyll has some
remarkable surgical skills.
Dr. Jekyll?
Whoever mutilated Mr. Bigelow.
What remarkable surgeon
steals a dead man
off the streets,
practices on him,
and then dumps him in an alley?
No surgeon I ever met.
You did get permission
from the family
to use this body for research?
Not necessary.
Take a look.
(laughs)
I'm hosting a luau later.
Well, don't invite Sara.
And before you put on
your grass skirt
and put pinkie on a spit,
I need you in Layout.
Nick and Sara need some
fresh eyes on the Mason case.
Okay... Come on,
come on, come on...
(sighs)
DNA has come up empty.
There's no sign of either victim
on Craig Mason's
clothes or shoes.
I did notice some scars
on his arms.
I think he was using
the straight razor
to cut himself.
STOKES:
Hodges analyzed the white trace
that was found around the
peephole at the Webcam house,
and it was a match
to Craig's corpse makeup.
So we can put him
at the house,
but not in the house.
And we have nothing
so far
that puts him
at the drug dealer's house.
We keep looking.
His mother hasn't
bailed him out yet.
I don't think
she's going to.
She had that look
in her eye
that maybe he did it.
It is classic escalation.
From peeper
to murderer.
He's a teenager.
There were attractive women
coming in and out of that house
all the time.
It doesn't seem that
sinister to me. Besides,
he didn't murder the person
that he was peeping.
STOKES:
Maybe he saw Ryan Lester
as competition.
You know, Lester was intimate
with Marnie.
Craig could only watch her
from a distance.
All right, say that's true.
Then what about
the second victim,
Cliff Kilo?
WILLOWS:
Extensive criminal record.
It's mostly drug related.
Why would Mason murder
a drug dealer?
Did he have drugs
in his system?
No.
Tox panel came back clean.
And it wasn't about money.
I mean, there was cash
all over the house.
All right, if...
Craig wasn't a ghoul,
and if his father hadn't come
after Grissom,
would you be considering him
at all?
And whose hand is this?
It's Millander's.
Used his own hand to make
the mold.
All right,
did Paul Millander's thumbs
and forefingers have
a congenital malformation?
No.
Then this isn't his hand.
(latch clicks, door slides)
Hello, Craig.
My name is Ray.
I work at the
crime lab.
Can I see your hands?
Please?
Hmm.
Good. Just a moment.
Let me just
document them.
(camera shutter clicks)
I'm gonna need your help
with a little
experiment.
Why would I help
the crime lab?
Who said
you'd be helping the crime lab?
You're going to help yourself.
(click)
See, Craig, you and I
have something in common.
We both have fathers
who killed people.
Your father was a serial killer?
No. He was a soldier
in the Korean War.
He even got a Bronze
Star for his work.
That's different.
No, it's not.
See, after the war was over,
my father continued to fight.
Every once in a while,
he would go out to a bar.
Not so much to drink,
but to pick fights?
I remember one day, he came
home, he was very excited.
Had a black eye
and a fat lip.
Was bragging about
how he had knocked somebody out.
Said he hit the man so hard,
the paramedics had
to peel him off the floor.
Said it was the most fun
he'd ever had.
(Langston groans)
Why don't you come over here
and cut his throat, Craig?
What?
Come on, cut his throat.
Don't hold back.
Show me how much
you're not like your father.
Hey.
Hey. We got a warrant for
Craig Mason's medical records.
You were right. He was born
with a congenital malformation.
He made a mold of his own hand?
Like father,
like son.
Well, both neck wounds
were uniform.
Left to right,
slightly downward.
Take a look
at Jell-O Man.
SIDLE:
Cut's uneven. Shallow.
It's almost
vertical.
Huh.
He could have done that
on purpose.
LANGSTON:
Well, his anomaly makes it
virtually impossible for him
to hold a box cutter properly.
I watched him.
That was the
best he could do.
Okay. So,
if Craig didn't kill them,
who did?
You guys got any evidence
outstanding?
ECKLIE:
Diane, tell the mayor
I'm on my way.
You know,
I just had to make
a little pit stop
at the crime lab.
Yeah.
Yeah, all right.
Thank you.
What do you
need, Ray?
Crooked?
What are you doing?
Thank you.
You know how hard
these things are to tie?
Got your text.
What's up?
What do you see?
WILLOWS:
A guy who likes having
his picture taken?
He's wearing a bow tie.
Oh, right.
When we found the body,
he wasn't wearing a tie.
There's no bow tie on the body,
not anywhere on the body.
Not even in the pockets.
A man who wears a tuxedo
every day
doesn't forget his bow tie.
So what?
Someone took it?
His bow tie's missing.
His intestines are tied
into a bow.
That can't be a coincidence.
I think Dr. Jekyll
took it as a souvenir.
A souvenir?
That's what serial killers do.
Joe Joe died of natural causes.
I have a bad feeling
that this is not
the last time
we're going to see Dr. Jekyll.
And I think next time,
he's not gonna be content
starting with a dead body.
♪ ♪
If Marnie embraced Harvey,
then the blood on his shirt
would be secondary transfer.
But on Harvey's shirt,
there's an additional
blood pattern
here,
across the shoulder,
but not on Marnie's.
Which means it can't be
secondary transfer.
Shoulder area,
large, discreet drops
in a single line.
That is arterial spurt.
(yelling)
(groaning)
(sirens wailing,
indistinct radio transmission)
Las Vegas Police!
Mr. Wincroft, I need
you to step outside.
We have a warrant to
search your house.
Captain Brass.
Here to make sure
the neighborhood's safe?
OFFICER:
Gun!
BRASS:
Okay, okay.
Harvey, put the gun
on the ground.
You know how many times
I've called you guys,
calling for help?
How many times you told me
you couldn't do anything
until a crime was committed?
Look, next time, you ask for me.
You tell them you want
to speak to Jim Brass.
So this Ryan,
he buys the Greenes' house
for five bucks, then he starts
selling Webcam sex out of it.
My daughter's seven.
To see that on her way
to school?
Obey the sign.
(door closes)
Okay, call it in--
man with a gun,
potential hostage situation.
Check around the back.
I need you to stay clear.
Jim, we gotta get that
family out of there.
(door opening)
Hey, I want to ask you
something.
Come here.
You know how much money
you owe on your house?
What?
You said you could go
scuba diving in your house.
STOKES:
Yeah, yeah, uh...
I don't know.
About 300 grand.
Why don't you talk
to me, Harvey?
Why don't you take a step back?
We're having a conversation.
All right. Okay.
Okay, Harvey,
I-I'll talk to you, man.
What is it?
You know, I own this house
outright.
25 years of lifting
heavy boxes for World-Send.
I put every cent I made
into this house.
You know, I don't have
a retirement fund
or a life savings.
(sirens approaching)
This house...
...is all we have.
Where I come from,
that's the American Dream.
Well, my American Dream became
kind of a prison, didn't it?
Hey, wait a minute now, Harvey.
We're... we're
talking here, remember?
Answer me this:
Why did you buy this house
in the first place?
For my family.
Then why are you putting
your family in danger?
Please, put the gun down.
I told you to stay back!
Come on, Harvey.
If you love them,
let them go.
Sweetheart, Daddy needs you
to go with the nice man, okay?
Daddy, please, no.
Just go, okay.
No...
STOKES:
It's okay, honey.
I got you.
I got you, come on.
No, Daddy, please.
Go!
No.
I said go!
Come on.
I got you, baby.
It's okay.
I'll take care of her, Harvey.
Why don't you
put the gun down
and let her mom go, too?
Come on, Harvey!
Cherry.
(cocks gun)
BRASS:
No, Harvey...
Don't-don't-don't
do it. Don't.
Don't do it, Harvey.
Don't do it.
I just wanted to protect
my family.
(handcuffs clicking)
♪ ♪
Soon as you're processed out,
you're free to go.
Craig...
if we made you feel like
you were paying for
your father's crimes,
I'm sorry.
You know, I never even
met Mr. Millander.
Yet, I'm more like
a Millander than a Mason.
You probably wonder
how that happened.
It has crossed my mind.
You see, my father,
Doug Mason,
took me to the Halloweird
warehouse once a month.
He told me that the owner,
Mr. Millander,
was his friend.
And in there,
my father played with me
just like any father
would play with his son.
Millander's costumes
were toys to me.
And I told my father,
every time we went,
to tell this Mr. Millander
that he was a genius.
And then, one day,
it all stopped.
I lost both my father...
...and my idol.
Making masks and rubber hands
is my way of keeping
the connection alive.
Is my mom here to pick me up?
I can give you a lift.
Let's go.
♪ ♪
LANGSTON:
See, Craig, you and I have
something in common.
We both have fathers
who killed people.
CRAIG:
Your father was
a serial killer?
No, he was a soldier
in the Korean War.
He even got a Bronze Star
for his work.
That's different.
No, it's not.
See, after the war was over,
my father continued to fight.
Every once in a while,
he would go out to a bar.
Not so much to drink
but to pick fights.
I remember one day he came
home, he was very excited.
Had a black eye
and a fat lip.
He was bragging about how
he had knocked somebody out.
He said he hit
the man so hard
the paramedics had to
peel him off the floor.
Said it was the most fun
he'd ever had.
Why don't you come over here
and cut his throat, Craig?
CRAIG:
What?
Come on,
cut his throat.
Show me how much
you're not like your father.