Wow, I love it already.
I can't believe we're doing this.
Is that the lockbox?
Broker gave me the combination.
He's doing a walk-through
in Seven Hills.
Owners are out.
Wow.
Wait till you see
the master.
Oh, my God.
This is gorgeous.
Amazing.
What?
Want to snoop around?
Hey.
What do you think?
I don't know, yeah.
It's nice?
Looks good.
Cut it out.
No, seriously,
I think I hear a car.
Will you relax?
No, really.
You're paranoid.
( laughs )
Oh, my God.
I could get used
to this place.
I bet you could.
I could.
You're an animal.
The backyard is the best
part of the house.
Really? Is there
a Jacuzzi?
Oh, my God.
Looks like something
out of a magazine.
Cal and Monica Newman.
Owners of the house.
My guess, second marriage.
'Cause she's a babe
and he's...
He's, uh...
got a good sense of humor.
.380 auto caliber.
GRISSOM:
Gunshot, right temple.
Women don't usually shoot
themselves in the head
do they, Catherine?
Well, gunshots do
a number on your face
so typically women
prefer pills.
BRASS:
So what are we calling this,
murder, suicide, what?
Is the husband around?
No.
Well, do the math:
Dead female spouse
plus missing husband...
equals murder.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
Okay, Warrick, hit it.
( beeping )
White female,
multiple bruising...
Bullet hole to the temple
doesn't help.
.380 auto on the side.
Yeah, somebody manhandled her
pretty good
before they killed her.
Reminds me
of my daughter.
She used throw butts
out the window, too.
The Newmans have kids?
A kid.
Son, 15, Max Newman.
He's MIA like the father.
The secretary said
he went out for lunch
and never came back.
I checked the garage--
three cars.
None of the hoods
are hot.
We're missing something.
Grissom.
Mr. Grissom.
Where would I find
Mr. Grissom?
Great, great. Thank you
very much. Mr. Grissom?
Hi, I'm Augie Heitz.
This is my listing.
Someone died, I know.
It's a terrible thing.
But we got people
knocking down awnings
stomping through
the flower beds.
How am I supposed
to sell this house?
You're not.
It's a crime scene.
Mr. Heitz, you're
Mr. Newman's broker.
Have you seen
your client lately?
What, you kidding?
I mean,
this is actually
the beauty of the service
I provide.
My clients never have to see me.
They don't even have to be home
when I show their house.
Do you always give
out the combination
to your lockboxes?
It's illegal.
It's a hot market.
Um...
You know, I had a fish
on the line.
Potential bidding war.
Look... ( clears throat )
I only give out the combination
to people that I really trust.
All right, look,
I read rooms for a living.
That closet was tossed.
The carpet lit up.
So I'm going to ask you again.
What were you doing in there
besides copulating?
It was my idea.
Right. Well, we found this
laptop on the vanity still on.
You didn't play
with it, too, did you?
Hey, Warrick.
Check this out.
It's a little thin
for blood, isn't it?
Yeah.
What do you...?
Tastes like sugar water.
Erythrosine.
Red dye number three.
Hummingbirds
do love the color red.
You've been watching
way too much
Discovery Channel.
This guy needs a girl.
I'm going to check out
the cabana.
No visible footprints.
Doesn't mean someone
wasn't out here.
Grab the LS.
Yeah.
Hey.
Sara.
I am so sorry.
I paged you two hours ago.
Right. Uh, it's my day off.
I was up in Pahrump
at some vineyard.
You told me to get a life,
remember?
Did I?
I'm sorry, but I needed you.
Dispatch called in a 419
at Tuscadero High School.
You're on your own.
On my own?
Solo.
See you around.
Solo?
So does this mean
when I come in on my day off
I get to work solo?
Process.
Whoa.
I got what looks like
two sets of prints.
Ballpark in a size ten
from the house.
And what looks like a...
size 12, possibly
from the pool.
There were definitely
two guys here, Griss.
Now we just need to
figure out if one of
them was Mr. Newman.
Hey, fellas.
Looks like the husband
pulled a Clark Kent
and left all his clothes behind.
Couldn't have gone far.
I got his wallet,
credit card
and keys.
You hear that?
What is that?
Oh, yeah,
it's the pool.
It's been doing it
all night.
Sounds like
it's clogged.
Did someone
check this pool?
First officer
said it was clear.
Does that pool
look clear to you?
Uh... no.
One of you guys
is going in.
( clears throat )
I'll go in the pool.
Oh, man!
Male D.B.
You have dinner yet?
Yeah. Why?
You might be
seeing it again.
Mandy Kirk.
Seventeen.
Senior.
Janitor found her.
Hi, David.
Hey.
Eviscerated.
Maybe a wild animal.
They picked up a mountain lion
last week in Henderson.
Suburbs are encroaching
on the hinterlands.
We'll know more
after the autopsy.
It's a cheerleader.
She had to have good lungs.
How come nobody
heard her scream?
Didn't have to do
much of a "Y."
Attack did it for me.
Died of exsanguination.
Bled out.
Trauma to her
internal organs.
Spleen, liver, heart
they all sustained
multiple mastications.
Hmm.
You able to isolate the species?
From the tooth mark
on her left ninth rib.
Dog maybe?
Teeth marks are too small
for a mountain cat.
They're human.
You're lying.
You can see the bridgework
on this impression
of a premolar and
an adjoining molar.
Can you tell how old
the attacker is?
Well, I can't give you
the exact age
but wisdom teeth erupt
between 16 and 30.
And there's no evidence
of a wisdom molar
on this impression.
Thanks.
Oh, one more thing.
I found an infection
in the mucus
overlying the
large intestine.
This girl suffered
from the E-coli bacteria.
E-coli?
Unsanitary conditions?
Or a bad burger.
So whoever did this to her
also has E-coli.
Oh, yeah.
Spiked temp, vomiting,
lower GI problems, the works.
Smoking gun.
I mean, I don't get it.
She's not even
slated to work
she comes in
on her day off
and she gets to work solo.
You still harping on
the solo thing?
You know every time
you work with me
you learn something.
( chuckles )
Is that right?
Yes.
I live here.
Why can't I go in?
I want to see my father.
I'm Cal's ex-wife, Jeri Newman
and this is our son Max.
We have the right
to an answer.
And we have a right
to protect the crime scene.
What's going on?
I can't tell you anything
until I get all the details.
I'm sorry.
Catherine?
We need someone
to identify the body.
Ms. Newman.
Would you come
with me, please?
What about me?
Uh, no, honey.
You stay right here.
No skin separation.
Minimal gaseous buildup.
This guy's been in here
under 12 hours.
According to his office,
he left work at 1:00.
It's about right.
What is that,
some kind of filter?
It's an anti-vortex filter.
Hey, I'm from Jersey,
we swim at the shore.
It's designed to keep his hand
out of that pipe.
But it's missing a few screws.
Ms. Newman, is this
your ex-husband?
It's Cal.
Virtual tour.
Right on, Archie.
Before and after photos
of the crime scene.
( imitating Elvis Presley):
Thank you, thank you very much.
It was on
the hard drive
of the computer you
got at the crime scene.
Looks like
a Peter Croft sculpture.
You know your art.
You a collector?
What? On my salary?
Guggenheim's as close as I get
to something
like that.
Oh, I haven't been yet.
Really?
Well, if you want a tour,
I know a docent.
A docent.
So, you think
that's legit?
House like this, probably
not a knock-off.
You'd be surprised.
The rich go cheap to stay
rich, know what I mean?
Yeah. Let me show you
the after photos.
Please.
Same spot.
And, uh, what happened
to the sculpture?
Good question.
You saying somebody lifted it?
Well, they don't call them
open houses for nothing.
Put your house
on the market
your privacy's
up for grabs, too.
The Newmans
unlocked their door
to anybody
with Internet access.
Soccer bunnies?
What are soccer bunnies?
Well, each cheerleader
is assigned a soccer player.
She's his bunny.
Gives him gifts the night
before the big game
places his wake-up call.
Sounds sexual.
Yeah, that's what
I asked the principal
but he said no.
He said that, uh
it's all good, clean fun.
Gifts are
inspirational videos
like, uh, Rocky
and wake-up calls are
pep talks, nothing more.
Yeah, well, I'm not
sure the principal's
up to speed on teenagers'
sexual habits.
Yeah, well, victim Mandy
was soccer bunny
to a Chuck Darwell.
And when I called him
on his cell this morning
he said that he
hooked up with Mandy
after every game
except last night.
Said he hadn't
seen her last night.
He in class?
Hospital.
Got rushed there
two minutes ago.
I bet I know why.
ROBBINS:
No surprise here.
He drowned.
We found his right hand
caught in
a pool filter.
Lack of bruising,
no bleeding wounds.
Indicates his circulatory system
had stopped.
This was postmortem.
Any significance
to the marks
on his chest?
Uh, don't know.
Not a rash.
Some kind of abrasion.
Maybe even
a friction burn.
Definitely peri-mortem.
X-rays reveal
several broken ribs
and he's got a bruise
on his forehead.
He could have taken
a bad fall.
Or he could have been beaten.
Maybe.
How about the new wife?
No physical findings
for sexual assault
though I did send a kit to DNA.
Looks like cause of death was
a single gunshot to the head.
I'll know more later.
You always tell me that.
Yes, I do.
Depth of bruising
gives us a timeline.
Apparent thumbprint
on her neck came first
the, uh, prints
on her hands second.
Major impression on top.
It's some kind of
recoil bruise
on her palm.
She didn't shoot herself.
( screaming and a gunshot )
She had help.
Of course, no house
is complete without a pool.
Why live in Vegas
if you don't have a pool?
Mm, water's warm.
You want to come by
and take a dip?
Quite the saleswoman.
Come on, take a...
It's got to be
a fantasy of yours, huh?
Huh, double feature.
You know you want this.
STOKES:
Blam.
You can say that again.
Down, boys.
I probably should even
be saying this, but, uh...
sex is on my mind all the time.
Hey, Archie,
freeze it.
And, uh...
Who's that in the background?
STOKES:
Hmm?
Oh, that guy in the mirror.
Good.
Archie, help us out.
Yup, I got him.
STOKES:
Nice.
BRASS:
Hey this is the broker.
I just did a background
check on that guy.
Half a dozen robberies in
the houses he has listed.
Art, antiques,
stuff like that.
Like the Peter Croft sculpture.
Exactly.
STOKES:
Looks like Augie was helping
himself to a little bit
more than the artwork.
SIDLE:
I understand,
Mr. Darwell.
Have your son's wisdom
teeth come in yet?
What?
Whoever killed Amanda Kirk
ingested her organs,
Mr. Darwell. Left teeth marks.
Excuse me.
Hi, uh, Chuck, I'm with
the crime lab.
I'm going to ask you
to show me your back teeth.
Give us an odontological
impression.
I didn't see Mandy
last night, I swear.
DARWELL:
You have no legal right
to question or to touch my son.
I want you out of here.
Now.
Is that stomach contents?
That's right, officer.
Anything he throw up
no longer belongs to him.
PD, public domain.
It's going to tell us
everything we need to know.
Look, anyone could have
lifted that Peter Croft.
I thought this
was about murder.
WILLOWS:
Oh, it is.
( cell phone rings )
Excuse me.
Yeah?
Hey, yeah...
Hey, can I
call you back?
Okay, then.
Bye-bye.
I'm sorry,
where were we?
The tape.
It wasn't anybody's face on
that tape, it was your face.
I recorded their house
for the virtual tour.
That's what I do to sell houses.
Selling house
as a front for porno
a little blackmail
on the side.
What are you talking about?
I have done nothing wrong.
Oh, you're innocent in all this?
I admit to having
lust in my heart.
Lust doesn't live in your heart.
I'm going to need
that DNA sample.
Well, my DNA is your DNA.
Great.
Look, for what it's
worth I can tell you
at least one guy
other than her husband
that saw Monica in the buff
on a weekly basis.
Say, "ah."
Ah.
BROWN:
You must get a lot of ass
on a job like this, huh?
I'm the pool guy, it's one
of the perks of the job.
One minute
I'm scooping leaves
the next I'm staring at...
Yeah, I get it.
The last time
you were there
did you happen to see anything
out of the ordinary?
What? You mean sexual?
Maybe.
No.
But, uh...
Newman had a temper.
He and
his kid Max
were always going at it.
What are these, huh?
Where did you get these?!
I thought the old man
was going to beat his ass
but... Newman just screamed
some more and took off.
You mind if I take a look
in your cab?
Sure.
Well, that's a coincidence.
Newman's anti-vortex filter
was missing three screws.
I can explain, okay?
I remove them screws
from the filter
so I'd have an excuse
to go back.
Oh, you mean,
like, a "leave-behind"?
Yeah, I figured
the more I was around...
The more she'd want you.
Oh, yeah.
Well, the lab
wants more of you, too.
We're going to need
your fingerprints
and a DNA sample.
Take whatever you want,
I've got nothing to hide.
GRISSOM:
Anything
from the pool?
Some hairs,
I may have found a filling.
Tributlyltin oxide,
aluminum sulfate
quaternary ammonium.
Chemicals
in the vic's lungs
match the chemicals
in the pool water.
Anything from his head wound?
Trace matches
the side of the pool.
No surprises.
Mildew.
Hmm?
Aureobasidium pullulans.
One of the very few fungi
that can withstand
the desert temperature.
Gives us possible transfer.
Exactly.
and here's the basic chemistry of the transfer.
GRISSOM:
Add sugar water
spoiled from the heat
mix in some human biofilm
you got yourself
an all-you-can-eat
mildew buffet.
Cal Newman wore size tens.
So assuming our killer
wore the size 12...
He may have transferred mildew
from the pool to the house.
Normally I don't like
to speak ill of the dead
but, uh, Mr. Newman's
sperm had company.
Bad company.
Look at D7.
Three alleles.
Genetics only gives you one
from each parent.
Which can only mean
one thing--
Menage d'allele.
She was cheating on her husband.
What about stutter?
Percentage is too high.
We're looking at a minor
and a major sample.
Minor donor?
The husband.
Major donor?
Pool man.
Nope.
The broker?
Ibid.
Major donor
is still unaccounted for.
BROWN:
How's it coming?
STOKES:
Good. I'm almost there.
Hang on.
Sometime this year.
Okay, I think that's the angle.
All right, where do I stand?
Back up.
Keep going.
Big steps?
Little steps?
Big. Keep going.
Keep going.
I go any further,
I'll be in the closet.
Well, go in the closet.
Oh, you got to be kidding me.
What?
How's this?
What the hell is that?
( scoffs )
( clattering )
These slime will do anything
to sell a house, huh?
JOHNSON:
Sometimes, reflections
beget reflections.
I figured if I could get
a glimpse of the Augie cutout
maybe I could get a glimpse
of the cameraman.
Check out the lamp.
Her stepson, Max.
Did you get
any DNA
off the cigarette butts?
Yeah, we did.
So, let's get Greg to compare the
reference sample
and see if we found
our major donor.
SANDERS:
Driving someone else's
porcelain bus?
Suspect's dinner
from last night.
The coroner left this
in your mail slot.
Can you read it for me?
What's this
look like, Greg?
Uh, Caesar salad.
Oh, and Pele used
an interesting dressing.
PCP.
Angel dust. Hallucinogen.
Well, it acts like one.
But PCP's such a powerful drug
it's in a class all its own:
Disassociative anesthetic.
Brain disassociates
from the body.
Yeah, after it takes you
through the paces.
How many milligrams?
Uh... 20.
Dude's dose was off
the charts.
I'm surprised
he's still alive.
Yeah.
Too bad everybody
didn't make it.
Tell me this
is raw chicken skin.
Well, it's raw...
and it's definitely skin.
My son was nowhere near
that pool.
He was at...
Red Rock Canyon.
A field trip.
Oh, I'm getting that.
What I'm not getting
is this.
Oh, now, this is disgusting.
Look, whatever Cal wanted to do
behind closed doors,
that was his business.
This is not for my eyes
or for his eyes.
This is not the first time,
is it, Max?
Can I plead the Fifth
or something?
Max
we found two sperm donors
on the sample
from your stepmother.
Your father's and yours.
Now I know why you were spending
all that time
at your father's.
Mom, look, I...
Mom...
I don't want to hear
a word from you.
Well, let me lay it out for you.
So you must've thought you won
the lottery.
And the only thing
standing between you
and the winning ticket
was your father.
( yelling )
What's your shoe size, Max?
Twelve.
This can't be happening.
Yes, it's happening.
Okay, this is a fling.
Okay, it's not real.
You're confused.
You're a kid.
I killed my father
for you.
That's not possible.
How come?
Because I can't swim.
He's telling the truth.
When Max was a child
he had this terrible
pool accident.
He nearly drowned.
We need that
report, ASAP.
Your temperature
is spiking.
Of course, you didn't
know Mandy had E. coli
when you... ate her,
did you?
No, no, I would never do that.
You would on PCP.
Normal brain, neurons
send a message
synapses blink on and off.
On PCP, synapses
never stop firing.
Like your entire brain
is on constant DSL.
LOCKWOOD:
You and Mandy
were on the soccer field.
You were cranked up.
Do you remember
anything?
Yeah.
But I don't remember
killing her. I swear to God.
Lieutenant Lockwood's
going to arrest you.
We'll assign you
an advocate.
GRISSOM:
So, how does a kid who can't
swim drown his father?
The kid didn't do it.
Look, we found
the father's blood
on the underside
of the pool ledge.
And his body at the bottom
of the pool
with abrasions
on his chest.
So there was a struggle
in the water.
With someone
who can swim.
Right.
You cannot be serious!
Hey, John McEnroe,
where's the game?
All the prints
are accounted for
by people who had a reason
to be in the Newman house
all the way down to the vortex
cover, Warrick.
Prints came back
to the pool boy.
Yeah. Yeah, so all I've got
is an errant blond hair
a tooth filling and some
detritus from the bottom
of the pool.
All right, now, don't get
your panties in a bunch.
Uh, so we got the blond hair,
the tooth filling...
That's it, huh?
Yeah.
I mean, I did identify
some Neoprene
and it was white.
White Neoprene.
Yeah.
Like in a wet suit
Neoprene?
Was the vic a diver?
Not that I know of.
The son can't even swim.
Let's think about that.
Who wears a white wet suit
in a pool?
Scuba diver.
Or a professional.
A professional.
No, I mean like
a hired gun professional.
Yeah.
Tooth hurt?
You might, uh, need your filling
which we found
at the bottom
of the Newmans' pool.
BRASS:
We also found
your fingerprints
and your hair.
Look, I'm sure
you'll find me all
over the house.
I wanted to buy it.
I was everywhere.
Well, you made sure you were
everywhere, too, didn't you?
I wanted to thoroughly
inspect the property.
Caveat emptor, right?
Or caveat venditor.
Let the seller beware.
Your prints
came back military.
Navy Seal.
Ex-Navy Seal.
Oh, yeah, that's right.
You rang the bell.
You had the physical tools
for the training
but not the character.
And if you had anything
more than a filling
and a piece
of Neoprene
we wouldn't be here.
Berglund.
That's a Scandinavian name,
isn't it?
That's what
my parents tell me.
Hey, heard you nailed
soccer boy
for the murder.
Not exactly.
No match
on the bite plate.
Well, maybe there was someone
else with them.
Someone getting sicker
by the minute.
Greg.
Yeah?
I need you to take off
your shoes and socks.
See, now we're getting into this
whole strip forensics thing
and I'm not so sure
I can hang with that
even if you are my boss.
Your mother's maiden name
is Hojem, correct?
Hojem is Norwegian?
Yeah.
And you know, my grandfather
got tossed from Norway
for getting my grandmother
pregnant
before they got married.
To this day,
he still tells me
"Som man reder sa ligger man."
One must lie in the bed
one has made.
That's true.
Right foot first, please.
Now, you're sure you want
me to do this?
Things could get loud
in here.
Left foot.
So you want
to tell me
why we're doing this?
It's an experiment.
Put these on.
Come see me in six hours.
Nicole Exmoor, 18.
School nurse said
she couldn't stop
throwing up.
Teacher found
her passed out
in the locker room.
She have an
explanation?
Said that she
ate something
that didn't
agree with her.
Nicole, do you know
what E. coli is?
Your friend Mandy
was infected with it.
We think we know
how you got it.
We can test
your blood for PCP...
( sniffling ):
Chuck brought the weed,
not me.
This guy told him
it was a really great high.
These photographs are...
of Mandy's ribs.
We believe these
are your teeth marks.
Ms. Sidle can make
an impression
of your teeth
or you can
help yourself
and explain
what happened.
When Jack and I went
to the field...
we were hooking up
behind Mandy's back.
She showed up, she was like,
"He's my player."
Mandy!
I don't know what happened.
I started to feel weird
like my blood
was surging through me.
It didn't make any sense.
I think I wanted to be her.
It felt...
It felt like somebody else
walked over and did it.
Like she was split
from my body.
It's called
psychological detachment.
It's a function
of PCP.
It's like out
of a really bad dream.
Nicole, I was at
Mandy's autopsy.
It was not a dream.
I'm placing you
under arrest
for the murder
of Amanda Kirk.
( sobbing )
What's going to happen to me?
That's up to the D.A.
Hey, Cyrus, next time
somebody says
experimenting with
drugs is harmless
remind me of this.
What did you do to me?
You had a reaction.
I'm Hazmat meat.
Quarantine,
here I come.
Your right foot,
I swabbed
with a placebo,
regular tap water.
Yeah, well, I'm not worried
about the right foot.
Left foot...
eumycotic dermatitis.
Oh, great.
It's probably fatal.
It's a mildew-induced
skin rash.
You infected me with mildew?
Here. Hydrocortisone.
Follow the directions,
clear it right up.
It's called
Aureobasidium pullulans.
Is that supposed
to mean something to me?
It may.
This is a warrant.
To see my feet?
Yes, both of them.
Take off your shoes
and socks, please.
Aureobasidium pullulans
is a mildew.
We found it around
the Newmans' pool.
It induces rashes
in people
of Scandinavian descent--
and it does so in
a predictable progression
which provides us
with a valuable
timeline.
You have the rash.
And size 12 feet.
Let me tell you
how you did this.
( gasping )
And then you went upstairs.
Cal?
( gunshot )
You're still
going to have to
convince a jury
that I killed
two strangers
for no reason.
You ever been to the theater,
Peter?
There's a play called
Six Degrees of Separation.
It's about how all the people
in the world
are connected to each other
by no more than six people.
All it takes
to connect you
to the victims
is one degree.
Peter Berglund?
No, I don't recall
ever having met
somebody
by that name.
Well, do you recall
living in San Diego?
What does that have
to do with anything?
Oh, it just might
help jog your memory.
San Diego's
a military town.
Your sister
married a guy in
the Navy, right?
Did you really bring me in here
just for this?
Well, we could go
someplace else
if you'd like.
How about your house?
The one you're selling.
What's this?
Well, you see,
we didn't have
enough evidence at this point
to get a warrant
but you put your house
on the Internet.
I didn't need
a warrant.
Gave me
complete access
via this
virtual tour.
And all with
your permission.
That's you...
that's Peter Berglund...
and that's the Pacific.
So what?
I know Peter.
Yeah.
You hired him to kill your ex-husband
and his
new wife.
The picture doesn't
prove anything.
No, but it did
give me access
to Peter's
financial information.
Loan application.
Two signatures--
Peter Berglund
and yours.
You cosigned for Peter
because he couldn't qualify
on his own.
Payment for the hit.
He gets
your house
you get your
ex-husband's money.
The thing about
murder for hire...
there's always a paper trail.
Good night.
Good night, Sara.
Hey.
Nice work on
the high school case.
I'm, uh...
...sorry I missed your page.
It's just, um...
you tell me to get a life
and then I get
one, and...
then you expect me to be there
at a moment's notice.
It's, um, confusing.