♪ On your mark, get set ♪
♪ Let's go ♪
♪ You got to move now,
before she explodes ♪
♪ Look out the window,
lookout below ♪
♪ Back away from the glass ♪
♪ Well, there she blows ♪
♪ The city's been leveled ♪
♪ The hills are in flames ♪
♪ The streets cracked open ♪
♪ And they're pushing up clay ♪
♪ Temperature's dropped ♪
♪ The sky is gray ♪
♪ And it ain't even over ♪
♪ Here comes drivin' rain ♪
♪ It ain't me that you feel ♪
♪ It's something moving
around in here ♪
♪ Well, that's blood,
that's tears ♪
♪ This ain't a warning ♪
♪ Everybody
out of the water... ♪
Tom Haviland!
Oh, my God.
It's really him.
I loved him
in I-95 and...
and that other movie
with Julia Roberts.
Odds on six and eight.
Give me 35 on the hop.
And a quarter on the horn
for the boys.
Thank you, sir.
All right.
♪ ...Now I'm treadin'
high water ♪
♪ To get back to you ♪
♪ Looking for a low spot ♪
♪ Or something to cling to ♪
♪ There's too many bodies ♪
♪ There's not enough room... ♪
Whoo!
(cheering)
♪ ...They say nobody panic ♪
♪ Help is on its way,
we're already on it ♪
♪ You've got to be brave,
if you can fix it now... ♪
Hey.
How you doing?
So what are you
in the mood for, huh?
A little French,
Italian...
No, man, I had
Italian last night.
How about Chinese?
All right, Chinese.
MAN:
All right.
Shooting good.
♪ Everybody out of the water ♪
♪ Get up on dry land ♪
♪ Take what you can ♪
♪ 'Cause you won't
be here again ♪
♪ Well, I loved you then ♪
♪ Like I love you now ♪
♪ That won't matter anyhow ♪
♪ Well, this is
the new frontier ♪
♪ Everybody out of the water ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh ooh-ooh ooh ♪
♪ Ooh ooh-ooh ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ Now, I'm treading high water
to get back to you ♪
♪ Looking for a low spot
or something to cling to ♪
♪ There's too many bodies ♪
♪ There's not enough room ♪
♪ God help me and God help you ♪
♪ They say nobody panic ♪
♪ Help is on its way ♪
♪ We're already on... ♪
The subject, Tom Haviland,
says he had a romp
with two ladies between
1:00 AM and 2:00 AM.
Then he left them
in the sheets
and went back
to the crap table.
He returned a half
an hour later
and found Kim like this
with her throat slashed.
The extent of the coagulation
suggests she died
before that.
Possibly before 1:00 AM.
When he puts himself
in the room.
You said "ladies."
Where's the other one?
Uh...
Tonya.
He said she was gone
when he returned.
Gone?
That's an elastic term.
Yeah, Mr. Haviland's
assistant
a Raymond Lester, notified
hotel security and called 911.
What do we know about Raymond?
Eyewitnesses
place him downstairs
at the time
this took place.
Mr. Lester is in...
LA at a morning meeting.
He's flying back
this evening.
And Mr. Haviland?
He's in the other room.
MAN:
Do you do
your own stunts?
Yeah, I do my own stunts,
but, look, I don't want to dog
on the guys who use
stunt doubles, right?
Believe me,
when you're hang gliding
over the Grand Canyon,
you should think twice.
You don't recognize
that guy, do you?
It's Tom Haviland, movie star.
Clark Gable was
a movie star.
Excuse me, fellas.
Keep the peace, boys.
Mr. Haviland,
my name's Gil Grissom.
I'm with the
Las Vegas Crime Lab.
Oh, well, do you have
a sheet of paper?
'Cause I'm kind of running out
of things to write on here.
What?
Oh.
My bad.
I need to ask you
did you, by any chance, touch
the victim after you found her?
No.
You sure?
Look, I wouldn't want people
to know, but I got creeped out.
I kept my distance
waiting for the ambulance.
That's all you did?
Well, I did ask her who did it.
And she said Tonya.
Really?
The other girl.
Hey, Warrick?
Would you mind
if we took a look
at your hands?
Yeah, sure.
Palms down, please.
You said you never touched the victim.
It's blood.
I guess you forgot to scrub
the back of your hands, huh?
I get one phone call, right?
Sure, just like in the movies.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
REPORTER:
Tom, did you do it?
(reporters clamoring)
Tom, stay strong.
Can you tell us exactly
what prompted PD to arrest Tom
for this murder?
Conflicting statements
and forensic evidence.
Could you be
more specific?
Blood evidence.
What kind? Where did
you find it, exactly?
That's all for now.
When we have more information,
we'll release it to you.
Thank you. Excuse us.
(clamoring)
Tom, did you do it?
I like his movies.
Some of them are good.
DA just got the call.
Tom's manager hired
Marjorie Wescott
to defend him.
STOKES:
"Soundbite" Wescott?
Guilty, rich client,
high-profile case
it's right
up her alley.
Publicity for her
new cable show.
Forget about
who's involved.
We do this like we
do any other case.
Well, I'm going to get
this blood evidence to DNA.
I'll catch up
with you guys later.
So, we'll take the suite.
It's the penthouse, right?
Later.
(pounding dance music plays)
Witnesses place
Tom Haviland
at this table
before and after
the time of the murder.
I'll look for transfers.
Yeah, well, he's
already admitting
to sleeping
with the victim
so hair and fiber
evidence won't
mean anything.
Okay.
You coming?
I'm just going
to supervise on this one.
All right.
Hey, Sara.
Hey.
I thought you left.
I need to talk to you.
Uh... can it wait
till after work?
It's about work.
When I tried
to revive the victim
the bra was in the way,
so I repositioned it.
I didn't think about it
until I was at the elevator.
Oh, um...
Can you tell me
where it was exactly?
A little...
a little over here.
You sure?
Thanks.
Thanks?
Thanks nothing.
I'm going to
have to put it in my report.
"Evidence moved due
to life-saving efforts"
with before
and after pictures.
Sorry.
I could live in that bathroom.
So, I've checked every plumbing
fixture in this place.
There's no blood.
Grissom said
he found blood
under movie boy's nailbeds.
And that sheet looks
like a butcher's apron.
Movie boy had
to wash his hands
someplace.
♪ ♪
MAN:
Can the casino do anything
to hurry this up, Mr. Stokes?
I'm processing
as fast as I can, sir.
It would help
if I had the dice
used at this table.
We replace the dice every hour.
I've got my work cut out for me
then, don't I?
(exhales)
(up-tempo dance music plays)
BROWN:
Great. What is this?
Oh man, great.
CSI. Brown.
I got a TC
at Ogden and Main.
Please send EMS,
Emergency Medical Assistance
as soon as you can.
Hey...
I can't see.
You all right?
Help me.
Okay. Okay, all right...
Help me!
Okay. Hey, stay with me.
Stay with me.
Let me look at you...
I think I'm going
to pass out.
Hey, no, no, no...
(groans)
Okay. All right.
All right,
keep your head back.
All right, I got to get
a towel for your head.
No, no, no!
Don't leave me, please.
Okay, I'll be here with you
for the ambulance, okay?
Uh-huh.
Take a deep breath.
Can someone give me
a towel?!
(siren approaching)
Wound tract tells us the weapon
was sharp, irregular
with a tight curve.
GRISSOM:
Well, let's see.
Hotel suite.
Probably a weapon
of opportunity.
Corkscrew, maybe.
Corkscrew would be
consistent with
this tissue damage.
Is it all the way down
to the larynx?
Transected the superior
thyroid artery
external carotid,
causing exsanguination.
Both laryngeal branches
of the vagus nerve
and her larynx were severed.
Vagus nerve controls
the muscles in the larynx
any injury to this nerve
and its surrounding muscle
results in immediate
paralysis of the throat.
(screaming)
(screaming stops)
Voice box was immobilized.
Why the look?
Tom Haviland claimed
that this victim
told him the name of her
murderer before she died.
(scoffs)
TV REPORTER:
Detectives and forensics experts
are sifting through evidence
a this hour, making their case
against actor Tom Haviland.
We'll recap the story as we wait
for a live feed
from a downtown news conference
with Haviland's attorney.
Several witnesses have already
spoken to police
about Haviland's actions
outside the murder...
(turns of TV)
Proceed, sir.
Okay, we got at least
one murder charge on Haviland.
I imagine we'll add another one.
Tonya.
GRISSOM:
So, let's run
Kim Hsu's murder.
Haviland slashed her throat
probably with a corkscrew.
(no audio)
Then, showing
consciousness of guilt
he washed the blood off
in this room
which is right around the corner
from his suite.
We found dilute blood
in the sink, pipes
and... footprint ridges
there.
Do we have the results on
the blood from Haviland's hands?
I got held up behind
a traffic accident.
I put it in with Greg.
I'm not sure if he's
done with it yet.
I got it right here.
The forensic sample matches
the reference.
The blood on Tom's hands
was definitely the victim's.
Triple-checked the data.
We got our guy then.
Oh, here she is.
WOMAN:
Aside from the fact that
the other woman in this case
also known as Tonya,
is still at large
and is still a likely suspect
in this murder
the evidence
Las Vegas CSI did collect
the evidence they're using to
railroad my client, Tom Haviland
has been completely and
irretrievably compromised.
I'm holding in my hand
compromised, contaminated
evidence, ladies and gentlemen.
CSI should be ashamed;
and you, as citizens,
should be outraged.
This not how we do things
in America.
They're saying the chain
of custody was broken.
The sample was contaminated
when you stopped
to help the woman.
That blood was
not contaminated.
I recovered it from the back
of Tom Haviland's hand
sealed it, delivered it
to Sanders in DNA.
Did you lock your car
when you helped this driver?
I was out of my car two,
three minutes tops.
WILLOWS (distantly):
Dispatch put you
out of your vehicle
for seven minutes
and 11 seconds.
(speaking indistinctly)
...at the DA
if you had.
They day I do that
is the day I turn in my badge.
Our evidence is solid.
We can't let 'em take us
out of our game.
That may be difficult.
Marjorie's been flooding
us with legal motions.
Oh, that's
what lawyers do;
especially when their
clients are guilty.
These motions are different.
Tom Haviland's attorneys are
not waiving time.
Are you serious?
They're actually
exercising their right
to a speedy trial?
No requests for continuances,
no stall tactics.
They're pushing
for their day in court.
Good defense attorney always
does the last thing you expect.
Yeah. What typically drags on
for months
has now been put
on the fast track
and the prelim is less
than 72 hours.
I'm only done processing
half the evidence.
You're going to have
to call in help
because if the judge thinks
that our evidence
isn't strong enough
to go to trial
he's going to dismiss
the charges on Tom.
Can't the DA
drop the charges
and we'll refile
when we get our
evidence together?
Sure, but the odds are
that Tom will relocate to Europe
and pull a Polanski.
And what's a Polanski?
Get-out-of-jail-free card.
One more thing:
Wescott just added
a forensic scientist
to their roster.
She wants him to examine
every piece of evidence
we have against Haviland.
As soon as it's processed
they'll get a copy
of our report.
They're entitled to see it
as it's processed.
I've never done a case
where the defendant
took advantage
of that rule of discovery.
Well, when you can't attack
the evidence itself
you attack the method
of gathering the evidence.
So who's their guy?
Dr. Phillip Gerard.
Phillip Gerard?
Your mentor is their
forensic scientist?
Yeah. Marjorie Wescott's
a smart lawyer.
BRASS:
Tom's best friend, Ray--
he's coming in tonight.
Volunteering to give
a blood sample.
He knows his blood's
not on those sheets.
They're trying to choke us
with evidence.
He also lawyered up.
Guess who's paying
the legal bills?
The movie star.
Legalized hush money.
Ought to be
a law against it.
(keyboard clacking)
(beeping)
(clears throat)
You beeped me
from across the hall?
Uh, yeah.
I waved; you didn't look up.
The blood contributions
on that die...
Yeah?
...Tom Haviland and Kim.
So when he blew on the dice,
he blew victim blood.
(rock music plays)
Now, I know I haven't
been getting
out in the field very much
but how does a guy
get a girl's blood
in his mouth
when he's killing her?
Murder's messy, my friend.
So, now you have to find it
on the surveillance tape?
If I want to present
it to a jury, yeah.
Nowadays, people expect a show.
I should've gone
to film school.
Okay... so the flowing
pattern is from
the victim's neck wound.
This other pattern,
though...
The waffle pattern--
I know, I'm trying
to figure that out.
No, no. Here--
the blood spatter.
Vic didn't sustain
any trauma
that would've caused
a medium velocity spatter.
She wouldn't have.
I think her throat was slashed,
to shut her up.
(woman screaming)
(ripping sound;
screaming stops)
She was collateral damage.
My guess...
these blood patterns mean
that Tonya's dead.
And I bet she was
the first to die.
Rage killing.
Sudden hand-to-hand combat.
I'll get all this to Greg
but we are definitely
going to need
the DNA guy from days
to pull all this
together in time.
Sorry, Gil.
Just doing my job.
Sara, this is
Dr. Gerard.
Anything you
say to him
will be considered
testimony.
Then, hopefully, you'll say
I'm better-looking
than I appear on TV.
You're the CSI who recovered
the clothes
from the crime scene.
Yes, and the bedsheets.
Did you follow
departmental procedures--
transporting this evidence
back to the lab?
To the letter.
Took multiple photos
at the scene?
Our protocols stipulate
we take overalls
locator shots and close-ups.
I took multiples of each.
That's great.
Save your gloves from the scene?
Eight pair in the evidence room,
in a sealed envelope.
Terrific.
DA just provided me
with copies of pictures
of the victim's bra.
Well, we already know
the bra was moved.
Sara filed a supplemental
report to that effect.
I know.
I wish she'd mentioned
her relationship
with the EMT who moved the bra.
Relationship?
A Hank Peddigrew.
We just interviewed him.
He says he thanked her for
letting him move the bra back.
He was just, uh, being polite
and, um, it's not
a relationship.
We go to movies...
Doc?
Why don't you and I
go to my office.
We can talk there.
Thank you.
I'll get the blood swatches
to DNA
identify any additional donors
on the sheet.
TV REPORTER:
When asked about the murder
of Kim Hsu
a spokesman for Tom Haviland
says
he sends his condolences
to the Hsu family.
Certainly, this is an event
that he won't soon forget
and neither will the resort
where the grisly crime
played out.
Now it's up to prosecutors...
Catherine?
Marjorie's requesting copies
of CSI's proficiency test
records, by midnight.
So relax.
If any of us had failed
the yearly proficiency test,
we wouldn't be here.
You completely forget,
don't you?
My test is on appeal.
Oh, right.
Board said I was wrong
on one question.
I said the question was
ambiguous.
They're going to rule my way
but not before the prelim.
(sighs)
Just trying to rattle me.
Is it working?
Maybe I should just take a page
out of your book.
If I don't collect or analyze
anything
I don't have to testify.
Of course, it helps
to be boss.
Very politic.
Ecklie must be rubbing off
on you.
Yeah, that's it.
Ecklie.
I just got served.
Movie star's lawyer
wants the shirt
that I wore
to the crime scene.
So give it to him.
I had to throw it out.
Why?
It was covered
in the blood
from the accident victim.
Well, you have to find it
otherwise, it'll look like
you've got something to hide.
Oh, CSI's on trial now?
CSI's always on trial, Warrick;
you know this.
Burden of proof is on us.
(keyboard clacking)
I want to compliment you
on how quickly
you've organized
the video forensics.
(keyboard clacking)
Raymond.
Nicky, wait a minute.
Go back.
Freeze it on the sticks.
He's jammed a lot more clubs
into that bag.
Without those clubs,
the hard-shell bag
could be big enough
to fit a body.
Yeah, Tonya's.
Looks like Raymond was disposing
of the bodies for your client.
You think he ran out of time
before he could move Kim's out?
Or Ray was disposing of them
for himself.
You've just supplied
Tom Haviland
with reasonable doubt.
No. What I showed you
on video
is Ray in the casino
during the time
the murders were committed.
His zeal is clouding
his judgment.
It's not what did happen;
it's what the jury will believe
could have happened.
Very considerate of you
to bring this golf bag in
without insisting
on a warrant.
Ray wants to help
the investigation
in any way he can.
BRASS:
Tell me, counselor
does Tom Haviland pay
in a timely fashion?
Ray and Tom are friends
but we're just looking
for the truth here,
aren't we?
Great. Then you
can confirm
what we already know from
Ray's cell phone records:
Tom Haviland called you
to his suite at 1:31 a.m.
to help him clean up
his double murder.
No, he called
so I could hear him
with the girls.
He does that sometimes.
Okay. We have a
surveillance tape
of you carrying
what appears to be
one of the bodies
out of the casino
an hour later
in a golf bag
identical to this one.
Here are some photos
from that tape.
He was taking Mr. Haviland's
clubs to the airport.
He's dumping a body.
And as we speak
the Police Department
is out looking for it.
Solvent.
This bag's
just been cleaned.
(spray bottle squirting)
Uh, Ray was caddying
a dead body.
We show him this
he'll rat out Tommy
Terrific in a heartbeat.
Uh-oh.
Glow's too uniform.
The Luminol's
cross-reacting
with the bleach.
I don't believe this.
Any blood evidence in there
has been destroyed.
This is B.S.
Man, total B.S.
This guy Tom
Haviland's got blood
all over his hands...
Nick...
...and friends to lie
for him!
This is B.S.!
Nick! Go get a soda.
Marjorie's going to take him
to the cleaners.
(snaps off gloves)
Hey. What happened to you?
You were a pioneer
in forensic science.
How many bad guys
did you put away
in Hamilton County?
My share.
How many innocent men have
been locked away since then
because of sloppy
investigating
shortcut forensics?
You look for mistakes
in any lab
you'll find them.
I shouldn't be able to, Gil.
Humans are fallible.
Not this fallible--
compromised blood
sweetheart deals...
No, no, no, no.
You're subverting
good evidence.
These are good people.
The accused is entitled
to the best defense possible.
The accused is
entitled, yeah.
He's a movie star,
that's why he's entitled.
He's killed two women.
You know it.
But you're willing
to decimate these CSIs
so that you can spoon-feed
a jury into letting him walk?
A jury believes me
because of my reputation
just like they do you.
The difference is, Philip
I get the same paycheck
regardless of what
I testify to.
(sighs)
I'm saying this as a friend.
For the reputation
of CSI
tell the DA to drop this,
refile down the road.
What about the
victims' families?
Who's their friend?
My guys will see you in court.
Psst, Grissom.
(speaking quietly):
We got a development.
I went over those swatches
that Sara gave me
from the bed sheet.
Are you whispering?
I don't want that Gerard guy
to hear me.
Well, he's not
here, so stop it.
What's, uh, going on?
Well, um...
I was testing those swatches
that Sara gave me,
and three of the swatches
came up Kim.
The other four,
with the spatter
Amelogenin results are XY.
Blood's from a male?
Tom Haviland's.
No.
And not his friend Ray's,
either.
There was another guy
in that room.
That's-That's great.
The defense has us
moving so fast
we can't make sense
of our own evidence.
That's what they want.
Should we call the DA
and let him know?
Tell him what?
That we might have found
a motive for the movie star?
Motive.
What are you talking about?
STOKES:
Hey, Grissom.
Brass just called.
They found
the other victim, Tonya.
Briarway Golf Course.
BRASS:
Matches the description
of Tonya.
Maintenance guy found her
a half an hour ago.
The golf pro says they've closed
the back nine down for months--
improvements.
Did, uh, Tom Haviland
ever play a boxer?
Girl's face looks like
hamburger meat.
Looks like uncontrollable rage
to me.
Grissom, you might want
to come down here.
Just say it, Nick.
Beans and franks.
Tonya's a man.
Looks like
that old Hollywood saying:
"Never get caught with
a dead girl or a live boy."
So, let's see
Tom's in bed
with what he thinks
are two girls.
He reaches down on one,
becomes very confused.
Most guys would have
just cleared the room
and gargled with whiskey.
But movie boy, who brags
about doing his own stunts
couldn't take the thought
of having a man in his bed
so he freaked out.
I'm just here to observe
CSI's investigating techniques.
Well, Nick is the primary
on this.
GERARD:
You're not running evidence.
Or have you changed your mind?
By the way
tell your mother I say hello
next time you talk.
I was so impressed
that night we
all had dinner.
The sign language
how you interpreted for her.
Fluid, didn't miss a beat.
What'd you do,
subpoena my doctor?
Knowing your genetic
predisposition for hearing loss?
You've become a bottom feeder,
Philip.
Your work is
dependent upon
your five senses.
The fact that you're
losing one of yours
wouldn't bode well
for any evidence
you introduced.
You know, all those years
I worked for you
you never got to know me
at all, did you?
(bird chirping)
(woman giggling)
I've looked
at everything
in that hotel room.
Nothing matches that pattern.
What about
the booking photos of Tom?
Were you able to make
comparisons off those?
I told Brass I needed them;
he hasn't sent me anything yet.
This case is a moving target.
I'll get ahold of Brass.
You look nice.
Thanks.
Wish me luck.
Sara?
Whatever happens in court
it's not because
you're seeing this guy.
You deserve to have a life.
Remember, if you get stuck
just maintain
the same posture.
If there's any adjustments,
you're seen as squirming.
It's going
to make you look shifty.
Thanks, Cath.
You know, I've
done this before.
Well, I've done it
longer.
Hey, any luck?
I've been through every Dumpster
on these premises.
Better keep looking.
BAILIFF:
In the cause now pending
before this court
do you swear to tell the truth,
the whole truth
and nothing but the truth?
I do.
(no audio)
Please state and spell your name
for the record.
(almost inaudible):
Nicholas Stokes.
S-t-o-k-e-s.
Pull it closer,
Mr. Stokes.
Oh. Sorry.
I'm used to the old ones.
(clearing throat)
Nicholas Stokes.
Damn!
What?
Damn, damn, damn,
I blew it.
I forgot to put case identifiers
on my dice photos.
Date, time and file number?
Yeah.
Don't look at me that way, okay?
I wrote it down
on the evidence envelope.
I had to move fast.
The casino manager
wanted us out of there.
The dice
places Tom at the murder.
Victim's blood mixed
with his saliva.
How can we be confident
in your collection
if you can't be confident
in your own documentation?
This is it.
You're sure
you want to go with that one?
This is the one.
I was sweating bullets
looking at those photos.
Did the judge
exclude the dice?
No. No, just my credibility.
Warrick Brown?
Yeah, he's, uh,
he's in the men's room.
We'll send him right in.
Two minutes grace,
the court moves on.
You're telling us
the shirt just
disappeared?
It would only prove
that I got blood on my shirt
from an accident victim.
That blood never came in contact
with the blood evidence
that I was transporting.
But we can't
verify that
now, can we?
Do you still have
a gambling habit?
I don't see what that has to do
with this case.
It goes to the character
of the witness, Your Honor.
JUDGE:
I'll allow it.
For the record
are you addicted
to gambling?
Damn!
Why didn't I
see that coming?
Gambling?
Hey, we're all in Nevada.
It's legal;
don't worry about it.
Legal doesn't matter in there.
You know the judge
is going to throw out
our blood evidence, right?
Truth is,
it is compromised, Warrick.
The blood is fine.
It's the methods that are dirty.
WESCOTT:
For the record
are you addicted
to gambling?
I am.
It's a low blow.
Low blow.
Your guys didn't get
any extended body photos?
Chest, hands, arms
right there.
I need lower
extremities
for comparison.
Hey, Marjorie Wescott
blew in here and shut us down.
She said if we wanted
full body shots
we were going to have to get
a court order.
So the D.A.'s working on it.
When, between
testimony?
No kidding.
Meanwhile, we're presenting
half a case to a judge.
WESCOTT:
Well, it certainly
looks posed.
You date-- you and Hank.
You share
a subtle communication.
Did he move the bra to where
you might have wanted it?
I didn't want it anywhere.
I collect evidence
without emotion.
You do get emotionally involved,
though
with the men on your cases.
Hank Peddigrew isn't
the first time.
Excuse me?
A murder investigation
at the residence of one
Charles Renteria.
Eyewitness stated
he saw you and your supervisor
Gil Grissom standing
alone outside and...
you were touching him
in a romantic gesture.
I brushed chalk from his face.
Is that what they're
calling it now?
D.A.:
Objection,
Your Honor.
Drywall dust.
We were looking for a body.
It's a fair question,
Your Honor.
Just how far will Ms. Sidle go
on the evidence
to please her
boss, Gil Grissom
whether he returns
her attentions
or not?
You have
a Bachelor of Science
from West Las Vegas University,
am I right?
Night school, yes.
And prior
to joining
CSI, you worked
as an exotic dancer?
That's correct.
Took your clothes off
for a living.
For a very good living.
No doubt,
Ms. Willows.
Now, you recently
failed
your yearly proficiency test,
didn't you?
Technically, yes,
but it's on appeal.
I'm confident
that I will prevail.
Did you treat this footprint
evidence the same way?
There's the truth
and then there's
your interpretation?
No.
But you're appealing
your test.
Actions speak louder
than words.
I have no further questions,
Your Honor.
We are through
with this witness.
Grissom...
they're beating
our heads in.
Judge is going
to dismiss--
you can feel it.
Don't get ahead
of yourself.
I'm not ahead of myself.
I'm up there
front and center
taking hits along
with the rest of CSI.
You know, you've
turned into a really
lousy leader.
I need your
help, and you're
on the sidelines.
Would you know
where I could get
pictures of Tom Haviland?
Full body shots.
Like, uh...
an Internet site,
or his fan club?
Ah, I hid all these when I heard
Gerard would be
snooping around.
"Tom Haviland...
"Away from the Set,
Between Films
and... in Paradise."
Paparazzi;
long lens.
I'm going to go to court.
D.A.:
The defendant's
statement
is that
when he left the room
the victims
were both alive and well.
Now, does that statement
support
your new evidence?
No, it does not.
This unique blood pattern
which I'm highlighting
and resizing
for the court's edification,
was made
by the defendant
during the attack.
Okay, thank you,
Dr. Grissom.
Nothing further, Your Honor.
(no audio)
(almost inaudible):
Unique pattern.
By what standard
are you basing
this "match"?
Dr. Grissom
please answer the question.
Could she repeat
the question, Your Honor?
JUDGE:
Ms. Wescott?
(almost inaudible):
By what standard are you basing
this "match"?
One more time, please.
(almost inaudible):
By what standard
are you basing
this "match"?
On visual comparison.
The accused
has a distinct
waffle-like scar
characterized
by diamond-shaped patterns
on his left knee.
WESCOTT:
So, Tom has a scar
on his leg.
Whoop-de-do.
There's no forensic database
for scars.
It's not
a discipline.
Yes, but it's unique
to the accused.
He says he got
it in a stunt
on his last film.
According to Mr. Haviland
in his statement
and I quote,
"It happened
"when I was rappelling
down the Alps
firing an AK-47
with my free hand."
But he actually got it
tripping on his way
into the wardrobe
trailer.
Objection.
There's no question
to the witness here, Your Honor.
Your Honor, it's
a preliminary hearing.
May I?
The witness may proceed.
The production report
by the Unit Production Manager
on the film that day
and I quote,
"Tom Haviland slipped
"on wardrobe trailer number 38,
step number two.
"He sustained cuts to his knee
"and was bandaged
by the company medic.
The production was shut down
for half a day."
The company medic documented it
with Polaroid photos
and I have managed
to acquire
step number two...
from trailer 38.
I think these graphics
will help explain
my findings.
The step, the scar...
the sheet.
No further questions,
Your Honor.
You may be excused, Dr. Grissom.
I'm binding this case
over for trial
60 days from today.
WESCOTT:
We'd like a continuance,
Your Honor.
I'll take it under submission.
Gil... good work.
My team did it, Philip.
I got good CSIs.
Oh, and, uh, my
mother says hello.
JUDGE:
Bailiff?
WESCOTT:
I'd like
to make a motion
for a bail hearing,
Your Honor.
JUDGE:
It's a double murder,
Counselor.
Request for bail
is denied.
The accused
is remanded
into custody
of County Jail.