(applause)
(clanging)
I need one volunteer
from the audience.
You.
In the blue dress.
(woman singing
mystical melody)
(gasping)
Step into the box.
Hands by your sides.
Don't move.
(hissing)
And ladies
and gentleman
I assure you
she's quite all right.
In fact, she's...
Spotlight, please.
(whispering):
I don't know where she is.
(chuckling):
Ladies and gentlemen...
I can't quite explain...
Welcome to the house
of illusion.
This is bizarre.
You're not going
to believe this.
Female volunteer goes
on the stage, disappears
and doesn't
come back.
Was she supposed
to... reappear?
The Amazing Zephyr
won't say.
You know magicians,
they never reveal their tricks
but we're working
on him.
Well, I can understand
why he doesn't want
to reveal his trick...
but would he
like to explain
this blood?
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
BRASS:
I got a bunch
of police officers, uh
canvassing the
theater right now.
No sign yet, but we
have traced the woman
back to her
aisle seat, 8A.
Paid cash.
Magic is fun, Jim,
but it's not real.
The woman is somewhere.
Thanks for that. Thanks.
Excuse me.
Yeah?
Um, hi, are we finished here?
No. You were sitting in front
of the volunteer, right?
You take any photos
during the show?
We're going
to need your camera.
But our whole trip's
on there.
We'll get the negatives
back to you. Michael.
Excuse me.
Thanks for your help.
Dull as a spoon.
From a distance,
it looks razor-sharp.
That's the point.
So is it real blood?
Well, let's see.
That's real blood,
all right.
Nothing is as it seems, is it?
That's the conflict
of magic--
the burden of knowledge
versus the mystique of wonder.
And you're wondering
right now--
I can hear
your mind ticking--
"Was she a plant?
Was it real?"
Well, there are no
secrets, are there?
Only hidden answers.
I'm an honest liar, sir.
In my line of work
it's accepted.
You could say
it was my livelihood.
Well, my livelihood
is dispelling lies
and finding
the truth.
My secrets can't be revealed
by any microscope.
Yeah... but there's
a woman missing.
The only thing missing...
...is this.
Very nice.
So, where'd she go?
From the salt in my marrow,
I don't know.
I mean, I can't give you this
but I can
give you... that.
It's as real
as my answer.
No, you can keep it.
WILLOWS:
What's the name
of the band again?
STOKES:
Pekinpah. Back in '93,
first album was a moderate hit.
Don't you remember that song,
it was pretty popular--
uh... "Symphony
of Epiphanies"?
♪ Na, na, na,
na, na, na ♪
♪ Come here,
come here... ♪
(both humming)
(speaking indistinctly)
Yeah, that was good
to dance to.
MAN:
He's been laying
in the back of the bus
for half an hour now.
STOKES:
I'm guessing
that's the road manager.
He does not look
too happy.
Well, he just lost
a lead singer.
Ooh...
rock and roll, baby.
Gus Kenyon.
It's a shame, man.
He had a good voice.
WILLOWS:
Heroin.
If this was an overdose,
why leave some in the syringe?
No vomit around, either.
That's a first for me.
Wait a second,
what's this?
Doesn't look like
a bruise.
How'd he do that?
What's that?
The tourniquet.
He's obviously
left-handed
if he shot up in the right arm.
If he tied it off himself
he would have pulled
it towards him, like so.
It's tied the other way,
pulled away from him.
By someone else
standing over him?
Easy... if you're incapacitated.
You people seen enough?
When can I put him
to rest?
You really shouldn't be in here,
sir.
Hey, look, I'm sorry.
You know, this is a tragedy
for all of us,
and his family.
I just don't want the press
to see him like this.
We understand that, sir,
but this is a crime scene.
Crime scene?
It's an O.D., right?
He killed himself.
Then you knew
he was a drug user?
Well, he was a drug user.
I mean, he's been clean
for a long time.
A health freak,
actually.
It's a shock to us all.
Big glass box and all I got
is a partial thumb print.
Is this
processed yet?
Yeah. Want me
to bag it for you?
Let's take it back
to the lab.
Maybe we can make
Greg disappear.
Who controls this
stage, do we know?
MAN:
I do.
And you are...?
Punky Dillinger. I'm
Zephyr's stagehand.
Well, Mr. Dillinger
do you know how
this trick works?
I only control
the stage part.
Yeah.
Good.
Make me disappear.
(hissing)
Bye-bye.
Oh, I get it.
There's a chute
inside the steps.
Still here.
At this point
of the trick
I'm supposed
to escort the volunteer
out of the basement.
Now I only turned my back
for a second and she was gone.
Is there any other way out
of here besides that door?
No, that's the thing.
Stage left's the only exit.
I don't know.
You have any lights
in here besides red?
We're looking
for blood.
Mm-hmm.
Oh, hey? Hey?!
Those are Zephyr's tricks
in the corner.
No one's allowed to go near them
not even me.
I've got ovoid blood drops
leading towards the wall.
You guys want
more lights?
No. Turn them off.
Magicians of Zephyr's caliber
belong to a very
secluded society.
They barnstorm
from city to city...
no contact
with the outside world
no association
with other magicians.
They're like ghosts with skin.
This looks like
an admixture of blood
and some sort of clear liquid.
Someone bolted out
of here pretty fast.
I'm no psychic,
but I have been known
to read palms.
Hey!
I got a print.
You're kidding me.
Nope.
No heroin
in his system.
Lots of bourbon,
but no heroin at all.
So what killed him?
Embolism to the heart.
Air bubble.
I withdrew air
from his
right ventricle
and air can be
deadlier the heroin.
It travels through the vein
into the right ventricle
to prevent blood from entering
or leaving the chamber
which eventually leads
to heart failure.
WILLOWS:
Shock. Suffocation.
Explains why
he didn't throw up.
And why his pupils
weren't pinpoint.
They would have been
bilaterally small
after an overdose.
There was heroin
still in the needle.
Why didn't it
make it into his system?
His blood alcohol count was .31.
My guess is he was unconscious
before his heart stopped.
Catherine, wait.
That black mark...
Oh, right, on
his index finger.
Ink.
Standard black
printing ink.
SIDLE:
The stagehand was lying
about another exit.
I got his palm print
off the trap door.
BROWN:
Try this one.
It's a print from
the "Chamber of Doom."
Hands on the trap door?
Hands inside the trick?
There are no secrets.
Mmm.
Hey, hey, hey.
This is a non-smoking facility.
I'm not a bad magician,
you know.
When you find that,
put that out.
Okay.
Truth is... I lied.
We know that.
That's why we're here.
I love magic, you know?
One of the fringe benefits
of my job
is knowing how the tricks work.
Zephyr wouldn't
let anyone go
near his tricks.
You think I want
to be a stagehand
the rest of my life?
I got aspirations,
too, you know?
So, I snooped
around.
Climbed inside the "Chamber"
one night
and tried it out.
Is that a crime?
We don't know yet.
The videotape
from last night's show
has you...
wearing this.
So what?
So, it was used
as a tourniquet
on Gus's arm.
Look, I-I was with these guys
the entire night
last night.
Okay.
When was the last time
you saw him alive?
On the bus last night
after the show.
He said he wanted
to be left alone
so we left him alone.
We finished the set
with, uh
"City of Sin."
You know, the hometown pleaser.
He always hated that song.
I don't know why.
It was his best one.
I talked to your manager,
and he said Gus was clean.
Yeah.
The whole band
for six years now.
We-we did it together
as a band.
You know, we kind of had to.
We went gold
three months
after we signed
our first contract.
The next couple
of years
got pretty crazy.
Crazy?
Dude, hit single
24 years old.
Touring with Pearl Jam.
I mean
Gus had bitches lining up
outside of his room
24 hours a day.
Sleep ain't
an option.
So, by your next gig,
you're going
you know, need a little bop.
I obtained Gus's
medical records
from L.A.
that said he
was treated
for depression.
You guys know
anything about that?
Sober suits some better
than others.
He could get
pretty dark.
I mean,
sometimes
you couldn't even speak
with him, you know?
He's been wanting out
for some time now.
I know you didn't beep
me for a magic trick.
Swami doesn't do
magic tricks.
Swami's here to reveal all
of your DNA secrets.
I'm very busy, Greg.
Blood from the
"Chamber of Doom."
Same as the donor
of the blood
found on the
basement floor
but different than
the blood found
in the alleyway.
Different person?
Different...
animal.
Really?
What kind of animal?
Oh, Swami needs more time.
Now...
clear liquid
found near the blood droplets.
It's not
from Thora Birch, but...
Thorazine.
That's an animal
tranquilizer.
Zephyr didn't use any
live animals in his act.
Maybe he didn't use it
on animals.
GRISSOM:
Whoa.
Go back one, Arch.
Is that her?
Blue dress, red hair.
Go on.
Is that who
I think it is?
Who?
JOHNSON:
Toby Arcane.
Freak man.
What makes him a freak
besides that shirt?
All I can say
he's not for the
faint of heart.
(banging and whirring)
(yelling and cheering)
(punk music racing)
(music stops)
(music resumes)
(flame roaring)
(applause and cheering)
(music ends)
It's, uh, called
"The Cross-ifixion."
I get, uh, nailed to it
every night.
Well, miraculously,
you've resurrected.
Have you ever been
to the Zephyr show?
He's a hack.
I wouldn't be caught dead
at that show.
I know.
But we caught you alive.
You should see
my nudes, Grissom.
(laughs)
The, uh, woman
who disappeared--
do you think she was a plant?
Of course she's a plant.
Zephyr's on life support.
His way of
doing magic--
it's dead as, uh...
dead.
Fooling people
from a hundred feet away.
'Cause I'm in your face.
Right here.
We have reason
to believe
that that woman,
planted or not
sustained injury during
the first insertion
of the saber.
Do you think
it was part of the act
or do you think
it was some kind of mistake?
Uh, yeah, could have been
a blood pouch
but knowing him...
it was a mistake.
Is it possible
that he put his saber
into the wrong slot?
Well
this is Vegas, baby.
The band's last two albums,
and the DVD.
You know, I heard
that they were splitting up.
Where did you hear that?
Uh, the New World Library--
Internet.
This contains, uh,
TV appearances
live footage, things like that.
He wrote every song.
Who, the singer, Gus?
His name's on every title.
If they were
splitting up
and he took his songs back
no more Pekinpah,
no more money for the band.
Why don't you get back
on the Internet for us?
See if there's any gossip
floating around.
We need to get back
to the crime scene.
I'm looking for ink.
I showed the road manager
a copy of the warrant.
He went nuts.
He's on the phone with
his lawyer right now.
Why do they want us off this bus
so badly?
Standard printing ink.
What to do
when your cell phone's
not working.
Empty.
(rapping on glass)
This doesn't work.
Seems like nothing
on that bus does.
Yeah, but this doesn't work,
'cause the batteries suck.
Oh.
Belongs to the guitarist.
Looks like
Mr. Clean and Sober had a habit.
Bet it matches that smack
we found on the needle.
Yeah. You, uh,
trying to make a call?
No...
but somebody did.
Got a smudged name.
"Dean."
(beeping)
BROWN:
Goodyear Wrangler.
Ford F-150.
Hallelujah.
Did a DNA profile
on your blood.
Ran it through CODIS.
Guess who I found?
Who?
Zoe Clein.
White Caucasian.
Female.
Red hair.
Wait a minute.
CODIS? What database?
Missing persons.
She's in the
database already?
Yeah. She's been
in there for six months.
Same time she's been missing.
Brass is working on an address.
Nice house.
(train whistle blowing)
Built it so
close to the
railroad.
(knocking)
I bet this house was here first.
Las Vegas Crime Lab.
BROWN:
It's a little
too calm.
Yeah.
I'll take upstairs.
(door closing)
Wow.
What?
Six pints of "A" positive.
(train whistle roaring)
(train cars clattering)
(loud rumbling)
(train whistle blowing)
(door creaking)
Hey, guys?
Zoe's bedroom seems intact.
Suitcases, purses, clothes.
It looks like she never left.
(door closing)
Guys?
(screams)
Sorry.
You keep
disappearing.
Take a look at this.
SIDLE:
Huh. Looks like
the "Chamber of Doom."
Designed by Zoe Clein.
SIDLE:
So, she's an inventor.
Hey, guys,
check out this old photo.
The Clein Magical Tour.
The one with beard
must be the father.
SIDLE:
Zoe Clein
the daughter.
Young Zephyr...
What's he doing there?
And who's that baby
in his arms?
What up, G?
Well, I did my
snooping around.
Obviously everyone's
upset about Kenyon croaking.
And?
And they were planning
a "Best of..." album.
No surprise.
Cash cow,
everybody does it.
Well, someone e-mailed me
a clip of Gus on MTV2
a few months ago.
(laughing)
GUS:
Compilation albums
are for has-beens.
They can release one
over my dead body.
As long as I'm alive, I'm going
to continue to write originals.
Who's planning the album?
Keith Castle.
The guitarist?
Mm-hmm.
I'm chasing the smack.
I'm chasing the phone book.
Warrick, come here.
What is that,
a butterfly?
A male Io moth.
One of the largest
in North America.
How'd it get in here?
I don't know. It feeds
on trees and foliage.
There's none of that in here.
See the eye-like spots
on the back of its wings?
It's an illusion
to confuse predators.
Birds get fooled
into thinking it's an owl.
I have a similar one
in my office.
(creaking)
Didn't we release
Officer Henderson?
Hello?
(shouting)
Hold up! Back up!
I really didn't...
Warrick!
Hey! Back up.
Look, I got a family, okay?
They think
I'm clean.
The band, too.
Did you give some
to Gus last night?
Needle, too?
No, no,
no, man.
I don't shoot up.
That's just for snorting.
Well, Keith...
think Gus would get
messed up enough
to kill himself?
That'd help you sell
a few more albums,
wouldn't it?
Gus is dead, okay?
You never had
the pleasure
of finding out
what an ass he was in person.
Yeah, we made some
money off his talent
but he made us feel worthless.
At least when
he was high
he'd shut up.
(doorbell chimes)
Samantha Dean?
I'm with the Las Vegas
Crime Lab.
Do you know Gus Kenyon?
Gus Kenyon looked up
your number and address
in this directory
and, uh, called you
last night...
from a phone booth
outside of his tour bus.
Records indicate the call
was made around 2:00 a.m.
I must have been asleep.
It lasted 20 seconds.
I didn't answer.
So it rang?
No, I mean, I can't remember.
We're both in bed by 9:00.
What's your son's name?
Brandon.
You a mother?
Yeah, yeah,
I have a, a daughter
who is nine.
Yeah, I know how hard
it is to do it alone.
Now those are some cool
shades Brandon has on.
Are those Silhouettes?
Those are expensive.
Um, do you have
any more question
because, uh, Brandon needs
to go to my mother's.
I have to go to work.
All right.
Thanks for your time.
♪ Down in the city of sin ♪
♪ That's where I've been ♪
♪ And I caught a glance ♪
♪ Of what could be,
yeah, you and me ♪
BRASS:
How long have you been
working for the Zephyr?
MATILDA:
A year.
The magician I used
to assist for retired.
GRISSOM:
What are
you doing here?
I came to talk to Zoe,
and the door was open
so I thought I'd snoop
around a little.
BRASS:
A lot of people are
snooping around these days.
You know, everybody
who works for the Zephyr
wants to be
a magician. How come?
'Cause we do everything.
I mean, what does he do?
Wave his arms around?
I work my butt off
for that guy.
Bring this out,
bring that out
keep proper timing,
inspect the tricks.
You know, follow his lead.
Zoe is the best inventor
in the business.
You know, she sells me
just one of her tricks
and I can be in business myself.
So you know Zoe Clein.
Through Zephyr. Yeah.
Was she
a plant
the night she disappeared?
Yeah.
It's one of
her stipulations
that she's the volunteer
opening night.
Zoe Clein
has been missing
for six months.
And you saw her
the night she...
disappeared.
How do you explain that?
I don't know.
By the way
how'd you get here?
Drove.
My car's parked
down the street.
What kind of car
do you drive?
A Ford F-150.
Ford F-150.
It's a match.
(growling)
Whoa.
Well, at least we know
the animal.
Black panther.
Dispatch,
this is P-4981.
We need animal control at, uh...
Oh, my God.
Thorazine.
What did they do?
Drug her and feed her
to the panther?
There.
What?
Where?
Samantha Dean.
She knows him.
She's backstage with him.
So?
Backstage
with a rock star.
Trust me, it's a big deal.
See that VIP pass
around her neck?
That's like diamonds.
Really?
Hmm.
So...
groupie?
Girlfriend?
There was a scuff on
Samantha Dean's door.
Was it a red door?
Kick ass.
MATILDA:
Sadie's my cat.
She's my pet.
I got her from a previous gig.
Zephyr hates animals
so I just keep her in
my truck during the show.
I let her out between shows
so she can get some air
and she cut her leg
on the tailgate.
So I sedated her.
Can I go?
I've got a lot
of work to do.
Tonight's a really big night.
We're sold out
for the first time
and Zephyr's debuting
a new trick.
Really? New trick.
(applauding)
Ladies and gentlemen
I know you all
want to disappear.
But tonight,
there'll be no sabers
no surprises
and no volunteers.
(groaning)
Tonight I will attempt
to make myself disappear.
(chuckling)
(screaming)
SIDLE:
It's been rigged.
With a metal stake.
(grunts)
Someone just got
nailed to the cross.
He's got external burns
covering approximately
80% of his body.
Majority are second-
and third-degree.
Extensive damage
to his hands.
Curled and closed.
The human body
protecting its prints.
You're going to have
a tough time
finding anything
substantial here.
Better run his dental
records, then, huh?
Yeah, sure.
COD?
Laryngeal spasm.
We usually see this
in drownings.
Only instead of swallowing
water, he swallowed fire.
(screaming)
It causes the larynx
to pinch shut
protecting itself,
yet cutting off his air supply
and that leads to immediate
unconsciousness and death.
Another example of the body
trying to protect itself.
And, uh, I'd say in this case,
it didn't work.
Unusual, though.
Not as unusual
as what I found in his mouth.
Surgically created soft tissue
pouches within the gingivae.
It's like pockets of skin.
In the lining.
I've never seen
this before.
Neither have I.
I knew that Houdini
could swallow
and regurgitate
keys on cue
but I've never heard
of skin pockets.
Learn something new
every day
don't you?
(loud rattling)
Come on, trust me.
Okay.
It's fun.
(taps mallet on table)
(loud bang)
This, uh
collapsible stake right here
breaks a tiny little
blood capsule inside
giving the illusion
that I'm bleeding.
Look
it doesn't suit me
to kill Zephyr.
See, I've been killing him
for years.
Come on, people, this is magic.
(metal rattling)
It's B.S.
It's all fake.
Look at this.
Even this tattoo.
(chuckling):
I'm from Orange County, dude.
Thanks for your time.
On earth.
You're welcome.
SAMANTHA:
This is ridiculous.
I don't even
own a stereo.
So, you never met
Gus Kenyon?
No.
You sure?
We know he
was here.
We matched the paint
from your door
to the pain on Gus's ring.
And it's not so much
that this girl
in the photograph looks
exactly like you.
It's that,
the sunglasses that Gus
is wearing... familiar?
Of course not.
Very rare, custom-made
graduated lenses.
Your son is holding them
in his hands.
Were they a gift to him?
No.
He has
his father's eyes.
The two of you met
on a video shoot
in Vegas six years ago.
Last night...
Hey, baby.
...alone and depressed...
I tried to call you.
...he just decided
to look you up.
Who's that? Huh?
He knew immediately
that it was his son.
Any father would.
For some reason you had
kept Brandon a secret.
Why didn't you tell me?
Please, just leave!
Just go! Please!
Gus gets angry.
He can't understand why
you won't let him be a parent.
(banging on door)
Honey, it's okay.
You've changed a lot
since your days with Gus.
You were protecting your son
from his father's
lifestyle.
Miss Dean, you're a registered
nurse, is that correct?
That means you
have access to
medical supplies.
Needles?
STOKES:
Gus left here
and he went back on the bus.
He thought about doing
some of Mr. Castle's drugs
but he didn't.
He said he just passed out
from the booze.
But you, you've been around
heroin before, haven't you?
You know how
to cook it.
Did you think you put
just enough in the syringe
to make it look
like a suicide?
Am I under arrest?
No.
No, we're just here
for your son's DNA.
Then I think I should hire
a lawyer.
I just have one other thing,
Miss Dean.
I'm just guessing that when
you found out you were pregnant
that you stopped listening
to Gus's band
and that you haven't heard
any of his latest songs.
"I'm drying up like rain
and sand
"Without you wiping away
my tears with your hand
"You saw through the lies
"That make up
my disguise
"I need you back
to set me free
"Just give me
one last chance
Come back to me."
I think that he
wrote this for you.
loved you very much
and... that he missed you.
When I made him leave
he said he'd call
an L.A. lawyer
and take Brandon away from me.
I'm not sure now
what I was going to do
but... when I saw him
with the heroin next to him...
I knew nothing had changed.
I carry needles in my kit.
Took a tourniquet
from the dresser.
Injected him with air
multiple times.
I am not proud of my youth
and my son was never going to be
a part of that world.
You're a mother.
What would you be willing
to do to save
the life
of your child?
I think that I'd rather have
my daughter know a bad father
than no father at all.
Warrick.
I need you to find out
everything you can
about Zephyr
and his crew.
Sara, check Web sites.
Concentrate on Punky.
I've got a hunch
about these guys.
Where are you going?
Coroner.
I need a piece of the Zephyr.
(grunts)
BROWN:
Zephyr Dillinger
and Punky the stagehand.
They're related?
Father and son?
Magician and his double.
GRISSOM:
He fooled us.
It was Punky
burning in that box.
Zephyr murdered his son.
The little boy
from the picture.
They pulled a switch.
(audience cheering)
See this coin?
It's two-headed.
Two heads as one.
One and the same.
Zephyr and his son
are interchangeable
in physical appearance
like the Io moth.
You know what that mean?
Zephyr's still out there.
So, if you're a master
of deception
where do you hide?
Or do you?
I think this room is shrinking.
(grunts)
Nothing is what it seems.
But I fooled them all.
Even that ungrateful masochist.
ZEPHYR:
You, in the blue dress.
Who's he kidding?
That's a plant.
That was a plant.
It-It's amazing
what you can do with a stagehand
and a masquerade mask.
You know, not to mention a prop
like a packet full
of Zoe's blood.
You know,
lucky for me
she let me have some before
she mysteriously disappeared.
You made her disappear.
No, I assumed her.
Quick-change artistry.
A magical transformation.
With a good seamstress
and some Velcro...
We know that you switched
with your son, Punky
to set up Toby Arcane
for your murder.
That trick didn't work
so well, did it?
Not as planned.
And your finding me here
has thwarted my transmutation.
Abracadabra.
That's a cabalistic charm
said to be made up
from three Hebrew words
meaning, father, son
and the holy spirit.
You're the father
who took his son's life...
so that you could disappear
and become the holy spirit?
No.
From caterpillar
to cocoon.
From cocoon
to moth.
And from moth...
...to dust.
Your son aspired to be
a great magician, didn't he?
Yeah, but he served better
as a prop.
You're about to be arrested
for his murder.
You don't want to know
how I did that trick?
No.
Magicians shouldn't reveal
their tricks.
And they say they save
their best trick for last.
Officer?
Officer, wait a minute.
Turn him around, please.
Open your mouth, please.
Satisfied?
Yeah.