I'm so sorry.
I got to go, baby.
I'll call you tomorrow.
WOMAN:
Just one more minute.
( electronic gunshots)
FATHER:
Turn it off.
I'm not going
to say it again.
Dad, just five more minutes
and I'll be on level nine.
Now!
GIRL:
Dad!
You said I can watch
Nickelodeon.
You've watched enough TV
for tonight.
It's time to go to bed.
How come he doesn't have to?
Both of you, bed now!
Dad!
You got to save it first.
This game saves it
automatically.
Oh, no, no, you know
how much sugar's
in that thing?
( gunshots)
( car tires squealing)
Son, are you all right?
Aimee?
Aimee! Aimee!
Aimee.
BROWN:
Hey.
GRISSOM:
Didn't you grow up
in this neighborhood?
Yeah, not too far away.
My grandmother still
lives down the block.
Lot of familiar faces.
MAN:
Hey, Brown, you going to
find the guy who did this?
We're going to do our jobs.
Jason Gilbert.
Shot through and through.
He's going to be
all right, though.
What was he doing here?
BRASS:
Visiting his girlfriend
next door. He hit the deck
when the shooting started.
Didn't see a car.
Drive-by.
His girlfriend
see anything?
Nobody saw a thing.
Little girl inside
wasn't so lucky.
Aimee Phelps,
age nine.
Phelps?
Father operates a rec center
down the block.
What happened, man?
They killed my baby.
( sobs )
I'm sorry, man.
I'm sorry.
BROWN:
I got here as quick
as I could.
What happened?
Cops said they were aiming
at some white kid.
I thought I was making
a difference.
( sobs )
You are making
a difference.
I'm living proof.
I'm sorry.
You going to be able
to handle this?
I want this case.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
Matt told me his house was
broken into about a week ago.
They took all of his awards,
his medals.
Everything in this case.
I hope whoever took it,
it meant as much
to them as it did to him.
( sighs )
Well, we're obviously
looking for an automatic.
BROWN:
No doubt.
All this damage.
The bullets went
through the glass,
shed their jackets
or disintegrated completely
on impact with the wall.
All we have left are
lead cores, which are
of no comparison value.
The only bullet
that may help us
is inside that little girl.
HyperTrix?
Sounds like a
breakfast cereal.
Some Internet
service thing.
I stopped thinking
about that stuff when I
found out my NASDAQ fund
was worth less than my son's
comic book collection.
Dot com, dot bomb.
The office floor
where the DB's located
is restricted--
authorized employees only.
I'll need the access log.
I already spoke
to building security.
Cool.
Night shift started
at 6:00 p.m.
STOKES:
And since then,
four people have entered
the building,
and nobody left.
VEGA:
Three of them are
still breathing.
( beeping )
Ooh.
Hey, David.
Nick.
Cool enough
in here for you?
I'll manage.
Most computers dissipate over
two thirds
of the energy
they consume as heat.
AC's here for them,
not the worker bees.
Victim's name's Garret Kwan.
Job title, CTO.
Chief Technology Officer.
T.O.D.?
Ambient here's
about 65 degrees,
which makes core temp drop
roughly two degrees per hour.
Figure he's been dead
five to seven hours.
Apparent blunt
force trauma.
Minimal seepage
around the wound.
No blood on the floor.
The paramedics roll him?
Uh, yeah.
Said they found him face down,
head towards the rack.
Any sign of a weapon?
Nothing obvious.
No windows.
Only one way in or out.
Yeah, but there's plenty
of places to hide.
Okay.
One dead boss.
Three live employees.
I like the odds.
BRASS:
So, Jason Gilbert,
the kid who was shot,
not too popular
in the neighborhood.
Just in a fight last week,
down the street.
Yeah?
Uh-huh.
You saw his girl.
She was hot.
They're probably
macking on her.
Matt said he heard
tires screech.
Mm-hmm.
And the bullets went
from right to left.
Uh-huh.
Over there?
You know, it's
a federal offense
to be messing with
the postal service.
Took that corner
pretty hard, huh?
Yeah.
Doesn't that dent look
a little high to you?
Like a truck or an SUV?
Yeah.
I'm not just another
pretty face, you know.
There's a silver paint transfer,
though, right here.
Captain.
Yeah?
Just got a call.
PJ's tavern, a few block away.
Guy was brandishing
an automatic weapon.
They're holding him
at the site.
This guy's a punk.
Hey, tell me
what you're telling him.
This guy's no good.
He's been in here before,
and every time it's trouble,
so this time, I exercised
my right not to serve him.
You know what
the little freak does?
Lifts up his jacket,
and shows me a piece.
I tell him
to take a hike.
BRASS:
Yeah?
Then he proceeds
to tell me
how I better watch my back,
'cause it wouldn't be
the first time tonight
he killed somebody.
No kidding. All right.
Jay...
Jacobs?
No, it's Gene Jaycobs.
Gene Jaycobs.
I knew that kid.
I went to school
with him.
He got kicked out.
Okay, let's see what the lad
has to say for himself.
Thanks a lot.
Gene Jaycobs
Uncuff him.
Do I know you?
Put your hands out
in front of you.
Oh, it's like that, huh?
I can process this now.
It would tell me
if you fired a gun
within the last
couple of hours.
But I'm going to take this
back to the lab,
make you sweat it out.
BRASS:
Okay, Officer,
I think someone needs
their cuffs put back on.
I know what that is.
You're checking me
for blood spatter.
I watch the Discovery Channel.
I found the body,
I called the police.
Not too smart, if I'm the one
who killed the guy.
( quietly ):
That's good.
Not too... Not too smart,
if I'm the one who...
Mr. Benton, could you stand up
for me, please?
I know what that... is.
I know what that is.
You're checking me
for blood spatter.
I watch the
Discovery Channel.
Look, I... I found the body,
I called the police.
Not too smart, if I'm the
one who killed the guy.
Thanks for pointing that out.
When was the last time
you saw Garret Kwan?
I didn't; not tonight.
I was working.
Working halfway to
carpal tunnel syndrome.
So-called ergonomic chairs.
Should be a crime,
if you ask me.
The chairs are...
okay, you know,
it's, it's not like my office
has a good view of the door.
You should be
talking to Charlie.
Charlie has the good view.
Charlie?
Yeah, okay, yeah,
um, Charlie...
Charlie doesn't
work here anymore,
so that doesn't
really help you.
Could you hold your hands
out for me, please?
Pretty easy to see the door
to the server farm
from here.
That is a fact.
And here's another.
I didn't see anything.
I was coding.
Link. Compile. Debug.
All night.
The work absorbs me.
What kind of work?
My code monitors Internet
traffic and server load.
So you make your computer
watch other computers
that other people
are watching?
Just because you can't see
the beauty in data flow
doesn't mean it
doesn't exist.
What was your relationship
to Garret Kwan?
I'm employee number seven.
Kwan was employee number six.
Big brain by reputation,
my boss by random chance.
You know, they, um,
they confiscated
all my murder weapons
when I left Microsoft,
so I don't know
if you'll find anything.
Yeah, you don't exactly
fit the corporate image.
Well, it's my image,
the company doesn't
get a say in it.
VEGA:
Looks like you get special
treatment around here.
Yeah, well, I earn it.
I optimize 'Net infrastructure.
I saved this company
$8.3 mill last year.
Got a five-figure bonus.
And, uh, yes,
I did see Garret
go into the server farm
around 6:00, 6:30.
STOKES:
So your boss is
laying there dead
for five and a
half hours plus,
and you never even
notice he's gone.
Oh... well, I mean,
nobody else did, either.
Look, I was, you know...
Working.
That is what we do here.
Right.
Bullet entered
through the throat,
severing the spinal column.
C2's adjacent
to the brain stem.
Sever that, respiration
shuts down,
resulting in almost
immediate death.
Wood splinters embedded
in the jacket.
Well, it went
through a bookcase.
Nine millimeter.
Thanks.
( muffled automatic gunfire )
( water splashes in tank )
Hi.
( sharp clank )
All right.
Bingo.
Your bullet came from that gun.
You're sure.
Yeah, I'm sure.
We got him.
BRASS:
So, Jason Gilbert--
what did he
ever do to you?
Drawing a blank.
The kid you shot!
I didn't shoot nobody, man.
Jason's girlfriend told us
that you were practically
stalking her.
She must have turned you down
a hundred times.
You didn't like that, did you?
Is that what she told you?
Yeah.
Lying bitch!
I found that gun!
Gun was jammed,
I cleared it.
You cleared it,
all right--
into Mr. Phelps's home,
killing his daughter!
No, it was the last bullet.
What are you talking about?
You threatened a bartender
with an empty gun?
He didn't know that.
I can show you where I found it:
Alleyway behind
Washington Avenue,
( over speaker ):
next to a big
yellow dumpster.
BROWN:
Oh, come on.
That's it?
That's his genius story?
We only found a small amount
of GSR on his hands.
Could have been transfer
from just picking up
the murder weapon.
He's lying.
BROWN:
Our shooter isn't only a liar,
he's a thief.
Found tons of electronic
equipment in there,
still in the boxes.
Well, either he's buying in
bulk, or that stuff's hot.
No guns or ammo.
But I do have his car keys.
( car alarm chirps )
I'm afraid the only bullets
in here are silver bullets.
I may have something here.
The shooter's vehicle
took out a mailbox.
The dent's in
the right spot,
and the car is the
right silver color
You got any paint transfer?
Nothing visible.
Call auto detail.
We'll tow it back to the lab.
Blow came from an object
roughly rectangular
in shape, resulting in
a depressed fracture
of the parietal bone,
with radiating linear
fractures extending outward
from the point of impact.
Based on the fracture pattern,
I'd say it was a single
strike to the head.
Explains the lack of spatter
at the scene.
First hit's free.
Killer knew what
he was doing.
And, uh, take a look at this.
Black plastic.
Found it in the wound.
Possible transfer
from a murder weapon?
Hey.
I heard you
got the shooter.
It's not that simple.
You think it's him?
We got all our guys on
this, Matt, all right?
Yeah.
You still using them
same old uniforms?
That stuff's expensive, man.
Yeah.
But we managed to get the
basketball court tarmacked,
thanks to contributions
from folk like you.
Hey, I ain't stupid.
I know where I came from.
I wouldn't be anywhere,
if it weren't for this place.
Well, you was
always going places.
You just lacked discipline.
Still do.
I don't recognize
this ugly-ass gang symbol.
You know, it's, it's hard
to keep up with it all.
I just don't know anymore.
What with all
the break-ins...
Break-ins?!
Rec Center's van was
stolen a couple days ago.
How am I going to
tell these kids
that they can't play
in the semifinals
'cause I got no way
of getting them there?
I'll look into it
for you, all right?
We'll get them there.
When's Aimee's service?
Wednesday.
Matt, if there's
anything I can do...
Just get me five minutes
alone with the shooter.
Just five minutes.
I know it's not going
to bring Aimee back...
but I can't sleep at night,
knowing that he's still
breathing out there.
Can you?
( cell phone ringing )
Brown.
What?
( indistinct conversation )
Mr. Phelps,
it's good to see you again, sir.
Would you excuse us a moment?
Warrick.
What's he doing here?
If Jaycobs is going to
slip through our fingers,
I need someone else
to explain to him
what went wrong.
This was not a good idea.
That's supposed to be
his alibi?
David Artiss.
Says he was
with our suspect
the night of the drive-by.
Says he dropped him off
at PJ's Tavern
right before we
picked him up.
Says he also saw
him find the Mac.
Clothes he slept in,
bloodshot eyes.
The guy's a junkie, Grissom.
You can see it, I can see it,
and the jury will see it.
DA listened to
the alibi's statement.
He knows it's questionable,
but, uh....
But what?
Half an hour
before the house
was shot up,
Jaycobs and his alibi
were at the Sports Chalet.
Come on.
Salesperson remembered
seeing both of them.
They bought a baseball bat.
Artiss even has the receipt.
Sports Chalet is
ten minutes away.
That's no alibi.
I don't know.
After what the DA heard, he said
he's not going to file charges.
Doesn't want the clock to tick.
So that's it?
BROWN:
As easy as that,
he walks.
BRASS:
Look at it this way--
you have more time
to build your case.
Is that him?
Why are they
letting him go?
letting him go?!
What are you guys doing?
What are you doing?!
He killed my daughter!
They're going to put Jaycobs
in protective custody
to avoid repercussions
in the community.
Where are we going
to put Warrick?
...cool-looking office.
It was kind of fun
being out in the field.
Pulling drives,
collecting evidence...
flashing I.D.
I think
I got a flair for it.
You bucking
for a promotion?
Not bucking...
Nudging.
You know people put their lives
on these hard drives?
Yeah, yeah, that's
what I'm counting on.
Hey, Arch.
Wow!
Serena.
Can defrag my hard
drive anytime.
Are these, uh,
business e-mails?
I'm a little confused.
No, um...
this is actually
harmless fun, so...
VEGA:
Court documents
Garret Kwan was suing you
for sexual harassment.
Are you, um, familiar
with the term "spurious"?
VEGA:
Are you familiar with the term
"murder suspect"?
I was just trying
to let him know
I was available, okay?
Low pressure.
The guy freaked out,
he thought I was
trying to get him into
some bogus lawsuit,
so he preempted me
with one of his own.
It's called a scare tactic.
Scared to lose your job?
Your five-figure bonus?
Scared enough to kill him?
Okay, look, I was
flirting with the guy.
I will e-mail you with
the number from my lawyer.
( cup clatters )
( door slams )
( hollow clanking )
( clanking continues )
This guy's been
in Matt's house.
What is this?
Matt's team won this
three years ago.
This trophy was given to
the rec center last year.
I found all this stuff
in Jaycobs' car.
Well, if this is evidence,
it needs to be tagged
and catalogued.
This is the same guy who shot
Matt's daughter in the head.
He's walking around
laughing at us.
Can you prove that?
What is this?
I've been putting guys
away like this for years.
And now that it matters,
it's like you're
holding me back here.
GRISSOM:
The job, Warrick, is
to process evidence.
Objectively,
and without prejudice.
I'm so tired
of hearing that.
I've heard it
a million times.
I can't be like you.
I'm not a robot, okay?
I actually care
about these people.
You know what?
You're not working
on this case anymore.
I'll have another assignment
for you tomorrow.
Keep it.
( slamming cart )
Where were we?
At a dead end.
Go back to work.
Hey, Stokes?
Yeah?
We got to talk.
Hey, did you I.D.
that scraping
from my vic's
head wound yet?
Yeah, yeah,
it's a common plastic,
polyethylterephthalate--
P.E.T.-- used in everything
from garbage bags
to magnetic tape
to floppy disks.
Okay, thanks.
Yeah, but that's not what
I wanted to talk about.
What, then?
Look, I thought that
we had a relationship.
What are you doing taking
Archie out into the field,
instead of me?
It's the right tool
for the right job, man.
You have to understand the world
you're investigating.
Hey, Archie.
Yeah?
Hey, what's that
Star Trek episode
where the guy's got
the forehead thingy,
and the time portal...?
In Classic, TNG, DS9,
Voyager or Enterprise?
Point taken.
Or were you thinking
about Farscape?
I have no idea what
you are talking about.
It doesn't matter.
Look, I got something
to show you here.
I found this
on Anders' computer.
What is this,
a video game?
No, it's actually an FRPG:
"Fantasy Role-Playing Game."
You see, players use avatars
to represent themselves
in a fantasy world.
There's Serena, Todd, and Kwan
in this alternate universe
conjuring up a gateway,
which summons a
beast-like Anders,
who decapitates Kwan.
( beast roaring )
You know a lot about
this stuff, don't you?
Mm-hmm.
You got to get a girlfriend.
You first.
It was merely a game.
An entertainment.
Nah, it's more like a place
where you can play God, right?
Maybe treat people
the way you wish
you could treat them
in real life?
VEGA:
Virtual murder
is not quite
as satisfying as
the real thing, is it?
You look a little
uncomfortable,
Mr. Molyneaux.
This office is
always uncomfortable.
Ventilation sucks.
I put Kwan in my game
because I was upset.
Upset about what?
I was designing characters
for a new multi-player sim...
on company time.
Kwan found out...
somehow.
Man always seems
to be one step
ahead of his underlings.
How?
If I'd known, he would've
been working for me.
In this instance,
he informed the board.
Unauthorized use
of bandwidth.
Nearly got me fired.
VEGA:
But you didn't
kill him.
No.
Am I sorry he's gone?
( loud clanking )
( sighing )
What's going on, fellas?
Possible burglary.
Homeowner's on vacation.
Neighbor called it
in last night.
Just getting around to it.
I may have to climb over.
( gate clanks )
What have you got?
Stovepipe.
Possibly jammed
in our murder weapon.
Never fired, never
exposed to the heat.
And you're thinking there
might be a recoverable print.
Yes.
Dare to dream.
JOHNSON:
Well, you were right.
Kwanspy.
On every employee's computer.
Program runs in the
background, invisible.
Copies documents, e-mails,
every keystroke.
Then transfers the data
to Kwan's machine.
Big Brother.
Company owns a network,
company owns what's on it.
Sick, but legal.
Well, knowledge is power.
Kwan had his computer set up
to auto-burn a new disk
every night-- here.
This was made
the night of the murder.
If we found out
who was away from their desk
at the time of death...
We've got our killer.
Nick, based on
these time stamps,
everybody in that office
was working
when Garret Kwan was killed.
Great.
We just eliminated
all of our suspects.
BROWN:
Assistant District Attorney
Kelly's Office, please.
This is Warrick Brown.
Oh, he's not in?
Okay.
Well, maybe you can help me out.
I, uh, I have Gene Jaycobs'
personal belongings,
and I need to get them
returned to him.
I need his relocated address.
Yeah, I know it's not
standard procedure but, uh,
I missed him at lockup,
and I'm going to be in hot water
if I don't get this stuff
back to him, so...
Good.
It's just me.
Nobody here.
Got no heater.
What, what, what can
I do for you, Mr. Brown?
I just thought I'd
come by and let you know
we're going to get you
for robbery, if not murder.
By the time
you get to lockup,
every roughneck in the joint
is going to know you offed
a nine-year-old little girl.
( snickering )
You know, in school,
you were a nerd, Brown.
You were, remember?
Every kid there used to
beat your ass.
Thick glasses,
hand-me-down clothes,
always with a book in your hand,
like you were better
than everybody else.
Nigga, I ain't scared of you.
Want to step outside, then?
( scoffs )
( door slams )
DR. LEWIS:
Fractured nasal bone,
fracture of the right
zygomatic arch
extending
into the maxilla.
Fracture of the
right anterior ribs...
Assistant D.A.'s
office, please.
Who found him?
Motel manager called it in.
No weapon
was found at the scene.
Thank God his assailant
only used his fists.
Given the severity
of force,
anything else
would have killed him
Thank you, Doctor.
Yeah, this is Jim Brass.
I'm at Desert Palm Hospital.
I'm looking at
a half dead Gene Jaycobs.
Now, only two people
knew where he was.
That was you and me.
You want to tell me how
the hell this could happen?
What, you think I did this?
I don't jump to conclusions.
Well, I didn't.
I'd like to shake
the hand
of the guy that did, though.
Well, you may get a chance.
Your new assignment.
Check out the pattern
in the center
of this contusion.
It's probative.
No suspect.
No motive.
No weapon.
You don't just spontaneously
develop a fatal head wound.
Somebody had to kill him.
A guy goes into a room with
no windows and no doors.
How does he get out?
I don't know.
Same way he got in.
You know, there is one thing
that comes in and goes
out of here all the time.
Cold air.
Anything?
Just black P.E.T.,
as far as the eye can see.
And a possible transfer.
BROWN:
Where were you last night?
Right here, man.
I'm going to need
to see your hands.
Dad?
Trav, go to your room.
Other side.
Look, you went there too.
That's how I knew where to go.
But I never touched the guy.
He didn't kill your daughter!
If he's guilty, we're
going to put him away.
Yeah, yeah.
And then what?
Lawyers? Trial?
You wait ten years for somebody
else's definition of justice.
And they always put
the criminal's rights
before the victim's.
The first good night's
sleep I had
was last night.
Eye for an eye
and the whole world
goes blind?
You taught me that.
My perspective has changed.
Aimee's dead.
I've got no choice here.
My hands are tied.
I got to let them
bring you in.
It's going to be okay, Trav.
I love you, son.
Look, uh...
make sure they take care
of him, all right?
Of course.
All right.
OFFICER:
Sir.
You, um, asked us to check
on a stolen minivan?
Yeah.
You know,
from the rec center?
We located it.
Great, thanks.
Hey.
Blue paint transfer.
Possibly from
your mailbox?
I found a jammed
nine millimeter cartridge
in the backyard of a house
a few doors down
from where Jaycobs said
he found the gun.
Backyard of a house
that had been broken into.
You said he was a thief, right?
Yeah.
See, I think he
lied about where
he found the gun
so we wouldn't know he was
breaking into houses.
Apart from that, I think
he was telling the truth.
( glass breaking )
Shall we?
Grissom.
Matt used to have
this really harsh rule
about no eating in the van.
( knocking )
Yeah?
Hugo Karlin?
Yeah, uh, you know what?
You guys aren't
supposed to be back here.
This is a restricted...
Detective Vega.
LVPD.
This is Nick Stokes
from the crime lab.
Uh, hey.
What's up?
Interesting
choice of words.
Facility management
says you've been
working on the
air conditioning
above HyperTrix.
Yeah, well, I work
this whole building.
That's a lot
of companies.
I don't really keep
track of the names,
I just fix the air.
You'd remember
this company.
It's where you
killed a guy...
with that.
One in a million shot.
It happens.
It was an accident.
You got to believe me.
I, I always keep
my hammer right here.
I don't even know
how it came loose.
Oh, it just
came loose, huh?
Yes.
Okay.
Well, then how'd
you pick it up?
Um, the same way
I close the duct cover.
I call this my grabby tool.
I made it myself.
You know, people never
notice me
when I'm around here,
and I just figured that if
I covered my tracks,
this time
wouldn't be any different.
Why don't you, uh,
show him our grabby tool?
You're under arrest.
You have the right
to remain silent...
( laughing )
Greg.
How many licks
does it take
to get to the center
of a Tootsie Pop?
The world
may never know.
( giggling )
Just see if you
can get some DNA
off of this stick,
would you?
All work and no play
make Greg a dull boy.
All play and no work
make Greg an unemployed boy.
WOMAN:
Hey, Grissom.
Your stovepipe.
Pulled a good thumbprint.
Happens sometimes
when they load
the magazine.
Tyrel Constantine.
Arrested last June
for joyriding.
Date of birth '87?
This guy's a juvie.
He's only 15.
So, Tyrel, let me
get this straight.
You didn't know
Jason Gilbert?
I never heard of him.
So you shot someone
you didn't know?
Who says I shot anyone?
That would be me.
Tyrel Constantine.
Oh, yeah, I knew him.
He used to hang out
at the rec center.
He used to?
Until he lost
his privileges.
So you threw him out?
He was smoking weed
on the field.
Showing up late to practice,
starting fights.
When did this happen?
A couple weeks ago.
We found your saliva
on this lollipop stick
in Mr. Phelps's van, and
we found your thumbprint
on this bullet.
BRASS:
You stole a van
from the rec center,
didn't you?
The van wasn't hot-wired,
so I think you knew
where Mr. Phelps
kept his keys.
Why, why, why you asking me
about Tyrel?
The vehicle that was used
in that drive-by
was the van that was stolen
from your rec center.
Oh, God.
Look, we know you didn't
mean to shoot anyone.
It was a stray bullet
that hit Aimee Phelps.
I just wanted to scare him.
Scare who?
Jason Gilbert?
No. Mr. Phelps.
That's it, we're done here.
No, wait, Tyrel, wait.
They need to know
it was an accident.
He shouldn't have
thrown me out.
Pushed me around like that
in front of my friends.
I just wanted to shake him up.
So Jason Gilbert
was just collateral damage.
I was driving pretty fast,
didn't look where I shot.
What about Aimee?
I gave up on him.
If I hadn't...
He gave up on himself.
I blew it.
Yeah.
But you're not the one
who's paying for it.