( car accelerating )
( yelling and screaming )
( glass shattering )
( yelling )
( furniture breaking )
( siren wailing in distance )
( indistinct background
radio communication )
Yeah, yeah. No.
All right.
Yeah, hold on,
hold on.
Happy hour. Joint was packed.
Two fatalities, four critical.
How about the driver?
Nonresponsive.
I've got
a GCS of three.
I need to intubate.
WILLOWS:
That's Sara's boyfriend.
Hey, Sara. Typical Thursday.
Hank?
Your wrist is broken.
Larry, take over, will you?
The car's dry.
This must've happened
right before the rain.
I was sitting at the table.
Next thing I knew...
MAN:
I got a heartbeat!
Excuse me.
Some happy hour, huh?
I think
happy hour's over.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
( indistinct background
radio communication )
Mind if I take over?
You okay?
Yeah.
I didn't think
I'd see you tonight.
So that's what
all this is about.
Thanks.
Any time.
Listen, I got to head
over to the hospital,
and I'm sure you got
to get back to work.
Yeah, but...
will you call me if
you need anything?
My cell will be on.
Anything.
You and Catherine are running
the evidence on this.
Warrick just got done
with Internal Affairs.
He's on his way.
You need to talk to the
restaurant manager, too.
Anything else?
No.
Where are you going?
I got gas.
Oh.
Residential gas leak
in Henderson.
Are you the
restaurant manager?
Yes.
I'm Sara Sidle,
Crime Lab.
Oh, hi, Fred Lychock.
Ooh, sorry.
Um... your supervisor
asked for a seating chart.
Everything's computerized--
software program.
This here'll show you
the number of people per table.
Where were you during the crash?
I was at the register,
behind the bar.
Did you see anything?
A blurry Jaguar speeding
through the intersection.
I thought the car
would slow down,
but it kept
right on coming.
If you ask me,
that's the reason
why old people don't
belong behind the wheel.
Yeah, I didn't ask you.
Thanks for your time.
I'm sorry.
I got wrapped up in...
Hank.
Yeah.
An old Jaguar
with a GPS unit.
That's strange.
Yeah, not your
granny's Oldsmobile.
GRISSOM:
We're cleared to go in?
Yeah.
Gas company shut off the valve
at the street.
Paramedics aired out the scene.
STOKES:
Homicide radioed
in a D.B.?
Vanessa Arnz.
She's in the
master bedroom.
GRISSOM:
Thanks.
The gas company spikes its
natural gas with mercaptan--
smells like rotten eggs.
I don't
smell anything.
GRISSOM:
All's I smell is mothballs
and stale tobacco.
STOKES:
Science geek.
Takes one to know
one, I guess.
Hello, David.
Hey.
She's hot pink,
like a maraschino.
Makes our job easier.
Death was not the result
of natural gas inhalation.
No, but carbon monoxide's
still gas.
Right, when carbon monoxide
displaces oxygen in the blood,
victim asphyxiates,
turns... pink.
Was Mr. Arnz
in bed with her?
Uh, yeah.
Paramedics said they
found them both in here.
So why is she dead
and he's alive?
You know, Dave,
when I was a CSI-One,
I would've tried to answer that,
but now I know
"where" before "why."
First step, find
the source of the C.O.
I'll grab the Nighthawk,
fire it up.
Mr. Arnz has been
stabilized.
They're preparing
him for transport.
I want to take a look at him.
Yeah.
I wake up in the middle
of the night sometimes,
if I get cold.
Vanessa steals the covers.
Uh, I woke up and my
head was spinning.
I think I'm coming
down with something.
Then I look over at her...
( gasping )
Vanessa.
( clattering )
( phone dialing )
My wife isn't breathing.
Do you remember
anything else?
No, I don't remember
hanging up the phone.
I must've
passed out.
Next thing I know
the paramedics
are taking me out.
PARAMEDIC:
We got to roll.
Patient will be
at Desert Palm.
Wait a minute.
What about my boy?
Peter seems fine.
The kid's 18.
Signed an AMA.
Peter...
my name's
Gil Grissom.
I'm with the Las Vegas
Crime Lab.
You want to ask me questions.
I was in my bedroom,
asleep.
I heard the doorbell.
It was the paramedics.
A few minutes later,
the police showed up.
I'm very sorry about what
happened to your mother.
Why are you sorry?
You're
not responsible.
You didn't know her.
You don't know me.
How's she doing?
Doctors are working
on her right now.
Doesn't look good.
Relative?
Driver's been I.D.'d
as Diane Lambert.
That's her
grandson Corey.
Hi, Corey?
I'm, uh, Sara Sidle.
I'm with the Las Vegas
Crime Lab.
Do you mind if I ask you
a couple questions?
I don't even know
why she was in Las Vegas.
We live in Laughlin.
She hates it here.
Corey, um... did your
grandmother own a Jaguar?
Yeah... ( sniffles )
Yeah, she won it in the, uh,
quarter slots.
First two coins and bingo.
Triple stars.
She also win the GPS?
No.
She hadn't been
driving it much.
Uh, she got lost
a couple times
and it scared her,
so for her birthday last month,
I bought her the unit.
Can you excuse me for a second?
Yeah.
Hey.
And the EMT of the year
award goes to...
Not me.
Death toll's now three.
Could climb to four.
Elaine-- the girl
in the wheelchair--
she's one of the lucky ones.
You were amazing.
Eight years in the rig,
first time I've actually
been a part of the scene.
I can't stop it
going through my head.
Yeah, you never know when
your life's going to change.
Listen, I...
I got to get out of here.
You need a lift?
No, I drove.
Hank?
I'm really glad you're okay.
Thanks.
Plenty of tire treads,
but nothing looks fresh.
So you going to
tell me how it went?
I got called in
by Internal Affairs.
How do you think it went?
Too many questions.
Thanks.
I wish I could've
pleaded the Fifth.
Yeah, you don't answer
their questions,
you're looking
at more days off
without pay,
and that blows.
Yeah.
It's a red light camera.
Did any of
the witnesses
see the driver
run the red light?
Nobody mentioned it,
but the camera's there.
Big Brother knows.
I'll put in a call.
WILLOWS:
Black gold.
Now, that looks fresh.
( car accelerating )
( metallic clank )
Hitting the curb could've
caused the car to buck.
Traffic light,
intersection, curb.
Well, either the
car wasn't working,
or the driver wasn't.
Looks like the newspaper
dispenser used to be here.
( car accelerating )
( metallic clank )
Catherine.
Tire treads.
That kills one theory.
Car's brakes
must've been working.
She tried to stop,
but it was too late.
Let me guess:
no air bags
in the vehicle.
No.
Preliminary cause of death,
epidural hematoma.
Her head impacted
the steering wheel.
( glass shattering )
Blood accumulated between
the inner table of the skull
and the dural
membrane.
Her injury is consistent
with a severed middle
meningeal artery.
What about pre-impact?
At the risk of feeding
a stereotype, she was 72.
Any indication of stroke,
Alzheimer's, heart attack?
I considered and dismissed
all age-related factors.
No arthritis,
no significant
impairment of her senses.
She has had part
of her colon removed,
probably due
to injury
or prior medical condition,
but Sara, it's irrelevant
to your case.
I found no physiological
explanation for the crash.
Well, that's a bummer,
'cause at this point, we got
no forensic one, either.
STOKES:
Carbon monoxide fills the air
when any carbon-based
substance is ignited.
( detector beeps slowly )
The kid checks out, so...
the point of ignition's
probably this room.
Now, the two
most common causes
for accidental
household C.O. poisoning:
unvented space heaters
and improperly
maintained chimneys.
I don't see any heaters.
My dad's a fireman.
Last Christmas, he gave
all the kids C.O. detectors.
( beeping faster )
Would've saved
this woman's life.
25 parts per million.
That's the highest
reading in the room.
This is a natural gas
burning fireplace.
Burns clean.
C.O. fumes should be
minimal at best.
Foreign substance.
Still warm.
There was something other than
natural gas burning in here.
If the gas company
hadn't shut off the gas,
whatever that is
probably burned up.
Chimneys are designed
to funnel smoke up and out.
If this fireplace
was the source of the C.O.,
the fumes should've
traveled up the chimney
instead of permeating the room.
LOCKWOOD:
Unless the chimney
isn't doing its job.
( clanging )
Damper's busted.
( creaking )
Foreign fuel source
in a compromised chimney...
I think we just ruled out
accident.
Hey, I hear you're
working on Hank's case.
I believe
it's my case.
Territorial.
You know, guys
don't like that.
You're crowding me,
Greg.
Well, I have
some information
that could bring
us even closer.
But you first.
What are we looking at?
I downloaded the memory
from the GPS in the Jaguar.
She wasn't a local; I wanted
to see if she got lost.
SANDERS:
Well, did she?
Diane Lambert
lives in Laughlin.
Excuse me.
She took 95 North
to Summerlin Parkway.
Then she took Parkway
to Rampart,
made a left on Main Street
and headed straight
to Meadows Lane--
16 North Meadows Lane.
That's where
she was going,
and that's where
she ended up.
So does that thing tell you why?
What do you have, Greg?
Well, maybe
she had the munchies.
Tox screen came back.
Mrs. Lambert tested positive
for cannabis sativa.
Grass?
"Grass"? So '70s, man.
Sticky green, the dank.
The chronic, the cush,
happy stick, wacky-tobaccy...
Well, wait, wait, wait.
Grandma was high?
Yeah.
Grandma was high.
( inhales )
As a kite.
Hey.
Return visit, huh?
You're here
about the tox screen.
Yeah. Was Diane Lambert
legally impaired?
Less than two nanograms
of THC,
so per NIDA,
she wasn't.
Oh. But, if she were
a long-time user,
her reaction time could've been
slowed down, right?
I know where you're going.
Let me stop you.
THC has no significant
cumulative effect,
so maybe the question
you should be asking is:
Why was a woman
her age doping up?
Okay, why was a woman
Tell you what-- check
out her optic nerve.
SIDLE:
Nerve's damaged.
She had glaucoma.
I thought you said
she was in good health.
That was before the
tox screen came back.
You know, it's not
standard procedure
to check for glaucoma, but
the Mary Jane tipped me off.
People think it slows the
progression of the disease,
but it just reduces
the pressure in the eye
and that reduction's
only temporary.
Prescription medications
do a much better job.
Unfortunately, they don't
have the same side effects.
Her vision could've been
impaired by the glaucoma.
It didn't affect
her driving.
Sara, Diana Lambert has
nothing more to tell you.
( beeping )
Hello.
Oh, hey.
So, I got photos of
the restaurant patrons
off the DMV database
and input the information
per the restaurant seating
chart and the police report.
Who's Elaine Alcott?
Who?
Oh, well, she was
seated with Hank.
I just thought
maybe that...
Oh.
Anyway, um...
Apparently, she told PD
that she was returning
from the ladies' room
at the time
of the impact.
They must be friends.
I saw him with her
at the hospital.
Okay.
Um... okay, so, we've got
36 people in the restaurant.
12 worked for Sillmont
Healthcare, a block away.
Another ten were from
the brokerage firm
across the street,
a couple of regulars,
a few out-of-towners and...
restaurant employees.
You know how long it
takes to get in touch
with anybody at the
Transportation Safety Bureau?
It's way out of hand.
Diane Lambert
ran the light.
WILLOWS:
Wow. She sped through
that intersection--
52 miles per hour.
That's more than twice
the speed limit.
Well, the tread marks
tell us
that her brakes did work,
so it must've been something
else that malfunctioned,
causing her
to accelerate.
Gas pedal could've
gotten stuck, or...
throttle plate could've jammed.
There's only one
way to find out.
I'm on it.
♪ ♪
Hey.
You have, uh...
Don't worry about it.
How's it going?
You find anything?
No. Car checks out perfectly.
Well, I did some more
digging down at the TSB.
I found out that the red light
camera that photo'd our driver
catches four times
as many violators
as any other camera in Vegas.
Intersection's dangerous.
Could be a death trap.
I didn't page you.
No, I just figured
I'd come by.
You're checking
up on me again.
No, I'm checking up
on my evidence.
( sighs )
You think if you hover,
the FTIR will work faster?
Yeah... Hodges,
that's what I think.
HODGES:
Hey, boss.
( printer whirring )
Nice timing.
The foreign substance in
the fireplace is carbon.
Associated minerals?
None. Pure,
unadulterated carbon.
It may be pure,
but it's not solid.
Micro-pores.
Sample's under the scope.
GRISSOM:
Activated charcoal?
Used in filtration
systems, kitty litter,
some medications...
And possibly a murder.
BROWN:
The building has
mirrored glass on it.
Lets in the light,
but it keeps out the glare.
SIDLE:
Sun sets in the
west behind us.
Glare could be pretty
intense in the afternoon.
This could explain why this
intersection is so dangerous.
So you think the
sun was a factor
in the crash?
Well, according
to the accident report,
the sun set
at 5:30 yesterday.
The accident
was at 5:15,
so the sun was
still in the sky.
Trees and buildings
extend at least
ten degrees above
the western horizon.
Yeah.
All right, well,
there's 24 hours in a day,
360 degrees
in the Earth's rotation.
360 divided by 24 is... 15?
15. Sun moves
about 15 degrees an hour.
At 5:15 yesterday, the sun
would've been about what--
3.75 degrees
above the horizon?
Wow, you're fast.
3.75, huh?
Then the sun was
behind the trees
at the time
of the accident,
so it was not a factor.
Great, and our investigation
is still in the dark.
( rock music blaring )
( music stops )
I just got a page
from James Watson.
And I got one
from Francis Crick.
What's going on, Greg?
Well, as you both know,
Watson and Crick
are the granddaddies of DNA.
Without their discoveries,
I'd have nothing to do all day.
What have you been doing
all day?
A tox report on your d.b.,
Ms. Pretty in Pink.
She died
of carbon monoxide poisoning.
Blood saturation level
of 46.2%.
No surprise there.
Nicotine levels are high--
she was a smoker.
And she popped a couple
of sleeping pills that night.
Nothing probative.
What if I told you that Mr. Arnz
had a carbon monoxide blood
saturation level of 37%--
nearly 10% lower
than his wife.
Mrs. Arnz was a smoker.
Typically, a smoker's blood
is already 10% saturated
with C.O.
STOKES:
You mean smokers
get a jump start
on the poisoning process?
Could explain
the 10% difference.
It could also explain
why he lived and she died.
Nice theory,
but what if I told you
that Mr. Arnz had high
nicotine levels as well.
They were both smokers.
That still doesn't explain
why one lived and one died.
Well, I don't know
if this is going to help,
but the sleeping pills
are zolpidem.
Prescription only.
I thought I'd save you
some time,
talked to Lockwood.
She didn't have a prescription,
but her husband does.
Thanks, Greg.
( rock music blaring )
Hey, check this out.
The red light camera
clocked her speed
at 52 miles per hour,
right?
Mm-hmm.
The computer software
pegged her at 60
by the time she hits
the newspaper dispenser.
She accelerated
into the building.
You already reviewed
the driver's tox screen.
Now you want
her basic blood panel.
I'm running
with a hunch.
Let's go.
SIDLE:
Acetylcholine levels were low,
epinephrine was high.
Why are you focused
on those hormones?
Kamikaze pilots,
World War II--
their blood work
was very unusual.
Acetylcholine levels
were low,
epinephrine was through
the roof.
Well, you're talking about the
sympathetic response to stress--
eyes dilate, uh, heart rate
goes up, hormones go haywire.
Diane Lambert lived
two hours away.
If she drove her car into Vegas
with the intention of using it
as a murder weapon,
I imagine she would be
pretty stressed out.
Kamikaze Granny.
( door bells jingling )
Isaac Asimov-- one of
my favorite writers.
"If knowledge
can create problems,
then it is not through ignorance
that we will solve them."
Is that what you're doing here?
Solving problems?
It's my job to figure out
what happened to your mother.
Scientists derive satisfaction
from figuring out the puzzle.
It's about the quest...
not the grail.
Asimov believed
that only scientists
could understand the universe.
His corollary:
"It's not so much
that I have confidence
in scientists
being right..."
"But that I have
so much confidence
in non-scientists
being wrong."
You a scientist?
Yeah.
I am.
Peter?
The boxes won't
unload themselves.
Peter and I were hoping
to get back into
the house tonight.
Well, not tonight, sir.
It's still an active
crime scene.
Our lab found zolpidem
in your wife's system--
20 milligrams.
That's twice
the recommended dosage.
Do you know anything
about that?
Well... Vanessa was having
trouble sleeping.
The, uh, prescription
is in your name.
Are you accusing me
of something?
No.
We're just telling you
what we know.
Look, uh... ( sighs )
ever since this discount chain
opened a branch down the block,
I've been working
16-hour days
just trying to survive.
And I'd go home
and Vanessa would come at me.
You're always tired.
You never talk to me.
Y-You need to
communicate with me.
You know, I have needs.
I'm here all day long.
You never talk to me.
She'd just go on and on and on
talking.
And when she'd finally let me
get to sleep,
she'd want
what every woman wants.
I-I don't mean
just sex.
She'd want to talk and talk.
Next thing you know,
it's 5:00 a.m.,
the alarm is screaming at me,
and I got to go back to work.
So you drugged your wife
to get some shut-eye?
Yeah.
I put it in her ice cream.
I know it
was wrong, but...
STOKES:
It's also illegal.
Yeah.
Happened as an accident
the first time.
See, I got a problem
swallowing pills,
so I crush them up
in the ice cream.
One night, she grabbed
the wrong bowl
and was out like a light.
Best night's sleep
I'd had in a long time.
Well, if you...
you got nothing else
you want to ask,
I got things I got to do.
I have one more question.
When did you quit smoking?
I noticed the, uh,
nicotine patch on your arm.
Oh, uh, about three weeks.
Doctor's orders.
I got high
blood pressure.
STOKES:
I have another question.
Did you know the damper
on your chimney was busted?
Why, did this have
something to do
with my wife's death?
I mean, I asked
Peter if he'd...
( sighs )
Is this my fault?
SIDLE:
If the crash was intentional,
I'm thinking either
the restaurant was the target
or someone inside
the restaurant.
I'll call Brass.
If Lambert had a grudge
against the place,
somebody there
should know her.
If she was gunning
for someone specific,
there's a lot of variables.
Maybe we should start
with the most obvious targets--
the people sitting
in the window.
Let's run it.
Okay... top to bottom.
Cameron Black,
deceased; from Jersey.
First time in Vegas.
Unlikely mark.
Second table:
Rachel Krandall,
and...
Tom Krandall.
Both died at the scene.
Both worked
for Sillmont Healthcare.
Table three:
Hank and...
Elaine Alcott.
Also works
at the insurance company.
Three out of five of the people
sitting in the window
work at
Sillmont Healthcare.
Maybe I should go talk to her.
Yeah.
Maybe you should.
ALCOTT:
I'm sorry,
I don't recognize her.
Well, uh, could she be
one of your policy holders?
It's possible.
I oversee hundreds
of members' accounts.
I can check my list.
That'd be great.
I wish I had some more time off,
but with Tom Krandall gone
and half my department
in the hospital...
I'm back
at the office tomorrow.
Let's see...
Diane Lambert.
My boyfriend.
Saved up my miles
and took him to
Hawaii last year.
He's going to take me to Tahiti
in a few weeks.
I can't wait.
Ms. Lambert isn't on my list.
But if you want, I can
go on the company database.
Thank you.
Um, I-I have to get back
to the lab.
Um, maybe you could call me.
Okay.
( water bubbling )
You're not supposed to be
in here.
It's my home.
Well, perhaps you didn't see
the crime scene tape.
Do I look stupid to you?
On the contrary.
I heard you have
an almost perfect 4.0 GPA.
With the exception
of a B in English.
Our detectives do complete
background searches
on all the principles
at a crime scene.
I understand you threatened
your English teacher.
I have to feed my fish.
Clown loaches,
tetras, angelfish.
You might want to check
your filter, too.
You're out of charcoal.
GRISSOM:
In 1939, Isaac Asimov
was an undergraduate
studying zoology.
As part of
a course requirement,
the students were asked
to find a stray cat,
kill it and dissect it.
Isaac found his cat,
he killed it,
and then he promptly
dropped out of zoology.
50 years later,
he wrote that the memory
of killing that cat
still haunted him.
Do you have
a question for me?
Yeah, I do.
Why didn't you fix the chimney
damper in your parents' bedroom?
Why would I?
You told your father
you fixed it.
So he'd quit
bugging me.
And if you're accusing me
of disobeying a man
with only a tenth-grade
education, then you're right.
We know you took advantage
of the broken damper.
Placed activated charcoal
from your fish tank filter
in the back of the fireplace...
( granules rattling )
...then waited for your father
to do what he does every
night.
You killed your mother.
You almost killed your father.
That's good science fiction.
Well, you thought
the charcoal
would burn up, destroying
any evidence of the crime,
but your father woke up,
called 911.
Nick, at what point
is the saturation level
of carbon monoxide in
the bloodstream lethal?
Approximately 45, 50%.
Mmm.
Well, his mother's
level was in the range,
but his father's
level was low.
STOKES:
Yeah, but two people
exposed to the same level
of carbon monoxide
for the same
period of time,
their C.O. saturation levels
should be approximate.
As long as the variables
are consistent--
body mass, health, age.
What about smoking?
Of course.
STOKES:
Three weeks ago,
your father quit.
Yeah, we didn't know
he'd quit, either.
The nicotine levels
in his system were high
but when we went
to speak with him,
he was wearing a nicotine patch.
STOKES:
The patch
delivers nicotine
to the blood,
but since your father
quit smoking cigarettes,
his C.O. saturation level
returned to zero.
You made a basic scientific
mistake, Peter.
You stopped observing
the human element
because you thought
it was inferior.
STOKES:
What I don't
understand is why.
Man, why would you want
to kill your parents?
Your high school told us
you were accepted to Princeton,
early action.
A few more months,
you would've been
2,000 miles away.
Whatever your parents
did to piss you off
wouldn't have mattered.
I know why.
They weren't going
to let you go, were they?
They refused to pay for it.
I don't qualify
for financial aid
because my father makes
too much money.
Not enough money
to live well,
but enough to destroy my dreams.
So with your parents gone,
you could sell the business
and pay your tuition.
You figured out the puzzle.
Must be very gratifying.
GRISSOM:
Science isn't about
the gratification, Peter.
It's about the truth.
Hey.
So, how did it go
with Elaine Alcott?
She didn't have anything
to add to the investigation.
Hey, how's it going?
Here are the phone records
from the driver of the vehicle
that you asked for.
You know, there may be something
to that kamikaze grandma
theory of yours.
Last week, Diane Lambert
closed out her bank accounts,
paid off her credit cards,
and updated her will.
Well, that's certainly
more evidence
to suggest that her actions
were intentional.
There's only one Vegas
phone number on this statement
and the prior statement.
There's got to be 80 calls
here to the same number.
Dial the number.
( keypad beeping )
( ringing )
WOMAN:
Sillmont Healthcare.
How can I direct your call?
What's your address?
16 South Meadows Lane.
Thank you.
Right. The Checkerbox
is at 16 North Meadows.
BRASS:
I don't think
that's a coincidence.
If Sillmont Healthcare was
the intended target,
how did she end up
at the Checkerbox?
Well, I'll tell you
what happened to me.
Last week, I was driving
to a crime scene in the car
and the GPS said go right.
Had I done so,
I'd be coughing up fish
from the bottom of Lake Mead.
Well, GPS is hardly perfect.
Maybe north was
a directional default.
Or maybe she put in
the wrong address.
SIDLE:
Either way...
it does leave one question:
Why was Diane Lambert so angry?
Mrs. Lambert was a member
of our HMO.
I was, uh, going to call you.
Well, did she have
some kind of problem
with her policy?
MAN:
Not to our knowledge.
Then you won't mind
if we take a look at her file.
I'm sorry, member files
are confidential.
Well, this
member's deceased.
Not even the doctor-patient
privilege extends postmortem.
Mrs. Lambert had colon cancer.
If you read further, you'll see
that it was in remission.
No, actually,
her most recent CAT scan
shows recurrence two months ago.
That's about the same time
she started calling
your office two times a day.
Why would she
be calling you?
You know what?
Four people are dead.
Don't waste our time.
We can take this downtown.
Mrs. Lambert's oncologist
recommended immediate
and aggressive treatment.
Did treatment commence?
The recommendation was pending.
Well, what exactly
does that mean?
Not yet approved,
not yet denied.
In other words,
Mrs. Lambert's health
was in limbo.
She wasn't
receiving treatment,
but she couldn't
file an appeal,
since you hadn't officially
denied her claim.
The authorization process
takes... it takes time.
Time Mrs. Lambert didn't have.
We have a procedure,
and we follow it.
( car accelerating )
And while you were
following your procedure,
and postponing a decision,
her cancer cells
were multiplying.
What were you,
playing the odds?
Were you hoping she would die
before you had to spend a dime?
We're not liable here.
We're not
responsible for
Mrs. Lambert's actions.
For what it's worth,
that makes me sick.
Catherine.
Yeah.
We missed something.
SIDLE:
Corey, when
I was reviewing
your grandmother's
insurance policy,
I noticed she that didn't
specify an e-mail address,
and that got me thinking.
Some people her age aren't
technologically savvy.
Maybe a GPS device would be
intimidating to her.
I wondered if she actually
even knew how to use it.
So I printed the unit and I
found your fingerprints on it.
I installed it.
SIDLE:
The prints just weren't
on the base of the unit,
they were on the face.
You punched in addresses.
( quiet mumble )
WILLOWS:
If you were aware of your
grandmother's intentions
and programmed the GPS,
you're guilty
of aiding and abetting
in the murder of three people.
Oh, God.
Uh...
Last week, she came by my place
'cause she said
she didn't know how
to work the GPS.
Okay, Grandma, look,
it's really easy.
I'll explain it to you again.
You just type in the address
of where you want to go.
Look, I swear, if I had known
what she was planning,
I would've stopped her.
Uh...
Well...
Corey, Homicide has informed us
that your grandmother
had a life insurance policy,
in which you're
the sole beneficiary.
I had no idea.
She never mentioned it to you?
No.
No, no, wait.
Promise me.
Okay, fine.
When I can afford it,
I'll go back to college.
You should have a degree.
Grandma, I promise.
I love you.
You're such a good boy.
I love you, too.
SIDLE:
Your grandmother's
death has been
ruled a suicide,
which nullifies the policy.
There's not going
to be any money.
No...
Look, I don't think you
understand.
I loved my grandmother,
and she's dead.
She killed herself,
and she killed
these three other people.
What are you telling me?
She killed these people for me?
And I'm supposed
to live with this?
I'll meet you at the car.
I called the lab.
They said you were here.
I heard you met Elaine.
Yeah, she's really something.
I didn't tell her about us,
if that's what you're wondering.
I'm really sorry, Sara.
Yeah, me, too.
I don't know what else to say.
I'll see you around.
♪ Childhood living ♪
♪ Is easy to do ♪
♪ The things that you wanted ♪
♪ I bought them for you ♪
♪ Graceless lady... ♪
You got plans?
Nope.
♪ You know who I am... ♪
You want to get a beer?
Drive.
♪ And wild horses
couldn't drag me away... ♪