( guns clicking )
( laughs ):
Jimmy,
stop staring.
It's okay, ma'am.
( tires screeching )
Up against the glass, now!
Come on. Let's go. Move it!
Move it! Come on. Let's go!
( woman screaming )
Let's go. Let's go! Up there!
Get near the glass. Don't move!
One peep, and you die.
The boy, too.
Hands on the wall, now!
Move it!
( screams )
Open it! Open it!
Open it!
( shouting )
( panting )
I have to get out of here!
Any one of you moves a muscle,
I'll blow you away.
( whimpering ):
Oh, my God!
( beeping )
( screaming )
( alarm ringing )
Got it! Go!
Go!
Let's go!
( police sirens blaring )
( gunshot )
( tires screeching )
( tires squealing )
( alarm ringing )
( alarm fades )
What a day to come
back to work.
Coming?
( alarm grows louder )
This crew
was in and out.
Three, maybe four guys,
depending on who you talk to.
Detective Lockwood
drew his weapon
protecting a woman and a child.
WILLOWS:
Wrong place, wrong time.
There is no right time
to kill a cop.
PHILLIPS:
I only see
one bullet wound
through the back.
Yeah, witnesses say
that he was, uh,
taken down
with a single shot.
Beveled edges on the inside.
The shot came from outside.
We need to get a picture
of this.
These guys
were pros.
How much did they get?
According to the tellers,
they weren't interested
in money.
What were they
interested in?
( electricity crackling
and hissing )
See the blast marks?
Charges were placed
in corner quadrants.
Four boxes up,
five across.
The rest looks like
collateral damage.
Whoever did this knew
precisely what they were after.
Well, the one good thing
about their precision...
it'll narrow our focus.
and Volkswagen.
On the road of life
there are passengers
and there are drivers.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
SIDLE ( muffled ):
I heard "officer down."
I didn't know
it was Lockwood.
BROWN ( muffled ):
Wonder what he was doing here.
He's supposed
to be off duty.
STOKES ( muffled ):
He was only
34 years old.
WILLOWS ( muffled ):
All right, good. All here.
We've got a lot of work to do.
Grissom...
( normal audio volume):
Grissom?
Sorry.
I was thinking.
Well, I was thinking
that we need to start
processing this bank.
Right.
I'll take
the safety deposit boxes.
Sara,
you're with me.
Radio car's
shot up pretty good.
I'll dig around
in there.
Take the cameras.
They made sure
we didn't have eyes.
Check the tape
anyway.
BRASS:
I think we found
the getaway vehicle.
Where?
Block from the off-ramp.
Coroner's en route.
The coroner?
The driver's dead.
( electricity crackling
and hissing )
Electric
blasting cap.
Brown leg wires feeding
into the grommet.
Means they could've used C4.
Utah, New Mexico,
Colorado, and Arizona.
Four corners.
What does that tell us?
Whatever they were looking for
was definitely in the center.
The Monroe Effect:
all force generated
towards one central area.
SIDLE:
How are we ever going
to find out what's missing?
GRISSOM:
I just found the detonator.
I'll get it fumed.
What have you got?
Radio car traveled
about 15 feet after being hit.
I followed the leakage back
to its original position.
Two in the hood,
one in the windshield,
Lockwood.
High power,
long range.
I'll take any part
of that bullet.
Oh, God.
Near
decapitation.
Wire's still around his neck.
BRASS:
The driver became
a liability
after the heist.
No honor among
thieves, I guess.
Tells us something
about them.
Hey, why are we stopping here?
( grunting )
Your job is finished.
( tires squealing )
Lockwood was a good cop.
It's too bad.
Grissom, I just talked
to Hodges.
That black substance
from the camera lens?
The FTIR spit back
magnesium aluminum,
silicate, talc,
methylparaben,
and sunscreen.
All of these chemicals
are consistent
with camouflage cream.
Blackface paint.
My guess
is the same stick
they used to cover up
that camera lens,
they used to paint
their faces with.
I just found
an eyelash in it.
Gil.
Just coming
to see you.
I pulled the bullet
from Cyrus Lockwood.
Fully intact,
well preserved.
Well, you didn't
have to bring this over.
We could've picked it up.
I wanted to.
Every day I see people
I don't know,
but I saw a lot of Lockwood,
and I did get to know him.
I felt like I owed it to him.
Thanks, Doctor.
( computer beeping )
We got a bullet.
We got prints.
Getaway driver.
Larry Whiting.
29.
He was convicted of assault
and drunk and disorderly
five years ago.
Did some time.
Occupation:
valet at the Rampart.
Isn't that one
of Sam Braun's hotels?
Mm-hmm.
You have to have
a non-gaming work card
to park cars
at a Vegas casino.
How does a guy with
a criminal record get one?
He doesn't.
Unless he was juiced in
by Sam Braun.
Well, it is his hotel.
It's his call, ultimately.
Yeah?
Well, it's our case,
so it's our call.
Mmm.
Check it out.
I may be compromised.
You know I have a personal
relationship with the guy.
You'll be fine.
( coins clanging )
( slot machines ringing )
I'm going to have
to talk to H.R.
about this Larry Whiting.
Human Resources is never
supposed to process
anyone with a record.
Well, his record caught
up with him, Sam.
We suspect
he was involved
in the First Monument Bank
robbery.
Getaway driver... except
everyone got away but him.
I have to tell you, Mugs,
name doesn't ring a bell.
Sam...
( laughs )
That's like you telling me
when I was a kid
that you were too tired
to drive home every night
when you were sleeping
with my mother.
Well, you can't fault a fellow
for wanting to be
with his two best girls.
All right.
Where is all of this leading?
( inhales )
Well, last year,
one of your cocktail waitresses
is murdered.
Still unsolved.
She worked at another one
of my hotels--
the Whiskey Town.
And this Whiting guy
worked here at the Rampart...
They're both your hotels....
How does that look for business?
Mugs, I got a P.R. department
that deals with that.
When one white tiger
killed another one
in the Secret Garden
at the Mirage,
the P.R. Department
had it buried
on page 16E,
under the car ads, about...
this big.
Right. They made it go away.
Some things
are people's business.
Some things aren't.
Well, this is my business.
It's not going to go away.
Then I'll be rooting for you.
BRASS:
Las Vegas Police.
Manager said he lived alone.
If this getaway driver's
stupid enough to get whacked
by his partners,
he's stupid enough
to leave something behind.
BRASS:
This whole neighborhood's
stupid.
Whew.
Sixty grand a year
for jockeying cars?
I'm in the wrong line of work.
Well, look on the bright side:
you're still alive.
BRASS:
Bedroom's a bust.
What do you got?
I got two $5,000 stacks
from the Rampart.
Sam Braun's hotel.
Um, Lockwood's bullet
on the right,
and the cop car bullet...
what's left of that cop car
bullet's on the left.
Both projectiles with 308s.
Consistent with the M1A.
Long gun.
Mm-hmm.
And long guns
are only registered
to the person who makes
the initial purchase...
and the serial numbers
aren't recorded.
( sighs )
Impossible to trace,
so it's a dead end.
Well, forensically, yeah,
but not cognitively.
See, shooting someone
from long range,
and taking out the engine
of a radio car
while it is hauling ass...
You're looking
at one sharp shooter.
And that kind of training
only comes from...
The military.
Thank you!
♪ We fall ♪
♪ Sign ♪
♪ A sign ♪
♪ We fall ♪
♪ Sign ♪
♪ A sign ♪
♪ We fall ♪
♪ Sign ♪
♪ A sign ♪
♪ Here I lay ♪
♪ Our questions answered ♪
♪ Fear inside ♪
♪ Is truth uncovered ♪
♪ While we fight ♪
♪ Sharing in the other... ♪
WILLOW:
Wow.
Almost looks good as new.
Kind of.
This was the epitome
of precision.
The outer rim of boxes
sustained the most damage
The intent was not to blow out
the 23 surrounding boxes,
but to preserve the sanctity
of the center box.
Box 729? It's history.
It's the only thing
that's gone.
That's the box
they were after.
And we still don't know
what was inside.
( sighs )
What is up with
the bank manager?
We've been
waiting forever.
Hey.
( muffled ):
How long have we known
each other?
In days, months, or years?
I'm serious here.
Can you hear me?
Sorry I'm late.
Been on the phone all night
with corporate...
not to mention I had
a gun in my face.
So, you want to
know the lessees
of some of our
safe deposit boxes?
Oh, not some,
just one.
Box 729.
Why don't you just
hold up a touch?
I want to help
you, but...
you're going to have
to give me a court order.
Oh, no worries.
Box 729 lessee
is Benny Murdock.
Benny Murdock?
You know him?
Yeah.
MAN:
Benny.
He was my first doorman
at the Whiskey Town.
A year later,
I made him a casino host
at Pike's Gambling Hall.
Within six months,
he had all the play
at the Tangiers.
( laughs ):
Six months.
Became my right arm
when we opened the Rampart.
I never thought
I would outlive him.
He died a couple
of weeks ago, right?
Brain aneurysm.
You never know
when you're going to go.
All those memories...
Benny, we're going
to have a great summer.
( woman giggling )
Did Larry Whiting... know Benny?
Everybody who was anybody
knew Benny,
including you.
Informally.
Informally enough
for him to direct the high-end
whales your way
when you were dancing.
( laughs ):
Ooh...
That is
old Vegas, Sam.
Sunset on that time.
I hear you and Benny had
a little sunset of your own.
A falling out
about six months ago.
WOMAN ON INTERCOM:
Mr. Braun, it's "Bravado"
regarding BJ 19.
If you will
excuse me,
I have to take care of that.
Yeah?
( muffled and echoing ):
Raise the limit,
and change the cards.
If he wins three double downs
in a row, call me back.
We'll send "Mr. Happy."
I'm sorry. Where were we?
Benny.
Sorry. That's off limits...
but I was with him
in the hospital
when he died.
We made our peace,
if it's for the record.
You wouldn't happen to know
what he kept inside
his safe deposit box,
would you?
You'll have to ask him.
Well, I wish we could.
If you'll excuse me,
someone is robbing me
downstairs.
You know what "off
the record" means,
don't you, Greg?
Yeah.
GRISSOM:
Albert,
got a minute?
Sure. What's up?
I'd like a second opinion.
Boy, I wish you'd
come to me sooner.
Your condition's
pretty far along.
Why did you wait?
( sighs )
I hoped it would go away.
Doesn't your mother
have this condition?
Yeah. It's hereditary.
I know.
I wasn't rational.
( laughs )
Look, Gil, I'm not going
to preach to you.
You came to me, but...
doctor to doctor...
there's a chance
the bone deposits have spread
into the inner ear,
in which case,
your hearing loss
will eventually
be permanent.
If I were you,
I'd schedule surgery
as soon as possible.
SANDERS:
You know the eyelash
Warrick found
embedded in the black
greasepaint--
I extracted the DNA, ran it.
CODIS gave me a, uh,
Mongolian beef.
I'm sorry.
What does that mean?
That means he got nothing.
There, try these, big guy.
Training wheels.
Thanks.
STOKES:
Hey, guys, guys,
let's focus
on the robbers.
Grissom?
What do you think?
I think we're giving these guys
too much credit.
They're experts
at robbing banks,
not experts
at concealing evidence.
Well, unless the answer's
in that fortune cookie,
what's the plan?
Do you ever wonder
how the fortune
gets inside the cookie?
I know.
Of course you do.
The cookie comes out of a press,
like a tortilla,
and then some lady puts
the fortune
in the center of the dough,
and then folds the dough
around a piece of metal,
and then folds it again.
That's the answer.
( beeping )
Robert Rubio.
Work card.
Non-gaming.
He's in the
hotel business.
Rampart.
Hey, didn't that other guy
work at the...
Run him through the
military database.
Why?
Just run it.
After that, give us an address.
All clear.
It's all yours, boss.
Come on.
Let's see what's cooking.
Whoo!
WILLOWS:
Oh, well,
that is... one example
of the evidence going up
in smoke.
This guy's a piece
of work, huh?
( phone ringing )
( metal clanging )
One of the black
coats, you think?
Box 729.
Fire-resistant.
It's some kind of fabric.
Silk, maybe.
What do you make of that?
Out of context,
I don't know.
( phone ringing )
WILLOWS:
Pink Panther.
Well, Clouseau,
how does blood get
in a safe deposit box?
Maybe has something to do
with this fabric.
Mr. Nine Volt, Rob Rubio--
ex-military,
security expert.
Went to work for casino owner
Sam Braun
when one of his soft count
cronies got caught
skimming the skim,
so... all roads
lead to Rome, except,
in this case... the Rampart.
( camera clicking )
Triple homicide
in the desert.
Old-time Vegas.
We found Tommy "The Aspirin"
out here.
Remember him?
Used to make his boss'
headaches disappear.
Until they made him disappear.
I think this is the origin
of the word "termination."
There's the
corporate way,
and the way
of the gun.
High-powered rifle.
Close range.
Visible gunpowder.
( gunshot )
This guy got it
in the chest, too.
( gunshot )
And this one took it
in the back.
( gunshot )
This one's carrying a Glock.
Never got a chance to use it.
WILLOWS:
Well, all three
were carrying,
so they're not tied up,
and they're still armed.
They didn't fly here.
Where's their car?
It's not a dump job.
Killer drove them here,
killed them, and drove away.
BRASS:
They knew
their attacker.
Never let a man
do a woman's job.
What do you mean?
They didn't get
all their makeup off.
BRASS:
Where's he going?
WILLOWS:
Let's just hope
he stops.
Look familiar?
WILLOWS:
Bloodstain.
Rainbow-colored thread.
Safe deposit box.
Those guys are definitely
the bank robbers.
Where's the fourth guy?
The guy who's rapidly becoming
a mass murderer.
Rob Rubio.
Grissom, hey.
Grissom, hey,
just tested the bullets
from your trio in the desert.
( muffled ):
Same GRCs as the bullet
from Lockwood.
Fired from the same rifle.
Slow down, Bobby.
I'm sorry.
I just got excited.
You don't get to see
many .30-caliber rounds
used in crimes, but, uh...
( door banging open )
You rang?
Uh, yeah.
The, uh, blood flecks
from the safe deposit box--
two distinct samples.
I only got one hit, though.
Uh, the primary sample
belongs to Vivian Verona,
a cocktail waitress.
She was killed
on the top floor
of the old
Pike's Gambling Hall
about two years ago.
Here's the report.
Multiple
puncture wounds,
different depths,
possibly two knives...
I've pulled the crime scene
photos for you, too.
Case still pending.
Murder weapon was never found.
Now, the secondary blood
sample came back N.D.
Uh, could be the killer.
You always say murder's messy.
Greg, your hands are shaking.
No, they're not.
Hold your hands out.
Uh...
they've been shaking
ever since...
I can't really make it stop.
Is it affecting your work?
Well, if I was
a bomb expert, maybe.
No, I...
I think I have it under control.
It'll stop.
If you need me, I'll be around.
Okay.
I have your scarf
back from Sanders.
I need you to open
this evidence bag
and cut me
an identical piece of fabric.
You want me to replicate
the blood pattern?
Yeah.
You guys need a hand?
Warrick, hand me those scissors.
Nick, give me that apple.
But I didn't get any lunch.
Give me
the apple.
You're not supposed
to eat in here.
Two puncture wounds, right?
Scissors.
That's what was wrapped
in the scarf.
BROWN:
These don't look like
your ordinary household pair.
STOKES:
No, man, look
at the blades.
They're almost double
the size of the handles.
What's the purpose
of scissors that long?
Murder.
I hear scissors, I hear murder.
What did I miss?
We may have the murder weapon.
SIDLE:
Hey, Vivian Verona
worked for Sam Braun--
a cocktail waitress
at Pike's
Gambling Hall.
Murdered the night before
it was imploded
in a penthouse suite.
Sounds like somebody wanted her
to disappear in the rubble.
Bet you Braun hired his own
clean-up crew for that one.
SIDLE:
The pyro guys
found her on their
last walk-through.
They assigned a CSI,
but the case ran cold
before it even got started.
There was no suspect
and no motive.
Warrick,
enhance the blade area.
BROWN:
Hmm, let me see
if I can flip it around
so we're not looking
at an eye chart.
GRISSOM:
R-P-R-T.
Rampart.
WILLOWS:
He's not returning
any of my phone calls.
I just need to confront
this Sam Braun business
once and for all.
I'll drive.
I'm not going with you.
What do you mean?
I'm scheduled for surgery
at Desert Palm.
Surgery?
Your hearing?
Yep.
I'm sorry.
I'm not. Has to be done.
What can I do?
Nothing. I'm fine.
Take care of the case.
Oh, eh, mm...
That's it?
That's it.
Um...
good luck.
You must really like
the ham steak at the Primm.
One more mile north--
you're gone forever.
They got good ham.
That's good to know.
I'll know what to get you
for your last meal...
for killing a cop.
You know the rifle
we found in your trunk?
The bullets match one we pulled
out of a friend of mine--
Detective Cyrus Lockwood.
Tough losing one of your own.
You lost three of yours.
Ballistics made
a match there, too.
So, you're ex-military.
That why Sam Braun
hired you
to be head of security
at the Rampart?
You asking me,
or you telling me?
I'm telling you.
My guess is Sam needed
a job done, he came to you.
You know,
when I get out of here,
I'm going to take pleasure
in putting air in your head.
Let me put a fact in yours.
You left a lot of yourself
behind, killer.
( gunshots )
So, here's the deal.
You give up your boss,
you get to spend the rest
of your life in a jail cell,
not on Death Row.
I'll take Death Row.
I'll live longer.
WILLOWS:
Tangiers,
Pike's Gambling Hall...
Where are
the Rampart scissors, Sam?
I think they went to one
of those silent auctions.
You know, the kind
where you put a number down
and remain anonymous.
Uh-huh.
I'm sure they went
to a good cause.
How much money they make?
More than
I anticipated.
I think that we're past
playing games, Sam.
I need the truth.
You sure about that?
Oh, yeah.
Now more than ever.
Benny killed Vivian.
He caught her
cheating on him...
with me.
( gasps )
I can explain.
When I heard he was dying,
I went to see him.
He told me he killed her
with my scissors
from a ribbon-cutting ceremony.
He always kept
the scissors--
had them shadow-boxed for me.
He stashed them
in the safe deposit box.
Why would Benny do that?
Why would Benny murder Vivian
and then keep
the incriminating evidence,
not even attempt
to wash off the blood?
You're asking me
to answer on his behalf?
I don't know.
Maybe he was
paranoid.
Figured you would
drag Lake Mead.
Let me just get this straight.
To protect Benny
after he's already dead,
you hire Rob Rubio
and three cronies to commit
federal bank robbery
to steal back
a pair of scissors?
They weren't just
any pair of scissors.
They were tied to a legacy.
If Benny goes down, I go down.
40 years...
building a reputation-- gone.
Games are meant
to be played downstairs,
not upstairs...
so I ask Rob to take care of it.
We have the safe deposit box
in our possession, Sam,
along with
the bloodstained sash
the scissors
were wrapped in.
We recovered two
different blood samples--
one belonging to Vivian,
and the other unknown.
I guess I didn't have a good
enough reason until now, but...
I tested my DNA
against the unknown
sample.
( sighs )
And wouldn't you know...
there were
seven alleles in common.
That supposed to mean something?
It means that you and I
are biologically related.
You killed her, Sam...
and Benny covered for you.
Part of the old
double standard.
No woman that you're with
is ever going to be
with another man.
I swear on your mother...
it didn't happen that way.
Oh, now, that holds
a lot of weight.
To this day my mother still sits
at home waiting for your call.
Do you really think
I could murder someone?
Science...
tells me that you did.
So, yes, I do.
It's just such a lousy way to
find out that you're my father.
They're preparing the surgery
right now, Mr. Grissom.
They'll be ready
for you in moments.
WILLOWS:
Hey.
What are you doing here?
I just wanted
to see you.
And I didn't want you to go in
without wishing you good luck.
Thank you.
For being here.
I don't need that.
and Volkswagen.