( heavy breathing )
Okay, this is where
it got weird.
( panting )
I've processed hundreds
of bogus snuff films.
But this, this one
just felt different.
Yeah, it should.
Arterial spray was real.
GRISSOM:
It's not fake blood.
It's human.
That was a murder...
on 16 millimeter.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
Has this pornographer
sent you film
to be developed
in the past?
I'm sure he has.
We get raw film
from hundreds of
adult film companies.
No names, just
those private boxes.
You can film porn, develop it,
sell it, buy it
but you can't send it
through the U.S. mail.
I've got several envelopes here
from various
private shipping companies.
We'll be taking those with us
as well.
Whatever.
( cell phone rings )
Grissom.
It's Brass.
I got a d.b. out
on Henderson Road.
I'm already on a case.
Yeah, well, reconsider.
I mean, these ants came flying
out of the body.
They're taking chunks
out of the coroner.
The CSI day guy says he's not
going near the body again!
They're fire ants, Brass.
Keep everyone away
from the colony.
They're evidence.
Reconsider.
Bring bug spray.
No bug spray.
BRASS:
So a kid was driving along
and spotted
the tool box.
He thought it would
look good in
his pickup truck.
So he looked inside
and freaked out.
Ran to call for help.
Hey... Grissom
you ever see anything
like this?
GRISSOM:
Well, any species
that finds itself
in a place it
doesn't belong
can do this kind
of damage.
What are you using?
Cortisone.
That'll help.
You know, I heard
that these things
can kill a deer.
Is that...
Is that right?
Well, with enough colonies
they can kill people.
What about
our person?
Well, only if they also learned
how to put him in a box
and dump him in a ditch.
( coughing )
Man or woman?
Ant hill.
They're using this body
as a colony site.
I'm going to have
to take this box
and the specimen back to the lab
as is.
These insects are evidence.
I followed up on the
private mail depot
for our snuff movie.
The place has got
over 1,000 boxes
no records of renters
and they deal
in cash only.
Dead trail.
Yeah.
I got Archie to digitize
that film
blow up a head shot
of our victim.
I find any
missing persons
that match her description,
I'll beep you.
Thanks, Sulik.
Find any fingerprints?
I should be able to.
Imaging components
on a filmstrip
are held together by gelatin.
Same stuff
that makes Jell-O jiggle
but they're smudged.
I can tell you
that the film was
manufactured in 2002
by a big company.
Homicide's contacting them
now to get a buyer's list.
Won't help.
Pornos buy "short ends" from
legitimate clearing houses.
Saves money and they're
impossible to trace.
Really?
I pulled a porno ring
using teenage girls
a couple years ago.
Learned all you want to know
about the adult
entertainment industry.
Hell of a way to go.
I always thought
that snuff films
were an urban myth
I mean, outside
of urban Bangkok.
FBI's official position on
snuff films in the U.S. of A?
No such thing.
What's their
unofficial position?
Single film goes
for 100 grand...
original negative.
And this snuff filmmaker
decided to send his film
out to get processed.
Greedy doesn't mean smart.
( grunting )
Come on, you bitch!
I'm allergic to red ants,
you know.
Yeah? I put them
on my eggs.
If they're dead,
I hope.
Something tells me
that isn't Black Flag.
Ecozone Pyrethrum.
Toxic to ants, fleas
roaches
and silverfish.
And how does
an entomologist feel
about putting ants to death?
I view them as martyrs
in a scientist's holy war.
I see.
Man without a face.
Timeline for death?
Hard to say between
the insects and the elements.
At least a year.
It smells more like two.
Multiple fractures
of both clavicles.
Right clavicle healed...
broken four months before death.
Left was more recent...
hairline fractures
are still present.
Give me a hand turning him over,
will you?
What are these?
I'm not sure.
Sharp impact wounds
to the interscapular.
Same trauma here
in the vertebrel.
Stab wounds?
I can't say.
Uh, maybe some round weapon
of some sort.
What, two feet apart?
More like 18 inches.
What?
A pupa case.
Is that a good thing
or a bad thing?
It's a good thing.
If I can postdate the pupa
I can establish
an entomological timeline.
Okay, all right,
let's run this back again
from the beginning.
This time
without the sound.
All right.
Stop.
Can you zoom in on his back?
What is that?
A mole?
Non-cancerous.
You think?
Too bad, the bastard.
This room is like
a dime a dozen
It could be
anywhere in Vegas.
Between the drapes
can you get any other detail
outside of that window?
Uh...
I'll reverse the polarization
see if we can get any more
information from this frame.
That looks
like a blob
outside of the window.
It's spherical.
Blow it up.
Times ten.
The Stratosphere Tower.
South face maybe?
Using that Stratosphere Tower
as a point of reference
could you triangulate
and pinpoint the street
that this was filmed on?
I can.
SULIK:
Hotel's in receivership.
The security guy says
the elevator still works.
BROWN:
We're going to need
to talk to him.
Soon as he gets off the phone
with the owner.
What's up?
Oh, nothing.
Only difference between kitsch
and beautiful
is time.
SANDERS:
Heard you're doing a
timeline on the ant man.
Slow day in DNA, Greg?
Yeah.
You know, I, uh...
I can take notes.
Very good.
Go right ahead.
Week zero: body dies.
Week two:
green blowflies arrive...
and leave
their pupal casings.
Week four: black soldier flies
move in.
At week 28... they leave
their pupa casings.
Now, the presence of winged
reproductive fire ants
suggests that their colony
was in existence
for at least a year.
Now, since we found
no more pupa casings
after the black soldier flies
left at week 28
we know that this is when
the fire ants must've
first arrived.
So, calculating
the gestation period
between ants and flies,
we get...
One year plus the 28 weeks...
the guy's been dead 19 months.
Very good.
It's an approximation,
but it's a start.
Well... Sara,
you take that one.
Warrick, you go there,
I'll go in here.
Hey, guys?
We got it.
Somebody moved out
all the furniture.
And painted the wall.
If they can't see it,
we can't, huh?
Arterial spray.
There's a void.
Could be a face?
WILLOWS:
Yeah, maybe.
How does somebody cross the line
where killing a woman
is a turn-on?
Oh, I don't think snuff makers
cross a line, Sara.
I think they start
on the other side of it.
Biology determining pathology.
Yeah, some people
were just born bad.
Where's that security guard?
SULIK:
How long you been
a day guard here?
Four months.
But I don't know anything
about this murder
you're talking about.
Do you anything about
who painted Room 918?
No idea.
You should try
a scalp conditioner.
What?
Your dandruff.
Oh, my bad... primer.
Alkyd-based.
Never comes out
in the wash
but you already
know that.
Warrick?
You were in that snuff film.
You stabbed that girl.
I let them use the room
to make a movie,
that's all.
Yeah, we saw you
in the movie.
You and your nice mole.
The guy threw in another $200
if I had sex with the girl.
She was hot,
so I figured why not?
Did her and left.
She was breathing fine.
So when you came back
in the room
and you saw the blood
on the wall
did you think
to call the police?
I didn't want
to lose my job.
Oh, touching.
Arrest him.
Turn around.
I see you're now learning
to cook for yourself.
Well, I had to, Teri
I heard you
were married.
Hopefully not
to a criminalist.
( chuckles ):
You think I'm stupid?
He's a teacher.
Well, congratulations.
Thank you.
So what's the special occasion?
I have someone I'd like you
to introduce me to.
What, did I miss something?
Actually, yes.
( forceps clang )
It's a dung beetle.
Probably hid
in the nasal cavity.
The ants ate everything
but the exoskeleton.
Mm-hmm.
So he was probably
murdered
near some large animals.
Maybe a farm or a zoo.
Anyway, as to who,
I'll leave that up to you.
Will do.
Damn, security guard
was telling the truth.
There is another guy there.
He's almost
one and three-quarter inches
taller than the security guard.
Our minds must've filled
in the negative space.
Look, the security guard
just left the room.
You see the door shadow
right there.
The camera stopped moving.
That's because he's not
behind it, he's in front of it.
Well, then, that's our guy.
There's got to be
some way to I.D. him.
I have enlarged
and re-enlarged every frame.
There's no tats,
there's no birthmarks, nothing.
What about the rest of the room?
The film picks up everything
there is to see, Catherine.
We've seen everything.
Maybe there's a short end.
What?
Pornos use short ends of film
which means they never know when
the film is going to run out.
Roll out.
Camera slows down,
the last frame stutters
gets hit with more light.
BROWN:
So there's more visual
information on the negative.
Right.
Good editors
always cut the roll out.
WILLOWS:
So all your editors' cuttings
are in there?
Yep. Negatives
and unused dailies.
Collection guy comes
by once a week.
Silver on the film
makes it environmentally unsafe
for landfill, so...
Be nice if people
were as concerned
about the women in these films.
I am the one who called y'all,
remember?
Knock yourselves
out, ladies.
Thank you.
Bins of sin.
Well, looks like
mostly 35 millimeter.
Our 16 should've
settled at the bottom.
What the heck is that?
What did Trace say?
Carbon steel.
There was some rust on it.
Carbon steel?
19th century.
Mostly used for
surgical instruments.
Well, you found
some stab wounds
on the vic, right?
Underneath all those ants?
Maybe it's somebody's
old scalpel.
This prong-like extension
could be part of
a repeating pattern.
Geometrical extrapolation?
That would give us
possibilities.
You got a pencil?
From the tip down, the slope
looks to be slightly curved.
Now, if I extend
that trace outward...
What do you think?
Blade of a saw.
Keep doing the math,
maybe we won't have to guess.
You see how the base of
the fragment curves downward?
Suggesting something circular.
Repeating pattern.
Circular saw, maybe.
( sighs )
This doesn't seem sharp enough
for a saw.
Wait a minute.
I've seen one of these
before, man.
A spur... cheap spur.
What's that old
cowboy expression?
Got to see a man about a horse.
That reminds me.
I got to see a woman
about a face.
Yee-haw.
You notice all the guys
in these movies
are wearing condoms?
Yeah, industry policy.
Ever since '98.
Even have a quarantine list:
who's positive, who's not.
And that security guy
wore one, too.
Pretty surprising
for unregulated porn.
Maybe she made him wear one.
I got it.
You did?
I got it, I found it.
Thank God.
Hot frame, all right.
I still can't see who it is.
You can see a little more
of the room, though.
There's a small table
and a lamp in the left corner.
Good eye, Sara.
Yeah, that kitsch lamp.
Somebody moved it out
to the lobby.
I'll have Warrick go back
to the hotel and grab it.
Tissue depth markers.
21 of them, right?
16 actually.
Excluding five
nasal markers.
Like I said.
This one's very interesting.
The occiput
the bump on the back
center of the head
unusually flat.
The eyes have epicanthal folds.
A triangular flap of skin
that gives a vaguely
Asian appearance.
You see how the bridge
of the nose is poorly developed?
Almost too small
for the size of his head.
The ears seem
slightly odd.
Like the nose
they too, are
disproportionate
to the head.
Almost childlike.
These elements are small
for the head
which, in itself,
is almost too short and wide.
Your victim was born
with trisomy
of the twenty-first chromosome.
Down's Syndrome.
BRASS:
So I sent out a community fax
to every Down's Syndrome link
in Clark
and the surrounding counties.
Special Olympics-type groups,
societies, schools
and I got lucky.
Randy Traschel, age 25.
Been missing for 17 months.
I guess my ants
were off a little.
"Last employer:
Las Vegas Ranch."
Horses. Dung beetles.
Hey, where's the tote board?
Every time I see a horse,
I want to place a bet.
Smells like Belmont Park,
doesn't it?
You ever ridden a horse,
Grissom?
Nope, just
roller coasters.
( horse neighing )
( cheering )
Howdy.
Pete Banson.
Ranch manager.
Howdy.
Jim Brass, Las Vegas Police.
This is Gil Grissom,
Nick Stokes
of the crime lab.
What seems to be the trouble?
Have you ever seen this man?
Yeah, he's one
of my stall muckers.
Hired him about a year
and a half ago.
A little slow in the head,
but got the work done.
And all of a sudden,
he up and disappeared
never heard from him
since then.
( horse neighs )
Did he ever ride horses for you,
Mr. Banson?
No, he just mucked the stalls
and went home.
Who mucks your stalls now?
Look, guys, am I in
some kind of trouble here?
A former employee of yours
was murdered.
Now, who mucks?
Enrique. He's an illegal.
Shocking.
Where is he?
There's the lamp I got
from the lobby.
The bulb is red...
in the film and here.
Guy thinks he's Zalman King,
playing with the lighting.
I guess he was going
for a certain look.
You know, if I had screwed
a hot light bulb
I'd probably lick my fingers.
Saliva.
Guy replaced it with a red bulb.
Got residual saliva on it.
Process for DNA,
run it through CODIS.
( doorbell rings )
Douglas Sampson?
Yeah.
The same Douglas Sampson
who did three years
for sexual assault
and battery?
( coughs )
Did. Past tense.
We want to talk to you
about a recent homicide
at the Mandolin Tower Hotel,
off Fremont.
I'm working.
Take a break.
SAMPSON:
Take ten.
Give it a rest, guys.
I bet I could guess
your exact height.
What?
That guy out front
just confirmed
you shot a snuff film
with this girl
at the Mandolin Tower Hotel.
I've stayed there
over the years.
I never saw her with that guy
out front.
We've got you on
film, killing her.
If you had me from any angle
I could be identified
you would've arrested me
already.
( snickers )
We've got ourselves
a film student here.
I'm one of the best in
adult film and I'm going to be
making the jump to mainstream,
you watch.
Financed by a snuff film?
You have no right
to be in my house.
I'm not breaking
any laws.
I have a permit
for adult film production.
You leave now or I'm going
to file a complaint.
( sniffles )
Getting a cold?
Maybe you should raise
the heat.
I'm sure they wouldn't mind.
WILLOWS:
Hey, what do you got?
This is Sampson's
car, right?
Some soil up in
his wheel well.
He washed the tire
and forgot the well.
WILLOWS:
Butterscotch?
Yeah.
Remember that body dump
a couple years back?
Yeah.
Down near
the Colorado?
Bidahochy Range.
Butterscotch-colored soil.
I'll radio the sheriff up there.
And the park rangers.
Great.
BRASS:
You never met
this man?
No.
Stop the shoveling.
Take a closer look.
All I know about him
is they call him "Stubs."
Stubs.
What is that,
some kind of nickname?
I guess.
I hear the cowboys
joking about him.
I think they call him that
because of his fingers.
BRASS:
Did the other cowboys
ever make fun of him?
I really don't know.
Do you ride, Mr. Vasquez?
Every day.
You wear spurs when you ride?
When I'm breaking
a horse, yes.
BRASS:
You don't call this
breaking a horse, do you?
I forgot to take them off.
I'm going to need to take a look
at those spurs, Mr. Vasquez.
Enrique said he
got those boots and
spurs from Hero's Row.
Mm-hmm. That's where
the cowboys toss all
their unwanted gear.
And they just leave
them there for
anyone to pick up?
It's either that
or Goodwill.
Hmm. Mr. Banson, the
Pro Rodeo Association
banned sharp rowels
on spurs back in
the early '70s
because they were found
to be cruel to horses.
Yeah, I know all about that.
I don't particularly
agree with it
'cause as far
as I'm concerned
horses are on this earth
to service human beings.
There's an order
to things.
Well, somebody on your ranch
is stuck in the '70s.
Do you have any idea
who this spur could belong to?
Billy Rattison.
Pro bronc rider.
( phone rings )
Brown.
MAN:
I think we got
your snuff film girl.
Where?
By the river.
Okay, I'll be right there.
Warrick stick you
with post?
He's working evidence
from the riverbed.
You going to be
able to I.D. her?
Already did,
from her dental records.
Susan Hodap, 26.
Exsanguination from
a trans-section of
the carotid artery.
Slicing stab.
Any chance of finding any
serration marks on the bone?
To tie to a knife?
Eh, that'll entail a boil,
but sure, I can try.
What I can tell you conclusively
is that Susan Hodap was already
on borrowed time.
I tapped her
cerebral spinal fluid
didn't wait for a batch,
had the lab run it solo.
She was HIV positive.
Susan Hodap...
There it is.
Tested positive six months ago.
I can't believe that porn
actors' monthly health records
are on the Internet.
Yeah, right.
The rule is, the actor
tests positive twice
they go on permanent quarantine.
That's why she ended up
in that snuff film.
She got bounced out
of regular porn.
Walked right into
her own death scene.
The thing is...
porn director may have, too.
( horses whinnying )
This would be
a pretty cool little truck
if it weren't for
the shiny new toolbox.
Yeah. And it might be his.
See you boys
are back again.
Mr. Banson, is this
Billy Rattison's truck?
Yes, sir. It is.
We need to speak
with him.
I don't know nothing
about no damn retard.
He wasn't a "retard,"
Mr. Rattison.
He had what we call
Down's Syndrome.
I don't care what he had.
Always sticking his nose
where it don't belong.
You left this?
I left it on the post.
I don't want it in my pocket
when I ride.
Damn!
( snuff splats )
The, uh, toolbox in your
truck, is that new?
Nope. Bought it a
couple months ago.
Somebody stole the last one.
See, we got a big problem
with that around here
the help walking off with stuff.
Nick, where did you
acquire this photo?
Pro Rodeo Association.
That is you.
Yeah.
Do you remember
where this was taken?
Looks like Bronc Finals,
Wichita, Kansas.
Spent a month there
training for the finals.
But you leave here normally,
right?
Mm-hmm.
What month, exactly?
( heavy sigh )
This photo here...
uh, March, 2000.
19 months ago.
STOKES:
Your ants put the time of death
at 19 months
Rattison puts being out of town
yet Randy Traschel's
been missing 17 months
so... ( chuckles ) now what?
We need a more precise
timeline.
Yeah... so...
back to the bugs?
On to the rust.
Ah.
( grunting )
Why are you
throwing phone books?
'Cause a beaker gets glass
all over the place.
What's wrong?
It's this curtain
that the porn girl
was found wrapped in.
I've got no prints,
no second donor.
I've got nothing to link this
porn guy to the girl's murder.
It's just driving me nuts.
I'm fine.
I'm sorry. Are you okay?
Yeah. You missed
me by a mile.
We may have something.
Really.
Right here.
I wanted to show you.
When he's stabbing her
she's bleeding all over him.
Well, a void proves that,
but we still can't
prove it's him.
Yeah, but her blood might.
Catherine and I suspect
transference.
She had HIV.
Well, how are we going to get
a sample of Sampson's blood?
Warrant, based on
the butterscotch dirt
that you found on his car.
Oh. I like that.
You might want to apologize
to the phone book.
GRISSOM:
We sliced the shard
into layers of 100 microns
to measure the level
of oxidation.
Moisture from the body
hits the carbon steel
and then corrosion begins.
And we can be certain that
there was moisture right away.
So it's like slicing
the mold off of bread.
And measuring it.
The rust penetrated
the 13th layer
and just barely
in the 14th.
Archie, run the weather.
National Weather Service
for Las Vegas.
Average relative humidity
30.29.
Temperature 22.61 Celsius.
So, corrosion
versus time...
March, 2000.
Spur exposure time
was exactly 17 months.
And we can testify
to this.
Missing persons were right.
The ants were off.
Yeah, so was Rattison.
He was in town.
Two feet.
We have reason
to believe
the wounds that
killed Randy Traschel
were made by one
of your bulls.
That's why we cut the horns,
to prevent such.
We're looking
for horns with
points attached.
Yeah. We need to see
your other bulls.
Curly's the only
one I got.
What do you all want now?
BRASS:
We're waiting on you,
actually.
Mr. Rattison, we have reason
to believe you were in town
the month that Randy Traschel
was murdered.
Could you tell us
what used to be here?
My belt buckles.
Somebody stole it
last year, like I said.
You do get a lot of stuff
stolen, don't you?
Mind if we look
around your truck?
Sure.
Don't get any tobacco juice
on my shoe.
Got a tape measure?
18 inches.
Phenolphthalein.
Positive for blood.
Looks like the only thing
stolen around here
was Randy Traschel's life.
( horse neighing )
What you laughing at, huh?
You want to come
over here and try it?
( chuckling )
( laughter )
By the way
the definition of
the word "retard"
is "to hinder" or "to
hold someone back."
I think your life is
about to become retarded.
Okay, one more time,
for the record:
You have never had
sexual intercourse
with Susan Hodap?
I told you, I've never
even met her.
I know, but
I got to ask.
You've never
had sex with her?
Not ever.
You still have those chills,
Mr. Sampson?
Feeling hot, achy?
Back of your
throat scratchy?
Yeah, it is.
Original flu.
Happens at the onset
of HIV.
Seroconversion.
Usually presents
two to six weeks
after the exchange
of fluids.
Exchange of fluids?
That temperature is
your body working up
a resistance to the virus.
HIV? Me?
Now, come on.
You just took my blood
a few days ago.
A private lab can
run a virus test
within a day.
CDC doesn't
broadcast that.
Tests are
very expensive.
We dipped into the budget
just for you.
You're playing me.
I don't have HIV.
Susan Hodap had it.
The exact same strain
that you have.
We had that lab do
what's called
a phylogenetic analysis
of your HIV's DNA
and Susan's.
SIDLE:
As you can see,
the genes are identical.
Which means Susan gave it
directly to you.
But we never had sex.
You did stab her, though.
And at that moment...
her arterial blood
hit your eyes
entering your body through
the conjunctival membrane.
Non-sexual transmission
is extremely difficult
but obviously it's possible.
Susan's blood was absorbed
into your bloodstream.
WILLOWS:
Where the new HIV cells
immediately started attaching
to your
healthy white blood cells.
Gets inside one, replicates
about 2,000 times.
Disables the host cell,
pinches back out
infecting more good cells...
lowering your immune system
until your body loses
its ability
to fight off even
the simplest invader.
Of course, the strains
will have changed by then
and you and Susan Hodap will
have a different strain of HIV.
The sooner you
see a doctor
the better your chances
for longevity.
But for now, we got you.
You killed her.
I guess she killed you back.