MAN ( over radio ):
We have a high-speed chase
in progress.
( sirens wailing )
( thudding, tires squealing )
He is going in a tunnel.
What's your stand of a pursuit?
The suspect become intoxicated.
We will maintain.
Over.
( sizzling )
Driver, cut the engine
and throw the keys
out the window.
Driver, cut the engine
and throw the keys
out the window!
GRISSOM:
Excuse us.
Excuse me, sir.
Thank you.
Death-- the cheapest
show in Vegas.
Yeah, it doesn't surprise me.
You remember the MGM fire?
We found people burned
to their slot machines
'cause they wouldn't
leave the action.
Only in Vegas.
This guy's got a piece of wood
sticking out of his head.
Alex James,
age 42.
Found his wallet
in the glove compartment.
SUV is registered to him.
No previous record.
How was he able to drive?
I once saw a guy walk 15 blocks
with three bullets in his face.
The victim was traveling west
on Flamingo.
The Desert Palm isn't too far
from here.
I guess he was en route
to the hospital.
I don't much care
where he was going.
I want to know where he's been.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
I like coming in
the back way, huh?
Yeah, makes us
VIPs tonight.
Let me help you,
ma'am. Sir?
No, thanks.
Oh, it's not luggage.
Thank you, though.
You must be CSI.
I'm Warrick Brown.
This is Catherine Willows.
You said you had
a situation in
your casino?
A kidnap.
Is it a high profile?
Yes. We'd like to deal
with this locally
before we involve
the FBI.
Well, until we know
the victim was taken
over state lines,
the FBI has no
jurisdiction.
Do you have any contact
from the kidnappers?
A ransom note was left
at the front desk.
Who are we looking for here?
A five-year-old boy.
Whose
five-year-old boy?
Tavian Tombs.
Tavian Tombs,
professional basketball player.
Very high profile.
TOMBS:
I got eight people
to make sure
that something like this
does not happen.
Where the hell was everybody?
Out spending my money?
You're supposed to be
the head of security,
and you let my son
get kidnapped
right from under
my nose.
You better have a good reason
for being here.
We're here to find your son.
WILLOWS:
We're with
the Crime Lab,
and I'm assuming that
that's our ransom note.
It's my note,
my kid, my show.
BROWN:
Look, I've seen
you take out
three guys on the glass
and still finish.
I'm not here to
bang boards
with you.
I'm here to
do my job.
It's your son,
it's your call.
BOY:
I'm going to dunk on you again.
Yeah.
"I have Isaiah.
"Bring $5 million
"to the northwest corner
of Telfair
and Juniper,
4:00 a.m."
How many of you
touched this letter?
I did.
We all did.
I just want my boy back.
Did this note come
in an envelope?
Yeah... I threw it
in the wastebasket.
We have a better chance
of getting uncompromised prints
off of this.
You said that
Captain Brass
was here?
Yeah. He's interviewing
the nanny.
( sighing ):
We were at the carnival,
me and the boys.
( children cheering &amp;amp;amp; laughing)
They wanted to ride
on the carousel. I said no.
But you gave in.
Special weekend.
Dad's in town.
Everybody's together.
Trust me, they don't
understand "no."
( children cheering &amp;amp;amp; laughing)
Jason!
Jason,
where's Isaiah?
Jason!
Where's your brother?!
Jason, where's your brother?!
He was right there.
And then he...
I swear to you,
I looked everywhere,
but I knew he was gone.
( sighs ):
So...
I brought the kids back here
and had to tell Tavian.
And his wife.
( scoffs ):
They're not married.
And even if they were,
it'd still be Tavian's show.
A woman who knows
her employer.
I should.
He's my brother.
It took you that
long to pull the
paper together?
Soft Count Room
wouldn't go any faster.
The casino's fronting
the ransom money?
Mr. Tombs has a
multimillion-dollar
line of credit
with us.
We strongly advise
that you don't
hand over
that money.
At least
let us mark it.
You know how long it'd take
to mark $5 million large?
The kidnapper knows.
Longer than the
drop-off time.
Now, the letter said corner
of Telfair and Juniper.
That's where this bag is going.
( garbled radio transmission)
Sharp force trauma.
Shouldn't we get
the spike out
of his head
before we try to get
any prints off it?
I'm afraid if we
try to remove it,
we'll eradicate
the prints.
( shutter clicks )
I'm not going to get
any prints off of this.
Well, he sure is dirty.
I mean, he isn't homeless.
This is his car, right?
Yeah.
I'm going
to scrape his nails.
GRISSOM:
Hand me a bindle.
Hey, fellas,
you're never going
to guess what I found
under the seat.
A .38 Special.
Catherine wanted to know
if you have anything.
She can't
convince Tavian
to change his mind
about the ransom money.
8 1/2 x 11 plain white
copy paper.
It's mass-produced.
You can get it anywhere.
The envelope, unfortunately,
is self-adhering.
No DNA.
No.
What about the text?
It's just standard laser,
nondescript.
So you got nothing.
Nothing I can see.
( writing )
( lid clamping )
( suction whirring )
( whirring stops )
Looks like something
out of Nosferatu.
Yeah, only
the wooden stake
is in his head,
not his heart.
I've never seen
that before--
a wooden stake embedded
in the high parietal
scalp in the midline.
Hold his head down
firmly, will you?
On three.
One...
two... three!
Irregular puncture
defect to the scalp,
laceration
to the sagittal sinus.
The wound track stops
at the falx cerebri.
No gross penetration
of the cerebrum.
That stake is what
kept him driving.
Tamponading?
Well, the application of
more than normal pressure
to the wound
acts like a plug,
temporarily keeping him alive.
The spike
probably struck
between the brain hemispheres
most likely lodging
into the parietal bones
and holding it
in place.
They say it's
a game of inches--
a centimeter to
the left or right,
and he would have bled
out and died instantly.
Yeah, but head trauma
this severe,
surgery would've probably
killed him anyway.
That,
or live an extra hour
in excruciating pain.
They weren't lying.
They all touched it.
Everybody's who's got
a piece of Tavian
got a hand
on that ransom note.
Even the bellman
and the desk clerk
left prints
on the envelope.
Any unidentified
prints?
Just a few smudges,
a couple of partials.
So prints don't help.
No.
Liquid extraction
results.
Yeah, that was detected
on the ransom note--
menthol
and nicotine.
Nicotine.
So we're looking for a smoker--
menthol smoker.
Everybody hold.
We don't make a move until
after he's taken the money.
( both sighing )
Stand down.
We're way past
the drop time here.
Yeah. Well, let's
give it a couple more.
So, what's your
take on this?
Inside or outside job?
No, I think it's
just some freak
with a nicotine habit
and access
to a laser printer.
Did you see the
action he got?
One phone call,
$5 million
gets delivered
to his hotel?
Yeah, that money's not doing
him any good now, huh?
Yeah.
It's just gone bad.
Oh, man.
WARRICK:
Hey! Hey!
What are
you doing?
Put the guns down!
( sighs )
What the hell
are you doing?
Tavian wanted me
to be sure
the transfer got done.
This is our job--
not yours, not Tavian's.
What are you
concerned
about here--
the kid or your job?
I didn't do nothing.
Nobody took the money--
didn't even show.
I been here all night
just like you.
They spotted you.
You understand?
The kidnappers
saw you.
They made us.
( cell phone rings )
I was doing what
Tavian asked
me to, man.
Brass.
It's him.
I'll take
the perimeter.
Body's in an unnatural position.
BRASS:
Maybe this is only
the dump site.
His body's also coated.
Makes me think
whoever did this
didn't even stop the car.
Something had
to have gone wrong.
Something did.
Do not let them cut him.
I don't want them
even touching him.
We're taking the body.
Mr. Tombs
I'm sorry,
but in a crime like this,
an autopsy's mandatory.
Evidence from your
son's body may lead us
to the suspect.
You're telling me what
I can and can't do?
It's not your call anymore.
( sighs )
How you doing
over there?
I got scat.
Feces?
Yep.
Under the fingernail?
He wiped his own ass?
No, Nick, it's not human.
It's scat.
Could be from a bat.
STOKES:
Bat scat.
Bat guano.
Well, whatever.
It's a lot better
than what I got.
As far as I can tell,
the wood's Douglas Fir
with a side of God knows what.
I'm no geologist,
but these splinters
are intertwined
with some kind of mineral.
Is it sparkly?
Oh, yeah.
Let me see.
I think it's quartz.
Or fluorite.
Great.
That limits it to every
outdoor area in Greater Nevada.
Mountain ranges,
mine shafts,
quarries... underground sewers.
All home to bats.
( sighing )
Hey.
Why don't you
let me handle this?
Thanks.
I'm not ready to deal
with another murdered kid.
I'll process
the evidence.
No apparent
cause of death.
I'll send a blood
sample to Tox.
The foam around his mouth?
Could indicate
pulmonary edema.
Found bruising
in the lower extremities
and the knees,
but these injuries
are a few days old.
The bruises are at
various stages of healing.
Well, that could be
from roughhousing
with his older brothers.
What about this bruise?
Well...
let's see,
it extends around the body...
like so.
Ah, I've seen
this before.
Did you find rope at the scene?
We haven't found the scene.
Outer City
Salvage Company.
Owned and operated
by Alex James.
Las Vegas Police.
I have a warrant.
I'll clear the back.
Thanks.
( chuckling )
When's the last time you
saw a dinosaur like this?
Lemons on the reels.
Not since Sam Braun
ran the town.
Old Vegas.
Buckshot pellets.
Looks like he
loaded his own.
GRISSOM:
A melting furnace.
What's that for?
Melting precious metals.
Quenched it in the tub?
Hey, fellas,
take a look at this.
More precious
metals.
And the pawn tickets.
Easily traceable.
Topographical maps
of the Sierra Nevada.
Delamar Quadrangle,
Lincoln County,
La Madre Mountain...
Clark County.
Hey, Nick.
Blood spatter and
a bullet hole, maybe?
Through-and-through.
Oh, yeah.
Medium caliber.
This is our primary crime scene?
Except that our vic had a stake
in his head. He wasn't shot.
Yeah, but he had
a .38 in his car.
We're looking for another body.
It was a tip.
A $10,000 gold chip?
I don't think so.
If it was a tip,
you wouldn't have had to lose
the bellman's outfit
to cash it in.
Now where'd
you get this?
I found it, sort of.
You found it sort of.
Tavian is always
surrounded by women.
Guys, too,
but they want autographs.
The chicks--
they want something else.
Now, usually
his boys turn them away,
but this one got through.
Get the hell
out of my way.
I want to
see Tavian.
There were definitely
chicks a lot hotter,
but I guess
when you can have anything...
They leave together?
No, just the opposite.
They got into it right there.
You're a lousy
father to Tramelle.
And you think
the whole world worships you.
But the truth is,
you're just a deadbeat.
Whatever.
This what you want?
Casino taxes me $24 an hour
regardless of what I make.
And do you know
how much a zillionaire
like Tavian Tombs tips?
Zip. Nothing.
Not even change
I can throw in the fountain.
And why? Because he's comped
all the way around.
R.F.B.-- room, food, beverage--
including tips.
So, when ten large goes
sliding across the floor,
and nobody sees it?
Get out of the way,
'cause Kevin's coming through.
Yeah, I get the picture.
Hey, I tried to give it back.
This is yours.
Keep it.
Yeah, yeah, sure you did.
So, uh, what about my money?
Don't be stupid.
Who's the blonde
he's talking about?
I don't know.
Look, big casinos honor
each other's chips.
So, how you tracking these?
Bar code,
embedded transmitters, what?
Look, it's okay.
It's easy for the guys
at the lab to figure this out,
but we'll let the other casinos
know you helped us out.
Her name is
Bridget Willis.
She's on his list.
Thank you.
Hey, Griss,
ballistics matched
the .38 bullet
to the gun
in the victim's car.
As for the splinters
on the stake...
you were right.
Quartz. Fluorite.
Dolomite, barite,
calcite, antimony.
Well, the Mass Spec dug deeper.
Arsenic and cyanide.
Now, as of late,
that's what's used
to extract gold.
Do you have any idea
how many mine shafts there are
in the state of Nevada?
Yeah, hundreds.
Including gold and silver mines
in Nelson, Searchlight,
Goodsprings.
You name it.
I've got Lockwood running
a background check
on our vic.
Maybe we'll get lucky.
BRASS:
Bridget Willis?
Mm-hmm.
I'm Detective Jim Brass,
Vegas PD.
This is Catherine Willows
from the Crime Lab.
You're here to talk
to my son Tramelle?
We already have.
I was in college.
He was the "man,"
Mr. Final Four.
I thought I'd won the lottery.
Then I got pregnant,
and he went
in the lottery, so...
Take a look around.
Guess what we fight about.
Money.
He's rich, I'm not.
I've accepted that.
But he does
have responsibilities.
Tramelle.
A weekend here and there
doesn't make a father.
Tramelle's not one
of his "boys."
He's his son.
Kid comes home
with a armful of presents
and a broken heart every time.
Ms. Willis...
is Tramelle your only child?
No.
I have a little girl.
Why wasn't she with Tavian's
other kids at the carnival?
She wasn't invited.
I'm not taking her.
I'm not taking your girl.
Tramelle's been talking
about this weekend for months.
She just wants to come.
Then what you better do
is explain to her
that I'm Tramelle's father,
not hers.
What difference does
one little girl make?
It's all about what's mine.
GIRL:
Mommy.
What's for lunch?
Just a minute,
okay, sweetie?
So, instead,
I took her to Sweet Creatures
at the Forum Shops.
( laughs )
Don't fill it too much, sweetie.
Oh, yes, I've been there.
Works wonders
on the disappointments
of little girls.
That's what I was hoping for.
For you.
Thanks.
Have you taken a look?
I'm just trying to learn.
Well?
Well, the fiber
you tweezed
from that sweatshirt--
Trace pegged
it as sisal.
Sisal?
Rope?
Mostly likely
from the restraint.
What's under the scope?
Take a look.
Oh, hair.
But cuticle's a single layer.
Overlapping.
It's not human.
It's canine.
Sweatshirt was riddled
with dog hair.
Many different breeds.
You think the kidnapper
used it as a lure?
Kids love dogs.
I know when I was a kid,
I was all over them.
That's a good start.
Thanks.
Found them in Isaiah's
stomach contents.
Pill casings.
Starts to break down
as soon as it hits the mouth.
The shell is porous.
In the stomach,
the medicine leeches out,
enters the bloodstream.
The case is left behind.
Eventually, the
casing's broken
down, as well,
but by then,
the medicine's
already working.
I see a USP number.
Well, it should be
listed in the PDR,
but I couldn't
find it.
What have you got?
Pill casings.
He was drugged?
Looks that way.
Well, we lifted dog hair
from the sweatshirt
we found near the body.
So, our kidnapper had contact
with dogs.
Multiple breeds.
Dog lover? Dog walker?
Hey, how about a vet?
Try the reference
of Veterinary Pharmaceuticals
and Biologicals.
Acepromazine Maleate.
Tranquilizer.
25 milligrams.
Four pills wouldn't
have been fatal
for a child
Isaiah's size.
Based on the
blood levels,
these remnants were
probably a second dose.
BROWN:
It wasn't the money drop
that went bad.
The problem was Isaiah died.
I'll call Brass.
I'll have him check vet clinics,
kennels, pet supply stores,
and we'll extend the radius out
from the dump site.
Okay.
Our man Alex James
is quite the land owner.
According to the Mining Laws
of 1872,
public land can still
be patented
for five dollars an acre--
a law which
is still in effect.
That's all this guy did
was buy and sell
publicly-owned, government land.
Funny thing is,
there was one mine
that he sold over
and over again.
Now, why would he do that?
Now, there lies
the mystery.
So, who was the last
person he sold to?
Joe McPherson. Local.
Where is he now?
No one knows.
He's been missing for 48 hours.
( chuckles )
There lies the mystery.
Where's the mine?
What's with the gate?
It's a bat gate.
It keeps people out,
lets the bats in.
Old mines are considered
bat habitats and preserves.
Who puts the bat
gates in?
Batman.
What have you got?
Insect chitin.
It's usually
found near the
entrance of caves.
Guano.
We got bats.
Oh.
Good.
Probably California
Leaf-nosed Bats.
They don't bite, do they?
They're like bees, Nick.
You don't bother them,
they won't
bother you.
Well, hey, let's...
let's not bother them, okay?
I'm serious.
Are you seeing this?
Gold.
We're rich.
I'm not so sure.
Another buckshot casing.
And these look
like impact patterns.
So, he was loading his own.
But not with pellets.
With gold.
Pawn shop jewelry
and melting furnace.
You know, Lockwood
said that James
sold this parcel of land
multiple times.
I think he was running a scam.
He was salting the mind.
( gunshot )
Insect party.
Yeah.
Cockroaches,
cave crickets.
Carabid beetles.
All heading deeper
into the cave.
Why?
Maybe they
got tired
of eating bat guano.
BRASS:
So, this is three blocks
from the place
where Isaiah's body was found.
Why don't you guys
take the kennel?
Metcalf and I are going
to take the dog run.
( dogs barking )
( barking continues )
( ferocious barking )
( snarling )
( barking )
Cath?
We found something.
I think you wanna take a look at this.
Jacob Price. Local.
He works night shift here.
Looks like somebody
beat us to him.
Partner you think?
Or a guy who knows
how to finish.
I don't want
to hear this.
Yeah, well... I've been
on the job a long time,
and I know what a
tragedy like this
can do to a family.
I told you,
I don't want to hear it.
What's going
to happen
is one day
Kenisha or Tramelle
or one of
your other kids
is going to come to
you and say, "What
happened to Isaiah?"
And they're going to
want to know the truth.
Nothing you say
is going to change anything.
The guy who
took Isaiah
worked in a kennel.
He was used to handling dogs,
not children.
When Isaiah
tried to escape,
he was restrained,
and when that
didn't work,
he was drugged.
Now, drugs have
a different effect
on adults than on children.
It's called
"the paradoxical effect."
So, when the
tranquilizers
weren't working,
this guy-- Price--
upped the dosage.
Now, as a father,
I can understand
why you'd want this guy dead.
What?
Whoa.
You think I killed him?
Yes, I do.
I didn't kill anybody.
I don't even know who he is.
But if I'd gotten to him
before you,
I swear I would not have stopped
to think about it.
Don't fill it too much, sweetie.
You said the bigger the better.
( coughing )
Air's getting thick.
Smells like
trinitrotoluene.
( coughs )
Look familiar?
Yeah. But how did it get
in the back of the guy's head?
Fuse line.
Dynamite.
( coughing )
GRISSOM:
Chest wound.
Possibly from our .38.
Looks about 2days old.
Joe McPherson.
Local.
Mr. MIA.
You know, wooden support beams,
fuse line,
TNT...
I think, uh, Alex James
was trying to hide this body
in the back of his mine.
McPHERSON:
You scammed me.
JAMES:
No.
That was my
life savings.
Take it easy.
Listen, now-now,
now, lookit.
I-I, I can explain everything,
all right?
Listen, Joe.
Joe, come on,
I-I sold you
the wrong mine.
I-It's
an honest mistake.
You're a liar!
( grunting )
( gunshot )
( panting )
GRISSOM:
Like most fuses,
it probably burnt too quickly
and he couldn't outrun
the blast.
( yelling )
Or the wooden stake.
Okay.
Sample from the kennel
is on your right.
Your bear is on the left.
Visible match.
( knocking at door )
Bridget Willis?
Las Vegas police.
Tramelle, where's
your mother?
I don't know.
She left with my sister.
She said my daddy
would come get me.
BRASS:
She's not here.
I'll put out
an APB.
So, Tavian was paying
Bridget child support--
three grand a month.
Three grand a month?
Tavian Tombs has been
a $12 million-a-year player
for eight seasons,
not including endorsements.
Well, he made his deal
with Bridget
when Tramelle was born.
Bad timing for her.
Motive for us.
She was right to assume
that Tavian would immediately
pay that ransom.
What's five million to a guy
who makes hundreds of millions?
And it is his son.
I'm sure he would have paid
any amount.
So, how does that
dog kennel guy Price
figure into all this,
and was killing him
part of the plan?
I don't know.
I think that Bridget Willis
killed him
because he killed Isaiah.
( yelling )
( dog barking )
In her act of redemption,
she gives Tramelle to Tavian.
Come here.
Hello, Tramelle.
Hi.
Okay.
According to Greg, the
blood on the bullet's
a direct match
to Joe McPherson.
It's a done deal.
You know,
I was talking to a lady
in the County
Records Office.
She said those land patents
have been changing hands
for over 50 years.
That figures.
There's a sucker
born every minute.
Yup, and they all
come to Vegas.