♪ ♪
Stop.
Oh, come on!
We've gone
way further than that.
♪ ♪
( laughing )
( screams )
BRASS:
The vic's wallet
was still in her purse.
One credit card,
couple of 20s.
Nebraska ID.
Her name was Alison Carpenter,
age 28.
A little old for a student.
BRASS:
School district
has been contacted.
They're checking
their records.
Petechial hemorrhaging
indicates strangulation.
She definitely died here.
Yeah, lividity
bears that out.
She wasn't moved.
The padlock's been cut.
It was rusted over,
definitely not recent.
Beer bottles.
Well, it's high school.
Lover's lane.
Defensive wounds
on her hands.
Sexual assault?
She's not wearing any underwear.
David, I thought you said
she wasn't moved.
Paramedics say
they didn't touch her.
Kids who found her swore
they didn't touch her either.
There's still perspiration
on her upper lip.
Take a liver temperature.
Let me just finish this...
Now, David.
98.1.
She's been dead
less than an hour.
The killer's still on her.
and Volkswagen.
On the road of life
there are passengers
and there are drivers.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
STOKES:
Latent prints on skin,
oil on oils,
we're cutting it
pretty close here.
Yes, we are.
Nothing usable around the neck.
I think I've got
a partial on the ankle.
GRISSOM:
Very few sweat glands
around the ankle.
Prints survive longer.
Fortunately for us.
There's nobody
in the evidence vault.
I guess we're still
between shifts.
Yeah, well, we'll log it
in tomorrow.
You know, O'Riley
interviewed
the victim's wife.
Yeah?
She said her husband was
in the garage drinking
and just "done fell over."
Oh, the ever-popular DFO.
Right up there with the
"Mysterious Dude" defense.
Right.
You thinking poison?
I wouldn't be surprised.
Wife had two priors
for spousal abuse.
Seems pretty
straight up to me.
Well, that would be nice--
an easy case.
Yeah.
These double-ups
are killing me.
Although I'll take it
when I can get it.
These nannies
do not work cheap.
Yeah, how is Lindsey,
by the way?
She got caught
fighting at school.
Lindsey? Fighting?
Yeah, she lost
her dad recently.
She's just having
a hard time.
SIDLE:
Company said the vic checked
the car out three days ago.
The contract was for a week.
STROKES:
It's a generic econo-box.
Might as well just paint
a bull's-eye on it.
You got the front?
Yeah.
I've got a ripped-up
pair of panties.
Possibly
the vic's.
Bag that for me, will you?
Whoa.
Sex in the backseat.
Blister pack.
What have you got?
Ceramics, maybe?
Hey, who's working Trace
tonight?
Hodges.
Great.
Guarantee you that kiss-ass
will have the results
to Grissom before we do.
So I'm thinking
the vic was car-jacked,
dragged to
a secluded location...
( screaming )
raped, murdered, body dumped.
What do you think?
Killer had her in the car.
Easy getaway.
But still,
why take her all the way
up the bleachers,
to risk getting caught
in a room
with only
one way out?
Cause of death was asphyxiation
due to strangulation.
Multiple round oval bruises
over the interior
and lateral neck
with occasional crescentic
red abrasions.
GRISSOM:
Fingertip bruises
and fingernail scratches.
Apparently.
No ligature marks.
None that I could find,
but take a look at this.
The, uh, bruises
are concentrated
on the left side
of the neck.
On the right side,
there's only one.
Killer strangled her
with his right hand.
One hand only.
Yeah, prolonged pressure
on the jugular.
He must have been looking
right in her eyes.
Yeah, that takes hate.
I'll get a measurement
of the, uh, grip size.
What about the SART kit?
It's on Graves' desk,
but he's pretty backed up,
more than usual.
Bruises on her hands,
her arms,
upper torso--
it's consistent with rape.
Maybe not.
I did a vaginal clock on her.
Signs of activity
at 11:00, 12:00,
and 1:00, and that would imply
rough sex, not rape.
May have started as sex,
but it ended as murder.
BRASS:
Alison Carpenter was a waitress
at a coffee shop outside Omaha.
The boss said that she asked
for this week off
over a month ago.
And, uh, no immediate family.
Single woman on vacation
in Vegas... alone?
Yeah, weird.
We're looking into it.
Who takes a tape recorder
with them on vacation?
Well, I keep one by the bed.
In case I dream anything useful.
Hmm?
What?
I can't have deep thoughts?
( laughs )
Just kidding.
Hey, Boss.
Just analyzed the evidence
found in your vic's rent-a-car.
You should be telling
Nick or Sara.
Yeah, couldn't find them.
They must be on another break.
Anyway, the blister pack
is methadone.
40 milligrams,
former smack addict dose.
And that ceramic chip?
Not ceramic.
It's acrylic
with a quartz resin composite
used primarily
in dental crowns.
Cheap ones.
Good work.
Yeah, thank you. Listen,
I'd like to think that and I...
Now go tell
Nick or Sara.
( sighs )
Problem is AGIS doesn't play
real nice with partials.
So here's what I'm going to do.
I'll pick eight or nine
distinctive features,
run those through the system,
and examine anything
with a 60% or better match.
You could end up
with over 100 hits.
You trying
to discourage me?
It's all about
interpretation.
Knowing what's
commonplace,
and what's unique.
That's where
skill comes in.
You still have to check
each one by hand.
You're going
to have to sign
my time sheet.
SANDERS:
Grissom!
I'm about
to rock your world.
The semen inside your victim--
I got a DNA match through CODIS.
It's Jason Kent.
Ring a bell?
1987, they called him
"The Circle Killer."
BRASS:
Guy's only been out of jail
six weeks.
( knocking )
Las Vegas Police.
This a bad time?
You know, I know
a couple of guys
who worked your case.
Viking Circle.
Remember that girl
you suffocated
while you were raping her?
What was she, a cheerleader,
homecoming queen, or both?
She was a friend.
Oh, I didn't
expect that.
I expected you to say, uh,
"No, I'm innocent"
or "No, it was an accident."
I served my time.
That's right.
You did the whole bit.
The whole 15 years.
You're a hard-core ex-con.
This must really piss you off.
You know what?
I know the conditions
of my release.
So you can check
whatever you'd like.
You want to tell me
what this is about?
You're under arrest for
the murder of Alison Carpenter.
Last night, your old high
school, Go Monarchs.
I'm not talking to you
without a lawyer.
Looks like you bit your lip.
May I see your hands, please?
Recently clipped your nails,
huh?
BRASS:
And you're such
a smart guy,
bet you flushed them
down the toilet.
All right.
How'd you do
with the nail clippers?
Right over here.
Figured it wasn't
high priority
since I'd already ID'd
the semen in the victim.
GRISSOM:
That only proves
that they had sex.
The nail clippers can place
Jason Kent at the murder scene.
His nails,
her DNA,
traces of the booth, et cetera.
Killer, victim, location.
Holy Trinity, Greg.
I need that.
So?
ARCHIE:
Just getting started.
I'll keep you posted.
SECRETARY:
Mr. Grissom, I have
your phone messages.
Thank you.
Grissom, do you
have a second?
MAN: His vitals are stable
...full thickness burns
on the neck and back.
Burn unit.
Let's move.
Are you okay?
Uh-huh.
Honey, this doesn't
look good.
It's fine.
Cleanup's
going to be something.
We should get started.
You need to get stitches.
I'm okay.
Would you take care
of her hand, please?
MAN:
Yes, sir,
I just got here.
Several injuries,
one serious.
Fire department
arson explosives
are assessing
the damage right now.
What'd you do to my lab,
Grissom?
I'm going to need a complete
evidence inventory by case.
What's been lost,
what's contaminated,
what's salvageable.
We have LIMS backup
for every computer
on the network.
I'm sure we've only lost
an hour or two of data.
Well, we'll never
sell that in court.
Defense attorneys
will rip us apart.
That, uh,
double murder movie
star case last year,
compromised evidence,
lax procedures, mistakes.
We got a conviction on that.
You got lucky.
This is a priority.
I want to know
how this happened.
And who's to blame?
I'm going to have Catherine
run the investigation.
I'm on a murder case.
I'll be waiting for her report.
So what was your relationship
again with Alison Carpenter?
Once again, my client asserts
his Fifth Amendment rights
and declines to answer.
Why bother?
His semen was found
inside the victim.
A finding from a crime unit
that blows up its own DNA lab?
You really think that's going
to carry a lot of weight?
BRASS ( over speakers ):
I understand you're
in a methadone program.
WOMAN:
So what?
My client's a recovering addict.
He got hooked in prison.
The war on drugs
works about as well
on the inside
as it does on the street.
Well, methadone puts him
in the victim's car.
There are thousands
of methadone users
out there.
With chipped dental crowns?
We're going to need
an orthodontic sample.
This is harassment.
We're done cooperating here.
My third week in prison.
Break the new guy's teeth,
he can't bite down on something
that's shoved in his mouth.
JOHNSON:
That box of tapes
we found
in her motel room,
this is the third one.
She recorded about
nine hours in total.
Started like this.
CARPENTER:
It's almost 6:00.
I'm almost ready.
I know there's nothing
to be nervous about,
but I am.
He's suffered so much.
I'm going to help him remember
who he really is.
So, she knew Jason Kent.
He wasn't just some
random pickup.
At first I thought maybe she was
working on a book or something.
Then I hit this.
Day two.
You threw four touchdowns
that game,
didn't you?
And ran for one
from right here.
Everybody was thinking pass...
I ran it right up the middle
for six.
Sounds amazing.
I wish I could
have been there with you.
Is it just me or does it
sound like she's in love
with this guy?
Maybe she was a murder groupie.
Hey, Manson,
the Night Stalker--
all those guys had them.
I think for some freaks,
killing's a turn-on, you know?
Well, check this out.
Day before
the murder.
Last thing on her tapes.
Well, this is an apartment
and it is the right address, so
I guess I'm just waiting here.
Let's go. Let's go.
Start the car.
Jason,
what happened?
( spitting )
I don't want
to talk about it.
This about
Jesus Carden...
Jesus Cardenas
is a scumbag convict,
and we're not talking about him.
Okay, I'm sorry.
Shut that thing off.
Run Jesus through NCIC.
Cardenas.
Jesus Cardenas.
Heroin,
possession for sale
and manslaughter.
Currently serving 25
at the Western Nevada
Correctional Facility.
The former residence
of Jason Kent.
Look, I'm pretty tired.
WILLOWS:
This won't take long, Greg.
We promise.
BROWN:
Why don't you tell us
exactly what happened.
As best as you can remember.
I was working
three cases.
Mixing solvents.
Did you
notice anything
prior to the explosion?
A power surge,
a spark, a smell?
Plastic.
Burning plastic.
I turned around to see
where it was coming from.
After that...
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
We done?
Yeah, we're done.
Feel better, all right?
Get some rest.
( printing )
STOKES:
Jesus Cardenas
and Jason Kent
were two prisoners with
the same taste in visitors.
Alison Carpenter.
Yeah, she visited Jason
13 times in the last 18 months.
And the last two times,
she also visited Jesus.
GRISSOM:
A murderer,
his groupie
and a heroin dealer,
what a team.
Mm.
Does Western Nevada
Correctional
use surveillance cameras
in their visitation room?
Yeah, and it's all cued up.
JOHNSON:
It's pretty casual for prison.
It's medium security.
Nicer criminals.
Right.
Anyway, every time we visit
it pretty much went
the same way.
She sits down with Jason Kent,
they talk for a little while,
and Kent goes back to his cell.
Then the last two visits,
she stayed behind.
Jesus Cardenas.
JOHNSON:
They're offscreen here
for about five minutes.
Then they come back to the table
and she leaves.
Run that again.
Can you enhance that?
Yeah, I think so.
Jason's little girlfriend
was screwing a guy he hates.
Well, if you can't kill
the one you want...
kill the one you're with.
What a mess.
Want to strip it?
I'm thinking spiral
with an overlap.
I'll head this way.
All right.
Damage radiates from here.
Well... there's no crater.
Yeah, so it's not
a high explosive.
I guess we're looking
for a combustible liquid?
Yeah. That narrows things down.
Yeah.
Oh.
Somebody left the hot plate on
inside of the fume hood.
Genius.
( sighs )
What do you think?
Developer pan?
Presence of acetone, methanol,
all kinds of combustibles.
Mix that with a heat source,
and what have you got?
This.
Hey.
You back on?
Yeah.
I hear you're going to prison.
Hmm.
Why don't you come along?
( explosion )
STOKES:
What can you tell us
about Alison Carpenter?
Knew her real well,
but I guess
you already know that.
How did you like the show?
Alison Carpenter is dead.
I got an alibi.
Yeah, you're completely
innocent, and so, tell me,
why would a woman
like Alison Carpenter,
who was obsessed
with Jason Kent,
have anything to do with you?
STOKES:
You remember Jason.
Two cells down.
Hates your guts.
A lot of anger in that boy.
Not much sense.
Doesn't understand
how things work.
In here or out there?
Either way.
It doesn't matter.
This is still
the U.S. of A., my man.
It's capitalism.
Every one us a buyer or seller.
Which one was Alison?
Exchange of goods for services.
I gave Jason credit,
he walks out of here in debt.
Thinks because he's
on the outside,
he don't have to pay.
Man who doesn't
pay his debt undermines
the whole system.
What did he owe you for?
STOKES:
We pulled Jason Kent's
disciplinary
file.
He spent some
time in solitary.
His CO caught
him with heroin
on two separate
occasions.
Once in, uh, '97
and again in '99.
Did our lab examine
the physical evidence?
Yeah, we pulled
those records, too.
The analysis had yielded
a black tar heroin
with trace amounts
of blue and red linen fibers.
Linen? In a prison?
You know, they got him
on the heroin once.
They didn't follow up
with the trace.
So how did Jason Kent get
the heroin?
STOKES:
Uh...
you-you know how these guys are.
All they do 24/7 is figure out
how to beat the system.
We figure the drugs probably
came from Jesus.
So what are we saying?
Jesus sells Jason Kent heroin.
Kent falls into debt,
and pays him off
with Alison Carpenter?
I'll-I'll get
the money somehow.
I'll work another
shift, and we'll...
pay him later.
I owe him.
And one way or another,
he's going to collect.
I'll do whatever I have to do.
Yeah, they passed her around
like a party favor.
Actually...
she passed
around herself.
Hmm.
We understand that you handled
a meth lab yesterday.
Contaminated
filter papers.
So what?
So, you had
to do a solvent extraction?
What did you use?
Chloroform, methanol
and acetone.
I cleaned the pan.
Same way you turned
off that hot plate?
If it was on,
it wasn't my fault.
That thing gets turned on
by accident all the time.
Mysterious dude defense.
Well, our report is going
to reflect the fact
that an active heat source
was under the fume hood.
I know what this is.
You guys hear the lies
and rumors about me from L.A.
You know
how much Grissom depends on me.
So you figure,
let's get
rid of him.
I'll lawyer up before I let you
pin the tail on the new donkey.
Start dialing.
WOMAN:
Partial from your vic's
ankle on the left.
Jason Kent on the right.
One point of commonality?
That's it.
So it's not his print?
Couldn't be.
'Cause it belongs
to another guy.
Ten points of commonality.
I think I could get a couple
of more,
not that we need it.
Miguel Dorado.
Mickey D.
Las Culebras.
What's the connection?
Jesus Cardenas
is in the same game.
Mickey D. could be the guy
who's getting the heroin
into the prison.
How did his prints turn up
at the scene?
I'm not sure how, but I
may see a potential why.
Could be Mickey D. is
collecting Jason Kent's debt.
( thudding )
( screaming )
( groaning )
( sighs )
One way or another,
you got to pay what you owe.
Suze can't wait
to see you again.
Jason Kent
was suitable for framing.
Hey.
Oh, you work fast.
Which color charts
Hodges' developer pan?
Blue.
The blue.
That's 180-degree array.
That's not the epicenter
of the explosion.
Hodges' pan wasn't the source.
It got pushed out.
By what?
By this.
The primary frag.
The green glass.
Then who blew up the lab?
I did.
( TV playing in distance )
Las Vegas Police!
OFFICER:
Miguel Dorado.
We know you're here.
Come out!
You. Go. Go. Go. There.
There.
( glass breaking )
I got him!
Get back!
( grunting )
You got him?
Got him.
Okay.
Holster your weapon.
What were you doing?
What were you thinking?
You know that we clear
the room, not you.
I got him.
You're all done, hombre.
( sighs )
( phone rings )
Grissom.
WOMAN:
Director Covallo
is ready to see you.
Okay, thank you.
CSI Brown and I
had collected evidence on a case
involving a woman
whose husband had collapsed.
We suspected poison.
When we returned
to the lab...
You hadn't identified
the liquid?
Not yet, no.
And it was consumed
in the explosion
so I guess we'll never know
what it was.
In any event,
you placed
this unidentified chemical
under the fume hood.
Right.
Next to an active heat source.
I didn't know that
at the time.
Because you didn't check.
Unlogged evidence gets placed
under the fume hood.
A hot plate was left on.
It's a lab.
It's nobody's fault.
It's my
responsibility.
I didn't follow procedure.
Why not?
Because there's 24 hours
in the day
and I'm pulling 16
for the County,
spending three
pretending to sleep
and the other five
lying to my daughter
that everything's
going to be all right.
There were 13 active cases
in DNA.
They are all now tainted
or destroyed.
What do you want to hear?
I screwed up.
I'm sorry.
"Sorry" doesn't cut it.
You're on suspension.
Five days unpaid leave.
Grissom.
We're not done here.
I've heard rumors
that you've been kicking back
Willows' reports.
One report.
The Jenkins case.
She made a miscalculation.
I've asked her to reissue
the report.
Great.
Well, while you're at it,
maybe she can reissue
the lab explosion.
Let me explain something to you.
Every one of us
( audio fading ):
in this building,
all of us...
( no audio )
Robert.
If you have something to say
to me, say it to my face.
Okay.
It's not your job
to protect your people.
It's to protect the integrity
of this lab.
Without the people...
there is no lab.
I hear you think you're
indestructible now, Sara.
Have you ever had a gun drawn
on you, Sara?
No, I haven't.
Hey, Nick.
Know those red and blue
fibers we found
in Jason Kent's heroin?
Mm-hmm.
I think I know
where they came from.
Take the G.W. Bridge?
I don't know
what you're talking
about.
Did you cut yourself shaving
or were you just thinking
too hard?
Police brutality.
You ever hear of it?
Those are human bite marks.
Yeah?
His.
You're not looking
at assault, Mick.
You're looking at murder.
What?
You have Jason Kent's
teeth marks on your head.
( groaning )
STOKES:
And your fingerprints
are on Alison Carpenter's body.
You're not putting
this murder rap on me.
It was that freak Jason.
He did it.
We're placing you
at the scene.
Yeah.
I was there...
for the money.
I told him
that he had one day
to pay up what he owed.
Make everything right
with Jesus.
That's it.
You know, it's not a bad deal
for prison.
Mickey D. brings the heroin
to Jesus Cardenas
and you trade him
a woman for smack.
Testimony
from Mickey D.?
Hearsay from
a gangbanger?
Oh, there's more.
You left prison
without paying your tab
and when Jesus sent
his collection agency after you,
you figured you'd pay him back
just the way you
did in the joint.
GRISSOM:
We know that
you had sex
with Alison Carpenter
that night.
Most probably in her car.
BRASS:
Get her in the mood.
I want you to do
something for me.
Anything you want.
Good, come on.
This get us square?
Yeah.
For now.
Take care of him.
No, I don't want to.
You said you'd help me.
I did help you.
Alison,
just one time.
Come on.
No!
( hands pounding on walls )
( pounding continues )
( squeaking )
( pounding stops )
You're in on this.
You're going back
in the joint, freak.
You can't prove
any of this.
You have no evidence that places
my client at the scene.
Would you place your hand--
your right hand--
on this paper, please?
Extend the fingers outward.
ATTORNEY:
You have a known
gang member
in custody and yet
you persist
in harassing my client.
You're protective, aren't you?
Of my clients.
Do you pay the rent
for all your clients
or just the ones
you really like?
Mickey D... has a hand
span of 19 centimeters.
The hand that strangled
Alison Carpenter...
has a span of 22 centimeters.
And your hand...
...22 centimeters.
You going to go
to the DA
with a connect-
the-dots hand
on a piece of
tracing paper?
It's all we got
that links him to the murder.
Everything else blew up
in the lab.
The guy's
going to walk.
Yep.
( groans )
What time is it?
Late.
How long have you been here?
A while.
I got a little time on my hands.
You figured out what happened
in the lab, didn't you?
Yeah.
( sighs )
Yeah, and, um...
I wanted you
to hear it from me.
( knocking )
You... got a minute?
I was just leaving.
Yeah, the,
uh, schedule
says you're off tonight.
I am.
Me, too.
You should be
on paid leave.
I'm fine.
You were fortunate.
And I'm not talking
about the explosion.
You, uh, you talked to Brass?
And Nick.
We got the guy.
Is that all you have to say?
Would you like to
have dinner with me?
No.
Why not?
Let's... let's have dinner.
Let's see what happens.
Sara...
( sighs )
I don't know what to do
about this.
I do.
You know, by the time
you figure it out,
you really could
be too late.