Is this some kind
of convention?
Little people convention.
Every year they come
from all over the world
to a designated city.
Socialize, network.
It's their prom, Olympics,
and New Year's Eve
all rolled into one.
Oh, hey.
Excuse me.
Don't think so, square jaw.
SIDLE:
Grissom, how
do you know this?
I get the newsletter.
BRASS:
Lawrence Ames,
clothing salesman from Phoenix.
He's 35, four foot,
five inches tall.
One of the, uh,
convention organizers
found him.
She was checking
out the stage.
There's a fashion
show tomorrow
if you're interested.
She looked up and saw him.
SIDLE:
Guy does a suicide
in a public place.
He was trying to make
a statement.
Suicide?
It's a reasonable
suspicion.
STOKES:
Suicide among
any disability group
is above average.
Being a dwarf doesn't mean
you're disabled, Nick.
It means you're...
short.
I think we've got
a little murder.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
My favorite CSI.
I was hoping you'd
get the call out.
Look who is back in town.
So, what happened, Drew?
You didn't like, uh, Idaho?
Is that it?
Had everything but you.
( chuckling ):
Yeah, right.
So, what do we got?
One body,
male Caucasian.
Looks like a home invasion.
Listen, I'm
headed next door.
I'm going to talk
to a neighbor
heard shouting,
called 9-1-1.
Keep me posted?
Always did.
Hi.
Willows.
Akers.
You clear the place?
Just finishing.
Okay.
( sighs )
( groans )
( cell phone ringing )
Yeah?
Oh, hey, Warrick.
Uh, yeah, it's, uh
some kind of home invasion
gone bad.
Don't run any lights.
I'll just process
till the coroner gets here.
Okay. Cool.
We were just pulling out
of the chili place
when dispatch radio, uh
arrived on the scene
at 1900 hours.
My partner secured
the perimeter.
I've been in here...
This your first time
on body watch?
Well...
alive...
it's inside your bowels.
Dead, it ends up
on the floor.
( gagging )
Go. Go, go, go.
Just get some air.
( chuckles )
( yells )
Suspect on location!
( grunts )
( moaning )
Out back.
Catherine,
what happened?
He went out back.
I'm all right.
I'm okay.
He must have gotten out
the back window.
You the first officer
on the scene?
When you clear a place
you clear it, do
you understand?
Yes, sir, I'm sorry.
We lost a CSI
two years ago
because
of the same mistake!
Warrick...
ease up.
My fault.
I sent him out.
Use your radio
and call for backup.
Hey...
Hey.
Are you okay?
Yeah. I'm all right.
Don't touch me.
I'm evidence.
I got some fibers here.
Possibly secondary.
This rope was
identical to the rope
around the victim's neck.
Wait, David.
Got a hair in the knot.
Killer's in the rope.
I want to preserve this
as is, so cut higher.
Yes, sir.
Hey, um, hand me a swab,
would you?
You know I could do this
for you.
Not going to hurt
any less.
( groans softly )
That cut is deep.
Damn.
All right, um,
hey, uh, turn around.
Huh?
Privacy.
The guy bodied me full-on.
I don't want Trace to miss
one hair or one fiber.
You decent?
Looks like we're up.
These scars are old.
Tell me this wasn't
bone-lengthening surgery.
ROBBINS:
Probably done
when he was a teenager.
Surgical pins
are inserted into the bone
and linked
to an external screw.
Turn the screw,
it cracks the bones.
Osteogenic cells flood in.
Callus forms
to bridge the gap.
The fractures heal
and the bone gets longer.
You have to break the bones
every four to six hours
a quarter millimeter
at a time.
Excruciating pain...
for an extra few inches.
What people will endure
to be "normal."
"What fools these mortals be."
Hmm.
So, hanging?
At least.
COD was asphyxiation
due to strangulation.
Give me a hand here.
Bruise behind the ear
is characteristic
of a hanging.
This bruise is not.
What is that,
blunt force?
Take a look at this.
Separation of the first
and second vertebrae
prior to death.
He was paralyzed?
That's something that would
only happen to a dwarf
with pseudoachondroplasia.
Physiology can make for
cervical spine instability.
So it's possible that
whoever did this
knew something
about dwarf anatomy.
Suspect on location!
He was drinking.
It was beer.
I'll go process the back.
Denim fiber from the cabinet.
Could be nothing.
And lots of smudges
but no prints worthwhile.
Yeah, I didn't get
any prints either
but I did get
a partial shoe tread
from the back gate.
And I don't think
our dead guy lived here.
Based on...?
These pictures.
Got Detective Wolf
looking for the homeowner's name
from the real estate records.
So, our home invasion robbery
may be not a home
invasion after all.
So, would you mind if we
tape-lifted your shirt?
Comb your hair
for evidence?
Evidence of what?
Well, the first person
at a crime scene
often turns out to be
a viable suspect.
I'm the one that
found his body.
I'm the one that called it in.
If you're innocent
it'll rule you out.
Go ahead.
Does he ever talk?
Yeah.
At, uh, random intervals.
I was admiring
your reaching tool.
I have one I use
to wipe my tush with.
Would you like
to take a look
at that, too?
Hey, if the world
doesn't adapt itself to you
you have to adapt yourself
to it, right?
Yeah.
You know, you probably
think I'm cold.
Pulling slots
after I found Lawrence
up there.
This is the convention.
Everything moves at warp speed.
I'm done.
Thank you.
You know, 51 weeks
in your hometown
with nothing
but average-sized people.
I have to fit a lifetime
into this week.
We all do.
Business connections,
gambling, romance.
Excuse me.
Did Lawrence have any
problems in those areas?
Romance? Not at all.
Lawrence was a pseudo.
He could have his pick
of any girl in here.
What's a pseudo?
Dwarfs with
pseudoachondroplasia
have features
and head size
like normal people.
Dwarfs with achondroplasia
have shortened limbs
and enlarged heads.
Different types of dwarfs,
different social status?
Hey... discrimination
isn't just for tall people.
Excuse me.
Isn't this, uh,
Lawrence Ames's room?
Yes.
Who are you?
( sighs )
I'm his fiancee.
We always got those looks.
I'm five-seven,
in case you were wondering.
Our concern isn't your height;
it's your proximity.
You're standing
in a potential crime scene.
Would you please
sit down here?
We want to keep
the contamination
to a minimum.
This is CSI Sidle.
We need a uniform
in room 312 right away.
Thanks.
Didn't the police
tell you not to come in here?
Yes.
But I wanted to be near
Lawrence's things.
And, um... these are
Lawrence's things?
Yes.
Sara?
Yeah?
Gouge is deeper at the bottom
than the top.
So the strike was made
coming down.
Grissom.
Did you and Mr. Ames have
an argument, say last night?
No.
You don't believe me?
Well, right now,
we believe the evidence.
What are the marks
on his forearms?
Hmm, can't say.
But I do know
that Teddy Henders died
from blunt force trauma.
From what, do you think?
A hammer, butt of a gun?
I was just going to see
if I could figure that out.
( electric razor buzzing )
( turns off razor )
"Z"?
There was a Z-Mover video game
on the floor
next to the vic.
Murder by Z-Mover.
The neighbors heard shouting.
Two guys break
and enter
and get into some kind
of an alternation.
One ends up killing the other.
And almost Catherine.
That had to be scary, huh?
I didn't have time
to be scared, David.
Oh.
Is the lipstick on this
champagne glass yours?
No champagne for me.
I'm pregnant.
Only seven weeks.
Is this your computer,
or Lawrence's?
Lawrence's.
We're going to have
to take it with us.
BROWN:
Cath?
You all right?
Don't let him get to you
like that.
I was scared...
and I still am.
Don't tell anybody.
Hey, Greg.
Hey.
Get anything
off the rope?
Yeah, a few brown hairs
around the knot.
Only one with a skin tag,
though.
And those fibers that Sara found
on the body?
Yeah?
Polyester upholstery.
Cheap rugs and
tacky furniture.
I need these hairs.
Uh, uh, no DNA tags on those.
Doesn't matter.
( scoffs )
You know, I hate it
when he does that.
I like to make a presentation,
you know?
So, present.
Eh, forget it.
Scope's interesting.
All right,
fresh epithelials.
Yeah, I found them on the rope
near the anchor point.
A minuscule sample, but useable.
How long for DNA?
Well, give me something
to compare it to.
Get me the fiancee's blood.
Well, I can't just give you
her blood.
That takes a court order.
I'm open 24 hours.
"Met you in a pseudo chat room.
Do you remember me?"
"I remember you."
( muttering )
"...to the convention
this year?
"I'd love to meet you.
"See if you can pick me out.
"Perfect face
"perfect body.
Count of three, handsome."
SIDLE:
Jessica, you knew Lawrence
was having an on-line affair
with another woman
didn't you?
BRASS:
You logged on at times
when Lawrence
was at work.
We checked his work records.
A lot of girls liked Lawrence.
He was funny and smart
and sweet.
Danielle
was different.
She was his size.
She was... perfect.
We found your skin
cells on the rope
that hung Lawrence.
You're making that up.
No, I'm not.
BRASS:
Our court order
your blood.
I did not put a noose
around my fiancé's neck.
Then explain how
your skin cells
got on the rope.
I can't.
Hey.
Confronted the fiancee;
she stonewalled us.
Brass told her
not to leave town.
He sounded a bit
like Jack Lord,
don't you think?
Well, she can go
wherever she wants to.
She didn't do it.
Take a look.
Hair from the knot.
They look thin.
Diameter's 60% less than normal.
Tensile strength
is also
way below normal.
You have a cross section?
Mm-hmm.
Hmm. No pigment
at the central core.
No color.
Cartilage hair hypoplasia.
C.H.H.
It's characterized
by fine, brittle body hair.
It's an extremely rare syndrome.
It's a form of dwarfism.
Okay.
So, back to the midgets.
Nick... dwarfs or little people.
You'll need to know
what to look for.
So, I'll put together a list
of C.H.H. attributes.
Well, you better do it fast.
The convention's over
in two days.
After that,
the little people go home
and we lose all our suspects.
Ms. Grace?
Excuse me.
I need your help.
What now? My DNA?
No, actually... your eyes.
GRACE:
I'm sorry, I don't recognize her
and a girl this pretty
I would remember.
The guys would
still be drooling.
Well, according
to the police
there's no one named
Danielle registered
at the hotel
or at the convention.
You expected an Internet
handle to be a real name?
Maybe the girl
got cold feet.
My first IOLP convention--
I walk in, see 200 dwarfs
staring back at me
and what goes
through my head?
"There's no way
I look like these people."
I ran.
But you went back.
Eventually.
I guess I realized
it's nice to see
eye-to-eye with someone.
Mm.
I get the impression that's
a little tough for you.
"The freaks have looked
at her in a secret way
"and tried to connect
their eyes with hers
"as though to say,
'We know who you are.
We are you.'"
Faulkner.
Close.
Another southern writer.
Carson McCullers.
I think we look for
the differences in each other
to prove that we're not alone.
What's yours?
Your difference?
Mine's the worst.
Random gene.
Anyone can have a dwarf.
Sometimes I've even seen terror
in average-size people's eyes.
I remind them that
their little carbon copies
might not be
such a copy after all.
Well, mine's genetic
progressive
and impossible to predict.
And hard to notice...
unless you tell someone.
Got your beep.
What'd you get?
Denim fibers at 400x.
The skin
from the dead guy
and the denim found in
the cabinet were both coated
in the same substance.
You get a breakdown?
Yeah, partially hydrogenated
soy bean oil
traces of beef fat, sugar
and potato starch.
Cooking grease.
That would explain the marks
on the guy's forearms.
Grease burns.
So there's a good chance
the victim worked
in a fast food joint.
WOLF:
I got a feeling
they both did.
The owner of the house
has a franchise
of fast food places.
Uh, Fast
and Fresh Burgers.
I just got off the phone
with him from Hawaii.
Alvin Jackson.
Three stores in the Vegas area.
And he's on his
yearly
vacation.
Something his employees
would definitely know.
Get any addresses?
You bet.
Let's go check it out.
SIDLE:
We're looking for
anything in the picture
that might
give us a way to find her.
Something in the background
that determines location
a useful reflection, anything.
Huh...
Oh, I get it.
This is like
a test, right?
What do you mean?
Individual
hair shadows
are amorphous when they
should be distinct.
In these two areas--
here and here-- they're
on the same focal plane
but this one's sharp
and this one's fuzzy.
This picture's a fake?
A composite.
A very good one.
This explains
why nobody ever saw her.
She only exists in pixels.
Nat King Cole.
Excuse me?
Archie would you separate
the composite elements, please?
Yup.
The image
was built out of these.
GRISSOM:
Now if you could,
pull up a photo
of the victim,
grey scale.
There's a theory in art
that the Mona Lisa was really
a feminized version
of Leonardo da Vinci
himself.
Concept suggests...
deep down we're all narcissists?
Yeah.
What attracts us the most
is ourselves.
Scale to match the original
picture with Danielle.
SIDLE:
Danielle is
a virtual woman
created to attract and lure
Lawrence Ames...
away from his
fiancee, maybe?
BRASS:
Boy, do I have
good timing, or what?
I did a little checking
with the phone company.
In the past year,
Lawrence Ames received
over 200 calls
from Melanie Grace.
The same woman
that found him dead.
He got call-blocking
against her two months ago.
Well, that's interesting.
That's the same time
Danielle started
sending him
instant messages.
Yes, I called Lawrence.
We met in a chat room.
He also called me.
Did you look at
my phone records?
He eventually
blocked your calls.
The same week he got engaged
to Jessica Marcus.
It was at that time
he began receiving
messages from...
a perfect woman...
...who doesn't really exist.
You think that I would do that?
Present myself
to a man
as anything other than who I am?
If it would break up
his new engagement.
So what happened?
You went to the convention
you saw him with his tall
girlfriend and you go to Plan B?
You think I'm capable of that?
Killing because a woman
has some height on me?
Pretending to be
an ideal...
If you think that...
then I was wrong about you.
Hey.
Do you mind, little man?
I'm trying to work here.
Really?
Yeah.
You making any progress,
CSI man?
Some.
Uh-huh.
Are we getting your
A-game or your B-game?
Come again?
You see
us little people
we're used to getting
the short end of the stick.
( chuckles )
You don't get to laugh at that.
What I want
to know is
are you treating this like
a case or like a joke?
Well, a man was killed;
that's no joke.
You got my A-game.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Carry on.
Uh, Grissom.
There's, uh, something
weird going on
with the hairs
from the ropes.
Well, not weird.
More like... hair-raising.
Sorry, bad one.
Um, okay,
at first I thought
that maybe I was
doing something wrong--
running too many
DNA samples, you know
seeing things.
Greg?
( exhales )
Uh, the dwarf hair
has seven alleles in common
with Jessica Marcus's
skin cells.
The two donors are related.
Profiles say so.
( cell phone ringing )
Grissom.
STOKES:
He looked like he fit
your profile.
So, I asked around.
Two little people
confirmed he has C.H.H.
Okay, thank you.
Yeah.
Kevin Marcus?
Buying or browsing?
Maybe a little bit
of both.
Rope for makeshift
banisters, huh?
That rag rope... cuts the hands.
Now you feel this nylon.
Go ahead
feel that.
I do trade shows
mail order...
I even sold to this convention.
So what do you,
buy from wholesalers
and then repackage
in your home?
Yeah, Chicago.
Well, that explains
how your daughter's skin cells
got all over the rope
that hung
Lawrence Ames.
Your daughter's name
is Jessica, right?
The lab
also found
your hair all over that rope.
Well, I touch
all the merchandise.
Nice try, Kev.
They hair
was caught in the noose.
Did you know
your father killed Lawrence?
That's what they told me
but I couldn't believe it.
I still can't.
So you created
Danielle
to break up your
daughter's engagement.
That's an interesting theory.
What?
You guys trace an online
account to my credit card
or something like that?
Oh, no, wait.
Um, I use a free ISP.
That means no name,
no trail, no case.
Mr. Marcus, in your business
you deal with proportions,
correct?
You provide little people
with what they need
to compensate
for their proportions
and to live with them.
You know what little people
aspire to be.
Your, uh,
logo is interesting.
Da Vinci's "Vitruvian Man."
In the perfect human form,
arm span equals height.
You're very aware
of what, uh
people are looking for
in a mate
aren't you?
The night before he died,
Lawrence and I had a fight
about Danielle.
Are still
in contact with her?
She e-mails
or IM's.
I don't answer. I love you.
You're lying.
You're cheating on me!
And I ran
out of the house
and I went to my dad.
I was crying and he told me
to leave Lawrence
but I couldn't because...
I... I loved him.
I'm having
our baby.
And I went back to our room
and we made up.
And the next night...
he said he was going out
to meet a friend.
I'll be back
in an hour.
And he never came back.
So, what'd you have
against the guy?
What are you, blind?
He was a dwarf.
My wife and I
our daughter--
a genetic miracle.
One-in-four shot
she'd be an average.
And she was
a beautiful average.
So your wife is also a dwarf.
Yeah.
Jessica didn't have
to fight the world
every day, like we did.
We freed her from all that.
But that
little bastard
kept dragging her
right back down into it.
So you killed him.
I said I didn't like the guy.
I didn't kill anybody.
( exhales deeply )
Can we prove it?
Not yet.
The rope was anchored
to the lighting truss
which was at least five feet
over his head.
So?
He can barely lift his arms
above his shoulders.
He suffers from
lumbar lordosis
swayback...
which is typical of C.H.H.
and it limits his mobility
even more.
Hey, the guy put a rope
around the victim's neck.
Yeah, but how did he hang him?
Listen, Catherine
me and Warrick
can handle this.
I'm going in.
Well, the guy
assaulted you.
You don't have to put yourself
through this, you know.
I don't, I'll be scared
of the next guy
and the one after that.
Shoe tread, denim fiber,
a lot of cooking grease.
Based on that evidence,
they all did it.
All right, so we
take them one by one.
Transfer works both ways.
( unzipping )
Warrick?
Blow your nose.
I don't gotta.
( blowing )
Guess.
I don't think so.
Then I guess I'll just
have to look for myself.
You want to look
at my boogers,
lady, go ahead.
Hey!
Nose hairs...
are nature's filter.
Traps all
kinds of things.
Dust, dirt...
...fingerprint powder.
( exhales )
You did it.
( grunting )
You inhaled the fingerprint dust
I was using.
We went up there
to party 'cause the
boss was out of town
and I saw the
Z-Mover first
but Teddy... Teddy...
I saw it first.
It's mine.
I called it.
You want it,
you bastard?!
I didn't mean
to kill him.
It was
an accident.
I mean, I...
Get up.
I didn't mean...
You all right?
Yeah.
NICK:
Hey, did you get anything else
off that laptop?
No, a bunch of the files
were corrupted.
Archie's taking
another run at them.
( sighs )
Victim was paralyzed,
couldn't fight back.
Kevin Marcus puts the
rope around his neck
makes a slip knot.
And ties off
the other end
on the truss
even though there
is no way
he could
have reached it.
No way he could've
reached it.
Nick, what
are you doing?
Changing my perspective.
( groans ):
Oh, man.
Can you imagine going
through life at
this height?
They do okay.
If the world doesn't adapt
itself to you, you...
...Adapt yourself to it.
Where's Grissom?
( patrons talking )
Grissom?
We know how
he did it.
BRASS:
Your wheelchair
was in the booth
at the convention.
The fibers from the seat cover
to your wheelchair
match the fibers
we found on the victim.
Uh, faux, fake sheepskin.
We also know
how you got Mr. Ames
into the theater.
Our lab retrieved
a final instant message
to Lawrence
from Danielle.
Mr. Marcus, what
are you doing here?
It's enough to convict you.
GRISSOM:
May I ask
a question?
How did you get him
into the wheelchair?
Well... I appealed
to his vanity.
I told him I needed
a brochure model
to sell my new chair.
You don't want me
near your daughter
but you want me
to hawk your chairs?
I never said
you weren't handsome.
I mean, come on--
your face, your build--
a million chairs, "Sold."
Great, come on.
Hop in.
Hop in, let me see you in there.
Come on.
Model for me.
There you go.
Wait, let me make an adjustment
for you, here.
I paralyzed him.
I couldn't let Jessica
marry him.
Any kid they have...
a 50% chance
it would be a dwarf.
You have
to understand that.
( sighs )
It's genetics.
Mr. Marcus, I think
you should know...
your daughter is
already pregnant
by Lawrence Ames.
You know
what's really sad?
This wasn't just a murder.
It was a hate crime.
Kevin Marcus hated himself.
Dr. Grissom,
welcome back.
Take care of yourself.