( rapid breathing )
( rapid heartbeat )
( phone ringing )
Grissom... a stay.
New evidence appeal:
hair analysis.
I already overnighted
the six pubic hairs
found on the victim
to Norfolk--
Department of Criminal Justice--
for mitochondrial DNA analysis.
Defense thinks DNA's
a magic pill for exoneration.
I doubt if it's going to change
the outcome.
You don't know
what I'm talking about.
Not really.
People v. John Mathers.
Serial. Western LVU.
I was a rookie...
Three dead coeds?
All sexually assaulted,
but no semen was found.
Suspected he wore a condom.
Dumped in garbage bags.
Case with the
strongest evidence
was victim number three:
Charlene Roth.
Mathers, a campus
security guard
got murder one for that.
When are you going
to get the test back?
I put a rush on it.
Is this your first one?
First to exhaust
all of his appeals
and get an execution date.
How many have you had?
Two.
So, how do you
feel about it?
Mathers was convicted
and sent to death row
by a jury of his peers.
I played a small part.
I presented my findings...
Non-responsive.
Okay.
I haven't figured
out how I feel yet.
It's just about evidence.
It's not up to you
whether he lives or dies.
Case has no face.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
BRASS:
Cops did a welfare check
on this residence.
A girl, 17,
didn't show up for work
and they found
Dad passed out
on the sofa
in a blood-soaked
T-shirt.
Did he have anything to
say about his daughter?
Mr. Reston, uh,
can't remember what day it is.
Claims he was in a bar fight.
"Pass" test?
His blood alcohol level is .37.
Ooh... alcoholic.
Yeah.
Lucky me.
( loudly ):
Hey, buddy, this is Sara Sidle
of the Las Vegas Crime Lab.
She's going to ask you
some questions.
Sir, I need your shirt
and I need to see your hands.
Shirt and hands!
( TV playing )
Hey.
People are pigs.
Don't insult
the pigs, Nick.
They're actually
very clean.
Must be the girl's room.
Doesn't seem like
the same house.
Dead bolts on her bedroom door.
Trying to keep
something out.
Hmm.
A bedroom refrigerator?
There's milk, fruit...
a toaster?
Guess they weren't much
on family dinners.
( camera clicking )
Nick?
A gi and a black belt.
Trained in the art
of self-defense.
( camera clicking )
( sighs )
I'll bag it.
BROWN:
I heard Mathers
had that I.V. in his arm
and everything,
when that call came in.
Never had a death penalty case
get that far.
Just working it all out?
Yeah. Old case, new eyes,
new technology.
This evidence was processed,
what, 15 years ago?
That was before DNA.
Now that the case
has been reopened
I can re-evaluate
all three murders.
We always thought Mathers
was good for the other two
but if they overturn
Charlene Roth with
the new DNA
we can go back and try Mathers
with the other two murders
with the new evidence.
Keep Mathers in prison.
You pro or con?
Pro, if he did it.
The applications sucks, though.
There's a lot of brown skin
on that row.
Yeah.
What about you?
I try not to give it
much thought.
I stick to the work.
Really?
Campus police
found the victim
Charlene Roth in
this trash bag.
The trash bag, yeah.
I was looking at that.
Processed with superglue,
rhodamine, laser.
No prints found though.
Who's working
the print lab tonight?
Franco. Just off of days.
Hey, I hear you're
cheating on me
with an out-of-state
DNA analyst.
Apples and oranges, Greg.
15-year-old hair samples
no roots, room-
temperature storage.
Room temp?
Yeah, that's how we
stored hair evidence
back then.
Microscopy was king.
Really? I thought
Elvis was king.
And you are how old?
Age is irrelevant
in our relationship.
Maybe so, but
face it, Greg
you just don't
have the equipment.
The government results
won't give you an
individual profile
and you can't put
them through CODIS.
Well, maternal lineage
is good enough on this one.
No one else on Mathers'
mother's side is a suspect.
So, if it's a match,
the stay is lifted
he's back in the chamber.
If not, we're back in court.
( clock ticking )
Jacqui...
I'm so glad
you're back on nights.
Got a good one for you.
Trash bag?
Yeah, love it.
Give it some
vacuum metal deposition.
Hottest thing going for plastic.
If there's anything to be found,
my machine'll find it.
And, um, super-rush.
You're in a race
with the federal lab.
Make my night;
love to compete
with the Feds.
You and me need
to catch up.
How's Lindsey?
Second grade, tons of homework.
Lucky for her
she got your smarts,
not Eddie's.
Now I know why
I missed you so much.
So, page me
as soon as you're done.
Mm-hmm.
Putting you up first.
You owe me a beer.
Yep.
( dog barks in distance )
( garbled radio transmission)
Looks like somebody's
been doing some digging.
Glock.
Laser sight.
Slide's missing.
Mr. Reston was a bit
of a garage tinkerer.
Great. Drunks with guns.
Hey.
GRISSOM:
M11-9.
Empty box.
He didn't have
any kind of weapon.
Okay, we're into it.
I'm going to take
Reston's shirt back
to Greg.
Mm-hm. Do me a favor.
Yeah?
Inside, bloody towel,
bagged and tagged.
You got it.
Thanks.
Woo. After this place,
I need a shower.
( board creaks )
STOKES:
There's our M11.
16-round magazine.
Two remaining.
One in the chamber.
Modified to fully automatic.
Up to 14 rounds expended
and unaccounted for.
Missing girl's old man's
got blood all over him.
Blood in her room...
I think it's time
for dear old dad
to go to detox.
I would like a vanilla
ice soy blended latte, please.
Ms. Willows.
Yes?
Sally Roth.
My husband Tom.
I'm sorry.
Do I know you?
We're Charlene Roth's parents.
Mr. and Mrs. Roth.
I'm sorry.
I didn't recognize you.
We were just wondering
if you had any news.
You know...
any news has to go through
the Attorney General's office.
I can't divulge any information
on an open case.
He was convicted.
It is not an open case to us.
I was confident at trial.
I'm still confident.
The evidence is solid.
If the court overturns
the conv...
We just can't go through
another trial.
( phone rings )
Uh, well, you will have
an answer very soon.
I'm sure of it.
Excuse me. I need to go.
What's going on?
I'm not on call.
I know.
I called you
because your name's
on the memo.
Which memo?
Young female, bound,
trash bag.
Copycats come out
of the woodwork
every time there's
an execution.
Mather's attorney is going
to have a field day.
Everybody liked Mathers
for the Kent and Reese cases
but the DA wouldn't file
because he already had
a slam dunk
with Charlene Roth.
How many times
can you fry a guy?
Right.
Maintenance guy
thought it was trash.
Picked it up,
ripped open.
Body dump.
Just like 15 years ago.
( buzzing )
PHILLIPS:
You ready for me?
Not yet.
May I?
Sure.
What do you think this is?
That's Grissom's bailiwick,
not mine.
That's what I was thinking--
bug.
What you got?
Two-fer.
Looks like some kind
of a bug casing
and black fibers.
She's all yours, David.
How come I get you?
Grissom says
it's precautionary
in case Mathers
gets overturned
and you get swamped.
I'm glad to have
the help.
This looks familiar.
A little too familiar.
Let's figure out
how she got here.
( beeping )
( beeping rapidly )
Hey, Griss...
found a density change.
The screen's showing something.
What's your depth estimate?
Two and a half feet.
Oh, dear.
Shovels and screens,
chutes and ladders.
Yeah.
A little more.
There we go.
She's in rigor.
At least 12 hours.
Get out your ten card
and print her.
But look out
for this blue paint.
Catherine's going
to need to see it.
Well, we got
something else
to hold Reston on:
Illegal burial
of a domestic animal.
Weak.
I'll cover him back up.
So Debbie Reston
never showed up at work
and she's not buried
in the backyard.
Where did Debbie go?
I don't know her schedule.
She works, goes to school.
I hardly ever see her.
GRISSOM:
She's 17.
She lives in your house.
You're going
to have to do better than that.
Stuck-up bitch is ashamed of me.
Can't wait to graduate
high school and move out.
She's already got
a job:
coffee shop.
Got a car.
What kind of car?
VW convertible, blue.
And as a concerned parent,
you're going to ask me
to put out a broadcast,
aren't you?
Whatever.
Is the car in her name
or yours?
I'm going to need
the license plate number.
You listening to me?
I just left Greg in DNA.
Blood on Reston's shirt
is his own.
Blood on the towel?
Eight markers match.
Family member.
There's only two people
in the house.
It's probably Debbie's
but there isn't that much
blood on the towel.
So what?
Innocuous injury?
That's what
I'm thinking.
You got kids?
They think it's all about them.
Like I owe her.
You owe your daughter more
than being a drunk.
You know, I think
that maybe jail
might be the best thing
for you right now.
I think she just took off...
like her mother.
Can you believe
this guy?
I wouldn't blame
his kid
if she just took off.
Hey. Catherine and I
got a case
at the university--
dead female.
Prints just came back.
Matches your
missing girl,
Debbie Reston.
Brass just put a broadcast out
on her car.
Then my guys
will find it.
They're posting her now.
ROBBINS:
Crazy world out there.
Sorry I'm late.
So, where are we?
Debbie Reston, 17.
She was taking a night class
at Western LVU.
Prereq for early admission.
So technically she was
a Western LVU student.
Yep. Just like
Mathers' other victims.
Thought Mathers
was on Death Row.
Mm-hmm.
Doc, you were here back then.
Tell me why this one's
different.
Suspect must be
intimately familiar
with the minutiae
of the prior cases.
What's identical:
cause of death-- strangulation.
Bruising on her wrists
plastic zip tie,
navy-blue paint.
There is one new element:
defensive wounds on the hands.
Whatever she grabbed onto
shattered
and caused these lacerations.
Is that before or after
she got the paint on her hands?
After.
One of these cuts
sliced right through the paint.
The paint was there first.
It's still wet.
So she's been dead
at least 12 hours, right?
Right.
What kind of paint
doesn't dry in 12 hours,
I wonder.
( clock ticking )
( whirring )
Ms. Willows.
I heard you're investigating
the murder at Western LVU.
Female, young, bound
dumped in a trash bag.
( clearing throat )
You know that I can't confirm
or deny any information
regarding an active
investigation.
Excuse me.
Ms. Willows, my client's
life is on the line here.
We've always maintained
John Mathers' innocence.
Ms. Campbell, I have
no personal opinion
about your client.
I tested the evidence
in his case
and that evidence failed
to exonerate him.
15 years ago.
Before DNA.
Before the real killer
struck again.
You are going to test
the pubic hair
sent to the federal lab
against the new suspect...
What suspect?
I can't help you.
You CSIs are biased
for the prosecution.
You decide ahead
of time
how you want the
evidence to come out.
Ms. Campbell, I am only
an interpreter of the evidence.
I know how to make
the evidence speak to me.
I don't care about the outcome.
How about guilt or innocence?
John was 15 seconds
from execution.
Sure you're not biased?
I hear the same
evidence speaking.
You know what
it's telling me.
The killer's still out there.
( garbled radio transmission)
It's
Debbie Reston's car.
Looks like you and I are
officially running
with
the same case.
Yeah?
It's got to be the cleanest
tape lift I've ever seen.
There's no stains
of any kind in this car.
Whatever happened to her
happened after she
left her car.
Debbie Reston was taking
Economics 101.
6:00 to 8:00 p.m.
Never missed a class
before last night.
Well, this is
my alma mater.
Econ 101-- that's Sabian Hall.
It's a long walk from here
but I know the way.
( beeping )
I'll have to catch
up with you.
Damn.
It's still wet.
What's the first thing you'd do
if you got paint on your hands?
Wash it off.
GRISSOM:
We found glass
in the lacerations
on her right hand.
I'll see if I can get
a match from this.
He painted the railing and just
waited by the water fountain.
Victim was like a fly
in a spiderweb.
We just learned something
we didn't know about
the prior murders.
Yes, what the paint
was all about.
And if we just learned
about it now
how did the copycat killer know?
Looks like Debbie isn't
the only one
who got paint on her hands.
Well, maybe he was waiting
till he saw the girl he wanted.
That's creepy.
I'll call the Fire Department,
get a circular saw.
Take this back
to the lab.
I've got a backpack.
Wallet...
Debbie Reston.
Credit cards...
money, keys.
Not what he was looking for.
What are you doing?
I found pieces of this
in the victim's hair.
What's it look like
to you?
Hmm, what does
it sound like?
With the exception
of the termite queen
the cicada is the longest-living
insect.
Spends 17 years dormant
underground
and then the cicada nymph
emerges and sheds its skin.
As adults they flit
around
for about five
weeks of activity
in the hot sun
and then they die.
They spend their
whole lives waiting
for the end.
Not unlike death row.
( high-pitched whirring )
WARRICK:
This is the spot.
You can see the path
and the rail.
Well, and if
she was trying
to clean off her right hand
in this fountain
she would have had to be
in this position.
And he waited till
her back was turned...
and came up behind her.
I found some more glass.
Looks polarized.
Well, lightbulb glass
isn't polarized.
Eyeglasses are.
Yeah.
You know, she was a black belt.
Maybe she fought back.
That would explain
why she had defensive wounds
and none
of the other victims did.
( yelling )
Sorry about the "no print"
results on the Mathers' case.
Make it up to me.
I got a new case.
New bag.
( electrical crackling )
It's only partial
but I've got a hit off less.
Great.
Hey, you know that black fiber
that Catherine pulled from
Debbie Reston's hair?
STOKES:
Yeah.
It's trilobal.
Vehicle upholstery.
It's not from her car.
Her upholstery is red.
That's good for us.
She was killed
at the water fountain
but the body was dumped
at the library.
You can't carry a body
in plain sight on campus
even in at night.
Odds are decent we're looking
at a fiber
from the killer's vehicle.
Generic Chevy.
Well, that kind
of narrows it down.
WARRICK:
The glass on the left
is not polarized.
There's not color change.
What, from the busted
security light?
Yeah, the one found
in the path.
Not the one found
in her hand.
Okay, the guy broke
the bulb on purpose.
Gives him an advantage--
cover of darkness.
I'll buy that, but the glass
on the right was the one
extracted from the cuts
on her hand.
And it matches the glass
that Catherine found
near the water fountain.
Confirms that Debbie
fought with her attacker.
Suspect's minus
one point two five.
What is that, 20/80?
That's like half of mine.
It's not much of a correction.
Great. We're looking for a guy
with a 20/80 prescription
who drives a Chevy
with black interior.
Hey.
Got your report from the feds.
Why did it come to you?
Because they returned
the DNA evidence to me.
I took a look
at the results.
Didn't think you'd mind.
I do.
All six hairs are a match
to Mathers.
He raped and murdered
Charlene Roth.
Dead bang. Airtight.
Good night, John.
How are you coming
with that twist tie, Greg?
The new case?
Yeah.
Working on it.
Good.
Keep working on it.
Slam dunk on Mathers.
Good.
The paint on
Debbie Reston's hands...
Yeah?
...oil-based blue.
Oil-based?
That's for canvases,
not railings.
Not only that, it was mixed
with 30-weight motor oil.
Which isn't a component
of any commercial paint.
As an additive however...
keeps paint from drying.
Okay...
he knew what he was doing.
Expanding his window
of opportunity.
Hello?
Hairs.
Hopefully from his paintbrush.
And the paint matches
Western LVU shade of blue.
He knows a lot about paint.
WILLOWS:
He knows a lot
about that campus.
I don't know
what I can tell you.
I've only been here
since '95.
Well, is there anyone
in the art department
who was here when
the first murders
took place?
A couple of the guys
predate me.
I'll ask around.
Are any of these brushes
made with badger hair?
We artists covet
our brushes.
That's Russian
blue squirrel...
Japanese synthetic...
badger.
In the oil paint sample
we collected
we found both badger hair
and nylon bristles.
Anyone who's studied art
would never use nylon with oils
unless they were
using the paint
for something else.
When brushes age,
they shed hairs.
Then, if they used
a nylon brush the next time...
Say I wanted
a badger hair paintbrush--
where would I buy one?
Student Union sells them.
Most art stores.
You can get them cheaper
on the Internet.
Sorry. I was admiring
your frames.
Nice.
The results are back
on the zip tie
you removed from
Debbie Reston's wrists.
No foreign
epithelials
but I did find
an errant hair
DNA tag still attached.
It's not Debbie Reston's.
Catherine asked me
to cross-check
everything with the old cases.
It actually belongs
to Janet Kent.
Janet Kent-- the first victim?
I know.
So Janet Kent's killer
saved some of her hair
and planted it on
Debbie Reston 15 years later
on the night
that John Mathers
was set to be
executed.
John Mathers is the copycat.
Yeah.
And the original killer's
still out there
playing a really twisted game.
Oh. Hey.
Mathers' execution's
back on.
The Roths asked me
to sit with them.
Is that a good idea?
I just need to do it.
Why?
It's like your
first autopsy...
your first
murdered child.
You can make it
through that
you can keep
doing this work.
All the paints
match all the victims
except for Charlene Roth.
See, being capable of
matching paint samples
that are 15 years apart
that's why I keep
doing this work.
Well, that's the difference
between you and me.
Hey.
Dean of the Art School
came up with a name.
A Cody Lewis.
He was a grad student
at WLVU in the late '80s
same time the three girls
were murdered.
He left just after the Roth case
for a post-doc in Louisiana.
Where is he now?
WLVU since September.
He's an assistant professor
there.
So you like to paint
dead girls?
I paint what I feel.
Yeah, sure.
You know,
you're an artist.
So back in '87
when you painted this girl
what were you feeling?
That you wanted her to die?
What's the subject matter
this week?
More dead girls?
I haven't been doing a
lot of painting lately.
Uh-huh.
So it's just a coincidence
that another coed gets murdered
right after you show up
in Vegas, right?
Listen, I painted that
15 years ago.
Right after that second
girl was murdered...
Marjorie something.
Really affected me.
Affected everyone.
Yeah, but it affected you more.
Because you knew
the first victim.
Janet Kent.
Yeah, I knew Janet.
Come on, Cody, man.
You two had a thing.
We had a date.
I took her to a
Springsteen show.
We had drinks afterwards
and that was it.
So what, did she reject you?
Did she give you
the "Cody, we can still
be friends"?
That speech?
No.
Never got that far.
I was just wondering
because some guys can't
take "no" for an answer.
But that's not you, right?
Okay, I'm getting this to Trace.
Hey, check out
the vehicle's upholstery.
It's black and
it's a Chevy...
We got nothing.
Nobody cleans a car this good.
There is no evidence
that Debbie Reston
was transported in this vehicle.
Still doesn't rule out
Cody Lewis as a suspect.
You got to wonder when a guy
gives it up this easily.
Prints, DNA, his car...
Yeah, well...
maybe he's thinks
he's some kind of smart guy
you know,
covering all the bases.
Or maybe
he didn't do it.
What's that?
His prints don't match
the partial
on the Debbie Reston
trash bag.
Wonderful.
Thanks.
Ammonia... in case
anyone starts to feel...
unsteady.
I keep racking my brain
going over these
unsolved murder cases.
And I keep coming back
to the fact
that they're 15 years apart.
That means
he's either out of town
or in the joint.
Why wouldn't he
take his business
to some other college
if it was only
about young girls?
It's got to be personal.
He wanted to kill
those girls.
( heart beating )
( heartbeat slowing )
I mean, I don't know
much about bugs
but most animals hunt
in their own backyard.
True of insects as well.
You know why?
It's where they feel
most comfortable.
And where they can
blend in the best.
This guy had ties
to Western LVU.
He paints a railing
on a campus walkway.
I tried it;
took me about five minutes.
My guys were all
over that school.
Nobody remembers
seeing anything.
Probably because there
wasn't much to see.
He must've looked
as though he belonged.
Like the insects, he blended in.
( sighs heavily )
Yeah.
You off the clock?
I guess.
( protesters yelling )
He's going to kill again.
Yeah.
And all we've got
is a partial fingerprint
and an MO that may lead us
in the right direction.
You know sometimes
in this job
I'd rather be lucky
than good.
Maybe next time
we'll get lucky.
I don't believe in luck.
My only real purpose is to be
smarter than the bad guys
to find the evidence
that they didn't know
they left behind
and make sense of it all.
It makes me very uncomfortable
to realize that this guy...
may be smarter than me.