( rap music plays )
( applause and cheering )
♪ Don't sweat it,
time to test it ♪
♪ Let's get messed up,
throw your best stuff ♪
♪ Don't sweat it,
time to test it ♪
♪ Let's get messed up,
throw your best stuff ♪
( both grunting )
( applause and cheering )
( shutter clicks )
( grunting )
( bell dings )
REFEREE:
That's enough!
( applause and cheering )
Come on, Laroi.
He's okay!
We're going to dry
it up, Laroi.
We're going to dry it up.
Take it, Paul.
I got that.
Suck it up.
Suck it up, son.
Lo teine donde
deseas!
Â¿Me entiendes
lo que te digo?
El cuerpo...
siempre moviendo...
Laroi, listen to me!
You keep your
hands up, hear?
He's killing you
with that left.
Bum don't got the heart
to put me down.
Yeah, well, you
better start
throwing your hands,
hook to the body
hook to the head,
upper cut.
Like we worked
it in the gym.
( bell dings )
( applause and cheering )
( grunting )
( cheering fades out )
( blow landing )
( thudding )
( cheering fades in )
One!
Two!
Three!
Laroi!
Laroi, talk to me!
Come on, Laroi!
Come on, baby,
talk to me.
Laroi!
Come on, get the doctor!
Step it!
( Brass sighing )
Laroi, "The Fists of" Steele.
BROWN:
WFB welterweight
champion.
19 wins.
One loss.
Boxers have died
in the ring before.
Why is this one a crime?
Casino management got a heads-up
from the sports book.
Five hours before
the opening bell
Steele goes from
a two-to-one favorite
to a five-to-one
underdog.
Fight fixing?
Yeah.
That's a felony.
And if death occurs
during commission of a felony,
that's a murder.
( beeping )
( shutter clicks )
Gang member.
Tenth Street
Vandals.
Isolated incident
or they having a war?
It's hard to tell.
Vandals are based
in L.A.
but on a weekend
like this...
brings
knuckleheads in
from all over.
Witnesses?
They were all in
the bathroom.
Aren't they always?
( beeping )
We are just trying to
be reasonable here.
I am not giving this back
unless I get my ring.
Mrs. Ramsey, it
is not our policy
to allow clients to...
Oh, really? I guess you need
a new policy, don't you?
Now you are being
unreasonable.
Now you...
Smash and grab.
Left that behind.
How many guys?
One.
Yeah.
Waited till the manager
was alone
knocked her down
and hopped the counter.
Got away with a whole
sack full of stones.
It takes some stones
to pull off a job like this.
Good evening, gentlemen.
What have we got?
Well, you and I have
got a dead boxer.
Nick, you're going to
get to run this solo.
Yeah?
Yeah.
We're tapped out.
Welcome to fight night.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
Okay. What are we looking for?
Blinding agents
in the Vaseline
stimulants in
the water...
So...
basically, everything
goes to tox.
Yeah.
Nice sport.
Well, it's only dirty
if you make it dirty.
You know, boxing's about
discipline.
It's two guys beating
their brains out
in a race for early-onset
Parkinson's.
No, no, you know,
it's mind and body.
Mind and body.
If you train one
and not the other
you're half a person.
What'd you find?
Saliva.
Oh, the spit bucket.
What's so funny?
Smiling, uh, represses
the gag reflex.
This is coming from
the same woman
who processed fecal fat
from a ruptured colon.
Every crim's got
at least one problem area.
Mine's saliva.
Want me to get
that for you?
No, no.
You're sure.
Mind and body, right?
REFEREE:
Everybody knew
they hated each other.
They fought two times before.
Title wasn't even
on the line tonight.
Just pride.
How'd the other
fights go down?
I didn't get to ref
them, but I saw them...
$39.95 a pop.
Damn pay-per-view's
just like stealing, but
they were good fights.
Laroi won both
of them.
First one was a knockout
in the eighth
off this sweet right hook.
The other was a...
a TKO in the tenth, yeah.
Uh, he really dropped the hammer
on Molina that time.
Well, evidently,
Molina hammered back tonight.
Two previous wins
by knockout...
tonight, he dies.
What's up with that?
What do you mean?
Did you notice anything
out of the ordinary
about either fighter?
Slowed reactions,
unusual strength?
All I noticed is that boy took
one hell of a beating.
I got a gun.
Make that two.
WILLOWS:
Put up a couple of booths
we could have ourselves
a gun show out here.
Disposable firearms.
They know we can't link
them to the weapons
if we can't find
the weapons on them.
Smith &amp;amp; Wesson .40.
High end.
They're stealing their
way to better guns.
And bringing them to Vegas
for target practice.
Great.
That's everything
he got.
What's it
highlighted for?
It's a Riviera necklace.
We loaned it to a couple
for the fight
and they refuse
to return it
until we return
the ring
that they brought
in for cleaning.
Which was stolen along
with the other items, right?
Exactly--
and they won't leave
until we get this
sorted out.
Can you help me out here?
Sorry, mediation's
not really my thing.
Thanks.
Mm-hmm.
O'Riley?
Stokes, listen,
I'm at a smash and grab.
Lots of glass, a little blood.
Do me a favor:
Check the local hospitals.
Anyone comes in with
a forearm laceration,
it could be our guy.
Thanks, man.
I promoted this
match, Mr. Grissom.
I spent 16 months
of my life stroking
fighters, managers, handlers,
and kissing a whole lot of ass
that never got past junior high
and I resent
the implication
that the fight was fixed,
or that Laroi Steele's death
was anything
other than a tragedy.
These photographs are from...?
The last
Steele-Molina fight.
What, does he use them
for motivation?
And for show.
Boxing is theater.
Well, according to
your poster, this fight
was about revenge.
Boxers fight
for money.
The rest of it is just hype.
These Mr. Molina's?
Yeah.
From tonight's fight?
Technically,
after a fight
those gloves
become property
of the Boxing Commission.
Right now, they're evidence,
so they belong to me.
What do you think
you're going to find
on those gloves--
liniment?
Like Sonny Liston used
to blind Cassius Clay?
The sport has come a long way
since then.
It's still
two skulls and four fists.
It hasn't come that far.
What did you find?
GRISSOM:
What appears to be
a unique metal: mercury.
Like in a
thermometer?
Amongst other things.
Looks like
it was fight night
for a lot of people.
It sure does.
And some guys
get paid
a million bucks
for it.
Sorry to keep you waiting, but,
uh, Commission rules, you know?
Before and
after a fight.
Boxing and drugs
don't mix, you know?
All yours.
So... Â¿que onda?
What's the crime lab
want with me?
Well, for starters,
we need to see your hands.
Why?
Is that a "no"?
No.
One more.
Now, who do you think
you're looking at--
Felix Trinidad?
Who is that?
Felix Trinidad
is a fighter
who was once accused
of dipping his wraps
in ice water
before a fight.
It turns the tape and gauze
into a hardened cast.
It's like punching
with concrete.
And it also shreds your hands.
Mine are clean.
A fighter's lost his life.
We're just making sure
that there was
no unfair advantage.
All I did was out-punch Laroi.
Okay, you think I wanted it
to go down like this?
I mean, people are going
to remember me now
like Ray Mancini
when he killed that Korean guy.
That's my legacy now.
Ah, this wasn't my fault,
all right?
He brought it upon himself
talking all that trash
saying I could never beat him.
Look...
he should have never came out
in the seventh round.
He could barely
stand up.
I knew it was over right then.
So why did you keep hitting him?
Because
real fighters
don't stop hitting
until somebody makes them,
all right?
When you're in the ring,
your life's in the ref's hands.
Now, one word from that ref,
and I would have stopped.
But he never gave the word.
How we doing, Bobby?
Hey. Well, good news.
All the bullets
pulled from the vic
are from the same gun.
Six right, .380.
The bad news?
We're 0 for two
matching the bullets
to the guns y'all recovered.
I did find something,
though
on one of them shells,
if you want to take a look.
It's set up for you
over there.
Could be biological.
I'll send it to trace.
Well, I hope
it gets you somewhere
'cause all we got here
is strike three.
BROWN:
Brass, Brown.
I need as much information as
you can give me on a referee.
Hey, Sara.
Hey.
I'll be right there.
I have something
to show you.
We gave Molina a ride in.
You did?
He didn't say much
which is no big
surprise, considering.
There's not much in here
but, uh, I know
how you like to
see everything.
Thanks.
We checked vitals,
cleaned his lacerations
and he wanted
his hand wraps cut off,
so we cut them off.
Is this it?
Right.
He autographed it.
Nah, that's
the inspector's signature.
Whoever watched him wrap up.
It looks like there's some kind
of metal in the gauze.
Mercury, maybe?
No, there's no mercury
in any of our instruments.
We're fully digital.
How do you think
it got there?
I don't know.
Massive soft tissue damage,
severe facial fractures.
Are they letting guys
go at each other
with clubs these days?
Only on cable.
It never ceases
to amaze me
the damage one human being
can inflict on another.
Or how much damage a
human body can sustain.
A heavyweight
can land a punch
at 1,000 pounds
per square inch.
The energy of the punch
is transferred
through the
cerebrospinal fluid
compressing the brain
against the skull
temporarily disrupting
neural activity.
Like a short circuit.
Too many short circuits
and the brain shuts down.
And hence, a knockout.
This guy should
have been so lucky.
This, uh, bruising
under the chin
seems heavy.
Yeah, I thought so, too.
I did a postmortem angiogram.
It's a basilar
subarachnoid hematoma
the result of a massive
vertical blunt force trauma
to the chin.
The sudden forced rotation
of the neck
tears the vertebral artery
and blood pours out into
the surrounding soft tissue.
It's called an uppercut.
♪ You say tomato... ♪
and I say "cause of death."
Gil, I never had you pegged
as a fight fan.
I'm not, really.
My first year as a criminalist
I thought boxing
would be a good place
to observe live blood spatter.
So, I went to a
couple of bouts.
There wasn't much spatter.
Some interesting bruise
formations, though.
So, uh,
this is a socially acceptable
live-subject laboratory for you?
Yeah. Not in this case.
Thank you.
Preliminary tox?
Yeah.
Professional athlete.
Would have expected
performance enhancers--
uh, creatine, dianobol.
This man had sufentanil
in his system.
Sufentanil? A sedative?
Yeah.
So, if the fighter
won't take a dive...
help him take a dive.
What's my cousin
got to do with the fight?
Your cousin bet 20
large on Javier Molina
at five-to-one against.
Hey, he's always been
a lucky guy.
Yeah, I know,
I'm sure he is.
Well, you know
how this works.
I mean, you hear
the fight's fixed
you tip off your cousin
for a piece of the action
he tells a couple of
friends, so on, so on.
They make a bet at
the last minute, and
the odds go south.
Hey, big fight,
money moves around.
Oh, yeah, that's cool.
This is Vegas.
Money flows.
As long as it doesn't
flow out of your pocket.
Maybe that's why you let
the fight go on so long.
Yeah, you see a
fighter in trouble
you give him
a standing eight.
If he comes out a winner,
you're in the poorhouse.
So, what are you saying,
that if I'd stopped the fight
Laroi Steele
would still be alive?
You charging me
with something?
No. Not yet.
You know where to find me.
Randy Watkins.
I'm Detective
O'Riley.
This is Nick Stokes
of the crime lab.
Hi, there.
Where'd you get the cut
on your forearm, man?
You practicing for
a job at Benihana?
Hey, this is a hospital.
I got doctor-client
privilege here, huh?
Well, you don't get
any privileges, Randy.
You're wearing
stolen property.
Let me trade that
bracelet in for this one.
( handcuffs click )
Ladies and gentlemen,
in this corner
wearing red leather
coming from
the great fighting city
of Everlast, USA...
the gloves
that Javier Molina wore
when he killed Laroi Steele.
This is a piece
of boxing history.
Do you know how much
this would go for
on eBay?
Greg, the residue
on the gloves, what is it?
Half inorganic salts:
magnesium, potassium, etcetera
and half
organic derivatives:
urea, choline and uric acid.
Sweat.
Occasionally found
at a boxing match.
Oh, but wait.
In this corner
fighting way out
of his weight class
coming from... that place
that textiles come from
a cotton swab
soaked in sufentanil.
BROWN:
Sufentanil?
I did recover this swab
from the victim's corner.
Time to talk to the cut man.
I would have got a bonus
if we won.
Why would I mess
with the guy who pays me?
Why is for
the lawyers.
BROWN:
Your corner, your swab
your drugs.
Suck it up.
I been doing this 28 years.
Back when every cut man around
was using Monsels solution
getting it in kids' eyes
blinding them.
I wouldn't touch the stuff.
And I didn't hurt Laroi.
I been in his corner
six fights.
Every one, he fought hard
and never stiffed me.
Him dying
was a tragedy.
Molina trains here?
Yeah, maybe.
He owns the place.
And you're looking for work.
Work comes to me.
Well, here's something else
that's coming to you.
What, you want me
to give you my bag?
We're not asking.
It's kind of primitive.
So is boxing.
Did you get anywhere
with that mercury?
Yeah. Ensenada, Mexico.
Molina has a personal
physician down there.
It turns out that
mercury is used
in a folk remedy
for empacho.
It's a chronic
stomach condition.
And Molina has it?
Medical history
confirms it.
The guy eats metal.
It's not the eating
that will get you.
The poison's
in the mercury vapor.
It's toxic.
Well, I guess we're
left with the sedative.
Any luck?
Greg's working on it.
Three guns
found at the scene.
None match the bullets
recovered from the victim.
What does that tell us?
The shooter
kept his weapon.
Means he likes
his gun
and may have
used it before.
Which is where the shell case
and IBAS come in.
I'll run it against
the national database.
Firing pin impressions
and breech face marks
a closer look.
Well, okay.
Got us a hit.
Los Angeles County
Sheriff's Department
found
shell casings from the same gun
used in a gang murder
two years ago.
They get a conviction
on the suspect?
No. Guy beat the rap.
"Timothy Fontaine,
aka 'Tiny Tim.'"
Member
of the Snakebacks.
Current residence unknown.
I bet I could find
where he stays in Vegas.
Hey.
CATHERINE:
I guess Tiny's mother can be
proud of her son for one thing.
He sure knows how
to clean a room.
Well, there is one
Snakeback still in town.
Who's that?
That guy
right over there.
What's his dealio?
Okay, I'm The Man,
I take care of my people.
That is
Jerome Anderson.
AKA, The Man.
The Man?
The Man.
Technically a former
Snakeback who shed his skin
and worked his way
into the real world.
Record producer,
clothing designer
sports agent.
Why didn't you get
a warrant for his room?
We're working on it.
He's got an entire
law firm on retainer.
...five percent here,
ten percent there.
Better get back in the ring,
Laroi, and keep fighting.
See, what Laroi needed
was a giver not a taker.
That's why
he came to me, The Man
so I could stand
by his side
and give him honest
representation.
Police.
Another thing
that The Man understands
because he comes from
the same place
as today's
athletes.
I'm Detective Vega.
This is Catherine Willows
from the Crime Lab.
We'd like to ask you
a few questions.
The Man ain't got
nothing to hide.
We're looking
for members
of the Snakebacks.
A Timothy Fontaine,
in particular.
No idea.
The Man is here
on business.
So are we.
Do you mind
if I ask
how The Man
got the burn mark on his neck?
Well, all the ladies
say that The Man is hot.
I guess I must have
just burned myself
and forgot all about it.
No, you didn't.
Are you crazy?
No, no, no, no.
Hold on, hold on,
hold on, hold on.
Ooh, ooh...
I guess you are hot.
Oh, that's old.
The Man
is all about the new.
Did you get a hold
of that cut man?
Yeah, we found sufentanil
in a bottle of coagulant
in the guy's kit.
Doesn't make sense.
If the cut man did it
why would he hold on
to the evidence?
I was thinking
the same thing.
I'm not convinced he actually
knew it was in his kit.
The prints that I got
off the bottle came back to...
Gerry Barone,
the victim's manager.
And I thought
Don King was bad.
The reason my prints
are in the system
is I'm a foster parent.
Six kids in 30 years.
Treated them like my own.
Trained them,
took them off the streets.
We know that.
We know
you're a good guy.
So what made you
dope up Laroi Steele?
We found your prints on
a bottle of coagulant.
It was laced with a sedative.
Found it in the cut man's kit.
I was trying to save Laroi.
By drugging him?
We kept it out of the press
but in their last fight,
Molina hurt him bad.
How bad?
The signs were all there
in training--
sagging eye, drooping shoulder,
brain damage down the road.
Laroi couldn't handle
another beating.
But I couldn't talk him
out of this fight.
Molina got under his skin.
Laroi wouldn't let it go.
I taught him not to quit.
I was trying
to get him out alive.
Laroi was 16 years old
the first time I saw him fight.
And the only thing
faster than his hands
was his mouth.
There was this one time
he made his sparring partner
laugh so hard
the man pissed his trunks
before he hit the mat.
Can you imagine that?
NICK:
We arrested the guy
and recovered
all the jewelry.
Thank you so much,
Mr. Stokes.
Not a problem.
I just need you to fill out
some documentation
and then I can release
your ring back to you, okay?
That's not your ring.
Of course it is.
I'm telling you,
that is not the ring I gave you.
That's a different cut.
Now I wore this ring
on my finger
every day for five years.
I think that I...
I bought you
that ring.
Who do you think spent the week
looking for the perfect stone
for our first anniversary?
Sir, I matched
every item recovered
to a log provided
by the jewelry store
piece for piece.
Then maybe you should
explain to me
why I'm not looking
at my wife's ring.
I need to explain to you?
Come on, Mack.
How do I know you didn't switch
this ring out?
Man, I would n...
'Cause that's not
the way it works.
Oh, we screw
the out-of-towners
and nobody's going
to care, right?
Are you making
a formal accusation?
You bet I am.
Knock yourself out,
big dog.
Forms are
at the front desk.
BROWN:
Okay...
It's about a month ago
at a pre-fight press conference.
Check it out, he lost
the last couple of times.
I'm the one who did
all the whupping.
And I'm just going to do
a three-peat, baby, you know?
What I'm saying is
anytime, anyplace, cabron.
You can't wait to get whupped,
is that it?
Steele is slurring his words.
Fast forward
to the fight.
Watch his shoulder,
how he keeps dropping it.
The manager was right.
Pugilistic dementia.
They say eight out of ten boxers
suffer some form of brain damage
later on in life.
The Greatest-- Muhammad Ali.
Steele must've known
what was happening to him.
He would never admit it.
Fighters need to psych
themselves up before a fight.
They got to believe
they're going to win.
Or they'd never fight.
In a way, every opponent
Laroi Steele fought
contributed to his death.
I don't know if he was
incredibly stupid
or just... brave.
We'll contest this
on the grounds
that your request
to the judge
was based on a specious
connection to the Snakebacks.
Contest all you want.
It's still coming
after the fact.
Open.
The warrant was based
on physical findings.
A burn mark?
Could have happened anywhere.
Jerome is under
the misguided impression
that he's a one-man
pyrotechnic display.
Watch too many movies
and kids start to think
that people actually
shoot like that.
The most you're
going to prove
is my client was
in the vicinity.
Period.
That's it.
If his DNA matches what we found
on the shell casing
we'll be able to extend
the scope of the warrant.
If it matches.
File says you're a smart guy.
Three years in Georgetown.
Why turn stupid
all of a sudden?
Give us the guy
we're looking for.
WILLOWS:
Look, we all know
that you forget what the word
"loyalty" means
as soon as you step away
from the mirror
so what do the Snakebacks
get you?
R-E-S-P-E-C-T, baby.
I thought that's what
college was for.
( chuckles ):
I went to school.
In fact, I have carefully
analyzed business models
of African American
entrepreneurs
such as Darian Daze
at Dis-Kard Enterprises
which grosses
$250 million a year.
And my analysis has
led me to understand
that an emerging CEO
needs to have as solid a command
of flow charts and spreadsheets
as he does
a bad-ass street rep.
And let me tell you something,
sweetness, I got it all
coming and going.
So the more you try to stress me
the more you're just selling me
to the people
out on the streets.
So crime pays.
Oh, don't hate the player,
hate the game.
Right, you don't make the rules,
you just exploit them.
Ain't that a bitch.
Nice work on
that jewelry heist.
Yeah, well,
it's not done yet.
You got the guy.
Oh, yeah, it was
a little rough.
We had to check a few ERs,
but we snatched him up.
Being efficient is not
a bad thing, Nick.
Yeah. Why are you tossing me
a softball
and putting everyone else
on real cases?
You wanted to work solo.
Yeah, but it's like
Night of the Pifflings out there
and I'm on a smash and grab.
Pifflings?
Puffin offspring.
First time out of the nest
every year
they crash land in this town
near Iceland
because they're attracted to the
lights of human civilization.
It's the same way people
flock to Vegas for a fight.
Animal Planet.
How come when you talk
about bugs
everyone says you're a genius
but when I talk
about birds
everyone says
I watch too much television?
I don't know.
Look, the next night
of the Pifflings
you get the first dead body.
Copy that.
The victim suffered
tripod fractures
of the zygomatic arch
in two places.
There's also a fracture
of the orbital floor.
This tripod fracture
of the zygoma
is what caused the flattening
of the victim's face.
It indicates that
he was struck
with an extremely
powerful blow.
Which couldn't be caused
by normal boxing gloves.
We checked Molina's gloves.
There's nothing in them
or on them.
Well, we're missing something.
We have a problem.
Pile it on.
Well, in the interests
of posterity
I took it upon myself
to establish provenance
for the killer gloves
I mean DNA-wise.
On my own time,
of course
of which I have
precious little
so that should count
for something.
Greg, why are you
always doing this?
Because you make me nervous.
My point is,
the epithelials
found on the surface
of the glove.
They're not Laroi Steele's.
Those aren't the gloves
that killed him.
Gloves look brand-new.
Padding's still stiff.
It's like
they've never been used.
What are all these dots?
Looks like a little piece
of red leather.
Hmm.
And more mercury.
Well, Molina does take it
for his stomach, right?
He's a sloppy eater.
Hmm.
Mercury's volatile.
It emits a toxic vapor
at room temperature.
So you're saying
if I find the vapor
I find the mercury.
Grissom.
BRASS:
That your
signature?
Yeah. That's my signature.
So what?
Well, according to fight rules
you were supposed
to watch Molina wrap his hands
and sign them,
then watch him put on his gloves
and then sign those.
Which is what I did.
SIDLE:
Okay, you
signed his wraps
but the gloves
that we found
were not the gloves
used in the fight.
Molina switched them.
There's no way.
You watched Molina glove up?
Not exactly.
Come on.
Get her out of here.
CROSS:
Look. It was a big fight.
There was
a lot of pressure.
You've got to give the fighters
a little space.
So, no one saw him
put his gloves on.
I guess not.
I should have called you first
to apologize
for my husband's
unfortunate outburst.
You know what?
You should apologize.
But not for your husband.
Excuse me?
You know damn well
your diamond
isn't a diamond.
It's a substance
called moissanite.
Really?
Really. White light refractions
and inclusions of your stone
are inconsistent
with a real diamond's.
Then the thief
must have switched the stone
before you caught him.
The thief. Yeah.
I don't think so.
Because before the store
could clean your ring
I was able to collect DNA.
Wow, that's very thorough
of you.
Isn't it?
You know, it's my guess
you switched out the
stone some time ago
because judging from
your husband's response
he knew nothing
about it.
( laughs )
Mr. Stokes,
can I...?
You're from Texas,
aren't you?
'Cause I can always tell.
I'm a criminalist for
Clark Country, Nevade.
Yes, well, one's body
might reside elsewhere
but one's heart never really
leaves home, does it?
Look, all you
have to do
is say that you recovered
a fake diamond
which is the truth.
So you can file a
false insurance claim
which is a felony?
Better yet,
why don't I have
an adjuster come
over to your place
and check out all your rocks
and see which ones are real
and which ones
you've switched out?
No?
Look, if you
find yourself
in a hole, the best thing
to do is stop digging.
You know what I mean?
Sounds like a plan.
Put it in motion.
I guess clothes
do make "the man."
In this case,
"the man" makes the clothes.
And produces the music
and represents the athletes...
when he's not involved
in street shootings, of course.
And when you asked him
what he was wearing
the night of the murder,
he couldn't remember?
As far as he's concerned
murder is just another way
to separate himself
from the Calvins and Ralphs
of the world.
Calvin and Ralph?
Klein and Lauren.
Fashion.
Oh. Well, for most CSIs,
fashion is irrelevant.
Speak for
yourself.
The only thing between me
and a wardrobe like this
is a few extra zeros
on my paycheck.
Well, what's standing between
you and this Tiny Tim character?
The Mojave.
Highway patrol is out looking
for our guy.
Odds are that Tiny Tim
is back in L.A.
Evidence disposed of
along the way.
That means my last chance
of connecting the dots
is somewhere
along these racks.
Fibers, GSR, blood.
Hey. Guess who never left town?
WILLOWS:
Calling card?
10th Street Vandals.
.380 automatic.
Tiny's favorite piece.
Odds are
it traces back
to the original murder.
Same as it always does.
Somebody gets dissed.
The Snakebacks kill a Vandal.
Then the Vandals kill
a Snakeback.
Everyone goes home satisfied.
Round and round and round
it goes.
Where it stops, nobody knows.
There was this one case
where a boxer put lead shot
in his gloves to increase
his punching power.
And also ancient Greek
and Roman pugilists
used a glove weighted
with metal, called a "cestus."
You making a
classical reference?
Yeah. I thought
you'd like that.
Question is, if Molina was
using mercury to load up
how'd it get
into his gloves?
Well, he injected it.
Those circular pieces
of leather that you found
in Molina's locker
are the same diameter
as a 14-gauge needle.
Well, mercury's
incredibly dense.
It could easily be
contained in the leather
in the form of
a boxing glove.
The boxing gloves
weighed eight ounces
so the question is,
would a few ounces
of mercury
be enough to cause
the damage that we observed
on the victim?
Right.
I smell an experiment.
All right.
Normal gloves.
Ready.
And... go.
Good?
Little more.
Good.
Loaded gloves.
Ready?
SIDLE:
And...
go.
Ooh, this thing's are heavy.
Good.
Good, good.
GRISSOM:
And mercury
kills steel.
Boxing is a combat sport.
Sometimes fighters die, okay?
That's all part
of the game.
Laroi Steele's death
was a tragedy
not a murder.
It became murder
when your client injected
mercury into his gloves.
SIDLE:
And your hands,
Molina
literally, became
lethal weapons.
BROWN:
Heavy gloves.
That's why you kept your hands
to your side.
It also kept the mercury
on the tip of your glove.
SIDLE:
With every punch
a little bit got forced down
through the padding
through the seams
and on to your hands.
That's how it got
on your wraps.
BROWN:
And into your lungs.
SIDLE:
And finally out
into your urine.
We tested the sample
that you gave the
boxing commission
after the fight.
It came back positive
for mercury.
I have empacho.
I take mercury
for my stomach problems.
We didn't find mercury
in your stomach.
We found it
in your locker
in your gym bags,
on your wraps...
SIDLE:
When the fight was
over, your trainer
cut the tape off
your gloves
and you took the
pieces and put them
in the hamper
with a pair of
sparring gloves,
just in case
anybody wondered what
had happened to them.
BROWN:
But the real gloves
were in your gym bag
at that hospital, weren't they?
Steele had already
kicked your ass... twice before?
Must have been
humiliating.
You push a man too far,
there are consequences.
You knew there was no way
you could beat Steele
in a fair fight.
BROWN:
The best way
to punish a guy is
to beat him to death in the ring
in front of two million people
on pay-per-view.
That's boxing.
No, that's murder.
I'll see you in court.
MAN 1:
So that means the
title's vacant, right?
MAN 2:
Not for long.
I heard it's Lopez
versus Lewis at Caesar's
in six months.