WOMAN:
This won't help, don't you see?
After me, there'll be others.
You'll have to go on killing,
on and on until they catch you.
I won't be the last;
there'll be others after me.
You can't help yourself
because you're mad, mad, mad!
( cell phone rings )
MAN:
No one will question you.
They'll say it's
just another suicide.
( phone rings )
WOMAN:
Hello?
( cell phone rings )
Hello?!
( ringing continues )
Shh!
( cell phone ringing )
WOMAN:
Burgess!
( phone hangs up )
( ringing )
( screaming):
Burgess!
( glass shattering )
Excuse me, sir.
I'm going to have to ask
you to turn the phone off.
Sir?
I'll have to...
( cell phone continues ringing)
Whoo! Theaters are
like nightclubs;
they should always
keep the lights off.
This is the last art house
left in Vegas.
I saw Baraka here,
on a double bill
with Koyaanisqatsi
Was there anyone
else here?
Sure.
With you?
No.
BRASS:
Thursday night is Noir Night.
The poor sap was slumped over
like a sack of potatoes,
oozing blood like a broken
bottle of ketchup.
His name is Gus Sugarman.
Runs a dental practice
in Henderson.
Cell phone went off
three times during the movie.
So, the usher finally
came over to shut him up.
Yeah, somebody
beat him to it.
Single puncture wound
to the base of the skull.
And nobody saw anything?
They were watching
the movie.
Dark room. Loud music.
Four exits.
Everybody looking
the other way.
Professional killer?
Or a movie buff.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
It was
Build My Gallows High,
with Robert Mitchum, 1947.
with Robert Mitchum
and Jane Greer.
And Kirk Douglas.
Trust me, the book
was Build My Gallows High.
Mr. Siskel, Mr. Ebert,
may I have a cause of death,
please?
Puncture wound is small.
Not a knife.
Seems like it penetrated
all the way to the brain stem,
and there's some bruising
around the mouth.
Well, the killer could
have stood over him,
placed his hand over his mouth,
stabbed him in the back
of the head.
Didn't Telly Savalas do that
in The Dirty Dozen?
Anthony Quinn did it, too,
in Guns of Navaronne.
Right.
Well, what movie
did you see this in?
DR. ROBBINS:
Looks like somebody ripped
something off his neck.
Small patterns; could have
been a chain, maybe, huh?
Or necklace. Oh!
( sighs )
Butterfingers.
( flashlight rolling on floor)
What'd you got?
Well, whoever called him
didn't leave their number.
Hey!
I wasn't the only one who
dropped something tonight.
I got a witness.
I only noticed 'cause she got up
during the best part
of the movie,
right before the gunfight.
Is the gunfight loud?
Yeah. I mean it's not
THX Surround-sound.
This was 1950 and
mono optical track.
I like how loud
this theater keeps it.
Perfect moment to do it.
Cover up any noise
the victim might make.
You get a look at her?
I drove 40 minutes
to see this flick;
my eyes were on the screen,
but, uh, she was tall,
not old... a redhead.
Did she come back in?
No.
And, uh...
I-I don't see her here.
Did anyone see her coming
into the lobby?
BRASS:
Well, Manager had left
for the night.
The usher who found the body
had left before we got here.
He had been smoking blunts.
He was afraid we were going
to bust him for marijuana.
I'll be tweaking him when
I call him for my statement.
If you ask me, anybody who
leaves their phone on in a movie
deserves to get
stabbed in the head.
That's why nobody ask you.
( siren chirps )
( garbled radio dispatches )
STOKES:
Detective.
O'RILEY:
Guys ...
Who called it in?
Passing motorist
heard gunshots.
First Officer
did a drive up.
Found the scene.
Called in the world.
I hope you brought
extra supplies.
Why's that?
You're gonna
be here awhile.
Looks like a war zone.
BROWN:
We got an I.D. on the body?
O'RILEY:
No cash,
no ID, just a
driver's permit.
Driver's permit.
What is he, 16?
O'RILEY:
Fifteen-and-a-half.
Timmy McCallum.
Coroner's on his way.
Tell them to watch their step.
There's casings and blood
everywhere.
Divide and conquer.
Inside or outside?
Outside perimeter.
I'm Dennis Rodman.
I'll take everything
below the knees.
Question is not what we're going
to find on the murder weapon;
question is what isn't on it.
The sticky substance?
Soda.
Yellow crumbs?
Popcorn.
Carpet fibers.
It wasn't the cleanest
theater in the world.
I just want to match
the blood to our victim.
And you want to know if
there's a recoverable print.
Uh-huh.
You want to race?
What's the bet?
Hmm...
JOHNSON:
Is that our guy?
Phone Company unblocked
all his private numbers for us.
They can do that now?
Yeah. On the left side of the
screen are the outgoing calls.
On the right, the incoming.
What time did the movie start?
10:40.
Last outgoing call your vic made
was at 10:38.
555-0110.
26 seconds.
That sounds like a no answer.
Yeah, but 555-0110
was the number
that called him
three times in a row:
11:26, 11:27
and 11:28.
Someone needed
to talk to him
pretty bad.
Yeah, well, he was
already dead by then.
Dr. Robbins was that accurate
with the TOD?
That's when the gunfire erupted.
There was gunfire?
In the movie.
I'll need an address
for that number.
( lilting intro plays )
Hey, guys.
What do you make of
this piece of bamboo?
I found it
on the roof.
STOKES:
Bag it.
That's funny.
Very funny.
Did you get the hole
in the roof?
You find anything else up there?
No.
Got some shards of glass.
Clear in color.
Mixed with small pieces
of black plastic.
BROWN:
You almost finished
with that?
What's your count?
Yeah. 109 rods.
109 bullets?
How in the world
do trajectories
occur 15 to 20 feet
off the ground?
Horizontally?
What the hell
went on here?
Audrey Hilden?
Yes.
We're with the Crime Lab.
Do you know a Gus Sugarman?
Why don't you
come inside. Please.
He was my dentist.
That's terrible.
He'd asked me to go
to the movies,
and I said yes, but...
it was a late show,
and I had to get up
early for work.
Well, we know that
Dr. Sugarman called
you at home
two minutes before
the movie started,
and that you
didn't pick up.
I was screening. I figured
he'd get my message.
And why did you call him
three times in a row,
40 minutes later?
I felt bad standing him up.
I called to apologize.
I figured I'd get his Voice
Mail, but when I didn't,
I tried again.
And you were here alone?
Yes.
Can anyone verify that?
Why?
( phone rings )
( ringing continues )
Still screening?
( phone ringing )
Do you see a lot of movies
at the Art House Theater?
Sure. I love old movies.
I see they recently had
a Hitchcock Retrospective.
I prefer French New Wave.
If you'll excuse me now,
I have to go to work.
We'll be in touch.
Geez, what was
this kid, tortured?
Couple of fractured ribs.
Deep purple contusions
of the presternal chest wall.
Each one around two inches
in diameter.
I stopped counting around nine.
What do you think
could've done this?
Baseball bat?
It's hard to tell.
Whatever it was,
it had a great deal of velocity.
Yeah.
Cause of death:
single gunshot to the chest.
No evidence
of gunshot residue.
Shot from a distance. Yeah.
And at a downward angle...
It's, uh...
It's about 25 degrees.
He was shot from above.
( gun cocking )
Rooftop angle is 45 degrees.
This is 25 degrees?
It's impossible.
If that's the case, he was shot
by somebody 10 to 15 feet tall.
What else you got?
Scabbing abrasions
on the elbows, the back
and kneecaps.
Looks to be harmless
"boys will be boys" stuff.
There's nothing harmless
about death.
Don't tell me--
Greg won the bet.
The blood on the screwdriver
definitely belongs
to your victim.
It was incredible how fast
he got me back the results.
I don't know how he does it.
Now I got to wear
this stupid thing all day.
Oh, look at him, hovering.
Making sure
I still have it on.
Do us all a favor and
get him out in the field,
will you, Grissom?
He's going stir crazy
in here.
Jaqui, do you have
anything for us?
A palm print.
Oh, great.
Let's, uh, go back to Audrey's
and see if we
have a match.
Not quite.
Look at the ridges.
Too consistent.
Looks like fine grain.
Leather.
Killer wore gloves.
BRASS:
Okay...
here's what's happening--
three months ago,
Audrey Hilden filed
a sexual malpractice suit
against our Dr. Sugarman.
The suit claims that
she was molested while
she was under anesthesia.
And she was going on a date
with this guy?
Yeah. Sugarman
countersued.
He's represented
by big-time attorneys,
so she backed down.
Well, a screwdriver's
cheaper than an attorney.
( chuckles ):
Yeah.
Well, uh, there's more.
Remember the usher
who likes to smoke the chronic?
He claims he saw a redheaded
woman make a phone call
halfway through the movie,
so I'm going to check it out.
Want to tag along?
This where the
limbo party is?
Can I come in?
Yeah.
Sorry, I don't let
everyone in here.
Well, I've got
your one-to-ones.
The tire treads,
there's nothing specific here.
Bummer.
But the shoe prints
that you took,
they look interesting.
It looks like five
suspects walked in,
and four ran out.
Four guilty people
out there somewhere.
No doubt.
How's it coming with
your big bamboo here?
Well, I have black lung
from all the powder,
and not a single print,
nothing, nada.
You test for GSR?
The place was riddled with
bullets-- it wouldn't hurt.
Wouldn't hurt.
Nothing.
Maybe this has nothing
to do with the case.
Maybe it was just a piece
of debris left at the scene.
No, no. I-I'm not quitting. No.
I am in too deep.
Where you going?
Trace.
Maybe Hodges can find something.
Oh, coming through.
Careful, people.
Easy.
Hey, Brown. PD called.
Mrs. McCallum's there.
The mother.
Tell them I'm on my way.
I was getting myself a soda.
You know,
we're allowed to do that.
A tall redhead
came out of the theater,
and then she made a phone call
from over there.
From the pay phone.
What? I... What?
I'm on it. I'm on it.
Did you happen to notice
if she was wearing gloves?
Yeah, she was, actually.
I thought it was really weird,
'cause it's, like,
70 degrees in here.
Did you notice anything else?
No. She just threw something
in the trash
and headed out.
The cleaning crew's
in the theater now.
They got a late start
'cause of you guys.
Excuse me.
What happened to the garbage
that was in the can
in the lobby?
Well, it's already
been bagged up,
but it should be
around here somewhere.
Excuse me.
Where'd you get those gloves?
If it's garbage,
it's hers.
They let us keep
whatever we find
as long as it's been thrown out.
I'll tell you what--
I'll buy you a new
pair of gloves.
♪ 99 bottles of beer
on the wall ♪
♪ 99 bottles of beer ♪
♪ You swab one down ♪
♪ Run it through CODIS ♪
♪ 98 bottles of beer
on the wall. ♪
Whatever happened
to "Take one down,
pass it around"?
That's the best part.
You know us lab rats
have to do something
to get through the day.
I know, I just dumped a sack
of bullets on Bobby Dawson.
So, why don't you sing me
a tune I want to hear?
Well... how about...
Harold Melvin
and the Blue Notes.
He ain't heavy.
He's my brother.
DNA? From the beer bottles?
Five different donors--
two of them are related.
Donor number one,
Tim McCallum, the victim;
donor number two,
his relative,
most likely a brother.
No telling if he's heavy or not.
I'm very sorry for your
loss, Mrs. McCallum.
Are you Timmy's brother?
Yeah.
Kevin's the only son
I have left.
We were able to
identify Timmy
by the driver's permit
that we found at the scene.
Had he been driving long?
A few months.
I know that law says
you're supposed to have
an adult present,
but I work graveyard.
Kevin usually drives with him.
What kind of car
does Timmy drive?
We have a mini-van.
It's more safe.
This is an ongoing
investigation,
so we are going to need
to see that vehicle.
Do you ever drive
the mini-van, Kevin?
Sometimes, yeah.
Did you drive Timmy to the
warehouse the other night?
No.
What warehouse?
We have reason
to believe
that Kevin was at the
warehouse that night.
We found his DNA
on some beer bottles.
Beer?
Kevin...
Mom... I bought beer for Timmy.
I don't do it all the time.
He begged me.
He... he said
he was going out partying
with some friends.
If Mom catches you with these,
you didn't get them
from me.
Bro, there's one missing.
I got thirsty. Later, freak.
I took a sip-- I gave him
the rest of the 12-pack.
Sorry, Mom.
Mr. Brown,
I don't know what to say.
I'm a single mother...
I work nights,
and you can't keep
your eyes on your kids
all the time.
At a certain age,
you just have to trust them.
I understand.
We are going to need
to keep Kevin here
to ask him some
more questions
about that night.
Do you object?
N-No.
Spiral gouges.
Check it out.
From tip to tip.
What do you think
caused these marks?
Give me more time--
I'm not a miracle worker.
Well, that's obvious, Hodges.
If you were a miracle worker,
you wouldn't be rude.
I wasn't being rude,
I was being curt.
Rude would be, "When
I know, you'll know."
Friends?
No.
Hodges, how's it coming
with that glass?
Looks like there's some kind of
coating on it.
More specifically,
crystallized calcium fluoride.
You ran it through the I.R.?
Please. I.R. says fluorspar.
I say high-end optics.
Camera lens.
You think someone
has this murder on tape?
WILLOWS:
So, the gloves match
the palm print
on the murder weapon as
well as the pay phone
in the theater lobby.
Unfortunately,
there was
no epithelials
inside the gloves
because the cleaning woman
had ammonia on her hands.
Ah, I see.
Well, according to this,
a phone call was made
from the theater lobby
to Audrey's home at 11:25.
Well, Audrey called
Dr. Sugarman's cell
from her home at 11:26.
Well, obviously, she didn't
make it home in one minute.
We're looking
for someone else.
The mysterious redhead
in the theater?
Maybe Audrey hired a pro
who called up to say, uh,
"It's done."
Well, if she couldn't
afford a powerful attorney,
how did she pay
for a hit man?
Hit woman.
Why don't we ask her?
( knocking on door )
( disconnect tone beeping )
You hear that?
Phone's off the hook.
There must be another way in.
( beeping continues )
WILLOWS:
She used an extension cord
and tied it to the railing
and must have jumped off.
Yeah, this is Brass.
I got a DB.
Yeah.
WILLOWS:
Our only suspect
apparently commits suicide.
Convenient.
Too convenient.
Catherine...
she's got a whole nother set
of horizontal marks
on her neck,
below the cord.
And postmortem bruising.
I think she was strangled first,
and then hanged.
( groaning )
WILLOWS:
No signs of
a break-in...
or a struggle.
She may have been killed
by someone she knew.
She was dragged.
She's got carpet fibers
on her heels.
( grunting )
Yeah, she was dragged over here,
tied off and shoved over.
( grunting )
You got something?
When we were here earlier,
there was a movie schedule
pinned up there
that had a handwritten
note on it.
I'm not sure she
wanted me to see it.
Now it's gone.
Maybe she threw it away.
Venus and Serena.
Perfect match.
Timmy's 15, I'm 18.
He's got his friends,
I got my friends.
We don't do
the same things.
We don't hang together.
Evidence says
you were there.
You want to go down
for suspicion of murder?
( sighs )
( over speaker ):
Or you want to stop digging
your own grave?
Just talked
to Bobby Dawson.
All the bullets came
from the same gun:
nine-millimeter
semi-automatic.
How's this going?
I found
a 12-pack container
in the McCallum minivan.
Sales slip said
"Jenko Liquors."
I'll check
the surveillance,
see if we can get
some footage of this guy.
What is that on his elbow?
It's just a scab.
Got it skateboarding.
Can we see it?
( sighs )
Peel it back.
Skateboarding?
Why don't you stand up
and take off your shirt.
Don't you guys need
a warrant for that?
We get a warrant,
and we're going
to strip you down
to nothing, then ask you
to bend over-- choose.
BROWN:
Geez, man, what
happened to you?
Turn around.
Those are the same markings
your brother had.
You want to tell us
what went down here?
I can't talk about it.
I'm sorry.
Hey, listen,
if-if you're the victim here,
you can tell us.
Okay?
Kevin, who did this to you, man?
Well, there's an awful lot
of water damage, but, um...
there's some kind
of an impression.
GRISSOM:
Well, maybe this
will bring it up.
( computer beeping
and whirring )
GRISSOM:
It's written above
Strangers On A Train.
Is that the one with
the perfect murder?
Two strangers
meet on a train,
make a pact to get rid
of each other's problems.
They figure since neither
has a motive for the killings,
they won't be caught.
Life imitating art?
In the movie, Robert Walker
kills Farley Granger's wife.
Granger didn't think
he was serious,
so when he refuses
to kill Walker's father,
Walker goes after him.
So if Audrey
is Farley Granger...
Who's playing
Robert Walker's part?
( beeping )
WILLOWS:
"Sphere E4-117."
Well, that's got to be
the Sphere hotel.
GRISSOM:
It's not a hotel room,
though.
Locker,
safety deposit box...
Parking space, maybe.
Yeah.
MAN:
Audrey who?
Hilden.
Nah, I never heard of her.
What's this about?
WILLOWS:
E4-117.
Your assigned
parking space.
It was written on
a movie schedule
we found in Ms. Hilden's home.
Well, look,
I meet a lot of women.
She a dancer?
She work for me before?
Hey, Michelle. Mmm!
I'll tell you guys something:
this show is very hot,
all the chicks
want to be in it,
and actually, they, uh,
got to go through me.
Ever been to the Art House
movie theater?
No. Where's that?
WILLOWS:
Have you ever seen
any Hitchcock movies?
Strangers On A Train?
BRASS:
Alfred Hitchcock?
Mr. Haines?
Whose station is this one?
Oh, that's Kelly Goodson's.
Royal pain in the ass.
( show music strikes up
in distance )
Can I help you?
That's my locker.
It was open.
You always snoop through
other people's things?
I'm with the Crime Lab.
I'm a professional snoop.
Do you, uh...
ever wear that wig
when you go out?
I never get to go out.
Two shows a night,
three on weekends.
Why? You have
something in mind?
Do you like the movies?
I, uh, noticed you have
an Art House Theater schedule
on your mirror.
Yeah, I've been
there a few times.
Ever seen Strangers On A Train?
No.
Is it any good?
Yeah, it's good.
You use a lot of creams, huh?
16 shows a week
in these shoes,
your legs would be
killing you, too.
Is that your own recipe?
What was it you said
you do for a living?
I'm a scientist.
And, um, I'm up in five minutes,
so... you mind?
I don't mind.
( brassy music
ends with a flourish )
( typing slowly )
( computer beeping )
I'm sorry I'm late.
What bullet are you on?
109, finally.
Height, distance, angle.
This has been
a very laborious shift.
Are you in the mood
for a light show?
Yeah, hook it up.
( computer beeping )
BROWN:
The trajectory
is all pointing
in one uniform area.
Looks like some
kind of a pole.
Or a bamboo stick.
( weary laugh )
The whole case
has been like this.
It's like you can't
wrap your head
around it, you know?
A bamboo cane with black swirls
descending downward, no GSR,
109 rods, 109 bullets,
all fired
from the same gun.
Camera glass, blood
droplets everywhere,
DNA that says five
people were there,
one boy's dead,
one boy's injured,
and he ain't
sayin' nothin'...
( sighs )
Is this the end
of the road?
Forensically?
Yes.
Hey.
Hey, Sara,
I was just coming to get you.
Surveillance footage
from Jenko Liquor.
Archie just put together
some black-and-white stills.
Check it out.
Kevin, the older brother,
buying beer.
Looks like he
wasn't alone.
No, you're right.
He had four other friends
with him, including Timmy.
And here you go.
( both chuckling )
It's a classic
distraction technique.
Did it many times.
You go in
with a group of buddies
and you cause
a little ruckus.
Store owner
gets flustered.
He wants the kids
out of his store.
So, he sells them the beer,
even though they're underage,
and of course they drink it.
Well, you know about the camera
glass Warrick found, right?
That means someone has this
all on tape.
I say we track down
the other kids,
see which one of them thinks
he's Tarantino.
So, get this-- Anthony Haines
had a sexual harassment suit
filed against him recently.
There's a lot of that
going around.
Uh-huh, from one
of the showgirls.
Kelly Goodson?
She claims that he
threatened to fire her
if she didn't perform
certain sexual favors.
You know, she had a business
card in her locker--
Langly &amp;amp; Langly,
Attorneys-at-Law.
It'd be interesting
to find out...
If Audrey hired
the same firm?
She did.
So, they liked
the same movies...
they had the same problem...
and they hired
the same lawyer?
Knees bothering you?
The extension cord used
to strangle Audrey Hilden.
The dentist's gold chain.
The murderer's gloves.
Well, any physical evidence
on those gloves
would've been compromised
by the ammonia.
Only on the inside;
not necessarily the outside.
You use two hands
to put on gloves.
You're looking for transfer.
Special recipe.
We go to the warehouse
all the time...
just go there to party,
talk about chicks.
Sometimes we smoke out.
You take off your shirt, please?
I ride BMX bikes...
play soccer.
Man, I wake up with bruises.
We were just messing around.
I'm not.
A kid's dead.
Back to the question.
How'd you get the shiner?
( laughs )
JJ found a gun
in North Town.
We were messing with it,
shooting the walls.
So, one night,
I brought my hi-eight camera in,
and one of the stray bullets
shot my lens out.
( gun fires/moans )
Who was the shooter?
( chuckles wryly )
You can tell us
and save yourself,
or you can let the tape tell us.
It's your call.
KEVIN:
What up?
My name's Kevin.
These are my boys-- JJ, Earl,
Zach, and my little bro Timmy,
and this is called...
ALL:
Speedway surfing!
( yelling and laughing )
Timmy was a big fan of
all those reality shows.
You know, the "don't
try this at home" stuff.
We-We all watched it on TV.
So, one day, we're bored.
We started making up
stunts on our own,
trying to outdo each other.
Speedway surfing...
that was my idea.
( shouting )
Come on, hit it!
Yeah! Whoo!
( engine racing )
Whoo!
We all did it.
Some ate it bad.
JJ bruised his tailbone.
( snorts )
We were just messing around.
Whoo!
( boys yelling )
KEVIN:
Then Zach got the fever.
Next day, he came up with one.
The Human...
ALL:
150-Yard Marker.
( cackles )
Ready, boys?
Suck it up, big boy.
( cackles )
( laughing )
KEVIN:
Then it came time
for Timmy's turn.
He stayed up all night...
and by morning
he had it.
Hi. My name is Timmy McCallum,
and this is my debut stunt,
so I'm really psyched.
It's called...
Bamboo Russian Roulette!
You ready?
Whoo!
We did it a bunch of times.
You know, we all took turns
going up on the roof.
We almost stopped when I
got shot in the arm...
but we were drunk, and so...
...we decided to try
it one more time.
Yeah!
( gun firing )
( whooping )
( firing continuing )
( laughing )
Whoo!
( gun fires )
( gasping )
KEVIN:
He kept trying to breathe.
I didn't know what to do.
I came down from the roof.
I went over to his side.
I kept saying... "Come on,
breathe, bro.
You can't die on me, man."
Why didn't you call
an ambulance?
I didn't want to get in trouble.
So, you just left him
for dead?
It was an accident.
It's not like
we had a death wish.
You sure about that?
Langly &amp; Langly.
Mm.
I'm sorry?
Oh, it's the law firm that
both you and Audrey hired
to deal with your problems--
Gus Sugarman and
Anthony Haines.
Tony Haines is a pig...
but who's Gus?
Well, we're guessing
that that's where the
two of you first met,
at the lawyers'.
GRISSOM:
Or they could've met
at the movie theater.
Right. Right.
I mean, either way, you
ladies had a lot in common.
Boy, can't you see them
watching Strangers
on a Train together?
Oh, yeah.
GRISSOM:
I'm thinking that Audrey
told her everything
about her dentist, and she told
Audrey everything about Haines.
( speaking indistinctly )
WILLOWS:
You needed them both dead.
So, right out of
Strangers on a Train,
if you swapped murders,
no one could tie you
to the victims,
and then you started
talking specifics--
where the best place
would be to kill Haines...
someplace dark, secluded--
the parking lot right
here at the Sphere.
After you stabbed Sugarman,
you ripped the gold
chain off of his neck
as proof that you'd kept up
your end of the bargain.
And then you walked
out into the lobby
and called Audrey
on the pay phone,
to say that the
deed was done.
And then Audrey
called Sugarman
three times in a row
to see if it was true.
She was the one
who picked the movie...
and made the date.
But that's all she
did, isn't it?
'Cause just like
in the movie,
she had no intention
of killing Haines...
and that's when you
started harassing her.
WILLOWS:
You'd killed for her.
Now she wasn't holding up
her end of the bargain.
GRISSOM:
You couldn't let
her betray you.
So, unfortunately,
she had to die, too.
So, you made it look like
she'd committed suicide,
and then you planted Sugarman's
gold chain, in hopes
that we would think
that she killed him, too.
The only thing that
she had on you was
that movie schedule.
That had to go.
( toilet flushing )
Wow...
that is a really good story.
You guys must be
movie fans yourselves.
You're right.
It's just a story...
...but the chemicals
that we found
on your gloves
and on the extension cord
that was used to kill Audrey,
that's our proof.
Menthol... trolamine
salicylate...
capsaicin...
Eucalyptabalm...
Isorcreme...
capsaicin ointment--
a unique concoction--
your unique concoction...
...and this stuff is
all over the evidence.
Yeah...
it's a pretty good movie.
Well, the character that
you've been playing,
the character that Robert
Walker played in the movie...
he dies at the end.
( movie music playing )
( gunshot fires )
( dramatic movie music playing)
MAN:
I said he'd be alone.
Hi.
What'd I miss?
Murder, seduction,
deceit-- the usual.
Mm.
This one of your favorites?
Actually, I'm not a
big fan of noir.
Okay.
Well, what do you like?
I like silent movies.