♪ People sing around ♪
♪ Now people gather round ♪
♪ Now people jump around ♪
♪ Get your freak on,
get your freak on ♪
♪ Get your freak on ♪
♪ Get your, get, your,
get your freak on ♪
♪ Get your freak on,
♪ Get your freak on... ♪
( music stops )
The last time I was out here,
this was all desert.
CABBIE:
One day, I'm looking at cactus;
the next day a mini mall.
What brings you all
the way out here?
Work.
Stop!
( tires squealing )
Miss, you okay?
Stay here.
Hey!
( shouting )
Where do you think
you're going?
Get out of there!
( shouting encouragement )
( screaming )
( siren wailing )
Where's your posse?
I have no idea.
I was actually on a date.
Hmm?
My God, what am
I looking at?
Taxi hit a kid
crossing the boulevard.
The crowd over there
saw the driver
Rajeeb Khandelwahl,
trying to get away.
So, they pull him out
of the front seat
of the cab
and they beat him up.
I mean, they...
they beat him up bad.
He's on his way
to Desert Palm.
His insides are
on the outside.
Did you move
this body, David?
No, sir.
Auto Detail hoisted
the cab off the kid.
Yeah, but I supervised.
No one's touched him.
Have you ever seen
anything like this?
What do you mean?
Well, how many hit-and-runs
have you pulled?
Too many to count.
How many times
have you seen
the victim's
viscera exposed?
First time.
There's a first time
for everything.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
( garbled radio transmission)
My high school
science teacher
used to say
that your small
and large intestines
could stretch across
the Brooklyn Bridge.
But in reality?
Only 25 feet combined.
Fiction is often
more compelling.
We got the eyewitnesses
lined up, ready to go.
Testimonials, Jim?
I don't consider that evidence.
But easier to clean up.
Keep them
all together, David.
I'll tuck the viscera
in the bio-hazard bag.
Good plan.
I picked up the
taxi at McCarran.
I'm in town on business
staying with my cousin,
who's a few blocks away.
BRASS:
Did you see the pedestrian?
Crossing the street.
I don't think
he saw the cab.
Did the cabbie see him?
No, he was looking at me.
What brings you
all the way out here?
I think I yelled, "Stop,"
but it was too late.
And that's when Rajeeb,
the taxi driver
tried to leave,
to drive away?
No, no, no, no.
He got out of the cab
to see what happened
and... then he freaked
and he got back in
and he reached
for his radio.
That's when the guys
attacked him.
His radio?
He wasn't fleeing the scene?
No, he was calling
for help.
BRASS:
Oh.
Okay, what can you
tell me
about the men
who attacked him?
You always think
you'll be a great
witness but...
( all yelling )
There were so many of them
and it happened so fast.
He was just begging
for his life.
I couldn't see
their faces
but I know it was them;
all of them.
They were the only ones around.
We're heroes, man.
They have no respect
for our laws.
Who?
The damn cabbie!
Why, because he's
not from Vegas?
No, because he's not from here,
this country.
Oh, and you know
that because you saw
his birth certificate?
We didn't exactly need
to see it.
Tell me what you did see.
He hit the boy.
Then he hits his brakes,
and I figured
he's going to stop
and do the right thing.
Instead, he jumps
back into his cab.
Hey! If it weren't for us,
he'd have gotten away.
Citizen's arrest, yo!
People are going
to want our autograph.
I don't want
your autograph
but I would like a photo
and a bit of your DNA.
So line up.
What?!
Look, the guy
that you "arrested"
is in critical condition.
That makes you all
suspects in a battery...
Figures.
We do something good
you guys try to turn
around and pin it on us.
Yeah, if we were
wearing badges
you'd be throwing us
a ticker tape parade.
If you're wearing badges
I'm playing left-wing
in the NHL.
I know my rights.
I don't have
to give you squat.
Oh yeah, you're
the lawyer.
Let me tell you
how this goes down
if you don't cooperate.
You all get a free ride
in the cruiser
down to the station
where I hold you there
until the warrants clear.
So what's
it going to be?
It's your choice.
Line up... single file.
Say, "Cheese."
Open up, please.
Thank you.
WOMAN:
He's critical.
Ruptured spleen,
collapsed lung,
fractured ulna,
possible intercranial bleeding.
Doctors are still waiting
on the labs.
Do you have his clothes?
His personals are bagged--
top shelf.
They're ripped up
pretty bad.
That's good.
That'll help.
NURSE:
He said he killed a boy--
ran over him?
Did he say
anything else?
No, that was it.
Gene Rayburn.
What?
Point of reference.
Uh... Match Game...
Nipsey Russell,
Fannie Flagg
Game Show Network.
Look, I don't have time
for your humor.
Ecklie's got
a multiple
Warrick tells me his home
invasion is my top priority
and I'm still backed up
on Catherine's no-suspect rape.
One servant, many masters,
you know what I'm saying?
Greg... this is your DNA lab.
You are the master.
We serve you.
Well, your stuff just moved
to the top of the pile.
What do you got?
Individual DNA
from a mob attack on a cabbie...
and the cabbie's clothes.
"Get ready to match the stars."
Okay, Doc, tell me
something I don't know.
Okay.
In fourth grade,
I dropped out
of karate class
because a kid half
my size made me cry.
About the body.
No pedestrian fracture.
Almost without exception
when a pedestrian's
hit by a car
there's certain expected wounds
in his lower extremities
most significantly
the pedestrian fracture.
Tip of the triangle
always points
in the direction
the car was moving.
His tibia's intact.
In fact, there's no bruising
to the lower extremities.
So, no fractures,
no bruising.
Cause of death?
Chest was crushed.
Multiple rib fractures
and hence the white bucket
you and David filled
with his intestines.
They literally popped out.
So he wasn't hit by the taxi;
he was run over?
Well, he would've
died anyway.
He was stabbed.
Clean incised wound
to the abdomen.
Five inches deep.
So how much time elapsed
between when he was stabbed
and when he encountered
the taxi?
I can't give you
an exact time frame
except to say it
wasn't immediate...
and before you ask,
we don't have an ID
but Missing Persons called.
A woman called and
said her son never
came home last night.
She's on her way in.
You know you
pulled me away
from a forensic
anthropology
seminar, right?
It's required.
It's part of the continuing
education program.
Well, I'm sorry,
but everyone seems
to have something to do today.
I have a teenager
who was run over by a taxi.
He wasn't hit by it;
that's not what killed him.
He was stabbed, fatally.
For now, I have no ID,
no suspects
and no primary crime scene.
I need you.
How can I help?
Hey, Grissom?
The directionality
of this drop
is facing the boulevard.
I think your victim
was bleeding
before he crossed
the street.
Blood trail.
Want to go for a walk?
( camera shutter clicking )
SIDLE:
Blood leads into the grass.
Trail's obscured.
Okay.
So, where do we pick up
the trail?
Well, vic's in his teens...
Probably wasn't
on the playground.
My money's
on the basketball court.
He crossed Lake Mead Boulevard
at 8:15
and it gets dark at 5:00.
He was here after dark.
And I don't see any lights.
Droplets and castoff.
This is our primary
crime scene.
So, maybe the killer
tossed the knife.
It's a big dump site.
Yeah.
I'll, uh,
order up some scent dogs...
get some uniforms.
That's him.
That's my boy.
I'm so sorry.
How did something
like this happen?
He's only 14 years old.
Mrs. Branson, I'm afraid
you'll have to talk
with the detectives.
Hey, Sara.
Hey.
You working that case
where some mob beat up
an Indian cab driver
for hitting a kid?
Cabbie didn't actually
hit the kid.
He was in the wrong place
at the wrong time.
You think
it was racially motivated?
Yeah, I do.
White mob, white kid,
dark-skinned cabbie--
I don't like the math.
Yeah.
We got to wait
for the science, don't we?
I'm trying.
That's the job.
Good luck.
Captain, there's a Mrs. Branson
here to see you.
Oh good.
Send her in, Joe. Thanks.
Mrs. Branson, thank you
for coming in...
Have you arrested
that taxi driver?
He's in intensive care.
How did he not
see my son?
That's a well-lit intersection.
My son is five foot six!
Please, Mrs. Branson...
please, sit down.
Um...
( clears throat )
Your son was stabbed
in Haskell Park
and you live
on Loring Avenue.
My best guess is that
he was on his way home
when the accident occurred.
No, I don't understand.
The taxi didn't kill your son
but someone did.
Did Todd have any problems
that you're aware of?
Did he have any problems
at school?
No, no, nothing like that.
He's a... he's a great kid.
He's-He's athletic.
He's popular.
He's, uh, he's a good student.
We-We moved here from Portland
nine months ago.
He fit right in.
Did you know
he was in the park
after sundown?
No.
I thought he was at
a friend's for dinner.
He was supposed
to call me, but
you know teenagers.
Yeah, I do...
and they don't often confide
in their parents, I know.
Uh, I've been on the run
from my
ex-husband.
He's threatened to
kill me and my boys.
I just try and stay
one step ahead of him.
When was the last time
you saw him?
In Portland.
He showed up outside
of Todd's school.
The boys and I were
on a bus that evening.
You know, a couple days
ago, the phone rang.
I answered it.
It was him.
I don't know how
he found us here
but this weekend,
the boys and I were
going to disappear.
Why didn't you call
the police?
Because you knew
we couldn't protect you.
( murmurs indistinctly )
( metal detector humming )
( humming continues )
SIDLE:
What have you got?
You got the gloves on.
Looking for a knife;
uncover a gun.
What is happening
to our parks?
( howling )
Officer...
Back the dogs
off, please.
Dead body found 20 yards
from where our vic was knifed.
You think
they're related?
Well they're related
by geography...
but for now
it's just a dead guy
in the park.
Hey.
I thought you had
a couple days off?
I do, but I left these
on my desk.
I'm on my way
to Circus Circus
with five nine-year-olds.
It's Lindsey's birthday.
Got to wrap
a Bridal Barbie.
What's a Bridal Barbie?
Funny.
Oh, blue...
gun shot residue.
On our stabbing
victim's jacket.
So it means that he may have
fired the revolver
that you and Grissom
found in the park?
Yeah. Too bad GSR testing
can't tie the vic
to a particular gun.
Right.
Hmm... but maybe Grissom can.
Grissom?
Yeah, I just passed him
in Ballistics.
He was meditating
on your revolver.
Didn't even look up.
Excuse me.
Mm-hmm.
Have fun.
Thanks.
You know,
you could've waited for me.
Take a look at this.
Looks like burnt skin.
I think maybe someone palmed
the cylinder gap.
Todd Branson had
GSR on his jacket.
If we could get his
DNA off this revolver
we could tie him to this.
Burnt skin is useless
for DNA.
Yeah, but, what about sweat?
There's a 17% chance
of DNA recovery
from the shooter's
perspiration.
17%?
Yeah. New paper
out of Australia.
You haven't seen it?
17% chance
of DNA recovery
from the grip of a gun,
67% chance from a cigarette
32% chance from the brim
of a hat.
Would you like a copy?
I don't need one.
I have you.
Swab the pistol grip;
get it to DNA.
Albert, did you notice
if Todd Branson had
any burn marks
on his palms?
No.
What about this guy?
Negative.
What are you looking for?
A specific injury.
Well, I can't help you
with burns
but you'll want to check out
this guy's right palm.
An incised wound.
Well, that's a common injury
sustained by knife-wielding
killers.
So assuming that
this is the man
who stabbed Todd Branson,
what killed this guy?
A bullet.
It's lodged in
the left ventricle.
I was contemplating
my method of extraction
when you arrived.
You reach in
and pull it out.
Not if it's only
a jacket fragment.
Maybe a
frangible bullet
designed to fragment
on impact?
That would explain
the mystery of
the shattered femur.
It's covered
in copper dust.
I'll remove the heart,
peel back the myocardium
and get you what's left
of that bullet.
Did he have
a dislocated shoulder?
Yeah, torn musculature,
but no inflammatory response.
It happened postmortem?
Excuse me, I'm headed over
to the hospital.
Taxi driver didn't make it.
Another one for my table.
Emerson once said
"The mob is man
voluntarily descending to
the nature of the beast."
The beast is up for murder.
Hey, buddy,
how's it going?
I'm Detective Jim Brass
from Las Vegas Police.
Is your mother home?
No.
What's your name?
Eric.
Sorry about your
brother, Eric.
Mom's out getting more boxes.
Yeah, she said that
you were moving.
Where are you going to?
You know, when I was a kid
we moved around a lot.
It's not easy.
So you're going to
be seeing your dad?
My dad's dead.
Died when I was two.
Hey, Eric, will you
do me a favor?
When you see your mom
ask her to give
me a call, okay?
Okay.
Take care.
Is that the frangible?
Yep.
These were originally used
in indoor shooting ranges
where lead buildup's
a problem.
Copper's less toxic
than lead.
Take a look.
On the left,
bullet from the vic's heart.
On the right, bullet test-fired
from the revolver
recovered at the scene.
Oh, serendipity.
Yep.
Hey.
Just made a match
to your revolver.
Nice.
I ran the serial number
through NCIC.
It's registered
to a Jonathan Raurk of
San Jose, California.
John's my ex.
Is he in Las Vegas?
BRASS:
Well, we, uh...
we found a gun
registered to him
in the park where
your son was murdered
but when I spoke
to your son Eric
he told me that his
father died years ago.
That's what I told both my boys.
I told them that John
was killed in a car accident.
It's not easy
to lie to them like that
but every time I move I have
to make up some crazy story.
I just want them to be able
to sleep at night.
Ms. Branson
we also found a dead
body in the park--
a white male in his mid-30s.
You think it's John?
We have no ID,
but we have a photograph.
No...
No, this...
This isn't John.
This isn't my ex.
This is Stewart.
It's Stewart Bradley.
He's my boyfriend.
Where have you been?
I went back to the park.
I kept thinking
there must be some
physical evidence
connecting the stabbing
to the shooting.
GRISSOM:
Drag marks?
SIDLE:
Leading from
the basketball court
to Stewart Bradley's body.
We know Todd was bleeding
but there were no blood drops
around the drag marks.
So you're thinking
someone else was there?
Now, the revolver was registered
to the boy's biological father
but they haven't seen
each other in ten years.
Assuming Todd fired the gun,
how did he get ahold of it?
Well, maybe Dad gave it to him
behind Mom's back.
Or... maybe Todd
wasn't the shooter.
True.
Presence of GSR only places Todd
in the vicinity of the gunfire.
And since there were no
burn marks on Todd's palms
evidence is suggesting
someone else fired that gun.
Which brings us
back to Dad.
BRASS:
You know something, John,
you don't scare me.
According to your ex-wife,
you're some kind of monster--
threatening her life
setting her car
on fire in Boston
breaking and entering
in Chicago
showing up at your kid's
school in Portland...
I don't know, I mean
I thought maybe
you'd be like the guy
in Sleeping
with the Enemy.
You're more like
Gumby, aren't you?
Look, if this is
about my ex...
cop pulled me over
outside Moapa.
Jane lives in Vegas.
I didn't violate any damn
court order, all right?
You know where she lives.
Is that a crime?
Yesterday, your son Todd
was murdered
and that is a crime.
Hey!
John, baby
I'm not talking about
the weather here, man.
I'm talking about your son.
I haven't seen that kid
since he was in his diapers.
Geez, I didn't kill him,
if that's where you're going to.
Hey, what about
Stewart Bradley?
( speaking indistinctly )
He was shot
with your gun.
Which one?
Revolver. Smith &amp;amp; Wesson.
No, I don't have
a Smith &amp;amp; Wesson.
It's registered to you, John.
Has your name on it.
That got stolen.
Oh, you file a police report?
But I know,
you're busy.
You forgot. That's okay.
You know what I think happened?
Here's what I think.
You called up Todd,
you said, "Hey, Todd
"why don't you meet me
down at Haskell Park?
"You know what? Why
don't you bring Mom's
new boyfriend along?"
No, no. Come on, man,
whoa, whoa, hey.
You know what?
Last night, I was
at Taos, New Mexico, okay?
I didn't cross over until...
it was the afternoon in Nevada.
Check it out.
Adobe Inn.
Watched pay-per-view
and I had a pizza, okay?
( sighs )
May I see your hands,
please?
You better do
what he says.
He's in Crime Lab.
Can you hold him?
He's got some unpaid
speeding tickets.
There's warrants
that have been issued.
Is three days good enough?
For now.
What do you weigh?
Uh, that's between me
and my trainer.
Do I have to get a scale?
A buck 95,
give or take a doughnut.
Don't even ask.
I'm not telling you.
Warrick, would you lie
down on the floor?
I don't get paid enough
to play dead.
Please?
( sighs )
Sara, grab Warrick's
right arm.
See if you can drag
him across the room.
This does have something
to do with the case, right?
You don't trust me?
( sighs )
( grunts )
( Brown groans )
You're such a drag.
( Sidle chuckles )
Stay there a minute.
Excuse me. Hi.
Judy, right?
Judy, would you
like to be part of
a little experiment?
I-I'm a secretary.
Besides, I heard
what you did to Greg's feet.
You'll keep your shoes on,
I promise.
Can I get up?
No. Spin around.
Judy, would you take
Warrick by the right arm
and try and drag him
across the room?
Hi, Judy.
Hi.
( grunting )
Hey, I like it gentle, okay?
( grunts )
Thank you, Judy.
You've been a big help.
Thanks.
You can go back to
the water cooler.
You want to tell me
what's going on here?
Stewart Bradley had
a dislocated shoulder
postmortem.
He's about the same
weight as you.
How does your shoulder feel?
You saw her dragging me around.
You know, I'm glad I can help.
I, uh, I'm late
for the chiropractor's.
I'll send you the bill.
I get it.
I'm bigger than Judy.
In order to get momentum,
she had to start and stop.
Which could explain
Stewart Bradley's
postmortem
dislocated shoulder.
Especially if he was
dragged by somebody
with limited upper
body strength.
Where does that get us?
Well, maybe Jan Branson.
She's about Judy's size.
Why would Jan Branson
shoot her boyfriend?
He stabbed her son.
Motive?
I don't know.
But mothers protect their
children, don't they?
Okay... okay, so...
she sends Todd home, not knowing
the severity of his wound.
She buries
her boyfriend's body.
She ditches the knife,
which we still haven't found.
She hides the revolver...
So perhaps the evidence
is in Mrs. Branson's hands.
Mrs. Branson,
you got a minute?
Uh, Eric and I
are leaving town.
Well, your ex has
been picked up on
an unrelated matter.
Even if he makes bail,
you still got a day
or two head start.
Good.
Ms. Branson,
may I see your hands?
Excuse me?
Could be important.
Palms up, please.
Hi, pal.
Hi.
Hey, Eric.
This is Mr. Grissom.
We work together.
May I see your hands, please?
We have to get going.
As soon as Eric shows
Mr. Grissom his hands
you're on your way.
Palms up.
Eric...
I need to know
how you burned your hand.
Look at Mr. Grissom, Eric.
Not your mother, okay?
Ms. Karpell.
Eric, it's okay to
answer the question.
I burned it on an iron.
BRASS:
I think something
a lot more dangerous
than that burned
your hand.
We recovered a gun...
in the park.
Your burn indicates
that your hand
was over this gap
when the gun was fired.
( gunshot )
I followed Todd to the park.
Todd, I got your e-mail.
What's up?
We're not moving again.
I want you to tell Mom you're
passing on that promotion.
You should discuss this
with your mother.
She'll do whatever you say.
You don't understand.
I am not leaving my
friends 'cause of you!
Todd, this has nothing
to do with me.
Todd, no!
( gunshot )
Gotta get home.
( gun clatters )
Hide the body.
I was just looking out
for my brother.
I swabbed the pistol grip
of the revolver.
The DNA from the suspect's
perspiration
isn't a match to Todd's.
But it is male.
With eight markers
in common
and familial relationship.
GRISSOM:
We found gunshot residue
on Todd's jacket.
We assumed that Todd
fired the gun.
But I think maybe he was
standing next to you
when you fired the gun.
You didn't go to the park
to stop Todd, did you?
He went to the park
to stop you.
Eric, what's up?
TODD:
Whoa! Eric, Eric!
Eric, don't be stupid.
I'm not moving again!
Not 'cause of him!
( gunshot )
Go home!
Where'd you get
the revolver, Eric?
JAN:
From me.
BRASS:
Ms. Karpell...
Eric, why don't we
step out in the hall
for a few minutes.
So, the gun was
in your possession
and you didn't say anything.
I, um...
I had it in a lock box.
And, uh, when I got that call
from John a couple of days ago
I took it out
and I put in my nightstand.
I didn't even know it was
missing until this morning.
And then, I thought that John
must've gotten in the house
and taken it.
I was so sure that he was
the one who killed Stewart.
I've spent the
last ten years
looking over my shoulder
every day.
BRASS:
Your boyfriend was found
carrying a knife
the night he died.
I spoke to some of his friends
and associates, and no one ever
remembers him
carrying a knife.
SIDLE:
Ms. Branson?
You warned your boyfriend about
your ex-husband, didn't you?
He asked me what was wrong
and I shouldn't have said
anything.
He panicked.
He overreacted.
He started carrying a knife.
What's going to happen to Eric?
He'll be remanded
to a juvenile detention center,
awaiting trial.
And then?
BRASS:
If he's convicted
of a homicide
he'll be sent to
a state custodial facility
until he's 21.
Where we at, Greg?
I paged you, like,
ten times.
I was busy.
Well, so was I.
First, I processed
Mr. Khandelwhal's clothing.
Then I compared the DNA
I lifted from said clothing
to the DNA from
the Dirty Dozen.
All I see is a sheet.
But what I do is art.
And now, I'm ready
to unveil it.
Welcome to the new and
improved Match Game.
Now, Graham Cooper
grabbed Rajeeb's collar...
( men yelling angrily )
Claude Allen
and Barry Lawrence
used their fists...
( men clamoring
and blows landing )
Joey Gillman, Bill Kendal
and Rick Midgen
got into it, too.
Very nice presentation, Greg.
What about the others?
They all participated.
They even bragged about it.
Well, only six of the 12 left
behind their epithelials
when their skin made contact
with the vic's clothing.
I've got no physical
evidence to tie the
others to the crime.
( indistinct conversation
echoing eerily )
Stop!
( tires screeching,
body thudding )
Hey!
( mob yelling )
GRISSOM:
The mob mentality...
relieves individuals
from having to distinguish
between right and wrong.
Anonymity shields them
from prosecution, though.
Yeah, six of them,
to be exact.
Unfortunately, physical evidence
is limited by human action.
Well, nothing's absolute, Gil...
even forensics.
Yeah, well...
this is as far
as we can take it.
It's up to you guys.
BRASS:
The physical evidence confirms
that you're the "hero"
who pulled the driver
out of the cab.
I'd do it again, too.
Mr. Cooper,
why don't we just hear
what Captain Brass has to say.
You're looking at
first degree murder.
What?!
Mr. Khandelwhal didn't make it.
( sighs )
And, for the record,
he didn't hit that boy.
He wasn't trying
to flee the scene.
He was reaching
for his radio
trying to call for help.
You know who the real
hero of this is?
Rajeeb Khandelwhal.
The taxi driver.
So...
what does that make you?
D.A. willing to deal?
( heavy sigh )
( over speaker ):
We want your buddies.
I mean, either you
talk or they'll talk.
I mean, it doesn't matter.
And the clock
is ticking, so...
♪ Everything... Everything
in its right place... ♪