( thunder crashing )
Hey, Danny.
Thanks.
( beeping )
( door bolt clanks )
( announcements over P.A. )
Some night, huh?
It's ugly out there.
( thunder rumbling )
( man grunting )
( device beeping )
We have two types
of patients here:
the criminally insane
and sexually violent predators,
all with multiple
convictions.
We get all the inmates
the prisons can't handle.
Keep your kits closed
and locked when not in use.
Um, Ms. Sidle, best
if you remove the vest.
New uniforms
upset them.
We're mostly concerned
with maintaining
psychiatric remission.
We want to stabilize
symptoms
and reduce an individual's risk
of violence to himself
and to others.
Oh, uh, could
actually stop here
and put your backs
against the wall, please.
It's standard
safety procedure.
( exhaling heavily )
MAN:
Put your tongue
in your mouth, Jake.
We're moving them all
to the Day Room.
This is Captain Brass.
Dr. Grissom and Ms. Sidle
are from the Crime Lab.
Lt. Reed Owens,
Desert State Hospital Police.
We have our own
internal police team
and Lieutenant Owens was
the first officer on the scene
after the call came in.
The victim was found
by Nurse Faber
at approximately 12:10 a.m.
Joanne was coming off shift,
I was coming on.
Doing bed checks,
I found Robbie on the floor.
Kenny was in the corner
covered in blood.
Are the patients locked in
their rooms at night?
No. The doors
are left unlocked.
BRASS:
So they're free
to roam around?
Locked rooms usually lead
to patients trying
to harm themselves.
BRASS:
Where's Kenny now?
He's been taken to seclusion.
( screaming )
Shh-shh-shh.
Leon, let's get a couple
more milligrams
of Lorazepam into him.
How did he get
those wounds?
Oh, Kenny's a self-mutilator.
He suffers
from Renfield's Syndrome;
gets off on blood.
Shh...
Couple of weeks ago
I caught him gouging
himself
with a carpet staple.
He was wearing these clothes
when you found him?
Yes.
There was blood spatter
all over the victim's room.
Blood but no spatter
on Kenny's clothes.
I'm not sure this is our guy.
Locked unit.
Finite number
of suspects.
Crazy or not... here we come.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
Who's this guy knitting
an imaginary sweater?
How's he know
when it's finished?
His brain tells him
that what he's
doing is real.
He has no reason
to doubt it.
Or any desire to.
GRISSOM:
They asked John Nash
how he could believe
that extraterrestrials
were sending him messages.
He said that the messages
came to him
in the same way that his
mathematical ideas did.
So he had to take them
seriously.
Hey.
Valerie Dino.
I'm the on-call doctor.
Did you pronounce?
Yeah.
The administration asked me
to set up some rooms
for your interviews,
but, uh, personally,
I don't see what you hope
to accomplish.
These patients are criminals
with severe mental disorders.
They're not going
to give you a straight answer.
No one ever does.
( thunder rumbling )
I definitely heard something.
He said, "I'll get in!"
No, no, it was,
"I'm coming in."
I heard him say it.
And it's not like
he isn't serious.
Who isn't serious?
The, uh, perpetrator.
Can you tell me anything else
about him?
Oh, no, I couldn't.
Why not?
( whispers ):
He's here.
In this room?
Is his name Ronald?
No. My name is Ronald.
What's his name?
He doesn't have a name.
He's a cricket.
Here.
A cricket?
Yes.
Trying to burrow
a hole in my head.
I don't sleep.
Never?
So what do you do at night?
Day, night, it don't make
no difference.
I think.
About what?
Bitches.
What's so amusing?
So let's say you find out
who did it,
and maybe it's me.
What are you going to do?
Are you going to convict me
of murder
and put me in a bad place?
Is it you?
Check the files, sir.
I'm a rapist, not a murderer.
( thunder crashing )
Robert Garson?
Hmm?
GRISSOM:
Do you know what happened
to Robert Garson?
Female pig relation hanged,
it sped even,
well, too.
What?
No. I ground it... blindly.
Wet and dirty.
Cut the blood oven.
It spoke justly,
repeatedly, calmly.
Some thin rod dared your wash.
They foretold this
into some ready child,
which fell crossly.
They hag-rode me... again.
Why are you looking at me?
You got Leon, he's a spic.
Earl, the brother.
And the crazy frickin' jewboy
with the bug in his head.
You know, most of the doctors
here are Jewish.
They're the ones
with the access.
Yeah?
Dr. Dino.
Hi.
Paperwork.
This is a state-run facility.
What can I help you with?
Question about the victim.
I have heard that
in some cases
of deviant sexual
predisposition,
you slow the sex drive...
If you're talking
about chemical castration,
the answer is, yes, Robbie was.
So he didn't masturbate.
Masturbate, yes.
Ejaculate, no.
So the semen that I found
on his bed is someone else's?
Likely.
Thanks.
Sure.
Hey, guys, I found semen
in the victim's room
and it's probably
not his.
He was chemically
castrated.
So you're thinking
the donor could be
the killer?
Sex is the foreplay.
Violence is the climax.
Well... happy swabbing.
They've been prepped.
You're all set.
Thank you, Lieutenant.
Here you go, padre.
Wash your worries away.
Thank you.
Well, you take that side.
I'll take Jiminy Cricket.
Excellent.
( indistinct P.A. announcement)
Say ah.
Ah.
Thank you.
( thunder rumbling )
Say ah.
You, too, Leon.
I work here.
Exactly.
Open your mouth,
please.
Would you open your mouth, sir?
( muttering )
Grissom...
you take this one.
( muttering )
( car horn blares )
Let's start with
the stomach contents.
They're fascinating.
It reminded me
of that scene in Jaws
where Dreyfuss cuts open
the shark's belly
and all kinds of weird
things come out.
You find a license plate?
Not quite.
Highlights include Band-Aids,
wood chips, hair
and half a snapshot.
Pica?
Boo?
Pica is a compulsion
to eat non-nutritive food items.
It's from the Latin word
for magpie,
a bird with a large and
indiscriminate appetite.
Trichotillomania would explain
the pulling out
and eating of hair.
Another OCD disorder.
I sent hair and blood
samples to Tox.
Stellate lacerations.
Linear skull
fracture extending
into the calvarium.
And contre-coup contusions
to the frontal
and temporal lobes.
So C.O.D. was
blunt force trauma?
No. Asphyxiation.
During the struggle?
No. Coagulation
of the blood
tells me that the head trauma
was post-mortem,
at least two hours
after he was suffocated.
So evidently dead
wasn't dead enough.
I also found ligature marks
on the wrists and ankles.
They showed up
during the Y,
peri-mortem.
So, what, tortured? Tied up?
Restrained.
Nobody mentioned restraints.
HODGES:
Would you ever
bleach your hair?
I wouldn't.
It's so Greg Sanders.
Most of the hair
is the vic's, but I also found
that bleached sample as well.
In my continuing quest
to further my standing,
I took it upon myself to
get you the tox report.
Thanks.
You're welcome.
Blood came back with pretty
hefty levels of Olanzapine.
That's a potent
anti-psychotic.
Good for drooling.
And also there's
the, uh, not so potent
smattering of Ibuprofen.
That's it?
That's it.
If I were
institutionalized,
I think I would hope
for something better.
Clonazepam, maybe.
What, you, uh,
think I'm crazy?
Crazy is as crazy does.
His chart indicated
at least four other
anti-psychotics.
Why wasn't he getting
those meds?
Do I look clairvoyant?
BRASS:
News flash from the loony bin.
Two reported deaths
in the last three years
from "complications
due to restraint procedures."
And how many have
gone unreported?
The hospital
just got off probation.
One more death by restraint
brings the Feds in.
Good incentive
to keep it quiet.
Or make it look like
someone else did it.
Yeah. Somebody who's crazy.
DUNBAR:
We're legally required
to tape all our sessions.
This is Robbie
in the seclusion room
the day he died.
( fast-forwarding tape )
As you can see,
the on-call doctor
and Nurse Mckay
checked in on him.
Two hours later,
he was escorted out,
so I resent the accusation.
We've made a lot of changes.
Policy, staff, surveillance
have all been overhauled.
Look, Robbie left
the seclusion room alive.
Okay, fine.
Who administers
medication?
Uh, the nurses, psych techs.
Why is this important?
Well, according
to his tox results,
Robbie's system was short
four anti-psychotics.
Maybe he was cheeking them.
Why would he do that?
They think
they don't need 'em.
They sell 'em, trade 'em or...
store them up,
get high later.
We're gonna need
to talk to his pharmacist.
Who's next?
Oh, come on, Earl.
There you go.
Hey, you know I'm gonna bust
your ass on the court, right?
You better bring
your 'A' game next time.
Come on, Chuck,
I got something for you.
Love your hair, Leon.
Thanks.
What do you got here?
Ibuprofen, laxative,
aspirin.
What are you treating exactly,
schizophrenia
or constipation?
Where are the real drugs, Leon?
Man... Xanax, Lanzopine,
Zoloft, Suprazadone,
Clozapine, Loranzapan,
lithium, Valium,
Wellbutrin, Haldol,
Respiredone.
You took everything
with street value.
( chuckles ):
Look, dude...
I get 22K a year.
That's nothing.
Diddly-squat.
I should get hazard pay.
These people, I get...
I get spit on, puked on,
peed on, bitten.
I get my hair yanked out,
I get my ass pinched,
I get... I get
death threats.
All for 22K.
So I supplement
my income.
It don't hurt nobody.
Are you a doctor?
Look, these places, they
overmedicate all the time.
It controls
the population.
And I don't endanger
the patients, okay?
I-I'm all about the patients.
Maybe Robbie
caught you skimping
on his meds, threatened
to blow the whistle.
There goes that
supplemental income.
I see what you're doing.
I'm reporting you.
You're stealing.
Robbie, hold on
a second, will you?
( screaming )
All right, here you go,
here you go, here you go.
( continues screaming )
No. All right, no way, man.
That's a story.
'Kay? That's not why
he went to seclusion.
Why did he go to seclusion?
He freaked out in group.
I wasn't even there.
Ask somebody who was.
Am I gonna lose my job?
'Cause these people...
need me.
SIDLE:
According to the video logs,
the victim was brought
into seclusion at 5:03 p.m.
and taken out of the room
at 7:06 p.m.
Nurse Mckay noted that
he was awake and in bed
at the 9:30 p.m. bed-checks.
Body was found at 12:10.
So sometime between 9:30
and midnight, he was suffocated.
Probably closer to 9:30.
The blood would've needed time
to coagulate
before his head was smashed in.
And not necessarily
by the same person.
Hey, how about
some pillow talk?
Robbie's pillow
had saliva on it.
Lots of it; all his.
Could be from drooling.
Or it could be from dying.
Well, look at this--
I found slits at both ends.
Left hand...
and right hand.
Looks like we have
a murder weapon.
WOMAN ( over P.A. ):
All past-level-three patients,
please return to your unit
for a head count.
All past-level-three patients,
please return to your unit...
Thanks, Officer.
Nurse Mckay, hi.
Dr. Dino said
that you supervised
group therapy yesterday.
Uh, yeah.
I heard there was
an incident involving Robbie.
He had a personal item.
A personal item?
You can't bring anything
in group except a beverage.
It distracts the other patients.
What did he bring?
A photograph.
Of what?
A little boy.
What did you do?
I followed protocol.
Anybody else have anything
they want to talk about?
MAN:
I wanna know why everybody's
always staring at me--
especially him.
He's staring at me.
I'm not staring at...
Hang on, hang on.
Robbie?
What have you got there?
Nothing.
Fag candy.
Well, what's the rule?
There's no personal items...
No!
Give me the...
No! Don't touch me!
( Robbie shouting )
Boom, boom and boom: medication,
seclusion, restraint.
Tough love.
Call it what you want--
these aren't my children.
Why didn't you mention
this information last night?
Because crap like that
happens every day here.
I should get back
to the unit.
Sure.
( phone rings )
Sidle.
GRISSOM:
We got the DNA results back
on the semen on Robbie's sheets.
Patient Adam Trent--
the nail biter.
Okay.
This stuff is dark.
Yeah.
'Course, I wouldn't expect
Winnie the Pooh.
Adam's subconscious
was working overtime.
SIDLE:
I bet you aced
your Rorschachs.
When I was
in fifth grade,
I drew a picture
of a harpooned whale.
Everyone thought I was gonzo'd.
But I had just read
Moby Dick.
Sometimes a dying whale
is just a dying whale.
These are all postdated
over a year ago.
It's not just his subconscious.
This guy's got stuff
buried everywhere.
DR. DINO:
"Dearest Angel,
I think of you wherever I go.
"You are my prince.
I miss you.
Write to me.
Your only love, Mother."
Another one.
Uh... "It rained today.
"I thought of that time
when you and I got caught
"in the storm at the lake.
"The fire... I came home
and made your favorite dinner.
I even set a
place for you..."
So on and so forth.
That does not sound
maternal to me.
It's not.
Incest?
Fully consummated.
Mother-son incest is rare
and deeply pathological.
Oedipal complex taken too far?
Oedipus...
implies son to mother.
In this case, the mother
was seeking the love
and creating the codependence.
We call this a Jocasta complex.
Oedipus' mother.
When Adam was nine
his father died.
His mother replaced her
dead husband with her son.
That's got to mess you up.
Yeah. Adam is schizo-affective,
suicidal,
and a pathological narcissist.
When he was a teenager
he was unable to retaliate
against his mother
and incapable
of actual intimacy,
so... he started raping woman.
GRISSOM:
Always women?
Yes. Which is why I don't think
he killed Robbie.
We found Adam's semen
in Robbie's bed.
You see, that surprises me.
Like any good psychopath, he
rarely veers from his pattern.
Adam is
a single-celled organism
who exists wholly for himself.
He must've been getting
something tangible in return.
What?
Drugs? Cigarettes?
Drugs aren't his issue.
And as far as I know
he doesn't smoke. Um...
So, uh, what can we
learn from his art work?
Uh... He starts with
an innocuous object;
a tree, a cat, an oboe--
all of which he morphs
into something deadly.
You can see...
all of them.
So what should
be safe turns
into something unsafe.
Mother becomes lover.
What about the mother?
Do you have any idea
where she is?
She lives near Reno.
Based on the postmarks, it seems
like she stopped writing him.
Every time a letter came
a manic episode followed,
then a severe depression,
including one suicide attempt.
So I started sending
the letters back.
Eventually, she stopped writing.
( thunder softly rumbles )
Did I kill him?
Yes.
Why?
He was queer.
But you had sex
with him.
No.
He had sex with me.
He was the punk.
Was it consensual?
I don't know.
So why did you do it?
SIDLE:
Okay.
So then what happened?
I took his head
and I smashed it into the floor.
And that's how you killed him?
What? You don't believe me?
I'm just wondering if
that's how you killed him.
Yes. I'm saying this
and this is true.
And if you don't believe me,
just look in the bucket
in the latrine.
Okay...
Do you really want to know
why I killed him?
Yes.
It's because I'm crazy.
Not a word about suffocation.
Well, his nails
weren't long enough
to leave those tears
in the pillow.
And there would have
been traces of blood
from his cuticles.
Something is off.
Here's the blood splatter
we've been looking for.
What is that on the crotch?
Lipstick.
( rain splashing )
Where is Nurse Mckay?
I need to talk to her.
She's on lunch duty.
All right. I can
either take this
and the underwear
back to the lab
and confirm the match,
which will only extend
our presence here.
Or...
you can give me access to
the nurse's station right now.
WOMAN ( over P.A. ):
Dr. Walsh,
please call your service.
call your service, stat.
SIDLE:
This must be the photo
that Nurse Mckay confiscated
from Robbie in group.
The missing half?
I found blue tape
in Robbie's room.
Kind of looks like Adam.
Where would Robbie
get a picture of Adam?
Well, they were having sex.
I'm going to find someone
who can open these drawers.
Okay.
WOMAN ( over P.A. ):
Dr. Stoon, please pick up
the white telephone.
Dr. Stoon,
call on the white telephone.
Hey.
Are you a spiritual person?
Sometimes.
Do you believe that everything
happens for a reason?
That bad things are
there to teach us
a karmic lesson?
You know, maybe
all our problems
can be cured by tuning
in to a higher frequency.
There's this one guy I read,
he believes that
illness, anxiety
and fear
all occur when people
are vibrating
at 10,000 cycles a second.
( groaning )
If they could just get up
to 100,000 cycles per second
they'd be in the realm of sound,
light and spirit,
and everything would be
just fine. Right?
Yeah.
ADAM:
You know what I think?
I think I'm just vibrating
at the wrong frequency.
SIDLE:
It's okay.
ADAM:
Do you think I'm smart?
Yeah.
Yeah?
Uh-huh.
Do you think I'm right?
SIDLE:
I do.
Open the door.
I can't. I don't have my keys
to open the door.
Don't you move.
Please open the door.
You move a muscle
I will grind you, bitch.
You hear me?
Do not look at them.
Keep your eyes on the floor.
You! You, go away!
No!
Adam, stop!
Get a medic in here!
Hold still.
Apple pressure!
Where is he?
( Adam crying )
We need some help in here!
When my father died,
my mother came
to a place like this
for awhile for evaluation.
It looked the same,
it smelled the same.
It smelled like lies.
You sure you're okay?
Crazy people
do make me feel crazy.
If you want, I can have somebody
take your place.
I appreciate that.
I do, I really do, but...
I kind of made
a decision
to move beyond that and...
I really want
to finish this case.
We have rules
for a reason.
You people come in here
disrupting things.
You're unsafe.
This is your fault.
Really?
You seem to take your
job rather personally.
What are you suggesting?
That you had an intimate
relationship with Adam Trent.
That's ridiculous.
Your lipstick
is on his underwear.
I gave Robbie my lipstick
sometimes.
Maybe he was
wearing it when...
We didn't find any on his lips.
Well, that's your problem.
What are you waiting for?
Get him to
the medical unit, stat.
Excuse me.
Adam Trent was working on
this piece?
Yes.
He made it on Monday.
But he never got a chance
to fire it.
Nurse Mckay came in,
they had a
conversation.
Actually, it was
more of an argument,
very heated, very loud.
And then she yanked
him out of class.
Was this on the wheel
while they were arguing?
Yeah.
Adam's work is
very provocative.
Yeah.
It speaks to me.
SIDLE:
Acoustic Archeology?
In the '60s,
experiments were done
on clay pots
and painted canvas.
Scientists were able
to ferret out
sounds that were captured
during the creative process
in the clay and the paint.
Trippy.
It's actually
not that out there.
In the old days, the first
gramophone recordings
were made by taking
the vibrations of sound
and cutting them
into wax cylinders
while they were turning.
Based on the frequency
and intensity of the sound,
the stylus cut into the wax,
creating distinct variances
of depth and width.
For playback,
a mechanical transducer
vibrated along a groove,
generating a current
which, when amplified,
turned into sound.
When the art therapist
told me
that there'd been an argument
while Adam was on the wheel,
I thought well, maybe we can
pull some sound
off his pot.
SIDLE:
Doppler laser.
Optical transducer.
We've come a long way.
Baby.
( beeps )
Well, there's something there.
And it sounds like...
( beeps )
this.
( static )
It's lousy signal-to-noise.
It's going to need a lot
of processing.
( warbling )
Speech elements skew
to consonants.
I'll try and dig them out.
( computer beeps )
( warbling )
Rrr-bee... Rrr-bee...
Robbie?
Maybe.
Could you run that
back a little bit?
Sure.
( warbles )
What is that?
( warble repeats )
Right there.
Nnn-gl. Nnn-gl...
Angle?
Angel.
...my angel.
My angel. My angel.
In her letters, Adam's mother
called him "angel."
The hair from the brush
in Adam's room
was fresh enough
to get a DNA profile.
It came back female.
We tested it against
your cigarette butt.
It matched.
Adam liked it when
I brushed his hair.
I bet he did.
You were lying about
giving Robbie lipstick.
You have seven out of 13
alleles in common
with your patient,
Adam Trent.
Your dearest angel.
Okay.
Joanne Mckay,
registered nurse,
licensed by the Nevada
Board of Nursing 1978.
Married Howard Trent 1980.
The board requires you
to get a new certificate
when you get married.
I guess you never complied.
I've always gone by
my maiden name.
I guess that makes it
less embarrassing
to check into the motel
with your son.
Oh, I'm sorry.
You checked into
a psycho ward instead.
My son needed me.
SIDLE:
For what?
To destroy his ego?
To fill him with guilt?
To make him hate himself so much
he would take his own life
just to be free of you?
You have no idea
what goes on between us.
Let's cut the umbilical cord,
okay?
Six months ago your
letters started
to come back.
No more communication with
little Lord Fauntleroy.
So you apply to Desert State.
They were desperate
for nursing staff,
so you got a job.
Gentlemen, this is our
new nurse, Nurse Mckay.
Hello.
Bet it's tough to turn
a folie á deux
into a menage á trois.
N'est-ce pas?
Even tougher that your son
was cheating on you...
with a man no less.
You need to stop this.
Stop what?
End it with Robbie.
Don't tell me
what to do.
End it or I will.
But he didn't end it, did he?
Robbie was lover's leverage.
He was that thing that Adam
kept in his back pocket
and pull out
whenever he needed
to distance himself from you.
So you had no choice
but to get rid of Robbie.
And being a good nurse,
you knew his trigger.
I want you
to talk about this
in group today.
B-But I thought that we...
It's okay.
You can bring it.
Hey! Robbie.
What do you got there?
There's no personal items
in group.
B-But y-you...
you told me...
that I could bring this.
I didn't say anything.
Give me that.
What is that,
a picture?
You remember?
Give me the picture.
No, do you remember?
You remember? No!
Give me the picture.
No, you don't tell me!
You told me...!
( yelling )
Hang on!
( screaming )
( muffled screams )
You manipulated the situation
and took advantage
of his weakness.
SIDLE:
Exactly what you have
been doing to Adam
for the past 20 years.
And being such a good mother,
you made him cover it up.
Again.
Why would my son do that?
Because he loves you
as much as he hates you.
You can't prove any of this.
Just the incest,
which is a Class B felony.
It carries a penalty
of up to ten years.
That's ten years
away from Adam.
Good luck getting him
to testify.
Okay.
Well, jail or no jail,
I don't think she'll
last six months.
She'll die
without her son.
That would be better
for both of them.