WILLOWS:
What are you doing?
GRISSOM:
I'm going insane.
I don't understand
this diagram.
You don't need a diagram.
You need a woman.
I'm looking forward
to your speech.
( applause )
What A.D. Cavallo
will enjoy the most
is no longer having to lie about
how much work he has to do.
Enjoy your retirement, Bob.
But seriously, folks...
appointing the new
Assistant Director
for the Crime Lab is not a task
I take lightly.
I believe
in promoting
from within.
I believe
in rewarding
years of dedication
and devotion
to this Department.
I believe in Conrad Ecklie.
For a proper introduction,
I'd like to turn
to his good friend...
( pager ringing )
...Supervisor
Gil Grissom.
( applause )
Gil...
I got a 419.
Don't even think about it.
Swing's tapped out.
I'm the back-up.
Here...
you give my speech.
Good luck, Conrad.
( no audio )
Gil...
( whispering, murmuring )
What's going on?
( no audio )
MAN:
Hey, Griss...
What's with
the monkey suit?
I was at a funeral
across the street.
At a casino?
My condolences.
Scene's in
the east penthouse.
Gotta use
the VIP elevator.
Thanks.
( elevator bell dings )
Hey.
Hello.
What floor
did you want?
Where do you think
I'm going?
I wouldn't know.
You don't
recognize me.
Apparently not.
In the lab, I usually
wear my hair up.
Oh, yeah...
You're pulling in
when I'm pulling out.
Sofia Curtis.
CSI-Three, day shift.
You work for Ecklie.
As of tonight, so do you.
Hey, Gil... hey, Sofie.
Sorry to drag you away
from the Chicken Cordon Bleu.
It's the McKinley High
Homecoming.
The dance is downstairs,
but the cool kids' party
is in here.
CURTIS:
This place makes
the Rain Man suite at Caesar's
look like my condo.
These rooms are just
for whales and royalty.
What's up?
We're running down
the VIP host,
see who's got it tonight.
Okay,
paramedics pronounced,
left the scene undisturbed.
Name is Nicole Jensen, 17.
Coroner's en route.
I'm gonna talk
to the MTV generation.
Where's your kit?
I can send a uniform
to bring it up.
Teenager abuses drugs
and/or booze...
there's a news flash.
Contusions on her neck.
And the position suggests
she was grabbed from behind.
CURTIS:
"A night to remember."
A night to forget.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
Okay... so I talked
to the VIP host.
The room was checked out
to Charlie Macklin.
It's his casino.
Yeah, it's for his
daughter, Janelle.
She's having
an after party with
her and her friends.
Oh, off the streets
and out of trouble.
Best laid plans.
So what's
the daughter's story?
You know, I don't know.
We haven't seen her yet.
We're still looking.
( chuckling )
I can barely move in this dress
and we haven't cleared
the bathroom yet,
so there it is.
Don't worry,
I'm wearing underwear.
As far as you know.
( camera shutter snapping )
PHILLIPS:
Liver temp is 97.2.
She's been dead
less than two hours.
Banana peel...
G-string...
Scared of that.
Ligature marks
on both of her wrists.
Some kind of adhesive residue,
too.
( whimpering )
So, she was bound?
Marked impression
on her left cheek.
Maybe some sort
of circular device
pressed against her face?
( camera shutter clicking )
CURTIS:
No beer or liquor.
Just water,
yogurt, and OJ.
Mixers, not for drinks...
maybe for drugs.
Right pH in the stomach
speeds the buzz.
I think there's narco
around here somewhere.
A-A-Are you
talking to me?
No.
Do you always process like this?
Like what?
With your mouth.
Whenever I meet someone new,
I always say their name out loud
a few times.
Keeps a picture in my head.
Hm...
I thought that's why
we had cameras.
GIRL:
So, Nikki comes running in
and starts laughing
at the carpet.
You know, hurling,
blowing chunks, vomiting.
BRASS:
I got it, Miranda.
I get the picture.
I know what it means.
The others came in,
and, uh...
Someone tried CPR,
I guess.
Didn't work.
We called 911.
So, uh, you tight
with Nikki?
God, no.
Her dad was
a freelance limo driver.
I mean, you have to have
a felony to get that job.
( chuckling ):
How would you know that?
Everybody knows that.
The guy was an ex-kneebreaker
for the old mob.
You ever see Casino?
The movie?
Yeah, sure, yeah.
Whatever.
The guy Joe Pesci played.
Tony "The Ant" Spilotro.
Well, he and Nikki's dad
were friends.
Oh, yeah?
In real life.
Real lowlifes.
That girl was Kryptonite to me.
I'd be lying if I said
any different.
STOKES:
Kids have been going in and out
of the suite all night,
but the front desk
only issued card
keys to seven.
Brass has five
of them upstairs...
uh, Janelle Macklin
and Sean Paland
are unaccounted for,
so I'll check the casino.
I thought you were going
to process the scene
with Grissom.
I was. He said
he had it covered.
Sofia Curtis is up
there with him.
Right...
Ecklie's right hand.
Ever do a case with her?
Uh-uh.
Hey, I heard Grissom
stuck you with his speech.
A napkin is not a speech.
I'm going to need
to see everybody
who went in or out
of the east penthouse
since check-in,
and that includes stairwells
and service entrances.
You know,
that's Janelle Macklin's suite.
Yeah, I know.
Her father owns the casino.
Okay...
Dance is still
going strong.
That's the beauty of high school
in Las Vegas.
Homecoming
in a casino,
dance can go all night.
( hip-hop music playing )
I've been down here
dancing for hours.
Ask anybody.
Why don't you come
over here
and talk to me
for a second?
Come on, man!
What, you need to tell
your date?
I came stag.
Come here.
If I want a date,
I'll get one in there.
You know how many couples
break up at Homecoming?
I looked it up.
It's like ten percent.
Staggering.
Hm... you hang out with Nikki
a lot?
Please-- the girl's a scarf.
Always hanging on the neck
of anyone with loot.
Is that what was she doing
up in the P. Diddy suite
with your buddies?
Guess everybody wanted in
on that party.
And Nikki wasn't on the list.
Hey, wait, Janelle...
Janelle, wait!
Look, Nikki,
it's no big deal.
You're not
missing anything.
That's easy for you
to say.
C'mon, Janelle,
we're seniors.
This is my last
homecoming-- please!
Janelle's
always taking in strays.
Yeah, Janelle...
Do you know where Janelle
is now?
I have no idea.
You know, when
I busted outta there,
she was still up there chillin'
with the rest of them.
ROBBINS:
Standard SAE kit was collected.
Physical finding
of sexual activity.
Unable to determine
if consensual or rape.
Collected heart blood sample.
Preliminary tox indicates
psilocybin, MDMA,
and THC in the system.
Green-colored fiber
was collected
from the nasal passages...
to be forwarded
to Trace Evidence for analysis.
Vomitus mass was found
in the throat and lungs
and there was
petecchial hemorrhaging
of the lower eyelids.
Preliminary C.O.D. appears
to be mechanical asphyxia
from aspiration
of gastric content
as a result of acute
drug intoxication.
Albert Robbins, M.E.,
employee number 228369.
CURTIS:
Collected seven
used condoms
from two bedrooms--
not a record
in my book.
Fact that the victim's
wrists were bound
suggests possible
sex games.
Also pulled a plastic
Baggie from a toilet
containing what looks
like ground-up mushrooms,
probably not the kind
you put on pizza.
Could be the source
of the psilocybin.
One of those kids
is still holding.
I'm gonna
let Brass know.
That time I was
talking to you.
What?
Sorry.
I was, uh, treating it
like white noise.
What are you seeing?
Chicken Cordon Bleu.
Okay, there's no evidence
of that meal anywhere here,
and Ecklie
always said you
had an odd sense of humor,
so that would make this
a joke.
Not really.
If you're on your feet
when you're throwing up,
the vomit goes everywhere.
The higher you are,
the wider the splash, right?
But...
this vomit is confined
to one specific area.
So she was probably
lying down
when she was throwing up.
Maybe unconscious.
Or already dead.
Vomit could've been forced out
by CPR compressions.
But that doesn't explain
the bruise on her cheek.
Or the green fibers in her nose.
Well...
may have started here.
( shouting )
Stop it! Stop it!
( shouting continues )
Come on, you're
all done-- let's go.
What do you mean?
We know you're
dealing drugs.
Nikki Jensen's dead
because of you.
No, okay, wait, okay,
I don't even do... I
don't even drink, okay?
You don't... you don't want
me, you... you want Rex.
Hey, Rex.
Look, my name is Gavin.
You got my license, check it.
No, no, it's "Rex,"
you know, as in RX.
I guess it's a lot more subtle
than "drugstore," right?
I got nothing to do
with drugs, my man.
You already searched me.
Is there anywhere else
you care to look?
Hey, you better save
that position for
later, brother.
You're gonna need it,
where you're going.
Is this our dealer?
Oh, yeah.
Get this straight, okay?
I'm not a drug dealer.
My dad owns seven restaurants,
including one at the Bellagio
and the gourmet room downstairs.
I don't need drug money.
Well, maybe you just like
getting your friends high.
There's a song about that,
I think.
Hold out your hand.
Duct tape residue.
What do you know?
You know, if the water
is relatively still,
submerged prints
can remain for weeks, months,
sometimes even years.
Thank you.
When we match your prints
on this bag,
you'll be charged with murder.
I didn't give Nikki anything.
The 'shrooms were for the room.
She was diving in there
with both hands, and...
Did you have sex with her?
So what if I did?
She was... giving it away.
You tied her up and forced her
down on the couch.
That wasn't me.
( phone ringing )
Grissom.
WILLOWS:
I just found Janelle Macklin.
Good. We need to talk to her
right away.
That's going to be tough.
( indistinct conversation )
Everybody hit the floor!
Now! Now!
They had duct tape.
They tied everyone up,
and they dragged Janelle out.
So how did Nikki
end up dead?
Um...
eventually, we all...
got ourselves free.
Everybody was scared,
but Nikki was possessed.
She was wasted.
Freaking out.
No! I'm leaving!
Shut up!
Shut her up!
BOY:
Friggin' 'shrooms!
Chill, will ya?!
( grunting)
( screaming )
We weren't trying
to hurt her.
Well, that's for the DA
to decide.
Why try to hide the kidnapping?
MAN:
I told the kids
not to report it.
And I told 'em
not to leave the room.
They were smart enough
to listen.
Janelle's fine.
It's a game.
ATWATER:
You know, Mr. Macklin, based on
the surveillance videotape...
I've seen it.
Your daughter looked terrified.
She does school plays.
Says she wants to be an actor.
At least that's the story
this month.
So you think
this is all an act?
Daddy's little girl
begging for attention.
Right on the button.
Let me tell you
about Janelle:
I sent her to a nice prep school
back east,
she flunked out
on purpose.
I gave her a Bentley
for her sweet 16,
she wraps it around a tree.
I've been putting up
with this crap since
she was a kid.
I'm done.
When was the last time
you actually talked
to your daughter?
Yesterday, when she asked me
to comp the suite.
You want me to call her, fine.
She never goes anywhere
without her cell phone.
( ringing tone )
DIGITIZED VOICE:
We have Janelle.
Wire one million U.S. dollars
to Grand Caymans National Bank,
account number 489-27-63.
If the money is not deposited
within 24 hours, she dies.
I take it that's not
her usual greeting.
If this is a game,
why ask for money?
She obviously doesn't need it.
I pay, she wins.
You want to know
why the "abductors"
want the money wired
to the Caymans?
Smart move.
Most kidnappers do get busted
at the drop.
That's where Janelle
has her trust is set up.
She knows how those banks work.
When Steve Wynn's daughter
was kidnapped,
he didn't tell the police.
He went to the Mirage
casino floor,
he got 1.4 million in
cash, he made the drop...
Got his daughter back
in a couple hours.
Yeah, I know the story.
Steve Wynn's daughter
was a real victim.
Janelle isn't.
Game or not, Mr. Macklin,
one girl is dead
your daughter is missing.
We're compelled
to investigate here.
You do that.
And when Janelle turns up,
crying,
saying how sorry she is,
you make sure
she answers for it.
Mr. Jensen, your daughter's
personal effects
are at the front desk.
Least you got your money's worth
out of the rental.
I just wanted to let you know,
no hard feelings about
you leaving the banquet.
You're just...
doing your job.
Have you decided yet
who's going to be
the day shift supervisor?
Well, Sofia's
a logical choice,
but nothing's
official yet.
You should consider Catherine.
She's earned it.
I'll, uh, I'll give it
some thought.
Oh, you know...
I'd love to get
a copy of your speech.
Just a little souvenir
for my scrapbook.
I'll get you a copy.
That'd be great.
WILLOWS:
Tell me something.
SANDERS:
I think my eyes need Band-Aids.
WILLOWS:
Tough shift.
You did say
"shift," right?
SANDERS:
I reviewed roughly eight hours
of video surveillance
you so generously provided.
Janelle Macklin
and several friends
rode the VIP elevator
to the penthouse
around 8:00 p.m.
The only other time Janelle
set foot in the elevator...
she was a ransom note.
Well, we know they didn't take
the VIP elevator down...
And, based on the video,
they didn't use the stairs
or the service elevator,
either.
Maybe's she's still
in the suite.
It's a big room.
Man, there must
be over a hundred
shoeprints in here.
WILLOWS:
Even more fingerprints
on those buttons.
Good luck.
Thanks a lot.
How's it going?
Great.
Got all the towels
we need here.
Yeah...
I might stick a few of those
in my trunk.
The same costumes
as the kidnappers.
These guys definitely knew
their way around this hotel.
Yeah.
Hey, Catherine...
...got everything we need
for Halloween except the candy.
The abductors exposed their
faces to Janelle Macklin.
That's one of two things--
either she knew them,
or they were going to whack her.
BRISTOL:
Look, I don't know why
you had to drag me down here
on my day off.
What's this, Kenny?
I don't know.
Sure you do.
A digital video
time-delay.
TiVo-ing the casino.
Now that's ballsy.
You time-shifted the signal
from the west penthouse
service elevator
and you fed it
to the east monitor.
You were in on it.
Janelle asked me
to do her a favor.
I really like her.
You know, I practically
watched her grow up,
I mean, through the...
cameras.
( sniffling )
I'm so fired.
I screwed with
Charlie Macklin.
I'm probably dead.
Where is she?
I don't know.
She said she wanted to sneak
some guys up to her suite
that Mr. Macklin
wouldn't like.
What was I supposed to do?
I mean,
she's the boss' daughter.
She's also
a person of interest
in the death of Nicole Jensen.
If you know anything...
I'm telling you,
I don't know where she is.
GRISSOM:
Definitely not synthetic.
Medulla is 14 microns
in diameter.
Continuous cortex.
Imbricate scales.
I'm thinking sheep.
Merino.
Fine wool for
fine fabrics.
Why are you talking
to yourself?
I'm trying a new technique.
Is it working?
I have no idea.
Aniline dye.
Most likely BASF or Dupont.
Probably used by every high-end
garment maker in the world.
And black wool is definitely
not used for party dresses.
So it's got to be from those
tuxedo boys in the suite.
You'll have to take
their clothes.
BRASS:
Thread's from your tux, kid.
Nothing's going
to change that.
So the DA's offered you immunity
in Nicole Jensen's death
for your full cooperation
in the kidnapping
of Janelle Macklin.
Let's hear it.
All right, straight up.
Janelle hired
an eye-in-the-sky geek
to knock out the cameras
in the service area.
We swooped in, scooped her out,
and bam, I mean,
we were over it.
So she paid you to kidnap her?
No. I wouldn't take a penny
from Janelle.
We've been friends
since grade school.
Oh, so you did it out of the
goodness of your own heart.
Look, my parents have dealt
cards for 20 years, all right?
I didn't grow up with squat.
Janelle, she didn't care
about that.
She still
kicked it with me.
So when she asked for my help,
I helped.
Even if it involved
several felonies?
I wasn't even
thinking about that.
You don't even get it.
You don't understand
what it's like
to be born
and raised here.
I mean, Vegas was a dirt lot
until the '60s.
I mean, it's lucky
that I'm not a drug dealer,
and Mr. Mack should be happy
Janelle's not a junkie stripper.
I mean,
he was never there for her
like my parents
were there for me.
They instilled good
values in my head.
Like kidnapping?
Who's your partner?
Look, counselor, you better
educate your client
on the meaning
of full cooperation.
Uh-uh, nah. Vegas has
got too many rats,
and I'm not gonna
be one of them.
You want to know where
Janelle is, I'll tell you.
But you're not going
to believe me.
Try me.
( loud knocking )
( cartoon music plays
on TV )
Don't, don't...
Do it! Do it!
No, son! No!
Why did you volunteer
to take a polygraph test?
I want to clear my name.
What crime have you
been accused of?
Kidnapping Janelle Macklin.
( screaming )
Did you physically assault
Janelle Macklin?
No way.
Did your partner assault
Janelle Macklin?
No.
I don't know.
Did you kill Janelle Macklin?
No.
Do you know where she is now?
It was just a prank.
WILLOWS:
"Not deceptive."
So, Dean Tate was
telling the truth.
Well, according
to the polygraph, yeah.
Hey, guys, I got
a work card hit off
of that maple syrup print.
Let me guess.
Mrs. Butterworth?
What are you accusing me
of, eating French toast?
What, eating carbs
is against the law now?
No, but kidnapping is.
I don't know anything
about that.
My prints are in that room
because it was Deano's room.
He got it so we'd have a place
to bring the ladies
after the dance.
So you're telling me when I take
a sample of your DNA
and compare it
to the kabuki masks here...
that's not going to be you?
Deano rat me?
No. No, the evidence did that.
Look, we were playing around.
I bus tables every day
after school, all right?
A grand's a lot of dough for me.
You know,
this was a joke.
You see us laughing?
Where's Janelle?
I don't know.
When's the last time
you saw her?
After the kidnapping.
Janelle planted one on my lips.
You know, to thank me.
I felt it was
more than that.
You know, I felt a vibe.
I gave her an hour to chill,
then I called her.
Asked her if I could
bring her anything.
She said she was kind of hungry,
so I told her I'd bring her
something sweet to eat,
other than me.
For a couple seconds,
I thought I was in.
Then she got a voice mail...
checked it and flipped out.
( glass shattering )
I figured that was
my cue to bolt,
so I rolled back down
to the dance
to continue with the honeys
I was already working.
I haven't seen Janelle since.
I swear to God.
WILLOWS:
Well, there he is,
stepping onto
the main elevator
from the 15th floor.
Alone.
( Willows snickering )
You crack this kid's head open,
all that would come out
would be T and A.
I think you said that
about me once.
Actually, more than once.
What's the time code?
2:04 a.m.
That's right after
Janelle Macklin's last call
to her voice mail.
Just like he said.
Let me access the message.
So when are you going to be
doing your final proficiency?
Every time I ask Grissom,
he says, "next time out."
And then I end up here.
Okay, here it is.
MACKLIN:
I'm really disappointed
with you, Janelle.
All these years you spent
around me at the casino
and you think you can put
something like this over on me?
The only thing I'm giving
you tonight
are four little words:
Get... your...
ass... home.
And since the
surveillance feed
was still being time-
shifted at that point,
my guess is that
Janelle took the
service elevator out.
So... where does
that leave us?
I think we're done.
WILLOWS:
No actual crime
was committed.
The kidnapping wasn't real.
Nicole Jensen's death
was plenty real.
Janelle Macklin's
ultimately responsible
for putting into motion
the events that led
to Nicole's death.
Well, the broadcast's out
on Janelle and her car.
When she turns up,
she'll have to answer for it.
Well, that's...
...highly unsatisfying.
You forgot this at the suite.
I fixed it for you.
You never know when
you might need to get
dressed up again.
She glued it.
( phone ringing )
Just keep in mind,
Gil, that she is
on Ecklie's team.
State trooper
reported the car.
Who wants to tell
Mr. Macklin?
( Janelle screaming )
( camera shutter clicks )
( muffled crying, yelling )
♪ ♪
MACKLIN:
Janelle left a message
a couple hours ago.
She...
she was all worked up,
she was crying,
saying how someone threw her
in the trunk of her car.
And then the call cuts off.
I thought it was
just more drama.
This time didn't seem
any different from
all the others.
What kind of kidnapper...
lets you keep
your cell phone?
You should let us
answer that question.
Where did you find her, Captain?
Sunset Road.
Near McCarran.
Janelle loved airplanes
when she was a kid.
She was always...
begging me to go...
see them take off and land.
I took her down there.
A couple of times, I think.
Her mother is in Paris.
That's, uh...
what... nine hours ahead.
Kind of late to call right now.
Oh, my God, Charlie.
They told me
about Janelle.
I'm so sorry, honey.
Captain Brass, my wife.
How do you do?
I want you to find
whoever did this.
That's what we're trying to do.
Now what?
Mr. Jensen,
we need to ask you
a couple of questions
regarding Janelle Macklin.
Hm. And I thought
you were gonna tell me
you were gonna charge somebody
with my daughter's death.
Drink?
Step out of the car, sir.
Not a peep about my daughter,
but page one
on Macklin's rich bitch.
Oh, you boys sure move quicker
when there's cash behind it.
Can you account
for your whereabouts
in the last six hours?
Why don't you kiss my ass.
Look, we have a witness
who saw Janelle Macklin
get into a town car
near the Hard Rock
earlier this evening.
That's why we impounded
your vehicle.
Found Janelle's bracelet
in your car.
What do you think
something like
this is worth?
Hundred G's
at least. Huh?
Enough maybe to help
ease the pain?
For you, maybe.
I got a call for a pickup.
I went.
Trying to keep my head
in the work,
'cause what else do I have left?
Mr. Jensen,
you've got to believe me,
I never meant for anything
to happen to Nikki.
You get out of this car.
( voice trembling ):
I-I can pay...
whatever you need
until the day I die.
You wanna pay!?
I told her
I was gonna put two bullets
in her head
and dump her
on her daddy's front step.
But then what, you decided
maybe it'd be more fun
to tie her up,
let her choke to death
in the trunk of her own car?
No.
I told her
what I felt like doing
so her father would know
the way I feel.
And she got out, and she ran,
and it's a good thing she ran,
because I might've changed
my mind.
Maybe you did.
( mutters )
I'm not that guy anymore.
You sure about that?
It really doesn't make any
difference what you do to me.
( sighs )
My baby's dead.
ROBBINS:
C.O.D. was asphyxia.
Scarf lodged all the way
down the esophagus,
obstructing the epiglottis.
Completely cut off her air.
And the tox came back positive
for benzodiazepines.
Yeah, that makes sense.
They suppress the gag reflex.
And knock you out
at the same time.
Girl probably didn't
even realize she was
suffocating.
Would've been something
like falling asleep.
All right, so...
based on the time
that she called her father
and the time
we found the car,
she was in the trunk
at least three hours.
That's a slow way to go.
I just got off the
phone with Brass.
WILLOWS:
Let me guess:
Jensen lawyered up?
No. He says he didn't do it.
And based off the DNA
report, I believe him.
Mia found saliva and epithelials
on the gag and ligature.
We ran them against
all known suspects.
Everything matches
Janelle Macklin.
♪ ♪
Daddy, I'm...
I'm in really big trouble.
Um, some guys threw me
in the trunk of my car.
( trunk closes )
WILLOWS:
The position of the knot
was the key.
The only way that it could've
ended up in that position
was if she had tied it herself.
And her saliva on the ends
of the scarf confirmed it.
You saying
she committed suicide?
( sighs )
I guess I am.
Although I don't think
that was her intention.
I think that she was...
hoping that her father
would save her in time.
JANELLE (over phone):
Daddy, I'm in really
big trouble.
Um, some guys threw me
in the trunk of my car.
You've got to believe me.
I-I can hear airplanes.
Um, I-I must be
near the airport.
I know you'll find me.
Please hurry.