( soft moaning )
Freshman dorm, coed.
Two DB's on the third floor--
Trip Wilmont
and Paula Levine. Both 18.
SANDERS:
Hey, Grissom,
when you went to college
did you live in the dorms?
Surely, you jest.
You know,
they say a BA
is worth
a million dollars
in extra income
over a lifetime.
Yeah, but the present cost
of college tuition
is about the same amount.
SANDERS:
So you're
saying college
isn't worth
the expense?
I guess it depends
on what you learn.
BRASS:
So this is Trip's dorm room.
When he missed a big B-ball game
this afternoon,
his coach called his R.A.
His R.A. got the kid next door
to jimmy the lock.
Paramedics pronounced
and took off.
The coroner's
en route.
SIDLE:
Music, alcohol, candles.
Kid was a regular Romeo.
"For never was a story
"of more woe than this of Juliet
and her Romeo"
Condom wrapper.
So much for safe sex.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
PHILLIPS:
Sara, do me a favor
and open the window,
please.
Sure.
You feeling
okay, David?
Yeah.
Take a look at the skin
coloration on both victims.
Their bodies
are slightly pink.
And you're thinking "pink" skin
tones are a common effect
of carbon monoxide fumes.
That vomit's
also consistent
with exposure to C.O.
We'll need a sample
of that vomit.
( cell phone rings )
Grissom.
Okay, I'll
be right there.
My testimony's up
in the Hoyt case.
I gotta go.
I see no common source
for C.O.,
so you'll have
to use the detector.
You're running point.
I knew something
was wrong.
Trip lived
for basketball,
and it was the semis,
so there's no way
he'd miss a game.
Yeah, I saw Susan
banging on his door,
so I used my pocketknife
to jam it open.
Had you done that before?
Yeah. All the time.
Whenever Trip would get drunk
and lock himself out,
he would bang
on my door.
So you and Trip were friends?
Me and Trip?
Mm-hmm.
No. I'm not really
the type of guy
that Trip Wilmont
would hang out with.
So I guess that's a no?
Yeah. But we had
Spanish 102 together.
Sometimes he'd roll
over to my dorm,
and I'd help him
with his homework.
Did you help him,
or did you do it for him?
Look, it's not the
Spanish Inquisition.
For a jock, it could
have been a lot worse but,
no, we weren't friends.
Okay.
( beep )
No trace of carbon monoxide.
There's a trace of semen
on the door handle.
( beep )
This one, too.
Trophy condoms.
Trophy condoms?
When a stud scores,
he announces his victory
by putting his spoils
on his neighbor's doorknob.
Oh. Well, my bet
is Trip scored a lot.
( explosion )
Everyone okay?
Excuse me.
Spontaneous
toilet combustion?
Or a college prank.
You think this has anything
to do with the case?
20 feet away
from two dead kids.
We got
to check it out.
Guess you should, uh...
start processing.
Conrad.
Hey, Detective.
Homicide called you guys
over an hour ago.
419 at the Tangiers.
No one's responded.
Not even the coroner.
Have you tried Grissom
or Catherine?
Catherine's on a case,
I think. Grissom...
Oh, that's right.
Grissom's in court.
Oh. And Sofia's still
on her Task Force leave.
Both shifts are tapped.
Did you check...?
I checked the board.
No one's available...
except for you.
I'm the Assistant
Lab Director.
I know. But you're
still qualified
to process
a scene, right?
Yes, I am.
I'll dust off my kit.
Meet you there.
Hey, Doc.
Two dead bodies.
Both were in perfect health.
I am so hoping
that you have
more in your
report than that.
There are two toxins which can
turn a body pink postmortem.
We already ruled
out carbon monoxide.
Which leaves one--
cyanide ingestion.
Interesting fact
about cyanide--
not everyone can smell it.
Right. It's a genetic quirk.
Unfortunately,
I don't have that ability.
"The Nose" has arrived.
Hodges has
the genetic quirk?
It's a blessing
and a curse.
Stomach contents
of both decedents.
Hodges, start
your sniffer.
Hints of stale beer and...
Cheese Whiz.
But I don't smell any cyanide.
Thank you.
Anytime.
Well, all due respect
to "The Nose,"
I would still like to send
a sample of blood to Tox.
It's already done.
Is there anything else?
Nothing on or in the body
indicates cause of death.
Nothing consistent
with homicide whatsoever.
Two college kids die under
mysterious circumstances.
Let's treat this as a homicide
till we know otherwise.
Finally.
Yeah, well three hours.
All right. Thanks.
Crime scene's getting cold.
Had to refill
my powders.
I found a rental
car agreement in
the glove box.
James Billmeyer.
New Jersey.
He's not registered
at the hotel.
Probably stopped by
to lose a few bucks.
Did the coroner
step in the blood?
No. We're still
waiting on him.
That shoe print belongs
to Mrs. Vivoldi.
She called it in.
We been waiting on you
to take her statement.
Let's do it.
Yes, let's do it.
Thanks.
Ma'am, sorry to
keep you waiting.
I'm Detective Vartann.
This is Conrad Ecklie
from the crime lab.
Do you mind if we
ask you a few questions?
I'd mind if you didn't.
I am the one
who found the body.
Yes. At the time,
were you walking
to or from the hotel?
I'd had just finished
lunch with the girls.
We say "girls,"
but we're, you know, women.
I don't find being
called a "girl" derogatory.
That's good. To or from?
I was walking to the car.
The SUV?
A gift from Oscar.
30 years with the same man.
Congratulations.
Thank you. Are you married?
Divorced.
Oh. And you?
Uh... ma'am, so you were
walking to your car...
Walking to the car,
and I think I stepped
into gum or something...
( screams )
That's when I called
911.
Which was about, um...
two hours ago.
I'm sorry, ma'am.
We've been very busy.
I'm going to need
your shoes.
We'll get them
back to you.
Even wash off the blood.
WOMAN:
I just talked to Paula
yesterday afternoon.
She was on her way
to the library.
She had a biology final
this morning.
She shouldn't have
been in a boy's room.
None of this makes any sense.
Trip was a serious athlete.
He would never sleep around
the night before...
Sleep around?
It's not like your daughter
was Trip's girlfriend.
Ms. Sidle...
I need to know.
Did Trip take advantage...?
Did he force himself
on Paula?
My son would never
force himself on anyone.
Trip could have
any girl he wanted.
Mrs. Levine, the coroner
found no evidence of assault.
Did Paula ever
mention Trip to you?
No.
I know she liked a boy
on the basketball team.
I never
knew his name.
I guess it was Trip.
I just want to know
what happened to them.
So do I.
( garbled radio transmissions)
This land used
to be part of
the Bennett estate.
Bill Bennett?
Guy who owns
the Sahara?
Yeah.
Huh.
We used to come
out here
when we were
in high school.
Used to be, like,
a seven-acre lover's lane.
I thought you said
you were a dork
in high school.
I was a dork
I'm still
a dork,
but I had dimples.
I got a little action.
I don't doubt that.
Hey, Dave.
Oh, hello.
The path to the body
was made by the paramedics.
They pronounced
and took off.
ID'ed has Kevin Staniland,
age 30 from Reno.
I figured before
I processed the body,
you'd want to photograph
the crop circle.
Crop circle?
PHILLIPS:
Well, it's a circle
in the middle of a field.
What would
you call it?
I guess it's
a crop circle.
The guy has a blindfold on.
WILLOWS:
Pin the tail on the donkey
gone wrong?
Lividity is fixed.
Lividity's fixed?
So this wasn't
a body dump?
He died there?
The only pathway
is from the paramedics.
How'd he end up
in the middle of the circle?
I have an idea.
I'll keep it to myself.
Hey.
How's it going?
I swabbed every square inch
of this toilet.
So far, no evidence
of explosive powders
or a detonation device.
Well, I spoke
with maintenance.
It is an isolated incident.
There are no other
reports of exploding johns.
How about
methane gas?
Maybe there's a natural reserve
under the dorm.
Theoretically, pressure
could have built up,
broken a sewer pipe
and shot up through the toilet.
Yeah.
I already checked.
There's no methane gas
in this region of Clare County.
Well, there's got to be
some logical explanation.
Well, if dorm food
is as bad as I can remember,
we should consider
explosive diarrhea.
Crop circles?
( laughs )
Come on, Super Dave.
Wasn't the Alien Autopsy
embarrassing enough?
Given the circumstances,
alien was not an unreasonable
conclusion at the time.
You need to get
a girlfriend.
I'm engaged,
but thank you.
Could you just check out
his pants?
There's grass stains
on his knees.
That's odd, because
the grass around the victim
was undisturbed.
His tighty whiteys
were soaked in urine.
Don't know if it's
pre- or postmortem.
Oh!
Now, that's alien.
What is that?
I've got to document this.
Oh, hang on.
We have ourselves a tapeworm,
gentlemen.
This guy's been eating
meat or fish
infected with tapeworm cyst.
WARRICK:
Yeah, that cyst grows up
to be nice fat tapeworm
that attaches itself
to the intestinal wall
and suck out
all your nutrients.
Yeah, and since this guy's
already dead,
the tapeworm
needs to find
a new host.
Only two ways out.
I'm glad it picked the mouth.
( all chuckle )
Well, the tapeworm
could have made the guy sick,
but it didn't kill him.
Hello.
Hey.
Want to talk
about semen?
Okay.
Okey-doke.
The semen
on the vic's
doorknob
and the neighbor's
is consistent
with Trip's DNA.
So, what I'm thinking
is that Trip
put a trophy condom
onto his neighbor's door
and then transferred
a trace
of his reproductive
material
back onto
his own doorknob.
( chuckling )
You've, uh, you've heard
of trophy condoms?
Sara, I went to college.
Ladies, I just spoke
with Western LVU's
Student Affairs Officer.
Apparently, Trip's next-door
neighbor, Zack Capola
filed several grievances
against him.
I'm headed
over there now.
I'll drive.
You always do.
So, crop circles and tapeworms,
you got quite a case.
Mm.
You have C.O.D.?
I have T.O.D.,
about midday yesterday.
Cause of death
is less definitive.
Cuts and abrasions
are superficial.
There's no obvious
anatomical defect.
And at this point, I'm going
to have to check the default--
cardiac arrhythmia.
A young man's heart stops,
and you don't know why?
Tox and vitreous lytes
are all normal.
That's all you're
getting from me.
BOY:
This is bunk.
I was told my grievances
were confidential.
They said my name
wasn't even on the form.
Why was confidentiality
so important?
Ask him.
You look like you were
a jock in college.
Me?
Him?
Whatever.
Look, if it had gotten around
that I had ratted out Trip,
the whole basketball team
would have come down on me.
You are a straight-A student.
We've reviewed
your academic records.
The distractions
must've
pissed you off.
You had problems
with his loud music,
banging on the wall,
used condoms hanging
on your doorknob.
A handful of used condoms
would have pissed you off, too.
Look, what are you getting at?
We're trying
to figure out
what happened
to Trip and Paula.
Earlier you said
he wasn't
such a bad guy.
Because I didn't see a need
to badmouth the dead.
But you want the truth,
he was an ass, okay?
Well, Conrad,
can I help you?
Where have you been?
I posted three bodies
and then I took a time-out.
A time-out?
A personal hour.
A few weeks ago,
my Siamese had kittens.
I went by the house
to check on 'em.
They're just about weaned.
You want one?
I'm allergic.
So tell me
about James Billmeyer.
Guy found at the Tangiers.
I'm just about
to post him.
Per my prelim, there was
an abraded laceration
to the right occipital scalp,
and a penetration
of the epithelium,
but not the galea.
It's not what killed him,
but I'll know the full story
once I open him up.
I saw David
put him in here.
So where is he?
I'm not sure.
Maybe he's taking
a time-out.
David probably moved him.
He had no reason to.
A few years back,
a body was
prematurely sent
to a mortician.
Remember that?
This is weird.
Maybe someone
in your department
mislabeled the corpse?
It's highly unlikely.
Fine. When you find him,
get back to me.
Sir?
We have a situation.
I know.
A body disappeared.
No, no.
Mr. Billmeyer didn't disappear.
He's missing.
There's a difference.
Sir, this isn't my fault.
You prepped him for autopsy,
right?
Yes, sir.
Walk me through that.
Walk you through what?
Everything you did
to Mr. Billmeyer.
Okay, um, I brought him
into the washroom,
photographed the body,
took hair
and fingernail cuttings,
emptied his pockets,
removed clothing,
washed his body, tagged him.
I put him into the cooler
and I haven't seen him since.
What?
I was just thinking, David.
I've lost my keys,
sunglasses,
even a wallet.
Sir, this really isn't my fault.
But I've never lost a body.
I didn't do anything.
Find him,
Phillips,
or this goes on your record.
What would you like me to do?
Get out! Get out.
Out!
I don...
( sighs )
Six-one, brown hair and eyes,
about 200 pounds.
Are you sure?
All right, thanks.
I've checked every mortuary
and funeral home in the city,
no luck.
Right, 'cause you never
authorized a transfer.
David, are you familiar
with the Latin word
necrostuprum?
Body snatcher?
We didn't mislabel
or misplace the body.
Someone took it.
If you wanted to steal a body,
wouldn't it be a lot easier
to go to a hospital
or university facility?
Absolutely,
which means somebody wanted
this particular body.
Some of the leading theories
on crop circles
include extraterrestrials,
wind vortexes, Earth energies,
and of course,
hoaxes.
But in 1985,
farmers near one
U.S. military base
suspected the source
of a recent incident
to be the downwash
from a helicopter's
rotor blades.
The spinning of the blades
caused the chopper to rise
forced the air downward,
in effect, bending
the grass below.
For every action,
there is an opposite
but equal reaction.
Since I'm a skeptic
when it comes to aliens
and Earth energies, ooh.
So we started
with the chopper.
Hey, Archie.
Oh, hey.
Nellis sent over
the radar surveillance.
Current feed goes back 48 hours.
This is where your decedent
was located.
Decedent's T.O.D. was
approximately 12:00 noon,
yesterday.
Using echo and Doppler shift we
can determine an object's speed.
( computer beeping )
Freeze the frame, Archie.
Found your chopper.
It's holding steady.
Airplanes can't do that.
Let's see who owns it.
( phone rings )
Hey, I got your 911.
Don't you work days?
Ecklie keeps moving me around.
Your pink college kids
were both blotto.
Yeah, there were beer bottles
at the scene.
That's not a surprise.
You want a surprise?
Check this out.
Now, I know you and Greg tested
the scene for carbon monoxide,
but did you check
for carbon dioxide?
No.
I've been a CSI
eight years.
I have never processed
a C02 scene.
I mean, you'd need
a ton of that gas
to cause serious damage.
It's a first
for me, too.
I found traces of blood
in Trip's vomit.
C02 levels are usually .03%.
His levels were 8%.
Lethal.
C02 replaces oxygen
on hemoglobin molecules.
At 8%, those kids
would've literally
suffocated
on a cellular level.
Still doesn't explain why
they were pretty in pink.
Carbon dioxide,
unlike carbon monoxide,
doesn't affect
skin coloration.
So what did?
What are we expecting
to find here?
Someone went to
a lot of trouble
to steal
James Billmeyer...
Maybe there's a clue
in his personal effects.
So you're a CSI now?
If I were, I would have
printed the cooler.
Really?
Maybe you should
just put together a list
of everyone who had access
to the morgue.
Law enforcement
personnel, CSIs,
paramedics,
funeral home personnel,
maintenance workers,
hospital workers,
janitors...
people that get lost
in the building...
Yeah, that sounds good.
Two pairs of socks,
two pairs of underwear,
two T-shirts.
That tells me the guy
was going to be staying
in Vegas for two days.
Your powers of deduction
are remarkable, Detective.
Thank you.
"Jacinda Hendler,
call me."
Written on an
airline napkin.
Decedent probably met her
on the flight,
possibly hours before he died.
You think?
I'll run it down.
WOMAN:
Yeah, I know Jamie.
He's a sweet man.
He was supposed to call me.
What happened to him?
He died.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Why'd you contact me?
Well, your name
was in his pocket.
Napkin.
We, uh, we met
on the plane.
( laughs )
And, uh, there was only
one blanket, so we...
shared it, and I got
a little frisky,
and...
Anyway, there was a kid
sitting two seats away, so...
So you gave him your number...
...to meet up later?
Yeah.
Do you have any idea
who may've killed him?
Or who might want
his body
in its current condition?
No.
Jamie told me that
he-he was flying in to party
with some pals from high school
in Seven Hills.
Said he'd
invite me over.
Figured he blew me off.
It-it happens.
I mean...
I have a healthy self-esteem.
Good for you.
Yes.
Thanks.
( sighs )
What exactly are
we looking for?
Most sources of carbon dioxide
come from...
factories, cars and volcanoes,
not something we're gonna find
in a dorm room.
Maybe somebody pumped
the gas in through a vent.
Uh, sex journal.
Lists of girls...
dates...
and sexual activities.
Boys and their conquests.
I've never even heard
of some of these.
Really?
Never mind.
Would you help me move
the bed, please?
There's a fresh hole
in the wall.
Splinters are
on the inside.
Someone drilled in
from the other side.
( knock on door )
Hey.
Hi, Zack.
Mind if we come in?
Why?
SANDERS:
Ah, you're a car buff, huh?
I guess.
Yeah, me, too.
I always wanted
a Testarossa.
What about you,
what's your dream car?
ZACK:
Uh, I don't know.
Zack, can you explain
this hole in your wall?
I didn't even know
there was one.
( sighs )
SIDLE:
I think maybe
we should step outside.
Your room is now
a crime scene.
Are you Morgan Wendel?
Yeah.
We're from
the Crime Lab.
We have information
that put your chopper
at a crime scene
yesterday, around noon.
You're here about Kevin.
That's right, yeah.
I'll tell you everything,
but I want immunity.
MAN:
All right, Kevin!
Yeah! Whoo!
I want you
to prepare
to jump!
Without a parachute?
That's my stunt?!
No way!
Dude,
the name of the show is
"Going All the Way."
You signed a contract.
Now, do it!
Jumping out of chopper's
not going all the way--
it's suicide!
Listen, man,
you don't have a choice, Kevin.
You already ate raw meat,
you stuck your face
in a beehive.
You don't go all the way,
you don't get nothing!
Come on, Kevin!
No!
( laughs )
What are
you doing?!
Wait a minute,
wait a minute.
Dude, dude, check this out,
get a shot of this.
Get his crotch.
Come here.
( grunting )
Our first contestant
peed his pants.
Re-a-li-ty!
Come on, let go!
You can't fake this.
Now, Kevin...
Go, baby!
( yells )
( man laughing )
Keep going, keep going.
But here's the thing.
We're only four feet up.
Joke's on him.
Let's check it out.
Kevin! Kevin!
He's not moving.
Turn off the camera.
Turn off the camera! Turn...
Kevin thought that
he was being pushed
out of a helicopter
a thousand feet
in the air, but...
See you later, Kevin!
( yells )
Hey, Kevin?
He's not moving.
Come on, let's get out of here!
Did you have a warrant
for that tape?
WILLOWS:
The pilot gave us the name
of the cameraman, who supplied
the tape voluntarily.
Look, I assured Kevin
all our stunts were safe.
And they were.
Besides, he signed a waiver;
I'm not guilty of anything.
When you saw that
he wasn't moving,
you just took off.
That sounds like
guilt to me.
STOKES:
You scared him
to death.
He had a heart attack.
So the signing of a waiver
doesn't make it
any less criminal.
WILLOWS:
When the jury
sees that tape,
you'll be going all the way...
to jail.
Second-degree murder.
25 to life.
I hope this is a fire drill.
Conrad.
We found our body.
Looks more like
he found us.
Doc, I want you to
process the body ASAP.
Yeah, Conrad,
I'll get right on it.
Ah, yes-- the guy we
left on the bench.
Right.
Hello, Conrad.
I thought
you were in court.
We had
a one-hour recess--
I'm on my way back now.
And this must be Mr. Billmeyer.
I'm so glad he's back.
Very funny.
You might want to have
Hodges analyze that cigar.
Oh, and the print tech is free.
He could, uh,
spray the party hat
with ninhydrin.
I think I remember how to do
my job, Gil, thank you.
I love it when you
wear your gloves.
I swear, I don't know
how that hole got there.
And if you think
that I had
anything to do with
Trip's death, you're wrong.
I was in L.A.
for four days.
I had just gotten
back, and I saw Susan
banging on his door.
Trip, are you in there?
Open up.
If you can hear me,
open the door. Please?
Hey, are you all right?
Yeah, Trip missed a game.
I thought something's wrong.
Trip?
Hey, man, we're coming in.
Can anyone verify
that you were in L.A.?
The whole dorm can verify it.
I was visiting my boyfriend.
It was his birthday.
We went to the auto show.
Does anyone else
have access to your room?
No, I've got the only key,
but like I said,
it's easy enough
to break in.
SIDLE:
What happened to your finger?
I'm not sure.
I had just gotten
back from my trip,
and I saw something
on the floor,
so I picked it up.
It kind of burned me
or something.
And that
didn't seem weird to you?
I'm in college.
A lot of things
seem weird to me.
Okay.
This thing...
that burned your finger,
where is it now?
I tossed it.
Excuse me.
I don't see anything
but a couple pieces
of balled up paper
and a soda can.
Nothing incendiary.
It was there.
I don't know what
to tell you, man.
All right, Zack,
we are not
going to take you
into custody,
but we are going to need
access to your room
for the rest of the day.
Okay.
I'm late for
Ancient History.
Can I go?
Sure.
And this, uh,
this nice officer...
he's gonna be your
"study buddy."
Thanks.
Well, what are
you thinking?
Name a chemical compound
that can burn skin
and can also disappear
into thin air.
The only thing I can think of
is dry ice.
And dry ice releases
carbon dioxide
as it sublimates.
Yeah, but can you put
enough dry ice
in Zack's room to
raise the amount
of carbon dioxide in Trip's room
to a lethal level?
Is that a dare?
Level's only 1.2.
We need more dry ice.
It took 30 pounds
of dry ice
to reach the lethal
level of saturation.
On the floor,
where the sleeping bag was.
Carbon dioxide is one and half
times heavier than air.
You know,
it's conceivable
that if Trip and Paula
had been sleeping
in his bed,
they might still be alive.
I think I know why
the bodies turned pink.
Really?
Dry ice is cold.
The dry ice significantly
lowered the temperature
in both rooms,
and the drastic decrease
in temperature
can turn a dead body pink.
We see it all the time
when we pull dead bodies
from frozen rivers.
Nice, Greg.
You know, if Zachary
is telling
the truth, and he simply
burned his finger
on a remnant of dry ice,
who put it there?
I'll have P.D. run a credit card
check on everyone in the dorm,
see if anyone recently purchased
a large quantity of dry ice.
Your decedent smells
like a pine tree.
Whoever stole him
probably sprayed his body
with disinfectant
to cover up the stench.
You got cause of death?
Yeah, he died of a heavy heart.
Heart weighed
500 grams instead of 300.
Hypertensive
Cardiovascular disease.
So his heart stopped,
he keeled over,
hit his head on the pavement.
Do you think he was aware
of his condition?
Oh, I know he was.
I sent blood to Tox,
he was taking
Atenolol.
A heart that size,
he was a walking time bomb.
Anything else?
Yup, our guy chugged a beer,
after he died.
Lungs were full
of foam.
So somebody poured it
down his throat?
Wouldn't be my postmortem
beverage of choice,
but to each his own.
So did you get any prints
off that cooler drawer?
Three.
Two were yours,
one was David's.
See you later.
Anything?
Just so you know, I moved
all your trace evidence
up to the top
of my pile.
Well, thank you.
Why don't you quit
blowing smoke
and tell me about
the cigar?
Low in nicotine,
high in furfural.
I compared it to other
tobacco samples
from the Exemplar collection.
It's consistent with
the Perdomo Reserve brand.
I took the liberty
of calling a cigar society.
They referred me
to the Vegas distributor.
Spoke to him directly.
Perdomos are very
high-end.
He only made one sale
this past month.
It was to a guy
in Seven Hills.
Smells like
my grandfather.
Am I interrupting?
Actually, yeah.
Conrad was about
to pat me on the back.
What do you got for me, Neil?
NEIL:
Lifted four clear prints
from the party hat.
They all came back
to Preston Hayburn,
from Henderson.
He's a paramedic.
Would've had access
to the morgue.
Good work, Neil.
Good work.
I have a number.
Oh, me, too.
The woman he met on the plane
said he was heading
to party in Seven Hills.
I'll start there
and then I'll head to Henderson.
Okay?
Yes.
I found this toilet behind
my apartment complex.
It's, uh, volunteered
for an experiment.
It's moving.
I put dry ice
in the bowl.
So you're thinking
that the killer
might have put his excess
dry ice in the dorm toilet.
When the ice
was flushed,
it would've lodged
in the drain trap.
As the ice sublimated
and gas was released,
it would've built up,
causing the toilet
to explode.
Good theory.
I spoke with Brass.
Zack's alibi checks out.
He was in L.A. all week.
And, uh, P.D. checked
credit card records.
No one in that dorm
bought dry ice on credit.
There's only two retail outlets
in 20 miles that sell it,
and no one's
purchased a large
quantity of dry ice
in the last few weeks.
( laughing )
Well, I think I explained
the explod-o-potty.
Gregg, maybe the dry ice
wasn't purchased.
I mean, we are looking
at a university.
Science department
would probably
keep the stuff on hand.
Science major would have access.
I was his R.A.
The guy lived for basketball,
beer and girls.
Didn't want much to do
with dorm activities.
Have you... seen
this before?
No.
Trip kept record of his, uh,
relationships with women.
Your name is in here.
Three times.
On, uh, February 2nd,
you hooked up
for the first time.
Looks like second base.
On February 9th,
you rounded third,
and on February 18th,
he got
a grand slam.
He wrote that down?
Mm-hmm.
We had sex, I admit it.
No big deal.
I didn't tell you guys
because I'm not
exactly proud of it, okay?
Trip and Paula
died
from of carbon dioxide gas.
We already know
that you have access
to dry ice, and as
a materials science
grad student,
you are familiar
with the chemical properties.
This is crazy.
Last week,
you checked out
40 pounds
of dry ice
from the campus lab.
My thesis is on metallurgy.
I use dry ice to test
the physical constrains
of certain metals.
I also spoke
to your advisor
who told me that your
experiments require
two pounds of dry ice, at most.
He broke your heart.
He led you on,
he let you believe
it was serious,
and after you went
all the way,
you were history.
Look, this has been a wild ride,
but if I gave you the impression
that I want
a relationship,
then, uh...
I was an idiot.
I had been consulting
my female advisees
not to take that kind of crap.
You knew Zack was in L.A.,
so you broke into his room
during the day
and drilled a hole in the wall.
Later that night,
you returned.
SANDERS:
Trip and Paula were asleep,
passed out from the alcohol.
When the ice evaporated,
the gas engulfed the room,
killing them.
I didn't know Paula was there,
and I never meant to kill Trip.
So drilling
the hole
in the wall and leaving
the ice behind was an accident?
No, no, look.
Trip's room
is 16 feet by nine feet.
I used exactly the right amount
of ice just to make him sick.
If he had been in
the bed three feet
above the ground
and not on the floor...
I just wanted him
to miss his basketball game.
Trip only slept on the floor
when he had girls over,
and he never had sex
before a big game.
He shouldn't have been
on the floor.
Your science
was perfect,
your instincts were not so good.
And you
miscalculated
one huge factor:
the sex drive of a college jock.
( door bell chimes )
Who is it?
( through door ):
L.V.P.D.
Can I help you?
Are you Charlie Jackson?
Yeah.
Do you know a James Billmeyer?
Yeah, we went
to high school together.
Are you aware that he
passed away?
Yeah, yeah, it was a big blow;
we were close.
You mind
if we come in?
Yeah, come in.
You, uh...
smoke Perdomo
Reserve?
Yeah, on special
occasion.
Why?
Do you know a Preston Hayburn?
Paramedic
from Henderson.
Yeah, he,
James and I were tight.
We went to high school together.
What's this about?
Cut the act,
Charlie.
We know
that Preston
had access to the morgue.
We believe he stole
James Billmeyer's body,
maybe brought it here.
But what we don't know is why?
All right, James was dying.
He had a bad heart,
everybody knew it,
so we flew him
out here for one last bash,
and Preston got called to the
Tangiers and it was Jamie.
The poor guy
died in the parking lot.
ECKLIE:
And then what?
You decided to throw him
a dead man's party?
Well, we already
bought the booze.
( laughing )
( indistinct conversations )
He was my best friend, you know?
It's a class D felony
to steal a corpse
with the intent
to sell or mutilate.
I'm not really sure
how to classify
"partying with the dead."
Look, I know
how it looks,
but if you knew Jamie...
it's what he would've wanted.
And we did return him.
You're still
under arrest.
Obstruction of justice and
conspiracy to commit theft.
You're looking at
one to four years, Charlie.
He would have done it for me.