♪ ♪
( engine starts )
( tires screeching )
This is the best
taco I ever had.
I'm happy for you both.
What, did you piss
off Ecklie again?
This is a
hit-and-run.
I was expecting
Greg Sanders.
We're slammed.
Everybody's on a case.
Is this a Fiero?
Yeah, the old Fiero.
Kind of makes you nostalgic
for a "Members Only" jacket.
Anyway, the
Hummer was going
the wrong way
on a one-way street.
The guy in the Fiero,
lucky to be alive.
Nobody saw
the driver get out.
People who drive
$100,000 vehicles
don't usually run
away from them.
Well, you obviously haven't met
any paroled rappers.
Tread mark shapes
indicate acceleration.
Pedal to the metal.
Maybe a getaway.
Or maybe a joyride.
There's a red
smear on the door.
Somebody's got blood
on their hands.
Well, at least we know
one thing about the driver.
He's had a face lift.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
( telephone rings )
TREMONT:
Crime Lab,
how can I help you?
Sara, I just
want you to know
that when we were
in the shower, I
didn't see anything.
Really?
Gosh, I saw everything.
TREMONT:
Mr. Grissom,
PD just called.
Apparently, the Humvee
from your hit-and-run
was carjacked earlier tonight.
Yeah, it was
our Hummer...
for all of
20 minutes.
We... We won it
in a raffle.
So, what happened?
All of a sudden, this fat guy
comes out of nowhere and...
Fat guy?!
No, that's you.
What's me?
Fat guy...
Well, um, how do you see it,
Mrs. Shaw?
The kid who took the car
was skinny.
Well, maybe he wasn't as big as
me, but he was definitely fat.
I'm going to sock you one.
He was not.
He pulled me
out of the car!
He was as skinny
as a stickman!
Yeah...
According to the,
uh, witness statement,
the carjacker was hanging
over there by the fence.
What are we, about three blocks
from the crash site?
Uh, yeah.
Nice freakin'
neighborhood.
( sirens wailing
in the distance )
( tires screeching )
Come on, man!
I didn't do nothing! Let me go!
Try to steal from me,
you miserable lowlife!
This time,
I get justice!
You're going to jail!
You are going to jail!
Man, you just a damn racist.
BRASS:
Hold up.
This guy matches
the description
of a suspect in a
carjack hit-and-run.
Naw, dawgs, yo,
I jacked a 40,
not no car, a'ight?
Yeah, a'ight...
One Cent, let's go.
So the kid denies jacking
the Hummer.
Says he's never
even been in one.
We matched his blood
on the gearshift
and on the headband
I found in the alley.
And he's skinny,
which matches one
of the descriptions.
I'm charging him.
HODGES:
The oily stain
you collected
from the Hummer's
airbag was,
ironically
enough, oil.
More specifically, lard.
It looks like there's
tissue fibers mixed into it.
Several different types,
actually,
so I ran an ELISA
to differentiate.
Pork, beef, chicken
and possibly human flesh.
A real taste treat.
It's all been cooked up,
so I doubt we'll get any DNA.
What are you thinking about?
Tacos.
( sizzling )
Hola.
Chicken, beef or pork, boss?
Los carnitas, por favor.
Carnitas.
Say, uh...
have you had any trouble
around here recently?
Just a little scuffle yesterday.
Nothing I couldn't handle.
Yo, Pops,
give me the loot!
( screaming )
Why didn't you file
a police report?
Bother you guys
with something like that?
( scoffs ):
I was a kid once.
Those guys just
needed someone
to set 'em straight.
Here you go.
Gracias.
Denada.
Oh, it's on the house.
Muchas gracias.
( auto-dialing beeps )
Jim, we need to go
back to the hospitals.
We're looking
for a burn patient.
Lawrence Lafontaine,
you're under arrest.
Vern rat me out?
No, the taco did.
Everyone around my hood
knows that taco guy.
To get whooped by his old ass
and not do anything about it?
For real, stop, yo!
Man, dawgs, it
hurts for real, man.
Here, now, you straight?
Stop being such a little baby.
I need some medicine--
I ain't talking
about going
to no hospital, either.
Well, have fun then, man.
I'm-a get me some payback.
Vern just bitched out,
wanted to forget
it ever happened.
Not me.
So you stole the Hummer
for revenge.
I knew we should've asked
for directions.
Out of the car, man!
Hey, hey, hey!
Get the hell
out of the car!
( tires screeching )
Let me get this straight, Larry.
An old man refuses
to let you steal his money,
so you jack a Hummer
and try to run
over his taco stand?
Maybe.
I think this is the dumbest
thing we've ever heard.
( Sanders speaking
in reverse )
It's a beach house,
a ski lodge,
a state-of-the-art office,
your home on the road...
Ladies and gentlemen,
Daluca Motorcoaches
is proud to present the G-4700!
( cheering )
Gentlemen.
Hey.
What's going on here?
Lisa Schumacher, 29.
There's no surveillance
on the floor, and none
of the rent-a-cops
remember
the last time
they saw her.
A convention girl.
A what?
You know, a model,
stripper or a
showgirl working
the convention for extra cash.
You got a T.O.D. yet?
Well, based on lividity,
I'd say around 4:00 a.m.
Laceration on the lower lip.
Contusions on the neck.
Petechiae in the eyes.
So she got slapped around,
strangled.
Maybe somewhere
in between,
she was raped.
These streaks right here.
They don't look like blood.
Possible hair fragments
and some skin
under her nails.
She fought back.
It'd be good for us.
( indistinct radio
communication )
( crowd murmuring )
♪ ♪
( snaps swab )
So that's why they call it
a "recreational vehicle."
ROBBINS:
C.O.D. is asphyxia
due to manual strangulation.
Whoever did this
used a lot more force
than they needed to.
There's bleeding
in the neck muscles.
Fractures in the cornu
of the thyroid cartilage
and hyoid bone.
Did you do a wet mount?
Sure did.
Found motile sperm
in the vaginal cavity.
Well, Warrick found several
used condoms at the scene.
Killer must have run out,
and started riding bareback.
Eh, I'm not sure
he rode anything at all.
There's an absence
of trauma in the vaginal cavity.
Enough to rule out rape?
Yeah.
The semen was found at a depth
not indicative
of penile penetration.
In this case,
only a couple inches in.
Maybe that's all the killer
had to work with.
WOMAN:
And now, the moment that we've
all been waiting for.
The winner of the brand-new
Humvee is...
Kyle Shaw!
( screams )
Oh! Oh, my God!
Honey, we won.
Whoa!
Hey, I got over 70 women
working this convention, man.
Booth bimbos,
crowd gatherers,
hostesses, narrators,
demonstrators, translators.
Whatever you need, I got it.
Well, we're only interested
in Lisa Schumacher.
She's one of my girls.
I represent her.
They call her "Cris,"
as in Cristal,
the champagne.
She can't get enough of it.
She likes to party?
She likes to make money.
Girls who party
make the money.
This ain't L.A.,
where you get up at
10:00 a.m. for an audition.
At 10:00 a.m., my girls
are still at Drai's
partying with the client.
What's this about?
She was found dead
this morning.
No.
Come on, she's over there
working the Daluca account.
You didn't hear?
There's two million square
feet of exhibits here, man.
40,000 people.
This place is a mini-city.
That RV exhibit's across town.
I was told that
the doors close at 10:00.
Any idea why she
was here after hours?
Look, she worked
behind a booth,
yapping her mouth.
Can't really throw her
in a bikini no more.
She's getting up there.
Three-oh, uh-oh.
( chuckles )
I didn't really keep tabs.
Donny.
You're late.
And you're not dressed.
What's the deal, girl?!
Please, Donny, I just
had the worst morning.
Oh, you think you had it bad?
Well, Cris is dead.
Oh, my God.
It's a tough business.
Hodges...
( clank )
What do you want?
What are you doing?
I'm looking for leaks.
Call Facilities.
You got my results?
If you knew the kind of stuff
that grows in these pipes,
you'd be on your hands
and knees with me.
The results, Hodges,
from the swabs I gave you?
From Lisa Schumacher's
fingertips?
Fine.
I found several substances.
Nonoxynol-9 spermicide.
Spermicide.
So she did handle a condom.
Also found traces
of PVP, sorbitol,
carbomer,
hydroxypropylcellulose--
Probably a hair gel.
Well, she did have skin
under her fingernails,
so she could've scratched
her attacker's scalp.
Not my job.
And last,
the brownish-orange substance
on the vic's fingers,
chest and shoulders:
instant tanning lotion.
Hmm.
Got four work card hits
from the motor coach.
Dana Simmons,
Candice Mosti,
Lane Kelly,
and your vic, Lisa Schumacher.
29 and already over the hill.
Please tell me you're kidding.
( chuckles )
This town has
different standards.
BROWN:
Let me see something.
( presses keys )
Looks like Lisa had a roommate.
So my prints are on the RV.
Okay, I work
that display sometimes.
It's not just the print
that makes you look bad,
it's you.
You're raffling off a Hummer
hours after your roommate
turns up dead.
What am I supposed to do?
I'm broke and
my car insurance is due.
What is that on your arm?
Is that tanner?
Forgot to rub it in, I guess.
Razor-tight girl like you
forgetting to rub
tanning lotion in?
Doesn't sound right to me.
You know, the funny thing is,
is your girlfriend Lisa
had streaks of tanner
on her body, too.
Were you girls
together last night?
Donny asked us to hang out
with Mr. Daluca after work.
You and Lisa?
Me, Lisa, Dana, and Lane.
You guys just "went out"?
Come on.
Look, I'm not a hooker.
All I do is
these conventions.
So when a big baller
like Mr. Daluca comes into town
and offers us a little cash
to hang out,
I'm with it.
"With it" where?
We had dinner at Fix.
Partied at Mix.
Gambled a little.
Then he took us back
to the convention center.
Hammered and horny.
Oh!
Okay.
Who gets the first ride?
( Daluca laughing )
If I wanted
someone your age,
I'd do my wife.
( laughs )
Price of one, huh?
Yeah.
( sobbing )
I left there as soon as I could.
I took a cab home.
Did Daluca get
rough with her?
Not that I saw.
He didn't even
want to touch her.
Really? Because we found
Lisa's DNA on a condom.
When I left, Daluca was busy
with Dana and Lane,
and Lisa locked herself
in the bathroom.
That was the last time
I saw her.
MAN:
You want my prints?
My DNA?
I mean, come on, guys.
I'm on vacation here.
Having a sample of your DNA
would help exclude you
as a suspect.
Voluntary or court order,
it's your choice.
My DNA is gonna be
all over that girl,
but I didn't put it there,
she did.
Now, this broad was expiring
like spoiled milk,
and she was looking
for a way out.
( sobbing )
( music playing in distance )
You still here?
You bitch.
( crying )
!
You bitch!
She puts my baby inside her,
hey, quickie retirement plan.
You know, I can't think
of a better reason
for a man to kill a woman.
If I'd have killed her,
you think I'd put her
in my own motorcoach,
and then present it
at an unveiling ceremony
that I was announcing?
You don't believe me, go ask
the convention authorities.
I told them what
she was trying to do.
It's the last time I ever hire
those skanks to work a show.
Ye... Yes, yes, I'm very aware
of Butterfield Academy's
privacy policy,
but this a homicide...
Daluca's all over the condoms.
Get this, on one of them,
his DNA and her epithelials
are on both sides.
Well, that's kind of like
turning a sock inside out.
It does support
his story, though.
Well, what about
the epithelials
under her nails?
It's not a match
to Daluca.
So where does
that leave us?
Oh, I'm not quite done yet.
Have a seat, Donny.
What kind of hair
gel do you use?
Well, I don't
think it would
work with the texture
of your hair.
Real funny.
What are you doing?
Please stay still.
How did you get these scratches
in your head?
Probably from scratching.
I'm always thinking.
I'll tell you
what you were thinking.
You were thinking about how Lisa
pissed off your best client.
And how much business
it was gonna cost you.
You kill her,
Daluca takes the fall.
Win-win for you.
Lisa was a nothing.
Old news.
Why would I risk everything
for a zero like her?
For that exact reason,
'cause she was
a "nothing" to you.
That's a good story.
You find that in one
of your forensic journals?
No, but when I match your DNA,
I'll make sure
you're on the cover.
Cuff him.
♪ ♪
( Brown speaking in reverse )
( Stokes speaking in reverse)
( cheering )
( doorbell chimes )
Hey, Paul, it's Gwen.
Come on, babe.
Let me in.
Work me out.
MAN:
Vic is Paul Charles, 28.
Competition bodybuilder
and personal trainer.
Doors were all locked,
windows closed.
No sign of forced entry.
This guy's a poster child
for self-love.
Maybe that's why
they went for the face.
Gwen, did you
see anyone else
near the house
when you arrived?
No, uh...
Paul cut down on clients
so he could train
for Mr. Las Vegas.
It's next month, and...
he really wanted to win
this time.
He canceled
my last two workouts.
So, why didn't you get
another trainer?
If be canceled again,
I was going to.
Did you
and Paul ever get physical?
Just once.
Last month.
Come on, feel it.
Come on,
you got to want it.
Come on.
I'll tell you
what I want.
What's wrong?
He said he had a headache.
But I mean,
he was training
really, really hard,
so he was probably just tired.
Or gay.
I don't know.
I don't care.
I mean, just lying back
on that bench
and sweating
and pushing the weight
with all of his muscle
right there beside me...
I mean, it, it was
totally... motivating.
No matter how hard
you work to get big,
there's always
someone bigger.
It could be
what keeps them going.
Like Freud said,
"Anatomy is destiny."
What do you think
Freud would have to say
about one of these
being the murder weapon?
SIDLE:
Killer didn't even have
to be his size.
Could have been a little guy,
or a woman.
All they would
have needed
was the right weapon,
some leverage,
the element of surprise.
Victim is a well-developed
Caucasian male.
Musculature appears
hypertrophied.
Care to guess?
Blunt-force trauma.
Absence of bruising.
Maybe it was a post-mortem blow.
Let's find out.
( shutter clicks )
Nine millimeter
in the nightstand,
and syringes
next to the bed.
Wow.
Maybe our vic
was putting the smack
in "smackdown."
There was no blood
on the poles or the weights.
Rigor mortis
is full and extremely rigid.
Liver mortis
is posterior and fixed.
Let's roll him.
That's good.
Present
on the bilateral buttocks
are multiple
fine punctures,
with some surrounding
faint purple ecchymosis.
Laceration noted
at the base of the scalp.
Uh, loss of blood
from that laceration
is significant but non-fatal.
( grinding )
( bone snaps )
Crime lab; how can we help you?
Sara, I just
want you to know,
when we were in the shower,
I didn't see anything.
Really? Gosh,
I saw everything.
ROBBINS:
The black pus
suggested a
possible infection
from an
airborne agent.
I took the precaution
to get you out
until Hazmat
cleared the scene.
Yeah, thanks a lot.
( clearing throat )
Uh, what did they find?
Actually, it's what I found--
mucormycosis, a
disease caused
by exposure to rhizopus oryzae,
a kind of mold.
Did you say rhizopus oryzae?
Mm-hmm.
We spent hours in that house.
You're not at risk.
You both have
healthy immune systems.
I suspect that's not
the case with your vic.
Copy that.
Trace on the syringes
was Deca-Durabolin,
Sustanon and Oxandrolone.
Steroids.
That guy was "stacking"
to get bigger.
HODGES:
Immune suppression is
a common side effect.
So, how does a mold infection
make it look
like someone smashed him
across the face?
His face collapsed
from the inside.
Mucor causes
deterioration
of the bones around the sinuses
and eye sockets.
You remember the
swollen eyeball?
The pus was pushing it out,
while the bones
that held
it in place
were getting eaten away.
The airborne mold spores
enter the nasal cavity
and they consume sinus tissue
as they multiply.
So, his compromised
immune system
wasn't strong enough to fight
the spread of the infection.
That's right.
Sick.
And what's even more sick
is that rhizopus oryzae
likes to grow on human tissue.
Mold grows outward
as spores reproduce
and are carried away
from the source.
If we can pinpoint the source
of the human tissue,
that should tell you something.
Whew! We have got to be getting
close to the source.
Hit the lights.
SANDERS:
Here?
A whole lot of blood.
We're getting warmer.
Looks like we found
the source of the mold.
SANDERS:
Okay.
So, how does human tissue
get inside a wall?
Good question.
SIDLE:
There's a hole in the air duct.
A bullet hole...
Looks like a nine mil.
Same as the handgun
I found in the bedroom.
Copper-jacketed.
Good penetrating power.
Somebody was shot here.
( woman screaming )
( gunshot )
Bullet pushed blood and tissue
through the wall.
Water from the pipe leak
fed the mold growth.
SANDERS:
Eventually,
the mold released spores,
which spread
through the house AC,
and right on up
into muscle-head's nose.
We ran the phone numbers
from the vic's planner.
Everybody checked out,
except for
a woman named Tiffany.
No last name?
Well, Tiffany is actually
a street name
for Angela Wheeler,
known prostitute.
Her family reported her missing
last month.
Well, anyone who appears
this narcissistic
may prefer paying for hookers
rather than wasting his love
on a girlfriend.
And as we know, in addition
to immune suppression
and heart and liver disease,
steroid abuse can also cause
shrunken testicles,
impotence and aggression--
"roid rage."
Oh, baby,
looks like you
have one muscle
that isn't hard.
You think that's funny, bitch?!
So, if the DNA
from the tissue on the bullet
matches Tiffany...
We have a sample?
A DNA reference sample
was collected from her apartment
in the initial
investigation.
Mia's on it.
Very good.
This is just like
that Edgar Allen Poe story
where the victim's
heart
under the floorboards
betrays the murder.
"The Tell-Tale Heart."
I thought you didn't like
reading the classics.
I do when they're about
dismembered bodies.
( Sidle speaking in reverse )
( Sanders speaking in reverse)
Move over Chester,
my dogs are barking.
Come on, now,
move over a little bit.
Let me sit down.
Chester, damn!
It's not me.
Why don't you
put your shoes
back on?
Oh, sweet Lord.
Kid can't be more
than 12 or 13.
You think he's homeless?
Jeans are a little nice
for a homeless kid.
Check his veins and
do a SART kit anyway.
Can you ballpark
a T.O.D.?
Sure.
Well, he's just
developing rigor,
so, I'd say dead
no more than eight hours.
This is a busy line--
buses, traffic...
And nobody noticed him?
Maybe be hasn't been here
the whole time.
Could explain the blanket.
Body dump.
Hey, Chester,
you been taking that thing
off road again?
Nah, mud screws up the ride.
I bet you always get a bad cart
at the store, huh?
Not me.
Thanks, guy.
♪ ♪
Sir, all I'm asking for
is your class roster.
Ye... Yes, yes, I'm very aware
of Butterfield Academy's
privacy policy,
but this a homicide
investigation.
Sir, please,
court orders take time.
You could help me
identify this boy tonight.
Okay.
No, no, no.
I understand your position.
Thanks.
ROBBINS:
Whatever happened
to this boy wasn't pretty.
First- and second-degree burns
on several areas
of exposed skin.
What about the
burn to the face?
Could that be
from an iron?
ROBBINS:
It's a possibility.
He sustained several hematomas
along his arms,
together with a nasty
skull fracture.
I'm thinking child abuse.
Skull fracture what killed him?
No. Positional asphyxia.
Check out his eyes.
Heat damage.
To all the respiratory mucosa,
as well.
I'd say this kid
was in a small, hot space
for quite a while.
Closet with a radiator,
boiler room...
Shake and bake.
WILLOWS:
Oh, Nick?
Yeah.
I heard you were looking
for the student directory
for Butterfield Academy.
Yeah. Yeah.
How'd you get this?
I talked to the headmaster.
He wouldn't give me jack.
I pay tuition.
Your daughter goes
to Butterfield?
Mm-hmm.
Wow. That's a little pricy.
She was at a crossroads
and I, uh, needed to put her
in a school with
tighter reins.
You know,
when it comes to your kids,
you, uh, find the money.
Yeah.
You looking for a prom date?
( laughs )
No. I'm trying
to I.D. a victim.
Thanks for this.
Good luck.
Thank you.
( birds singing )
( doorbell chimes )
STOKES:
Oh. Hi there.
I've been
ringing the bell.
Sorry. I was sleeping.
No school today?
I'm sick.
The whole house is sick.
Oh, gosh. Okay.
Uh, well, my name's Nick Stokes.
I'm with the Las Vegas
Police Department,
and, uh,
this is pretty important.
Parents around?
No. Uh, they're not home.
Do you have
their cell phone or
work numbers handy?
Okay, they're skiing in Vail.
What are you gonna do,
arrest me for having a kegger?
No, not exactly.
Um...
how old are you?
What's going on, babe?
Just go...
What?
How old is he?
My father's a lawyer,
so I probably
shouldn't be talking to you.
You have a brother?
Chase?
Yeah, Chase.
Is, uh... is he around?
No, he spent the night
at his friend Andy's house.
Is that the last time
you saw him?
I don't know.
Do you have a picture
of your brother
I can take a look at?
Yeah.
Would you get that
for me, please?
Thank you.
Um...
I'm gonna need your parents'
contact information
if you don't mind,
in Vail, okay?
Your Chase's
best friend, Andy.
I need to know what happened
last night.
Andy was supposed
to sleep over at Chase's,
but Chase wasn't feeling well,
so Andy came home
early instead.
Ma'am, please,
I need to hear
Andy's version.
Okay?
Go ahead, Andy.
I told my mom
I was sleeping
at Chase's house,
and he told
his sister
we were sleeping at my house.
Where were the Ryans?
They were in Vail.
We just wanted
to see a high school party.
And did you?
Some of it.
( loud music and chatter )
This tastes
horrible.
Just keep drinking.
It must get better.
Jackie caught us.
Made us leave.
We promised to
go to my house.
We didn't.
We went to this arcade,
played a few games,
and then I walked home.
What about Chase?
He stayed there,
playing the games.
Talk to me, Goose.
Well, according to tox,
junior was a boozer.
BAC three times
the legal limit.
Yeah, the, uh, teenage
sister had a kegger.
How old were you
when you first got drunk?
Oh, 16, 17.
Amortized over a generation,
12's about right?
So your saying,
two generations from now,
four-year-olds are just
gonna be getting trashed?
Pre-school graduation parties
are going to be off the hook.
Mm.
But Chase's party was just
getting started.
Tape lifts
were a cornucopia.
Hairs: Caucasoid,
Mongoloid, Negroid.
And feline and canine.
As for fibers,
we have cotton, wool, polyester,
and someone brought Lycra.
Transfer from the blanket?
No. I tested that.
It came back clean.
Okay. What about the, uh,
the gack in the guy's hair?
Melted vulcanized rubber
and thermoplastic elastomers.
From the sole
of your average
athletic shoe.
Hmm.
What's hot, cramped,
and full of other people's hair?
As I've often said,
that's your job.
( mechanical whirring )
Excuse me.
You the manager?
Yeah.
Yeah. Uh, I was taking
my laundry to the car,
and the cart locked up on me.
Yup. We got this fancy system
'cause people steal 'em.
I'm the only one with a remote.
So...
I spend all day unlocking 'em.
( laughs )
Which one is it?
Murder?
STOKES:
A 12-year-old
boy died in one of your dryers
the other night.
You trying to tell me
you don't know anything
about it?
Couple of kids were playing
around the' mat, making trouble.
I chased them out.
What happened after that...
I don't know.
That's it?
I don't buy it, Jared.
I don't.
You know why?
Your fancy carts.
And I know that
no cart leaves
that parking lot
unless somebody presses
the magic button.
And I also
matched tires treads.
Someone...
wheeled one of your carts
through wet grass...
( clears throat )
...and dumped a dead
12-year-old boy
on a bus bench.
Okay, look,
I'm supposed to be on duty
the whole time.
But this customer--
he was gettin' all pissed off.
Look at this, look at this!
See what it did to my vest.
I have to go
to work in this.
I demand justice!
Hey, will you get the hell
out of here?
So I went next door.
Had to get the smell
of detergent out of my nose.
Bought a Yoo-hoo.
I came back to check on things.
I didn't know
if he was dead or not.
Bus bench. Hospital.
I could see how you
could make the mistake.
You have any idea
what the liability would be
on something like that?
Uh-uh.
But I'll let you know.
I was just hoping
that somebody would find him
and take care of him.
Hey...
you found him.
You put him in the dryer.
Mm-mm.
Mm-hmm.
Mm-hmm. Chase can't even
lock himself
inside those things.
They lock from
the outside.
And I matched
your print
on the handle.
I got it off your school's
safe kit.
He asked me to.
( laughing ):
Whoa! Dude!
Come on, turn it on!
Turn it on!
And after that,
it gets a little fuzzy.
You put your best friend
in a... in a dryer,
and you turned it on,
and you just
walked away?
What is wrong with you?
Tough shift, huh?
Just another day
in paradise.
( phone rings )
Crime lab.
How can we help you?