( singing with the radio ):
♪ It was Christmas
in Las Vegas ♪
♪ When the locals
take the town ♪
♪ Theresa hit a streak ♪
♪ And laid
her waitress apron down ♪
♪ She was playing penny poker ♪
♪ Over at the old Gold Spike ♪
♪ She's tired
of Texas Hold 'Em ♪
♪ So she switched
to Let It Ride ♪
♪ Then over on Fremont Street ♪
♪ Six pits won her a car ♪
♪ She rode it up the strip
to where the flashy hotels are ♪
♪ At first, she hit a royal ♪
♪ Not a dirty one this time ♪
♪ And then she drew
four deuces... ♪
( radio shuts off )
( garbled voices
over police scanner )
MAN:
Nick.
D.A.
What's going
on out here?
Well, anonymous
911 caller
reported body parts
in this area.
I rolled and found this.
STOKES:
Hmm.
Tasty.
( camera shutter clicking )
Have any idea
how long it's going to take you
to get this stuff out of here?
Well...
I can't move the, uh...
the "body" until the coroner
releases the scene.
It's a busy night. It's probably
gonna take a while, man.
Great.
Hey, you mind if I step
away for a second?
I need to get
some fresher air.
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah,
sure, take your time.
( sniffs )
Whew!
( retching )
Hey, you, uh...
want some gum?
No, thank you.
( coughing )
( spits )
♪ ♪
Well, that's peculiar.
BRASS:
Think!
Did you see anybody else
in the area?
I didn't see
anything, sir.
I mean, I only took
my eyes off him
for a couple seconds...
You're not supposed to take
your eyes off him ever.
He's been gone
maybe 25 minutes.
♪ ♪
I got some white fibers
on Nick's vest.
Smells like alcohol.
♪ ♪
Why'd you bag that?
I didn't.
It's the wrong color tape.
No initials on the seal.
That's not Nick's evidence.
Maybe it's a message.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
( stifled whimpering )
♪ ♪
Two heads are better than one.
Spatter patterns
are a match.
One bullet, two victims.
No, no, no, no.
Grissom, that isn't possible.
I sampled every square
inch of that scene,
and there was
only one DNA type
on the bloodstains.
How 'bout that?
Our mystery vics
are identical twins.
Twins?
Well, that's different.
Technically, it's the same.
What's this?
GRISSOM:
I just got it.
It's a certificate
of honorary
ownership of Trigger,
"The Smartest Horse
in the Movies,"
issued by Roy Rogers
to the children of America.
Roy felt that the children
of America
were the true owners of Trigger,
so any kid that would write him,
he'd send 'em one of those.
And where did you get it?
The Roy Rogers
and Dale Evans Museum,
which used to be
in Victorville, California,
and is now in Branson, Missouri.
Roy Rogers, the cowboy?
King of the cowboys.
I wrote to him
when I was four.
He sent me one of those.
I lost it, so I thought
I'd replace it.
And then you thought
you would frame it.
Yeah.
( clears throat )
The object of the
game is to be the
first one to make it
to Uncle Jesse's farm
without running into Roscoe.
Now, there's two
ways to do that.
You can either
take the dirt road
or the highway.
Dirt road is slower
because you can only
roll with one dice,
but it's safe
because you don't run
into any of the
Hazzard cards
that you would find
on the highway, right?
But when you are
on the highway, you
get to roll two dice,
which makes
you go faster.
Pretend I'm gonna
take the highway,
so I'm gonna move
General Lee eight spaces.
One, two, three,
four, five...
Eight. I hit a
Hazzard card.
Now, Hazzard cards
you don't want.
"Cooter splashes mud
on your windshield."
You lose one turn,
all right?
Think you got it?
I think I got it.
All right, cool.
All right, well,
I've never been one
to take the path
of least resistance,
so I'm going for the dirt road.
One dice.
You know, far be it from me
to wax nostalgic,
but, uh, I kind of miss
the old Greg.
Ugly T-shirts,
goofy hair,
semi-pornographic magazines...
Yeah, well, at least I had
a style to change.
Four. One, two,
three, four.
"Take a Duke card."
What's a Duke card?
Duke cards are good.
You want one of those
'cause it gets you
through the dirt road
a lot faster.
Okay, so Duke cards, good;
Hazzard cards, bad.
Correct.
"Move five extra spaces."
Nice.
SANDERS:
Yeah.
Oh, and by
the way, uh...
this is just the work me.
You haven't had the full
David Hodges experience.
I think I'm having it right now.
Aw, come on, you
can't unfund me now.
I... I'm committed to
presenting the paper
at SWAFS next month.
If it means that much to you,
pay your own way.
Show a little dedication
to your discipline.
Oh, yeah.
Tragically,
my banking account
isn't as dedicated
as I am.
One word: plastic.
Wait. How 'bout
you kick me
a little overtime
under the table, huh?
Over my dead body.
Have you been to
Grissom's office?
You think the city
of Las Vegas pays
for his etymology library,
his insect collection,
his shrunken head
collection?
No. Take initiative.
People notice.
So I took my girl
to that Ultimate
Fight Championship
on Saturday night.
Oh, yeah, yeah, down
over at the, uh, Spur?
Yeah.
Almost ended up getting
into a smackdown of my own.
No way.
You almost got
into a beef?
You know, Tina doesn't
like me carrying a gun.
I play down the fact
that I'm a cop
when I'm with her anyway.
Yeah, yeah, you play
the scientist card.
You're a "copologist."
( laughing )
So, we're standing
out in front of the hotel,
making out
and this guy walks up to me,
gets in my face,
and asks me how she is.
No, he didn't.
So?
I tell him get lost.
He says, "make me."
So I took a
step forward.
And out of nowhere
his big, fat bodyguard,
looking like Wimpy from Popeye,
walks up and starts
to close in on me.
This fat boy
is looking like
he's obviously carrying
some sort of weapon.
And I'm standing there naked
as a porn star with my girl.
Did you tell them
you're a "cop"?
They didn't seem to care.
One of the guys
sounded Russian,
like he was wanna-be Mafia.
Mm-hmm.
Fat boy was obviously
his bodyguard.
Mm-hmm.
So, uh, you know,
I wasn't physically
afraid of the guys,
but something was kind
of sinister about them.
They were provoking me,
but they weren't
making a move.
It was almost like they were
waiting for me to make a move.
Say if I smacked big-mouth,
fat boy would've came over
and stabbed me or something.
Even fat boy was vibing me
not to take the bait.
So what happened?
Well, valet finally
brought Tina's car up.
So, I maneuver her
around these guys
and I put her in her car,
and I turn my back to them
and let 'em talk this smack.
I'm calming Tina down.
Tell her everything is fine.
She drives off and I walk away.
I called Tina
later on.
And I tell her, uh, you know,
if she got any problem
with me being a cop,
she needs to get over it,
'cause now I'm packing.
Yeah. Yeah.
What'd you do on Sunday?
Scoured the hotel
looking for these punks.
( laughs )
Oh, my two favorite guys.
So, I've got an assault
at Stripperama
and a trash run
at Flamingo and Koval.
I'm too busy to play favorites,
so duke it out.
Duke it out.
Boy better flip a coin.
I'll hurt you.
Yeah, you better
flip that coin.
Call it in the air.
Heads.
Have fun at the trash run.
You know, I'd do
two out of three,
but you got
a gambling problem.
No, hey, you know what?
You keep this.
It's bad luck.
( driver's door opens, closes)
( footsteps approaching )
( grunts )
( indistinct
radio transmission )
Dumpster's clean.
No apparent blood
or body parts.
Take a look at this.
This seems
contrived to me.
The blood pool
is too perfect.
There's no splatter.
Like somebody placed
these entrails.
A lure.
To grab Nick.
David, get this stuff
to the doc.
Look, I'm... I'm really sorry
I didn't get here sooner.
Maybe if I had...
We're going to get
him back, David.
Gil, Catherine.
I want you to know,
as far as I'm concerned,
lab's only got
one case tonight.
Same for the rest
of the department.
Thanks, Conrad.
Hey. What do you need me to do?
( barking )
They've lost the scent.
Might be as far
as it goes.
Yeah, there was some sort
of large vehicle here.
Well, there are a lot
of intestines here,
but no appendix,
which made sense
when I saw this.
A cecum.
Dog entrails.
Yeah.
That's not going to help.
I'm sorry.
Catherine...
has Nick's family been informed?
No, that would be my job.
SIDLE:
I swabbed the seal
for epithelials,
but there were no prints
on the outside of the bag.
What about Nick's camera?
No fingerprints.
There were some photographs,
mostly generals.
There were a few detail shots
of entrails and trash.
But no lucky grabs of
anybody else at the scene.
I don't think we're gonna
get lucky with this guy.
He knows how to work clean.
Grissom, I pulled all of Nick's
active and recent cases.
I want to know anyone who
had a grudge against him.
Civilian complaints,
death threats...
Got it.
There was a guy
a couple of years ago
that stalked him.
He may be back.
I remember.
Top of the pile.
I'm using your track
and wheelbase measurements
plus or minus five percent
to account
for rain-shadowing
and/or drying effects.
All right, print it out.
WARRICK:
I need you to bring up
the traffic cameras
in a three-block radius
between Flamingo and Koval
in the last 24 hours.
We only buffer
the video
for the past few hours.
I can take you back
as far as 10:37 p.m.
That's good enough.
Our guy was taken around 11:00.
Scan forward.
We're looking for a big truck.
How about that one?
Looks like a Suburban.
It's on the list.
Whoa, he's racing.
Wait a minute.
That one, the big Ford.
Follow it.
WARRICK:
The Expedition truck
left the area around 11:15.
Definitely in a hurry.
Took a right off Koval
onto Tropicana,
crossed Las Vegas Boulevard
onto the 15 South.
And then it drove
off the grid.
At least we have
a general direction.
SIDLE:
Great, so Nick could be anywhere
from Green Valley
to Seven Hills to Arizona.
Assuming he was in that truck.
WILLOWS:
Well, according to Hodges,
the white fibers
on Nick's vest were cotton
with traces of ether...
( grunting )
Ether?
That's old school.
WARRICK:
Yeah, stuff is volatile.
Flammable.
Outside of meth cooks,
no one uses it
anymore.
People use what they know.
All right, so, where are we
on possible suspects?
So far, none of Nick's active
or recent cases stands out.
And his old stalker's
still behind bars.
Maybe it's a random act.
WILLOWS:
Well, that's possible.
Because whoever staged
the crime scene
couldn't have known
that Nick was going to respond.
Yeah, it was just
bad luck he did.
Sara,
what about the coffee cup?
No DNA or prints on the cup
or in the bag.
HODGES:
Don't touch the edge of it!
MAN:
You got to sign...
Security!
Get your freakin'
hands off me, man!
Hold still. Hold still.
Hey, I told you, you
got to sign for that!
What are you doing, Hodges?
Guy comes in here with a package
with no return address.
You're violating
my rights!
I want a lawyer!
Shut up.
Way the guy was pawing
that envelope,
I figure I better
get it away from him
before he wipes off
all the trace.
What trace?
It's about Nick.
Let me do this.
♪ ♪
( loud thud )
( sighs )
( thud )
( thudding )
( spits )
( grunts )
( panting )
( cocks gun )
( tapping wood )
( panting )
Hi, CSI guy.
You wondering why you're here?
Because you followed
the evidence.
Because that's what CSIs do.
So breathe quick, breathe slow,
put your gun in your mouth
and pull the trigger.
Any way you like,
you're going to die here.
Okay.
( tape shuts off )
( yelling )
( screaming )
( sobbing )
( '60s rock music playing )
♪ You can try to please me ♪
♪ But it won't be easy ♪
♪ Stone walls surround me ♪
♪ I'm surprised
that you even found me ♪
♪ And you don't stand
an outside chance ♪
♪ Don't stand
an outside chance ♪
♪ You don't stand
an outside chance ♪
♪ But you can try... ♪
Son of a bitch.
He's screwing with us.
♪ Whatever you do, girl ♪
♪ You know you
can't get through, girl ♪
♪ Can't bring me down ♪
♪ Hang me up
or even hang around ♪
♪ And you don't stand
an outside chance ♪
♪ You don't stand
an outside chance ♪
♪ You don't stand
an outside chance ♪
♪ But you can try ♪
♪ ...try ♪
( music continues )
♪ I know you think
you'll get me ♪
♪ I'm only flesh and bone ♪
♪ But you may as well
forget me ♪
♪ 'Cause my heart is stone ♪
♪ You better leave me alone ♪
♪ Yeah! ♪
♪ You can try to please me ♪
♪ But it won't be easy ♪
( grunting )
♪ Stone walls surround me ♪
♪ I'm surprised
that you even found me ♪
( grunting hysterically )
♪ And you don't stand
an outside chance ♪
♪ You don't stand
an outside chance ♪
( screaming )
♪ But you can try ♪
♪ Yeah, keep on trying ♪
♪ Stand an outside chance ♪
♪ Come on and show me
you love me, baby ♪
♪ Stand an outside chance ♪
♪ You got to try, love... ♪
( device beeps )
I don't think he knows
we can see him.
How can we be sure
it's a live feed?
We've got to assume
that it is.
The space in that box
looks like 2x2x6,
which would be 24 cubic feet.
That would hold approximately
600 liters of air.
If you figure half a liter
per breath.
Slow breathing...
( device beeps )
maybe 12 breaths per minute.
Panic breathing would be, what,
twice that much.
Well, if the math is right,
he's got about an hour
and 15 minutes of air left
in that box.
But if they're going to keep him
alive for 12 hours,
it must mean that he's got
an additional air supply.
( grunts )
JOHNSON:
We lost the feed.
Looks like a live feed to me.
I say we keep the light on.
( door closes )
I'm gonna get right to it,
because time is
of the essence here.
Where'd you get
that package, bud?
I'd like to
advise my client.
Careful how you
answer that, son.
This man here's
slicker than a snake
in the curly green grass.
He's right,
so you better be careful.
I got called out to a pickup
on Viking Circle.
W-when I got there,
I didn't talk
to an actual person.
I just found
an abandoned package
with some cash taped to it.
How much cash?
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
That's confidential business
'tween me and
this here buckaroo.
Easy, boots.
I'm gonna need those bills.
It was a hundred bucks.
If you want it back,
you're gonna have
to ask Steve Wynn.
What's the address?
( groans )
( TV blaring )
( sighs )
Code Four.
( snoring )
MAN ( on TV ):
Whoo-hoo! Vegas!
Yeah, the address
was a waste of time.
Nothing here but a fat drunk
and a bad smell.
The guy probably
picked the house at random,
'cause he knew we'd chase it.
Any news
on the Web cam location?
Archie's trying
to narrow it down.
The feed stays active
for two minutes
every time you press
the "Watch" button.
Okay.
But I got to go.
I got people to see.
Everybody, I have
some bad news.
Uh, a little while ago,
I spoke
with the mayor directly.
The city of Las Vegas
is not going to finance
a ransom.
It's-it's against
department policy
to negotiate with terrorists.
No exceptions.
( clears throat )
Judge Stokes, Mrs. Stokes,
Gil Grissom.
Your Honor. Mrs. Stokes.
I'm, uh, sorry that
we're meeting under
these circumstances.
Have you been able
to make contact
with the animals
who took my son?
No, we haven't yet, but...
they should be contacting us
in roughly four hours.
We were able to rustle up
$20,000 cash.
Our bank's prepared
to wire another $100,000.
Now, we can sell the cars.
We can hock the ranch...
We can make the number,
but it's gonna take
at least another day.
Can we give them
Judge Stokes...
the money we have now,
try to buy more time?
I don't think that will help.
There's got to be
something we can do.
You've already done it
by coming here,
by showing your support...
We're not here
to show support.
We're here to
get Nick home.
We're not sure
who has your son...
...or why.
Well...
what the hell do you know?
Very little.
Let's just cut to the gist.
What proof do you have
that my boy's still alive?
( device beeping )
( beeping continues )
( sighs )
Oh, Poncho...
what the hell
you got yourself into?
( beeping )
You should have seen
this town
in the early '70s.
Gamblers were kings.
Yeah, not the
same anymore.
Showgirls
were showgirls.
Everybody knew your name
in those days.
You could dress
up in drag, huh?
Me, dress up in drag?
Who do you think
you're talking to, Jack Lemmon?
( laughter )
That's good.
Anyway, we had a good time
in those days, you know?
You could walk down the streets
in this town
15, 20 years ago
with 50,000 bucks
stacked on the top
of your head
in singles, and nobody
would bother you.
Except this guy.
He would bother you.
( laughing )
It's either your money
or it's my money.
Hey, w-w-w-w-w-w...
I gave you that line.
It's bad enough
you're on top
of that casino
saying, "Come
into my place."
That's the other guy--
the richer one.
Take it easy.
Easy? What do
you mean easy?
You talking
about yourself
( as Rodney Dangerfield ):
or her?
I'll tell you,
if she's easy,
I've got my
whole day planned.
You ought to come
and see my show, Tony.
I invited Jack
Nicholson; he said,
( as Nicholson ):
"I'd rather stick
needles in my eyes."
( laughter )
( as Dangerfield ):
What do you think of that?
( laughter )
Weren't we in The Vikings
together?
( as Burt Lancaster ):
Oh, I remember it well, Tony.
CURTIS:
That's the best
Burt Lancaster
I ever heard.
( laughter )
Sam?
( as Ed Sullivan ):
Oh, miss,
I like my coffee
with cream and sugar,
and I want you to give
the really big check
to really big
Sam over here.
Sam, I need to talk to you.
He's already got
someone to talk to, ma'am.
Zip it, sweetheart. Sam...
Everyone, I'd like for you
to meet my daughter, Catherine.
( as Sullivan ):
Well, you can
cancel the coffee.
Excuse us for a minute,
all right?
CURTIS:
Certainly.
One of my guys
is in trouble.
He's been kidnapped.
I need a million
dollars in cash.
Large bills.
And I need it now.
Let me guess, Mugs.
The department
won't pay the ransom.
No.
Why should I?
Considering the problems
that you've had with the law,
you could use
some good publicity.
Do I look like a man
that needs publicity?
If you're coming to me
like a cop
with a tin cup in your hand,
the answer is no.
I'm not here as a cop.
Then ask me
like you were my daughter.
I got the money.
From where?
Where do you think?
Catherine, if the press
finds out about this,
it'll look like Sam Braun
bribed the lab.
He's a casino owner.
A leader of industry.
Never convicted of any crime.
And right now, I don't care
about the integrity of the lab
at the moment.
I care about Nick.
Yeah, well, so do I,
but nonetheless...
Well, you're
sitting here
like Jack Handy
with your deep thoughts,
staring at a coffee cup.
You got a better plan,
I'm all ears.
( exhales )
All right.
But I make the drop.
You're hands off.
That's my money.
You can't be seen
anywhere near this money.
It was given to the lab
anonymously.
Agreed?
Agreed.
Las Vegas Crime Lab.
MAN:
Through the door.
Pretty quiet outside.
Almost sounds like
you came alone.
I've got your money.
Put it down.
Slide it over.
You're telling me
there's a million dollars
in here.
Yes.
Along with some cute
little booby traps?
Which is it--
a tracer, a dye pack?
Normally, you'd be 100% right,
but this time,
you're 100% wrong.
We want Nick back, no tricks.
( chuckling softly )
This looks real.
It is real.
Where is Nick?
You know,
I was under the impression
it was against
departmental policy
to negotiate with terrorists.
Are you a terrorist?
Depends.
Are you terrified?
Look, I really don't want
to talk to you.
Where is my guy?
Oh, so... he is your guy, huh?
Yes, he is.
Where is he buried?
Are you two close?
That's none of your business.
What does Nick Stokes
mean to you?
How do you feel when you see him
in that coffin?
Does your soul die
every time you push that button?
How do you feel,
knowing that there's
nothing you can do
to get him out of that hell?
Helpless...
useless...
impotent?
Good.
Welcome to my world.
Uh, if I were you,
I'd back up a little.