Lab's only got
one case tonight.
Why'd you bag that?
I didn't.
That's not Nick's evidence.
Maybe it's a message.
Nick could be anywhere
from Green Valley
to Seven Hills to Arizona.
Guy comes in here with
a package with
no return address.
It's about Nick.
MAN ( on recorder ):
Hi, CSI guy.
You wondering why you're here?
Because you followed
the evidence.
( screaming )
WILLOWS:
I don't think he knows
we can see him.
If they're going to keep him
alive for 12 hours,
it must mean that he's going
to have additional air supply.
GRISSOM:
The feed stays active
for two minutes
every time you press
the "Watch" button.
BROWN:
I say we keep the light on.
I got called out
to a pickup on Viking Circle.
I just found
an abandoned package
with some cash taped to it.
Yeah, the address
was a waste of time.
The guy probably
picked the house
at random 'cause he knew
we'd chase it.
Has Nick's family been informed?
That would be my job.
GRISSOM:
We're not sure
who has your son.
What the hell do you know?
Aw, Poncho.
What the hell
you got yourself into?
The City of Las Vegas is not
going to finance a ransom.
I need a million dollars
and I need it now.
If you're coming to me
like a cop
with a tin cup in your hand,
the answer is no.
If the press
finds out about this,
it'll look like Sam Braun
bribed the lab.
You got a better plan,
I'm all ears!
MAN:
What does Nick Stokes
mean to you?
Does your soul die
every time you push that button?
Welcome to my world.
( indistinct police radio
transmissions )
Pupils are even.
He blew himself up and
left us with nothing.
Sir, are you experiencing
any ringing in your ears?
We got the kidnapper's truck.
Nevada tags:
374-Robert-Charlie-David.
Run the plate.
That's the wrong box, Greg.
Well, pick one.
There's three.
That one right there.
Give me a break.
I haven't done
this before.
All right, let's go over it
again.
The diagnostic unit
gets attached to that black box,
which gives us the mileage
of his last trip.
Like an airplane.
That gives us the radius
for the search area.
Right.
Got it.
23 miles...
and we know he was heading east
on the 215.
I'll get a map.
Somebody bag this
money, please?
Don't get any funny
ideas, either.
( sighs )
What I had to do
to get this money and for what.
There's no I.D. on him.
( indistinct radio transmission)
I got a thumb.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
How's he doing?
Hard to say.
About the same, I guess.
I'm gonna get
some coffee.
Yeah.
( air fan goes on )
( beep )
( sighs )
Enough with the...
Enough with the damn light!
( panting )
( sighs )
( low whirring )
( low humming )
No.
The fan's connected...
The fan's connected
to the light.
( sighs )
♪ ♪
( air fan stops )
No.
( panting )
( groans softly )
( groans )
( panting )
What are you doing, Nicky?
( groans )
Don't do it, Nicky!
( gunshots, groan )
You son of a bitch!
( Nick laughing )
( panting )
( laughing )
( sighs, panting )
Oh.
You're still alive.
JOHNSON:
The light and the fan
must have been running
off the same battery.
Well, at least
Nicky's keeping it together.
That's good.
What about the Web cam trace?
Signal's running
through an anonymizer.
Different ISP each time
we click the button.
I think I've got a handle
on the pattern. Getting closer.
( water splashing )
Sara?
I got something off your thumb.
So when you struck out
on prints,
I ran DNA through CODIS,
hoping maybe the guy
was in the system
off an open case
or a prior felony.
I got no straight-up
match, but...
But you got a moderate
stringency match
for a Kelly Gordon.
Yeah, seven alleles in common,
and based on the age,
I'd say it was his daughter.
Good work, Mia.
SIDLE:
Kelly Gordon
is currently in state
prison serving year three
of a five-year sentence
for accessory to murder.
The address of her crime scene
is 625 Viking Circle.
That's the same place
where the messenger
picked up the package.
It wasn't random.
Hey, baby, let's go.
Hi. How ya doin'?
( two gunshots )
Neither was the Styrofoam cup.
So at trial, you testified
that you went
with your boyfriend
to visit a buddy of his.
And when you went in the house,
your boyfriend blew
the guy away.
He wasn't my boyfriend.
I knew the guy two weeks.
Why am I here?
SIDLE:
A Styrofoam cup
with your DNA on it
was found in that house.
You claimed you dropped it
running for your life.
My word against a cup,
and the next five years,
I'm being traded for cigarettes
by my cell mate.
You're not reopening my case.
What do you want?
Your father took
it pretty hard.
He was an aerospace
engineer, right?
Good with explosives?
So, this is about my dad?
( sighs )
You know, we got
your visitors log.
Your father stopped
coming to see you
six weeks into your sentence.
Seeing your daughter turned
into some...
...hood rat's lesbian sex slave
can be rather emotional.
Why did he come see you
last week?
Did you know
what he was planning to do?
I don't know.
What did he do?
He kidnapped a
friend of mine.
A CSI.
And then he blew himself up.
Tried to take some
cops with him.
How many did he get?
Hey, we're all still here.
Nick is still
missing.
Who's Nick?
The CSI is still
missing.
Do you know where he is?
That's pretty funny--
you guys not being able
to find something.
BRASS:
Yeah, look,
if you cooperate,
we can get
your sentence reduced.
You know what I used to do
before this?
Back when I was alive?
I used to grow things.
Outside.
I was studying horticulture.
Flowers.
My cell mate, Trish,
gave me one for Valentine's day.
Want to smell it?
I hope your friend dies.
♪ It was Christmas
in Las Vegas ♪
♪ When the locals
take the town ♪
♪ Teresa hit a streak ♪
♪ And laid
her waitress apron down ♪
♪ She was playing penny poker ♪
♪ Over at the old Gold Spike ♪
♪ She tired of Texas Hold 'Em ♪
♪ So she switched
to Let It Ride... ♪
( indistinct police radio
transmissions )
Hey, I found a trigger wire.
Maybe...
once we reassemble
all the components,
we'll be able to tell
where the bomb came from.
Maybe...
Yeah, maybe, maybe, maybe.
Maybe if
we count up
all the damn "maybes,"
maybe Nick will be alive!
You know what
I'm saying?!
Was that necessary?
Never mind my clothes.
Look at the evidence.
Damn it.
Sorry, Greg.
I'll go talk to him.
Hey, Warrick, hey.
Hey, how you holding up?
I'm not.
I know.
I just can't help but thinking
that could have been me
in that box, you know?
We flipped a coin
for that trash run.
Hey, Nick is not inside a box
because of the flip of a coin.
If that was me,
I would have...
Hey, you know what?
I know you.
I don't believe that.
Okay?
No. You're wrong.
I wouldn't have
lasted this far.
Catherine, if something
happens to Nick,
if we don't bring him
back in one piece...
SANDERS:
Hey, guys, come here.
I found something.
Look at this.
There's something
underneath there.
Oh, it's got an edge
right here.
All right.
Another one over here.
WILLOWS:
Greg, get
some crowbars.
SANDERS:
Do you think Nick
could be under here?
I don't know, man.
It would have to be
at least six feet long.
( grunting )
Yeah, but if he buried
him lengthwise--
and who's to
say he didn't--
he could be.
( scraping, gravel falling )
Hey!
I'm in here!
( creaking )
Hey!
♪ It was Christmas
in Las Vegas ♪
♪ When the locals
take the town... ♪
( gravel falling )
♪ Teresa hit a streak ♪
♪ And laid
her waitress apron down... ♪
I hit something.
( thumping with shovel )
♪ She was playing penny poker ♪
♪ Over at
the old Gold Spike... ♪
I'm here.
It's Plexiglas.
Nick!
Nick?
Hey, I'm right here!
WARRICK:
Nick, hold on there, buddy!
Nick?
WILLOWS:
It's a dog.
( panting )
( Plexiglas cracking )
( cracking continues )
( panting )
( softly ):
Stop, stop...
( cracking continues )
( quietly ):
Oh, my God.
( owl hooting )
♪ ♪
( cracking,
dirt slowly pouring )
( clicks recorder button )
My name is Nick Stokes.
If anyone... finds this tape,
turn it in
to the Las Vegas... PD.
There should be a reward.
Mom,
( voice cracking ):
Sisko...
...well, this is a lousy way
to say good-bye,
but it's all I got.
I love you.
You raised me right...
and I'm going to miss you.
As for the rest of you guys,
I know you did
the best you could to find me.
Grissom...
No, you never did, Nick.
He's going into convulsions.
He's losing it.
What's going on?
Wha...?
Wait a minute.
Ants.
My God, he's being eaten alive.
( agonized screaming )
( ants chittering )
( groaning )
( cloth tearing )
That's it, Nicky.
Stay still.
They won't bite.
As much.
This has got
to be a prototype.
It was probably built to test
how long he could keep
somebody alive inside.
Now, what are those?
I don't know.
All right,
based on this battery
and what's running off of it,
and the fact that
we kept the damn light on
for as long as we did,
I figure Nick's got another
90 minutes left in there.
( beeps )
GRISSOM:
Oh, come on, pal.
Yeah.
That's it.
Come on.
Little more.
Keep coming.
Show me what you're made of.
Come on, buddy.
Gotcha.
Solenopsis invicta.
They're fire ants,
very rare in Nevada.
They don't like our soil.
The only places
you find them around Vegas
are in plant
and tree nurseries.
There's 11 nurseries in
the greater Las Vegas area.
Okay, I've got the Web cam trace
down to here.
And the data
from the black box
in Walter Gordon's truck
gave us a 23-mile
travel radius.
Okay, I've got two nurseries
within the overlap area.
Here and here.
SIDLE:
Wait, wait.
wait, wait.
Kelly Gordon, the daughter,
worked with plants.
Hold on. Hold on.
You guys,
Nick is here.
( sirens blaring )
You said on the phone
you had a fire ant mound.
Where is it?
People usually
prefer
to stay away from it.
All right, look.
Fan out.
Look for loose soil.
Anything that might've
been dug up recently.
That's the whole place.
( indistinct shouting )
( electronic humming )
( all talking )
( loud, squeaky static )
Hey!
I'm picking up
the Web cam transmitter.
MAN:
She's got something!
Move! Move!
( beeping )
( thump )
( rapid beeping )
This is it! I found it!
It's here.
I found it!
This is it!
Nick!
Nick, we're here. Hang on!
( echoing ):
Nicky!
( groaning )
( heart beating )
It's a damn shame they
didn't get to him sooner.
PHILLIPS:
I sure will
miss him.
You know, David,
I've seen fire ant bites
in my time, but never
anything like this.
Do you think
he suffered?
Do I think
Yes.
Definitely.
( laughing )
All right.
( clears throat )
On three.
Uno...
Dos...
Tres!
♪ It was Christmas
in Las Vegas... ♪
All right. Would you care
to do the "Y" incision?
Well, "Y"
not?
♪ ...And laid her
waitress apron down ♪
♪ She was playing penny poker
over at the old Gold Spike... ♪
ROBBINS:
Mind your
hands and feet.
( saw whirring )
♪ ...She rode it up the strip
to where the flashy hotels are ♪
Yes...
♪ At first she hit a royal,
not a dirty one this time... ♪
( grunts )
He won't be needing
this anymore.
( song continues )
Nice.
A lung.
JUDGE STOKES:
So, Doc.
How did my son die?
Anaphylactic shock?
No, no, he didn't live
long enough for that.
COD was
asphyxiation.
Oh.
When the blood oxygen
drops to less than 16%
and the CO2 builds up,
there's a rapid loss
of consciousness.
Death within minutes.
With no disfiguring
physical findings.
He'll look great
at the funeral.
Oh, yes.
His mother will
appreciate that.
Good.
( heart beating )
Your son had
a good heart.
( beeping )
( grunts )
( sobbing )
( screams weakly )
( grunting )
I hit something.
WILLOWS:
We got you, Nicky.
( grunts )
( screams weakly )
( whimpering )
BROWN:
Hey!
We got you, man.
Hey, Nicky!
Nicky! Yeah. Hey, hold on there.
Hey, put that down.
Put that down.
We got you.
We're gonna get
you out of here.
Hang in there.
Oh, my God.
We need that fire extinguisher!
Give me that fire extinguisher.
These ants are getting
at him, man.
( indistinct voices )
Oh.
GRISSOM:
Short bursts, Greg.
Don't suffocate him!
Hang on, buddy.
Hang on. Almost out of there.
Get the paramedics!
BROWN:
Hang on. Hang on.
We're gonna
kill those ants.
Okay?
( mumbles indistinctly )
Yeah.
( phone rings )
Willows.
Yeah. Hey, boss...
We found him.
We're getting him out now.
That's great. Wai-Wait.
Don't-Don't hang up.
Just-just listen.
What? What?
Those dimples on the bottom
of the prototype;
GCMS found traces
of SEMTEX on each one.
You got to be kidding me.
BROWN:
One, two,
three.
WILLOWS:
Everyone out
of the hole.
That box is ready to explode!
Are you kidding?
WILLOWS:
Get out of
there now!
I'm not leaving without Nick.
WILLOWS:
There are charges
under the box!
BROWN:
I'm not leaving here
without him.
GRISSOM:
Warrick,
Catherine's right.
Get out of
the hole now.
I know what
we're gonna do.
Just trust me.
( screaming )
Help!
We need 200 pounds of dirt
over here right now,
and we're gonna use
that backhoe to get it.
( muffled screaming )
Nick!
Can you hear me?
It's gonna take us a minute
to get you out of there, okay?
Nick!
Poncho!
Listen to me.
Put your hand on my hand.
Good.
Now listen.
There may be explosives
under the box.
They're probably set
on pressure switches.
We need to equalize
your body weight
before we can pull you out,
okay?
Poncho, nod your head
if you understand me.
Okay, we're gonna use
the dirt from the backhoe
to equalize his weight.
I need a rope
and a caribiner.
MAN:
You got it.
All right, Poncho,
we're gonna open the lid
and get you out,
but I need you
to stay lying down.
Okay?
Or else you'll blow us all up.
Do you understand that?
STOKES:
Yeah, yeah.
Do you promise?
Poncho, say, "I promise."
I promise.
Bring it over.
This way.
Don't move.
( sobbing )
I got you, I got you,
I got you...
Stay still.
( panting ):
Okay, okay, okay.
All right, bring that over.
Okay, Poncho,
I want you
to close your eyes
and hold your breath.
Now!
Ready?
Go!
( explosion )
♪ ♪
( indistinct voices )
over dispatch )
( sighs )
I want my guys back.
♪ ♪
You the one?
Yeah.
( clears throat )
Yeah, back at you.
What do you want me to say?
I'm sorry?
No, you didn't
do anything to me.
And what your dad did, I...
I guess it's 'cause
he loves you so much.
Hey, Kelly.
Kelly.
Pick it up.
In a few years...
when you get out of here...
don't take it with you.
That's it?
Yeah.
Yeah, that's it.
We're done.
( sighs )
( chuckles softly )