( thunder rumbling )
( footsteps splashing )
( shutter clicking )
Who found him?
The police
were sweeping the area
looking for vagrants,
trying to keep 'em
above water.
Take a look at his nose.
Same thing with his chin...
His elbows...
And his knees.
He lost all his points.
Like a rock in a tumbler.
I'm sorry I'm late.
Stopped to get
my waders.
No wallet.
Hold on.
What do you think?
I'll get it to Narco.
Take a look.
Cause of death?
Water pressure
could have done it.
Or a person.
( shutter clicks )
Hey.
Whoo!
It's a mess.
I've talked
to every
resident in the area.
No one knows this guy.
No unaccounted‐for vehicles.
I don't know
what to tell you.
Well, at least we know
where he came from.
Aren't we at least
gonna draw straws?
No.
BROWN:
We must be under
the freeway by now.
Hey.
Did I ever tell you
that the city paid me
a dollar a square foot
to rip out my lawn
and replace it with rocks
because we're in a drought?
Are you
kidding me?
No.
This city was not made for rain.
Catherine.
Grissom.
We got another body.
( gasping )
I was taking a nap.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh‐oh‐oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
I'm real tired, okay?
I just want to
get some sleep.
I understand,
I understand.
Listen, I need
to ask you a question.
Have you ever seen
this guy right here?
No.
You don't know him?
No, someone comes down here
that don't belong,
I mean, bad stuff
can happen, okay?
I‐I‐I just want
to go home, okay?
A‐a‐and you can't make me
leave my house.
Nobody's making you
do anything, okay?
Now, you like coffee?
Well, yeah,
as long as it's a decaf,
one sugar, two cream, no skim,
and hot‐‐ your lawsuit hot.
Okay, you go
with that officer over there.
He'll get you a nice cup
of coffee, all right?
( sighs )
( rustling )
Is that you, Warrick?
There you are.
Phew.
Is that a sneaker?
Looks like an Aquasock.
Yeah.
Here's its mate.
Kind of upscale
for a tunnel rat.
So the vic
was barefoot.
The tunnel's
full of murder weapons.
Bum kills him, or finds
the body and takes the socks?
What was the guy doing here
in the first place?
Well, maybe the vic was some
punk, uh... with an attitude.
Decided to take it out
on some homeless guy.
You never know.
It happens.
The way the body
was ground down
means that the water took him
for a pretty long ride.
Well, we're already wet, so...
( sighs )
Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah.
WILLOWS:
Excuse me!
Down here!
Oh.
What's your problem, sweetie?
Uh, no problem, sir.
I'm just wanting to know
what street I'm on. Under.
Oh, it's, uh, Industrial.
You're just south of Tropicana.
Thank you.
And I'm not holding the bus.
Don't bother.
All right, so we're
about a mile south
of where we started.
Well, there's 300
miles of storm drains
in Clark County, so we
only have 299 to go.
What, do we, uh,
eenie‐meenie‐minie‐mo it?
Split up? What do we do?
No, that's
a dead end.
Sunscreen on a lanyard.
Fits with the Aquasocks.
I say we keep
going upstream.
I knew you were
gonna say that.
Don't hit your head.
I'm gonna need the drain pan.
This town isn't
built for rain, hmm?
( buzzing )
( grinding )
( gristle tearing )
( grunts )
Come on, don't be shy.
Take a good look.
In the end...
it's all we really are.
If you're gonna be sick,
Greg, do it in the sink.
Not in the drain pan.
I don't feel sick.
Take a look at the trachea.
What do you see?
Foam.
Like the head of a beer.
Sorry.
No. It's a good analogy.
Pulmonary edema, fluids
in the air passages.
So he drowned?
Well, doesn't prove it.
Same thing happens with, uh,
heart failure or drug overdose.
But the fact that
the heart of the victim
was a normal size,
and assuming tox doesn't
show drug overdose,
C.O.D. is most likely drowning,
but I'm not gonna rule out
blunt‐force trauma.
( buzzing )
Daylight. Finally.
We gotta be into some
golden time by now, right?
Oh, yeah. For real.
( sighs )
Ka‐ching, Ka‐ching.
What do we have here?
Brain bucket.
Hang on to that.
Hey, it's our dead guy.
No way.
Calvin Berkowitz.
Worked at the Tangiers.
Lifeguard.
So what's Calvin
doing down here?
It's an inner tube.
Yeah?
Guy gets the day off
and decides to go surfing...
Vegas style.
Oh, I heard about that.
He grabs an inner tube, a
helmet, jumps into the channel.
Hits his head
on something, drowns.
So it takes him down.
That would account
for all that body trauma.
This isn't about drugs
or beating up homeless dudes.
It's just plain stupidity.
( snorts )
Well, that's
what happens
when you don't have
a decent beach in Vegas.
Hey, you know something?
This is, uh, right around
where I found Lindsay.
Really?
Yeah, when Eddie's car
went off the road.
Ugh... Let's just
get out of here.
Can you take that?
( sighs )
Watch your step.
Hey.
Oh.
( laughing )
You all right?
Yeah, I think.
Whoa.
MAN:
Hey!
You guys CSI?
Yeah.
Well, the city's been
rehabbing manholes
with fiberglass liners.
All the hydrogen
sulfide down there
really eats up
the concrete.
Anyways, we, uh, pulled
these out of the main.
We find a lot of small
animal bones down there,
squirrels, cats,
rats, you know.
but that's really
tiny stuff.
This looks more like people.
Fingers or toes,
or fingers and toes.
Well, animal bones can fool you.
Pig's feet or sheep ribs
are not much different
from yours or mine.
Flaky texture.
Probably a couple years old.
( sighs )
Yep. We're gonna have
to flush the line.
You guys get a lot of jokes
about this thing?
What do you think?
( beeping )
Vactor's in place.
Ready when you are.
Rip it.
Let's go.
Warrick.
Yo.
I got some bones here.
Anything distinctive?
Yeah. I got part of a rib.
Uh‐huh. I can see
the costal groove.
And it's too deep
to be an animal's.
These bones are human.
This is the sewage vault
where they found the bones.
How do we know the bones just
didn't wash off the street?
Well, wastewater sewage
is a closed system.
It's completely separate
from the storm drains.
Someone must have flushed it
down a toilet, a sink, a tub,
or tossed them directly
into a manhole.
And the bones look pretty old,
so it could just be
from a grave robber
getting rid of his leftovers.
Or a serial killer
with a lot of patience.
200,000 service connections,
serving half a million
residences.
1,600 miles of pipe,
gravity fed.
If we're gonna find
where the bones came from,
we gotta work our way up.
Catherine.
Recovered more bones.
Oh.
Pelvis fragment
and two humerus.
Well, large bones wouldn't
travel down the line
as far as the small ones,
so at least we're getting closer
to the source.
WARRICK:
These plumbers must be working
overtime.
Lots of backed up toilets.
I don't think the bones
could have come
from any one of these houses.
Residential sewer lines
are only four‐inch pipes.
Okay.
And they make
a 90‐degree turn
before they connect
to the main.
Look at the size
of these bones.
Yeah.
They're too big
to make a turn like that.
Right. So the blockage has gotta
be from the main line.
One more vault down the street.
( groans )
Jackpot.
( coughs )
Oh, man.
I'll go check it out.
( gasps )
It's like
a waterline stain.
Hand me my florazene
and my glasses, please.
Uh.
Florazene
reacts to feces
as well as blood,
so I know that you're not
looking for blood.
No. These vaults
are built big
for access.
They're not reservoirs.
Water's supposed to stay down
in the pipes.
And the only way the water
would rise
is if there's something
blocking the pipe.
Mm‐hmm.
And loose bones
wouldn't do that.
But a whole body would.
Water rises, submerges the body.
WILLOWS:
Tissue decomposes
until there's not enough body
left to withstand the pressure.
( sighs )
I don't think we're looking
for a grave robber.
We're looking for a murderer.
ROBBINS:
Femur measurements make your
victim around five foot six.
Pubic arch, mm,
sharply angled,
less than 90‐degrees,
indicates male.
I'll send it to Greg.
He might be able to pull DNA.
Look at this.
Incise defect
on the left fifth rib.
on the left third rib.
GRISSOM:
Well, the tool marks
appear consistent
with each other.
Probably made
before decomposition,
and not from hitting any
obstruction in the sewer line.
Stab wounds.
Two separate strikes
back to front
would have punctured the lung.
What about age?
I'll let you know.
Okay, let's start with the
houses within eyeshot
of the manhole,
and then we'll work our way out
from there. Hmm? Okay.
You really, really ought
to have the one
with chocolate icing.
Hello, Officer.
Oh, dear.
Detective.
Detective. Sorry, I...
Uh, just a little something
for you and your boys,
uh, a token of appreciation
for local law enforcement.
You mind standing
behind the tape?
It's for your own safety.
There you go.
Go ahead.
Coffee's fresh.
Didn't even spit in it.
( laughs )
Not that I ever would.
I, I love cops.
What's your name?
Marty, uh, Martin Kessler.
I live here...
there, right over there,
number 2305.
So, uh, does this have anything
to do with the missing cats?
People have lost
a lot of pets
in this neighborhood.
Too many,
if you get my drift.
Well, you know, Marty,
I'm really not at
liberty to say.
But did you see anybody throw
any stuff down that sewer?
Not personally,
but, uh, I know kids around here
throw fireworks...
illegal, down there.
Kaboom! Kaboom!
4:00 in the morning.
Kids have no respect
for the law.
I heard you finally lost
your virginity.
First autopsy. How was it?
It was fine.
How was your first time?
How did you react?
I puked.
I didn't puke.
Way to go, tough guy.
It was weird, seeing a body
laying on a table like that.
Doc Robbins just pulling out
his insides
until it was all empty.
Were you expecting
a ball of light?
Doc Robbins said,
"That's all we really are."
It's what you do
with it that counts.
Victim had
incomplete formation
of the second molar
root tips,
and his wisdom teeth
hadn't erupted.
Teenager.
Yeah, approximately
13 to 15.
Eye orbits rounded,
almost oval.
Nasal aperture
narrow and tall,
jawline flat.
Likely Caucasian.
Uh, dental records
are out to NCIC.
That's all I've got.
How'd Greg do?
Bones are too degraded.
No viable DNA,
not even in the teeth.
Well, it's a bit of a long shot.
Sewer's a chemical stew.
Maybe Catherine
will get lucky with
Missing Persons.
STOKES:
Okay, I opened the age range
to give us a better margin
for error.
Currently 47
male Caucasians
between the age
of 12 and 16
missing from the Greater
Las Vegas Metro district.
Okay. Geography first?
Mm‐hmm.
Body was found here.
These are the last‐known
residences
of the missing persons.
There's no one
particularly close.
I'll narrow it down.
Two‐mile radius.
Missing five weeks,
eleven weeks,
eleven months.
That's not long enough.
The condition of the bones
suggested
the body's been decomposing
for at least two years.
Okay, I'll go wider.
Five miles.
What are you doing?
Good. You're here.
Fill this up
for me, will ya?
With what?
It's a urine specimen cup, Greg.
What do you think?
( scoffs )
Okay.
That took a long time.
You may need a prostate exam.
My prostate is just fine.
I'm not a soda fountain.
Hopefully you are,
'cause I need a number two
as quickly as possible.
What is this all about?
The victim's body was found
in a sewer.
Ambient temperature 80 degrees.
The corrosive chemicals caused
the body
to decompose faster than normal.
I want to find out
how much faster.
Today.
This is some kind of CSI hazing.
Make me appreciate blood
and semen more.
I mean, since we don't
have a solid time frame,
it's kind of tough
to jog memories.
But nobody saw anybody
throw anything like a
body down that manhole.
But several people suggested
we talk to this high school kid,
Owen Durbin.
Now, he's a neighborhood bully.
He likes to throw cherry bombs
in there and hear 'em go boom.
Uh, guys, how are
we supposed to get
through the door?
There's no evidence
linking this kid
to the bones.
We're not looking for bones.
Illegal use of fireworks?
This is crap.
We've had several complaints
from your neighbors, sir.
No one's complained to me.
Well, ( chuckles )
this is gonna happen,
so please step outside.
Ask your family
to come with you.
Thank you.
Come on, guys.
Let's go.
Anything happens
in here,
it's your fault.
Okay.
Whoa.
Lot of ammo here,
all different caliber.
Means multiple weapons
are present... somewhere.
BROWN:
Yeah?
I got a shotgun
under the couch.
Oh, yeah.
Loaded.
( dogs barking )
Sounds like we got
some nasty dogs out back.
I think I got blood.
( dogs barking )
Confirmed.
Okay. I'm gonna get
the warrant amended
for blood evidence collection.
Until then...
We stop searching.
Won't take long,
so hang loose.
And I'll get
the Animal Control
to get these mutts
out of here.
So, uh, no searching.
Yeah, right.
That closet's well stocked, huh?
Sara?
I'm not touching anything.
No. Put your stuff down
and step away from the closet.
What?
Put down your stuff
and step away
from the closet.
SIDLE:
Those are pipe bombs.
Yeah.
( walkie talkie beeps )
Dispatch...
this is CSI Brown.
We're at the Durbin
residence.
We have explosives
on the scene.
Roll out Bomb Squad immediately.
Roll out Bomb Squad.
What are you doing?
There's blood evidence
on the door.
If the bomb squad
detonates the place,
it's gone.
Sara.
It'll only take a second.
Here, try this.
( light whirring )
( screw plunks on floor )
Nice.
( light whirring )
( plunk )
( whirring )
It's stuck.
I think we're gonna
need a little push.
( sighs ):
All right.
On three.
One...
two...
three.
( slight creaking )
Can we get the hell
out of dodge now?
( garbled radio transmission )
( camera clicking )
Let's go over again
what you found on the scene.
Six pipe bombs.
Anything else?
Not that we know of.
Give me another 50 yards, okay!
That includes you.
You got it.
BRASS:
So tell me something...
what's a guy who
sells life insurance
doing with a half
a dozen pipe bombs?
Huh?
I mean, you got a grudge
against the government?
Is this a Timothy
McVeigh thing?
Or... you just have
a weird fascination
with watching things go boom?
I've never been
arrested for anything.
I've never hurt anybody.
You got a wife and a kid.
Aren't you afraid
they might get hurt?
Well, I don't know about you,
but in my house, there's rules.
Terry and Owen know what to do
and what not to do.
BRASS:
Well, clearly you don't.
The bombs are a Class‐B felony.
The penalty is one
to six years in prison
for each device.
And murder is 25 to life.
Somebody gets blown up,
it's nothing to do with me.
I told you
not to go in my house.
We found blood
in your house.
Then you must have put it there.
Oh, yeah?
How about this?
We found a body in the sewer
in front of your house.
Did we put
that there?
I don't know anything about it.
So what were you trying
to prove with this door?
I was just
collecting evidence.
Well, Greg couldn't pull
any DNA from the bones,
so there's nothing to connect
the victim to this anyway.
Not yet.
I don't have a death wish,
and I'm not a drunk,
in case you were worried.
I'm not worried.
I'm concerned.
Isn't that kind of
the same thing?
Oh...
GRISSOM:
How are you doing
with victim ID?
So far we've followed up
on 11 missing persons
who fit the profile,
ruled out every one
by case history.
What's the most
recent case?
Well, we're only
looking at people
who've been missing
more than a year.
The condition of
the bones...
Was misleading.
Tissue in a sewer decomposes
20 times faster than normal.
The victim could be missing
as little as five weeks.
( computer blips )
Are we clear to get back
in there?
We're not through.
We swept the house
for booby traps.
It was clean, but we still
haven't done a full search yet.
Well, why don't you
clear an area
and we'll process behind you.
Scene will still be under
my authority.
I don't have a problem
with authority.
Fire in the hole!
This is Travis's
ninth grade picture.
His father, my son,
was a punk.
He, uh, skipped out
just after Travis was born.
His mother's in Salt Lake.
She's a junkie.
The only time
she ever called Travis
was to use him
to get money out of me.
I mean, she can barely take care
of herself, let alone a kid.
You know how many times
I told him that.
Well, most of the time
kids believe
what they want to believe,
you know.
Did he run off to see his mom?
Mm. Yeah, it wasn't
the first time.
He's, uh... About six weeks ago,
I come home to a note.
So I called his mom, and...
He just never,
he never showed up.
Ms. Giles, do you, uh,
do you recognize this boy?
No.
No?
Mm‐mm.
Do you have anything of Travis's
he might have used on his body?
Like a toothbrush, hairbrush,
anything like that?
No, he took all that kind of
thing with him when he left.
Mmm.
Why?
Well, it would help
if I could get a sample
of Travis's DNA.
Look...
( sighs )
ma'am, I don't really
know how to say this...
Don't bother.
I know he's dead.
Is this a classmate of yours,
Owen?
No.
Okay, let's try that again.
You two went to the same middle
school, right?
Maybe. I guess.
You guess. Were you friends?
I know my son's friends.
That's not one of them.
Mrs. Durbin,
may I speak with you
for a minute in private?
Excuse us, Owen.
You know, sometimes kids
get self‐conscious
around their parents.
Maybe it would be better
if I spoke to Owen by myself.
He'll have an
advocate present
to make sure his rights
are respected. Okay?
I'm not leaving my son
alone with you.
My husband
wouldn't like that.
Medium‐velocity spatter.
This looks like the point
of origin.
( dialing phone )
Yeah, this is Catherine Willows
for Captain Brass.
Tell me about the blood
in your house.
Blood? Where?
Well, the top of the
stairs for starters.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
You do.
I don't.
Maybe it's the dogs'.
When they go upstairs sometimes,
sometimes they fight.
They fight a lot.
SIDLE:
Animal Control said the Durbins'
pit bulls showed no signs
of recent injury.
Dogs heal fast.
I guess I'll go back to the lab
and get a hematrace.
Don't bother.
( sighs )
The lowest point of spatter is
46 inches above the ground
with a downward angle.
Even if those dogs
could walk upright,
they couldn't have done this.
Kid's a liar.
( garbled radio transmission)
I'm not done yet.
Take your time.
Got some det
cord here.
Isn't that high explosive?
Stuff designed to be humped
around by grunts.
You gotta want it go off.
Only one thing you need
to worry about.
Ever see me running,
make sure you keep up.
Got it.
( shutter snaps )
GRISSOM:
Hey, Rick, watch your step.
This could be blood evidence
on the floor.
Okay, Grissom,
I located some
burnt clothes
in a barrel
out in the back.
I'm thinking he was killed
in the house,
dragged out back
and then dumped.
GRISSOM:
He might have been dragged
in here.
Make sure you bag that stuff.
Yeah, I'm all over it.
Don't touch a thing.
Get out now.
Uh, I think I have
some evidence back here.
Clear out now.
Hey!
The garage is packed
with liquid explosives.
They're gonna detonate in place.
So grab what's important
and get out now.
That means you, too, Sara.
Right now.
MAN:
Fire in the hole!
Sons of bitches!
I'm gonna sue your ass
into the ground.
I hope you know that.
Yeah. I'm gonna own you.
I'm gonna own this whole place.
In fact, maybe that's where
I'll live.
I'm just gonna
move in here.
Let me guess.
He lawyered up.
Yeah, he stopped talking
after I told him
we blew up his house.
And what about the wife and son?
They're still in play.
How much longer
is anybody's guess.
But, uh, we need something more
to go back at them with.
Well, I think at this point
we can agree that the murder
weapon was a knife.
These are pictures of a box
of knives
that I was unable to recover
from the Durbin garage.
So how about the tool marks?
I cast the stab marks
in the victim's ribs.
Bone deterioration removed all
the individual characteristics.
The best we can do
is rule out the
serrated blade.
Hey, what about
the kid's videos?
Uh, no tape of the murder
or body he dumped so far.
I'm not holding my breath.
Videos cover several years.
Kid running around the house.
Backyard barbecue kind of stuff.
You know,
home movies.
A teenage boy with a shoe box
full of home movies
under his bed?
It's weird, I know.
I'm still looking.
Well, we know Owen went to
school with Travis Giles, right?
Well, that was a few years back,
and we still can't place Travis
at the house.
With all the fire damage,
the clothes are the right size,
but I couldn't get any blood
evidence off of it.
Even if we had that,
we still don't have
a blood standard for Travis.
I mean, we can't even positively
ID the victim.
Miss Giles? Hi.
What can I do for you?
I wasn't able to find a
hairbrush or a toothbrush,
but the only thing
I have left
of Travis's is...
this.
When he was little,
I used to be his tooth fairy.
DNA from Travis Giles' tooth
matched the blood
that we found in your house.
BRASS:
And now you're gonna
tell us how it got there.
I don't know.
Kids get hurt all the time.
They fall down,
cut themselves...
get nosebleeds.
BRASS:
Wait a minute.
What are you telling me,
that a kid
that you've never seen,
a kid who's not even friends
with your son,
got a nosebleed in your house?
Huh?
You're lying.
You know,
we can make this quick,
'cause I got enough
to arrest you right now.
Look, it was an accident.
All right,
Travis came over one night,
said he wanted to buy a knife.
So I gave him a knife.
He said he couldn't pay.
He tried to run.
Wasn't moving,
he was just lying there,
knife stuck in him.
Now you're lying.
Don't you call my son a liar.
Travis was stabbed twice.
That's not possible
if he just fell on the knife.
BRASS:
So what happened?
He piss you off?
Get in a fight?
Maybe called you
a mama's boy?
Or did you just want to see what
it felt like to stab somebody?
Like I told you,
it was an accident.
Then why did you dump the body
down a sewer
in the middle of the night?
He didn't.
He didn't do it alone.
We found the victim's charred
clothing folded.
Kids don't fold anything,
mothers do.
You helped him clean up
the mess.
Yeah, that's kind of funny,
because, um, you're not much
of a housekeeper.
If you talk to my mother
like that again,
I'll kill you.
Don't you say
another word, baby.
I'll kill both of you.
I want a lawyer.
Well, we really don't need
a confession.
Well, the kid gets murder,
mom's an accessory,
and Dad gets felony explosives.
It's a family‐value pack.
Well, it's appropriate.
One way or another,
they each had a hand in it.
MOTHER:
Come on, Roger.
Do we have to?
Just keep the camera on it,
will ya?
Watch.
( frog croaks )
( sharp bang )
( laughs )
Violent environment,
oblivious mother,
disturbed child.
Here, stir this.
What's it for?
Blowing stuff up.
( laughs )
But you know, no matter how bad
your kid turns out,
it never changes how you feel
about him.
Unconditional love between
parents and offspring
is biological,
perpetuates the species.
Go ahead.
That's good.
Get it good.