♪ ♪
Hide beetle.
This guy's been here
at least two weeks.
Number four
buckshot, maybe?
Well, his pockets are empty.
There's no wallet
or any other kind of ID.
What'd be the point
of blowing someone's face off
if you're going to leave
their driver's license?
CORONER:
Well, he's all yours.
Hey, Cath.
Grissom.
What's the deal?
You're coming
to my crime scenes
before I get
to them now?
Weren't you on
a 419 in North Town?
Guess you missed me.
I'm just documenting,
then I'm leaving.
Oh. Ew.
Lot of animal activity.
Well, out here,
I guess that's, uh,
rodents, coyote,
buzzards...
( shutter clicks )
occasional mountain lion.
What do we have here?
A little ice?
The end of Rainbow Canyon.
And this must be
the pot of gold.
Las Vegas...
Greenbacks?
BRASS:
American Football
Franchise Association.
That league folded
about 20 years ago.
Now, that's what I call
a rat hole.
Shotgun wounds
tend to be separate hits
from individual pellets.
But only if the shooter's
far enough
away from the target.
This guy was shot
at close range.
Right between the numbers.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me
who are you, you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
STOKES:
I don't get it.
Grissom calls me up,
I come out here, and I find you.
Things were a hell
of a lot simpler
when we were all
on the same shift.
You saying you don't
like me as your boss?
( shutter clicks )
Whatever.
I got a shot cup.
Doesn't make any sense,
'cause our vic was
definitely shot point blank.
Yeah, a shot cup coming
out of a shell
is like throwing a potato chip.
It doesn't really go that far.
Yeah.
( shutter clicks )
Another casing.
That's got to account for
at least two more shots.
Typical pump-action.
Holds four in the mag,
one in the pipe.
This was a chase.
( gun cocks )
We know where it ended, so...
let's find where it began.
There's not much out here to do
for a couple of guys,
other than hike or hunt.
And the vic wasn't
dressed for either.
STOKES:
So they were up
to no good.
Is that a trail
over there?
( Stokes chuckles )
What you got?
C-note in a beaver dam.
Hang on.
( shutter clicks )
Damn.
This beaver's doing nice work.
They should do a commercial
for the city.
Las Vegas--
where even the beaver
can strike it rich.
( footsteps approaching )
Please tell me I finally
got a hooker roll.
Sorry.
Maybe next time.
Coroner was just here.
Maurice Hudson, 37,
lives in Tahoe.
$14,000 in cash, and credit
cards are accounted for.
That much cash?
Guy must have been a gambler.
GRISSSOM:
Casino W-2s.
Looks like we got a winner.
Name tag printed at the
Tangiers.
Probably a convention.
I'll check it out.
So tell me about the body.
Well, uh,
livor mortis is settled,
which means the body's been
laying in this position
for a while.
Pronounced petechiae
on the chest
from lack of oxygen.
Guy was struggling to breathe,
pressure built up,
and it popped the blood vessels.
Yeah, I saw that purple fiber.
I was going to collect it.
I just work on my own rhythm.
I don't see anything purple
in the room.
This table's cracked.
And we have what appears to be
ejaculate.
SANDERS:
Me, too.
This guy was a machine.
And he got around.
Have Sara process the sheets,
and then pull
the hotel surveillance.
Got you.
We want to see
who came... and went.
♪ ♪
Any luck?
Hotel gave us copies
of the surveillance tapes
from the time
Hudson checked in.
I'm all the way
up to last night,
and he's always solo.
Until Mia processes the sheet,
there's no way to know
whether the semen is the result
of self-service only.
No way.
Soft porn couldn't
crack that table.
Okay.
If he had a partner,
that would explain
the unusually large sweat stain
I found on the sheet.
No cell phone.
No calls out.
Always alone.
Who was he with?
Maurice Hudson is
a perplexing subject.
Check out his eyes.
GRISSOM:
Bulbar hemorrhages.
And petechial hemorrhages
on the chest.
Asphyxiation.
Yep. Lividity,
dark blue-purple,
settled in the posterior area.
Well, that makes sense.
We found him face-up.
Yeah? So then explain
the additional
blanching patterns
on the chest and thighs.
Blanching happens
when something's pressed
against the area,
displacing the blood.
Yeah, I know what
you're thinking,
but the body
wasn't moved.
And these two lividity patterns
taken together
are consistent with him
being on his back.
So there was something
on top of him?
Compression asphyxia?
It took at least two to three
very long minutes to kill him.
And whatever was on him
remained there until livor set,
about eight to ten hours.
Well, whatever it was
was gone when we got there.
I want two people in the room
at all times,
double counts, every pile.
If you don't agree,
do it all again.
I know the drill, boss.
BROWN:
Hey, Cat.
Yeah.
I think an ID off
the victim's ring.
Let's hear it.
The AFFA. It only
lasted a few years,
and only one player
wore the number 12
for the Greenbacks.
He was a wide receiver.
Okay, what's his name?
Gabe Miller. Fits the
general description.
All right, well, give it
to Brass. We'll follow up.
Minimal hemorrhage
around the head wounds
suggests the heart
was destroyed first.
Close-to-contact SGW
caused extensive pulpification
on the heart
and bilateral hemothraces.
Yeah, and that was embedded
in the back of his skull.
Not uncommon for
a close-range shot.
I think the guy used
a sawed-off shotgun.
How can you tell?
Check out the stria.
Hmm? Yeah, what is it?
Impatience.
STOKES:
Sawing off the barrel
of a shotgun is hard work.
Those that do it are usually
in a rush in to get it done.
Leaves a burr on the edge
of the barrel.
( gun cocks )
So every time the weapon fired,
the burr on the barrel
raked the shotcup...
...before the pellets
blasted holes
into Mr. Gabe Miller, here.
That's the vic's name?
Yeah, why? Is it that funny?
It's the same name as our new
councilman from Ward Seven.
Interesting story. The guy
played pro football...
Yeah, wide receiver for
the Vegas Greenbacks, right?
Right.
Well, his team ring
was on this guy's finger.
Yeah, then you mis-ID'd the vic.
Gabe Miller's still alive.
As much as a politician can be.
BRASS:
So, this is your ring, huh?
Yeah, that's my old number.
Haven't seen that ring
in a long time.
Why is that?
Every cent I earned playing ball
went up my nose
or on some dog
at Las Vegas Downs.
I was a real mess
until I accepted Jesus Christ
as my personal savior.
Do you got a problem
with that, Captain?
No. No, no. No, I...
No, I'm just listening.
Well, there's no need
to keep talking
unless you're gonna speak
your mind.
Okay, Councilman.
Say you're an alcoholic.
One day you decide
to give up the bottle.
And, more often than not,
you're gonna trade
in the shot glass
for a dozen Krispy Kremes
and start pounding them
away with both hands.
You know what I mean?
So you think
I'm an addictive personality.
Only now I'm into God
instead of greyhounds?
No. I-I'm really not making
any judgments.
When the Lord cleaned up
my life,
I promised Him
I'd always remember the man
that I used to be,
so I'd never be that man again.
I dedicated 20 years
of my life to playing football.
And I pawned
my championship ring
for a $50 parlay.
Sir, they're ready
for you now.
Okay.
You can file a claim
at our office
and get the
ring back any
time you want.
I don't need trophies
anymore, Captain.
Good luck on your case.
HODGES:
Take a look.
Based on
birefringence,
your fiber's the product
of a bivoltine moth.
You could just say it's silk.
Fine.
Acid washed, dyed, Tasar silk.
Color's unique.
Not found in our database
or the Feds.
That's it?
That's it.
It's not like you
to get right down to business.
Even I have off days, Sara.
( dance music playing )
VARTANN:
There's only one
convention at the Tangiers
this weekend.
It's the same name tag
as the one we found
on the vic's clothes.
♪ ♪
A hogs 'n heifers
convention.
Hudson wasn't fat.
What was he doing here?
GRISSOM:
Maybe he used
to be.
Or maybe he was a chubby chaser.
Hey, some men like curves.
VARTANN:
There's curves,
and then there's rolls.
Look,
have tons of fun.
I got a murder-suicide
to cover.
♪ ♪
Something heavy killed our vic.
SANDERS:
Heavy object,
heavy person.
Listen, pass this photo
around the registration desk.
Who knows.
Maybe he did like big girls.
Where are you going?
I'm going dancing.
Excuse me.
Have you ever seen
this man before?
Excuse me, ladies.
Have you ever seen this man
before?
Excuse me.
I'm with the Crime Lab.
Have you ever seen this man
before?
Never seen him before.
Do you see something
you like?
I'm sorry. I, uh...
I noticed your lovely
purple undergarments.
I bought it here
at the convention, honey.
You did?
Thank you.
Fat girl, gay guy.
It's not unheard of.
Yes, he's been
to some of our events.
We've exchanged hellos.
Was he here
last night?
I'm pretty sure
I saw him at the mixer.
Why?
We're investigating
Mr. Hudson's death.
Was he with anyone?
I didn't notice.
But you could
check the message board.
Message board?
When you see somebody
you like, you leave them a note.
If they respond, you're in luck.
If they don't,
it's softer
than face-to-face rejection.
We get that enough as it is.
Roughly 25,000
in cash,
money bands from five
different sports books,
some, uh, assorted
trash and junk,
and these.
Without the vig,
these are both $5,000 bets.
Duke minus 17
on a Tuesday, and Louisville
plus 23 on a Friday.
They winners or losers?
You know what? I don't follow
college roundball anymore.
Most of the good players
go pro
right out of high school.
The Mirage.
The Stardust,
The Golden Nugget,
and Sam's Town.
It's down the Strip,
across Fremont,
up Boulder Highway.
It's a classic runner's route.
Well, if he was placing
bets for a bookie,
maybe we can find
out who it is.
BRASS:
Hey.
So I tracked down
the football ring
from the pawn shop records.
The ring was bought
by Kelvin Russell.
Get this.
Russell worked for the VSL.
The Vegas Sports Line.
Yeah,
I've heard of them.
They set the spread
for almost every sports book
in Vegas.
Now, if the vic worked
for the VSL,
he's legally prohibited
from sports gambling.
I mean, that guy should be
nowhere near
a betting ticket.
Five? A lousy five?
This is the best left-handed
shooter in the country.
Yeah, you're right, Mitch.
Uh, my research has me at six.
Six?
They'll cover that
at halftime.
Where are you morons
getting your information?
Seven and a half.
Seven and a half
is a good start. Let me hear.
Scotty, come
on, beam me up.
I want some numbers.
Ten.
Good.
Okay, we're going ten here.
Mitch, add a hook for me.
Uh-huh.
That's the game.
Call it into the books.
Hey, Mitch.
So I see
you're still the man
with the plan, huh?
Yeah, I am.
I'm here about one
of your employees,
Kelvin Russell.
Then we got the same problem.
That kid's been a
no-show for two weeks.
By the way, if you see him,
you let him know
he's fired, okay?
Oh, I don't think you have
to worry about him coming back
to work.
He's dead.
We're gonna need statements
from everybody.
Who knew him best?
That'd be Scotty.
BRASS:
All right,
Scott, so, uh,
you and Kelvin were buds, right?
SCOTT:
No, not even.
I was just the only guy
that would talk to him.
Oh, so,
he wasn't the favorite?
He was cocky.
Well, there's
nothing wrong
with a little
confidence,
especially in
your line of work.
Yeah, well, I guess
the guys didn't think
he deserved
to be cocky just yet.
I mean, Kelvin was new here,
and Mitch Urbana's the man.
And you know what I mean?
His number is the number.
You taking drugs, Scott?
Yeah, it's for my Tourette's.
BRASS:
So, when was
the last time you saw Kelvin?
Monday.
Yeah, it was the morning
after the Duke-Louisville game.
He-He sort of just came in
and left.
What was the big rush?
He didn't come in to work.
He-He came in to gloat.
Hey, Mitch,
you picked Duke minus 15, right?
How'd that game turn out?
( laughing )
Just like I called it, old man!
Hey, you weren't even close!
Then he left.
That was the last time
I saw him.
Hi. Can I leave this message
for Melody?
Hi.
I'm from the Crime Lab.
There's potential evidence
on this board.
I need the messages
for Maurice Hudson.
Crime Lab?
Something happen to him?
Yes.
He's dead.
Oh.
A few ladies
here are going
to be in mourning.
He was popular.
Don't know why.
Guess some people like pigs.
I take it you knew him.
Well enough
to keep my distance.
Bastard liked doing fat girls,
but didn't want
to be seen with them.
There are some women
around here who spend
all their time and energy
giving pleasure
because they think
they aren't worthy.
You don't have to be large
to have low self-esteem.
Did he check his messages
last night?
Yeah.
He and Regina Owens
played message tag for a while.
I figured they hooked up.
Where can I find her?
She's a vendor.
Intimates.
That's some tickler
you got there.
Excuse me?
You got everything you
need to please a woman.
Fine.
Regina,
um, can I ask you,
is this silk or synthetic?
Oh, that's 100% silk.
How many sets of these
have you sold?
Four pre-orders and
another 15 commissions.
I even made a
set for myself.
Men love purple.
Do they?
It's Purple Rain.
Prince. Sexy.
Custom color.
You want it
for the wife?
I'm not married.
Girlfriend?
No.
You want one?
Yes, I do.
( laughs )
I'd also like, uh, copies
of your customer receipts.
Yeah, this is the guy.
Time-stamps match
what were on the tickets.
Looks like a runner to me.
WOMAN:
Got that right.
Name's Lou Barnes.
Yeah, we were kind of hoping
those babies wouldn't show up.
Why, because they're winners?
Oh, yeah.
Those little pieces of paper
are worth ten-five each.
Game hit us hard.
Yeah, I hear that
book's the only place
where casinos
actually lose money.
I worked here a long time,
never seen anything like it.
Not even ASU-Washington in '93.
Oh, that's when
the players shaved points.
Any indication
that this game was fixed?
Well, gaming commission
investigated.
They didn't think so.
I figure
we just got caught
in a good steam play.
A lot of one-way action?
Minute VSL opened the line.
Yeah, it was weird.
Those guys are usually
right on.
I mean, that's what
we pay them for.
The sharp number keeps you guys
from getting hit too hard, huh?
Not this time.
Number went all over the place.
Money was rolling in so fast,
guys were fighting
for position in line.
We lost over a million
on that game.
Could I get a printout
of the line moves?
You got it.
Hey.
So, uh, Brass got a home address
on the runner, Lou Barnes.
He's looking into it.
What are you still doing here
anyway?
I'm studying the game
that our vic got rich on.
These are the craziest
line moves I've ever seen.
Line moves?
Got to say, the only thing
that sports book means to me
is guys without showers.
( laughs )
That's actually true.
Yeah, I know.
Okay, well,
let me see
if I can break it down.
Monday morning,
the week of the
Duke-Louisville game,
VSL sets the line
at Duke minus 15.
So if I were to place a bet
on Duke,
they would have to win
by more than 15
in order for me to win the bet.
Right. Now according
to the manager of the book,
the moment that
number went up,
cash came rolling in on Duke.
The professional bettors
were all over the number,
dispatching runners
in every book in town.
Now, remember,
money moves the line.
So, by the middle of the week,
the tourists and local suckers
caught wind
of what the pros were betting,
pumping the line
to Duke minus 25.
Yeah, everybody's throwing money
on Duke.
Big favorite.
This is where it gets weird.
By Friday, all sorts of cash
starts rolling in,
but this time on the underdog--
Louisville plus 25.
Which means that Louisville
could lose by 24
and still win the bet.
So, why
would you bet on the underdog
if you had already put money
on the favorite?
Well, here's why.
Our vic had Lou Barnes
lay 17 points
with Duke,
and take 23 with Louisville.
And the game...
landed 22.
How do you think he did it?
WILLOWS:
He got more than 17
and less than 23.
He won both bets.
All that action
created this big "middle,"
so he was able to win
on both sides.
I think Kelvin Russell
sold VSL's numbers,
and got killed for it.
BRASS:
Lou Barnes.
Big money runner.
Still living
at your mom's house?
Hey, buddy, focus.
You all right?
Guess not.
Okay, Ma'am.
What've you got for us?
Pulled this out
of his calf.
Been in there
at least a week.
The guy was septic.
He's lucky to be alive.
( groans softly )
Number four buckshot.
Barnes was at Rainbow Canyon
with Russell.
Russell knows the line's going
to move on a big game,
and he wants to cash in on it.
But he can't go near a book
without being reported,
so he hires Barnes
to place the bets.
They win big, and both wind up
on the wrong end of a shotgun.
( gunshot )
( man yelling )
( gun cocking )
( gunshot )
We're looking
for a third guy.
Hey, Lou. Lou.
You want to tell us
who filled you full of lead?
I want a lawyer.
METCALF:
Walk softly.
Don't cause a stampede.
I am going to remember
that you said that, Metcalf,
especially after these ladies
sue you and the police
for discrimination, you genius.
Could you clear the
halls for me, please?
Come on, guys.
Hi, there.
I'm Sara Sidle; I'm
with the Crime Lab.
I would like to apologize
for him.
That was really out of line.
They all were,
and so are you,
unless you've got
a good explanation
on why we've been hauled
down here.
Well, as you know, this
is a homicide investigation.
We've recovered evidence
consistent
with custom-made lingerie
that all of you own.
JILL:
I'm no lawyer,
but that sounds flimsy,
even to me.
We also ran DNA on evidence
that we found at the crime scene
that proves
that two women had
sex with the victim
prior to his death.
I would like to rule you out
as suspects,
so I'm asking
for a voluntary DNA sample.
You think one of us
killed Maurice?
Who's Maurice?
You know, Maurice Hudson.
Big ego, little scab.
If I could just swab
the inside of your cheek.
The answer is no.
I can easily get a court order
with what I've got.
So, get one.
Let's go.
Jill?
I don't want
this humiliation
made more public
than it already is.
And I definitely
don't want to come back here.
So, you do what you want,
but this ends
for me right here.
You told us that
you didn't really
know the victim.
I didn't want
to get involved.
I still don't.
You were in his bed.
I'd call that involved.
Look... Maurice
wasn't a nice guy,
but I slept with him anyway.
I could service him all night,
and he wouldn't even ride
the elevator with me.
I bet that hurt.
Enough to kill him?
He was better when I left
than when I got there.
What time was that?
I went to his room around 7:00.
Stayed just long enough
to get mine and go.
( raucous laughter )
Ooh! Oh!
( laughter continues )
He knew how to have fun.
And that's why we all come
to Vegas, isn't it?
I'm fat, Ms. Sidle.
I am a fat woman.
I've tried diet after diet,
joined gym after gym,
done obesity programs,
obsessed about drastic surgery,
and I'm still fat.
I didn't get
my high school crush.
I did his homework.
Didn't get the one
in college, either.
He became my "friend."
But Maurice left a note
in my slot on the message wall.
And he made me feel special...
sexy...
wanted.
Did you know
about the other woman?
When I went up to his room,
she was leaving.
And you slept
with him anyway?
I thought about turning around,
but it's not
like I've had a lot of chances.
It wasn't till afterwards...
that I started to feel... angry.
At myself.
For letting him take advantage
of me.
Did you argue with him?
Was there a fight?
No.
I waited for him to fall asleep.
Then I smothered him
with a pillow
and held him down
until he stopped moving.
( siren blaring )
WARRICK:
Across town on a homicide,
you guys call me out here
for an abandoned vehicle?
BRASS:
The car was reported stolen
last week.
The R.O. is Mitch Urbana.
It's been picked clean.
You guys popped the trunk?
Waiting for you;
pop it.
What do you got?
Feels like metal.
BRASS:
The dust in your trunk
is high carbon steel
mixed with chrome--
consistent
with a shotgun barrel,
like the weapon used
to kill Kelvin Russell.
Look, uh, my car was stolen,
and I reported it, okay?
End of story.
I don't know nothing
about no shotgun.
Maybe the punk who stole my car
must have put it there.
You and Kelvin
weren't on the best terms, eh?
Oddsmaking's a little art
and a little science, you know?
Russell was... he was all mouth.
Hey, he nailed the Duke game.
He got lucky.
You know, there's about 30 games
a day, and...
Look, let me try to explain it
to you, okay?
Inside each game
is a number.
Once in a while, I'm,
I'm a little off.
But most of the time, I'm right.
I work very hard to be right.
I chisel through stacks
of statistics,
I sweep away
all the irrelevancies.
I try to get to the bottom--
you know, where the truth is.
And yeah, I want to know
what the quarterback
had to eat that day,
and if the point guard's
going through
a messy divorce.
All these things,
they come together,
and all of a sudden, bang--
a number just jumps out at you.
And within an hour,
every sports book in Vegas
got that number
up on their board.
My hard work
displayed up there in lights.
That's what I do.
Let me tell you what I think.
Kelvin made you look bad.
He made you
look stupid.
And for a guy
who thinks highly of himself,
who clearly needs to be right,
where there's a tremendous
amount of ego involved,
that's motivation for murder.
Kelvin Russell didn't know
what hard work was, okay?
He was a loudmouth
major pain in the ass.
You think I killed him?
Prove it.
Brenda Morgan
is claiming that
she smothered the victim
to death with a pillow.
He wasn't killed
with a pillow.
C.O.D. was compressed asphyxia.
She admits guilt, but
she's hiding something.
Maybe she's covering
for someone else.
We know that Regina
Owens was in the room.
She claims she left
the victim alive,
and Brenda is
backing her up.
Yeah, but she's a liar.
SANDERS:
Brenda got off the elevator
at 7:30.
Regina got on.
They knew each other,
so things must have been
uncomfortable.
The tape confirms
Brenda's account.
What time did she leave?
Spent the night.
She didn't leave
till the next morning.
Doc Robbins ball-parked
the victim's death
at sometime between 9:00
p.m. and midnight.
That means she slept
with a dead guy.
She's not only a killer,
she's a necrophiliac.
That's what I call
enjoying your work.
Hold on, hold on.
Uh, back up the tape, please.
There. Stop.
She's trashed.
Maybe she passed out.
How drunk
do you have to be
to sleep next to
a decomposing body?
The smell alone's
an alarm clock.
Not next to him.
On top of him.
BROWN:
Who do you like?
WILLOWS:
Uh, Charlotte.
My mom grew up
in North Carolina.
All right, I'll give you
Charlotte plus two.
What do I get if I win?
How about a fabulous dinner?
I'll take your action.
All right.
( indistinct voices on TV )
So, unless we find
our murder weapon,
the case against Urbana
is circumstantial at best.
But he's involved. I feel it.
Those sports betting types--
they'll lie to their own kids
about a game
that hasn't been played yet.
You were a sports betting guy.
Yeah, and I lied when I was.
MAN:
Coming down to the wire.
Six seconds left.
Pistons 89.
Charlotte 88.
Charlotte looking
for one last shot.
( horn blares )
Can't get it.
Final score-- Pistons, 89.
Oh!
Charlotte, 88.
My team loses,
but I still win that bet.
Well...
( phone rings )
Ah.
Brown.
Really?
Well, thank you.
That was the manager
of the sports book.
Says a guy
filed a lost ticket claim
for the tickets
that you found
at the Beaver Dam.
What's the name?
BROWN:
Cesar Dabo.
No wants or warrants.
Address in Lincoln County.
That's near Rainbow Canyon.
That's where
you found the body, isn't it?
Yeah. Professional
boxer from '79
to '85.
After that, he spent a lot
of time in Vegas
as a bouncer,
bartender, handyman.
Just another one of
those broken down,
punch-drunk bums.
It says Dabo was a
Welterweight contender.
A title match
against Archie Archman
was his biggest fight.
Lost by a split decision.
Check this out.
The only judge
who called the fight for Dabo
was Mitch Urbana.
Oh. So maybe Urbana
hired his former boxing buddy
to do his dirty work.
Dabo takes them out
to Rainbow Canyon.
Murders Russell,
but Barnes gets away.
Dabo grabs most of the cash,
goes back to Russell's body,
takes the wallet, ID,
takes off his face.
And Urbana reports
his car stolen to cover his ass.
Let's put out a broadcast.
( distant sirens )
Let's go.
Las Vegas
Police.
Cesar Dabo?
( sniffing )
Put your hands on your head.
Listen, Cesar,
you know, you're looking
at a lighter gig
if you tell us
who paid you to kill Russell.
( inhales )
Nobody paid me
to kill him.
What about your
buddy Mitch Urbana?
He called a fight
for you back
in '79, right?
Yeah. I won that fight.
Mitch was the only judge
that got it right.
But you're willing
to do time for that?
Mitch said
the kid was selling his number.
He asked me to follow him,
see what was going on.
BROWN:
So, why
were you driving
Mitch's car?
What, was I supposed
to take the bus?
My ride's been out all month.
All right, how much
you get paid for the hit?
It wasn't a hit.
I did it on my own.
I saw the money
that runner was taking out
of those books.
Making Mitch look bad.
He deserved it.
They weren't so happy
with a shotgun in their face.
I drove them out
to Rainbow Canyon.
( gunshot )
I took the cash and stuff.
I came back here.
I called Mitch
and told him what went down.
I said I'd kill him, too,
if he said anything.
I knew you guys would find me
sooner or later.
Dabo, tell me something.
Why didn't you take
the kid's ring?
That was worth something.
DABO:
Man, I thought
it was a Super Bowl ring.
Freakin' AFFA.
That's my luck.
How much does this thing weigh?
240 pounds
at the moment.
We'll increase the weight
incrementally
until you can't move.
SANDERS:
Oh, I can't lift that.
And if I can't, you can't.
This is a
safety issue.
Well, that's what the pulley
is for, Greg,
so relax and lie down
on your back.
You know, this is exactly
like a dream I had once,
except it wasn't in a garage.
And Grissom wasn't watching.
That was a
different dream.
( creaking )
How's it feel, dreamer?
Like 240 pounds
of pure woman.
How's your breathing?
( grunts )
Limited.
Okay, add another 40 pounds.
Ready.
( squeaking )
Well, the position's consistent
with the victim.
Face up, right arm is pinned.
SIDLE:
If we could leave the
dummy on long enough,
we could actually
match the blanching.
( high-pitched groaning )
Yeah, guys, help.
Oh.
( grunts )
( creaking )
Oh.
280 pounds.
Brenda's just shy of three.
( grunting )
( gasping for breath )
( choking )
SIDLE:
How long have you
had Type II diabetes?
A few years.
What difference does that make?
You also have hypertension.
Do you always ask questions
you already have the answers to?
The night
that Maurice Hudson was killed,
you'd been drinking.
There was enough sweat
on the sheets
to run a tox panel.
I don't drink a lot.
Well, it doesn't
take a lot
for someone to
pass out who's on
Propranolol and glucophage.
It was an accident, wasn't it?
Wake up. Wake up.
( crying ):
Wake up.
I just couldn't bear the jokes.
( crying )
Be some comedian's punch line.
( sniffles )
I would rather admit to murder
and go to jail...
than to ever be that.
I've finally regained feeling
in my spine, thanks for asking.
GRISSOM:
A little technical reading,
Greg?
Yeah, I guess I just wanted
to see what the big deal is.
Attraction is subjective.
It can't be analyzed.
Yeah, I consider myself
to be pretty open-minded.
Find other peoples'
predilections very intriguing.
What do you like?
What gets your juices flowing?
Someone who doesn't judge me.