( yelling ):
Joe! Joe!
I'm not your damn secretary
and your wife's not my boss!
You hear that, Cheryl?
This is a company phone.
If this is
an Indian burial ground,
I'm totally screwed.
I'll be in litigation
for months.
I can't make
any promises, sir,
but I don't think
the Paiute wore heels.
Hey! What's it look like?
Well...
The body's been
encased in something.
It's black.
It's flexible...
But it's pretty stubborn.
I think it's roofing tar.
It keeps the smell
and the animals away.
It makes our job a lot harder.
We've got disturbed soil
in a three-by-five perimeter.
Okay.
Gentlemen!
Start your shovels!
Do you think our Jane Doe
was buried alive?
Whoever buried her sure had
access to a lot of tar.
Maybe
a construction worker.
Nick, did you get
that last soil sample?
Yeah, but I think I got
something else, too.
Hey, guys.
Check this out.
A third foot.
Ugh...
Means there's
another body.
I don't know if she
was buried alive, but...
she wasn't buried alone.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
Two sets of hands.
Two sets of feet.
Two skulls, two bodies.
Both appear to be female.
Jane Doe Bottom's curled up.
Jane Doe Top's laid out flat.
WILLOWS:
This looks like... barbed wire.
It's in her mouth.
Could be a dental appliance.
Or maybe some kind
of torture device.
You're thinking
ritualistic?
I don't know
what I'm thinking.
Hey.
They told me you dug up
two bodies covered in tar?
So. How you going
to separate them?
I'm not sure yet.
Obviously I can't
saw through
without potentially
destroying evidence, so...
If the tar were harder,
I could chisel it.
If it were softer, we could
peel it off.
I have an idea.
Of course you do,
but last I checked,
the backlog on grave
was about... mmm...
a hundred cases?
You've been spending
too much time with Ecklie.
I'm off the clock.
I came in early for this.
You ever done
this before?
Nope...
but I do know that tar
becomes as brittle as glass
at about minus 200 degrees.
Okay, Mr. Wizard.
Not much left of her
but the clothes.
Well, let's see what our
other one looks like, shall we?
Huh.
( clearing throat )
Oh, boy.
I gotta get my
shift started.
Good luck
with the case.
No, no, no.
You're not going to just
destroy this skull and split.
You can make a nice mold
from the impression.
I'm short-handed as it is.
I think Sara
just wrapped a case.
If you need her,
she's yours.
Wow.
Look at you,
Mr. Straightedge.
I did not know that your
hair could do that.
I look like a dork.
No, no.
No, you look like a pro,
which is what you are.
Let me guess-- a
prelim for Sherlock?
Yep.
Uh-huh. Who's your judge?
Uh... Dudley... Anderson?
Yeah. Well, not
the sharpest
tool in the shed.
( clears throat )
Speak slowly.
Use simple terms.
You're gonna nail it.
Sara.
You're mine tonight.
♪ The ups and downs
and roundabouts ♪
♪ Where are they leading to? ♪
♪ The in-betweens
and silly thoughts ♪
♪ How do we make it through? ♪
♪ Homeward ♪
♪ Ah, ah ♪
♪ Heading homeward ♪
♪ Tell me what becomes of us ♪
♪ Ah, ah ♪
♪ Heading homeward ♪
♪ Tell me what becomes of us ♪
♪ Ah, ah ♪
♪ Heading homeward ♪
♪ Tell me what becomes of us ♪
♪ Tell me what becomes of us. ♪
Ladies and gentlemen,
Miss Jane Doe Top.
Nice job.
Thanks.
Thank you, Sara.
Well, Doc Robbins
told me that she had
severe trauma to the skull,
probably what killed her.
Well, that would explain the
blood David found on her shirt.
Mia's running DNA
right now to find out
if it matches the victim,
or any suspects,
for that matter.
Remember, now, she
had a broken jaw.
That was 26-gauge
stainless steel.
It's used to surgically
wire jawbones shut.
What's with the fingers?
Distal phalanges were cut off.
Both vics,
both hands.
I cast tool marks, Looks like
some kind of opposed blade tool.
Jagged on one side,
smooth on the other.
NICK:
Well, if it
was pre-mortem,
that would support torture.
Yeah, but if it was post,
they probably did it
to conceal identity.
Hey, you guys
still working
on that mass-
grave theory?
Yeah.
You know what I like
about flesh decomposing in soil?
It's predictable.
The constituent elements
diffuse
into the ground over time.
The longer they're there,
the lower the concentrations.
I tested the soil samples Nick
took from around each body.
Curly Sue was on the bottom
for at least five years,
and Flat Sally was
on top for only two.
So we've got
a killer who digs a grave,
dumps a body,
covers it with tar,
comes back three years
later, digs again
and dumps another
one on top of it?
Ten to one, it's
domestic abuse.
Beat up, then shut up.
WOMAN:
You hitting every E.R. in town?
Seems like it.
These are all
the jaw fractures
that came in from two
to three years ago.
Thank you.
We don't get as many
of these as we used to.
Domestic violence laws
have forced men
to get smarter
about their hitting.
♪ ♪
Why don't you, uh, you
wait for me here, 'kay?
Mr. Melton, take a seat.
I married, uh, June
about a year after
Svetlana left.
And when was the last time
that you saw Svetlana?
It was about two years ago.
She didn't come home one night.
Next thing I know, the cops
are knocking down my door.
I thought something
happened to her,
but they were there
to arrest me.
For hitting her.
Are you saying
that you didn't?
We were married for three years.
I never hit her.
Why would she lie?
I don't know.
And then what happened?
After that,
I... I was done.
I went looking for her to sign
the divorce papers, but...
it was like she fell off
the face of the earth.
Or got buried
a few feet under it.
MELTON:
Look, I took out ads
in the newspaper
every day for a month.
She never responded.
Yet you didn't file
a missing persons report.
I'd been accused of abuse.
How would that
have looked?
You seem
to care a lot about
the way things look, Mr. Melton.
WILLOWS:
Well, we're gonna need
a list of Svetlana's
friends and family.
She didn't have any.
She spawned from nothingness?
Her parents died in some kind
of industrial accident
in Odessa.
Russia?
Yeah.
How did the two of you meet?
Through an agency.
Svetlana was a mail-order bride?
We were introduced
through an agency.
So what happened,
the Russian agency
denied your application
for another wife,
or, uh, you lost your taste
for white meat?
Too tough?
You know what, lady?
I am not gonna feel bad
about my decision.
I dated American women,
like you.
They don't want to be
anyone's wife,
or mother-- you mention
the word "domestic,"
they're done with you.
It's nice to be needed...
not resented.
Yeah, I find isolation
and dependency really sexy, too.
You know, what,
you can think
whatever you want.
SIDLE:
Look, all I am
asking is to have
a black-and-white do
regular welfare checks.
Did the wife ask
for help?
Well, that's kind
of hard to do when
you don't speak English
and you're a sex slave.
I'm sure she doesn't
know her rights.
( sighs ):
You can't arrest someone
for marrying the wrong person.
You would know.
If the guy's an abuser,
if he killed his first wife,
we will build a case
and we will nail him.
And in the meantime,
he can just keep
using her as
a punching bag.
Sara, I was there--
there wasn't a mark on her.
Not that we could
see, Catherine.
You know... every time
we get a case with a hint
of domestic violence or abuse,
you go off the deep end.
What is your problem?
Yeah, I probably do,
and you let your sexuality
cloud your judgment about men,
and I'm gonna go over your head.
Sidle.
Get in my office. Now.
You are
a law enforcement officer
and a representative
of this city.
That means I expect you
to conduct yourself
in an appropriate manner,
in and away from this lab.
You know what,
if this is gonna be
one of your "for the good
of the lab" speeches,
don't bother, I've heard them.
Just take a seat.
Willows is a supervisor--
that means you treat
her with respect.
Insulting her in
front of coworkers...
She's not my supervisor.
All right-- your superior.
Sara, you
berate witnesses,
you disrespect
the people you work with,
you luck your way out of a DUI.
Take a look-- you got a half a
dozen complaints in your jacket.
And if Grissom
really documented
your performance,
there'd probably be
a dozen more-- that's not the
kind of person I want in my lab.
The only reason this is your lab
is because Grissom
doesn't kiss ass.
You couldn't hack it
in the field,
so you fail your way up,
you break up our team,
and now you just hang out
in the hallways
waiting for one of us
to screw up.
Sidle, you're
on one-week suspension
without pay, and
when you get back,
Great.
you're apologizing to Catherine.
No, I'm not.
What's going on
around here?
( groans )
I don't want
to talk about it.
Okay, so, this
is the jacket
that Svetlana was wearing
the night that she went
into the hospital?
Yeah. I pulled it
out of the vault
from the original abuse charge
two years ago.
Most of the blood is Svetlana's,
although there is
a small portion
that comes from an unknown male.
So I'll see if the
husband's willing
to give us a comparison.
Don't bother, he already
voluntarily gave a sample
the night that this happened,
and it's not a match.
So he was telling
the truth?
Eh...
I did find this...
in her pocket.
Is that the husband?
Nyet.
BROWN:
Well, they're looking
pretty friendly here.
And you could write
some teen poetry
from the words that are
highlighted in this dictionary.
Well, maybe Andrew
found out that Svetlana
wasn't as lonely as
he thought she was.
Catherine, I heard
Ecklie suspended Sara.
What can we do?
Nothing.
No?
Mm-mm.
Sara's always been there
for anyone who needs her.
She's always had my back.
So what if she flew off
the handle a little?
Greg, she crossed the line
with a suspect;
she was inappropriate with me
and with Ecklie;
she needs the time off.
BROWN:
A lot of blood
on that blouse.
Yeah, well, her wounds
don't just trickle,
man, they-they gush.
Were you able to get
anything off these jeans?
Uh, found this paper.
It was found in the pocket.
Decomp trashed it, though.
That reminds me of the time
I as at the Ghost Bar,
and I ran into this hottie.
I mean, the girls was
an absolute dime.
And I didn't have
my phone on me,
so I wrote her number down
on paper,
and put it in my pants.
The jeans ended up
in the wash.
Ouch.
Yeah.
But...
STOKES ( chuckles ):
Whoa...
Fatty acids dissolve the ink,
and it leeches
onto the pocket lining.
Yeah.
Huh.
That must've been a pretty hot
number you had there, boss.
Yeah, it was.
LITRA:
All right, first we mirror it,
and then we remove
the background texture
of the cotton weave.
Sharpen the contrast,
will you?
"Madame..."
"Matryoshka's."
"Tuesday...
g a.m."?
Some kind of appointment.
"g a.m."?
Do you know what matryoshkaare?
Sure.
( laughs ):
Russian nesting dolls.
Oh, yeah, yeah,
the dolls that look alike,
that fit inside
of each other, right?
My grandma had a set.
Anyway, people who've gone
from writing Cyrillic to English
often write their nines
as lowercase G's.
( clears throat )
You have appointment
for haircut?
Nah, I'm trying to get a
Rastafarian thing going.
Is there an actual
Madame Matryoshka?
( speaking Russian):
...polizia...
We're polizia. Yeah.
Chloe Daniels.
What can I do for you?
I'm Detective Jim Brass,
Las Vegas Police.
This is Nick Stokes
from the Crime Lab.
We're here about
Svetlana Melton.
Yeah, she used
to work here.
In what capacity?
Hairdresser.
You mean wife-to-be.
Yeah.
For money?
Sounds a lot like
prostitution to me.
Yeah, well, it's not.
Look, I didn't invent this.
Go on line--
there are dozens of sites
with thousands of women.
They advertise these
exciting trips to Kiev.
I just bring Kiev to you.
I sponsor 90-day work visas,
teach the girls a trade.
They cut hair for men.
So men shop for a wife.
You screen the guys?
You pick up a woman at a bar,
does the bartender screen you?
You take her home,
take her to your bed.
How well did you screen her?
You should be sainted.
STOKES:
Mm, I don't know
about that.
Svetlana ended up dead.
You recognize this guy?
DANIELS:
Yeah. Ken Wellstone.
Lives down the street.
Actually comes in for haircuts.
Isn't interested
in my service.
Not the marrying kind,
I guess.
Yeah, I-I'm sorry,
there seems to be
a really fine line
here between, uh...
peddling marriage
and peddling flesh.
When is marriage
anything else?
BRASS:
Nick is, uh...
he's an old-fashioned guy.
Really? ( laughs )
Well, what do you think
engagement rings are?
Just proof that a man
can pay for his bride.
Look, caveman
would go steal a woman
from a neighboring clan.
He'd tie her hands and her feet
till she wouldn't run away.
Once she'd stay put,
he would only tie her finger,
just to remind her.
So you're a romantic.
Marriage is not romance.
It's a contract with the state.
It's an investment
in your future.
I'm not making it about money,
it just is.
Uh, she cut my hair.
She licked your cone.
Well, I-I took
Svetlana out once
for... for ice cream.
It was...
it was a hot day.
That's it?
Yeah, that's it.
She, uh, gave me
some sob story
about how she was married
to some abusive guy,
you know, and how, uh...
She begged me
to help, and...
blah, blah, blah, blah.
I don't... I don't need
that kind of drama.
Mr. Wellstone,
what do you do for a living?
I'm a real estate agent.
You're not in construction
or anything?
No. Why?
Something happen to Svetlana?
Yeah, she was murdered.
Oh.
We're gonna need to
get a DNA sample
from you, and I'm gonna take
a look around your place.
Is that cool?
Sure. Yeah, go ahead.
( folk guitar playing )
( knocking )
( music stops )
Well, if you're here,
it can't be good.
Can I come in?
Want to ask me
if I'm drunk?
We both know that's
not your problem.
I spoke to Catherine.
Ecklie?
He wants me to fire you.
I figured.
( sighs )
Can I get you anything?
Sure. An explanation.
I... lost my temper.
That seems to be happening
quite a bit.
Do you know why?
What difference
does it make?
I'm still fired.
It makes a difference to me.
I have a problem with authority.
I choose men who are
emotionally unavailable.
I'm self-destructive.
All of the above.
Have you ever gone a week
without a rationalization?
It's from The Big Chill.
One of the characters
explaining a basic
fact of life--
that rationalizations
are more important to us
than sex even.
I am not rationalizing anything.
I crossed the line
with Catherine,
and I was insubordinate
to Ecklie.
Why?
Leave it alone.
No, Sara.
What do you want from me?
I want to know
why you're so angry.
It's funny...
the things that you remember
and the things that you don't,
you know.
There was a smell
of iron in the air.
Cast-off on the bedroom wall.
There was this young cop
puking his guts.
I remember the woman
who took me to foster care.
I can't remember her name.
Which is strange, you know,
'cause I couldn't let go
of her hand.
Well...
the mind has its filters.
I do remember the looks.
I became the girl whose father
was stabbed to death.
Do you think there's
a murder gene?
I don't believe that genes
are a predictor
of violent behavior.
You wouldn't know that
in my house.
The fights, the yelling,
the trips to the hospital.
I thought it was the way
that everybody lived.
When my mother killed my father,
I found out that it wasn't.
( sniffs )
( sobbing )
BRASS:
So the tar from your carpet
matches the tar
that Svetlana Melton
was buried in.
Tar... I... where?
I mean, I have no idea
what you're talking about.
We also found your
blood on her parka
that she wore to the
hospital two years ago.
I can explain that.
That was from...
So can we-- you beat her,
you killed her,
you buried her.
No, I didn't.
No, stop, please.
She... she ran away.
Put that in here.
"Ken, do not look for me.
"I need to go away.
Svetlana."
You know, after everything
that we'd been through
and everything,
this just seemed really, uh...
It was cold.
Didn't sound like her.
She usually called me...
Kenski.
So what was your relationship,
Kenski?
What was my relationship?
My relationship was, uh...
We were, uh... we were in love.
How did her husband feel
about that?
Her husband bought her,
so he thought he owned her.
And Svetlana was way out
of his league.
And what she wanted to do was
fast track her divorce.
So she thought maybe
if she made it look
like Andrew had beat her,
that that would do it,
but that didn't do it
because he'd actually
never hit her. So...
How'd she break her jaw?
Huh?
She begged me.
Please, Kenski. Please.
Hit me hard on face.
It is only way
for me to leave
this horrible man.
Please, Kenski.
Hit me if you love me.
I just loved her.
BROWN:
All of the blood
on Svetlana's sweatshirt
was hers.
Nothing from Ken Wellstone?
No, but some of the drops
look a lot like dried blood,
but they came back
"Aubergine Sheen number 315,"
professional grade
hair dye.
Well, she worked
in a hair salon.
Some of the patterns look
a lot like cast-off.
WILLOWS:
Hair dye was present
when she was being attacked.
BROWN:
Ken still could have done it.
True, but his story
is so absurd
I almost buy it.
Yeah, well, admit the punch
and you go to jail for a night.
Admit the killing and
you go to jail for life.
Find anything
you like, buddy?
( chuckles )
WILLOWS:
So, you can't sell your kids,
but you can buy their mother.
NICK:
"I looking
for kindest, noble man."
Well, I got news for you,
sugar pants.
Buying women
ain't that noble.
Well, life is short.
Dating's complicated.
This makes it much simpler,
doesn't it?
It's not supposed to be simple.
Complicated is the whole point.
It is?
Yeah.
Hey, wait a minute.
You're not telling me
you're into this stuff?
Me? No.
But you know,
for a guy who's over 40,
lonely, tired
of the bar scene,
got a little cash,
wants to buy himself
a sweet honey,
be his companion...
He needs a translator,
'cause you're not even speaking
the same language.
That's the best part.
Ugh...!
( chuckling softly )
Best part of what?
DANIELS:
What's all this about?
We have reason
to believe
Svetlana Melton
was murdered in your salon.
We have
a search warrant.
( sighing )
Let them in.
Jagged on one side,
smooth on the other.
WILLOWS:
I got blood spatter
next to the hair dye.
Svetlana was a tall girl.
Spatter looks
a little low.
Maybe
she was sitting.
These chairs
don't match.
I think
somebody's hiding something.
BROWN:
The stain on the chair
was Aubergine Sheen Number Four
hair dye.
DNA from the bloodstains on
the walls was too degraded,
and Mia could
not get a match.
So, we know
who the blood belongs to.
We just can't prove it.
I think we
can, though.
You know some guy was selling
a grilled cheese sandwich
on eBay for something
like $20,000
because he claimed
the burn pattern
contained the face
of the Virgin Mary?
How much you think I can get
for the face of Svetlana
in hair dye?
Hang on.
There's something else.
A recycled love token.
Now, that's tacky.
Yeah, that is
pretty tacky.
But it's cause for a warrant.
Everything in order?
I'm not giving you
a damn thing
until I read
every last word.
Take as long as you want.
We're going to be here a while.
Do you believe this?
What, that the guy
locks up his food?
Locks his wife out.
You think he's trying
to protect his investment?
Weight goes up.
Value goes down.
Control her food, control
her destiny, I don't know.
Look at this.
She can't even
call out for pizza.
Or help.
The necklace.
No, no, no. No, no.
I got it.
( computer beeps )
CATHERINE:
Svetlana's blood
was on the necklace
worn by Andrew Melton's
current child bride.
Could you imagine
a control freak like him
having to spend the night
in jail on a phony abuse charge?
You know he went looking for her
when he got out.
It'll never stand up, Rick.
You know how it is,
they'll say the blood
could've come from anywhere.
She could've left
the necklace behind.
We need a murder weapon.
Yeah, well, good luck
on that one.
Crime's over two years old.
( groans ):
All righty.
We know that this guy did it.
How do we prove it?
Can we prove he buried her?
I'm not convinced he did.
Svetlana was buried
in a pre-
existing grave.
Right on top of
Jane Doe Bottom.
And both girls' fingertips were
removed by blending shears.
Which we also found
at the salon.
And the only people
with full access to the salon
are Chloe and Vlad.
Yeah, and Chloe doesn't
really seem like the type
that gets her hands dirty.
All right, the relative size
of the letters
and the spacing between them
appear to be consistent with
both Vlad's appointment book
and the good-bye note
left by Svetlana.
My opinion is
it's the same writer.
Well, it looks like the Vladski
tricked the Kenski.
According to
your credit card statements,
you purchased
several buckets of tar
two and five years ago...
at a local hardware store.
Tell me, what's
a receptionist
at a hair salon
doing with that much tar?
In Russia, I work
for certain family.
When they want body
taken care of,
I go to oil field,
dump body in tar.
None ever found.
Sounds like fun.
Tell me about Svetlana.
Girl already dead.
Nothing I can do.
So you're saying
you did not kill her?
No.
Then why'd you cover it up?
Svetlana, time to lock up.
BROWN:
You didn't call 911?
You cleaned up the scene,
buried her, and then
you left a note for Ken.
America is land of opportunity.
Her death should be
a total loss?
Andrew Melton
is very good tipper.
Was Andrew Melton a very good
tipper five years ago?
No.
Svetlana wasn't buried alone.
There was another body
in that grave.
Many girls
want American husband.
Sometimes Chloe
can't get them a visa.
They come anyway...
She came here in a suitcase,
but she was dead
on arrival,
so you take her out
to the desert
and bury her in a hole?
Again, girl already dead.
Nothing I can do.
Boy, women can really
drive you crazy, huh?
I mean, this perfect
creature who needs you,
who loves you.
You think you've got
it all worked out.
Your Christmas card's
gonna look like
the Sears catalogue,
right?
And then what?
I mean, you give
her stuff.
You give her clothes,
money and shelter,
and then she goes and
makes up some bogus story
about how you
attacked her.
Which I never did.
Man...
a love like that.
So pure.
I mean, men have robbed banks
for less,
put their life
on the line...
would kill to protect it.
Everywhere we went,
men were making love to her
with their eyes,
defiling her
with their thoughts.
It got so bad
it wasn't safe
to let her leave the house.
But then she got lonely.
Like a person
I didn't recognize.
You made her an American.
In all the good ways...
...and the bad.
Svetlana!
You told them I hit you?!
Why would you do that? Huh?
Is that what you want?
Huh? You want me
to hit you?!
That you want?!
She never appreciated me.
Andrew, what happens?
Andrew?
It'll be okay, honey.
It'll all work out.
You'll see.
You wanted to talk to me
about Sara?
I haven't received
her disciplinary action.
What's the holdup?
Well, I'm not firing her.
What action are you taking?
I've taken it.
I thought I was clear.
You were.
Now let me be clear.
Sara's behavior is a direct
result of my management.
So I should fire you.
But you won't.
Look, Gil...
I've been there.
We're human.
We get attached to people,
we try to fix their problems.
It doesn't work.
She's a great criminalist,
Conrad.
And I need her.
I'm sure you do.
You know what?
She's a loose cannon
with a gun.
And she's all yours.