( car horn honking )
Everything all right, Sybil?
I'm fine.
What's taking Alicia so long?
We have a doctor's
appointment in 40 minutes.
She's not here.
She has to be.
I saw her leave for school
this morning.
Alicia hasn't been in
any of her classes.
( phone ringing )
April, get off the phone.
I can't talk right now.
Somebody took Alicia!
What did you do?!
What the hell
did you do?!
Mom, I don't know...
Where is she?!
I'm not sure.
Get off of me!
Go find my daughter!
I don't get to see Alicia
all that much.
Um, I don't get to.
Her life sucks, so sometimes
she would just, you know,
play hooky
and spend the day with me.
After girls' day out, you
stopped here for a snack.
BRASS:
Your father?
Yeah. Um...
I was just went in, and...
you know, to get something
while she changed back
into her uniform.
In the car?
It's not that
big of a deal.
It's like, you know, the
skirt over the jeans,
and back to school
before Mom knows anything
So what did he look like?
What kind of car
did he drive?
Alicia!
A black guy, uh...
He had a beard
and he had a crappy black Buick.
But, um...
I don't know, maybe it was blue.
( screaming )
I don't really...
No, that's... that's good.
You did good.
That's good.
Thank you.
Okay.
The cops won't tell us.
What are the chances
of finding our daughter?
We're doing everything we can.
That's what everyone
keeps saying.
No one will
tell us anything.
Did you injure yourself,
Mrs. Perez?
Oh, a nosebleed.
That's a lot of blood.
I'm going to need
to take your shirt.
Why?
If you like,
I can have someone
follow you home
so that you can change.
You think we had
something to do with it?
Our daughter
is missing.
She's out there somewhere
alone and scared.
What are you doing
about that?!
I'm just collecting evidence.
Fine.
Here!
Take it!
Go find her!
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
BRASS:
This is Captain Jim Brass.
I want to issue a Missing
Persons Emergency Alert Amber.
Notify all radio
and casino signatories.
The description is
as follows...
We have breaking news
from the Channel 8 newsroom
right now.
An Amber Alert has been issued
for missing
13-year-old Alicia Perez.
The suspect in Alicia's
abduction
is described as
an African American man,
35 to 45 years old,
about six feet tall.
How'd you shoot, man?
Rusty.
They say I have a flinch.
You and I need
to go practice some, huh?
Yeah, when do we have
time to do that?
If we're not processing
a scene or working evidence,
we're in court.
Well, when they take your piece,
you'll make time.
This girl seemed
a little old to be lured
by a lost puppy.
So how'd this guy
pull this off
in a lot this public?
Easy. With a map and a smile.
Rolls up--
"Hey, little girl, I'm lost.
You from around here?"
She gets close enough
he pulls her out
of her sister's car,
into his car...
Bam, she's done.
I bet he had a weapon.
Threatened her,
so he could drive.
Probably used his fists.
Bastard had to have hit her.
Look, dude, I didn't see it.
Chica had a nice, round ass
and that's what I was scoping.
What time was that?
About 3:00.
She comes in, grabs some candy,
looks outside,
waves at somebody.
The next thing I know,
she flips her wig.
She's screaming
about her sister.
I didn't see the girl or a car.
Besides, there's a lot
of traffic out there.
Was it busy?
Kind of.
How many surveillance cameras
do you have in here?
Inside we got five.
They're all state-of-the-art.
Place gets hit a lot.
Outside they're all dummies.
Well, I'm glad to see
you're so concerned
about your customers after
they leave the store.
( phone ringing )
Hello.
Yeah.
What do you mean?
What?
Nick, you failed firearms
qualification.
You can't be here.
Oh, yeah. Well,
I'm taking it again
day after tomorrow,
so I figured I could work.
Not in the field.
You're serious?
You're in violation just
carrying the weapon.
Copy that.
I'll be in the lab.
Uh, Nick, let me catch
a lift with you.
There's something going on
with Lindsey.
I'm Catherine Willows.
What's the trouble?
With the Amber Alert,
we've been keeping an eye out.
Found your daughter
up on Boulder Highway
trying to hitch
a ride downtown.
Now, kids this age,
they need a firm hand
at home, and...
Thank you, officer.
I appreciate
everything you've done.
Let's go.
Okay, what or who
is on Fremont Street
that you would
risk your life
to get to?
Mouthing off
to teachers,
slipping grades
and now hitchhiking.
I mean, what is next, Lindsey?
Stripping.
What did you just say?
( exasperated chuckle )
Okay, no phone, no friends,
no nothing.
For how long?
A month.
Whatever.
Hey, you want
to make it two?
Dad always said
you were a drama queen.
Well, what do you expect,
Lindsey,
since he was always high.
I'd take Dad high
over you any day!
Nana's coming to pick me up.
I'll be out front.
You paged.
Yeah.
What's missing?
I give up.
Her sister said the victim
changed back
into her school uniform
in the car.
So? Where are the clothes
she changed out of?
Hello.
SANDERS:
Mia Dickerson,
Warrick Brown.
Welcome.
Look, I already know you have
a running bet
with another CSI over how long
the new hire lasts,
so let's skip it.
You got something
for DNA?
The mother's
bloody T-shirt.
Exemplar?
It's on its way.
Just hedging my bets.
How so?
Well, I need
field experience,
but before I get that,
I need to find a replacement.
So far, I'm o-for-one.
Plus, she's hot
and thinks you're a tool,
so I'm way ahead.
MR. PEREZ:
A gardener and a pool man
come in once a week.
BRASS:
How long have they
worked for you?
Years.
How about a housekeeper
or a maid?
I do it.
Let's talk about
your daughter's routines.
Her routes to and from school,
any extra-curricular activities,
a list of friends.
There wasn't any
after school stuff.
Alicia isn't a joiner.
She walks to school,
I pick her up. That's it.
How often did April get
her sister to skip school?
We don't know.
We... we just
found out ourselves.
I'm curious because
April said she hardly
ever gets to see Alicia.
Why didn't she
just come here?
Because she wasn't welcome.
We kicked her out.
April's a troubled girl.
Problems with drugs,
the police.
You might
as well know,
she also did some time.
Juvenile lockup.
For what?
Heroin possession.
Intent to distribute.
There's nothing
suspicious on the server.
Only hits
are music downloads.
Wait a minute.
An organ transplant site.
For kidneys, heart,
lungs and liver.
What is that, homework research?
Maybe. These are
pretty detailed
biochem and immunosuppressant
citations.
It's a little over
a seventh grader's head,
don't you think?
I don't know.
I bet you were a pretty smart
seventh grader.
She has a serious crush
on a boy named Jimmy Jones.
Sara.
"I hate Mom &amp; Dad."
Who doesn't once in a while?
Daniel Perez.
And you are...?
Gil Grissom, Sara Sidle,
Las Vegas Crime Lab.
I guess that's why
you're pawing through
my sister's private stuff.
It's going to help
us find her.
Do you know a Jimmy Jones?
Yeah, a boy from school.
She liked him.
GRISSOM:
What's your
sister like?
Personable, friendly,
outgoing, trusting, maybe?
She's a giver--
from the day she was born.
Uh, Daniel... you're bleeding.
I'm sorry.
You want to know my sister,
you should check her diary
under the mattress.
"Last night
I didn't sleep very good.
I kept thinking
about the surgery."
I guess we know why she
was doing transplant research.
Serious illness takes
a toll on a family.
Alicia never complained.
She's used to the doctors.
She has friends there--
people who understand--
go through the same hell.
You know, if a victim
has a serious illness,
you really should
disclose it right away.
Our daughter isn't sick.
Our son's kidneys are failing.
Alicia is his matching donor.
Without her, he'd die.
Well, Alicia was
a great half-back--
strong right leg,
aggressive.
You don't see that
too much in girls.
WILLOWS:
She played soccer?
Yeah, for awhile.
She quit before she got cut.
She missed a lot
of practice
'cause she was
always going to the doctor,
and you can't really play
with one kidney
anyway, so...
She told you about her brother?
Yeah, on the way to school.
Hell, I thought that it was cool
that she was saving his life,
but she seemed pretty pissed.
Jimmy... language.
Sorry.
Anyway, uh, she
didn't seem too happy.
Said she had no life
and never would.
BRASS:
So, Jimmy, on your way
to and from school,
did anyone ever bother you
or approach you in any way?
Um...
there was this one guy,
with a track suit,
he was supposed
to be running.
He gave me the creeps.
What gave you the creeps?
Well, start with his gear.
I mean, nobody runs in velour.
And he never had
any water
and he was always
on the phone.
What'd he look like?
Black guy.
He was not a runner,
but he was in shape.
Bald, mustache, beard.
How old would you say he is,
Jimmy?
Qld... like 30.
I just... never liked the way
he looked at Alicia.
Thanks. You've been a great
help, Jimmy. Thank you.
Uh, if it's okay with your mom,
I'm going to have you hang
around, look at some photos.
All right?
Sure.
STOKES:
Here's the Perez house,
Alicia's walk route to school,
and the convenience store
where she was taken.
All the locations are
within a half-mile,
plus or minus three-tenths.
This is a map of all registered
sex offenders in the state,
the county,
and the neighborhood.
Phew! That's a lot of perverts.
Get out of jail,
come to Vegas.
They're listed in tiers
of projected recidivism,
zero through three.
Three being the most dangerous.
They're the ones most likely
to plan an abduction
and find the privacy
for sexual assault and murder.
If I remove the zeroes and ones,
since they have a low
or moderate risk designation,
this is what we're left with.
That's still a lot of perverts.
Mm, maybe not.
Here, I'll isolate
the Perez neighborhood.
( beeping )
Marlon Waylord,
Tier Two, 38, black,
lives alone, sometimes
handyman
and fits Jimmy Jones'
description.
( pounding on door )
Officer.
Did you, uh, cut
yourself shaving,
Mr. Waylord.
Marlon must be shy.
Marlon didn't do nothing.
And I believe you, too.
Come on, step over here, please.
You all know that sex offenders
under a felony conviction
have absolutely no unconditional
release and are under
lifetime supervision,
automatically assigned
by the Nevada Criminal State
Justice system.
Mandated, of course,
by state and federal Megan's Law
in effect 5/17/96.
And therefore
I am required
to register and update
my information...
whenever I move
from my current, uh, domicile.
Well, that's a big word.
Well, you got all your facts
right, Marlon.
Help us with this one.
We know you own a Buick.
Where is it?
Tangiers' parking lot.
It wouldn't start.
I hate that.
I'll have it towed
to the lab.
You do that.
♪ ♪
SIDLE:
Presence of semen.
There's children's
underwear in the bedroom.
GRISSOM:
Photos of children on his phone,
including Alicia.
So here's the deal:
When you go up, I won't
yell short eyes first.
How's that sound?
Sounds like a really good
deal...
you know, if I was, um, guilty.
The inmates didn't treat
you too gentle the last time.
Did they?
You know they didn't.
So tell me what you did
with Alicia.
Who?
GRISSOM:
She's been all over the news,
non-stop.
It's that why you shaved?
BRASS:
Oh, come on.
Don't make me smack you.
GRISSOM:
Her friend tells us that you
were always looking at her.
You went out in the morning
and watched them go to school.
She's sweet, very sweet,
but, fellas...
I wasn't looking at her.
You all should check my file.
BRASS:
No, I did.
I know that your recent
preference is for little boys,
but, uh, your first time was
with a female cousin.
Let me read what you said.
"I couldn't help myself
"'cause she was acting so hot.
It was her fault;
she was really hot."
How does
a six-year-old act hot?
( phone beeping )
Listen...
I'm, uh... I'm sick.
You know, I got this-this
this illness,
which... Look.
I don't want to go back
to prison.
That's why
I'm being so compliant.
Now, yo, I don't work
near no little kids.
I stay a hundred yards
from the school grounds.
Man, I don't even go
to the park.
It's not a disease.
It's a compulsion.
I stay away from youth
organizations,
after-school programs,
churches...
We found a pair of boy's
underwear in your bedroom.
Explain that.
I look at the photos.
I look at the photos
and I have the briefs
for, um...
release.
So you fantasize,
and eventually,
the fantasy's not enough
and you relapse.
Hey, they're mine.
I bought the underwear!
Well, if that's true,
then you were in a store
where little children were
shopping with their mothers.
And what would you have me do,
huh, man?
What?! I mean, I even thought
about chemical castration.
Medroxyprogesterone is
inconclusive.
It renders the subject incapable
of erection,
but it doesn't remove
the sex drive.
You would still be capable
of sexual assault
using other objects.
Listen...
Um, I haven't done
anything, uh, illegal,
so you can't hold me
in here forever.
Oh, is that killing look
in your eyes a compulsion,
Mr. Grissom?
BROWN:
What's up?
The seminal fluid
on the boy's underwear
matches your pedophile.
Epithelials?
His.
And only his.
That confirms his story
that the briefs were never worn.
Hair?
Synthetic.
Probably from a wig.
Great. That means
we have to let the bastard go.
It's only a matter of time
before he snatches up
another kid.
You got any friends in uniform?
Yeah, but they can't watch
him indefinitely.
Okay.
Megan's Law has holes.
Police aren't required to notify
a community about a predator.
So flood his block with flyers
detailing his crimes.
Trust me, the neighbors won't
let him out of their sight.
Or they'll kill him.
( pager beeping )
They found Alicia Perez.
A tour helicopter spotted
her around 4:00 p.m.
How many people have walked
through the crime scene?
Just the responding
officers,
lug soles,
sizes 10 and 11.
We're going to need
some time here, Jim.
Yeah, well, there's
no rush now.
She's wrapped up pretty tight.
Protecting her against insects
and carrion, maybe.
Somebody, uh,
wanted her intact.
Well, her face is covered,
that means remorse, guilt...
somebody cared.
She's been re-dressed.
Her panties are missing.
All right.
360-degree grid search.
Sometimes rapists like
to relive the event.
He may have wanted
to watch her.
So keep the body in view.
We're looking for shoe prints,
sperm clusters...
anything else you can find.
♪ ♪
( sighs )
PHILLIPS:
90 degrees?
Given the timeline,
it should be higher.
That-that can't be right.
Well, today's temp.,
last night's weather...
may have had something
to do with it.
PHILLIPS:
No signs of sexual assault.
GRISSOM:
No defensive wounds.
No wounds of any kind.
Were you expecting some?
( shutter clicks )
Well, she was wrapped
in a bloody blanket.
Since there's no trauma,
maybe the blood belongs
to her killer.
Roll her.
Look at those marks.
There was nothing underneath her
at the crime scene
that, uh, would've made those.
Well, maybe
she was moved.
Trunk of a car?
Tire iron?
( shutter clicks )
Yeah, but there's, uh,
two impressions,
and they're too long
to be a lug wrench.
WILLOWS:
Have you been to bed?
Yeah.
Did you sleep?
Me neither.
She was the same age as Lindsey.
She was trying to hitchhike.
Where was she going?
Fremont Street.
Was she buying drugs?
No! She's 12.
( sighing )
She's... just so angry.
She doesn't talk to me.
Well, if enough people knew
what was out there hunting them,
they'd never leave their house.
I think you need
to sit her down.
Well, I don't want to scare her.
I don't want my daughter
to be this... frightened,
paranoid kid who's always
looking over her shoulder.
Katherine, there's
a big difference
between scaring her
and preparing her.
And all the reasons why you
should are in that room.
GRISSOM:
What is all this bone scarring?
DR. ROBBINS:
I thought you should
be interested.
12 holes exactly made
by a large bore needle.
Marrow harvest?
Young Alicia donated
bone marrow at least twice.
Pretty selfless thing
to do once,
considering how painful
the procedure is.
Let me ask you: What most likely
causes shortness of breath,
obvious bruising,
sudden nosebleeds, petechiae?
Sounds like acute leukemia,
but without immunophenotyping,
I couldn't tell you what kind.
Alicia's cause of death?
Cardiopulmonary arrest.
Time of death?
That's a little trickier.
No solids
in the stomach contents,
just a milky liquid.
Liver mortis was fixed
and deep purple
with a vitreous
humor potassium level
of 20 millimoles per liter
with faint putrefaction.
So, I'd say she's been dead
about... 44 hours
between midnight and 8:00 a.m.,
the day of her kidnapping.
Which means April Perez was
lying about the abduction.
Yep. Story's got more
holes than her sister's bones.
I bought it The hell
we all bought it.
But your sister
was already dead
when you raised that alarm.
Her body told us that.
There was no
sexual assault.
The evidence
told us that, too.
So you didn't think this
through, sweetheart.
So what are
we left with?
A false police report
and a murdered little girl.
So it's one to four
for the Amber Alert.
And for your sister,
life imprisonment if it's
an accident, and the needle
if it's not.
I didn't kill Alicia.
But you know,
I get it.
I get the picture.
I mean, your brother's
the center of attention.
He's sick, he's dying.
Your cells don't match.
Your parents
have Alicia.
She's his savior.
So, where do you fit in?
What are you to this family?
I'm invisible.
But not anymore
you're not.
She's dead,
and your brother's sick.
When he goes...
That's crazy, okay.
I told you, I didn't
kill my sister.
I want to believe that.
Come on.
Help me to
believe that.
It just means you were in on it
because you put on
one hell of a show.
You still using?
No.
Maybe we should run your blood
just to be sure, huh?
I use now and then
to take the edge off.
So how do you pay
for this habit?
Are you pimping your sister
for drugs, April?
Why don't you make up your mind?
No signs of rape.
If I was selling my sister,
there would be, wouldn't there?
Depends on who you sold it to.
You're not gonna talk
your way out of this one.
You need to get clean.
What I need is a lawyer,
which means
this conversation is over.
Daniel Perez was diagnosed
with relapsing acute
promyelocytic leukemia
or APL when he was ten.
It's rare,
it's nasty,
and it usually hits Hispanics.
His sister, Alicia
was conceived in vitro
to be a genetic match.
Well, it's
not unheard of.
Have a baby, get the undeveloped
stem cells from cord blood.
New parents are even
storing it now.
But when she was four, they took
her blood for a transfusion.
No... no!
It's all right,
it's okay, sweetheart.
( crying ):
No... no!
At seven, they took her
blood to remove stem cells.
Well, Daniel must
have relapsed because
they took bone marrow twice.
It takes one to one-and-a-half
liters of marrow
for a successful harvest.
A living DNA factory.
( blender whirring )
I don't need help.
I know.
I'm just trying to make
the transition seamless.
Forget I'm here.
So would you like
to grab a bite later?
I know a diner
down the street
that serves a mean
liver and onions.
I don't eat out.
Never ever?
I don't like expectorant.
Really?
Kitchen staff talk
while they prepare your food
and then the wait staff repeats
your order over the plate,
and by the time
you get your meal,
there are several DNA samples
coating it.
Wow.
No, thank you.
I don't eat birthday cake
either.
Oh, blowing out the candles.
Ugh. Don't get me started.
( soft whirring )
Excuse me.
Um... what happens to April now?
She is being charged
and processed
and the court will
probably grant her bill.
Do you know how much...?
Why?
She's my daughter.
She's refusing to talk
about what happened
to your youngest
child, Mrs. Perez.
I can't leave her in jail.
I think it might be
the best place for her.
( sighing )
This is my fault.
I... I was never there
for her. I...
Why don't we step
in here, please?
I spent all my energy getting
Daniel to the next... thing--
the next pill, the next
treatment, the next remission,
hoping that this time...
And, uh... where
did Alicia fit in,
except for what she
could give to your son?
You have no idea what it's like.
I saw her medical records.
I looked at her X rays.
I know what that
little girl suffered,
what you put her through.
So you would let your child
die and do nothing.
Never.
No, you'd talk to doctors
and research.
And then you'd find out
that the National Bone Marrow
Registry can't help you
'cause your son is mixed race.
And even if he wasn't,
there aren't enough donors.
Out of four million,
only 205,000
are Latino.
I did what I had to do.
You put one child over another.
I don't expect you
to understand.
You don't have kids.
Uh, I have a daughter.
( wry chuckle )
So, what kind of
mother are you?
When do you
see her?
You work nights.
You probably don't even know
where she is half the time.
Alicia's life may not
have been simple,
but at least I knew her.
Can you say the same?
Where's Greg?
Helping, uh... Sara.
I need the tox results
for Alicia Perez.
Still pending,
but the blood
on the mother's
T-shirt
matches the blood
on the blanket.
Belongs to the victim.
Menstrual?
Negative.
Well, the volume of blood
that was found on the blanket
suggests injury
or some kind of trauma.
Nevertheless...
I was very thorough.
Run it again, please.
Greg, you said
you wanted to help out.
Well, yeah, with searching
April's apartment,
maybe finding the bad guy.
This counts as field work,
you know?
Oh, I'm smiling on the inside.
Dirty laundry or garbage.
You know what?
You take the garbage.
Thanks.
Hmm.
April own a computer?
No. Why?
Well, she MapQuest
the directions
to the convenience store
from the pedophile's address.
LINDSEY:
I already told you, Mom,
I heard you.
Can we go now?
No. You need to see
for yourself
why you can't
ever hitchhike
or go downtown
or be careless
with your safety.
Are you ready?
Just do it. I'm not scared.
She was waiting
for a bus downtown
when she was attacked.
She's was 23.
She was taller and stronger
than you, Lindsey.
She fought back
and didn't win.
Someone's gonna have
to tell her family.
Her parents are gonna
have to see her like this.
Do you get it now?
( huffing )
Kids don't belong in
the coroner's office
unless they're in a drawer.
You should've found
a different way
to deal with your
daughter's rebellion.
Well, with due respect, Doc,
this doesn't concern you.
Ever notice how childhood keeps
getting shorter and shorter?
Whose fault is that?
I honestly don't know!
We subpoenaed Map Quest--
they store each page
on a different server.
All queries are
saved for 72 hours,
then they dump the core.
The suspect doesn't
have a computer,
but she could've gone
to the library or used
a service.
No, physical location
doesn't matter.
What we do is
a reversal process.
Using the Internet
protocol number,
we can get to the server.
Which will ultimately lead
to the Internet account holder.
Right. We hunt for child
pornographers the same way.
Who does the account belong to?
Sybil Perez.
Mr. and Mrs.
Perez...
What's going on?
I'll tell you
on the way
to the police station--
where's your son?
At church. Why?
Let's go.
♪ ♪
( echoed distant shouts
of children playing )
SIDLE:
Daniel Perez is taking
Oxycodone for pain,
and Alicia was on Diazepam.
Diazepam? That's a pretty
hard-core antidepressant
for a kid that small.
I guess they didn't
want her complaining
while they were mining
her body for healthy cells.
You think they didn't care
about her?
I don't know.
Well, it must've
been hard,
trying to keep their son alive,
keep the family together.
Couldn't have been easy.
It wasn't for Alicia.
Did you find anything?
Yeah. Blue fibers.
I take it you qualified
at the range.
STOKES:
You take it right.
What'd you shoot?
260 out of 300.
225's passing,
which, I believe,
was your high score.
( laughs )
Where are you doing?
Well, this is Dad's car.
You ever see those guys
out in the street,
with the scope,
measuring distances?
Always thought they
were nuts for standing
out in traffic, but...
Look familiar?
Looks like the lividity marks
on Alicia's body.
BRASS:
I don't get you, man.
I mean, even if you
could explain it,
I would never understand how
you could stuff your daughter
in the trunk
of your car
and dump her body in the woods!
I had to protect my family.
Wasn't Alicia part
of your family?
You're her father,
you dumb bastard!
You're supposed to protect her.
What kind of man are you?
Guilty.
You know, we got
enough evidence
to charge you with
premeditated murder.
You don't have any proof
I killed my daughter.
You helped your
husband move the body.
You know, I really
don't see him taking
her underpants off,
so that job was left to you.
Then you or your
daughter, April,
checked
the sex offenders' registry,
and you tried to frame
an innocent man.
Innocent?
You trying to make me believe
you really give a damn
about a pedophile? Please.
Forget about that;
this is about you.
You're the tough one.
You run the house.
You run the family.
People do what you say
in a crisis.
So?
So this time Alicia said no.
She wanted to
keep her kidney,
and that pissed you off.
So you killed her.
That's ridiculous.
She was angry--
she wanted to play
on the soccer team,
she wanted a life.
Alicia got angry, sometimes.
Just sick of it.
We all did.
But she'd have been devastated
if Daniel had died
and she did nothing
to prevent it.
She loved her brother.
And you're just
the type of woman
that would never let her
forget it.
Come on, Alicia wanted out
of this game,
and you couldn't
let that happen.
Not to Daniel,
not to your only son,
your favorite child.
You slipped Alicia
some of Daniel's Oxycodone.
Alicia? Time for your pills.
So now you got a problem--
you had a dead body in the house
and no plausible explanation.
What are you gonna do?
So you call your
daughter April.
You make up a story,
you play your roles,
and put on a show.
SYBIL:
Wait. We have to do this right.
Oh, you know,
I-I thought the, uh, the slap
was a nice touch.
I have a confirmation.
Those blue fibers
are consistent
with the blanket that
the girl was wrapped in.
And the shoe prints that
I found at the scene
they're a match to the
father's work boots.
I retested the T-shirt
and the blanket.
The blood still matches
Alicia Perez.
The evidence
supports this
unless you'd like
to second-guess that also.
I just expect things
to be done correctly, Greg.
We all have to learn
how to accept change.
Mia's doing a great job.
It would be nice if someone
other than me said so.
You're right.
What about the
handkerchief?
I compared that
to the other blood evidence.
It's also match
to the victim.
I didn't realize
until... today...
...how lucky I am.
I know pretty much...
how and when I'm gonna die.
Most people don't.
It's what they're
afraid of.
Was your sister afraid?
Never.
I'm 11 years older than her,
and she took care of me.
She was my best friend,
and I miss her.
As much pain as...
I caused her...
and she wouldn't give up,
and she... she wouldn't
let me, either.
That's why...
during the last relapse,
I made my parents swear
that it was
the very last time.
But then your kidneys
failed, and they broke
their word, huh?
They told me they...
swore not to fight the cancer,
so this didn't count.
I wasn't gonna lose this fight.
( Daniel sobbing )
SYBIL:
Oh, my God! Please...
CARLOS:
We have to call the police.
They'll put him in prison.
I couldn't watch her
suffer anymore.
This wasn't a mercy
killing, Daniel.
This was an execution.
Bone marrow, transfusions...
That's her blood
in your veins.
It dripped out of your
nose onto the blanket
while you were killing her.
If you cared so
much for Alicia,
why didn't you take your
own life instead of hers?
Suicide isn't
an option.
It's an unforgivable
sin in the eyes of God.
But you believe your
God forgives murder?
If that's your defense, it
won't keep you out of jail.
But my death will.
See, I've got
about six more months.
I'll be dead before
there's even a trial.
( sniffles )
I-I do want to
thank you, though.
For what?
For speaking for Alicia.
You're probably
the first person
in her life
to think only of her.
You know,
you may not believe in God, sir,
but you do His work.