Hey.
Hi. Get anything?
My, uh, knight
in shining German armor
has arrived.
See if he has room for two.
( sirens,
motorcycle engine revving )
It's only been a few hours.
Dakota always calls me.
We have a system.
Something is wrong.
Why don't you
go home, Jersey?
Eat something for
once, get some sleep.
( scoffs )
( sighs )
( phone line ringing )
( phone ringing )
Hello.
Hello, Dad.
Ellie.
Are you okay?
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
Oh, hey, Sheriff.
I'm glad I caught you.
Um...
I got to take some
emergency leave.
It's a...
It's a family matter.
I didn't know
you had a family.
Well, you're new.
We haven't had a chance
to talk. Um...
I, uh,
briefed my lieutenant
on my cases.
He'll cover for me
for a couple of days.
This is not a good time
for family problems.
All the Narco guys are
at a HIDTA conference.
I got no backup.
I'm still learning
the ropes here.
( chuckles ):
Well, it's never a good time
to have a family problem,
Sheriff.
Look, I don't ask
for time off normally.
I'd appreciate the courtesy.
Do I have a
choice here, Jim?
Get back here as
soon as you can.
You look good, Jimmy.
You do, too, Annie.
L.A. seems to agree with you.
Oh, yeah, well,
I couldn't take
another Jersey winter.
Or another Jersey cop.
You stay in touch
with the old crew?
You know, dirty cops don't like
to hang with clean ones.
So that's why
they called me squeaky?
I thought
what you did took a lot of guts.
Integrity is, um,
hard to come by in vice.
Yeah, it's the only detail
where you're told
to drink, gamble
and pick up hookers,
all the while carrying a gun.
Garden of Eden.
Temptation kills you,
or it compromises you.
So, you got my message?
My daughter Ellie
and her friend Dakota
were out partying
and Dakota got
in some guy's car.
Ellie was able
to pull a partial.
Something about a whale tail.
California Coastal Commission
specialty plates.
I'll run it through DMV.
Cross reference with BMWs.
In the meantime,
I pulled Dakota's rap sheet.
She has a sheet?
They both do.
She, uh, works a stretch
on Hollywood Boulevard
between Highland and Vine.
When was the last time
you saw Ellie, Jimmy?
About three years ago.
Um, she got into some trouble
in Vegas.
Hanging around
with a bad bunch.
Looks like her taste
in people hasn't changed much.
Last known address.
In case you don't have it.
( distant car alarm blaring )
( indistinct chatter
and laughter )
Ellie, it's your dad.
ELLIE:
How'd you get this number?
Relax, take it easy.
I got it off caller I.D.
Oh, okay.
So did you make the call?
Yeah. LAPD's looking into it.
Thanks.
Hey, how are you doing?
Great, actually.
Livin' at the beach,
temping, waiting tables.
Got some really good friends.
( inhales )
It's a big bowl of cherries.
Okay, um,
I'll call you when
I hear something, all right?
( garbled radio transmission )
( helicopter whirring )
Hey.
We found the beemer.
Found these two
kids trying to
hot wire it.
Whale Tail
license plate
starting
with 1-T-A.
Let's talk to them.
I'll talk,
you listen.
All right, what the hell's
the matter with you?
You looking to die young?
'Cause you can do it inside
in lock-up or outside
with this wanna-be gang banger
stealing cars crap.
We weren't
stealing nothing.
Window was already busted.
Car wouldn't even start.
We were just
playing around.
You like playing
with cars, huh?
LAPD's having a car wash
fund-raiser on Saturday.
You just signed yourselves up.
You're welcome.
( garbled radio transmission )
BRASS:
So, no Rudy Giuliani
broken windows theory here, huh?
Jimmy, windows
are already broken.
Someone's got to fix 'em.
( garbled radio transmission )
Hey, check this out.
B-H-G-C?
Looks like a country club
or something.
Doesn't read
like Koreatown.
I'll have my guys run
the plates.
BRASS:
Anybody checked the trunk?
Not yet.
Doesn't look good
for Ellie's friend.
( garbled radio transmission )
Glazer.
Yeah, we're just finishing up.
No traffic, I'll be there
in about 20 minutes. Okay.
Vegas?
Hmm?
You know a Jim Brass?
( garbled radio transmission )
Jim.
Rick. Rick, what
are you doing here?
I'm here
for the HIDTA conference.
Buddy of mine
from L.A.P.D. told me
there was a new captain in town,
stirring things up.
What are you doing here?
Ah, it's a long sad story, man.
Have anything to do
with a feisty little blonde
named Ellie?
She's not a
blonde anymore.
Let's check out the car.
Captain Annie
Kramer,
this is
Warrick Brown
from Las Vegas.
Good to meet you.
BROWN:
Good to
meet you.
Matt Glazer,
L.A.P.D. Crime Lab.
Hey, Jim Brass.
BROWN:
Well,
I thought L.A. was
all about car culture.
This reminds me of home.
GLAZER:
Trunk's been stripped clean.
Too clean.
Oh, they missed a spot.
Looks like two large
caliber bullet holes.
BROWN:
But a bullet hole
wouldn't make those markings.
What is that?
I don't know.
Looks like a tool marking.
Let's haul it back
to impound and find out.
I'll be in touch.
Thanks.
BROWN:
Hey, you know, uh,
Jim, I'm here all weekend.
If you need anything,
don't hesitate to call.
Pleasure meeting you.
Same here.
Remember, what happens
in L.A., stays in L.A.
( chuckles )
You still a
Scotch man?
I'll take a rain check.
( garbled radio transmission )
Hey, baby, you want to party?
Ellie...
Oh, I can't ever trust you.
All I did was ask you
to make a call.
How's the beach house?
Go to hell.
I have
information
about your friend, Dakota.
Get in.
But I'm not playing 20 questions
with you.
( police siren sounds abruptly)
So, did you find her body?
No.
But we found
the car.
So she could still be alive?
We found blood
in the trunk.
No, no, no, she's alive.
I can feel it.
Look, do you have anything
with her DNA on it,
like a hair brush
or toothbrush or...?
No.
We keep all that stuff
in our purse.
How about clothes or sheets
or pillowcases, like that?
We share everything else.
Even the bed?
I told you
I'm not playing that game.
If the lab
doesn't have
anything to match the blood to,
then we'll never know.
That's it.
( sniffles )
Come on, let's get some dinner,
huh?
You look hungry.
Wait. Blood.
We went and got tested
last week
at the Free Clinic on Ivar.
Maybe they keep it.
Tested for what?
What do you think?
Don't you use
protection?
Guys pay extra for bareback.
( sighs )
You're a lot
smarter than that, Ellie.
Come on.
Yeah, well, just because
you want me to be smarter
and sweeter and safer
doesn't mean I am.
And I got to go.
Don't go away.
Guess you know how to find me
if you hear anything.
Don't-Don't leave,
don't leave.
You're one to talk.
All my life,
that's all you did, walk out.
Now we're gonna
Norman Rockwell it?
Look around, Dad.
It's too late.
Don't leave.
Leave me alone.
Ellie. Ellie!
Here at the clinic,
we pride ourselves
a confidential relationship
with our patients.
This is a highly
unusual request.
I understand,
but we're investigating
a possible homicide here.
We found blood
in the trunk of a car.
We have reason to believe
it could be Sasha Reynolds',
street name Dakota.
We're not interested
in whether it's
positive or negative.
We need it for the DNA.
How many do you need?
Ten.
Twelve.
Is that all
the help they get?
These kids come from
all over the place
with stars in their eyes.
While they're waiting
to be discovered,
they still got
to pay their rent.
They do a bump to
turn their first trick.
Next they're turning tricks
to get their next bump.
We do what we can.
You do what you do.
( phone rings )
Excuse me.
KRAMER ( into phone ):
Yeah. Kramer.
Good luck.
Good luck to you, too, Doctor.
You're kidding me.
Terrific. Okay.
We're on it. Bye.
We got an R.O. on the car.
( sighs )
( rings doorbell )
Captain Kramer.
Hey, Todd.
What's up?
I, uh, stumbled
across something.
Thought I'd pay you
a house call.
You missing a car?
Yeah, it was stolen.
You didn't report it.
No, I didn't.
What's that about?
Who are you?
I'm sorry, this is
an old friend of mine,
Captain Jim Brass, Vegas P.D.
Off the record?
Okay.
I went down the hill.
I was, um...
...lonely.
Partook of the services
of a certain kind
of young lady.
And while we were
getting acquainted,
I was carjacked.
( tapping )
I was set up.
It was probably her
pimp or drug dealer.
How'd you get up the hill?
Took a cab.
They didn't take your wallet?
The car was worth
more than the cash.
They knew what
they were doing.
It's a pretty sweet ride.
I'm still hung up on
why you didn't report it.
Captain, maybe I should
introduce myself.
Todd Piccone,
Assistant City Attorney.
Let's just say that
my reputation
is worth more
than my car.
Then maybe you should stop
having dates in your front seat.
You're right.
Lesson learned.
Thank you, Officer.
So the car was stripped,
I'm sure, uh...
South Central?
Koreatown? East L.A.?
Koreatown.
How would you know that?
'Cause, Captain,
that's where good cars
go to die in Los Angeles.
Hey, Todd, I don't suppose
we could take a look around?
You know, I'm
expecting company.
Now's not a good time.
We need to get a warrant
to get into that house.
Oh, yeah?
Well, we don't have enough.
Enough for a city attorney?
You know, give me a break.
You know how many cars
get jacked in L.A. every day?
He admitted to being
with a prostitute.
What makes you think
he's not telling
the truth about the rest?
He's hinky. I can feel it.
Your gut can talk to my judge.
Or better yet,
talk to Ellie.
You should.
You should get the 4-1-1
on Dakota from her.
There's an unreliable witness.
So what do we do now?
( sighs )
We eat steak.
Tony, how are
you doing?
Table for two, please,
in the back, if you could.
What are we
doing here again?
I'm doing you a big favor.
Annie, hello.
Hey, Judge Peters.
What a nice surprise.
Nice to see you.
Good to see you.
How's that porterhouse?
Eh, I haven't
started yet.
Gentlemen, I'd like
you to meet an old
friend of mine,
Captain Jim Brass, LVPD.
Hey.
This is Judge Silvio Peters,
Councilman Joe Cohen.
Judge, Councilman.
Comptroller
Daniel Reichmann,
and Vic Patterson.
Hey, Vic, how are you doing?
Soon to be Mayor.
( laughing )
Hey, you
know what?
We shot a couple episodes
of my show in Vegas.
You remember that?
Right.
The Eagle.
Yeah, you guys were great.
You always treated us
really well.
Well, we try.
Remember how great
he was as that cop?
( laughs )
Like he was playing you.
( all laugh )
Well, that's not easy.
Listen, since I happened
to run into you...
We found Todd Piccone's car
just off of Vermont.
Had bullet holes
and blood in the trunk.
He claims it was stolen,
but I'm hoping
that I could get a look
around his house a bit
You know what?
Let me get you
an autograph or something.
Little something for me.
And a little something for you.
If you had enough
for a warrant,
you wouldn't be here.
You'd be on your cell phone,
calling me from Tommy Burger.
Finish your steak
before it gets cold.
There you are.
I'm touched. Thank you, man.
Thank you.
Gentlemen.
Enjoy your lunch,
gentlemen.
Nice to see you.
Strike one, your turn.
( TV playing loudly )
Oh.
Well, if it isn't Dick Tracy
and his little sidekick,
Nancy Drew.
We're here on official business.
Just let us in.
Vote Vic Patterson.
Put some action
back in government.
You and Dakota
have the same pimp?
No. We don't have a pimp.
We're independent.
I can see that.
Look, if she were gonna
pull a con with some guy,
who would it be?
She's not like that.
So other than her customers,
there's, what,
no men in her life?
You and she are...
Roommates.
Look, you can be cute,
or you can help us
find your friend.
What's it gonna be?
Well, there's this guy
named Ronnie, all right?
He was kind of
like her boyfriend.
Sometimes he would get jealous
when she turned tricks.
Where do we find this Casanova?
Look, you know
I can't go in there
without probable cause
or a warrant.
You're not gonna arrest me
for breaking and entering,
are you?
( sighs )
Jimmy, what are you
hoping to find in there?
I'll know it when I see it.
BRASS:
Smelled something
in the hallway.
That's why we
broke in, right?
Yep.
KRAMER:
L.A. has over 200 criminalists.
You got to bring your own guy?
BRASS:
Well, Rick is like a vampire.
He needs to be invited in.
If this goes to court,
Warrick's going to have
to come back and testify.
Well, you got beaches, bikinis.
Free trip to L.A.? I'm down.
So we got coffee filters,
cough medicine, matches,
camping fuel...
hot plates.
Are you thinking
what I'm thinking?
If this is a meth lab,
then there would be free iodine
coated all over these walls.
And if Matt packed
this kit right,
I would have some
spray starch...
...that would react
with the iodine.
Turning it a nice Dodger blue.
Yes, it's a meth lab.
So meth dealer
and his hooker girlfriend
looking for a quick score.
Carjacking's
not such a stretch.
Neighbors are lucky
he didn't blow
the whole building up.
BRASS:
No guns, no blood.
Nothing in plain sight
linking him to Dakota's
disappearance.
Well, we'll haul him in
on manufacturing.
We'll get what we can
out of him.
Jail would be an improvement
over this hole.
KRAMER:
Drop the gun!
Now!
BRASS:
Put the gun down.
Bad guys go away.
You're trying to rob me?
Drop the gun!
I'm being robbed by cops?
You're trying to rob me!
Don't make me
shoot you.
Put the gun down.
Come on.
( sobbing )
( grunts )
How long has
the body been here?
...about three
and a half hours now.
OFFICER:
Jogger found her, called it in.
Description matched
your broadcast.
Looks like body gas
has brought her to the top.
God, somebody beat
the pulp out of her.
Any leads?
Yeah, he's detoxing
in the tank.
This is why I don't
believe in easy money.
Ellie.
You have to identify the body.
I'm going to be sick.
No, come here. Come on.
Look, I just need an answer.
Is this your friend?
Okay.
( cell phone rings )
( sighs )
Brass.
Family business?
That is a wedding
or a funeral,
or a bar mitzvah.
That is not permission
to become a vice cop
in another jurisdiction.
Get back here now.
Who you been talking to?
Not that it matters.
The police chief called me
after Judge Peters called him.
I hear they do a nice
T-bone at Musso's.
Look, my kid's in trouble, Ben.
Well, if she's not dead,
you get your ass back here.
Look, write me up
for insubordination.
I can't come back now.
KRAMER:
You have a prior.
Mandatory minimum
for manufacturing--
ten to 15.
You start to talk
about Dakota,
we'll see what we can do.
Dakota?
( sniffing )
Now, what that crazy bitch
got to do with this,
huh?
What, she snitched on me?
Not before you killed her.
I didn't kill nobody.
You have a relationship
with her?
Yeah, we kicked it,
all right? We kicked it.
Look, I would never kill no girl
with all that good...
All right, look,
let's just say
I enjoyed having her live
downstairs from me, man.
( chuckles ):
Listen...
She knew when to open her mouth
and when to keep it closed.
Now, her girl, Jersey...
Oh, God,
the best mouth I ever had.
Mmm.
That mouth gave me
a lot of pleasure.
It just never stopped.
Where were you two nights ago?
Out.
Be more specific!
I-I-I was seeing customers,
all right?
Dakota?
No.
You like BMWs?
Bitch, what the f...
what are you talking about?!
Watch your mouth!
( sniffing )
I'll lay it out for you.
Come on, man.
All right.
So, how was he?
What do you mean?
You wasn't supposed
to do him.
( screams )
( gunshots )
You want me to admit to a murder
I didn't commit
so you can reduce a drug charge?
( sniffing )
What, you high, right?
Y-Y-You must me high.
I'm sorry you
had to hear that.
What did he say?
Dad?
You were right; I
shouldn't have come.
I told you
he didn't do it.
It was that guy in the car.
You've got to find him.
Don't you understand?
We just pulled your best
friend out of a lake.
I mean, it was just
luck it wasn't you.
Yeah, well, it wasn't me.
Yeah, not today.
But look at you.
You've turned yourself
into a disposable human being.
Don't you get it?
You're nothing but plumbing.
What, you're going to send me
to my room and ground me?
Have a patrol car
pick me up at prom?
Or spank me?
Okay.
You're right.
I messed up.
But I'm just trying to do
the best that I can.
I wish you could say
the same thing.
Clothes test positive
for lead wipe.
Confirmed bullet hole.
Did her DNA match the blood
that you swabbed from the trunk?
Yeah, but the autopsy report
said she wasn't shot.
So, what's
with the bullet holes?
Clean-up.
WARRICK:
One bullet exited.
Is the other hole to the left
or to the right?
About seven and a half,
eight inches up.
That's the gas tank.
GLAZER:
Looks like a .45.
Big, fat and slow.
Lucky for us,
it didn't have enough power
to go through-and-through
the gas tank.
Yeah. Look at that.
No wonder those hood rats
couldn't get the car started.
It won't run on blood.
Well, that tweaker you busted
just got bumped off
the top of the list.
He had a nine millimeter.
You think you could run this
through IBIS?
We do have that here.
Hey, Doc, did you get my fax?
Yeah, I did.
Yeah, well,
it's all Greek to me.
Can you help me out?
Mmm, sure, of course.
But I thought you were asked
to come home.
I'll be home tomorrow.
I hope she was worth it.
What do you mean?
I don't know;
I mean, you put
your career on the line.
I assume
there's a woman involved.
What are you, a detective now?
All right;
let's take a look at this.
FX, OC-- that's a fractured
osseocartilaginous--
that's a broken nose.
FX, ST, CL-- sternal clavicle,
and LAC, SDH on her head--
lacerations
and subdural hematomas.
Cause of death?
It looks like exsanguination.
So, she was beaten
and left to die?
Beaten with something specific.
The L.A. coroner noted
repetitive
patterned contusions.
Anything else?
Yeah, the coroner's assistant
who prepped her body
collected a green, waxy
substance
under her fingernails.
Also, looks like he found
concrete chunks
in a bag tied to her waist.
Probably what they used
to weigh her down in the lake.
You want to say
I told you so?
No. I just want it
to be over with
and have a happy ending.
PICCONE:
What the hell's going on?
What's up?
Sorry, Todd.
We got the warrant;
we have to search.
You got to be
kidding me.
Wha...?
I just had the
floors polished.
Will you at least
take your shoes off, please?
I sleep in my shoes, Todd.
This guy married?
No.
Mm-hmm.
Anyone else's gaydar
going off?
Well, he did have
a female hooker in his ride.
Well, maybe he swings both ways.
Why, because he has
this nice shag carpet?
This carpet's wet.
Oh, yeah.
That's a lot of blood.
How much, you figure?
I don't know--
two, three pints?
Nobody loses that much blood
and lives.
She died in this room.
I don't think
we'll be able to get
any DNA off this.
The carpet solvents
probably compromised the sample.
She was beaten multiple times.
There must be
some spatter or cast-off.
I can't get a clean read.
You know what?
It's this metal surface.
It's giving us a false positive.
Does anyone see a remote?
Yeah, got one
right here.
Could you hit the input button
until we find a blue screen?
Yeah.
Look at that.
MATT:
I'll get a sample
for DNA.
Nice place.
BRASS:
Mmm.
Who needs
three trash bins?
Someone with a lot of dirt.
Wow.
Big party.
Tequila.
Whiskey.
Gin.
Absinthe.
BRASS:
The coroner
found green wax
under Dakota's fingernails.
( sighing ):
Yes, I solicited her.
So, you admit
to having sexual relations
with Sasha Reynolds,
a.k.a. Dakota?
PICCONE:
No.
But money changed hands?
I paid her $60.
For what?
I drove her back to my house
and introduced her to a friend.
And then?
I have no knowledge
of what happened after that.
Does this friend have a name?
Mmm. A big one.
You know, Todd, I think
you're smart enough
to recognize
consciousness of guilt.
Blood in your house,
in your car.
All of which
was cleaned up.
This friend
worth going to prison for?
Turn off that mic.
( no audio )
Officer.
He invoked.
( brakes squealing )
BRASS:
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
I wanted to catch you
before you left.
I got a look
at the print results
from the bottles
that we collected just before
I was escorted out
and asked to leave the lab.
They say why?
No, but I think I know why.
It's like Chinatown, Jim.
So visiting hours
are over, Doctor.
It's time to go.
What about Ellie?
What about her?
Well, she's the only one
who can I.D.
Todd Piccone as the driver.
Well, I couldn't get much
out of Annie, but I don't think
Piccone killed Dakota--
it wasn't his scene.
I don't know. He's involved.
It's his house.
It's his car. It's his party.
Who's going to believe
a tweaker hooker?
You better hope nobody, or
she'll be taking a dirt nap.
( phone ringing )
( on answering machine ):
Hey, it's Ellie. Leave a message
and I'll get back
at you when I can.
BRASS:
Yeah, uh, Ellie,
it's, it's your dad.
Listen, you were right
about the guy
He's a pretty important person
with pretty important friends.
So, uh, do me a favor.
Don't go out tonight.
Okay?
( tape beeps off )
If Dakota had wax
under her fingernails,
I think she must have been doing
more than just pouring.
Self defense?
( screaming )
Who was she defending against?
From the prints
that we got off the bottle,
I have a list of six suspects.
Silvio Peters, Joe Cohen...
Wait a minute.
Silvio Peters?
He's a judge.
He's on the list?
Yeah.
Daniel Reichmann,
Vic Patterson,
Todd Piccone,
Parker Smythe.
They're all in AFIS?
Yeah. I mean, you can be
in AFIS for a lot of reasons.
After 9-11, anyone who works
in a government building.
Right. I mean, doctors,
lawyers, right.
Or anyone who has a permit
to carry a concealed weapon.
You know what?
( dial tone )
( phone ringing )
Hello!
Hey, Nicky.
Where are you?
Are you near a computer?
Can you do me a favor?
Yeah, sure.
How's the conference going?
Uh, it's intense.
I have a list
of suspects, all in AFIS.
I want to know if any of them
have a permit
to carry concealed.
Okay, shoot.
Silvio Peters, Joe Cohen,
Daniel Reichmann, Vic Patterson.
Mm-hmm.
Todd Piccone,
Parker Smythe.
Vic Patterson does.
Are we talking
about "The Eagle"?
From that TV show?
Yeah. What kind of gun?
A .45, same kind he uses in
all his cheeseball shoot-outs.
Can you give me anything else?
Yeah, I can run
the serial number
through Automated
Firearms Service,
give you the history.
Colt sold it
to the Beverly Hills Gun Club,
who, in turn,
sold it to "The Eagle"
on September 28, 1983.
If he shops there,
maybe he shoots there.
BRASS:
You know, I'm just
in town for a couple of days.
It's always been a dream of mine
to shoot at the famous
Beverly Hills Gun Club.
I wonder if I
could get a day pass?
For Las Vegas's finest?
Sure thing.
Look, um...
Tell me something.
You know, is it,
is it true that, uh,
you know, the actor, Vic
Patterson, shoots here?
Not really supposed to
give out member info.
But between you and me?
The man is a damn fine shot.
No kidding.
Matter of fact,
he won several of
our competitions.
Wow.
You want to rent
or shoot your own?
Um...
I'll shoot what Vic shoots.
You shooting, too?
Nah, I'm just
going to hang back.
Let him blow off some steam.
Ain't that something?
Yeah, it's something.
Right this way.
Hey, Jim.
I just got your bullet.
I'm running it
through IBIS right now.
Not gonna ask how you got it.
So, did you meet him?
Yeah.
Ha-ha. Yeah.
Did you get
his autograph for me?
You know, actually I did,
and if you get me a match,
you might be able
to meet him at his trial.
Do you think that would make his
autograph worth more? Or less?
We got a match.
Entered by Matt Glazer, LAPD.
Recovered from a BMW gas tank.
Open investigation,
homicide-related.
Great, great.
Thanks for all
your help. Thank you.
Sure.
Was that Nick?
Yeah. IBIS
confirmed the match.
We're good to go.
So, where you been?
In Hollywood,
thinking.
You know, even if Vic Patterson
did shoot up the car
with his gun,
that doesn't mean
he killed Dakota.
Just means he helped clean up.
She wasn't shot. She was beaten.
Yeah. We need a murder
weapon to nail his ass.
I got these photos
at a Hollywood
memorabilia shop for ten bucks.
Who do you see?
A jackass.
Look closer.
Look at the pistol grip...
and The Eagle.
You know,
these autopsy photos I saw
all got me thinking.
This one. Look at
the pattern contusions.
The gun is the murder weapon.
( shrieking )
Stop it! Stop it!
About six months ago,
this strung-out hooker
comes into the PD,
beat to crap,
screaming that Vic
Patterson had done it,
and her wounds looked
a lot like this.
I figured it
was her pimp,
she was sniffing around
for a settlement.
Sent her home
with an ice pack.
I'm sorry.
I knew you thought
this guy was a winner.
I worked my whole life
to sit at the table
with the big boys...
only to find out
that the food is poisoned.
You know, the only record
of this investigation
is in that envelope,
and half the evidence collection
won't stand up in court,
so it's your call.
How many years
you got on?
Eight back
in Jersey,
15 here.
Well, that's
23 combined.
That's a lot of innings.
I mean, the worse they can do
is make you retire.
What am I gonna do then? Knit?
This is it, Jimmy.
This is all I got.
Well, if it's all you got,
then you got to do it right.
Remember
Mike O'Toole?
From Vice?
Of course I do.
Broke my heart when I
found out he was dirty.
Yeah, he was a heartbreaker.
Broke up my marriage.
I thought I did that.
Well, Nancy used our affair
because she was
looking for a way out,
but for me...
I mean,
I guess I'm old-fashioned.
You know, a bad marriage
is better than no marriage...
I thought.
And you thought
a kid would help?
You see, that's the thing.
I didn't have a kid.
Yeah, you did.
I don't see Mike O'Toole
out here helping her.
Well...
I spent a good chunk
of my life
looking the other way.
I mean, so much so
that my neck got tired.
So I, you know, I got a divorce.
I, uh... turned Mike
and his crew in.
Started over in Vegas.
Ellie.
She's like the unfinished
business of all that.
So it's my neck now.