Hi.
Hey.
Husband and wife got into it.
Hmm.
What set them off?
She caught him
with a hooker in their bed.
She cut him.
He killed her.
What about the hooker?
She grabbed his wallet
and took off.
I caught the guy
just sitting on a curb.
I swabbed his hands
for blood spatter.
I am super backed up.
Can this wait till tomorrow?
He's not going anywhere.
Thanks, Mia.
Yeah...
Oh, hey, guys.
I could really use a drink.
You want to join me?
I'm buying.
I'd love a drink,
but we made plans, though?
You did?
Tomorrow.
Rain check.
All right.
Okay.
( crowd chatter )
No way you were never married.
Oh, let me guess.
You were young,
he seemed more mature
than he really was,
he swept you off your feet,
and, uh, he let you fall.
Bruised, but not broken.
Get you another one?
No, I'm good, thanks.
So you're divorced?
You?
Yeah.
She seemed more mature
than she really was,
swept me off my feet.
( laughs )
Kids?
Uh, yes, I have a daughter.
If she's got her mother's looks,
you're in trouble.
( whispering )
( chuckling )
If I don't get home soon,
I will be in trouble.
Thanks. I needed this.
If you're blowing me off,
no worries.
But if you're not...
...give me a call.
Wait a second.
Let me walk you to your car.
( moaning )
I can't do this tonight. I...
I'll call you.
What the hell
is your problem?
( grunts softly )
Go to hell.
( Catherine groans )
( exhales )
You're not worth
the trouble.
( panting )
( phone ringing )
( groans and sighs )
( ringing continues )
( phone beeps )
Hello.
( whispering ):
Mom, Mom.
Grissom just called.
I've got to go in.
I'm backing up grave.
( sniffs )
What?
Vodka, with an Altoid chaser.
I brushed my teeth.
What did you do,
walk into a door?
Hey, listen,
Lindsey's got a dentist
appointment before school.
I wrote all the information
down in the kitchen.
Okay.
Okay?
Thank you.
Oh, good grief.
( garbled radio transmission )
( garbled radio transmission
continues )
I appreciate this.
Everyone's out.
I'm short.
You're welcome.
( camera shutter clicking )
WILLOWS:
Clotted blood hasn't
retracted yet.
She hasn't been dead long.
We have an I.D.?
Yeah, building manager
took a peek.
ID'd her as Alice Granger.
Apartment 207.
Moved here about
a month ago.
David,
you want to take the, uh,
jacket off her face?
What happened to you?
I walked into a door.
Can we not talk about it?
Gunshot.
Looks like
a small caliber weapon.
No cartridge casings.
No purse, no car.
I put out a BOLO.
Possible car jacking.
( whimpering and crying )
( gunshot )
Usually when a killer
covers the victim's face,
it suggests familiarity.
An act of
contrition.
Maybe she knew her attacker.
Great. Carjacked by a friend.
( phone ringing )
Vartann.
Yeah, got it.
We got a 20 on her car.
You go, I'll stay with the body,
I'll meet you there.
( sirens wailing )
You see anybody
get out of the car?
No, sir.
Saw it on patrol.
You checked
the bar?
I waited for you.
No one's exited
since we got here.
Okay, I'll
see you inside.
Can you open it up?
Thank you.
( garbled radio transmission )
I found a gun under the seat.
.22 Beretta.
Well, that's small
enough to be the weapon.
VARTANN:
So he shoots her,
takes her car,
and stops off for a drink.
He could still be in there.
VARTANN:
Let's find out.
Did you hear the one
about the cop and the monkey
who walk into a bar?
I'm not in the mood.
Neither was the monkey.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
Except for the Saturn,
all the cars in the lot
are accounted for.
Okay.
VARTANN:
Hi. You recognize
this girl?
WOMAN:
Yeah. She's been in
a few times.
How about last night?
Yeah.
Throwing them back
pretty good, too.
You see anybody hassle her?
She was getting
a lot of attention.
She didn't really
seem to mind.
Did you see her leave
with anyone?
No. She was wasted.
Had me call
her a cab.
VARTANN:
Around what time?
We were
really slammed.
Maybe 2:00... 2:30.
Which cab company?
Lucky Cab.
Well, that would explain
why her car's still here.
Doesn't explain the gun.
( whispering ):
Thank you.
Why? Do I know you?
ROBBINS:
I dug it out of the right
frontal cortex.
The bullet lacerated
the right occipital lobe.
It crossed the mid-line,
destroying the vital structures
of the brain
and bounced off
the left frontal calvarium.
Hmm.
This is a .25 caliber.
What, disappointed?
We found a .22
in the victim's car.
This just ruled that out
as the murder weapon.
So shoot me.
Stellate tear
means close contact.
See the muzzle impression
around the entrance wound?
This could help identify
the firearm.
This is an unusual
point of entry.
Yeah, I measured the trajectory.
Ten to 15 degrees
left of vertical.
Shooter would have
to be standing over her.
Which would make him a giant,
except for this.
Abrasions on her knees.
So... maybe she was kneeling.
Begging for her life.
SIDLE:
So, Judge Wilson
tells me I'd
have better luck
with a blue suit
than a gray suit.
What is that?
Do you think
he meant that?
Do you think he was
flirting with me or...?
I thought judges were supposed
to be color blind.
SIDLE:
Yeah, right.
That's cute.
WILLOWS:
I found some particulate
on the jacket.
Not sure what it is.
I'll get it to Hodges.
Pocket contents:
credit card, car keys,
lipstick and one matchbook.
Can I see that?
There's no name,
just a phone number.
Give me a call.
I'll have Vartann run it down.
You know, I've got to
go pick up Lindsey.
Could you cover for me?
Sure.
WILLOWS:
Thanks.
Tell her I said, "Hey."
Lindsey!
Yeah.
What happened to the trash?
I took it out, like
you always tell me to.
It's Thursday.
Uh, hello,
Mom, you okay?
Yeah, I'm great.
Are you sure about that?
You want me
to be the babysitter,
but you want me
to be deaf and blind, too?
Can't get into
this now, Mother.
I'm in a jam.
You haven't seen
your daughter all week.
Save the sermon.
I was a working mother,
too, you know?
( to herself ):
There but for
the grace of God...
Don't just assume
that my time
means nothing to me.
Damn it.
Catherine?
I threw something away.
It's gone.
( cell phone rings )
You're throwing
more than you know away.
Yeah?
Uh...
Yeah, just wait
till I get there.
Yeah.
Mom...
Go. Go.
I'll be here
when you get back.
Results from
Alice Granger's jacket.
Found trace elements of iron,
chromium, manganese and carbon.
Metals.
More specific,
automotive sheet metal.
The metallic balls
would've been
released into the air
during the welding process.
( buzzing )
So you're saying
our killer has metal balls?
Yes... maybe.
Turns out that the victim
worked in a car dealership,
so she could've gotten
metal balls on the job.
And just in case
you're wondering,
working here,
I'm developing them, too.
Yo.
Oh. What do you
have for me?
Bullet is a .25 auto caliber
Winchester full metal jacket.
You can't shoot .25s
from a .22 caliber pistol.
I know.
Which means the semi-automatic
you found in Alice Granger's car
isn't the murder weapon.
I know.
Okay, well, did you know
that the gun is registered
to a Douglas Granger?
I don't understand why
you're asking me this.
I'm her brother,
not her husband.
You still own
a lot of guns.
A .22 pistol,
Colt .25,
among others.
That's right.
We found the .22 in Alice's car.
( sighs )
If she carried it in her purse
instead of leaving it
in the car,
she might still be alive.
I don't follow.
I gave her the gun last week.
Then what?
You shot her with your .25?
Are you insane?
It's no mystery
who killed her.
Jeff Simon, her ex-boyfriend.
Guy was stalking her.
She changed her
phone number,
changed jobs,
moved a half dozen times.
No matter where she went,
there he was.
Last week, I was over
at her new apartment.
Jerk sitting in his car,
in front of the building.
Is that when you
gave her the gun?
( sighs )
Taught her how to shoot it.
Helped her get
a restraining order.
Got zero help
from you guys.
"Catch him in the act."
That's all we heard.
You know where we can
find Jeff Simon?
Yeah.
We used to be friends.
( distant tool buzzing )
( buzzing grows louder )
Hey, I'm looking
for Jeff Simon.
( loud buzzing )
( turns off saw )
Jeff Simon?
Are you Jeff Simon?
Yeah.
When's the last time
you saw Alice Granger?
Before the restraining
order kicked in.
Come on.
This is just a big
misunderstanding, Officer.
Well, I'm glad
you feel that way.
You mind if we take
a look in your truck?
What did Alice say I did now?
Where is it?
I don't get a break
for another half hour.
Look, we can get a court order.
You can look
anywhere you want.
Just give Alice
a message for me.
I love her, and
I want her back.
Look, buddy, she's dead.
What the...
I swear, I haven't been...
I haven't been anywhere near her
since her brother broke us up.
I'm gonna check out his truck.
( beeping )
( speed dialing )
Gil, the suspect has a laptop in
his vehicle that has a GPS unit
that's honed in on the lab.
Well, you can't track
a static location.
It has to be something mobile.
I know. That's why I'm calling.
( phone rings )
Yeah.
GRISSOM:
You were right.
We found a GPS transmitter
under the rear bumper
of the girl's car.
Thanks.
He was tracking her car.
Let's bring him in.
Get up.
You are a real prize.
Jeff, your prints
are all over that box,
which means one count
felony stalking.
That's seven to ten.
Murder two adds a quarter.
Now, you plead out now,
you'll live to see parole.
I didn't kill Alice.
I loved her.
Is that your idea of love?
Stalking her with a GPS unit?
I wasn't stalking her.
I wo-worried about her.
So that
restraining order
she filed against you was
because you're a nice guy.
Let me tell you about Alice.
She... liked to party...
...barely ate, hardly slept,
didn't want to admit
she had a drinking problem.
She needed me to
look out for her.
Well, there's a problem with
your story. She called a cab.
I'm telling you, Alice got
into a Chrysler or... a Buick?
It was blue,
maybe black.
And the guy
she was with,
maniac driver. Complete
moron.
Wait, wait. You...
you followed them?
I had to.
But I was pulled
over by the cops.
They kept me on-on the side
of the road for over an hour.
What time was this?
It was around 2:00.
It was a buck-fifty ticket.
I'm innocent.
Cut the crap.
We found trace amounts
of automotive sheet metal
on her clothing.
You work around cars.
If Alice picked it up from you,
you were in violation
of the T.R.O.
Lady, until we broke up,
we spent every waking minute
together.
She'd come over to my shop
on her lunch break
just to get some.
It was over, Jeff.
She didn't want you to be
her lover, her protector.
She didn't want you
within a hundred yards.
Whatever trace
from you we found
on her was fresh.
She worked around cars, too.
I'm telling you, I'm innocent!
You were living a fantasy,
thinking you still had a chance.
When reality set in,
you killed her.
I only did one thing wrong.
I didn't protect her
from that guy.
What did this guy
look like?
Sleazy bastard.
Slight build, dark hair.
I think he had a leather jacket.
( chuckling )
GRISSOM:
Okay.
Do you have a minute?
I got a problem in DNA.
WILLOWS:
Okay, uh, it really is
only gonna take a minute.
Um, I just need to have
a conversation with you.
( sighs )
I processed the swabs
from the wife
who found her husband
in the hooker case.
Right.
Two contributions.
Two?
One was a match
to the wife's DNA.
The other was from
an unknown male.
I found the same unknown
male contribution
on the swabs from the
Alice Granger homicide.
Well, it's unlikely
that they're connected.
They're not.
I also matched that
unknown male contribution
to a rape kit
from the day shift.
Cross contamination?
That's why I raised the alarm.
I was able to narrow the time
frame to the last 48 hours.
Are you saying that all the DNA
evidence from the last two days
has to be resubmitted
and retested?
We don't have any choice.
It's potentially
all contaminated.
Document everything.
Hey. Your suspect,
Jeff Simon,
just got released
from custody.
How the hell did that happen?
His alibi checked out.
I talked to the cop
who pulled him over
for speeding, at 2:15 a.m.,
right around T.O.D.
It's proof he lost track of her.
They jammed him
for over an hour.
I mean, made him walk the line,
gave him a breathalyzer,
the whole nine.
Guy confessed to stalking.
At least you
got him on that.
Which they'll
probably kick down
to a misdemeanor
because she's dead.
Hey. Phone number
on the matchbook panned out.
Guy's on his way
to P.D.
You got a name?
Was it necessary to
show up at my office?
Try the phone.
I'm an officer
of the court.
Mr. Novak...
do you recognize
this telephone number?
That's my work number.
Did you write it
on the matchbook?
I may have. What's this about?
A homicide.
That matchbook
was found
in a dead
woman's pocket.
This the only evidence
linking me to the victim?
This will go
much easier
if you just answer
our questions.
Oh, yeah? Easier for whom?
Why didn't you
write your name on it?
I'm a memorable guy.
Why not your home number?
This is getting tedious.
At bars, I give out my work
number to weed out the crazies.
This is Alice Granger.
Do you know her?
I bought her a drink last night.
VARTANN:
Okay, why don't you, uh,
walk us through your evening?
Start with
"I left the office..."
I was deposing a witness.
Left the office late.
Stopped at
the Peppermill
for a burger.
Medium rare.
No onions.
Got to The Highball
around 11:00.
Met this redhead.
Bought her a drink and...
( clearing throat )
Mr. Novak...
I'm Catherine Willows.
CSI.
You want to know
what happened next?
Ask the redhead.
At a bar that time of night,
we're all after
the same thing, aren't we?
I came onto her.
She was into me.
I know when a woman
is going to give way
and believe me,
she was there.
And then what?
I walked her out.
I put my arm
around her waist.
She moved in.
One minute she's got
her tongue down my throat.
The next, she puts
on the brakes.
She's a bitch
and a tease.
We should ask
for his clothes.
Black leather jacket,
black T-shirt, jeans.
What else should we
ask him, Catherine?
This is what I was
trying to tell you.
Yeah, but you didn't,
so now I'm way behind.
Is he telling the truth?
He's not lying about anything
that pertains to me.
He hit you.
No, it was an accident.
But... by the time it happened,
he wasn't who I thought
he was, and...
that scared me.
VARTANN:
Eyewitness claimed that a man
matching your description left
the bar with the victim.
Drove off in
a dark-colored, four-door sedan.
What do you drive, Mr. Novak?
Look,
I'm innocent,
but it's in my best interest
to retain counsel.
We're done here.
You have to
recuse yourself
from processing evidence
This guy's a lawyer.
He could claim
prejudicial treatment.
Your whole life
will become public record.
I have nothing
to be ashamed of.
We all live
in glass houses, Catherine.
You gotta be careful
where you take your shower.
Catherine.
Just walk me through your
interaction with the suspect.
I met Adam
Novak in a bar
called The Highball.
Were you drinking?
I had one cocktail, on his tab.
He walked me out to my car.
Things got physical.
Could you
define "physical"?
I believe that I outlined
the specifics in my memo.
Catherine, you know
what I'm asking,
and it's not in the memo.
I didn't have sex with him,
though he clearly wanted it.
And you didn't?
I went out
after shift to unwind.
I even invited Warrick
and Nick to come along.
They had other plans.
All right. So...
when you put on the brakes,
Mr. Novak... got angry.
Yeah.
I got into my car.
He went back inside.
Hey, El, will you do me
a favor and call me a cab?
Thanks.
This is just a theory, but...
she was drunk,
probably more compliant
than I was.
He walked her outside.
He waited with her for the taxi,
offered her a ride.
BROWN:
I hate to break
up the party.
Catherine,
you got a 419
in Seven Hills.
I'll grab the kits
and meet you outside.
We'll finish
this later?
Guess we'll have to.
Look familiar?
Yeah.
Like the other night.
You got an I.D. on the vic?
Yeah. Holly Pearson, 31, single.
She lived across the street.
Car was locked.
Keys and purse
were accounted for.
Found them in the mailbox
along with her mail.
WARRICK:
Any indication of
sexual assault?
Well, her clothes
and underwear are undisturbed.
Can you remove the jacket?
Sure.
Looks like
a small-caliber gunshot wound...
like the first victim.
Location of the entry
wound is different.
Slug's still inside her.
Grave is working
a case with similarities.
That victim
left a bar called The Highball
shortly before
she was killed.
I'm wondering
if Holly went out last night.
I'm on it.
Thanks.
There's two sets
of shoe prints...
With a bit of distance
between the strides.
Which means
they were both running.
BROWN:
Got some shell casings.
Well, there's
only one shot
fired in Grissom's case.
It was close contact.
He couldn't miss.
I'm thinking that
she was attacked
near her house...
and then made a run for it.
( gunshots )
Got a courthouse keycard.
For the parking lot.
I wonder where
Holly Pearson works.
Adam Novak's a
public defender.
Let's run his prints
against this.
Guys? I found
a couple
of the victim's
coworkers.
They said she was
at The Highball last night.
Got them coming
into PD.
Holly was just promoted.
Youngest systems
analyst at the bank
and we were celebrating.
She wasn't exactly
a party animal.
We practically
forced her to go out.
Any guys come on strong?
Yeah. We collected
numbers all night.
Anyone write their number
on a matchbook?
I got, uh... business cards.
So... you're having
a good time and...
Holly had had enough.
Yeah. We carpooled,
so she took a cab home.
I'd like to show you
some pictures.
See if you recognize anyone.
( sniffles )
He bought us a round.
He tried to get friendly.
When Holly left,
did you see that man again?
Actually, no.
Hell of a backlog,
here, Doc.
Yeah. Traffic
pile-up on I-15.
Holly Pearson?
Mm.
C.O.D.'s a one shot to
the back of the head.
Absence of gun
powder and stippling
suggests a non-contact wound.
Dug this out.
.25 caliber.
It's the same
as the first victim.
You know, I got something
you might find interesting.
I emptied the stomach
and she hadn't eaten for hours.
A small amount
of white zinfandel--
Less than a glass,
vintage undetermined,
and a tiny
scrap of meat.
Take a look.
Surface tissue
of a human tongue.
Those are the taste buds.
She bit her attacker...
when he tried to kiss her.
This woman did not go gently
into that good night.
Heard you may be looking
at a second victim?
Yeah.
Bullets from both homicides
are from the same gun.
I just got off the phone
with Courthouse Security.
That keycard that you
and Catherine found
belongs a guy
named Adam Novak.
Only prints I found
on the card were his.
Well, let's call PD
and bring him in.
Mom, Lindsey,
go inside the house.
Believe it or not,
Catherine does know
how to say, "Hello,
how are you? Would you
like a cup of coffee?"
I was talking to your mother
about the case we're working.
Mom, we're fine.
Take Lindsey inside.
Let's go.
I don't,
I don't want to.
Lindsey.
Are you going to go out again?
No. I'm coming in.
I want to hear about your day.
It was a pleasure
meeting you.
What the hell
are you doing here?
I want to know
why you're setting me up,
manipulating evidence
to make me look guilty.
All because
I came on too strong?
I want you out of here.
I didn't get
my signals crossed.
You changed the play,
and you're screaming foul.
That's some power trip, babe.
Who's the
guilty one here?
You want to talk to
me, call your lawyer.
Set up an appointment
down at PD.
You think I killed her?
Back off.
You going to shoot me?
If you take one more step.
( siren wailing )
You bitch.
You came to my house.
GRISSOM:
Mr. Novak, would you stick
out your tongue, please?
What is this about?
Well, right now, it's
about his tongue.
And two
dead women.
We believe the
second victim,
Holly Pearson,
bit her
attacker's tongue.
Open up, please.
Uh-uh. Once more.
Thank you.
That's all I need.
Have a seat.
You comfortable?
We're going to be a while.
I know how this looks.
Adam, I...
I advise some
of the stupidest guys
that come through this room.
And it's my job is
to keep their mouths shut.
And I know
what you're thinking--
that I killed Alice Granger.
( whimpers )
( gunshot )
You're a mind reader.
I already admitted
that I picked her up
at a bar
the other night.
What I didn't mention,
and you didn't ask
was that I gave her a ride home.
It got hot and heavy.
We both got what we needed.
Then she said good night
and got out of the car.
I drove off.
Uh,
Do you have any
evidence at all
that refutes my client's
account, or suggests otherwise?
Our evidence pertains
to the second victim,
killed last night
with the same gun,
and we believe that a portion
of your client's tongue
was in her stomach.
I can explain that.
Oh? Really.
Her taxi never showed up.
I was drunk. Out of line.
Bad couple of days,
thanks to you guys.
I was looking
for a little release
and I chose the wrong girl.
And what happened next?
Her taxi finally showed up.
I spoke to both
the bartender at The Highball
and the cab company,
and a cab was ordered
and drove the victim home.
Mr. Novak, have you ever
been to Holly Pearson's house?
No. I have no idea
where she lived.
Then how do you explain
your courthouse keycard
which we found
near her body?
CSI matched the prints
on the card. Only yours.
Every attorney in the Public
Defenders Office
is issued one card.
Mine has never left my car.
I keep it in
the center console.
You don't need a warrant.
You have my permission
to check.
It should be there.
Well, that won't
be hard to verify,
because your car's
already at CSI.
Nick.
Hey.
The center console.
Was there a parking
lot car key inside?
No. Two sticks of gum
and a pack of condoms.
Why?
Suspect claims some
incriminating evidence
found at the second
crime scene wasn't his.
It looks like he was lying.
We got him.
I don't know how you're
going to take this,
but I think this car
was recently broken into.
These scratches...
they look fresh.
B&amp;E 101.
The Slim Jim.
Somebody could've
swiped his keycard.
And then locked
the car back up.
Novak wouldn't
be the wiser
until he drove into
the courthouse again.
Did you find any prints?
Smudges and partials,
inside and out.
Run 'em.
( soft electronic chirping )
( beep )
( metal grinding )
Let's run through
the night Alice died again.
We've been through this.
I have an alibi.
Your alibi only proves
you lost track of her.
You knew where
Alice lived.
Have you been
in Adam Novak's car recently?
No. I don't even
know an Adam Novak.
But you identified
his vehicle
as the car that Alice
left the bar in.
I didn't know whose car it was.
Then why did we find
your prints in it?
Maybe somebody's
trying to frame me.
No, but I think that you're
familiar with the concept.
You were obsessed with Alice,
and when you saw Adam
having at her, you flipped out.
I mean, here's a woman that you
can't get any traction with,
yet she's willing
to do a stranger
she picked up in a bar.
I mean, lucky for you,
The Highball
was Adam's second home.
The next night, you came back
and saw his car
in the parking lot.
Creative justice.
You could get them both.
It was just bad luck that Holly
Pearson met Adam that night.
You had no reason to kill her,
but you followed her home
and worked up the nerve.
You made one mistake, though.
The evidence that you used
to frame him
brought us back to you.
You figured out the source
of the contamination?
I got a positive result
off my negative control.
Matched the contamination.
Turns out
somebody at the manufacturer
forgot to put on their mask
and then sneezed or coughed
on what was supposed
to be a sterile product.
You have to collect
everyone's swabs.
Kits. Trucks. Vests.
Work stations.
How long till the new
shipment gets here?
It's on its way.
Until then, do it old school.
Gil.
I'd ask you out
for a drink,
but under
the circumstances,
it's, uh...
Okay, how long is
this going to go on?
I don't know, Catherine.
Gil, it was an act
of omission.
How many times have we heard
a public defender say that?
I went out after work.
Is it a crime to want
a little human contact?
I guess that's
why I don't go out.