[♪ Spanish Music ♪]
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
Female, early 30s,
Hispanic descent,
vitreous potassium was 11.74
milli-equivalents per liter,
so PMI's approximately
six hours.
So time of death
roughly 1:00 a.m.
C.O.D.?
From what I got here,
I can't tell you much.
Minimal dilation in the pupils
indicates decapitation
was postmortem.
Scalp shows naked follicles
without hairs,
no inflammation around them
indicates
removal was postmortem as well.
Ripped out in chunks.
Takes time and dedication
to do something like that.
And a lot
of hatred.
So her eyebrows
have been shaved off
and drawn back on
with eyeliner.
I know that's popular
among Latinos in 28th Street.
She could be a banger
or a girlfriend of one.
Either way at least,
she took good care of her teeth.
What is that, nine digits?
Social Security number.
Dentists usually put on
some form of identification
on removable bridgework.
It's better
than a license plate.
Pulled a couple
of likely palm prints
on the newspaper
the head was on,
but I don't think
that's going
to be our best bet.
Okay, start with those,
but make sure
you run the partials
off the box as well
'cause I got
Ecklie looking
over my shoulder,
so, uh...
Cover your ass.
Yes.
My pleasure.
WOMAN:
Large, elevated
vertebral scales.
Definitely not your
typical U.S. Crotalus.
Herpetologists always
throwing the Latin around.
What's wrong with just
calling him "rattlesnake"?
My specialty, my jargon.
Stripes at
the base of the neck
makes it Crotalus simus,
indigenous to southern
coastal Mexico.
Apparent Mexican vic
on a Mexican newspaper
with a Mexican snake.
You don't find
a whole lot
of these buzz-worms
around Vegas anyway, do you?
Nowhere outside a zoo.
These snakes like to burrow
in damp soil.
They like it hot and humid.
We're hot and dry.
For a snake,
big difference.
What are the chances
that thing just
crawled in their on its own?
In a newspaper dispenser
in the middle of a desert city?
No way.
I think it was dead
when it was shoved
down the victim's throat.
BRASS:
The only car up here.
Security called it in.
Is that a handicap van?
Dead guy's in
the driver's seat.
Any witnesses?
Nope.
And no surveillance either.
We ain't on the Strip, baby.
500 bucks
and a Nevada license.
Vincent DeCarlo, 28.
It's an expensive-looking
Italian suit
just to be a chauffeur.
It's a wheelchair.
Any indication he's handicapped?
He's not wearing prosthetics
and his soles are worn.
Somebody's missing their wheels.
Gunshot wound
to the head.
Looks like it came
through the windshield.
Crater on the windshield
faces out.
Which means that the shot came
from inside the van.
( gunshot )
So he's tapped out.
Catherine asked
if I could lend a hand.
Thanks.
BROWN:
You see that blood spot
on the lapel?
It's inconsistent
with the head wound.
To avoid cross-contamination,
you think you could cut
that out for me?
Oh, sure.
Possible GSR.
Which means the shot
was fired from the wheelchair.
How'd he shoot him
in the face?
Hey, Vinnie.
( mimics gunshot )
( gunshot )
So we got a guy
who fired a shot
from a wheelchair
and then escaped on foot.
VEGA:
Social came back
on the dental work
of Veronica Juarez.
No immediate family
in the States.
Apartment's leased
in her name.
Well, that's why
bangers have girlfriends;
sign things they can't.
This is a pretty nice place.
A long way
from 28th
Street.
Sure is.
Catherine, Nick.
Gangbanger girlfriend
with a degree?
Sounds like a rock band.
Hey, Vega?
Check out these pics.
Think she liked to party?
That barely looks
like the same girl.
I know.
I'm going to
check out the kitchen.
Okay.
Well, there's no signs
of sexual activity.
Oh, hang on now.
That looks
like pure crystal meth.
You could be up for a week
straight on that stuff
and not even know it.
Perfect drug for this town.
Hey, you think
that our vic was a groupie?
Looks like a mariachi band
with artillery.
I had a big dose of them
when I worked
with a gang unit in LA.
The band?
The scumbags who listen
to that music.
Sinaloa cowboys.
Big drug producers.
Okay. We've got a female victim
with a degree,
Mexican artwork, drugs
and Sinaloan cowboys.
( music playing in club )
♪ No me puedes negar,
lo que te hago sentir ♪
♪ No me puedes negar ♪
♪ Lo que sientes por mi ♪
( song ends )
¿Que paso, que paso,
que paso?!
Hacienda Corona!
¿Como estan, como estan,
como estan, como estan todos?
Que bueno, que bueno,
que bueno!
Otra cancion! Otra cancion!
♪ Yo me paso las noches
tomando ♪
♪ Quierendo olvidar ♪
♪ Su recuerdo ♪
♪ Buena aquella
noche maldita... ♪
Carnal,
conoces esta muchacha?
Sordo, contestame!
That's Carla.
Carla? Not Veronica?
Nah. The girl in the picture
told me her name was Carla.
Yeah, well, the bouncer says
that she hangs out here a lot.
Yeah, I guess so. Yeah.
♪ ...que por ser poderoso ♪
♪ Que mi vida jamas pasaria ♪
She, uh, friends with the band?
I don't know about friends.
I mean, her and every other girl
in here jocks 'em.
I mean, Extremo, bro,
they're the best. Come on.
♪ Yo soy malo ♪
♪ Y no puedo negar ♪
♪ Que desde me acuerdo
no he sido ♪
♪ La vieja resulto
mentirosa... ♪
I know my Spanish
is a little rusty,
but I think he just said,
"She was a liar,
she wasn't who
she said she was."
♪ ... pero en cambio
le robe su vida ♪
"She stole my heart,
so I stole her life."
♪ ...otra vibora por ser... ♪
"I made the snake...
eat a snake."
...esta cancion...
( applause )
Oye.
LVPD. We need to talk.
Leave your card,
I'll send you a picture
and autograph, huh?
That's not really
what I'm after,
my man.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Excuse me.
I'm their manager.
El jefe.
You want to ask
my band questions,
you can ask me first.
Great.
What can you tell us about
the song they just played?
What do you want
to know?
Quite frankly,
the lyrics are very similar
to a homicide
we're investigating.
That narcocorrido was written
ten years ago.
It's a classic.
Surprised you haven't
heard it.
I don't listen to crap
about doing drugs
and killing cops.
Why don't you buy a CD
on the way out.
Yeah, I might do that.
Hey, listen, one more thing,
if you could.
This girl,
you know who she is?
That's Carla.
She's dead?
Yeah.
That's too bad.
She was a loyal fan.
She knew the words
to every song we did.
Anything else?
Yeah.
Your name and number.
( knocking on door ):
Hi.
You got a minute?
Sure.
We really haven't had a chance
to talk since the staff changes.
I, uh...
I wanted to let you know
that I said some things
to Ecklie
that might have done the team
a disservice.
Ecklie wanted to break
up the team, and he did.
He asked me
if you and I had had our
post-PEAP counseling session.
And we didn't.
Regardless, you should never
have to cover for your boss.
I'm sorry.
You've always been a little more
than a boss to me.
Why do you think
I moved to Vegas?
Look, I know our relationship
has been complicated.
It's probably my fault.
It's probably definitely
my fault.
You completed
your counseling, right?
Yeah. Yes.
And...?
Let's just say that...
I sometimes...
I look for validation
in inappropriate places.
Look...
Let's, um...
It's okay.
Okay.
You know what,
we did our session.
Don't forget to document
this for Ecklie.
Right.
Thanks.
Bullet entered through
the left zygomatic arch,
then penetrated the brain,
then fragmented up.
( bullet drops onto tray )
The bullet never exited?
Not even close.
The right ear injury
is a separate wound
unrelated to the entry
in the face.
So he was shot twice.
Yeah, can you identify
the weapon off these?
It's highly unlikely.
The frags are too small.
I'll go back to the scene,
see if I can find
the AWOL bullet.
All right.
So I hear you found
a wheelchair.
Yeah. No identifiable prints,
only smudges.
Did you check the serial number?
No.
You know, wheelchairs
are registered
with medical supply companies.
It's not something
the average person would know.
Thanks.
Good looking out.
WOMAN:
Mrs. Bakerset's grandson bought
her a top-of-the-line chair
about a year ago
after her stroke.
We need to talk
to her.
I'm sorry,
she passed away last week.
Really?
That's strange.
We found her wheelchair
at a crime scene downtown.
Any idea how it got there?
No, no, no, Bonnie hadn't left
hare in at least six months.
Her place is right over here.
When the residents pass,
their property remains
in the room
until their family picks it up.
Her grandson said
he'd swing by next week.
The woman loved to shop.
I'll see if I can get you
some info on that wheelchair.
Loved to shop?
Looks more like
a compulsion.
BRASS:
Fly fishing rods...
air purification systems,
vitamins, yoga tapes...
cleaning products...
Most of these boxes
have the same return address.
N.Z.A., Inc.
It's local.
It's in Henderson.
Scumbag telemarketers.
( knocking on window )
( mumbles )
Watch your fingers.
Excuse me...
What's going on?
And you are?
Stuart Manslow.
And I'm Betsy Lewis.
You shouldn't be in here.
Well, Betsy,
I'm Detective Jim Brass,
Las Vegas police.
And this is Warrick Brown
with the Crime Lab.
Hi, folks.
Could you all
tell me
what's the deal
with all these boxes?
Buying things made Bonnie happy.
After her husband died,
she was lost.
Then a nice salesman
kept calling.
They would talk for hours.
If you ask me,
she liked the attention.
Ma'am, do you know
what happened to
Bonnie's wheelchair?
It was a gift
from her grandson.
Yeah. He's not a doctor,
but he does all right
for himself.
Off we go
into the wild, blue yonder.
( clears throat )
Why are you here?
Grissom said it'd be okay
for me to come help.
I need the experience.
Well, if we can't find
the bullets,
we find the shell casings.
I'm thinking
the shooter had the driver
at gunpoint,
forced him to drive up to the
roof 'cause it was deserted.
Give me your pen.
You don't shoot a man
with the door open.
( ramp whirring )
Keep your eye on this.
You got it?
The shooter had to open
the door when he took off.
Okay, stop.
Nine-millimeter.
Photograph it.
( norteña music plays )
( CD searches backwards )
Hi.
Oh, hey.
What is this?
Oh, it's, uh, it's an old case
from San Diego.
"They were found
"the next dawn,
in a dry river bed,
"their intestines exposed,
and many cats
feasting upon them."
Yeah, now you put that to music,
sing it in Spanish,
and you have a narcocorrido.
Narco what?
A corrido is a Mexican ballad.
A narcocorrido...
A drug ballad.
Kind of more or less,
except their songs include
actual events,
like specific
dates, names...
Here.
Come over here,
check this out.
This girl was shacked up
with a local drug lord.
He dumps her,
she rats him out
to the authorities.
The rest of the body
was never found.
But the song was a big hit.
So apart from having
her hair removed,
Veronica Juarez's murder
was life imitating art.
Yeah, and if that's the case,
anyone who knows this song
could... could be the killer.
We don't even know that
much about the victim,
other than she was
somewhere between
art lover and meth user.
Something I said?
Huh?
Oh, no, no, no.
Sorry.
It was actually
something I saw.
MAN:
Veronica had been here
since last summer.
Maybe six months.
We ran Ms. Juarez's
social.
She wasn't an employee.
She was more
of a freelancer.
The narcocorridos piece
was her first major story.
Makes me sick to think
she's not going to finish it.
She was working
undercover?
She figured it was the only way
to get these guys
to open up to her.
She was right.
Yeah, her article
came down pretty hard
on the music, huh?
Narcocorridos glamorize
a criminal lifestyle.
Veronica felt the songs
were poisoning
our young people.
She used the intern's
desk right there.
I warned her that
it was a vicious subculture.
Had she receive any threats?
Well, there was
this one incident
right after part one
was published.
Nombre de Jesus Malverde...
Nombre
de Jesus Malverde...
( gasps )
Silencio!
EDITOR:
We didn't call the cops,
but it was unsettling.
I'm kind of
superstitious.
Good thing
Veronica wasn't.
( computer blips )
Hello?
LVPD.
Anyone here?
( low muttering )
( speaking Spanish )
( knocking )
Elindio Zapata.
No hablo ingles.
Oh, de veras?
Well, that's funny,
because the Border Patrol
said you spoke
perfect English.
We're going to take
a look around, coyote.
You break it,
you bought it.
Vayate.
That belongs to
Jesus Malverde.
What do you got?
Veronica Juarez had a jacket
just like this one.
Minus the tire tracks.
This jacket?
It's coming with me.
And you're going
with him.
( handcuffs clicking )
We know that you went
to the newspaper office
and you threatened her.
Si, señor.
I went to the oficina.
Her mentals
were going places
they need not.
You want to tell me
what this is?
ELINDIO:
Pollo bone.
Religious. ( chuckles )
My right in America.
I don't know, it looks more like
a human finger to me.
It's been burned.
Eyes can fool you.
That's right.
That's why I do a lot of tests.
And I'm also gonna match
the blood found
on Veronica's jacket right here.
ELINDIO:
I know nothing about this.
Nice... muchacho gave it to me.
¿Como se llama?
Don't know name, only...
face.
Cara.
Mm, people give me things
all the time.
Now, why would they do that?
Maybe they like me.
( chuckles )
Or for proteccion.
When you look at me,
you see un hombre pobre, sucio.
Poor, dirty man.
Pero soy mas.
I am much more.
I am descendent...
of Jesus Malverde.
God...
Dios.
Angel of the poor.
The Mexican Robin Hood,
a thief and a killer,
hung May 3, 1909.
He is the reason...
you cannot touch me.
No me puedes tocar.
You're a disgrace
to our community.
You're a greedy fence
who will do or say anything
to make a buck.
No, señor.
No, I may warn,
I may protect,
I may harm,
I may do many things.
But not for money.
Okay, hold out
your hands--
we're gonna get some prints.
You got lucky with
the blood-stained lapel.
I didn't match the vic,
but I got a hit in CODIS.
Great.
Dax Blanchard?
Assault and battery
against a police officer in '96.
Served two years.
No current address.
Thanks.
( line rings )
Detective Jim Brass.
( deep voice):
Congratulations, Jim Brass.
You're guaranteed one of these
five amazing awards.
Trip to London,
Warrick?
a brand-new Caddy,
tennis bracelet,
plasma TV,
water purification system.
You finally did it, Jim.
Just send NZA a check for $300
and claim your prize.
NZA. So, where'd you get
the sales pitch, man?
From the victim's
personal effects.
My guess, it's the same boob
who was calling Bonnie.
The company's address
was on the old lady's boxes.
( all talking )
Mrs. Mason, I am standing,
which means what?
You should be sitting.
That's right, because
I've got some great news.
You just won a Cadillac.
Well, does your
husband drive?
Have you ever shopped
on 5th Avenue?
Come on. Look, I've been waiting
my whole life to make this call.
Yes. Yes.
Well, as soon as we get that...
Come on, people!
Let's close these deals!
I got a room full
of pikers or closers?
My grandmother used
to say if it sounds too
good to be true, it is.
Only closers go on that board.
Can I help you gentlemen?
I'm Detective Jim Brass,
Las Vegas Police,
and this is Warrick Brown
from the Crime Lab--
we got a couple
of questions.
We know Vincent DeCarlo's
not available--
how about Dax Blanchard?
Corner cubicle,
burgundy tie.
BLANCHARD:
You were?
You know what I want you
to do, Harry?
I want you to stand up,
and I want you
to march over
to that checkbook, soldier.
It does not sound like
you're standing up to me, Harry.
You know why
we're doing this, Harry?
Because we have something
called trust, you and me.
You trust...
Harry, I need you to do me
a favor, though, okay?
I need you to hang on for me
for one second, okay?
Okay. You're the greatest.
BRASS:
Dax, at yakety-yak,
you're the greatest.
I got a one-time-only offer
for you.
Should we talk about it here
or downtown?
Come on, what is this?
This is a legal room.
What the hell is that?
Are you packing?
This a legal gun?
Yeah, it is. Registered to me.
BRASS:
Okay. Downtown it is.
Let's go.
Nine-millimeter.
Same as the casings
found on the scene.
Nothing I'm doing
is illegal.
In exchange for a small fee,
my customers get
one of five
specified prizes.
When was the last time
someone won a Cadillac?
While ago.
Long time ago.
Never, all right?
Look, I'm only obligated
to give one of the prizes.
Nothing says it can't be
the cheap one.
Apparently, you're very
good at your job,
but you're not the best.
I saw the board--
you're number two.
Right behind a dead guy.
Vinny's dead?
When was the last
time you saw him?
Yesterday morning.
We found your blood
on his jacket.
Good. 'Cause I thought
maybe I missed.
I got a room full of people
congratulating you here,
Dorothy.
Yeah, Dorothy! Yeah!
I...
What in the friggin' hell?
I had a live one.
You sold my grandmother,
you son of a bitch.
Took every last cent.
Everybody we sell
is someone's grandmother.
( spits )
The guy was a mook, all right?
He was constantly stealing
my leads, stealing my customers.
Then I find out he rips off
my grandmother?
Honor among thieves?
For crap's sake,
she's living in a nursing home,
confined to a wheelchair.
So you killed Vincent DeCarlo
because he was better than you,
because he stole your leads,
because he sold
your bubby Bonnie, and you
wanted him out of the way.
Who the hell's Bonnie?
Your grandmother.
Bonnie Bakerset.
My grandmother's name is Fran.
She lives
in Daytona Beach.
Would you like to call her?
♪ ♪
Hey, Catherine.
The palm prints
on the newspaper
don't match Elindio's.
Well, that
just means
he didn't place the head
in the box.
The vic's blood was
on the jacket in his store.
She was run over
by a Toyo Open Country
MT 38-by-15.5-by-18.
Now, that's
a big-ass truck tire.
Elindio didn't even own a car,
much less a big-ass truck.
What other characteristics?
Take a look.
That's a retread.
I only know of one place in
Vegas that does work like this.
So, what is
it you need?
Invoice copies
of any retreads
that were done
on this type of tire.
Oh, yeah. We sell
about a hundred
of these a month.
Really?
Yeah.
Over here.
Thank you.
Hey.
I'll take that autograph now.
Ven aca.
I was seeing Carla...
until Veronica Juarez's
article came out.
I figured out who she was.
And then?
Then I dumped her ass.
What do you think?
She put down my music,
my band, made it look
like everyone involved
in narcocorridos was a
drug dealer or a criminal.
She lied to me.
¿Asi es como pagas?
( shouting in Spanish )
Narcocorridos
are entertainment.
The drugs,
they're an economic activity
woven in the fabric
of Sinaloan history.
The music does nothing
more than reflect that.
Narcocorridos
also depicts actual events.
So does the 6:00 news.
A lot of people
were pissed off
when she wrote that trash.
So you're saying
that she deserved to die?
I'm saying she was
a two-faced bitch
who got off on
our music at night,
wrote about how
disgusting we were
during the day,
when she was the one
smoking and snorting,
screwing everything
she could find.
We tested her blood.
We know that Miss Juarez
didn't do drugs.
And... I seriously doubt that
she was having sex with you.
Listen...
I didn't kill Veronica.
But she was a pocha,
a traitor, and
people like that
aren't taken lightly
in Sinaloa.
We're not in Sinaloa.
When you're inside
La Hacienda Corona,
you might as well be.
Deutschland uber alles...
I identified the casings
recovered at the scene.
They don't match
Dax Blanchard's 9-mil.
So, did he have
any other firearms?
Nothing registered.
Well, head stamp on the casings
was a little unusual.
"DWM?"
Deutsche Waffen
und Munitions fabrik.
Well, that's
World War II-era German.
Well, it's one thing
to collect old guns;
old ammunition comes from
a trophy--
an enemy gun a
soldier brings back
from battle.
So, our shooter's
an old soldier.
Hmm.
STUART MANSLOW:
Bonnie had Alzheimer's,
you know.
And that son of a monster
sold her twice a day.
Once in the morning,
and again that night,
because...
he knew she had forgot
that she bought the first time.
I tried to talk her out of it,
but Vincent
just kept on calling.
And Bonnie just
kept on a-buying.
So, what did you do
about it, sir?
Huh?
What'd you do about it?
Vincent started calling
all of us.
I played along.
I told him I didn't have
a checking account,
so the bastard offered
to drive me to the bank.
I wanted him to think
that I was weak.
So I borrowed
Bonnie's wheelchair.
Drove me to the bank.
Pushed me right up
to the teller.
Oh, he was helpful.
( chuckles )
And then he drove me back
to the casino.
Why did you have him park
on the roof?
Why not?
Nobody parks on the roof.
Here we go.
Now all we need
is the money.
( yelling )
Would've killed him with one shot.
Lousy shakes.
( gunshot )
But I got him good
the second one.
Been a long time
since I had to kill someone.
Where's your sidearm, sir?
( clattering )
You know, the world has changed.
When I was serving
my country,
I knew who my enemy was.
The gun, please, sir.
Now the enemy is...
some punk... calls you up
on the telephone...
and wants
your credit card number.
Sir?
The gun.
( sighs )
Hmm.
( unloads clip )
( reinserts clip )
( sighing ):
Bad news.
Rafael's palm prints
don't match the one
on the newspaper.
Worse news, his tire treads
don't match the ones
on Veronica Juarez's
leather jacket, either.
Great.
Well, you know, there is one
place the victim was
where there's a whole lot
of these tires.
Vega!
What do you think?
Run the plates.
♪ ...que sin duda yo fui
el dueño de tus sueños ♪
♪ Gracias, corazón... ♪
Hey, Juanito.
Not barbacking tonight?
No, I got the night off.
I'm gonna go party today.
So, you guys, uh, still
looking for Carla?
No.
No?
No, we're looking for you.
Do you own
a 2004 Ford F-150?
Gray with panting on it?
Uh, yeah, that's
the full-blown cocino mobile.
Oh, your pig mobile, nice name.
Yeah.
( accordion solo plays )
That's a cool belt,
Juanito.
What's it made out of?
Human hair?
Ooh, um...
You guys want
me to show you?
( grunts )
No, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no, no
VEGA:
Muevanse,
muevanse por atras!
Muevan...
Hey, hey, hey, back up!
Calmense, todos.
Dejanos hacer nuestro trabajo
y no les vamos a molestar.
Calmense, ya!
Este muchacho mato a
una señorita inocente.
Inocente!
Calmense.
Ya.
Y tiene que pagar.
Y tiene que pagar!
Get him out of here!
Ya!
Go, go, go!
VEGA:
I don't understand
you, Juanito.
You manage to stay out
of the gangs, drugs.
Making honest money...
What? Seven dollars an hour?
( chuckles )
STOKES:
Hey, it's better
than the joint.
I can promise you that.
Besides, you didn't
prove anything...
taking the life
of an innocent woman...
It was the perfect
opportunity, bro...
Yeah? To do what?
Impress a bunch of fools
who don't give a crap
about what happens
to you, anyway.
( tires squealing )
( gasps )
Immortality, bro.
See, I-I'm not gonna die
a barback, or a dishwasher...
Mm-mmm.
VEGA:
You're gonna get
the needle, kid.
You're gonna die a murderer.
Yeah, maybe so, but they're
gonna write a song about me.
I'm gonna go down in history.
No, no, no, no.
You see, the song's
already been written.
You're just a sad copy.
Una copia triste.
Well, I gave it my
own twist, though.
Uh... 'cause I-I'm an original.
Right.
( chuckles )
♪ Machuque ♪
♪ El perro ♪
♪ Con la lengua ♪
♪ De la culebra... ♪
♪ Tome ♪
♪ El premio ♪
♪ De lo que hecho ♪
♪ Le pregunte yo a Malverde...♪
Limpia...
esta puta!
♪ Que me diere guiansa ♪
♪ Para quemar mis pecados... ♪
( chuckles )
Immortal.