♪ ♪
( panting )
NEWSWOMAN:
This is the scene
in Seven Hills,
where casino mogul Bruce Eiger
has been found dead
on the grounds
of his palatial estate.
Eiger turned 60
earlier this year,
throwing himself a half-a-
million-dollar birthday party
at his newly renovated
Queen Regent Casino.
Cause of death remains unknown,
but as Eiger himself
famously joked:
in Vegas,
if nobody wants you dead,
you're not working hard enough.
Reporting live from Seven Hills,
I'm Laurel Tessler.
What's the 411?
Wife comes home
from canasta at the club,
finds hubby dead
in the driveway, calls 911.
No sign of forced entry.
The alarm was off.
Nothing seems to be missing.
Welcome to the party.
What's going on?
This is my scene.
High profile
case-- woke up
the supervisors.
All hands on
deck, Cath.
Grissom's lead on this.
He's the senior supervisor.
If it's all hands on deck,
what are you doing
behind the tape?
You know if I cross
the tape, my name goes
on the crime scene log
that gets subpoenaed
by the defense,
and I have to testify.
And when was the last time
you testified?
That's not my primary job
anymore.
I'm an administrator.
I run interference
for you guys...
starting with the press.
It's nothing personal,
Catherine.
Cases like these
rain down hard.
You need all the help
you can get.
I need help, not supervision.
So, Warrick?
Initial observations
when we got to the scene.
Obvious impact to the face.
Severe facial contusions.
Broken nose,
cracked teeth.
No shoe prints.
No tracks.
No cast off.
No sign of a weapon.
We're standing on the weapon.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
Mr. Eiger had
a lot of enemies.
Any idea who might
have done this?
I'm not ready
to confirm the circumstances
under which Mr. Eiger died.
I will say that this is
the number one priority
for the mayor and for all of us
in law enforcement.
So, he either jumped,
fell or was pushed.
Well, the facial
impact is consistent
with the blood pool...
but not
with the current position.
Well, he landed on his face,
but it looks
like his head got moved.
STOKES:
And not by the paramedics.
And according to them,
he had a broken neck.
Well, then he didn't
roll himself over.
House this big--
where's all the help?
Oh, the staff always gets
Thursday nights off.
I-I-I don't get
what the mystery is here.
He was murdered.
Some guys collect art.
Bruce collected enemies.
I'm more interested
in what happened after he died.
And what is that
supposed to mean?
Mrs. Eiger, uh,
I don't know how to put this...
All right, please,
you're making me feel old.
Call me Donna.
Okay, Donna, sure.
Your husband's boxer shorts.
He wasn't wearing them
when he died, was he?
Oh, that's
what this is all about.
No, no, I-I pulled in.
I saw Bruce lying there naked.
I knew that the news
was on its way over here.
I didn't want the whole world
to see him like that.
So you moved the body?
Yes, yes.
I turned him over.
I put his shorts on.
What, is-is dignity a crime?
♪ ♪
Question. You come home,
see your husband lying
in the driveway.
What do you do?
Is that a trick question?
Stop, jump out, run over to him.
Or take the time
to pull into the garage
and park and lock your car.
Catherine...
look, it's not
that we don't have confidence
in you...
I smell crap.
What?
Don't take another step.
Joe?
Yeah?
The Eigers have any pets?
No kids, no pets.
Okay.
I saved you from putting
your foot in it.
I appreciate that.
STOKES:
Hey, Catherine.
WILLOWS:
Yeah?
I think I found
the launch point.
I'll be right there.
People who live in houses
like these don't get oil leaks.
But their visitors might.
Hasn't absorbed
into the stone yet.
It's fresh.
Well, swab it and then check
all their cars just in case.
Hey.
Whatever happened, it
happened right here.
Planter could've been broken
during the struggle
or been used as leverage.
Well, if he was pushed,
they'd have to be strong enough
to get that big boy
over the railing.
Well, I didn't see any trace
on Bruce's hands.
I don't think those
are his prints.
Well, maybe the killer
hung out...
enjoying the fruits
of his labor.
Well, I don't see
any signs of struggle
in this hallway.
No.
The only clue is no clue.
The inner sanctum.
STOKES:
If these walls
could talk, huh?
I wish they would.
STOKES:
Yeah, no doubt.
( sniffs )
Scotch... and milk.
Maybe the guy had
stomach trouble,
you know, ulcers.
Well, you get
as good as you give.
Who smokes half a Cuban?
Well, whoever was outside
might've been in here, too.
I've got some greasy handprints,
look very similar
to the ones on the railing.
What are they doing
on the floor?
I'll take a sample.
From everything I've
heard, this guy was
a considerable ass.
Speaking of which, from
the damage to his sphincter,
I'd say he suffered
repetitive insertions.
Rectal insertions?
Sizable.
Matching perimortem
bruises to the hips.
The deceased had a peculiar rash
around his genitals
slathered in ointment.
Doesn't read as an STD
I'm familiar with.
I swabbed the ointment.
I also found a gallon
of milky fluid
in his stomach.
Trace has that, too,
along with fecal matter
I scraped off his feet.
For what it's worth,
nicely manicured nails
on all but one thumb,
which has a groove worn in it.
Drugs?
Yeah, it could be.
His pupils were dilated
to the size of pie plates.
Tox has the blood.
There's a lot behind the curtain
of this guy's life.
CURTIS:
Cause of death?
ROBBINS:
Asphyxia.
Choked on his own blood.
So he survived the fall.
Well, it broke his neck, but
he continued to breathe a while.
Might've lived
if he hadn't been rolled.
I'm glad you decided
to stay, Sofia.
So am I... for now.
Thanks for waiting.
Got here as fast
as I could.
We just finished.
Grissom, what
the hell?
Am I going to have
any part of this case,
or should I just go back
to my office and start shuffling
some papers?
Catherine, it wasn't personal.
The body was posted.
We didn't think you'd be back
for a few hours.
There's the report.
Stay out of this.
So, is this an
Ecklie mandate,
or is this
just your thoughtlessness?
Well, look, I apologize,
but this is a group effort.
( harsh chuckle )
Thanks. I feel much better.
( keys rattling )
( sighs )
( door opens )
Okay, got back
from the crime scene.
Dropped the samples off
at Trace.
What's wrong?
You didn't touch my camera,
did you?
No.
I have a 256 memory card.
This is a 32.
Somebody switched it out
and took my crime scene photos.
What?
Am I being strong-armed
by private counsel?
Because, contrary
to what you may think,
not everybody in Vegas is
under the thumb of Bruce Eiger.
Captain Brass,
I am simply here
representing the interests
of Mr. Eiger's estate.
And those interests
would be what?
Well, finding out
what happened, certainly.
But doing everything
within our power
to protect Mr. Eiger's
private life.
Protect what?
The guy's dead.
Mr. Eiger was
a very private person.
And although he's no longer
with us, his intimates are.
Look, if this is
about him being a sodomite,
we already know that.
Excuse me?
After the case is adjudicated,
you can have access
to the autopsy reports.
In the meantime,
let me do my job, okay?
When Eiger was
looking into buying
the Queen Regent Casino
out from under Sy Magli,
the gaming commission
turned him down.
So he invited some
of the commissioners
over to his mansion
for a party.
A week later, he
had his gaming and
his liquor licenses.
Must've been
a hell of a party.
Well, if the Wizard of Oz
had nude photos
of the Wicked Witch,
Dorothy would have
never lost her slippers.
Well, if those files
exist, it gives us
a list of suspects,
but nobody actually knows
if he has dirt on everyone,
or just wants them
to think he does.
Brass subpoenaed Eiger's
home phone records
in the last year.
Yeah, anything interesting?
Numerous calls from Eiger's
house to Sy Magli's office.
Well, they were
known business rivals.
Between midnight
and 4:00 a.m.--
what I like to call
"love hours."
Wouldn't be the first time
that hate mutated into passion.
Public enemies,
private lovers.
So Jackie Collins.
MAN:
Tanya, get your sweet little ass
back over to the piano,
and we'll talk about it later.
BRASS:
Mr. Magli,
Detective Jim Brass,
Las Vegas Police.
Greg Sanders from the crime lab.
Let me guess.
You want to talk
to me about Bruce.
I hear they're using
all the backhoes in hell
to dig him a new pit.
We're, uh, focusing on his life
here on Earth.
Well, you know,
I thought that bastard
would outlive us all.
When was the last time
you saw him?
At his birthday party.
( Tanya singing
"Dream a Little Dream" )
She's going to
be a big star.
♪ ...whisper I love you ♪
♪ Birds singing
in a sycamore tree ♪
Bruce didn't have any friends,
so he had to invite
his enemies,
a real "who's who"
of Las Vegas.
See, Bruce was a shark
who circled around
for information.
And when he found your weakness,
he filed it away
to be used later.
His phone records indicate
that you spoke
more recently than that.
Oh... so now you
found my weakness.
What's that?
I was banging his wife.
We have a problem.
Oh, no, not again.
The memory card from my
digital camera was stolen
and switched with a blank.
The only time the camera
was out of my possession
was at the crime scene.
Well, how can that be?
It was a secure scene.
I don't know. I dusted
the camera and the card.
There weren't any prints.
All of the crime scene photos
of the body and the blood
evidence were on that card.
( sighs )
We do have a problem.
Yes, we do.
Get back to the crime scene,
Catherine. Get what you can.
Well, I know that
the scene's been released.
Well, go quickly.
Okay.
( sighs )
Ready?
The baddest ass in Vegas
had diaper rash.
The sample that
Doc Robbins collected
from between his legs
at autopsy: Brenner's Ointment,
used expressly for that purpose.
Okay. What about
the handprints
from the railing and
the floor in study?
Same deal.
I compared the hand size,
and, uh, the prints
aren't Eiger's, man.
Hmm?
No. Which means that...
You couldn't pay me enough
to rub ointment
on some old guy's butt rash.
( laughs )
Well, maybe some people
aren't as discerning
as you are.
How does a grown man
get diaper rash?
I'll take incontinence
for $200, Alex.
Maybe he had
gastrointestinal issues.
And the stomach contents.
All milk.
You get any tox back?
Yeah. No drugs
in his bloodstream.
Really?
He had dilated pupils,
and he was a sick guy,
but... no medications.
Mrs. Eiger!
Mrs. Eiger,
please stop.
Please stop? What, am I supposed
to look at his blood?
Do I need this?
( phone ringing )
I need to take
additional photos
of the crime scene.
if you could just
put the hose aside and...
Yeah.
Oh, Sy.
You know what? Don't bother.
You don't have to lie to me.
I get it.
I really, I really do.
No, he's dead
and you're leaving.
Yeah, well, maybe
I just thought
that I was more
than just a hate lay.
Uh, men just don't
appreciate us.
DONNA:
It's never enough.
When you put up with things
that nobody else would
and he stills wants more.
I mean, just how low
are we supposed to sink?
You know, I think you're
better off without him, anyway.
What's your name?
Catherine.
You know, Catherine,
this whole, um,
sisterhood thing that you're
trying to get going here,
it's just really not
working for me.
You can't con a con, sweetie.
WILLOWS:
Sara and Greg went through
these cans last night.
They were empty.
WARRICK:
Well, it looks like
Mrs. Eiger's been
a little busy.
Evidently.
Uh, Warrick?
Yeah.
Is that a diaper?
Mm-hmm.
Those safety pins,
they could match the bruises
that we found
on Mr. Eiger's hips.
Well, we can probably
get DNA from the blood.
But to confirm that Eiger
actually wore this thing,
Mia's going to have
to test the urine inside.
Lucky girl.
Lucky her.
Do you think Donna
always takes her laundry
to the city dump?
I've got handprints
in carpet.
He wasn't just incontinent,
he's was a...
A freak.
( camera clicking )
That's disgusting.
Look at these indentations.
I think they could have been
a desk or something.
Were gonna have to take this
back to the house
and look at it
in its original context.
Is that even legal?
Why are they...
Why are you
guys doing this?
Hasn't she been
through enough?
You know, you should
sue the city.
She's gonna sue you people!
How about that?
GRISSOM:
How do you explain a handprint
half covered by a wall?
I mean, we're not even certain
this rug came from this room.
Well, I was gonna say
the same thing,
but the rug has eight divots
that line up perfectly
with that desk.
Think outside the rug.
A man with secrets
needs a place to hide them.
Get the hell
out of here.
WARRICK:
Nice.
( Willows sighs )
( laughs )
WILLOWS:
Wow.
Just when you thought
you'd seen it all.
People lived in fear
of this guy?
Imagine the fear he lived with.
( camera clicking )
WARRICK:
A very powerful and paranoid man
with a secret this big?
It'd probably kill him
if anyone found out.
I think it did kill him.
So we're back
to suicide?
Well, let's
collect for now.
We'll, uh,
theorize later.
Whoa.
Who's your mommy?
The true inner sanctum.
( camera clicking )
Hey, maybe we're looking
for the hand that
rocks the cradle.
I think that
Bruce just wanted the same thing
as every other guy.
Nurturing?
Easy access.
Well...
...this could explain
the repeated insertions.
I think this was originally used
as a panic room.
Eiger's got a massive
security system here,
motion and site sensitive.
No video, though.
WILLOWS:
Well, I guess we won't
get to see who swaddled him.
WARRICK:
Well...
there is a hard drive.
I'll get it back to the lab.
( camera clicking )
I just don't get it, man.
What, you never had a
transitional object
when you were a kid?
A stuffed animal
or a blanket?
No. I mean, I had a wooby,
but who didn't?
WARRICK:
Oh, is that that blue thing
that's in your locker?
Don't even.
70% of children have something.
Helps them with
separation anxiety.
Maybe Bruce Eiger
never got over his.
WARRICK:
I got a question.
Where would you buy
something like this?
I mean, this crib
and this rocking horse
isn't exactly, uh,
regulation size.
Forever Baby.
For the child in all of us.
Do you think they do takeout?
Hey.
Oh, hey.
You asked me
to check the blood and
urine from the diaper.
Yeah.
Yeah, the blood
is a match
for Eiger, and the urine
had high levels of testosterone,
which is indicative of an adult.
It's a safe assumption
that it's his.
Yeah.
You know, one other thing.
When I was running the urine,
I found another spike
that I couldn't identify.
So I sent it on to Tox.
Well, I know that his blood work
came back clean.
Some drugs metabolize quickly,
so what doesn't show up in the
blood, shows up in the urine.
Catherine?
Yeah?
You gotta see the TV.
The photos you're about to see
are the latest evidence
in the strange death
of casino mogul Bruce Eiger.
We want to warn you
these are graphic images
of a bloody crime scene.
In them, Mr. Eiger can been seen
lying in a pool
of his own blood
in the driveway...
Those are mine.
I'll have
our Public Information Officer
contact his counterpart
at the station.
We'll also
call Judge Anderson
and get a warrant
for the memory card,
any copies,
and the name of their source.
...top Las Vegas gaming mogul
left him with more
than his share of adversaries.
Thank you, Conrad.
It's my job.
...however, there are still
no apparent leads.
Howdy.
Well, howdy.
I was wondering,
do you carry
adult diapers?
Oh, we sure do.
What are you,
about a 34, 36?
Well, they're not for me.
Oh.
Well, aren't you lucky
to have such a nice daddy?
I'm going to have a look around.
( clears throat )
Mommy-shopping?
Sort of.
I was wondering, in
your line of work,
do you ever wear a
uniform or a dress?
No,
but I could.
Are you a drinker or a stinker?
Excuse me?
Well, a drinkers likes to...
And stinker...
I get it.
Yeah.
We're actually
with the Crime Lab.
We're investigating the
death of Bruce Eiger.
Bruce Eiger.
WOMAN:
Are you with Vice?
Because nothing here
is illegal.
It's simply nurturing.
Mommy and Adult Baby play,
it's not erotic.
Well, Freud had a somewhat
different theory, but...
Well, I could take you
to my playpen.
You know,
I don't think the department
would let me expense it.
Okay, then, I'll just
cut to the short version.
Some guys can never love
any woman but their mother.
And some never had a mother
who loved them.
♪ ♪
WILLOWS:
Is Foxy short
for anything?
MAN:
No, no, it's just Foxy Harris.
That's what's on
my birth certificate.
I signed an exclusive
nondisclosure agreement
with KRAC.
Whoever gave you my name
is the one who broke the law.
It's funny what
people will say
when there's a
warrant in their face.
Yeah, your friends at KRAC
take obstruction of justice
seriously.
You stole
police department evidence
in a homicide investigation.
You're guilty of theft
and possession
of stolen property.
And we're looking at you
for murder.
I shoot pictures, not people.
Right.
You're a journalist.
What were you doing
at the Eiger house that night?
Okay, so KRAC
isn't my only employer.
I do discreet work for Sy Magli.
( camera shutter clicking )
All right,
let me get this straight.
Sy Magli hired you
to take pictures of him
sleeping with Donna Eiger?
That's right.
Why would he do that?
Eiger had dirt on everyone.
Nobody obsessed with secrets
doesn't have some of his own.
Magli asked me to find Eiger's,
but, well, I couldn't find any.
So in the absence of scandal,
Magli created some.
By sleeping with
Bruce Eiger's wife.
Brilliant.
You know, there were
cops everywhere.
Whose palm did you grease?
I didn't need to.
Donna showed Magli who showed me
all the secret ways
onto the property.
You really should
train your people better.
All it took was
a dark jacket,
a baseball cap, and a camera.
No questions asked.
So here's the thing.
The milk in the bottles
was not bovine.
It was human breast milk.
Human?
Mm-hmm.
All of it?
Yeah.
Well, it definitely
wasn't the wife's.
No, the widow Eiger's
DNA was not a match.
However, whoever
pumped all that milk
also wore this.
The epithelials were a match.
So we're looking for
one very tired milkmaid.
This is the same toy box
they sell at Forever Baby,
except the one in the store,
twice as big on the inside.
Well, he did like
his secret spaces.
STOKES:
Yep.
All right.
Whoa.
Bingo.
"Sy Magli...
"Sam Braun...
Rory Atwater"?
Sheriff Rory Atwater?
Looks like it.
Along with some
gaming commissioners,
judges, pro athletes.
( chuckles )
( papers rustling )
No name.
Just a date--
12-20-01.
STOKES:
Well, apparently,
Sy liked the spectrum--
old and this.
BROWN:
I downloaded the log
from the Eigers' security system
hard drive.
All of the perimeter
doors and windows
in the Eiger mansion
are protected.
If one of them is opened,
it's logged
into the security system.
According to Mrs. Eiger's
verified alibi,
she left for the club
around 7:15.
Okay.
Garage door opens,
7:18. Got it.
Dispatch received
her 911 call at 11:42.
So we're concerned
with the four hours in between.
8:00, the front door opens.
It was probably the milkmaid.
10:09, the third floor
balcony doors were opened.
Bye-bye, Bruce.
Now four minutes later,
the front door opens again.
Milkmaid exits?
17 minutes later, at 10:30,
the garage door opens.
I guess that was Mrs. Eiger.
But then a minute later,
at 10:31,
the front door opens again.
She didn't make her call to 911
until 11:42.
What was she doing
for over an hour?
Count Basie said
that it's the notes
you don't hear that matter.
Two voids...
one pointing towards 11:00,
one towards
1:00.
Something blocked the spray.
Something in a size eight.
Could that be explained
by her rendering aid?
I don't think so.
It's a fine mist.
Spatter.
I think he was still alive,
expirating blood.
( gurgled choking )
I wonder
what was going through her mind
when she stood there
and watched him die?
I wonder
what was going through his?
Fine.
I was, uh, playing canasta
at the club,
like I do
every Thursday night.
I come home.
I pull into the driveway,
and-and there he was.
You administer any help?
Uh, more like encouragement.
DONNA:
Oh, dear.
What happened
to Mummy's widdle baby?
Did Brucey fall down
and go boom?
So you're admitting
responsibility
in the death of your husband?
MAN:
No.
Mrs. Eiger is not a
health care professional.
She merely delayed
in calling for help.
She watched him die.
His had a broken neck.
If he'd lived,
he would've been a quadriplegic.
So it was a mercy killing?
It wasn't a killing at all.
You would've
had to take care of him.
Oh, bathe him,
feed him, change his diapers.
( Donna chuckles )
Freakin' gift from God to him.
See the thing was,
I-I just didn't want
Bruce to have the satisfaction
of being helpless
for the rest of his life.
Do you know
what the last words
I said to him were?
You lose.
So I take it that you weren't
his, uh, his mommy?
Look-- love, honor, cherish.
Diapering was never on the list.
How'd you deal with it?
Oh, I didn't.
Look, I'm sorry, but...
you can't have sex with a man
after you've seen him...
after you've seen him
behave like that.
So in order
to save our marriage,
we had, uh, an arrangement.
On Thursday nights,
I go to the club
with my friends.
He hires a baby-sitter.
We have reason to believe it was
the same baby-sitter every week.
Any idea who that is?
No, women in my position
have been looking
the other way for years.
I just had... something a little
stranger to look away from.
Why didn't you leave him?
Nobody leaves Bruce.
Well, maybe you had to
get Bruce to leave you.
You push him off the balcony?
No.
He'd already fallen
when I found him.
I turned him over.
I watched him die.
I got rid of the diaper.
I rolled up the carpet.
I changed my clothes.
Then I called 911.
And I should've left him
in the damn diaper.
I don't know
what I was protecting.
Your reputation.
Donna may be
an opportunist,
but she is not a murderer.
And since neither of us believe
that Bruce was suicidal...
You're both psychiatrists?
Look, my husband
did not commit suicide.
So why don't you just
find the guy who did,
and I will write him
a big, fat check.
WILLOWS:
That drug spike
that Mia detected
in Bruce's diaper--
"Lucy in the sky
with diamonds..." LSD.
But I don't get it,
because acid trips
last for hours.
Why wouldn't it
have shown up in
his bloodstream?
LSD is in and out
of your system in 20 minutes.
But it acts as a trigger,
which sets off cascading
reactions in the brain.
The brain keeps cascading
long after the drug is gone.
Well, there are good
trips, and bad trips,
and trips right
off the balcony.
Strange drug of choice
for a control freak.
Maybe not his choice.
So we're looking for
a lactating female
with a center
whorl print.
We recovered
two sets of prints
from the baby
paraphernalia.
His and...
presumably hers.
We've excluded
Mrs. Eiger.
How long can a woman lactate
after giving birth?
I had a professor in college,
her six-year-old
used to come in for lunch.
I guess they'll go
as long as you let them.
What, the boobs or the kids?
That's a two-legged
topless buffet.
I'm thinking, you know,
if you commit to something
every Thursday night,
you got to be getting
something good
out of it.
We found oil drops
on the driveway.
None of the Eiger
cars had leaks.
I ran it through Trace.
It was an Agip... Sint 2000.
It's a synthetic
motor oil.
A synthetic would
make it high end.
That particular
oil is only used
for Lamborghinis.
How many lactating women
are driving one of those?
So he either paid well
or was a good gift giver.
Maybe we're looking
for a cash cow.
With liquid assets.
I had the distinct pleasure
of testing all the modes of
ingestion from the nursery.
Most people take acid
on their tongue.
Bruce...
An enema.
And people call me anal.
Well, the whole point
of having a "mommy"
is to have her do
these things for you.
WILLOWS:
So the acid was
no doubt supplied
by the same sweet thing
who gave him breast milk
from that...
boobs-ahoy dress.
BRASS:
So, that new Lamborghini
is a pretty smooth ride.
Grant from the dealership
told me you
bought one recently.
It was a gift.
For who?
Tanya Rollins.
You got to woo the talent.
Yeah, she's cute.
How old is she?
Twenty-four.
So, you been together
nine years--
that'll make
her about 15
when you consummated
the relationship.
Don't you know that
15 will get you 20?
What do you want?
Why was Tanya's
Lamborghini
parked in Bruce
Eiger's driveway?
They were involved.
I thought she
was your girl.
Tanya always goes
where the best deal is.
I "rolled" her,
Bruce bankrolled her.
Her career-- smart move.
Turned out she actually
had other talents.
She was making him
a ton of money,
so I gave her a call.
You poached her.
Ah, come on, look,
she jumped at it, all right?
Tanya said he was a freak
and she wanted out.
Then what?
'Cause I got felony sex,
infidelities
and a picture of a baby
I don't know anything about.
Come on, we both
know what I was after.
So, all's well
that ends well, huh, Sy?
I didn't want him dead.
There's no sport
in humiliating a dead man.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
Captain.
WILLOWS:
Your fingerprints are
all over the nursery.
The DNA that we took
from your breast pump
matches the milk
from Bruce's fridge.
And the arresting officer
confiscated LSD
from your purse.
And your cell phone is full
of pictures of "Baby Bruce."
Sy said
all that Bruce had was fear.
Yeah, there's really
not much to fear
about a crying man
in a diaper.
All right, Baby Bruce.
Playtime's over.
( smooching noises )
I smell a smelly.
You made a big messy
in your diaper.
You ready?
There you go.
That feels so good.
Mommy's got a special treat
for you.
It's extra special today.
♪ ...wonder what you are... ♪
And then, he just started
acting crazy.
As opposed to soiling himself
and gumming your nipples?
Yes.
( grunting )
What is it with you, Brucie?
What are you doing?
What is wrong?
( grunting )
Wait, that's a bad boy.
( muttering )
The light.
I see the light... I see...
What is it
with you, Bruce?
What's wrong?
( Bruce crying )
And then, he just...
jumped off the balcony.
That's it?
You knew this man's
most intimate secret.
You could've left him.
Nobody leaves Bruce.
What were you afraid of?
That I'd never
see my baby again.
Bruce said that
he wanted a baby.
That he'd take care
of both of us.
And you believed him?
Yeah.
Only after the delivery,
he said he had
to take the baby away.
That he was going to take him
to be with his mom.
You know, wait
until my career took off.
Until I was ready
to be a mother myself.
And then he took me
to his nursery.
He explained to me, you know,
about infantilism.
Said that it was in the Bible.
And then he made me clean him.
How long ago was that?
Five years.
Five years and every week,
I would ask him
if I could see my baby
and he kept saying next week.
"Sure, Tanya, next week."
"No, maybe next week."
You know, "maybe
the next week after that."
I guess in my heart I knew that
it was never going to happen.
It's just that...
that was the only connection
I had to my baby, you know?
That and nursing Bruce.
Tanya,
this man exploited you
for five years.
He didn't allow you to see
your only child and...
there he was, high as a kite
and you're the only one there.
Are you saying that you didn't
offer him any encouragement
off that balcony?
If I asked you to jump
off a bridge would you do it?
( whimpering )
Fly, Brucie, fly.
Show Mommy how you
can fly like a birdie!
Come on, you can fly!
I can fly.
You can fly.
I can fly, Mommy.
You can fly!
I can fly.
You can fly,
you can fly.
I can fly, Mommy.
You can fly!
I can fly!
BRASS:
Do you recognize this infant?
WOMAN:
No.
I've never seen that baby
before in my life.
Well, Bruce said he gave you
his lover's baby to raise.
The mother's name
was Tanya.
Do I look like I
could raise a baby?
When was the last time
you saw your son, Mrs. Eiger?
Seven years ago.
You didn't know he had kids?
Do you know what my mother
told me when I had Bruce?
What's that?
Suckle the baby,
cuckold the man.
I don't follow.
You were breast-fed.
Yeah.
My mother was
a firm believer
that the way
you raised a boy
was to make him hard.
To let him know
what the world was like
right out of the womb.
And what's the world like?
No free lunch.
All these mothers
coddling their toddlers.
Look where we are.
Yeah, look where we are.
GRISSOM:
I've enjoyed working with you.
Which part?
The part where I got
in your face
or the part where I,
uh, lost evidence,
or maybe you just miss me.
I did miss you.
I missed your passion
and your tenacity.
I even missed your tush.
( chokes )
Really.
Thank you.
BRASS:
Sorry to interrupt.
I miss the punch line?
Yeah.
So Bruce lied about the kid.
There was
an out-of-state adoption
that placed the day
the kid was born.
And Bruce's mother...
A light beer, please.
His mother was
a piece of work.
So, is Tanya going
to take the fall?
Can't convict her
for cheerleading.
You can if there's LSD
in her pom-poms.
Acid makes
her culpable.
Class A felony.
Any more culpable
than his wife,
who just let him lie there?
You know, what I can't get
my mind wrapped around
is, uh, you got a guy
who's tough enough
to get to the top
of the heap in Vegas,
all this power,
and he ends up
crawling around a playpen.
That's the point,
isn't it?
It's only the truly powerful
that have the luxury
to relinquish power.
But diapers?
Why not?
Where would you go if you had
the connections and the cash
to go anywhere
you wanted?
I hear Fiji's nice.
Eiger went further.
He went all the way back
to his childhood.
Yeah.
I think I'd take Fiji.