( moaning )
Honey, slow down.
Hold on a second. Hold on.
Leave it alone.
We're already late.
If you hadn't told the
sitter the wrong time...
How do I look?
You look great.
( doorbell rings )
Hello.
Sorry we're late.
No, I'm so glad
you guys could make it.
( laughing )
You guys want a drink?
♪ ♪
Mm...
( laughing )
( woman screams )
Hey, fellas,
what's the holdup?
Come on.
I told you half an hour ago
turn the damn fountain off!
Give me a break.
You can't find good help.
As Lord Byron once said,
"In the desert,
a fountain is springing."
Well, this one sprung
a dead woman...
Vanessa Keaton.
She lived over there.
A neighbor walking her dog
found her.
This is a pretty well-dressed
crowd for this time of night.
Well, you know,
it's a shindig.
43 Niagara Circle.
The vic was there
with her husband.
Left the party early.
That's Dan Keaton,
and that's his daughter Amy.
You know,
you might want
to sneak some photos
of this crowd.
A gated community,
middle of nowhere--
if this wasn't an accident,
they're all suspects,
aren't they?
Foam in her nose
and mouth.
It's consistent with drowning.
Abrasion on her forehead
is fresh.
And lividity is unfixed.
Well, since water motion
has no effect...
She's been dead less
than two hours.
Thank you. Finally!
GRISSOM:
Still waters run deep.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
I can't do this right now.
What, a little hungover?
Too much to drink, maybe?
We'll have a police officer
get you some water.
Bernie.
So, the last time you saw
your wife was at the party?
Erin and Paul Brady's.
But you left early
without your wife, right?
Yeah, I wasn't in the mood.
She was.
For what?
Partying.
What time did you leave?
Around 11:00, I think.
Anyone see you come home?
Maybe your daughter?
This is Amy, right?
AMY:
I went out
with friends.
My curfew's 1:00.
I was a little late.
So, Amy, did you see
your parents when you came in?
My mom was in Detroit.
Vanessa's my stepmom.
The TV was on in their room.
I snuck into my room
and went to bed.
The sirens woke me up.
The sirens, huh?
SIDLE:
You know, they never go home
until they see
the body taken away?
Necrophilic voyeurism.
Hot shoes.
You think these are sexy, huh?
Did you know
that shoes like these
put degenerative stress
on the hip joints, throw off
the curve of the spine,
and the tilt to the pelvis,
over time,
women get headaches,
sore backs,
shortened calf muscles
and bunions, of course.
I take it back.
First thoughts?
Vanessa Keaton
was walking home.
She had a few.
Her feet hurt.
She takes off her shoes.
Dolce vida.
( laughing )
There's no sign
of blood or hair.
Nothing to suggest contact.
The fountain was on.
Maybe the action of the water
washed away evidence.
How do we know
it was an accident?
Maybe she wasn't alone.
We don't know that.
We're going to need
a water sample
and a bag for the shoe,
of course.
Okay.
STOKES:
You okay to drive?
No.
After a triple and three
back-to-back scenes,
I'm tired.
I'm going to take
a ten in the car
before we head back.
That's better than bouncing
off the curb, I guess.
Yeah.
Okay, you ready
to run it?
Sure.
Landlord's working late,
trying to fix
up the place
for the new tenant,
kicking up dust,
paint fumes.
Door's open
for ventilation.
Killer strolls in.
Next thing you know,
landlord's deli meat.
( gasps )
Well, we have
this eviction notice.
So, that means no business.
No business, no cash,
so that could rule out
robbery as a motive.
I'm having Detective Cavalier
run down the evicted tenants.
It's a Melissa Pooley
and a Charlie Pincher.
Sorry, can't let you in.
Hey, you guys call
yourselves investigators?
You've been here four hours.
You haven't figured
this out yet?
Crime scene cleanup.
Blood bucket brigade.
Hey, I prefer bio-
recovery services.
You know, it's funny.
I don't see an American
Bio-Recovery badge.
See, all you really need
is a strong stomach,
a thorough knowledge
of solvents,
a little sensitivity,
a little tact.
Whoa.
Man!
There must be three quarts
of blood in there.
Hey, you're using anhydron.
I charge extra for that.
Cha-ching, cha-ching.
You got photos, swabs.
Did you finish the sketch?
Yeah.
Great.
Hey, you guys have done
everything but leave.
What's the rush, Marty?
The wife of the deceased,
she would like this mess
cleaned up as soon as possible.
New tenant moves in
on the first.
Okay, Marty.
I'll have the detective
release the scene.
Well, I'll get my gear.
One of the most attractive women
I've had on my table.
But beauty's skin deep
and inside, we all look
pretty much the same.
What about this abrasion?
Have you no poet in you?
Beauty is truth,
truth, beauty.
That is all you know
on Earth
and all you need to know--
except cause of death.
Pulmonary edema
due to drowning.
I sent samples of the water
in her lungs to Trace.
The abrasion's
serious enough
to cause loss
of consciousness.
You may want to
look at this though.
You want to come over here?
Let's turn her over.
Puncture wounds?
Four, uniform diameter,
perimortem, non-lethal.
No corresponding holes
in her dress.
So she wasn't wearing it
when she was stabbed.
Collected lubricant
from the labia.
Which means, uh...
I don't know if she had a date
with her husband or herself.
I sent an SAE kit to DNA.
Personal observation--
you don't wear
La Perla to a
Tupperware party.
La Perla?
Very expensive.
I gave some to my wife once.
She accused me
of having an affair.
You know, sex on the steel.
Lubricant and lingerie.
I don't think the evening
turned out the way she planned,
do you?
Nope.
So your business goes bust
and Mr. Visingi evicts you.
Pac-Man, Pong,
loved these games.
Thought it was
a sure thing.
Well, today, it's all
3-D interactive.
You know, I got kids.
You want some advice?
No.
Never go into business with
somebody you're sleeping with.
Melissa Pooley?
Bitch.
We haven't been able
to find her.
You know where she is?
We broke up.
At least I think we broke up.
She skipped town
without telling me,
stuck me with the rent.
So you were angry
at her, you were
angry at him.
I didn't kill him.
He was holding
your inventory hostage.
How much you got tied up in
Centipede and Space Invaders?
Every penny I got.
About 20K.
You must have
wanted it back.
Hey, did you stop by
the store last night?
No, but I called him.
Asked if we could
maybe work something out.
Told me to go screw myself,
he'd see me in court.
Mr. Pincher, I'm going
to need to go ahead
and get your fingerprints.
( groans )
You're going to find my prints
all over that place.
It was my store,
mine and Melissa's.
I expect to find your prints
in certain places, sir.
We're just doing this
to rule you out.
Oh.
You alternate hands
when you double glove?
Yes.
And I don't like
being watched.
If you alternate,
there's more contact
between the exposed latex
of the first glove
and atmospheric microbes.
What?
You know,
it would have been better
if you didn't say anything,
but you did
making it impossible
for me to concentrate,
and now I have
to sanitize
and start over.
Hey, Hodges, you got
the results
of our drowning
victim?
Yeah, in five.
I'm in the middle
of the rest of my life.
Well, I kind of need them now.
I'll be back.
Good thing you didn't
have to take
a spelling test
to work the field.
"Funtain" water?
My people are Norwegian.
That's how we spell it.
So, is the "funtain"
water in her lungs?
All bodies of water contain
unicellular algae.
Called diatoms.
They're unique,
like fingerprints.
Diatoms from one
body of water
don't match those
from any other.
Well, you're roughly right.
Here, take a look.
The diatoms on the left
are from the water
found in your victim's lungs
and the diatoms on the right are
from the fountain.
Not a match.
Not even close.
Which means
she didn't drown there.
I'll throw you a bone.
She blew you off,
didn't she?
The water from
the fountain is
heavily chlorinated.
No, she didn't
blow me off.
I didn't ask her out.
But this sample,
found in your
vic's lungs,
contains polymethylhexalene
biguanide...
and anyway, I heard
she blew you off first.
It's a chlorine
alternative.
It's less irritating.
Vanessa Keaton
died in a pool.
Or a spa...
And by the way,
that's spelled S-P-A
in any language.
STOKES:
Only new items brought
into the arcade post-eviction
were the tools, tarps
and paint cans.
No prints from Charlie
Pincher on any of them.
Just the landlord
and some unknowns on the saw.
No hits off of AFIS.
According
to Cavalier,
the table saw was a rental.
So, there could have been any
number of prints on that one.
Yeah, but you don't
just lie down
when somebody's trying
to kill you, man.
There had to have been
a struggle.
Yeah, from that spinning blade,
there was blood everywhere.
Some of it had
to transfer
to the killer's clothes
and shoes.
I still like
Charlie for this.
I know we don't
have enough
for a warrant...
WOMAN:
Excuse me, guys.
There's a Mr. Gleason
to see you.
I told him you were busy.
He won't leave.
What's the problem,
Marty?
You and you.
You treat me like a janitor,
like a garbage man.
I'm a professional,
same as you...
an unsung hero
that's worthy of respect.
Okay, Marty...
You know exactly
what I'm talking about.
The smell back
at the store.
I know decomp
as well as you,
maybe better, okay?
So what was it?
Your lunch?
Rotten shrimp? Clams, maybe?
Whatever you hid there,
I am going to find.
We didn't even bring
lunch there, Marty.
And this wasn't a decomp scene.
You're jealous.
You're stuck in a dead-end
civil service job
while I'm grossing
six figures.
Oh, six figures.
Yeah. Picture that.
GLEASON:
We're colleagues.
My job starts
where your job ends.
You should not be messing
with me!
Nobody's messing
with you, Marty.
Phew... ooh...
It's decomp.
Subtle, but
it's in here.
The nose knows.
How'd we miss that?
STOKES:
We were tired.
Did you steam clean?
Yeah.
The heating process
must have brought
the smell out.
You know,
I don't
get paid until this place
smells
like Eternity for Men.
Could be a dead rat.
Lot of possibilities.
I don't know.
Your guess is as good as mine.
I know how to find it.
Okay, rich guy.
Shut down your gear,
you're taking us
to lunch.
KEATON:
Crack runs right through
the deep end.
Had to drain it.
Half the neighbors
have cracked slabs,
leaky roofs.
This was perfect when
Vanessa and I moved in.
Place isn't built
to last.
SIDLE:
Mr. Keaton,
I know this must be hard
for you and your daughter.
Why are you here?
Your wife
didn't die in a fountain.
We're taking water samples
of every pool and spa
in this community.
Was there swimming
at the Brady's party?
Why?
Routine question.
Some, I guess.
It was that kind
of party.
SIDLE:
Was your wife
in the pool?
KEATON:
She could have been.
After I left.
What does this have to do
with her accident?
Did anyone behave
inappropriately towards her?
We were with our friends.
Our best friends.
I wouldn't have
left her there
if I didn't think
she was safe.
No one's allowed to treat
their pools with chlorine.
It's in the homeowners'
regulations.
What the hell
is going on?
They have a warrant.
A warrant for what?
GRISSOM:
When was
the last time
you had your pool cleaned?
Guy was here
this morning. Why?
We're asking the
questions, Mr. Brady.
Look, look...
we're all in shock.
Vanessa was one
of those people
who was so alive,
so much fun
So, tell me about
last night.
Was it a special occasion?
We just had the neighbors
in for cocktails.
We do it once a month.
We, uh...
we all take turns.
Was Mrs. Keaton wearing
this dress last night?
Yes.
I noticed-- I have
the same one in pink.
BRASS:
You notice anything
else, anything out
of the ordinary?
Like an argument
or a fight?
No, no, no.
We are a friendly group.
Did she leave alone?
Yes. Her husband left
about an hour earlier.
He seem upset
when he left?
Not that I noticed.
Vanessa's death was an accident,
right?
Got it.
May we take a look
inside your house?
Look wherever you want.
Well, by the way
you've cleaned up, Mrs. Brady,
I wouldn't even know
you had a party in here
last night.
Thank you.
What kind of party
was it?
A mixer.
Mrs. Brady, would you
join me in here, please?
Where are your
other skewers?
I don't know.
Well, cleanliness
is next to godliness.
After overhead and costs,
50 cents a pound
for waste disposal,
I clear about three
to five bills a job.
How many cases
do you get a week?
do you do a week?
Rate gets us ten to 20.
Ditto.
STOKES:
You trying to tell me
you make between
three and ten grand a week?
You've got to be authorized
to clean up biologicals.
If some high school
wage slave
mops up a nose bleed
at Mickey D's,
they're breaking the law.
I've got three employees making
30 bucks an hour.
If you guys are interested
in earning
a little extra
on the side?
Working for you, no thanks.
Crime rate is on
the rise, my friends.
You'd be wise to get in
on the ground floor.
I am thinking about starting
a franchise in Arizona.
Retirees die messy.
Like, bodies been
on the floor for a while.
Sometimes you got
to replace the entire floor.
Oh, look,
I install floors,
and drywall.
( horn beeps )
Ceilings, too,
and homeowner's insurance
picks up the tab.
What's going on, Marty?
You're still here?
You promised the place
would be clean.
I found a contractor
to finish the work.
( Southern accent ):
It's out of my hands, ma'am.
The lab boys, they haven't
quite released the scene yet.
They're moving at
the speed of government.
How are you doing with
the funeral arrangements?
Your cousin is taking very good
care of me, thank you.
We are here for you.
Now, I tell you what,
I'm going to call you as soon
as I'm done, okay?
Thank you, ma'am.
You should be ashamed
of yourself, Marty.
Oh, no. The bereaved
often find
a Southern accent very
comforting.
Comfort is what I give
these people, living victims.
The kind you guys
never deal with.
I see people on
the worst day of their lives.
In a small way,
I make their world normal again.
Oh!
Well, it smells
like eternity
for somebody in here.
The plastic must
have covered the smell.
Oh!
( gasps )
Holy mackerel.
Bitch in a box.
Hey, hey, hey.
I'm sorry.
I get paid by the body.
Nine vibrators,
five plugs,
four strands of beads.
And a partridge in a pear tree.
Some kids are happy playing
in the sand box,
others want every toy
in the store.
And apparently these
are dishwasher safe.
I'll swab the nooks and crannies
for semen,
vaginal secretions
and epithelials,
but don't get your hopes up.
Oh, my money's on
bag number two.
26 used condoms.
Just like being back
in college, right?
Sara said you didn't lose your
virginity until you were 22.
Grissom and I figured that they
practiced safe sex,
so we processed their trash.
Check them inside
and out, please.
I've analyzed condoms before,
Greg.
Just not in bulk.
Skewers?
Yeah, screen them for blood.
Possible weapon.
♪ ♪
( wet crackling )
STOKES:
Dental records ID'd
the body found
in the arcade machine.
Your ex-girlfriend
Melissa Pooley.
She didn't leave
town after all.
You want to revise your story?
We also found semen
in her vaginal cavity.
It matches your dead landlord.
Your girlfriend was
paying rent on her back
and you didn't like it.
You had sex with
our landlord?
At least I got off my ass
and did something about it.
That didn't happen.
She told me she convinced
Visingi to give us
more time on the rent.
I-I didn't know she
was banging the guy.
We don't care why
you killed her.
I didn't kill her!
Visingi evicts you,
keeps your stuff
and now you've got
a big problem.
Yeah, the dead body someone
crammed into
Ms. Pac-Man.
You can keep the rest of it!
All I want is Ms. Pac-Man!
Get the hell out of here.
( screaming )
Mr. Pincher, when someone is
killed with a table saw,
blood gets everywhere--
your hair and your clothes.
You would have had to take
a long, hot shower,
wash your clothes,
clip your nails,
toss your shoes.
Are you sure you
got it all, Charlie?
Hmm?
That's a nice watch.
It was my dad's.
I was admiring
the band.
Lots of open spaces
and nonporous surfaces.
That's a perfect place for blood
to hide, don't you think, Greg?
Yeah.
There's a chemical
I use called phenylthaline.
It can detect a speck of blood
the size of a pinprick.
I bet if I take that watch
it's going to tell me
more than time, isn't it?
You mind baby-sitting him
while I get a warrant?
I just went
to the arcade to scare him.
Things got out of hand.
Did you kill him?
It was an accident.
You guys have got to believe me,
I did not kill Melissa.
I didn't even know she was dead.
I know that you got the memo,
I'm not sure that you read it.
Eckley is being promoted
to Assistant Director.
They are taking applications
for his supervisor spot on days.
I want it.
What?
You want the day spot
for yourself?
You're worried about
giving me a good A.P. score
and breaking up the team?
Or maybe you just think that
I'm incapable of the position?
Not worthy
of the promotion?
Is that it?
I'm just always, always,
always defending myself to you.
Unbelievable.
I have a daughter
who is so starved
for my attention,
she is thumbing rides
to Fremont street
to see her grandfather.
The last person
I want her around.
I mean, not that it's much
better with my mother,
who sees Lindsay much
more often than I do.
I am missing out
on my daughter's life.
I have no life of my own.
Would you just stop me
and say something here?
You want the job because
you're worried about Lindsay?
That's part of it, but...
The position calls for
leadership, Catherine.
You have to inspire others,
solve problems,
which means you have to leave
your own problems
at home.
I want the job because
I can do it.
I'm qualified, I'm motivated
and I'm ready, Gil.
You know that I am.
I do.
Which is why I already
sent in your A.P.
I gave you 100%.
I even put in a good word
with the director.
The rest is up to you.
And...
I hope you get it.
Thank you.
I couldn't get anything
from the items
in the dishwasher,
including the skewers.
No results.
However,
the condoms produced.
I extracted DNA
from the semen.
Results indicate ten males.
The lubricant, which
seemed to be popular,
was good at retaining
both epithelials
and vaginal secretions.
11 females, no CODIS hits.
Is our victim represented?
Yes. F-7.
We can match her with the semen
from four different males.
M-4, M-5, M-1, M-8.
She was the belle of the ball.
My husband and I have
a very strong marriage.
But yes,
we enjoy the lifestyle.
The lifestyle?
We play.
Swing.
Wife swapping.
Paul and I had a rough
patch a few years ago.
We almost called it quits.
Swinging saved our marriage.
It was being with
other people
that made me realize
just how much I love my husband.
Erin is the greatest wife
in the world.
But you still had sex
with Vanessa Keaton?
Yeah. Yeah.
It's fun.
How do you feel
about Vanessa Keaton?
Very attractive woman.
She was the reason we invited
the Keatons to the parties.
She was into it.
Dan really wasn't.
How did your wife feel
about you and Vanessa Keaton?
Well, it's not like
we were having an affair.
That'd be breaking the rules.
The rules?
No, means no.
Arrive as a couple,
leave as a couple.
Drugs, never.
Condoms, condoms always.
No affairs.
Sex with someone other
than your spouse
is only allowed at the parties.
No photos,
no video.
And the kids must never know.
I came home one night.
I parked the car in the driveway
and went to the fridge
to grab a beer.
It was the wrong beer.
I was in the wrong house.
Anyway, it just got
all the neighbors talking.
Variety is a good thing.
And if you get the right
group of people together,
a couple of drinks,
you'd be surprised
what can happen.
Everybody fantasizes
about other people.
Even you, Mr. Grissom.
A neighbor,
a friend...
girl at the office.
Thank you.
I know I'm supposed
to be objective...
but I think I have a problem
with the lifestyle.
Well, they're consenting
adults, it's not illegal.
At most, they only
hurt themselves.
Tell that to Vanessa Keaton.
Everyone has a jealousy gene.
You think it was
a crime of passion?
Yeah.
When you have to go outside
a marriage for passion,
you're in trouble.
Or your asking for trouble.
Well, they say
they're happily married.
You think they're happy?
( phone rings )
Grissom.
Very good, thanks.
Hodges matched the water
in Vanessa Keaton's lungs.
He knows where she drowned.
BRASS:
So Mr. and Mrs. Cunningham,
was Vanessa Keaton here
the night she died?
No.
Well, we matched the water
in her lungs to your spa.
And I see what appears to be
a blood smear on the stone.
Well, sometimes we forget
to lock the gate.
So your neighbors come in
and use the spa?
It's possible.
Yeah, I guess so,
I mean, you share
everything else.
Why not?
So what time
did you
leave the party?
Around 11:30.
But we didn't come right home.
BRASS:
Where'd you go?
We went to the Bellagio.
A nice, romantic night out,
just the two of us.
Sometimes being with others
gives you the urge
to be alone.
BRASS:
I see.
Well, we're going
to compel a DNA sample,
so we'll know if you were
intimate
with Vanessa Keaton.
I admit I had sex with her
and...
Karen Brady,
and Mallory Stone.
Three strikes you're out.
Heard your suspect's
looking pretty good.
You heard right.
Charlie confessed
to killing the landlord.
And the blood on his
watch is a match
to Visingi's DNA.
What about her?
Swears he has nothing
to do with it.
You got a C.O.D.?
Blunt-force trauma
to the occipital region.
No trace in the wound track.
Do you have any
idea what hit her?
Yeah.
The impact's deep.
Weapon was probably heavy.
Radius of curvature,
roughly three centimeters.
Could be a pipe.
Could be anything.
Mrs. Cunningham,
you told us that
you spent last night
at the Bellagio
with your husband.
That's correct.
Are you sure about that?
D-Do I need a lawyer?
I mean, that's your call,
that's your right,
but let me point out
that if you're covering
for your husband,
that's conspiracy
after the fact.
Now, are you prepared
to go to jail over this?
( chuckles ):
Look, I-I answered
your question.
Okay, what if I told you
the hotel maid told us
that you weren't with Tom,
what would you say?
I'd say she was lying.
You know, I'm trying
to help you out here,
and I want to help
you out, okay?
But you got to
cut the crap.
( chuckles ):
Okay?
Come on, tell me
what happened.
I mean, security confirmed
that you were with a female.
Late 20s, blonde, I mean,
she even paid for breakfast
with her credit card.
So... I'll tell you what,
why don't we start over, okay?
And you tell me what happened.
Look, Tom asked me
to think about our son.
He begged me
to say we were together.
I swear, I don't know...
anything that went on
between him and Vanessa.
I don't know.
Found some porn.
Well, nothing new
about this stuff.
The frescos at Pompeii
were more explicit.
The Kama Sutra
and Decameron.
Yeah, but that's art;
this... is not art.
Hmm.
Here we go.
Webcam photo.
And she's wearing La Perla.
Vanessa Keaton.
BROWN:
The first victim
was killed with a weapon of
opportunity, the table saw.
The second victim gets
a crack on the head.
So you're thinking
the weapon is still in here?
Yeah.
Why would the killer
leave it in here?
Well, the killer
left the body here.
That's true.
Mr. Pincher had
a cash-only business.
Yeah. And he didn't
have a gun license.
( sighs )
You got something?
Yes.
A little store security.
Liars, liars,
all men are liars!
It seems that the missus
caught her husband
collecting rent
from the late Melissa Pooley.
She just waited till
he left the building.
You slut! I don't care
what he told you,
you still have
to pay rent.
Go to hell!
Luckily, she left
her prints behind.
We had them on file
from an assault case in '98.
Yeah, she went a little
further this time.
Yeah, from what I hear, she did
a lousy job cleaning that bat.
Amateur.
You know, you guys,
you could have waited
till after she paid me
to arrest her.
What did I ever
do to you?
Oh, except
crack your case
wide open.
Don't worry, man,
Grissom talked to the
sheriff, said he's gonna
pick up your tab.
Really?
Mm-hmm.
( chuckles )
Thanks.
Hey, you think this could mean
a nice, fat city contract
for me?
Good to see you, Marty.
See you around, Marty.
Call me.
Innie, outie.
And Vanessa doesn't have
any moles on her torso.
The woman in the photo
is not Vanessa.
Oh, you got my message.
What message?
To meet me here.
I was preparing a body
for a mortuary pickup,
and I noticed something.
Postmortem bruising.
GRISSOM:
Well, it can take a day or two
after autopsy
for the bruises to percolate
through the soft tissue
and become visible.
Vanessa wasn't stabbed
four times with a skewer.
She was stabbed twice
with a two-pronged instrument.
♪ ♪
SIDLE:
I just started combing through
Tom Cunningham's computer.
I haven't I.D.'d
our mystery woman,
but there's just lots
of back and forth
between Cunningham's
e-mail account and Keaton's.
Any attachments?
Yeah.
Got one for
the Keatons' account.
"U axd 4 my pic so here.
SweetKeat."
Any reply?
SIDLE:
Yes. From...
Cunning1.
"Can you handle it?
Midnight.
Behind the skate park."
You can stop the tape.
Amy came on to me.
She's 15.
Does she look 15 to you?
Tom,
be very quiet.
They got me on tape.
I'm trying to explain.
She's a minor, you're an adult.
What's to explain?
We have information
pertaining to Vanessa
Keaton's death.
Get me the D.A.
We want a deal.
Too late.
You are an inny.
Amy,
you e-mailed this photo
of yourself to Tom Cunningham.
What's she talking about?
I have no idea.
You were having an affair
with Tom Cunningham.
He's just been booked
on statutory rape.
What?!
It wasn't rape.
I'm gonna to kill
that son of a bitch!
Like you care
who I have sex with?
I know about your parties,
all the kids know,
so don't get all
righteous on me.
I want to see Tom.
Let's go.
GRISSOM:
Mr. Keaton, sit down, please.
We're not done yet.
We retrieved this from
the Cunningham's backyard.
Your stepmother's blood
is on the tines,
and your fingerprints
are on them.
( woman screams)
MAN:
Easy, easy.
The stab wounds weren't fatal,
but your stepmother
was knocked unconscious.
It took two or three
minutes for her to drown.
GRISSOM:
That's a long time
to stand around
and watch someone die.
It wasn't like that.
How could you!
Calm down!
You need to go home,
right now.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
He was trying to protect me.
So we put her in the fountain.
He loves me.
Can I see him?
Arrive as a couple,
leave as a couple.
No photos, no video.
No affairs.
And the kids
must never know.