( electronic dance music intro)
( car horn honking )
( techno music playing )
♪ If I was in World War II,
they'd call me Spitfire ♪
( beeping )
♪ If I was in World War II,
they'd call me Spitfire ♪
they'd call me ...fire ♪
♪ ...Fire ♪
MAN:
What the hell is that?
( distant siren )
Yo, man.
When's the blitz?
( sirens blaring )
( cheering )
Right on time.
♪ But a bitch ain't one ♪
♪ I got the rap patrol
on the ... patrol ♪
♪ Foes that wanna make sure
my casket's closed ♪
♪ Rap critics that say
he's "Money Cash ..." ♪
♪ I'm from the hood stupid
what type of facts are those ♪
♪ If you grew up with O's
and you zap the toes ♪
♪ You'd celebrate
the minute... ♪
( gunshots, screaming )
WOMAN ( over radio):
...three, 1000 Chestnut at...
BRASS:
So witnesses heard
multiple gunshots.
They think.
Because if it was
during the blitz.
You know, the lights were out,
sirens were going off,
search lights, the whole
World War II experience.
When exactly did war
become a party?
( phone rings )
Gunshot residue,
close range.
.32 auto.
Belly got it.
( beeping )
How'd they get it
through the metal detector?
Well, uh... Oh, geez.
( phone rings )
I'll tell you,
it's a busy night.
Recently burned.
Another body?
Another murder.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
So there's good news
and there's bad news.
The good news is,
this is the busiest lab
in the country.
The bad news is
this is the busiest
lab in the country.
That's why I'm here.
Oh, I've waited
for you forever.
I love you!
Man, if I ever
have to search
another torched car...
Nick!
This is Chandra.
Chandra Moore.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, the new DNA girl.
Right?
MOORE:
B.S. in bio-chem.
M.S. in molecular biology.
Five years of service
in DNA at the CCL.
Okay, well, I'm going to
go use the no-pressure,
no-AC, stinks-of-feet
shower.
So...
welcome.
( sighing )
So I had some time
to think while I was away.
Enough time to figure out why
I made such a stupid mistake.
I-I do not have
a drinking problem.
I have a, uh,
me problem.
My P.E.A.P. counselor suggested
that it would be a good idea
for me to talk to my supervisor
and that's you, Grissom, so...
I never told you
about my family.
I never told anyone
about my family, why would I...
Sara?
I want you to meet
my replacement.
This is Chandra.
Nice to meet you, Chandra.
Likewise.
So, how was it?
How was what?
Well, you took
some vacation time, right?
Yeah, right.
It was great.
Yeah? Okay.
Hey, how was it?
BROWN:
It sucked.
I hate lawyers,
I hate court.
They all need
to dry up and die. Hi.
Warrick, right?
Yeah.
I saw your presentation
on longitudinal
striations of the toenail
in Dallas, A.A.F.S.?
Really good work.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
And you are?
Oh, I'm Chandra.
Chandra Moore.
I'm the new DNA person.
Well,
that's the plan anyway.
Would you like
to see the boss's office?
Good luck.
Thank you.
Nice to meet you.
Same.
Grissom...
I'd like
to introduce you
to Chandra Moore.
Pleased to meet you,
sir.
I'm a fan.
GRISSOM:
Wow.
You're hot.
I-I'm sorry?
You're emanating heat.
This is a new infrared camera.
It's good for looking
at evidence in the dark.
Did you get her blood yet?
My... why?
So many reasons.
WILLOWS:
Where is he?
You can't possibly call
that thing my office.
It's a cupboard.
Catherine, have you
met Chandra Moore?
She'll be doing DNA while
Greg's in the field.
Hello, I'm Catherine.
We need to talk.
Well, not now-- too much work.
You have a suspicious death
at the Palermo.
Warrick,
trash call at a weekly
at Fremont and 12th.
Nick, Sara, body
in a shallow grave,
dry lake bed, in Ely,
off Groom Lake Road.
All right,
I'll meet you there.
Greg, you're going
to be with me,
your final proficiency.
Great.
Let me show you
to your new digs.
Good luck.
We leave in five minutes.
SANDERS:
Okay.
Can I talk to you real quick?
Certainly.
Have you been seeing
your P.E.A.P. counselor?
Yeah.
How's it going?
Well,
it's been interesting.
( glass breaking )
It's going to be
a busy night, huh?
Mmm.
We'll talk later.
Are you sure?
Yeah, yeah.
MAN:
I don't remember,
okay?
Why don't you
believe me?
I swear to God!
I did nothing to that woman.
I have
never seen her before.
DETECTIVE:
Relax, relax.
Let's just go
over this again.
All right, let's go
over it again.
Tell me what
you remember.
Nothing.
That's what I remember--
nothing.
That's it?
Stop taking my picture.
Sir, wait here.
Hey. Housecleaning
found Mr. Johnson
passed out
on the bed
next to the victim.
They alerted security
and apparently
he just came to.
With the worst hangover
a guy could ever have.
Yeah.
He's a golf ball
salesman from Ohio.
WILLOWS:
Massive hemorrhaging.
Is this from
a single wound?
Cracked skull.
Did you I.D. her?
No I.D. on her.
WILLOWS:
Well, she's got
some breast implants.
That's for sure.
I'm going to guess stripper.
She's got
a locker room key.
We'll trace it back to the club.
DETECTIVE:
Quite a party
last night.
You can say that again.
Looks like she went back
into the bedroom
to call for help.
DETECTIVE:
Well, no calls
were made from the room.
WILLOWS:
Why is it you guys
can never
hit the bowl?
You know, if this guy
took Viagra,
you're lucky
he hit the floor
and not the ceiling.
Right.
Sign of a struggle?
How does a guy fall asleep
after killing
a woman?
BRASS:
How does somebody get
into your club with a gun?
Don't ask me;
ask the metal detector.
It's supposed to work.
Ever see
the dead guy before?
No, not me.
Hey, Crystal!
Hey, baby, you talk
to the guy that got capped
in your section tonight?
No.
Hey, Gil.
Wait, you've got
something stuck
to your shoe.
Oh, no,
it's just Sanders.
Hey, I went
through his pockets.
No wallet, no I.D.
Uh...
Just some cash
and these car keys.
It's a rental.
Thanks, David.
SANDERS:
I never seen
this place
with the lights
on before.
It's kind of like seeing
a one-night stand
in the morning
for the first time.
Beer goggles.
This is your
proficiency test, Greg.
You might want
to work the scene.
What do you see?
Chaos.
Look a little closer.
Cartridge casings.
Bullet impact.
We haven't recovered
the gun yet, so...?
( sighs )
Victim was shot
at close range...
in a crowd.
Witnesses say
there was a stampede.
It's a good time
to ditch a gun.
Maybe it's still here.
Good.
Where are you going?
Don't worry about me;
worry about you.
It's going to be a long night.
Hey, power went out
about an hour ago.
MAN:
I checked the circuit box.
Blown fuse, Room 39.
That's when I found him.
WOMAN:
Hey, we need some AC.
I got kids in here.
O'RILEY:
We're working
on it, ma'am.
We'll have someone up
very soon, okay?
Well, there's what blew
your fuse.
Hot plate?
Electrocution.
That's a quick way
to go.
BROWN:
Not always.
That's hardly
our first suicide.
You think it's a suicide?
Oh, come on,
this loser?
He's been here
four weeks.
He only paid for two.
Wore the same clothes
every day.
No family,
no friends.
You got a name?
Lance "I'll have it
for you tomorrow"
Frazer.
I was going to throw him out
in the morning.
Oh, thank God.
Yeah, he's got
some old school suicide scars.
Told you. Loser.
Looks like he was
getting ready
to skip town on you.
( screaming )
( sizzling )
( mumbling gibberish )
For inspiration
or for Last Rites?
O'RILEY:
Wallet's empty.
Pack of cigarettes,
sweetener, and a
hot dog wrapper.
Doesn't add up to much.
Don't be so sure.
You are so late.
What happened to you?
I'm late?
Sara Sidle and Nick Stokes.
STOKES:
Yeah.
Detective Travis.
I'm ex-LAPD Homicide.
SIDLE:
Nice to meet you.
Who are these people?
Uh, concerned citizens.
Come on, right this way,
please.
The weather's been
pretty bad out here.
I don't know if you're going
to find much.
A couple of teenagers
were out here
last night shooting off
their dads' guns.
One of them...
tripped over
this thing.
These kids thought
they'd found a
real space alien.
Yeah, we were the second call
they made.
The first one
was to Dan Rather...
who I don't think is coming.
Who called in
the space people?
TRAVIS:
From what I
understand,
they're always out here.
See this guy in the silver lamé?
He put it on the "Watch
the Skies" Web site.
It's been a freaking
free-for-all ever since then.
You know where you are,
right?
SIDLE:
Area 51.
TRAVIS:
It's the most secretive piece
of real estate in the world.
This is about as close
to the base
as we can get and still be
on public land.
I guess the killer
should've dug a deeper hole.
STOKES:
Not with a short-
handled shovel.
Not to mention Nevada desert
is compact dirt, not sand.
People usually give up
before they
hit three feet.
Got some paint... maybe.
Something for Hodges.
One thing's for sure:
it's going to take
a lot longer getting him out
than it did getting him in.
Can't you guys
just beam him back
to the morgue?
I don't know how many times
you wanna ask me--
I woke up this morning like this.
The handcuffs are new.
DETECTIVE:
Anything you want to add?
SUSPECT:
No, I don't want
to add anything!
DETECTIVE:
You don't remember anything?
No, you know what?
For the last time,
I don't remember, okay?
Okay.
She... she must have
slipped me something.
You sure it wasn't the booze?
I don't touch mini bars.
That bitch drugged me.
Well, if she drugged you, sir,
it'll still be in your system.
A blood test would be
in your best interest.
( alarm chirps )
♪ ♪
Her mother's coming
from Reno to claim her.
I know.
Vartann called.
Nicole Richards, 25.
Her stage name is Raven.
We traced
the locker room key
to the Embassy Strip Club.
Your turn.
Sharp-force laceration
to the frontal scalp
with underlying fracture
to the frontal calvarium.
Cause of death,
contusion to the brain
and subdural hemorrhaging.
Tox screen pegged
her alcohol content at .30.
That's almost four times
the legal limit.
Chronic drinking tends to cause
a reduction in platelets.
It thins out the blood
and retards clotting.
That would explain
why there was so much
blood at the scene.
The only other
thing I found...
was a swollen ankle.
Well, you ever try shaking
your ass in four-inch heels?
Don't answer that.
( water dripping )
( static
and electronic crackling )
( crackling resumes )
We think it's a hearing aid.
Good. Yeah.
Yeah. It's out of juice.
Yeah.
Hearing aids have unique
serial numbers, Super Dave.
If you get this
to Detective Travis,
he should be able
to run it down for us.
Arachnodactyly.
Abnormally long fingers.
Hmm.
David,
I know where he's from.
Hmm?
Planet Seiko.
E.T.
You've got to be kidding me.
Oh, you're going to love this.
"Like a blinding supernova,
"your love is blasted
throughout the universe.
"Two spirits become one
by the power of the sun,
"the moon,
"and all the planets
of the universe."
SIDLE:
Big City Costumes.
SANDERS:
Is that the burnt Polaroid
from the nightclub?
Yes, Greg,
I just scanned it in.
Bobby Dawson confirms that
this .32 auto from the club
is indeed the murder weapon.
He's running it
through NCIC and pawn shops.
What's this blue stuff
on the slide and the grip?
It's okay to say
you don't know, Greg.
That's why we have
a trace lab.
( siren wailing )
( cheering )
Whoo!
MAN:
There you go!
Congratulations.
All right.
On behalf
of the Golden Nugget,
let me congratulate you.
You know how long
I've played here
and I've never gotten laid?
Hey, Warrick, how you doing?
Good.
Listen, we've got
your favorite 21 table
ready for you over there, okay?
Tricks are for kids, man.
I don't play games anymore.
Then what are you doing here?
I'm working on a case.
Did anyone hit a big
jackpot here yesterday?
Yeah, guy won 50 G on that
big machine over there.
50 G?
Uh-huh.
Did he look like this?
Yep, that's him.
Do you remember
about what time that was?
Midnight.
That was the end of my shift.
Looks like he needed it, too.
Really?
Yeah, dirty clothes,
serious B.O.
Funkier than
James Brown, huh?
Big time.
Don't be a stranger.
Good to see you, man.
Blood standard, unknown urine,
tell me it's the same guy.
Now, Greg mentioned
to you that my stuff
gets done first, right?
Yeah, well, in my lab,
I decide what gets run and when.
Unless Mr. Grissom
tells me otherwise.
It's uh, quiet in here.
Greg played music.
Well, I find it
distracting.
Hit on your fingerprint
from the Palermo.
Carl Johnson?
Nope, George Craven.
Ex-con.
Record for
domestic violence.
Runs security
at the Embassy Strip Club.
Mr. Willard, Las Vegas, Police.
We have a warrant.
Go around the back, Bobby.
You get this address
off a pill bottle?
Herpes.
There was a prescription
for Valacyclovin.
I cross-referenced
the pharmacy logo.
( clattering )
Sorry.
I'm late.
BRASS:
Polaroid doesn't do him justice.
Same kind of wire I found
in the first victim's car.
Ken Willard.
Yeah, I recognize that
guy in the picture.
From Blitzkrieg?
Manny, the club owner.
So our first victim
( man choking )
strangled this guy with wire,
photographs it...
takes it to the club,
burns it for some reason,
and then takes one
between the eyes himself?
( gunshot )
Bring me the head
of John the Baptist.
Salome--
wanted proof
that he was dead.
They didn't have
Polaroids back then.
So you're saying our first
victim was a hired killer.
Hired by whom?
Whoever shot him?
( lisping ):
And like a blinding supernova,
your love is blasting
throughout the universe.
Two spirits have become one.
Earthling to earthling.
So...
by the power of the sun
and the moon
and all the planets
in the universe,
and the great state of Nevada,
I now pronounce you
husband and wife.
You may kiss that bride.
( applause )
Don't get all misty
on me, now.
So the deceased's costume
was similar to mine, you say?
Yeah, identical.
Manufactured by
Big City Costumes.
Specifically designed
for this chapel.
Yeah, that's who makes them.
I guess I shouldn't
be so surprised--
things get stolen
from here all the time.
Them sci-fi nuts,
you know,
they're big collectors.
Do the initials E.T.
mean anything to you?
No, just the...
Honey, we have a 3:00.
Oh, yeah.
So business is good?
Oh, yes, never better.
You know, I mean, people,
they come to Vegas
to get rich or to get hitched.
I mean, you know, that's
not why we do it, though.
Is it, honey?
We believe in love,
you know, in just
whatever form it might take.
Are you two married?
No.
No? All right, well,
we're open 24 hours.
There's a toll-free number right
there on the back, all right?
Don't let
this moment
pass you by.
She's gonna getcha.
( chuckles )
Hey!
You kids don't want
to get married
by Spock or whatever
his name is in there.
What would your mother say?
Here.
ELVIS IMPERSONATOR:
Come on, all you hound dogs,
get married by the king
at the Burnin' Love
Wedding Chapel.
Viva Las Vegas, man.
How do you explain
your fingerprint
on the murder weapon?
I don't need
to explain anything.
I didn't kill her.
Thumbprint on the towel bar?
In the bathroom at the Palermo?
Yeah.
Yeah, I was in there.
I took a leak.
Come on, Raven's my girl,
all right?
She always had me
check out her money.
You let your girlfriend
turn tricks?
Two grand to do
some Midwestern chump?
She wouldn't turn it down,
and I wasn't gonna stop her.
Dude stumbled in
from the Acid Drop
ready to go.
He seemed harmless.
I used the facility
before I left.
Then I bounced.
I was cool with
her way of life.
But I didn't want
to stay and watch.
Fresh wounds.
You get those
kicking guys out of
The Embassy, or...
kicking your girlfriend's ass?
I don't think that
you were cool
with her ways.
A big, strong guy like you,
you're not gonna
share her.
She didn't tell you
where she was going.
You followed her,
and you killed her.
You damn tramp whore!
No!
( yelling and gasping )
I need a lawyer.
I need your clothes.
So, you like her?
I like not being her anymore.
The sticky substance
in the slide of your gun
is tape adhesive.
What about
the blue coloring?
Chloromide M.E.A.,
sodium lauryl
sulfate, pine oil.
Components of your basic
bathroom disinfectant.
So, Greg, how do you
explain adhesive
and toilet bowl
cleanser on the gun?
I don't know.
I can tell you the toilets
in the club had blue water.
You inspected the toilet
bowls for evidence?
Well, when you got to go,
you got to go.
Whew.
GRISSOM:
At a crime
scene, Greg?
Everybody knows you hold it.
You go across the street
or next-door,
somewhere other
than the scene,
until you've
cleared the restroom.
Did you clear the restroom?
No.
Well, you could've
flushed away evidence,
wiped away fingerprints
from the handle.
Make sure you
include this
in your field notes.
I like Chandra.
She's cute.
The .32 automatic
we found at your club,
the serial numbers
were filed off.
I mean, you know better
than anyone, that's a felony.
Lucky for us,
the Crime Lab
recovered the numbers.
Hey, look, that gun was stolen
out of my desk last week.
So what's this,
"The dog ate my homework"?
Come on, man, think about it.
Why would I kill somebody
in my own club?
I still got yellow tape
across the front door.
What do you care?
You only own ten percent
of the club.
Ken Willard owns the rest.
Yeah, but the guy's not around.
Besides... things change.
You're damn right they do.
He's dead.
What?
Wait-wait-wait, you don't think
that I had any...
No.
Hi. Chris here?
You are...?
I'm Catherine.
Oh, right, you must
be his cop friend.
Hey.
Hi.
You should've
told me
you were coming down.
What's going on?
I'm checking out an alibi.
Was this guy in here
last night?
Yeah, he was, uh,
belligerent, drunk--
he was groping
every waitress
in the place.
We sent him over to the
strip joint next-door.
It was more his speed.
( phone ringing )
You're busy.
Am I gonna see
you tonight?
I'm working late.
Me, too.
( computer beeping )
Duct tape.
So the shooter stuck the gun
in the toilet earlier
to avoid the metal detector.
Echoes of Michael Corleone.
So if Manny is the shooter,
why would he need
to hide his own gun?
He wouldn't.
So what are you gonna do now?
Check for prints.
Please don't do that.
Oh, sorry. Uh,
I was just looking
for our alien
DNA analysis.
Not yet.
Come on, where's your
intellectual curiosity?
I hardly considered it
a priority.
It's very neat in here.
You're very neat, Chandra.
( printer printing )
Thank you.
Your shovel from
the desert?
Dug into the paint history
of somebody's car.
Black enamel undercoats,
General Motors,
'60s vintage.
Three layers of primer
plus a acrylic top, pink.
A pink Cadillac?
Hey. E.T. phoned home.
I got an I.D. off
the hearing aid.
Our alien is
Reverend Edward Thomas
of 49 Stuart Street.
Oh, the Chapel
of Intergalactic Love.
We've already been there.
Well, if the reverend is dead,
who's running the place?
( loud slam )
Could you please
take this somewhere else?
We know where there's
a pink Cadillac.
( like Elvis ):
Thank ya.
Thank ya very much.
( sighs )
I got the stripper's
boyfriend on camera.
If he just killed somebody,
he's being really cool
about it.
Yeah, and he didn't change
his clothes from last night.
I screened them
for blood--
negative.
And the tox report
on Mr. Johnson
confirms traces
of triazelam in
his blood.
So golf ball salesman
was too doped up to kill her.
The boyfriend couldn't
have bludgeoned her
without getting
blood on his clothes.
No.
Hey.
If Lance Frazer won 50 grand,
I can't find it.
It's not in his room,
no bank account, no car.
What time did the super say
the electricity
went out?
12:30.
12:30?
How does a broke-ass guy
like Lance lose 50 grand
in 30 minutes?
Had to take him ten minutes
just to walk back home.
Well, they say gamblers
are creatures of habit.
I bet you Lance did
the same thing every day.
Win or lose.
I'm going to need to take a walk
in this guy's shoes.
Hey, Captain.
Yo.
Do you sell
Clark cigarettes?
Yeah, I do.
You know, you've got to be
the only other guy in Vegas
that smokes these sticks?
Really?
Yeah.
Is this the other guy?
That's him.
He's here every night.
Big spender.
Pays me in quarters.
Sara.
Let's go talk to the king.
Hey, Pop.
Like the Buddha
said to the monk,
make me one with everything.
Sure thing, boss.
Coming right up.
Were you working last night?
Nope.
I don't usually work this stand.
Who does?
Some punk kid.
Just up and quit last night.
Left the stand
sitting right here.
Really?
Would you happen to know
where this punk kid lives?
Daniel Halburt!
We've got a warrant
to search the premises!
Open up!
Yeah, what up, man?
Get out!
Hey, man!
Clear!
Whoo!
Would you look at the size
of this flat screen?
My lord, that's a whole month
of my pay right there.
A new PlayStation?
A brand-new stereo?
You must have sold a lot
of hot dogs last night, huh?
Did you get that
from Lance?
You know, your old friend.
Did you sell a lot
of hot dogs to him?
I finally hit.
50 large, cash.
Kick back in the tub,
pay off that shifty super,
and I'm checking
into the Bellagio.
I gambled every day of my life.
I never won a damn thing.
Tell me where the money is.
( sizzling )
He should have just showed me
where the money was.
It was in the Bible.
Take this guy out of here.
So as the one
and only king of rock and roll,
I now pronounce you,
husband and wife.
You get over there
and kiss that bride!
All right!
There we go!
Does Elvis look
familiar to you?
That's the stuff!
Do karate if you do, right?
♪ Viva Las Vegas ♪
That's right, that's right.
You want to tell us about
the scratch on the Cadillac?
( lisping ):
I mean, come on.
That's more
than just a scratch.
I mean, it's nothing compared
to the vandalism or the stress.
I mean, come on.
It's a war out there,
you know?
Marriage is money
in this town
and every chapel owner
wants more.
I mean, last month,
middle of the "I do's,"
a rock comes flying
through my stained glass.
Were you in a war
with Ed Thomas?
We found the shovel
near the body.
The paint transfer
matches your car.
Well, I guess Ed was at war
with me.
( muttering angrily )
I mean, I was looking
for a truce.
At first I thought
that he was ignoring me,
and then I remembered
about his hearing problem.
Ed, I want
to talk to you.
Ed, I want to talk to you.
He was dead when I got there,
I swear it.
It must have been
a heart attack or something.
And so I took him out to Area 51
and then I buried him.
Why would you possibly take him
all the way out there?
Because it's what
he would have wanted.
And so then you just
took over his business?
Yeah, well, I mean,
it seemed like a good idea
at the time, you know?
Keep spreading the love.
The coroner determined
that Ed suffered
from Marfan syndrome,
similar to Abe Lincoln.
Abnormally long fingers,
arms, legs, scoliosis.
So, what does that got
to do with me?
The syndrome weakened
Ed's abdominal aorta.
When you found him,
he wasn't dead,
he was unconscious.
He was bleeding
internally.
Yeah, the coroner
found dirt in his stomach
and his upper airways,
underneath
his fingernails.
( screams )
He died from asphyxia,
all right,
but it was post-burial.
( softly ):
I think I'm going to be sick.
I'm sorry.
Hit the lights.
The victim had a swollen ankle.
What if this bracelet
is an anklet?
By then Johnson had passed out
from the triazelam.
The more docile the john,
the easier the job,
except when you need him
to save your life.
Please, wake up, wake up.
Well, if Johnson was innocent,
why'd he lie to us?
Try explaining this
to your family back in Ohio.
GRISSOM:
Are you aware
that your fingerprints
are in the federal system?
You're awaiting trial
on drug trafficking,
Manny posted your bail.
I was just
helping her out.
It wasn't my "E."
Oh, yeah?
Who's "E" was it?
Ken Willard
asked me to bring
a bag back from L.A. for him.
I didn't know what was in it.
So you and Ken had
a relationship?
We dated.
You both took
Valacyclovin as well.
We found your prints
on some duct tape
in the women's restroom.
The duct tape
was used to hide Manny's gun.
The gun used
to kill your hit man.
Hit man?
What the hell
are you talking about?
Well, with Ken Willard gone,
your 10% of the club
becomes 100%.
I didn't kill him
and she doesn't deserve
to go to jail.
Look, the guy was a snake.
Picking up girls,
using them as mules,
throwing them away.
So what does a contract killer
cost these days, Manny?
Manny didn't do anything.
He's only tried to help me.
The guy said
he could solve
my problem for ten grand.
When the job was done,
he said the price had doubled.
I couldn't afford that...
and I didn't want
to get Manny involved.
So I stole the gun
from his office.
I kept it
in the bathroom overnight...
( hip-hop music blaring )
waited till
that son of a bitch showed up,
picked my moment.
Second I get arrested,
Ken dumps me.
He says he'll kill me
if I roll over on him.
The way I saw it,
I had two choices:
either kill him or go to jail.
Congratulations. You got both.
( techno music blaring )
( laughing )
What do you expect?
I run a nightclub.
Who was that?
You committed
a fatal error, Greg.
You compromised evidence
at a crime scene.
A judgment like that
can cost us a conviction.
In order to solo in the field,
you have to successfully
complete three proficiencies.
I failed this one.
Yeah.
But...
since you found
a suitable replacement
in the lab,
I'm going to give you
one more chance.
Thank you.
Hey, Chandra,
how was your first day?
I can't do this.
It's too much
for one person.
They all want...
they all want you,
and I can't be you.
I'm sorry, Greg,
but I'm going back
to Connecticut.