( engine roaring )
( siren whoops, engine revs )
Officer...
thank God you're here.
You know why
I stopped you?
Yeah, I... I...
I was speeding, uh...
of course, but you have
to understand, you see,
someone is chasing me.
You see, I have videos.
I bet you do.
Let's start with
license and registration.
Officer, if I could...
if I could just show you.
WILLOWS:
Found a camcorder.
No tape inside.
Not much traffic.
Makes it a lot easier to run
someone off the road...
...and slash their throat.
She was slashed south
of the border, as well.
Women in convertibles
are low-hanging fruit.
And it was a top-down night.
and TOYOTA.
Choose any direction,
as long as it's moving forward.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
That's a nice ring.
It's at least four carats.
We've been shopping.
Lots of surgical
procedures here:
artificial breasts,
cheek implants...
collagen lips...
You'd be surprised
how many women
I get on this table
with fake parts.
Plastic lasts longer.
Wow. Mascara,
tweezers...
under-eye cream...
...neck-firming lotion.
Girls.
Pads...
One, two, three, four
jars of depilatory cream?
That's a lot of bikini wax.
Some girls hate
the nether-stubble.
Nether-stubble?
Swipe card.
Entertainment Department,
Tangiers.
Well...
Walter Clancy
didn't mind stubble.
Who's Walter?
The registered owner
of this vehicle.
So she either
borrowed this car...
or she stole it.
Genital wounds were more
profound than I expected.
Profound how?
Well, I was looking for ovaries
and I found a prostate.
She was a he?
"She" had genital
reassignment surgery.
And what does that mean exactly?
Exactly?
Her testicles were removed
and her penis was inverted,
creating a vagina.
And, evidently, the killer
kept subtracting.
Subtracting what?
Well, they don't call
it an Adam's apple
for nothing.
A man with issues might become
upset if he found one
on his woman.
Cause?
Severed carotid
and jugular complex.
Uh, incised wounds are
almost surgical in nature.
Used an extremely
sharp weapon.
Vicious attack.
Probably from someone
emotionally involved.
Time?
Best estimate,
between 8:00 and midnight.
I collected a standard SAE kit.
WILLOWS:
Good.
Because top or bottom,
this looks like a sexual assault
that turned into a hate crime.
OFFICER:
Clock a Thunderbird doing 90.
I nail it.
The skirt driving tells me
she's being chased.
And then she asks if she can
show me some videos.
How were they?
I didn't bite.
She was working it.
Rough duty.
Look, she gave me
this lame story
about the car
being her brother's,
and that she had
lost her license,
but she has his license,
and yakety-yak.
I just let her off
with a warning.
So you had speeding,
driving without a license,
possible stolen vehicle,
and you let her off
with a warning.
What are you implying?
She got off pretty easy.
How about you?
I resent that.
Well, I'm sure
that she resented
being sexually harassed
and slaughtered two miles
from the place
you pulled her over!
I didn't know
about that until
you called me in here.
You know, you have a sexual
harassment flag in your file.
Oh, so that makes me
a sex murderer?
I know a place
about two miles up.
It's a little more private.
I mean, you know,
if... if I found out
that the gal who was
stripping my gears was a guy,
I mean, I'd be mad, too.
( groaning )
What are you?!
( screams )
Or maybe you prefer a stick.
I told you, nothing happened.
You're on administrative duty
until we confirm that.
Mind submitting your DNA?
Just tell me where to spit.
Ran her prints through
I-AFIS and I got two hits.
A Wendy Garner
was a dancer at the Tangiers,
and Walter Clancy,
a blackjack dealer
at the Riviera in the mid-'90s.
Okay,
let's give this a shot.
The coroner noted that she had
collagened lips.
Okay, so 86
those cheek implants.
Now, estrogen
would've
rounded out the face,
so square that jaw.
JOHNSON:
Got that.
I'm gonna give her a haircut.
Add some whiskers...
BROWN:
Wow.
Take away the, uh...
eye makeup.
JOHNSON:
And I'll fix the eyebrows.
Well, one thing's for certain:
Walter didn't kill Wendy.
BROWN:
No,
it's more like
Wendy killed Walter.
Okay, Wendy's mouth had
two foreign DNA donors:
One seminal, one saliva.
Neither was a match
for Officer Mann.
Huh.
Wow. That is some rock.
Platinum setting.
Princess cut.
Somebody really loved
her-- oh-- him.
I think she's a her.
Right. Well...
a diamond that big, you
hope she had it LoJacked.
That is what I'm counting on.
There's a serial number
micro-etched into the band
around the diamond--
I'm hoping it gets me a groom.
You know, I once
heard this story
about this man who
became a woman
because he was obsessed
with a lesbian...
who was really a man.
Overshare.
Wendy just bought
her wedding gown.
She, uh,
she would've been
a beautiful bride.
We just wrote our
wedding vows last week.
I just figured
that she was
at a friend's house--
a girlfriend's house--
for the night.
Mr. Laner,
how long had Wendy
been a dancer?
About two or three years
in the line.
I mean, never topless.
In her costume,
she was a vision.
How long had you known
each other?
About a year.
We met in a Grief Support Group.
I'd lost my wife.
Sorry for your loss.
Thank you.
Who was Wendy
grieving for?
Uh, she'd... lost
her twin brother.
Would that be Walter?
Yeah, Walter.
Did you know him?
Sort of.
♪ ♪
Mr. Laner, I need to ask
you a personal question,
if you don't mind--
it may help us.
Did you and your fiancee
sleep in separate beds?
Uh...
we were an old-fashioned couple.
Neither of us
believed in
premarital sexual relations.
I mean, that's why
I fell in love with her,
because of her
traditional values.
This is confusing.
BRASS:
She had her period?
Impossible.
No uterus, no period.
So a guy desperate
to change his sex
hooks up with a guy
desperate not to have any.
A match made in heaven.
I think we need to tell
Mr. Laner the truth.
Are we sure
he doesn't know?
( cheering and applause )
Aborigines say
they dance naked
to make the gods happy.
The gods would be
happy in Vegas.
Did you ever see
any transsexuals
when you danced?
Only civilians
confuse strippers
and showgirls.
You can't cheat
the full monty.
That's Wendy's
station over there.
Thank you.
Hello, ladies.
I'm Catherine Willows.
This is Gil Grissom.
We're with the Crime Lab.
Do any of you know if
Wendy Garner worked last night?
No, she had the day off.
But she should be
working tonight.
And she is late.
That's not like her.
Why, did something
happen to Wendy?
Unfortunately,
she was found dead last night.
It was all those hormones
she was taking, wasn't it?
Shut up. What do you know?
GRISSOM:
Do you know
that Wendy was a, uh...?
Trannie?
All the best
showgirls are.
Yeah, and it don't matter
if they're packin'
a lop job or a gaff.
Okay, lop job I get.
What's a gaff?
It's like a jockstrap,
only it hides
what it's supposed to strap.
We all get work done.
Who cares
if it's up north or down south?
Pretty's pretty.
So do you know where
she got her work done?
You want the best,
you go to Dr. Mercer.
WOMAN:
Okay, so on tonight's agenda,
we're going to be talking
about hair removal,
gait, and we'll
do our pride walk,
hormones, and voice pitch...
Ladies, come on.
Over here.
Now, regarding hair removal...
Are they all women?
The ratio of MTFs
to FTMs is four to one.
Males to females rather
than females to males?
Bev is one
of my patients.
Right. Now, who hasn't done
their pride walk?
The law requires
re-gender candidates
to spend one year on hormones
and one living
as the sex of preference.
Wendy wanted to fast-track
the process
and I wouldn't do that.
I guess she found
somebody who would.
Every field has
its bottom feeders.
Surgery is the easy part.
Life afterwards
is the challenge.
Some candidates
get depressed.
They're unhappy about their
lives and they think surgery
is going to chase away
all their emotional problems.
Dr. Mercer,
Wendy didn't commit suicide.
She was killed.
Oh, God.
I am so sorry.
As ready as
my patients
are for the world,
I guess the world
isn't always ready for them.
Hey.
Anything on those pads
I collected?
Uh, yeah,
traces of EDTA.
Isn't that an
anticoagulant?
Yeah. Used in
blood-collection vials.
So it wasn't
the victim's blood?
No, it was hers.
His?
Hers.
But no epithelials
or fibrinogen,
so clearly
it wasn't menstrual.
So Wendy was having
blood drawn
and putting it
on pads?
She was faking
her period.
What I don't get
is why she would do that.
Well, she was living
as a woman,
and that's
part of it.
I-I don't know.
But you don't draw
your own blood.
I mean, she had
to have help.
Maybe the same doctor
that was keeping
her medicine cabinet filled.
Hey, these are
the pills
Eric collected
from Wendy Garner's
bathroom.
For the record,
I really like having a penis.
Okay,
the reds and blues
are bootleg estrogen conjugates
out of Mexico.
Apparently, HMO's don't consider
being differently sexed
a life-threatening condition.
So patients resort
to Mexican pharmacies.
Premarin's green,
a heavy-duty hormonal
supplement.
Name's short
for "Pregnant Mare Urine."
Talk about
your PETA nightmare.
What about these other pills?
Mexican-grade painkillers,
tranquilizers,
and a broad-spectrum antibiotic.
Sounds like
a post-surgery
cocktail to me.
( phone rings )
Grissom.
Yes.
Mimosa?
Yes. Today?
The Apple Martini, 1:00.
I'll be here.
Did you just get
a lunch date?
Hello.
I'm glad you
agreed to meet me.
Can I buy you
a drink?
Thanks, but I'm still
on the clock.
But you still let me
lure you away from the lab.
Is that because
I'm a beautiful woman?
Well,
I'm a beautiful woman now.
Beauty is a societal
construction.
So is gender.
People find out you're MTF,
and they think you're psycho;
Michael Caine
with a bad wig
and a pair of sunglasses
stabbing Angie Dickinson
in Dressed To Kill.
( chuckles )
De Palma had some issues.
You're an outsider.
That's why I trusted you.
You get it.
Don't worry, Mr. Grissom.
This isn't about sex.
It's about soul.
What was it you that you wanted
to trust me with?
I loved Wendy.
I was there with her
through her whole transition.
I was going to be
her maid of honor.
Do you know how hard
it is for people like us
to find love?
Do you know
what happened?
She called me,
hysterical.
Uh, I don't know.
She kept going on
about a videotape or something.
What kind of tape,
do you know?
Blackmail?
Pornography?
Porn? ( laughs )
Oh, my God.
Wendy was such a prude,
she'd cover the mirror
when she got out
of the shower.
People confuse
your obsession
with sexuality
as an obsession with sex.
Imagine being three years old,
tormented by the sensation
that you had the wrong parts.
Your body's like
a foreign country
and you're stuck
without a passport.
All because in
your first trimester
your "X" and "Y"
chromosomes split off
and went different directions;
girl brain, boy body.
It's like
the Guiterman poem:
"Amoebas at the start
were not complex.
But then they tore
themselves apart
and started sex."
Well, in the beginning,
Wendy's chromosomes might have
been tearing themselves apart,
but in the end,
she was tearing herself apart.
Do you know why?
I don't know.
Planning a wedding,
working a rookie vagina,
and about to lose her cherry
to a man who doesn't know?
So she talked to you?
She talked about it in group.
May I ask the name
of your therapist?
Dr. Lavalle.
Hey, I've been looking for you.
You found me.
I analyzed the blood
on the shoes you gave me.
I expected it to be
Wendy's blood.
It's not hers
and it's not Officer Mann's.
So it might be
the killer's.
Well, given the nature
of this case,
it might be misleading,
but I'll ask anyway--
male or female?
One donor. All male.
Lepidro.
What kind of name
is that?
It's from Lepidoptera,
meaning "butterfly."
Walter Clancy
started out
a gender-dysmorphic
caterpillar
and turned into
a bloody butterfly.
Bye-bye, scrumptious pumpkin.
Bye, Amber.
Dr. Lavalle?
No, I'm Francis.
My wife is the doc.
AMBER:
Grownups always
do that.
It's gender-stereotyping,
honey.
Okay, Francis. I'm Jim
Brass, Las Vegas Police.
This is Gil Grissom
from the Crime Lab.
Well, if I'm being,
intrusive, please tell me,
but, I mean,
why are you here?
Wendy Garner.
I know Wendy.
She's a patient.
She was a patient.
My wife is in group.
MAN:
This is really frustrating.
They don't get it.
She is a beautiful woman now
and I love her.
Our pastor doesn't know.
You need to tell him.
The truth goes a long way.
Mona?
These folks need
to speak to you.
Eddie, would you take over?
Sure.
In the Sanctuary Alliance
I saw an Eritrean girl
who had her labia
sewn shut.
I looked into her eyes
and I found a cause.
6,000 women a day
suffer genital mutilation.
So you travel
around the world
treating the victims
of sexual treachery?
You don't have
to travel
to find the genitally
disenfranchised.
Like Wendy Garner?
Wendy came to me.
She was denied surgery.
That's devastating.
I tried to help her
work through that.
By finding a doctor
who would operate on her?
By working with her
on what made her
an unacceptable candidate.
Which was?
Patience.
When was the last time
you saw her?
Last night.
7:00 to 8:00 for her individual
consultation.
How did she seem?
She was agitated.
She was worried
about whether her fiancee
would receive her well
on their wedding night.
So he didn't know?
I don't recommend
what we call "passing."
I suggested that Aaron
come at a group.
Wendy was adamant
that he never know the truth.
Doctor, do you videotape
your sessions?
No, never.
That would violate
the doctor-patient privilege.
STOKES:
Wendy lived here
at 118 Sunshine Road
in Green Valley.
She left
her weekly session
with Dr. Lavalle
at 8:00 p.m. here.
Now, Officer Mann
pulled her over
on Industrial Road
24 minutes later.
She was found dead
two miles south
of there,
supposedly on her way
to her friend
Mimosa's house here.
Takes ten minutes
to drive from
the clinic
to Industrial Road.
Yeah.
I had Greg run it.
( chuckles and
mutters softly )
14 minutes of Wendy's time
unaccounted for.
That's what
I'm saying.
She must've stopped
somewhere between the clinic
and where Officer Mann
clocked her doing 90.
Somewhere in this
highlighted area.
Yeah, but there's
nothing out there.
Not so fast.
Sara found this
in the medicine cabinet.
It's a Post-It.
"G-105, Section E."
What does that have to do
with her medicine cabinet?
Doesn't have anything to do
with the medicine cabinet.
I thought it was
map coordinates
or something like that,
but it's not.
You know what they
have a lot of
up in this area?
Storage facilities.
What's the number again?
G-105.
Should be right
down here.
Hey, hey, watch your step.
Watch your step.
I got footprints.
Those look like
bloody footprints.
Yeah.
Nick, hit the lights.
Oh, no.
STOKES:
Catherine.
Yeah?
What do you think went on here?
Someone outsourced
their health care
to the wrong provider.
At least...
something was sterile.
Maybe why I'm not getting
any prints.
Hey.
Hi, Jim.
So I, uh...
I talked to the manager.
All he said was,
the renter paid cash,
he was a guy, he seemed normal.
Normal people don't torture
people in storage bins.
( horn honks in distance )
ROBBINS:
Piano wires.
They're used to mobilize
the lower part
of the abdominal skin
and anchor the neo-vagina,
so it can heal in place.
WILLOWS:
I can only imagine
those cramps.
The surgeon stuffs
the portal
with a cylinder
wrapped in gauze
to hold its shape
while it heals, and sutures it.
( sighs ):
And how long does milady
have to wear a wire?
Well, after five days,
the vagina is un-sutured,
and the wires are removed.
Scarring indicates
multiple surgeries.
She appears to have
gone in for repair
due to infection.
I take it that
wasn't supposed to happen.
Maybe someone wasn't
taking their hormones.
Or they were taking
some bad Mexican bootlegs.
Now,
that is more than
a five o'clock shadow.
It's a myth that hair
grows after death.
What happens is,
the skin contracts,
revealing whiskers.
Contraction of the erector
pilae muscles, combined with
fixed lividity,
indicates time of death
was at least two days ago.
So she died before Wendy.
Yeah, sad as this is,
it presents as accidental.
Loss of blood due
to hemorrhaging.
Pelvic artery was severed.
My theory: surgery one,
they botched.
Round two, they
repaired her to death.
♪ ♪
( beeping )
Hi.
Do you know a Vern
Saldusky, aka
Tawny, peaches,
Vava?
One second, honey.
Okay.
You want to talk
to Mercedes.
She's in the back.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Thanks.
STOKES:
I've never seen junkies shoot up
in the face before.
It's not smack,
it's silicone.
Gives you
good cheek bones.
The ones who can't
buy silicone...
shoot motor oil.
Do they?
Calm down, pretty boy.
We're not the monsters.
The real freaks are
the suit-and-ties
want to take a walk
on the wild side--
before sneaking back
to the wife and kids.
Want to go?
Mm-mm.
Mercedes, I presume?
We're with
the Las Vegas Crime Lab,
and we're looking for somebody.
Isn't this where
you say my P.O.
would be interested
to know that I'm hustling,
and you ask for a freebie?
I'm actually not interested
in your ass,
but the person
we're looking for
is a human butcher who might be.
I'm listening.
The game is helping transgenders
who have been turned down
for surgery.
You want Benway.
Benway did my transition,
but something went wrong.
And now I can't be
a man or a woman.
Want to see?
No. No, that's all right.
No, it's not
all right.
He keeps canceling
my corrective surgery.
That may be why
you're still alive.
A friend of mine
had to go back four times.
Finally, he fitted her
with a colostomy bag.
Benway felt so bad,
he hooked it up for free.
Where can we find
this humanitarian?
Bulgaria,
Romania, Bosnia--
one of the "ias", I don't know.
He flies in and flies out.
No one's ever seen him.
He shows up
as you go under,
and splits before you come to.
Do you know Vern Saldusky?
You mean Tawny?
Yeah, Benway just did her.
Jacqui got an AFIS hit
off the bloody fingerprint
from the toothpaste tube
found in Vern's vagina.
Wow.
Came back
a Dr. Karl Benway,
military service.
Well, we found out that
this creepy looking thing is
an abdominal retractor,
used to keep
the cavity open during surgery.
It's only sold in
surgical supply stores.
And other than
hospitals,
the only individual
who's purchased one
in the last year and a half
in Las Vegas, Nevada,
is Dr. Karl Benway.
We know the name
of the butcher.
WILLOWS/BROWN/SIDLE:
Benway.
Okay.
What do you
know about him,
and do we have an address?
Total dead end-- he's not
registered with the AMA;
he's not in the DMV database;
he has no passport issued
in the state of Nevada.
So we've got a non-doctor
who served in the military
who doesn't drive
and never leaves the country.
SANDERS:
Sara, you asked for some...
research.
Microfiche. Medical journals.
The stacks.
There's not a lot
on this guy,
but this is what
I've been able to find.
Vietnam vet-- served as a medic.
Then it looks like
he did a short stint
with the Sanctuary Alliance
in Ghana.
He goes from Ghana to Mexico,
where he's arrested
and deported for performing
illegal abortions.
SIDLE:
Was his medical license revoked?
SANDERS:
No.
Benway never went
to medical school.
In 1983, he was arrested
for protesting
outside the Supreme Court.
1987, San Francisco Chronicle
article.
He was interviewed
at an anti-nuke rally.
And photographed.
Know what?
I believe Dr. Lavalle...
...is Dr. Benway.
Boy, you must get
pretty jet-lagged
flying back and forth
to Bulgaria.
Or is it Romania... Karl?
I haven't been Karl Benway
for a very long time.
BRASS:
Yeah, like three days ago,
when you killed
Vern Saldusky at the E-Z Access
storage unit?
That's a hell of a place
for an operating room.
I mean, why not go all the way
and use the men's room
at the bus station?
We found your fingerprint there.
I never said I wasn't there.
I attended Vern's surgery.
He was... terrified.
I tried to calm him.
BRASS:
Can't get any calmer
than dead.
I'm a counselor.
( sighs ):
Is that how
your fingerprint
ended up on
a three-day-old vagina?
Counseling?
I've devoted my life
to helping those who are
cast out by gender prejudice.
Where would these souls be
without me?
Who will stand in judgment?
As to who's a candidate
and who's not.
Dr. Mercer?
I was the only one
willing to help them.
I was 19 in the rice
paddies of Vietnam...
sewing legs back on grunts.
I performed abortions
in Mexico...
on rape victims when the church
turned its back on them.
I have been doing gender
reassignment surgery
for ten years.
You've been performing surgeries
without a medical degree...
Doctor.
How many Verns have there been?
How many Wendys?
Vern was an
unfortunate tragedy.
I have no idea
what happened to Wendy.
She saw you with Vern.
So you killed her,
so she wouldn't expose you.
That's impossible.
After I saw Wendy
at the clinic,
I went straight
to my daughter's soccer game.
I have nothing more to say.
We need you to say "ahh."
So, I heard Brass
arrested Dr. Lavalle,
who is really
Dr. Benway?
Mm-hmm.
Which means her
DNA is male.
Right.
In one of the latex gloves
at the storage facility,
I found female DNA.
Well, Vern was a male,
and Dr. Lavalle was a male.
So the doctor had help.
MAN:
This is ridic...
What you have
done to my wife
is disgraceful!
You're not gonna find
anything here!
Officer, could you
escort this man outside.
This is
discrimination.
We are normal people,
trying to live a normal life.
I think we have
a spitter, my friend.
Really?
Yeah.
BROWN:
I'll check the back.
All right.
FRANCIS:
Take her home!
Would you... just
get her out of here!
Can I take care of
my daughter, please?
AMBER:
Francis,
what is going on?
Daddy, what's
going on?
It's okay, honey.
Amber's gonna take you home.
I want to go with you.
Where's Mommy?
I know.
Mommy's gonna be right back.
AMBER:
I can't take her.
I have the night shift
at the hospital. Fr...
She shouldn't be
seeing this.
She's your kid, too.
Take some
responsibility.
Okay, fine.
Good.
AMBER:
Put your belt on.
Come on, can you pull it?
( car engine starts )
I don't understand why I'm here.
STOKES:
Well, you're here
because I compared
your DNA from
this cigarette butt
to sweat recovered
from the inside
of a latex glove
at the crime scene.
( beeping )
Busted artery!
( steady beep tone )
Ms. Hamshaw...
Dr. Lavalle was performing
illegal surgeries,
and you were assisting.
Now, why would you be involved
with something like that?
Mona and Francis helped me
clean up.
They gave me money to be
a surrogate mom for Tippi
and got me my RN degree.
They're family.
So Tippi has two dads
and one mom?
Actually,
it's two moms and a dad.
Okay, tell me
about Wendy Garner.
Her procedure was
completely successful.
Well, right up
till her death.
I had nothing to do with that.
I was at Tippi's soccer game
with Mona.
WOMAN 1:
Okay, now what's next?
WOMAN 2:
I don't know.
We've got Belle.
Belle.
That's so sweet...
( groaning )
God, what is this?
How could you do this?
I just wanted you to keep
my secret from Aaron, not this.
I trusted you.
How could you just
leave her like this?
I mean, this day means
so much to me.
And to have
girlfriends like you,
it's just amazing.
30 seconds
of mutilation
recorded over a bridal shower.
She told her best friend
and Officer Mann
that she had some videos
to show.
I think she must have been
trying to expose Lavalle.
( phone ringing )
Brown.
Really?
Thanks.
That was Brass.
Ten soccer moms confirm they saw
Dr. Lavalle and Amber Hamshaw
at the soccer game
the night Wendy was killed.
Another dead end.
Those fingerprints on the
videotape you recovered?
We got a match.
WILLOWS:
Wendy's videotape...
your fingerprint.
Doctor, help me
understand something.
Wendy videotaped
the storage area,
threatening to expose your
wife's "good work"
because your wife
was threatening
to tell Wendy's
fiancee that
she's not what
she appears to be.
But the three of you were
still getting it on.
I beg your pardon?
Based on
the DNA that we found
in Wendy's cheek,
you were swapping spit with her,
and your wife was swapping
something else
with her.
Now we know
that post-ops
can't ejaculate.
So the only way I can explain
the semen in Wendy's mouth
is your wife is still packing.
Yes, and I performed fellatio
on my wife...
after lunch.
Is that a crime?
I have no idea how anything
got into Wendy's mouth.
My wife and I did not cheat.
You don't get it, do you?
Because we're different.
We still love.
We still honor.
Is that why you hacked out
Wendy's Adam's apple?
Love and honor?
You went back
to the storage area
to get rid of Vern's body.
You saw Wendy leaving.
WENDY:
Mimosa, look, it's me.
I need your help, okay?
I have these videos
and I have to show you them.
You're never going to believe
what's on them.
These people...
( tires squealing
and horns honking )
( yelling )
How dare you?!
( both talking at once )
( screaming )
I tried to protect
my wife's work.
Not just for us.
For all the people like us.
So the man admits to murder
but not infidelity.
Well, maybe he
wasn't unfaithful.
You know, I read
a paper in the JFS
documenting a case where
a woman kissed a man,
who had smoked
a cigarette.
When they tested
the cigarette butt,
they found both
their DNA on it.
So you're saying
it was transfer?
Well, if Francis gave
his wife fellatio
shortly before he killed Wendy,
it's possible that some
of the semen
was still in his mouth,
and it got transferred
onto her through his spit.
Right.
Don't you think?
I thought you'd want to know
what happened to Wendy.
I appreciate
your telling me.
Killed by someone in
our own community.
As if we don't have
enough enemies.
Her parents never
understood her,
but still I think
they should know.
What do I say?
Show them an oyster.
I'm sorry?
There are two types
of male oysters,
and one of them can change
genders at will.
And before man crawled
out of the muck,
maybe he had the same option.
Maybe originally
we were supposed to be able
to switch genders,
and being born with just one
sex... is a mutation.