( siren wails in distance )
( heavy breathing
through respirator )
Get a list
of all the countries
she's visited
in the past 30 days.
Yeah, her passport.
Try the State Department.
My husband, please.
Yeah.
I have to tell my husband!
Oh, please call my husband!
Ma'am, I'm sorry,
but you can't go up.
Catherine Willows,
Crime Lab.
I know who you are,
but hotel rooms
are under quarantine.
No one goes up,
no one goes down.
Quarantine?
Okay, David.
False alarm.
We're clear.
VARTANN:
Hey.
Hi.
Someone want to fill me in here?
David assessed a potentially
infectious agent,
and per protocol,
he remained at the site
and called it in.
Her red blotches
are consistent
with CDC photos of Ebola.
ROBBINS:
You did the right thing.
So what are we looking at?
Um, 419,
suspicious circs.
Honestly,
I have no idea.
Okay, it's my turn now.
Clear the scene.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
Sorry I'm late.
I was processing
the scene.
Nothing probative.
There are 42
distinct laser burns
on Julie Stern's body.
Lasers?
Lasers cauterize
the skin
as they destroy tissue.
Lack of blood and scabbing
confirms their use,
so best guess would be
she recently underwent
a cosmetic procedure.
( zapping )
That's consistent with the
hotel manager's statement.
Said the vic had booked
into the Safari Suite.
Please tell me
that has nothing to do
with hunting wild game.
Women who... don't want
their friends to know
that they're freshening up
will check into the suite
while they heal.
Well, five-star hotel's got to
be cheaper than a hospital stay.
So, could complications
from this procedure
have resulted in her death?
No.
Histamine levels are normal.
There's no post-op infection.
But look at her fingernails.
WILLOWS:
Mees lines;
indicative of heavy metal
poisoning.
I sent blood and hair
samples to Tox.
Anything else?
I'm not sure if it's probative,
but I found ten cc's of urine
in her stomach.
Digestive system's
intact.
There are
no bruises or abrasions
in her mouth,
so there's only one way
it could have gotten there.
Chugalug.
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
So two days ago
the residence was tented
for termites.
This morning,
the bug guys came
to clear the house.
They found the homeowner
exterminated.
He's ID'd
as Elliot Beckman,
42, lived alone.
Body's in the family room.
Who's been inside?
Just the exterminators
and the paramedics who
pronounced.
They entered and exited
through the front door.
Good luck.
Exterminators use
sulfuryl flouride.
It kills the bugs
and then evaporates.
Agro scientists call it
the "safety" fumigant.
You know, I'm sure
he would disagree.
( crunches )
Eyeglasses on the floor.
Got vomit?
( gas hissing )
( gagging )
What flies when they're on
and floats when they're off?
Feathers.
Long and blue.
I'll bag 'em.
His cheek is bruised.
What was he doing in here?
Per the R&amp;R's,
we conducted
a thorough walk-through
before releasing the gas.
No plants, people
or animals were left behind.
All right, so you released
the gas, then what?
I took off.
Can't stick around
baby-sitting houses, you know?
Once you left the house,
could Beckman have snuck back in
in any way?
Yeah, if he had
a death wish.
The house is toxic
for the first 12 hours.
Mm-hmm. Not to mention
it gets wrapped up tighter
than a Christmas present.
You know tented houses--
they're prime targets
for burglars.
We secure these on the outside
of every doorknob.
Clamshell locks.
Nobody gets inside.
Yeah, says you.
Yes, Ms. Stern
was in my care.
And when was the last time
you saw her, Dr. Malaga?
Uh, I ablated her liver spots
three days ago.
Checked on her yesterday
at The Mediterranean.
I applied post-op ointment
to prevent scabbing
and infection.
She seemed, uh...
in good spirits.
From the marks,
it looks like you lasered
over 40 spots.
In one session?
Well, post op,
the patient's skin
is very red and raw.
It's really quite ugly,
to be blunt.
Most patients prefer
to minimize
the amount of time
they spend in recovery.
So you supersized the procedure.
You did it all in one sitting?
It's perfectly safe.
We'll need a copy
of her medical records.
Okay?
Oh, I'm sorry, but her file
contains medical history
which includes information
about other members
of the family.
I would be breaching
doctor-patient confidentiality
if I let you have that.
Hey, uh,
do you have a problem
with me, Doctor?
Excuse me?
Well, there are two of us here
and you're only addressing
my colleague, so...
Well, she's
a very beautiful woman.
You have
Venus de Milo aesthetics.
We'll be getting
a court order
for Ms. Stern's records.
I'd appreciate that.
Sara.
Looks like someone
tampered with the tent.
Window's open.
Well, exterminators leave
some windows open
to help circulate the gas.
This could have been
the victim's way in.
Once inside,
he was overcome by the fumes.
( gas hissing )
( gagging )
He must be an idiot
to go inside
a tented house.
Maybe he forgot something.
Figured the gas
had dissipated.
Well, assuming you're right,
and he went in and never left,
shouldn't the window
be open wider?
It's old.
The rope has snapped.
Okay.
Now, Mr. Beckman
never came out of the house.
Why is there a trail of sand
leading away from it
and straight
to the neighbor's house?
That's a good
question.
( knocking )
( man coughing )
Can I help you?
Yeah, we're
with the crime lab.
We're investigating
the death of your neighbor
next door.
Elliot?
What happened?
That's what we're trying
to figure out.
( coughing )
Have you been in his house
recently?
Look, man, I've been laid up
for the past two days
puking my guts out.
I haven't left my place.
Do you live alone, Mr...?
Rory Kendell.
My wife bailed
a few months ago.
Rory, have you felt
dizzy or disoriented?
How would you know?
We're going to need
a urine sample.
Why?
You may be suffering
from sulfuryl flouride
gas poisoning.
Urination's the only way
for the poison to get out.
I got the flu.
If that's true,
then your urine
will be sulfuryl-flouride free.
But if you're lying,
"you're in" big trouble.
What do Ozzy Osbourne,
Iron Maiden and our victim
all have in common?
Heavy metal.
Arsenic in her system,
poisoning was chronic.
Looks like it began
approximately
three months ago.
Techs collected the ingestibles
found at her home.
None were contaminated.
Can Tox confirm that
arsenic poisoning
was the cause of death?
Not yet.
Until the quants come back,
we won't know if
the concentration was lethal.
In poisoning cases, the
killer's usually a relative.
Right.
Someone with access
to the victim.
Next-of-kin is
an only child, a son.
Who has a vineyard in Pahrump.
You sent a cop all the way
to Pahrump to bring me in.
What couldn't we
discuss on the phone?
When's the last time
you saw your mother?
It was about
three months ago.
She came to my vineyard
for a visit.
How'd that go?
She left early.
Said she felt sick.
But you didn't think so.
Mom was uncomfortable
around my four-year-old.
Why's that?
He made her feel old.
"Grandma"
was a dirty word.
She could hardly
look at him.
Nice, huh?
Mr. Stern, I also did
a background check
and you recently maxed out
three credit cards.
My vines contracted black rot
last spring.
It's an expensive
problem.
Why are you checking my credit?
You're weren't worried about
paying off your debt, were you?
What the hell are you implying?
You're about to come
into some money.
When my dad died, he left
my mother boatloads of cash.
On her last visit,
I asked her for a loan.
Let me guess--
she turned you down.
She'd spend thousands
on designer clothes,
jewelry, plastic surgery...
but wouldn't lend me a dime.
Do you use pesticides
on your grapevines?
Yeah. Organic's a fad.
We're going to need
a sample of that.
Whatever.
We done?
This one's easy--
he drowned.
What?
The termite fumigant
entered his bronchioles
causing his lungs
to fill with fluid.
COD is pulmonary edema
and respiratory arrest.
Just like
a drowning victim.
Doc, tell me about
the bruise on his cheek.
Zygoma's fractured.
Check the X-ray.
Given the force needed
to cause this type of damage,
the injury's more consistent
with inflicted
blunt force trauma
than a simple fall,
if that's what you're asking.
Arsenic is the active ingredient
in the vineyard pesticide,
but you're ruling it out
as the source of the poisoning?
The pesticide is
a copper-arsenate mix.
It's chemically different
than the arsenic
ingested by Ms. Stern.
And, FYI, that pesticide
was outlawed by
the EPA years ago.
This guy is
poisoning the soil.
So he's not a killer,
he's a polluter.
He should still be arrested,
if you ask me.
People are saying that
you found urine
in the vic's stomach.
Not sure if it's
hinky or kinky.
When I used to play ball
for the Stars,
we would pee on our palms
during spring training
to toughen them up,
you know.
Remind me never
to shake your hand.
I'll put on a glove first.
That's always a good idea.
Just came from Tox.
Rory Kendell's urine
analysis is still pending.
I know we're not
supposed to get
ahead of the evidence here,
but if he's not guilty...
I lifted several prints
off the clamps
you found by the open window.
I AFIS-matched them
to a neighbor.
The guy's on file
for a D&amp;D in '82.
It's Rory, right.
No. Zach Alfano.
Who?
He's the neighbor
on the other side.
I called his house.
His daughter said
he was picked up
in an ambulance two days ago.
Apparently, he was vomiting,
he couldn't breathe,
he passed out.
Brass is taking a statement.
He's still in the hospital.
BRASS:
So why didn't you
contact the police?
I had... ( clears throat )
( speaking hoarsely ):
I had a tube down my throat
till a half hour ago.
All right, let me
get this straight--
so you came in from a run
and then what happened?
I heard screaming
from inside the house.
( screaming )
By the time I got to Beckman,
he'd already passed out.
I started to choke on the gas,
so I got out of there.
Ran to my neighbor's house,
Rory Kendell's, for help.
( doorbell rings )
I remember my daughter
calling 911.
Next thing I know...
I'm here.
( coughs )
The print on the doorbell
is a match to Zach,
and I found vomit
in the bushes.
Both support his account.
Sara?
We missed something.
What?
The directionality
of the floor rug.
The center of the rug
is pointing towards
the side window.
Also confirms
Zach Alfano's story.
We're back to Rory Kendell.
If he didn't leave
the house for two days,
how come he didn't
answer the door
when Zach Alfano rang the bell?
I was sick.
I figured it was some
Girl Scout selling cookies.
We got back the results
of your urine analysis.
There was sulfuryl
fluoride in your system.
You were at Elliot's house.
No.
Here's a thought--
after the exterminators left,
you met up with Elliot.
You had a fight,
you knocked him out,
and you dragged him
into the house
through the side window.
You figured the fumigation
would cover your tracks,
that we'd chalk it up
to an accident.
Why would I want
to kill Elliot?
You've had five noise complaints
against him last year.
That's hardly reason
to kill somebody.
Or is it a reason
to commit assault?
He filed charges
against you last May.
I knocked on his door,
and I asked him to turn down
that classical crap.
He refused.
I overreacted.
I apologized.
Charges were dropped.
I swear.
Save the swearing for trial.
You're under arrest.
( coughs )
DR. ROBBINS:
Renita Loakes, 38,
from Seven Hills.
New case.
Started as a routine autopsy.
She was shopping
at the Venetian,
keeled over at Lacoste.
Physically, she was
in excellent condition,
so I figured spontaneous
aortic dissection
or maybe pulmonary embolism.
Then I noticed Mees Lines.
Ah... just like
Julie Stern.
I spotted the tiny pinpricks
on her face,
so I painted her
with Toluidine Blue
to highlight the marks.
Have a look at this.
Now check out Renita's face.
An exact match.
It's an acupuncture facial
designed to reduce
the signs of aging.
For only the second time
in my career,
in the space of two days,
I found urine
in the decedent's stomach.
That's more than a coincidence.
Two women,
both fighting the toll of time,
die prematurely.
Why?
This is Renita's apartment.
Thanks.
You bet.
Dr. Robbins did say
Renita was in good shape.
"Supplement Diary."
"Daily Youth Regimen:
"Coenzyme Q-10-- 50 mg;
"Bee Pollen-- 500 mg;
"Grape Seed-- 200 mg;
"Deer Antler Drops;
"Chinese Mountain Ant Extract;
Tincture of Wild Reishi."
And that's just for breakfast.
How'd she have
room for pancakes?
Do you think these
supplements really
do any good?
Why are you asking me?
I'm just asking
a question, Catherine.
Scientifically, there's
not a whole lot of evidence.
( sighing )
More lotions
and potions.
You gonna ask me if
this stuff works, too?
No. I'm gonna process
the bathroom.
( camera shutter clicking )
Hey, Catherine.
Yeah?
You might want to come
take a look at this.
Urine in the bedpan
and in the glass.
She liked it fresh.
How's it going?
Ornithological database
just ID'd the feathers
I collected at the crime scene.
Hyacinth macaw.
So how come you and Brass didn't
involve me in the interrogation?
Greg, you still have
the solo to complete,
and, technically, you're
still a trainee, but
you're doing a great job.
Thanks.
♪ ♪
What are you doing
with potassium nitrate?
I'm making a bomb.
Two bombs actually.
And sugar.
You're making sweet bombs?
I'm making smoke bombs.
Ready?
One, two, three.
♪ ♪
Grissom.
We got smoke.
Coming from an uncapped
electrical conduit.
SIDLE:
Hey, I found it!
It's right behind the speaker.
Music traveled
through the conduit
directly into Rory's house.
No wonder he was
so pissed off.
At one time, both houses
must've been connected
to the same
electrical meter.
A single property.
How did you figure that?
We found fumigant
in Rory Kendell's urine.
But he claimed he was never
in the victim's house.
So you devised the experiment
to prove he was lying?
Exactly. He was
telling the truth.
So now what?
So you're the last one to see
Elliot Beckman alive.
So did he drive away
from his house?
Oh, we saw
him walk away.
His, uh, his car
was in the shop
or something. He was staying
down at some motel
down the street.
And that's the last
time you saw him?
Yeah.
No.
Ted is our, our gas-man,
so he stayed behind
to release the fumigants.
I headed on over
to the next job.
Saw the dude on the side
of the road,
so I-I gave him
a lift to the motel.
( chuckling ):
That bird crapped in my truck.
Can you describe the bird?
It was blue.
What motel?
Uh, Four Aces,
down there on Boulder Highway
and Water Street.
Does it ever bother you
that you make your living
killing insects?
What kind of question is that?
WILLOWS:
"If you believe in me,
you will never thirst.
"Rivers of living water
shall flow from your bellies.
John 7:38."
You getting religious on me?
Apparently, some fringe
health professionals
have used
the biblical passage
as justification
for Urine Therapy.
Drinking your own pee?
I ran an Amazon search,
I found 15 books
touting urine's
supposed health benefits,
including its magical powers
to reduce the signs of aging.
Listen to this.
It is a perversion
of medicine,
not to mention the Bible.
I don't get it.
These women-- the time,
the pain, the effort.
For what? Smoother
skin? Please.
Make a muscle, Nicky.
What?
Roll up your sleeve,
make a muscle.
( clearing throat )
Oh.
Now, how much time and
effort went into this?
I'm gonna guess five days
a week a the gym,
low carb, low fat, slow
burn, and for what, Nicky?
For what?
That's a good point,
but it's not the same thing.
No. It's nice, though.
Well, thanks, I'm not
even flexing it yet either.
Really? But it's rock hard.
( clearing throat )
Sorry, I didn't mean to
interrupt... barge in.
I... normally would've
knocked, but the door isn't...
No, no, it's all right,
Super Dave. Nice purse.
Oh, uh... paramedics
just delivered it.
Got separated
from Ms. Loakes
when she was loaded
into the ambulance.
Anything else?
Oh, no, no.
Thanks, David.
Sure.
"Dorian Spray."
"One spray twice a day
under the tongue."
Hey, check out
that second ingredient.
STOKES:
"Arsenicum."
Holistic for arsenic.
An oral spray?
"For refills,
contact Dr. Malaga."
This is a doctor's office?
According to Vartann,
Dr. Malaga bought the spa
two years ago
and incorporated
his practice.
Hi, and welcome
to the Sagebrush Spa.
Thanks. I'm Nick Stokes.
This is Catherine Willows.
We're with the Crime Lab.
We're here to see Dr. Malaga.
Is he expecting you?
Just tell him we're here.
Dr. Malaga.
Botox injections-- 500 bucks.
Restaylane injections-- 500.
Micropeel-- 300.
Whew.
That's my car payment.
STOKES:
You don't actually think
you need this stuff, do you?
It's Vegas, Nicky.
Everybody needs it.
You don't.
"Urine Therapy."
"Nature's Elixir..."
My clients swear by it.
Let's go to my office.
You sold Dorian Spray to both
Renita Loakes and Julie Stern.
Yeah. It's my
own formulation,
and I can assure you
that it's perfectly safe.
Doctor, you are aware that
arsenic is a poison, right?
So is Botox.
But 2.2 million people
had injections last year.
And Foxglove
is a deadly plant that also
doubles as a cardiac medication.
I'm familiar
with Digitalis.
Well, arsenic,
in extremely small doses,
fights premature aging
by improving skin elasticity.
Look, even if Ms. Loakes and
Ms. Stern drank a whole case
of that spray, the arsenic
content wouldn't be lethal.
Well, they teach you about
arsenic in medical school?
I did a course in holistic
medicine a couple of years ago.
Did you also take a course
in spa management?
Medical school left me
with a lot of debts
and with HMOs
cutting their fees,
my practice was barely
breaking even.
You know, th-the whole
profession is changing.
( keys tapping )
Doctors have to seek out
their patients.
The HMOs don't recognize
aging as a disease,
so I'm free to charge
whatever the market will bear.
Hang on.
You consider aging a disease?
With a 100% mortality rate.
Aging wreaks havoc
with every one
of our systems:
respiratory,
cardiovascular, nervous,
musculoskeletal and immune.
But you're not
treating the body.
You're battling crow's feet.
Righteous indignation.
That's one step
before acceptance.
Acceptance of what?
What I do.
The, uh... procedures
and products.
You've seen the ads
in all the beauty magazines.
You've studied all the
before and after photos.
It's okay,
Ms. Willows.
We'll all get older,
and nobody wants
to look their age.
I give you
what you need.
what you want.
So, what Ponce de Leon
couldn't find, you did, huh?
The fountain of youth.
Snake oil
in a fancy bottle.
Medicine is about hope.
And like any good doctor,
that's what I sell.
Medicine is about healing.
Hope is about prayer.
That should be free.
We need Ms. Sterns' and
Ms. Loakes' medical records.
And, uh, this time,
we've got a court order.
Sherlock Holmes and Dr. Watson,
I presume?
What do you need, Brass?
Well, it may be elementary,
but I have a conundrum.
I just got back
from the Four Aces.
The hotel manager said Elliot
tried to check in with his bird.
The guy turned him down
because he didn't have a cage,
so supposedly Elliot went home
to retrieve it,
but neither he
nor the bird ever returned.
Looks like we need
to find that bird.
( flies buzzing )
Greg.
Oh.
There were no flies in here
when we processed the house.
Fumigation kills
all household insects,
and it takes time for new flies
to find a portal of entry.
( sniffing )
Well, bird could've flown
up somewhere and died.
( flies buzzing )
Carcass with a fresh
colony of maggots.
( clearing throat )
The bird's not here;
it's a dead rat.
Which means the macaw
was either birdknapped
or he flew the coop.
MAN ( singsong voice ):
I love you.
I love you, I love you...
( clucks tongue )
( whistling )
I love you.
Teaching him to speak?
Although the cockatoo is
intelligent,
birds don't speak.
To speak requires
a cognitive ability
to understand,
which they don't.
They just imitate.
And Edweena is a she.
How can I help you?
I'm looking for a macaw.
Well, you came to
the right place.
Buy Buy Birdie's the only exotic
bird store in Clark County.
Has anyone tried to sell you
a macaw in the last few days?
No. Why?
Well, I'm trying to locate
a missing Blue Hyacinth.
Very rare.
In my whole career,
I've only sold one.
Do you remember
the buyer's name?
Sure. Mr. Beckman.
He's in here
all the time.
Bob likes to eat cashews
out of my pocket.
Mr. Beckman doesn't go
anywhere without Bob.
Mr. Beckman, um,
died three days ago.
We found these...
feathers in his house.
Tail feathers.
That's not good.
Why is that?
Macaws only molt
one tail feather at a time.
Get a pile like this,
someone yanked.
Real hard.
So, Dr. Malaga was telling
the truth--
both women
were poisoned.
But that's not
what killed them.
Yeah, so we can rule out
arsenic as a cause of death.
Hey, Travis?
These are the vials from
our decedents, right?
Yeah, I just finished
with them yesterday.
Why?
Well, the red blood cells
haven't separated
from the serum.
Is that relevant?
Maybe.
I mean, normally,
we'd see a yellow band of serum
on top of the crimson blood.
These vials are solid crimson.
Which means the red blood cells
have lysed.
Something caused the red blood
cells to lyse, or pop.
The hemoglobin
from inside those cells
infiltrated the serum.
If a sufficient number
of red blood cells lyse,
a person dies.
So, what caused the lysis?
We answer that question,
we solve this case.
CATHERINE:
So, the women were 30 years
apart in age.
They lived on different
sides of town.
They probably didn't know
each other.
But they both drank
their own urine
and were patients
of Dr. Malaga's.
Well, were either one
of their procedures
sufficiently invasive as
to compromise their blood?
Well, last Monday,
two days before
liver spot removal,
Ms. Stern had
a body wrap and...
hydrogen peroxide therapy.
Ms. Loakes also underwent
hydrogen peroxide therapy...
on the same day?
Here's the menu
of services
provided by the spa.
Let's see...
"Hydrogen Peroxide Therapy--
a three percent solution
"is injected directly into
a client's vein,
"bathing the red blood cells
in nourishing oxygen,
"boosting the immune system
and reversing the signs
of aging."
Question is, is it deadly?
Well, let's find out.
I'll get the hydrogen peroxide.
I'll get the blood.
Okay.
( knocking on door )
( clears throat )
Mr. Martin, we have a warrant
to search your apartment.
Please, stay with me.
Stay ahead of me.
Look, if you guys tell me
what you're looking for,
maybe I can
help you out, um...
Look, shut up and stay still.
Brass?
How many watches do you own?
Couple of sport,
couple of dress.
Why?
Mr. Martin has about 20 here.
Twenty?
I'm a collector.
This is a little small for
your wrist, don't you think?
Several rings, a necklace,
cufflinks
and a gold pen.
You know, these things all have
one thing in common--
you can kind of slip them
into your pocket.
This is engraved--
"Joan Arryington."
I wonder what the odds are
that Mrs. Arryington is a client
of Oden Pest Control.
( squawking )
Hello, Bob.
BOB:
Look what I found.
( Bob squawks )
I think we all know
what happened here.
After your buddies
left, you were
poking around
Mr. Beckman's house.
But he surprised you.
( murmuring ):
A cage! I can't believe
that manager.
What the hell are you doing?
Just getting ready
for the fume.
You were rifling
through my stuff...
No, no, no, no, man.
I was just making sure that
everything, uh, was, is secure.
I'm going to call the police.
( squawks )
( muttering ):
He can't do that.
No, he can't.
( grunts )
( squawks )
Somehow, you managed to get
the bird in the cage,
seal the tent
and release the gas.
( valve squeaks )
( gas whooshing )
( choking )
( grunting and choking )
( gas whooshing )
( moaning )
Despite his neighbor's
best efforts, he was a goner.
I'm not admitting to anything.
You don't have to, Ted.
We know why
the caged bird sings.
So, hand me the syringe
with the three percent
concentration.
Here you go.
No effect.
STOKES:
Upping the concentration
of hydrogen peroxide to...
seven percent.
Okay.
Concentration level 30%.
( popping )
( whooshing )
Lysis.
Concentration at 30%.
That's ten times the three
percent specified on the menu.
The death was in the decimal.
Dr. Malaga has
not committed a crime.
He injected a lethal
batch of hydrogen peroxide
into two of his patients.
Even if that were true,
you may have uncovered
a very tragic accident,
a very horrible mistake--
but certainly nothing criminal,
or we'd be downtown right now.
No A.D.A.'s going
to prosecute.
The procedures
were elective.
Catherine, you don't need me
to tell you
how many people die
every day as a result
of physician error.
Well, I am not talking
about other people.
I'm talking about Julie
Stern and Renita Loakes.
Yeah, both of whom
looked in the mirror...
and wanted
to turn back time.
They put their trust in you
because you're an M.D.
Your professional degree
made them feel safe.
All procedures carry a risk.
Is that what you tell yourself?
And when you
screw up again,
what happens?
His malpractice
premiums go up.
Oh.
I'll be notifying
the victims' families.
You can count on a civil suit.
Hi.
( whispers ):