BRASS:
BOLO out on the vehicle.
Missing Persons:
Lori Kyman.
Husband said she went out
with some girlfriends
earlier this evening,
and never came home.
CURTIS:
FOS.
What's an FOS?
Friend of the sheriff.
How else do you get listed
as a missing person so quickly?
Doors are locked.
No key in the ignition.
No sign of struggle
or foul play.
Flat tire.
Couple of smudges.
Okay, pop it.
So, she gets a flat.
There's no gas station around.
It's a Lexus, so
there's no On‐Star.
She must have had some kind
of emergency roadside service.
BRASS:
I ran her
cell phone log.
She made one call to
her husband at 9:30.
Said she was coming home
at 11:00; that's it.
Maybe some good Samaritan
offered her a lift.
Yeah, and evidently
didn't take her
where she wanted to go.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh‐oh‐oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
Lori hadn't
gotten out much
since Joey was born.
She needed some time away
from the baby, and from me.
Girls' night out.
We've been best friends
since high school.
Where'd you go?
The Top Floor.
That's right next
to O'Shea's.
Amy, why don't
you and I
go into
the other room?
Okay.
He's going to need
his bottle soon.
I'll take care of it.
So, Mark,
you were home
alone with the baby last night?
No. Uh, I, uh,
I manage the steakhouse
at the Tangiers.
I got home
around 9:00.
My mother‐in‐law
was taking care of Joey.
Your mother‐in‐law.
I'll need to speak with her.
Yeah, she's on her way over.
( baby cooing )
She's in love with her baby.
She wouldn't go anywhere
without him.
What about Mark?
Mark loves Lori.
He would never hurt her.
When a wife disappears,
it's protocol
to look at the husband.
( sighing )
I promised
I would never say anything.
Before the baby was born,
she suspected he was cheating.
But then Joey came,
and last night at the club,
Lori said things were great.
Did anything unusual
happen last night?
( cooing )
There was this one guy
who kept moving in on Lori.
Hi. Could I ask you a question?
It's critical.
Okay.
Am I your type?
I'm married.
Oh, yeah?
Nice try.
Ring.
I think his name is Brad.
Does Lori always go out
without a ring?
She had lost some weight.
It was being resized.
BRASS:
So, Lori calls you at 9:30
to check on the baby.
Yeah. Said she missed him.
Said she was going
to be home at 11:00.
I, uh,
passed out on the couch
waiting for her.
We stopped drinking at 10:00.
Left about an hour later.
What about the guy‐‐ Brad?
He didn't get the hint.
He seemed harmless.
Horny... but harmless.
I, uh, I woke up,
must have been about 2:00.
I called her
on her cell.
No answer.
And then I called Amy.
And then I called you guys.
So, you haven't left the house
since you got home last night?
We, uh, only have
one car right now.
My lease ran out.
Any news?
They found her car
off Boulder Highway.
Oh, my God.
This is Diane, Lori's mom.
Hi.
Diane, I want you to know
we have
every available officer
out looking for your daughter.
Thank you.
Where's Joey?
He's with Amy.
Okay.
You know, I just got
a quick couple of questions.
Can you confirm
you were here last night
when Mark came
home from work?
Yes. I was baby‐sitting.
What time was that?
Uh... I'd just
put Joey down.
A little
after 9:00.
And when did your daughter call?
About half an hour later.
We both talked to her.
BRASS:
9:30. Thanks.
That's all for now, thank you.
Excuse me.
What do I do?
I'd take care of your family,
Mark.
And if Ms. Sidle asks,
volunteer your fingerprints
and DNA.
RANGER:
I was making my 16:45 scan
when I saw the body.
I confirmed he was deceased.
Then I called you guys.
Hey.
There's no ID
on the vic.
Lividity is set.
Rigidity is still present.
Dead no more than 24 hours.
WARRICK:
Look at those
claw marks.
His carotid artery
is ripped to shreds.
He's got a high‐powered rifle.
He's obviously a hunter, huh?
Safe to say he was mauled
by a wild animal?
Yeah.
Your call came in
as "suspicious circs."
Is there something else
we should know about?
Yeah, that would be
the other body.
Follow me.
Damn.
It's a Kodiak.
It's nonnative
to the continental US.
Shot twice
in the head.
The stomach's been cut open.
WARRICK:
That's a pretty deep cut.
You think the hunter
was just trying
to defend himself?
I didn't find a blade
on the decedent.
And there's no way a person
can come this close
to a live bear.
STOKES:
Got some broken branches
over here.
Directionality
faces away from the victim
and the animal.
Looks like someone
even tore their pants.
Khakis.
Vic's wearing jeans
and a nylon vest.
I bet somebody else
was out here,
and they were running
for their life.
I had to see
with my own eyes.
You're actually
autopsying a bear.
It's called a necropsy.
And as the head ME,
it falls under my purview.
I'll write an article
for the journal.
They love this sort of stuff.
Yeah. You have a cause of death
on him?
I can confirm he was killed
by an angry bear.
As for the bear‐‐
two bullets
to the head.
The first, nonfatal,
was a straight‐on shot.
Bears' foreheads are sloped,
so the bullet
ricocheted off the skull,
leaving a copper jacket,
which peeled away
and embedded in the hide.
The, uh,
fatal bullet
entered
through the ear,
lodged in the brain.
I removed it already.
WILLOWS:
It's lead.
No copper jacket.
So, the copper jacket
had to have come
from his rifle.
But this is from
a handgun.
So, he shot one bullet
with his rifle
and another with his pistol.
Except he didn't have a pistol.
Or a knife, for that matter.
And his stomach
has been slashed open.
Yeah, and
the gallbladder removed.
Really?
Postmortem.
I can't tell you why.
Hey. I ran the
vic's prints.
Didn't get a hit.
We found this guy
25 miles from civilization.
Where'd he come from?
We know someone else
was out there.
Maybe he drove.
Check out this guy's watch.
It's pretty high‐end.
Yeah. Hunting's not exactly
a poor man's sport.
US presidents still hold up
dead ducks for photo ops.
But it just doesn't match
with the guy's clothes.
They're kind of
raggedy.
He's got
dirt stains.
I could smell the BO
from the guy's shirt from here.
Some hunters think
soap and deodorant
tip off their prey.
Truth is, body odor's
much more pungent.
So, Robbins confirmed
that our vic was
killed by the bear.
Okay. Case closed.
Uh, not quite.
I spoke with
the ranger.
There's no way
that a Kodiak bear
just wanders
into Nevada,
so whoever
smuggled him in
could be charged
with homicide.
How's that?
The bear could be considered
a lethal weapon.
Screw.
Excuse me?
Tire's valve stem
was unscrewed.
Two full turns.
A slow leaker.
Print around the fender.
Yeah, I was at the Top Floor.
I hit on a lot of girls.
You can't arrest me for that,
right?
BRASS:
Tell us
about Lori Kyman.
Yeah, I remember a Lori.
( laughs )
Said she was married.
Yeah, right.
You dress up like that
and go to a club...
( clicks tongue )
...you're looking
to get some.
I found your fingerprints
on her car's fender.
So? I walked her
back to her car.
I am a gentleman.
Is that when you messed
with her tire?
Is that what this is about?
I don't get out much.
Why would you do that?
I was hoping it would go flat
on her way back home,
and I'd come along
and fix it for her.
And then she'd
be appropriately
grateful, and what,
sleep with you?
Seemed like a good idea
at the time, yeah.
'Course I was tanked.
Okay, so Lori's tire went flat.
That's the thing:
it didn't.
I mean, I followed her
for like 20 minutes.
Way off Strip.
And, come on,
how long can you follow
someone for, right?
She never made it home.
I don't know anything
about that.
We're going to need
a sample of your DNA.
Any objections?
Excuse me.
Excuse me, Captain.
Found a dead female in Sutor.
Description matches
Lori Kyman.
Make yourself comfortable.
Guy walking his dog found her.
EXAMINER:
Liver temp's 71 degrees.
Given the ambient temperature,
her TOD's is roughly between
36 to 40 hours ago.
Bruises on the neck
suggest strangulation.
No attempt to hide the body.
Maybe the suspect
was in a hurry.
Or he just didn't
give a damn.
Are you gonna tell the family?
Yeah, how do you tell
a little boy
he'll never know his mother?
She was dumped
under a white birch.
Her hair is full of pods
and tree vegetation.
Red fibers and blue fibers
on her dress.
White powder on both palms.
A brown hair
with a follicular tag.
A person's entire identity
balled up
in a few nanograms of matter.
Assuming one's identity can be
wholly quantified by our DNA.
Well, genetically, it can.
We're completely programmed as
soon as the sperm hits the egg.
So we're defined
at a cellular level?
More or less.
No.
Identity is the totality
of our life experiences.
And our brain neurons
process
our relationship to the world
and each other.
( camera clicks )
I stand corrected.
DNA is what we are,
not who we are.
What we are never changes.
Who we are never stops changing.
Yeah. Whether we like it or not.
( camera clicks )
What's up?
Well, when I
fluoroscoped the bear,
looking for other bullets,
I noticed a microchip
between his shoulder blades.
WILLOWS:
I see.
I removed it,
called Animal Control
to borrow a magnetic reader.
Check it out.
( beeping )
I tracked it down:
Clark County Zoo.
MAN:
Are you sure the bear
came from our zoo?
Well, the microchip was
registered to you.
Take a look.
Oh, God.
It's Tippy.
What happened?
You mean you didn't
know he was missing?
We sold him to a broker
a few weeks ago.
He said he found him a home
at the Columbus Zoo.
A broker?
Animal broker.
Visitors want to see babies.
The brokers find other zoos
to purchase our
surplus adult animals.
You know, Tippy was so gentle,
he'd eat grapes
right out of my hand.
Well, we're going to need
to see some paperwork.
Yeah, I'll pull the file, but...
I remember the broker's name.
It's Ken Bovitz.
Out of Chicago.
He mailed me
his broker's license
and documentation.
The board approved the sale
last fall.
( sighs ):
They'll want to know
what went wrong.
Yeah, so do we.
SANDERS:
You giving the car a workout?
Well, you know
how you said
that the suspect admitted
to following Lori,
but when the tire
didn't go flat, he gave up?
Grissom wants me to
disprove his account.
How long has the wheel been
going round and round?
Three hours and nine minutes.
She left the club
around 11:00.
Time of death was between
midnight and 1:00 a. m.
Lori died
before the tire went flat.
WARRICK:
I think I know why someone
snagged that bear's gallbladder.
Apparently, in the southeast
Asian community,
some men believe
it enhances their virility.
It contains
some chemical called
ursodeoxycholic acid.
These gallbladders are going
for $500 a pop.
I, uh, talked to
the zoo in Columbus.
They never heard of Tippy.
Hmm. Any luck
with the broker?
The Department of Agriculture
never issued a license
for a Ken Bovitz.
Documents are fake.
I sent them to QD
for analysis.
We may have an ID
on our hunter.
Uniforms found
an abandoned Mercedes.
Plates came back
to a Mr. Ron Hollis,
who had hunting permits
that included tags
for wild goats, deer,
and bighorn sheep.
And what about Kodiaks?
That would be a no.
Mr. Hollis's wife's
on her way to PD,
so I'm gonna head over there
right now.
To be honest, I haven't seen
my husband in over a year.
STOKES:
You were separated?
He made it big
in venture capital.
Retired at 32.
That's when we started
having problems.
The officer said
Rod died while hunting.
Can I ask what happened?
He was mauled by a bear.
Ms. Hollis, I have
reason to believe
there was somebody else
out there with him.
Any idea who?
No.
In our circle of friends,
he was the only one
who owned a gun.
We used to fight
about his sport.
I showed him studies about
how the animals suffer,
how even the best hunters
don't always get center shots.
Well... I guess brutality
begets brutality.
ROBBINS:
COD is asphyxia due
to manual strangulation.
Petechiae in the eyes and mouth
and extensive bruising in
the strap muscles of the neck.
Sexual assault?
No abrasions or contusions
to the vagina.
No semen on the SART exam.
Is this a burn?
No tissue reaction
means it's post‐mortem.
If she were alive
at the time,
it'd have a red edge.
This one's bland.
Burn extends subcutaneously,
so the skin made contact
with something hotter
than 150 degrees.
Talk to me, Hodges.
Well, you kind of
inundated me with work.
I should be cranky.
But, uh, I don't get cranky.
Let's start with
the white powder you found
on your victim's bands.
It's talcum power
without the talc.
Excuse me?
Talcum powder can contain
asbestos fibers.
Who wants to put asbestos
on their baby?
So, today's baby powders
are made from cornstarch,
and are technically
talc‐free.
Did your victim have her baby
with her at the club?
No, he was at home.
So maybe the baby powder
was on her hands
when she left the house.
Well, we know she was drinking,
so she was probably peeing.
And unlike
some of the men in this lab,
whose initials are Greg Sanders,
she probably
washes her hands.
So the baby powder
shouldn't even be there.
Tell me about the fibers
we collected from her clothing.
Blue ones have a high twist rate
and are composed of nylon
and polyester olefins.
I'd say synthetic Berber.
And the red ones
are under the scope.
CURTIS:
Trilobal.
From a car.
Vic's clothing
was covered in them.
My guess, she was rolling around
in someone's trunk.
Can you be more specific?
You bet.
It's Wilton wool.
Very high‐end.
And given the unique
shade of red,
I'd say that you're looking
at the world's fastest
four‐seat coupe:
the Bentley Continental GT.
Thank you.
MAN:
Yeah, I was here last night.
CURTIS:
You park a Bentley?
Oh, man, my memory's
not so good since, um...
Well, I can't really remember.
You don't remember a Bentley?
Let me see what I got.
Yeah.
Yeah, here you go.
One Bentley.
Came in at 8:32.
Parked it in spot 19C.
Do you remember, uh,
what the driver looked like?
Male?
Female? Black? Caucasian?
Young? Old?
He have a hat on?
Sorry.
Amy.
Thanks for coming.
Of course. How can I help?
The other night at
the club, I was wondering
if you happened to notice
anyone driving a Bentley.
That would be me.
Birthday gift from my father.
Would you mind
if I took a look at it?
You want to see my car?
Why?
We found fibers from a Bentley
on Lori's clothing.
Lori was in my car all the time,
especially last week.
Mark was using hers.
The fibers we found are
from the floor or a trunk.
It's in the lot.
I'll call my father.
He'll pick me up.
Amy...
Did Lori use the ladies' room
at the club?
Yeah.
We both did.
Do you know
if she washed her hands?
Why are you asking me
all these questions?
We're pursuing a lead.
Lori was like a sister to me.
Investigate me all you want,
but when you're done,
you should take a look at Mark.
Mark. I thought you said...
I know what I said.
That was before
she turned up dead.
And I'm not saying he did it,
and Lori...
she never said anything.
It's just sometimes, um...
he can get rough.
( writing )
And you know this because...?
You were the other woman.
One of them.
I'm not proud of it.
Did Mark get rough with you?
That's why I ended it.
You started without me.
Actually, I finished
without you. Take a look.
Carpet's black.
Fibers on the vic's
clothing were red.
Obviously, we can
rule out this car.
I don't mean to pry,
but you want to talk about what
happened with you and Ecklie?
Not really.
I don't know if you
know this about me,
but I'm a good listener.
I blew up at Ecklie.
It was very unprofessional.
And very satisfying,
and now I'm moving on.
Thanks for asking.
MARK:
Joey just fell asleep,
so please, keep
your voices down.
All we need is a sample
of baby powder.
This is Berber carpet, isn't it?
Yeah, Lori thought
it'd be good for a boy's room.
I'd like to take a small sample.
What's going on?
Just collecting evidence.
You're coming after me?
Because I've cooperated.
I've let you swab
my mouth
and let you take my prints.
I love my wife.
I miss her.
DNA from Lori's
shirt came back.
It matches her husband.
That could be probative.
Or casual transfer
unrelated to the case.
I also picked up
your trace results.
Baby powder on Lori's palms
is consistent
with the baby powder we found
at the Kymans' residence.
According
to her girlfriend,
Lori washed her hands
at the club.
Which suggests that Lori came
home before she was killed.
Which contradicts
the husband's account.
I hate to state the obvious,
but maybe the husband is lying.
All right, well, let's say
she came home first.
Mark killed her, drove her out
to Sutor, and dumped the body.
One problem.
Mark doesn't have a car
and the carpet fibers
we found on Lori's clothing
are inconsistent with her Lexus.
Or, maybe Lori came home,
she and Mark had a fight.
Maybe she found out
he was fooling around again.
She takes off, drives around.
Tire eventually goes flat.
She pulls over
to the side of the road
and a stranger comes along
and abducts her.
A stranger driving a Bentley?
Hey, the rich are just
as deviant as the poor.
Hey, Dawson.
Yo.
Any progress
on those bullets?
Well, the copper jacket came
from your vic's rifle there.
A .30‐caliber Winchester,
Model 70.
What about the fatal bullet?
That came
from a .357 Magnum revolver.
A .357?
Ran the baby
through IBIS
and get this: the gun
was used in a '98 robbery.
The suspect was arrested
but released
on insufficient evidence
and the gun was returned.
You got a name for him?
Aaron Colite,
from Henderson.
BROWN:
Why don't you just stand
up by the counter, sir?
Here's your warrant
that we have here
for your .357
Magnum revolver.
We know you once used it
in a '98 robbery.
Serial number ML5684.
We don't want you to get it.
Why don't you just point
and show us where it is.
What's this about?
Where's the gun, sir?
Right under the TV.
Okay, Mr. Colite,
this gun is going into evidence.
Look, I was cleared
in that robbery years ago.
Well, someone killed
a Kodiak bear
up in the Black Mountains
the day before yesterday.
You wouldn't know anything
about that, would you?
Yeah, I did. I killed it.
Excuse me?
I killed it.
Look, I was...
I was out hunting.
MAN:
Help!
Help me!
Stop! Help!
Help me! Help!
Help!
By the time
I shot the bear,
the guy was already dead.
You mind if I have
a look around?
Yeah, I do, actually.
You just admitted
a felony of killing a bear.
Why didn't you report it?
I've been
through the wringer
with you guys once before.
I figured a guy was dead.
There was nothing
I could do about it.
I took off.
Look, I've got a hunting
license with tags.
I was out hunting deer.
Tried to save
a guy's life.
That's it.
Whoa, Mr. Colite.
I just have one
more question for you.
How long have you
been storing gallbladders
with your ice cream?
It ain't illegal
to cut up a dead animal
as long as it's already dead.
That's the law.
Could you lift
your pants leg
for me, please, sir?
For what?
Someone snagged
their pant leg
on a tree, probably
cut themselves.
I wanted to see if it was you.
Take a look.
Wasn't me.
So Robbins sent
the bear's blood to Tox.
It turns out there
were elevated levels
of Ketamine
in its system.
Barbiturates?
Yeah.
I think I know what's
going on here, Catherine.
( gunshot )
They're called canned hunts.
Going on all
over the country.
I'm sorry.
There's just
no sport in that.
It's just sick.
Well, you got that right.
Point is, you don't
have to go to Africa
to hunt wild game anymore.
If you've got the money,
Africa comes to you.
And they drug the animals?
To guarantee a kill, yeah.
But in our case,
both the hunter
and the prey ended up dead.
Something went wrong.
( knocks )
Hey.
Oh, filling out reports?
They tell me it's my job.
You doing okay?
Yeah.
Thanks.
I, uh, did a DMV search.
There are only five Bentleys
with red interior
registered in Clark County.
Two are leased.
Two are privately owned.
I ran the ROs.
Nothing suspicious.
PD is following up.
What about the fifth one?
Well, that one
is owned by a boutique
rental car agency.
I subpoenaed the rental history.
Diane Hoyt, Lori's mother,
had the car for
the last two weeks.
She returned it
the day after Lori disappeared.
Where is it now?
If you've added up every cent
I've made in my entire life,
I still wouldn't be able
to afford half this car.
Yeah, but why
would you want it?
The insurance premiums
are sky‐high.
Not to mention
theft, scratches.
It's art.
And I'd have every girl
in the neighborhood after me.
Not when they saw
your apartment.
You've been to
Greg's apartment?
Who hasn't?
Red carpet.
Same as the interior.
SIDLE:
Recently vacuumed.
We got better vacuums.
You found pods
in the victim's hair, right?
Same shape, size, color.
Too bad we can't ID
this pod and tie it
to that tree.
Who says we can't?
Plant DNA is
no different
than human DNA.
In fact, a plant genome
is larger.
I'm on it.
If we can prove the pod
came from that dump site,
you know what that means?
Lori's mother
is a viable suspect.
Why are you asking my client
about a rental car?
It may be probative
to our investigation
of her daughter's death.
I'll answer anything they want.
I backed my car
into a telephone pole.
So I put it in the shop.
I had to rent a car.
At a grand a day,
a Bentley's a
little extravagant.
I mean, I usually
rent a Taurus.
It's a fantasy car.
Ever since Amy got hers,
I've wanted one, so I splurged.
BRASS:
Was the vehicle ever
out of your possession?
You mean, did I let
anybody drive it?
That's what I mean, yeah.
Lori and Mark both did.
But I was always with them.
Ms. Hoyt, did you drive
your car to Sutor, Nevada?
No.
Where are you going with this?
On the hood of
the vehicle,
which affirmatively
matched the plant material
we found in Lori's hair.
All of which came from
the same tree in Sutor.
Okay, but my client
returned the Bentley
the day before yesterday.
It was washed
and then rented again,
so perhaps that individual
drove through Sutor
on his or her way
out of town.
Or, as you know, that "pod"
could be weeks
or months old.
We also collected a number of
errant hairs from the vehicle.
Several are
consistent
with Mark and
Lori's DNA
and also Joey's, but not yours.
Okay, I'm sorry.
You don't have a DNA sample
of my client's
for comparison purposes.
No, but we have her daughter's.
You're not Lori's
biological mother, are you?
I'm her stepmom.
That's not a secret.
I couldn't have children
of my own.
Ever since
Lori's father died
a few months ago,
she's all I had.
Look, Mark is
devastated.
I really should get back
to my grandson.
Before you go, could
we take a DNA sample?
You do not have
to do that.
Yeah, but if she
has nothing to hide,
it's no big deal.
Could you open
your mouth?
All right,
that's it.
We're finished here.
Let's go.
What are you thinking?
( sighs )
We have nothing
to arrest her on.
And we have
unexplained evidence
placing Lori back at the house
after her night out.
That's why I
like the husband.
Maybe they're
in it together.
Well, when two people
of the opposite sex conspire
to kill one
of their partners,
sex or money is
almost always involved.
Now, Lori's friend, Amy,
did say Mark was a player.
Hello, Mrs. Robinson.
I had this boyfriend
back in college,
and when he got
his first Harley,
well, let's just say
we sat face‐to‐face
and went for a ride.
A Bentley is a lot more
comfortable than a bike.
( chuckles )
Document was forged
by taking
an official license
issued by the
Department of
Agriculture
and scraping away
the top layer
of information.
Document was then photocopied,
and the bogus info was typed in.
Take a look.
WILLOWS:
Mm‐hmm.
A simple forgery,
but it doesn't get us
any closer to our suspect.
Actually, it does.
See, a couple years back,
some photocopier companies
started imbedding their machines
with serial numbers
less than a
millimeter in size
and visible only
under a blue LED light.
Of course.
I see it.
It's as good as fingerprint.
Thanks.
TRACY:
And you think
the broker's documentation
was forged here
on my copier?
We know it was.
Mr. Tracy, tell us
about canned hunts.
Uh, a wild animal is released
into a controlled area
where a hunter pays a fee
to kill it.
The promoters
guarantee a trophy,
so no kill, no pay.
They're illegal in Nevada.
Is that what happened
to my bear?
Aaron Colite worked here, right?
Yeah. Maintenance.
You fired him?
About six
months ago.
We let a lot people go.
Cutbacks.
Well, the evidence places Aaron
at the crime scene.
Wait, so you're
thinking he forged
the broker's document
and took Tippy
under false pretenses?
BROWN:
No. We spoke to
your distributor.
Your copy machine was
only installed two months ago.
We think you created
the false document.
We suspect that Aaron
figured out a way
to make a buck,
and he asked for your help.
BROWN:
So Aaron organizes
this canned hunt.
A few days ago,
you guys meet up
with Rod Hollis
up at Lake Mead.
Rod, Rod, Rod, Rod!
Right there.
You see him?
Yes!
I got him!
Yep, you got him.
Mr. Hollis
probably thought
that he had killed
the bear,
and he raced over
to claim his trophy.
( screaming )
Help! Help! Help me!
Help!
His shot only stunned the bear.
It was Aaron's shot
that killed it.
You can't prove I was there.
Would you lift up
your pants legs, please, sir?
What?
I have the judge on speed dial.
You want to save me
some time here?
HOLLIS:
Help! Help! Help me!
I got this gardening.
( laughs )
We subpoenaed
Aaron's bank records.
Rod Hollis sent Aaron
a check for $16,000.
Aaron sent you a check
for $8,000.
That's a 50‐50 split.
You're looking
at grand larceny
and obtaining property
under false pretenses.
That's about 20 years
right there.
I'm recommending to the DA
that he add another charge:
second degree murder...
...for the death of the hunter.
( sighs )
We found
your client's semen mixed
with a vaginal contribution
from Diane Hoyt
in the back
of her rental car.
You said you had nothing
to do with Lori's murder.
Would you like to revise
that statement?
No.
I met Diane, uh,
two weeks ago at Rain.
Banged the cougar
that night,
but I had no idea she
was anybody's mother.
So you haven't spoken
to her since?
Well, that's the whole point
of banging a cougar‐‐
you never got
to see 'em again.
One lie after another.
Are you questioning
my client's veracity?
These are your client's
cell phone records.
Semen in the car
was enough to get
a warrant.
On the night
that Lori
was murdered, he called Ms. Hoyt
on her cell phone
at 11:23 p. m.
No, I don't know him.
You've never seen
or spoken to this man?
No, not that I remember.
CURTIS:
Hmm.
Do you remember the men
you have sex with?
Ms. Curtis, that
is uncalled for.
SIDLE:
Here's the deal.
Lori left the club around 11:00.
By your client's own admission,
he followed her
for about 20 minutes,
waiting for the tire to go flat.
When it didn't,
you called her mother.
It was all a setup.
Brad was going to strike up
a conversation
with Lori at the club,
and on her way
home, abduct her.
And then, one or both of you
were going to kill her.
But when you got his call...
you went to Plan B.
I left Lori's house,
drove home and went to bed.
You never left.
Mark fell asleep
in the living room,
and you waited for Lori
to come home.
( gagging )
Lori's body was too
heavy for you to carry,
so you called for help...
on Mark and Lori's phone.
You got her call
at 1:17 a. m.
Coroner puts Lori's death
at some time
between 12:00 and 1:00 a. m.
Well, which means I didn't
kill her, like I told you.
Brad, be quiet.
Oh, I never thought
you did kill her,
but you did help
get rid of the body,
and that is conspiracy
after the fact.
Now, Mark would've
heard something,
and if he's
claiming he didn't,
I'd be looking at him.
The living room's
at the other end
of the house.
He was asleep.
Prove it.
I don't need to.
We found something of Lori's
on the rental
exhaust pipe:
her skin.
Your client's on record.
The vehicle was
never out of her possession.
SIDLE:
You drove back to the house,
picked up Lori's Lexus,
drove back into town.
Tire went flat
off Boulder Highway.
You can't prove that.
When we suspected
Brad's involvement,
we printed the interior
of the Lexus.
Your prints are
on the steering wheel.
Is there a deal to be made?
Why did Diane Hoyt want
Lori dead?
I don't know.
The lady paid me 2,000 bucks.
Um... said she was having
a fight with her daughter
and wanted to make good...
um, only Lori wouldn't return
her calls,
so it was my job
to get 'em together.
When she called me and asked me
for my help later that night,
she said she'd pay me
$2,000 more.
I know why she did it.
While you two were at PD,
I called the family lawyer.
He faxed over a copy
of Lori's father's trust.
Estate's worth
$50 million.
He left it all to Lori?
No, to her son.
Lori was the trustee with
a stipend of $2.5 mil a year.
If anything were to happen
to Lori,
guess who takes her place?
Her stepmom.
Yup.
( chuckles )
Listen, you guys,
I'll catch up later.
Hmm. She's fitting in
pretty well, huh?
You got a minute?
Sure.
You did a nice job
on the case.
I, uh...
( clears throat ):
I just wanted
you to know
that I've enjoyed
working with you.
Well, I've enjoyed working
with you as well.
No, it's time I made a change.
I don't like the direction
the lab's headed.
You mean Ecklie?
You can't pay any attention
to him.
No, you got a good team,
but I was a supervisor.
My demotion was undeserved,
and every day I'm here,
I'm reminded of that.
What?
Well, someone once said,
"What we are never changes,
but who we are...
never stops changing."
Let's have dinner, shall we?