( footsteps approaching )
( clicking, rattling )
( sniffing )
( man screams )
( man screaming )
MAN:
Local homeowner
called it in early.
We got it contained
pretty quick.
We were lucky.
( camera clicks )
Luckier than he was.
Low humidity, dry brush.
Perfect conditions
for maximum damage.
Firebugs listen to the weather
reports just like we do.
Only for different reasons.
Maybe some moron just threw
a cigarette out the car window.
You're an optimist.
Do you have a point of origin?
Not yet...
Fire spread down the slope.
Probably started
along top of the ridge.
I'll give you a shout
when it's safe to come up.
Okay, Mom.
This area was always
a good place for stargazing.
It's a good make-out spot, too.
So I've heard.
( camera clicking )
Sara!
We've got another
body down here.
Get the paramedics!
♪ Who... are you?
Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me
who are you, you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
WOMAN ( over P.A. ):
Dr. Forrest, dial 102, please.
Dr. Forrest...
I'm Greg Sanders
from the Crime Lab.
I'm here to collect trace
from the arson victim.
She was in the burn unit.
Bay number three.
Thanks.
I thought...
I just assumed
she was dead.
It's a miracle
she's not.
This is as bad
as it gets.
SANDERS:
How extensive are the burns?
DOCTOR:
80 percent.
Mostly third degree.
I hope the morphine's
working.
Third degree burns
are painless.
The nerves are burned away.
She's not conscious
of what's happening to her.
Not now.
SANDERS:
She's still a Jane Doe.
I'm going to need
all of her clothes,
as well as any trace
off her body.
We'll save whatever we find
during debridement.
Debridement?
We scrape off the dead flesh,
then cover it with cadaver skin.
We then wrap it with gauze.
It prevents infection
and allows the remaining
tissue to heal.
( metal snaps )
( ring clanks )
DOCTOR:
She's gonna lose those fingers.
EMT:
Continue chest compressions
and manual oxygen.
EMT 2:
Giving her Atropine
and epi via I.V.
ETA to Palm Desert--
eight minutes.
Just going
through the motions.
Kid's name is Dani
Stewart; she's five.
Neighbors saw her floating
facedown in the pool
from their second-story balcony,
called 911.
Why didn't they pull her out?
They couldn't get
in the backyard gate.
Childproof lock.
No key, no access.
Parents protected that kid
to death.
Where the hell were they?
Home.
We'll call you, Dave,
when we clear a path.
Okay.
( goofy squawking over TV )
( boinging, silly cackling
over TV )
Oh, man.
Whew.
Well...
She obviously fell forward...
As she ran down the stairs.
Lots of pictures
of the kid.
Family revolved
around the child, huh?
Yeah, way it should be.
WILLOWS:
Struggle?
She might have put her hand out
to break her fall.
Man.
What a scene.
BROWN:
What are you thinking?
Maybe murder-suicide.
I don't know.
This gun looks like
it might've been wiped clean.
WILLOWS:
You thinking professional hit?
( gunshot )
What about the little girl?
Loose end.
Mommy, why is
everybody screaming?
There are three bodies
in three locations.
A lot of variables.
Where do you want
to start?
( Sidle, Grissom panting )
I've got...
the business end
of a disposable lighter.
Could be an
ignition source.
( camera clicking )
( unzips backpack )
Hey.
What's that?
( indistinct background
radio communication )
( camera clicking )
Possible accelerant.
Or possible martini.
( camera clicks )
I didn't think
you could smell vodka.
Well, that depends on
how long it was distilled.
Cheap stuff.
Ironically, the word for vodka
comes from the Russian phrase
zhizennia voda.
"Water of life."
Hey.
Hey, Super Dave.
You have any idea when I might
be able to process the bodies?
Uh...
That'd be a question
for the boss lady.
She's upstairs to the right.
Thanks.
WILLOWS:
I've got some long hairs
on the pillow-- brunette.
Wife was a blonde.
So was the daughter, right?
Yeah.
Well, I'll collect the sheets
as soon as I'm finished up here.
PHILLIPS:
Hey, Catherine, um,
I was wondering if I...
Oh, I'm sorry,
David.
We're going need
to keep the bodies
in their original position
for a while longer.
STOKES:
Crime scene
this messy,
gotta bust out the big guns,
you know what I mean?
Hey, did you know
that Ecklie volunteered
the lab to evaluate
this scanner for Third Tech?
I'm sure he's hoping
they'll give us one for free.
I wouldn't count on it.
But I am definitely
going to enjoy
using this while it's here.
Virtual crime scene sketch.
Sure beats doing it by hand.
The whole family...
dead?
Dani, too?
She just had her birthday.
How long have you been
Morgan Stewart's assistant?
Uh...
about two years now.
Did you and Morgan ever see
each other outside of work?
Well...
I baby-sat Dani sometimes
for some extra cash.
I'm putting myself
through school.
We found a brown hair
in his bed.
Your color.
I wasn't sleeping with Morgan,
and if you knew him,
you wouldn't bother implying it.
He was devoted to his wife.
He was a...
He was a wonderful father.
Hmm.
Were you ever in his bedroom?
( scoffs ) No.
Then you wouldn't mind giving us
a sample of your hair.
No. Be glad to...
as soon as you show me
a court order.
You know how
that makes you look?
Save it.
I'm pre-law.
( beeping at varying rates )
( several long beeps,
then beeping stops )
I hear our victim
is still alive.
I don't see why.
Well, she's not ready
to let go yet.
SANDERS:
Some kind of melted card.
I found traces of alcohol
all over her clothes.
She was doused in it.
The accelerant and the
probable ignition source
were found at the
top of the hill.
That was the point of origin.
But the victim was found,
almost completely burned,
at the bottom of the hill.
I don't think she was caught
in the fire...
I think she started it.
♪ ♪
( camera shutter clicks,
quiet beeping )
( beeping )
SIDLE:
I got a work card hit
off the vodka bottle--
a Patrick Bromley.
He used to bus tables
at the Palms.
These days,
he's driving a big rig.
He's a trucker.
Let me guess:
he's on the road.
According to his
employer, yes.
Vartann is working
at bringing him in.
But, as it turns out,
the company tracks
its drivers via GPS,
and they were kind enough--
under threat of subpoena--
to give me access
to Mr. Bromley's route data
for the last 24 hours.
And what do you know.
( beep )
He was in the area
of the fire an hour
before the alarm went out?
Yes. And about a half hour
before that,
he made a stop at the
local Gas 'N' Sip.
Well, see if the store's
got video surveillance.
Done.
Footage is on its way in.
BROMLEY:
You got my dispatcher
crawling all over my ass
for the past five hours.
You know, you pull off
a route, that costs me money.
Hey... shut up.
Why don't you tell us
about your friend here.
BROMLEY:
She's not my friend.
I picked her up hitching
out on Sunset.
Did she tell you her name?
Never came up.
Where and when
did you see her last?
Dropped her off
on Blue Diamond Road.
In the middle of nowhere,
just like that?
Yeah.
She wanted out.
SIDLE:
I bet she did.
Where did you get the, uh,
scratches on your neck?
A bar fight,
couple of nights ago.
Hey, do you mind if we
look inside your truck?
If that's what's gonna
get me back on the road.
♪ ♪
SIDLE:
Mr. Bromley!
Pink is not your color.
Look, I was just trying
to help that chick out.
And then you
helped yourself.
Uh-uh. Wasn't like that.
Are you saying you
never touched her?
No way.
I mean, yeah... the girl
was ready to party.
We had a couple drinks,
and a smoke.
She was definitely
checking me out,
but I'm a happily
married man.
I just gave her a ride.
We already know what you did.
( bottle shatters )
Looks like you guys
already got your answers.
Which means I want a lawyer.
BROWN:
Bobby matched the bullets
to the gun that was found
at the scene.
He also ran a
registration check.
Let me guess:
Gun was clean.
No, it was registered
to Morgan Stewart.
So, what, we're looking
at a murder-suicide?
Guy kills his family and then
turns the gun on himself?
Well, you know
it's a possibility.
Brass pulled
his financials.
Morgan Stewart was in
debt up to his eyeballs.
He was in danger
of losing his house.
Never underestimate the
fragility of the male ego.
( wry laughter )
ROBBINS:
Bullet enters with
a marginal abrasion
on the underside of the chin.
The wound path traverses
the oral cavity, brain,
and the high scalp,
just right of the mid-line.
Bullet exited
with a stellate laceration
in the right parietal scalp.
Mrs. Stewart...
Bullet penetrates the back.
The hemorrhagic wound paths
traverse the skin,
subcutaneous tissue,
and the deep musculature on
the right side of the back.
Trajectory is
back to front,
right to left and
slightly downward.
And what about the daughter?
Cause of death
was drowning.
Any trauma to the body?
I noticed a fracture on the left
fourth costosternal junction--
with virtually
no hemorrhage--
caused by excessive pressure
on the upper
aspect of chest.
Broken rib.
Now, I know the paramedics
performed CPR...
Right, but the EMTs'
report states that she
already had the injury
when they found her
at the scene.
So maybe this all started with
the accidental death of a child.
( cracking )
WILLOWS:
Wife tells her husband,
whose mental state is
already hanging by a thread...
Eh, that works.
Except how do you
perform CPR on your child
and then toss her
back into the pool?
Did you get an I.D.
on our arson victim yet?
I ran the DNA through
CODIS and Missing Persons,
and I came up empty.
But one thing I do know
is that one of her markers
is out of the control range.
"Off-ladder" peak?
You talk the talk,
but did you know
the frequency of that
anomaly is one in every 250?
I learn something new
every day around here.
♪ ♪
GRISSOM:
Mr. Matthews...
when was the last time
you saw your wife?
MATTHEWS:
Last night,
about 6:00.
SANDERS:
She hasn't
been home since?
No.
We had a fight,
she left.
It's happened before.
Do you have
a lot of fights?
( sighs )
I don't know; what's a lot?
Look, things have been a little
rough for us lately.
Tara's been on anti-depressants
for awhile.
I own my own business,
so she's home most of the time.
What's this all about?
Where's my wife?
She's been in an accident.
I want to see her.
( monitor beeping )
I don't know
who that is, but...
that's not my wife.
That's not Tara.
Is this her ring?
Oh, my God.
( crying )
Tara.
How did this happen?
We're still investigating.
All day...
I've been waiting
for her to get home.
I was really going
to make it up to her.
How'd it go
at the hospital?
About as well as
could be expected.
Doctors had to amputate the
fingers from her right hand.
Too great a risk
for infection.
They gave them to me
to process for trace.
You've pulled a double, Greg.
You need a break.
I'll process it.
Thanks.
♪ ♪
Hey.
What's the problem?
Nothing. I'm fine.
You're not.
I feel like a wuss.
Grissom told me I should
take a break,
and I did.
Your burn victim.
How do you get an image
like that out of your mind?
You go home.
You, uh...
hug your cat,
your dog, your pillow.
You have a beer,
you watch a movie,
and then you come back tomorrow.
Is that supposed
to make me feel better?
Rumor has it you used
to be a pretty funny guy.
Don't lose that.
It's hard to look
and not touch,
isn't it?
That poor kid has been
working her tail off.
Only fair,
considering
how DNA gets most
of the glory these days.
Have something for me?
Of course.
The dark hairs you found
on Morgan Stewart's bed
were not a match
to his wife.
Pretty bold, to bring another
woman into his matrimonial bed.
Begging to get caught.
Well, so far,
you haven't told me
anything I didn't already know.
This is the broken glass
and paper
found on the floor
of the master bedroom.
Uh, looks like
a thermometer.
Yes, but what kind?
Do tell.
Notice how the gradations
are broken down
by tenths of a degree?
Yes.
And most thermometers
aren't that specific.
Correct.
It's a BBT,
a basal body temperature
thermometer,
used by women
to pinpoint
a temperature spike
that occurs...
During ovulation.
I know.
It maximizes your chance
of conception. So...
Corinne Stewart,
I guess, was trying
to have another baby.
With no clue as to
what her husband
was doing when she
was out of the house.
Or with whom.
Grissom-- hey, it's about
your arson victim.
Greg beat you to it.
I got an I.D.
Yeah, well, I got something
you don't have.
This is the standard
ladder of alleles
that I run against
every unknown DNA.
and it contains all of the
commonly encountered alleles
within the population.
As you can see, at locus D3
the alleles are 12 through 19.
Which is normal.
Right.
Now, as you can see
on the sample
on the bottom,
the locus D3 alleles
are 15 and 21.
Not normal.
The 21 allele is outside
the normal range.
An "off-ladder" peak.
Like Tara Matthews.
Right.
This is her profile.
And this...
is the DNA that was extracted
from the vaginal
contribution to the sheets
at the Stewart house.
Tara Matthews' DNA
in Morgan Stewart's bed.
We're working the same case.
There were several spots
of high density polyethylene
embedded in the fingers
of Tara Matthews' right hand.
SIDLE:
According to Hodges,
the material
is consistent
with the plastic tanks
in most disposable lighters.
We found the top of one
at the scene of the fire.
Well, heat melts plastic
and butane will explode
under pressure.
WILLOWS:
So the lighter
blew up in her hand?
Are you saying
that she...
set herself on fire?
It was attempted
suicide.
She'd been assaulted by a truck
driver shortly before her death.
She was clinically depressed.
She was having problems
in her marriage.
You know,
some Eastern cultures
believe that fire
cleanses the soul.
Well, Tara Matthews
was having sex
with Morgan Stewart.
So, if she
attempted suicide
several hours
after the Stewarts died,
she's a possible suspect.
Yeah, but just having
her DNA in the bed
doesn't prove she was
there for the murders.
SIDLE:
What about Tara's
husband Neal?
Well, according to Brass,
Neal and Morgan were good
friends since they were kids.
Neal was good
at making money,
and Morgan was good
at making debts.
Maybe Morgan
was jealous of Neal,
sleeps with Tara
out of spite,
Corinne finds out...
GRISSOM:
And three people
end up dead.
So the critical
question remains.
If Morgan shot himself,
then he's the prime suspect
in the murders,
but if he, in fact,
was murdered,
then somebody else
was in the house.
Mr. Matthews.
Detective Jim Brass,
Las Vegas Police.
How's your wife doing?
How does it look
like she's doing?
You know, I just have
a couple of questions.
Maybe we should talk outside.
We can talk here.
Okay.
You know, when the detective
interviewed you earlier,
why didn't you tell him
that your best friend
and his family
had just been killed?
I didn't know then.
Were you
at Morgan's house yesterday?
No.
How about
your wife?
Not that I know of.
Why would she?
Well, she's
been spending
a lot of time there.
What's that supposed to mean?
Your wife was having
an affair with your best friend.
Look, I feel for you,
Neal; I do.
Friends don't sleep
with their friend's wives.
You think you know how I feel?
Guilty?
Yeah.
I do feel guilty.
I was unable to give
my wife what she needed.
If she went to Morgan,
that's the reason.
She never
handled rejection well.
So, if Morgan rejected her,
how would she have taken that?
Badly.
Bad enough to kill?
Not Tara.
How's it going?
Hey.
Checking out
trajectory angles.
This is the shot
coming out of Morgan's body.
What's the
trajectory
going into the wall?
Oh, the wall trajectory
is a constant.
Morgan's is
the variable here.
Well, there's no way those lines
are gonna match up
with Morgan all the way
over on the bed.
So let's make them
line up.
Hang on. If he shot
himself there...
how did he end
up on the bed?
He was moved.
Where is the blood spatter
from the initial wound?
Wait.
Morgan's wound
bled out here.
The blood puddle
covered the initial spatter.
( gunshot )
There was someone
else in that room.
STOKES:
So maybe Neal or Tara Matthews
has blood on their clothes.
BROWN:
Time to check the house.
( knocking )
You found a basal
thermometer
at the Stewart house?
Yeah.
It was crushed on
the master bedroom floor. Why?
I found one in Tara Matthews'
vanity drawer.
I was just looking
at Corinne Stewart's
autopsy report.
Uh...
She had a tubal ligation, so...
she obviously wasn't
trying to have kids.
Tara was.
♪ ♪
WILLOWS:
So it's been confirmed.
Tara Matthews is pregnant.
Third-degree burns
on most of her body
and she doesn't miscarry?
A mother's body is designed
to protect her baby.
I don't know,
all that trauma and morphine...
it'll be a miracle
if she brings it to term.
Do we have any idea
who the father is?
Too early to tell.
She's just a few weeks pregnant.
Okay, we know that Morgan
and Tara were having sex.
The broken basal thermometer
we found in the bedroom
implies that she was trying
to conceive with him,
and not her husband.
Neal could've been
shooting blanks.
Medical records
will confirm that.
And Neal and Morgan
were best friends...
Somebody she may have
felt comfortable with.
WILLOWS:
Neal catches Morgan
in bed with his wife...
He knows where the best friend
keeps his gun.
The glass in Neal's shoe
just puts him at the scene.
We didn't find any blood
on the clothes
we recovered from his house.
Clothes are easy to dump.
The glass was an oversight,
he didn't even know
it was there.
Or maybe he didn't kill anybody.
Which leaves Tara.
There was no blood
on her clothes either.
At least nothing at the house.
And the clothes she was wearing
went up in flames.
Not everything.
♪ ♪
We got a problem, Neal.
We found chlorine
from the Stewarts' pool
on your wife's sweater.
That puts her
at the scene.
We're going to be
charging her with
the murders.
Whatever happened...
Tara couldn't have
done it on purpose.
It must've been
some sort of accident.
Well, the way we see it,
you know, Tara went back
to Morgan's house to tell him
that she was pregnant
with his child,
and...
What, she told you
the baby was yours?
Yeah.
And you
believed her?
We were trying to have a baby.
Why wouldn't I?
Oh, well, sure.
I mean, you and Morgan
are close enough in looks.
She probably would've
gotten away with it.
She always said that a woman
without a child of her own
wasn't a woman.
We tried in vitro fertilization
a half a dozen times.
Yeah, we know.
We subpoenaed
your medical records.
You had bad sperm.
Anyway...
Tara went over to try to get
Morgan to leave his family,
he said no, she flipped out,
she went nuts.
She's got a history
of depression, right?
Total terror.
I mean, I suppose
Morgan got what he deserved.
But just because you're
defective doesn't mean
that Tara's gonna jump
in bed with him.
I told Tara we could adopt.
She wouldn't.
And Corinne
and the kid...
wrong place, wrong time,
I guess.
She wanted to have a family
so bad...
And you couldn't give it to her,
so she took her business
elsewhere.
And it didn't
take long
for Morgan to
hit a home run...
Stop talking about it
like that.
Just because she's lying
burned up in a hospital room
carrying
your best friend's kid...
No!
...isn't going to cut it
with the D.A.
No, I'm...
Look, Neal,
Not another word.
she killed three people.
I want you to shut up!
Just shut up!
Neal, please.
Let's go.
Go ahead and walk.
Go ahead,
let Tara take the fall.
She's probably not
gonna make it anyway.
I love my wife.
Please, Neal.
Let's go.
We know you were there.
We got a fragment from
a basal thermometer...
You don't know
anything about her.
I know she wanted a baby
more than she wanted
to be your wife,
I know that much.
So tell me what
I don't know.
We were just hanging out,
having a couple beers
and I got a splinter.
Morgan said the tweezers
were up in his bathroom.
He said it was Corinne's idea.
They were just trying
to help us.
We did it for Tara.
You slept with my wife!
No!
Corinne! Call the police!
Mommy.
Morgan!
( gunshot )
She ran.
She was going to call the cops.
I was just trying to stop her.
You shot her.
What about Dani?
I didn't know what else to do,
so I called Tara.
When she came over,
saw what I'd done...
she just freaked out.
I made it look like
Morgan shot Corinne and then
he killed himself.
Are you out
of your mind?
Do you know
what you've done?
This is all because of you.
BRASS:
Neal...
what happened to Dani?
Dani!
She said we didn't deserve
to live, neither one of us.
And then she just ran
out the door.
I was afraid she was going
to try to kill herself.
All we wanted was a baby.