BRASS:
So, the Gang Unit
says our d.b. is
a 16-year-old Tyson Plummer.
How many holes in the victim?
I count four.
11 shell casings.
Shooter emptied the gun--
so he was moving and shooting.
Only hit the vic four times.
She talks to herself.
Hey, it works for me.
Bullets that missed hit
the outside building wall.
Bang, bang, bang, bang.
Man, Andre didn't
cap him like that.
Did too.
How you gonna tell me?
I saw him...
Hey, guys,
can I talk to you for a sec?
I just want to ask
you a few questions.
Grissom...
Go ahead, Greg.
We got a very young male d.b.
by the Dumpster.
I'll be right there.
Get your damn
hands off me!
BRASS:
Whoa, whoa.
I can't let you touch him.
What's your name?
I'm Plummer. Leo.
That's my brother right there.
They didn't have to do him
like that, dawg.
I know you know
who did this, Leo.
Ain't your problem, man.
Whoever did this
is gonna get got.
Oh, no, don't say stuff
like that.
Because only two things
can happen:
you in shackles
or you on a slab.
So, let's break the odds
this time. What do you say?
You done with me, bacon?
'Cause I got family to go bury.
( yelling )
( gunshots)
( screaming )
You okay?
Hell no, I'm not okay.
Who the hell's shooting at us?
I don't know,
but I think our single
just turned into a triple.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
( indistinct police radio
transmissions )
( camera shutter clicking )
Somebody tried to just
throw him out with the trash.
If the Dumpster wasn't full
he would've ended up
at the landfill.
He hasn't been dead long.
He's just coming out of rigor,
so I'd say less than
24 hours.
He wasn't in the box
long enough to mummify,
but the kid looks like
an ad for hunger relief.
Okay, let's, um,
transport him in situ.
Be very careful
moving the body.
You okay?
Yeah. Fine.
MAN:
Let me go, dawg!
Let me go, man!
Get off me, man!
That's Rodney King,
dawg! Let me...
Get off! Get off me!
( car door slams shut )
So, uh...
you think these
concerned citizens
are taping the capture
of a vicious killer?
GRISSOM:
If they're taping now,
maybe they caught that
second shooting on video.
Maybe you could collect
the cameras.
( chuckles )
I love this guy.
It says "forensics"
on our jacket.
I'm aware of that.
We had plenty of cops
chasing the suspect.
I wasn't chasing the suspect.
I was chasing the evidence.
I knew the idiot
was likely
to dump the gun.
All we have to do
is ballistics-match
the weapon to both victims.
Case closed.
( door buzzes )
Hey.
Hey, man.
What's up?
Suspects wait
in Central Holding
to be processed
and transferred to jail.
They assaulted the
officers with feces
and then the cops
went in.
Great.
To bust some heads.
STOKES:
Hoo...
So, you've got a Samuel Mendez
with a cracked skull
listed as death imminent, right?
Yeah. It's why they kicked it
up to Homicide.
You think the cops used
excessive force here?
Well, if they did
it's mitigating
circumstances.
Yeah.
Yeah, well, if they'd've thrown
a bunch of feces at me,
I would have cracked
some skulls too.
This is the last place
I thought I'd see a gun.
It was found under the victim.
Arresting officer
must have done a lousy search.
STOKES:
Wow...
this is a lot
of crap.
What, did they
squat on cue?
BROWN:
Overflowing toilet.
There's enough ammunition
right there.
So, the cops bust in to get
the prisoners under control
when they start throwing
raw sewage?
( yelling )
Well, there must have been some
real bad asses in here.
Look like it got pretty heated.
You want to tell me
what happened here?
Cops iced the kid.
What else you
want to know?
Could tell he was a fish
from the jump, though.
A fish?
New to the game.
( hawking )
What?
You see what happened?
The po-po gutted the fish.
I saw the whole thing.
Same thing they did to me.
Two beatings
in one day.
Rodney King, yo.
( camera shutter clicking )
I'm sorry, uh,
who are you?
I'm Catherine Willows.
I'm with the crime lab.
Oh. I'm Dr. Franks,
attending.
Have you located
his family yet?
No.
I need to
find someone
to sign a release, take
him off the ventilator.
He's brain dead?
Oh, yeah.
I'm hoping the family
will donate his organs.
Tell me about his injuries.
He's got blunt-force trauma to
the frontal and sphenoid bones.
It fragmented his skull,
damaged his temporal arteries
and imbedded in his brain.
Well, those are shoe prints
on his face,
which suggests that he was
attacked while he was down.
Well, he came from
County lock-up.
Must have been
a hell of a fight.
♪ ♪
( coughing )
The victim's about
five years old.
He was just losing
his baby teeth.
X rays show metaphyseal
fractures to the right humerus
and acromion.
They're called corner
or bucket-handle fractures.
Shake the baby?
It's more like snatch and shake.
Violent shaking
creates shearing forces
causing fragment fractures
at the end of the growth plate.
It's highly specific for abuse.
How old do you think
these fractures are?
Well, this kind of fracture
doesn't usually heal
with callus you
can easily see.
My guess, less
than six months.
He is emaciated.
He looks drawn.
The only thing missing
is a swollen belly.
It's called cachexia.
The soft tissue
is diminished
and drawn around the skull.
The eyes are sunken,
and there's prominent tenting
where the skin should retract.
SIDLE:
His ribs are poking
through his skin.
He starved to death, didn't he?
C.O.D. is renal failure
due to starvation.
His intestinal tract
was virtually empty,
except for these brown
flecks I found.
Hepatic steatosis,
the liver goes
yellow and greasy.
Ketoacidosis,
fat stores are used for energy,
and then rhabdomyolysis--
when muscle is broken
down for fuel.
Think of the body
as digesting itself.
This took weeks.
I have to admit, this seems
especially cruel and unusual.
When kids are involved,
it usually is.
It's a 10-by-18-foot cell
built for 25 people.
We've got 35 mutts and no place
to put the extras.
Between the yo's, the
cholos and the rednecks,
it was bound to happen.
35 guys, that's a lot of
men to fit in one room.
Cops round them up,
we process them.
It usually doesn't take long,
but today we got jammed.
What was the problem?
Computer went down,
plumbing backed up.
You name it, we had it.
Any rival bangers
in the same cell?
No. I rechecked the roster.
We don't want the yo's
killing each other
in custody.
Why we bother, I'll never know.
You ever think an overcrowded
cell mixed with bad plumbing
was the reason
they threw the contents?
They don't need a reason.
Bad monkeys at the zoo.
So, uh, how did the gun
get past security?
Arresting officer
did a bad search.
Don't you search them again
when they get
to the holding cell?
What?
Don't you search them
again when they get here?
Is there something you want
to get off your chest?
( wry chuckle )
A gun in a cell is
sloppy police work, man.
I don't like what you're
implying about me or my men.
Then maybe you need to
dial down your attitude.
A man is brain dead here!
I don't care what he was
like when he was alive,
and neither should you,
don't you think?
All I know, there's
one less bastard
I gotta watch my back for.
There's five of us, so the
odds are in their favor.
You're a crime scene tech.
I'm law enforcement, which means
you don't get to tell me
what to do in my jail.
If I find out you used
excessive force
on an unarmed prisoner,
you won't have a jail.
I think we're done here.
I don't think so.
Not quite. I'm going to need
your armor, your shields,
your boots and your
batons. Right now!
( footsteps thudding )
I, uh... ran
John Doe minor's DNA
against the Missing
Persons database.
I'm sorry, no hits.
Yeah, I'm
not surprised.
They didn't care
enough to feed him,
why would they
report him missing?
What's going on in here?
The victim had a prior
abuse fracture.
And you're hoping
Child Protective Services
investigated?
Well, based on the age
of the victim,
the age of the fracture
and the break pattern,
I found ten possible matches.
Well, it's going to
take you forever
to go through these alone.
I'll get it done.
It took me a long time
to get where I was, Sara.
Now I feel like I'm
starting from scratch.
I miss sleeping at night.
I miss my colleagues.
I miss...
What?
Being trusted.
What's on the menu today,
Warrick?
A gun...
face shields, vests... batons...
Please run the batons first.
Why? You thinking bad cop?
Well, the batons were the only
weapons inside of the cell.
Everything else was fixed...
( cell phone ringing )
...to the floor, to the walls.
( ringing continues )
You gonna get that?
No.
Player.
Oh, now I'm a player.
You make up your mind
pretty quick.
I'll, uh, page you
when I get the results.
Yeah?
He was a rough one last night,
so I called to check on him.
But since I'm here,
I can do it in person.
Anything else you
want to say to me?
Have a nice day.
Is that it?
That's it.
( chuckling )
Am I interrupting?
No.
Good day.
He's pretty hot.
Yeah, well, I think
he knows it.
Anything on the hairs
from the plastic coffin?
Ah, yeah,
I actually did find
one hair with a root tag
still attached,
and it's a priority run for me
as soon as I get something
to compare it to.
Sara also collected
a bunch
synthetic hairs.
I'm thinking doll,
wig, maybe fake fur.
I sent them over to Trace.
( clicking )
I went through child abuse
cases, looking for a match
to the victim's age
and fracture.
I pulled the X rays
of our most likely
candidates.
Sinus identification
is as reliable
as fingerprints.
Sinuses are unique; they have
distinct, scalloped edges.
No match.
It's harder to identify
children this way
because they, uh,
develop so quickly.
( clicking )
This is it.
Bingo.
Yep. Frontal and ethmoid
sinuses line up perfectly.
Devon Malton, age five,
last known residence
was a foster home
run by a Lorna Tenney.
LORNA:
So, which one of my kids
is in trouble?
BRASS:
No, you are, Mrs. Tenney.
Oh? Which one of my kids
lodged a complaint?
SIDLE:
That happen a lot?
Well, it goes
with the territory.
We're here about, uh,
Devon Malton.
Well, he hasn't lived here
in six months.
Since he fractured his arm?
CPS investigated.
They cleared me.
Records show Devon resides here.
Well, records are wrong.
Mind if we come in
and take a look around?
I do.
If you've got nothing to hide...
Oh, save it.
Those mind games
don't work on me.
I deal with the police
often enough to know
better than to talk to you
without my attorney
or to let you poke
around my things.
Look, Family Services
says you have this kid.
Mm-hmm.
They've issued
aid checks.
Now, who do you
expect me to believe?
The checks come,
I send them back.
I've got the copies to prove it.
Look, it's either here
or at the station.
So, you choose.
Then let's go, because you
don't set foot in my house
without a warrant.
♪ ♪
( pager beeping )
Heard you had a real
sphincter pucker last night.
So what kind of gun
are you getting?
Plenty of guns at crime scenes.
Cops have them,
some criminalists...
Yeah, cops make great targets.
Plus, CSIs get shot
at all the time,
or didn't they
tell you?
If this is why you paged me,
then I...
I got the results
on the bin contents.
Well?
Are you sure you're okay?
You don't
look so good.
I detected mineral oil,
titanium dioxide,
stearic acid,
isopropylpalpitate using
polarized lightmicroscopy,
GCMS and FTIR.
Is that makeup?
Burnt sienna foundation.
The cheap stuff.
What about the intestinal
tract contents?
Lead-based paint chips...
last used in 1978.
That whole neighborhood looks
like it was built in the '70s.
Could've come from any one
of the apartment buildings
or the houses.
Which means that
sooner or later,
you're going to have to be
going back out to the hood.
Nervous?
Hmm...
MENDEZ:
I'm sorry, Doctor.
I can't donate his organs.
DOCTOR:
I assure you your son has
no brain activity, Mr. Mendez.
He's gone.
No, no,
you don't understand.
I don't know
who that is in there,
but it's not my son.
Mr. Mendez.
I'm Catherine Willows, with
the Las Vegas Crime Lab.
Are you sure?
I've been waiting for this
phone call a long time.
My kid took a wrong
turn somewhere--
maybe it's my fault,
I don't know--
but somebody's boy is in
that bed and he's not mine.
Either he can't accept reality
or the County made
a big mistake.
Well, there's only
one way to find out.
I'll have to take his prints.
Guys.
Do your work.
Hi.
You like chemistry?
No. I'm not
smart enough.
Sure you are.
Glynnis, right?
Quantum theory.
That's compelling stuff
actually.
Look, you can
question me, fine.
You don't have to pretend
to be interested in me.
I'm sorry, that was lame.
I guess I was just trying
to put you at ease.
I know what it's like.
What?
Living with strangers.
Your fate being decided by
social workers,
advocates, judges...
You were in the system.
For a while.
I've been in foster care
for ten years.
I moved from one
home to the next.
Believe me, Mrs. Tenney
is one of the good ones.
She's not very cooperative.
She's been burned a lot.
Look, I know she
comes off as tough,
but she really cares.
Enough to tell
us the truth,
even if it hurts.
You remember a little boy
named Devon?
Yeah. Cute kid.
About five years old.
Your foster mom said that
Devon left months ago.
Is that true?
Yeah.
Why all the questions?
Did something happen?
Yeah.
( quietly ):
Is he dead?
Yeah.
I don't understand.
His mom came and picked him up.
That never happens.
You could just see how much
she loved those boys.
Glynnis...
did Devon have brothers
at the foster home?
Yeah.
Two older brothers,
Kevin and, and Raymond.
What happened to them?
The boys' mother,
Candace Malton,
served 47 of a
90-day sentence for
smashing a brick
into her abusive
boyfriend's face.
Sounds like self-defense to me.
Yeah, if she would've walked
after the first hit.
So, how many times
did she actually hit him?
Five. It takes battered women
a while to see the light,
but once they do,
there's no going back.
Okay, so the Malton boys
were placed in foster care
while Mom served
her sentence.
A single mother,
she reinstated her
parental rights
as soon as she
got out of jail.
After what happened
to her son,
she didn't want to
have anything to do
with Child Services.
Any idea where
the mother is now?
No.
I've already checked welfare,
Medicaid, HUD rolls--
she's in the wind.
( Brass sighs )
I'll put out a BOLO.
No offense, but...
why didn't you check in
to the kids' welfare
after the mom
was released from jail?
8,000 child abuse/neglect
investigations a year.
There's only so much we can do.
Look, despite her taste in men,
in my opinion,
Candace Malton
was a good mother.
One of her sons is dead,
and the other two are missing.
What's good about that?
Hey, Mia.
Have you finished
processing the batons?
Yeah, just now.
I found blood,
epithelials and hair
on all of them.
There are several DNA sources
from everyone but the victim.
Which means that a police baton
never connected with Sam Mendez.
He had to already
be down
when the cops entered
the cell.
Thanks.
Catherine Willows?
Yeah.
Lieutenant
Arthur Chan,
watch commander for
Central Holding.
We are almost finished
with our investigation,
but I can tell you that
the victim's prints
don't match the Sam Mendez
that's wanted for murder.
You telling me we
arrested the wrong guy?
It was a routine traffic stop.
The arresting officer
ran the name
and got an immediate
warrant hit.
An arrest warrant
for murder and...
two guys with the same name.
Out of the car!
What did I do?
Walk back.
Hands up.
The arresting officer
did his job; I did my job.
No one's saying
that you didn't.
Your subordinate
Warrick Brown did.
With all due respect,
Lieutenant,
that really doesn't sound
like the Warrick Brown I know.
You're a civilian,
but even you understand
chain of command.
Now, I'm giving you
an opportunity to
adjust his attitude.
Don't make me.
Heard you found a
print on the bin.
Yeah, I did.
Under the lip curve.
What?
Well, I'm not sure of the best
way to process the print.
You take digital photos?
Yeah.
Well, hand
them over.
I'll load it into
the computer,
reconstruct the image
while you finish processing.
Well, what else is there
left to do but run it
through AFIS?
You're gonna need an
actual print for court.
Are you saying
that I have to cut it out
in order to lift it?
Isn't that destroying
the evidence?
No.
You're recovering it.
As long as you document it,
you're fine.
Oh.
♪ ♪
Well, I appreciate your help.
No big deal.
I don't know if I'd be
quite as accommodating
after just being...
Well, you know.
Demoted?
Yeah.
No hit in AFIS.
I've widened the search.
I've got an FBI
database hit.
Your print belongs
to an enlisted man.
Private First Class
Philip Riley.
I hope you can tell me what
the hell's going on.
M.P.'s just dragged me
off a transport to Tikrit.
That makes me look bad.
Not that I mind.
Better here than over there,
you know what I'm saying?
Well, you're an American hero.
And I mean that, you all are.
What the hell were you doing
on D Street?
D Street?
Explain to me
why your fingerprints ended up
on a plastic bin container
in an alley off D Street.
Oh, come on!
Oh. Did I forget to mention
there was a dead kid inside?
Whoa, I thought this was about
paying for trim
inside county lines.
All I did was
take out the trash.
That's all I did.
For who?
Some chickenhead ghetto rat.
Uh... I was shipping
out, and-and I decided
to party, you know?
She was all I could afford.
Where'd you meet her?
Some dive. The Seven Sins.
What was her name?
Devine. I think.
I don't remember
if she told me her last name.
Anyway, we had some fun,
and when I was done,
she told me
to take out the trash.
End of story.
Not quite.
Where does she live?
North Vegas somewhere.
I was drunk as hell.
I want you to think real hard.
I-I swear to God, I don't know.
I really don't.
How'd you get there?
In a taxi.
And I left the same damn way.
Ah, looks good on you.
Thanks.
Have a seat.
So, what's up?
Lieutenant Chan dropped by.
Really?
I wonder what for.
To complain about you.
Wish you told me
you'd had a beef with him.
There was nothing to say.
We had words, it got heated,
then it was over.
Well...
( clears throat )
I'm the supervisor
of the swing shift.
I'm responsible
for the whole team.
It's my job to make sure
that we remain objective
and professional.
Yeah, I really don't see
what the big deal is.
I mean, I remember
talking to Grissom...
Well, I'm not Grissom.
He let a lot of things slide
that I won't.
Okay.
Is there anything else?
The evidence cleared
the extraction team.
You owe Lieutenant Chan
an apology.
Written or verbal?
From now on, anything that
happens at a crime scene,
I'm your first phone call.
Sure.
♪ ♪
Fire in the hole!
Shooting two!
( beeping )
We now know the cops
were not responsible,
so that leaves us
with 34 suspects,
all with rap sheets.
Is there anything
to narrow the focus?
Well, I compared
all 34 pairs--
I came up with
one sole pattern...
and one suspect--
Vincent Mendoza...
booked for
meth manufacture.
Well, the official
C.O.D. was
blunt force trauma
to the head, not stomping.
Well, it's not unreasonable
to think the same guy
that caused the
blunt force trauma
can also stomp him.
Well, that all
sounds good,
but why go to all that trouble?
Because the gun was hot.
Ran it though IBIS.
It was used
in an execution-style murder.
The last thing
the guy wanted to do
was to get caught with a gun
that had a body on it.
WARRICK:
Yeah, well, this
victim looks like
the perfect patsy
to drop a gun on.
STOKES:
Yeah...
little fish
in a tank full of sharks.
What's on the table,
gentlemen?
Murder, two counts.
Your client killed a man
in a holding cell
and tried to frame
the cops for it.
That's bull and you know it.
Shh.
Let's hear
the corroborating evidence,
and it'd better be good.
Mr. Mendoza was hooked
in a raid on a meth lab.
Problem was, he was carrying
a concealed weapon
and had no time
to ditch it.
BROWN:
He dropped the weapon
down his pants,
planned to get rid of it
in central holding
before the cavity search.
So far, I'm not hearing
anything you can
actually prove.
Well, I'm sure Vincent here
knew a lot of people inside
since he is
a repeat offender.
But only one man
didn't fit, huh?
Fear must've been rolling
off him in waves so strong
you could probably smell it.
What you looking at, huh?
Nothing. Nothing.
I said, what're you
looking at, mark?
Nothing.
911! 911, man!
Typical.
Knew you guys would
try to pin this on me.
I wasn't anywhere near the fish.
You sure about that?
That's what I said, isn't it?
Well, it's good to know,
since your boot prints
were found on the victim's head.
See, you didn't
want to get caught
with a gun used
in another homicide.
A meth dealer,
your partner,
was found in the desert
two weeks ago.
Any one of those guys
could've carried a gun
into the holding cell.
It's not likely, unless you
can explain how Vincent here
got his pubic hair and feces
caught in the gun's hammer.
Give us some time.
How's 25 to life sound?
♪ True respect and ghetto love ♪
♪ Now raise it up ♪
♪ 'Cause everything in life
gonna come to an end ♪
♪ Because it... ♪
$40 buys the lips,
a hundy gets you south.
Goes double for
around the world.
You got a car?
You sure about that?
Mm-hmm.
'Cause you don't look
like you got a car to me.
Take a hike, John.
I'm her next appointment.
I didn't do nothing
but sit here, Officer.
On your feet.
Can't believe you're gonna
ruin my day for this.
You don't have enough
to charge me with solicitation.
Hey! Watch it, bitch.
It's a wig, hair is consistent.
Could you open your mouth
for me, please?
Come on, you can do that
in your sleep, honey.
Open up or we'll have
to stick you with a needle.
( knocking on door )
Taking your pet for a walk?
I know how much you like
my little fetal pig,
so I'm giving him to you
as an office-warming gift.
That is so thoughtful.
Now tell me why
you really stopped by.
You checking up on me?
No.
What've you heard?
Who talked to you?
See?
You've been on the job
for a week
and you're already paranoid.
When I was your right-hand
and your left,
I always knew that
if it hit the fan,
that you'd be the
one to get dirty.
Hey, that's the job.
Yeah, that's the job.
Did you ever play politics?
I once ran for president of
the science club in junior high.
Mary Hardy beat me out
by one vote.
I'm going to guess that
you didn't vote for yourself.
I'm not any good at politics.
And it's cost me.
It's how I lost
Nick and Warrick.
Your loss was my gain.
Yeah.
And at least
they're in good hands.
We been sitting here
a long-ass time.
What can I say,
I like your company.
What'd you bring me
down here for?
I was only trying
to make a few bucks.
Yeah.
( light knocking )
DNA's a match.
Match to what?
To one of your hairs
that you left
on the body of a little boy.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
BRASS:
No?
I wonder why anyone
would leave one kid with you
much less three.
You have seven ileals in
common with the dead boy.
Although that's not enough
to say you're related,
it's certainly enough
to keep digging.
You know, I ran your wants
and warrants.
It kicked out some aliases.
I mean,
Devine's a street name.
But you're also known
as Darlene Lewis,
married briefly to a grifter.
And a.k.a. Darlene Malton.
Hey, that's the same
last name as the victim.
SIDLE:
To starve anyone
is beyond me,
but to do it to a child...
a relative, is unforgivable.
Wasn't even like that.
My half-sister Candy
left me with them bad-ass kids
and no money.
How am I supposed to feed them?
You don't look like
you've missed any meals to me.
Know what, skinny bitch,
go to hell.
I just scrape by.
If you couldn't
take care of them,
why didn't you just turn them
over to Social Services?
I promised I wouldn't.
Little D got hurt last time.
She would've killed me.
What's she going to do when
she finds out her son is dead?
I did the best I could.
Okay, where are the boys now?
Uh-uh, you're not gonna
blame this on me.
I want a lawyer.
You can have a lawyer
after you give me
the address.
But let me tell you something--
if those boys die,
I'm going to make it my business
to see you get
the death penalty.
There's no one
in the house.
Where are the kids?
I don't know,
let's check around back.
So, turns out that Mom
was sending money after all.
I found this letter inside
mailed from Seattle
with 300 bucks in it
for the kids' upkeep.
And that skanky bitch
used it to buy a new TV.
SIDLE:
Paint chips.
SANDERS:
Smells like a toilet.
Yeah, she never
let them upstairs.
Kevin, Raymond...
Oh, no.
I'm going to call an ambulance.
He's alive!
We need water and blankets.
Oh, my gosh.
Hey. Are you Kevin
or Raymond?
It's all right.
It's all right, you're safe now.
It's okay.
So, Seattle P.D. has
located Candace Malton.
They're putting her
on a plane tonight.
They said
she's pretty broken up.
She left her kids
with her hooker cousin.
She should've known better.
Where are you going
to take her first,
the hospital or the morgue?
Guess I might as well
get it over with.
I mean,
once she sees the kids
she's not going to
want to leave them.
What do you think?
Go with the living, Jim.
The dead can wait.