( engine idling )
( car door shuts )
♪ ♪
( violin playing )
Deerstalker cap...
violin...
...Meerschaum pipe...
even a Persian slipper
with tobacco stuffed
in the toe,
I imagine.
All in all, a
meticulous recreation
of 221-B
Baker Street:
residence of the world's
greatest detective,
Sherlock Holmes.
Also known as Dennis Kingsley,
delivery guy.
What do you think?
Ask Greg.
It's his case.
It's his final proficiency--
emphasis on the "final".
Okay, Dr. Watson,
run it.
( sighs ):
Victim's in a relaxed position
in front of
a fake fire.
Alcohol.
Solitude.
Powder burns around
the entrance wound.
Close to contact shot.
It all suggests suicide.
Well, if he killed himself,
where's the weapon?
( sighs ):
Huh...
Family and friends
who discover a body
sometimes remove
the weapon
to make it look
like murder.
No suicide stigma
and better chances
of collecting
any life insurance.
BRASS:
From the look
of the place upstairs,
this guy lived alone,
and the neighbors heard
the shot, so...
Pretty good. I guess I'll, uh,
go interview the neighbors.
So, are you going to say
the game's afoot?
I didn't know you were
a Conan Doyle fan, Greg.
I'm not. I saw a Sherlock Holmes
movie once by mistake.
Well, just so you know...
those movies never ended
like this.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
( chuckles ):
Yeah, boy, okay.
GRISSOM:
Anything useful?
Well, I found out
if I ever need
a home loan,
as a public servant,
I'm pre-approved.
You know, the guy looks
like a, uh, drug dealer.
Turns out he's
a mortgage broker.
Well, we all have
our costumes, Jim.
Yeah.
Yeah, apparently
some more
than others.
I assume you're
friends of Mr.
Kingsley?
We are friends of Mr. Holmes.
Invited guests,
in point of fact.
This is all
so contemporary.
Well, I'm
with the Las Vegas Crime Lab.
Ah, a colleague. Perhaps
we can be of some assistance.
Yes. Have you discovered any
shoe impressions in the soil?
Not yet.
This is a
crime scene.
Oh, a scenario created
for our own entertainment, yes?
I guess it depends
on what you find entertaining.
Anyone for pizza?
Very funny.
Got it.
Ooh. BFB.
Big freakin' bullet.
Nose is mushroomed.
Looks like pure lead.
Two cannelures
consistent with a revolver.
One, two,
three, four, five,
six lands and grooves.
Left hand twist.
Which usually means...?
Colt .45?
Are you checking up on me?
No, no, no, no.
Grissom said he was just
evaluating you on processing
this one room, so...
I figured maybe you
could use some help
with the rest
of the house.
Thanks.
Guess everyone needs a hobby.
We would study the Holmes text
in cases and important
19th century events.
We met every
Thursday night.
You make it sound
like a bowling league.
This is a serious
literary association.
As usual, Dr. Watson,
subtlety is lost upon you.
You see a stab wound
above her breast
and overlook
the absence of blood
on the chair as well as the fact
that her skirt is raised.
This body was posed,
and quite beautifully,
I might add.
Moriarty, if evil
for evil's sake were
a pathological condition,
it would be your diagnosis.
Gentlemen, your disdain
for one another distracts you
from the truth.
The wedding picture
on the wall?
The victims
were husband and wife.
As usual, Miss Adler,
your deduction is correct.
It was indeed a crime
of passion.
Sounds fun-- when was the last
time you saw Dennis Kingsley?
Last Thursday.
He said that he was
going to make
this meeting really special.
It seems
our time here tonight has ended,
and that, I fear,
is the gist of the announcement
I must share with you now.
Next week will be
the final meeting
of our society,
but I give you my
word: it shall be
an evening none of you
will ever forget.
I didn't think
that he meant this.
We're going
to need names
and contact information.
It would also
be helpful
if you'd let us take
your fingerprints.
Why?
Elementary.
So we can rule you out.
You've all
obviously been
in the study on
numerous occasions.
We need to find out if the
prints we find are relevant.
So you actually think this is
something other than suicide?
You know, I think you ought
to drop the accent.
I can't. I'm English.
Oh.
♪ ♪
There's possible signs
of forced entry
at the back door.
It could be recent.
Also, I think the vic had
a family at some point.
Brass is on it.
Check this out.
SIDLE:
The Hound of
the Baskervilles.
I read that in 10th grade.
Oh, yeah-- I
was supposed to.
There's a blood stain
on the page ends.
Huh.
The spatter goes
across and over.
That stain did not come
from this event.
It could be
the vic's,
or it could be stage blood,
for that matter.
Do you think
an obsessive
neat freak like our vic
would leave something like that
on one of his most prized
possessions?
I think... there's
only one way to find out.
Hey, Chris.
Nevada power guys--
they saw the Jeep,
called it in.
I ran the plates.
R.O. is, uh,
Cory Demayo, 25.
Lives on Florentine.
Spoke to
the roommate.
Driver fits the description.
Vic's got a contusion
on his forehead.
Probably
from the impact.
STOKES:
Yeah, I can see that.
It's just hard to believe
that's what killed him.
I didn't see any skid marks
on the road up there.
There's no signs
he tried to brake.
Well, maybe he fell asleep
at the wheel.
Uh, coming over that embankment?
That would've woke him up.
Key's still in
the ignition.
Car's in drive.
Engine's not running.
Did the paramedics open
this door?
Vitals were taken
through the open window.
Door was ajar when we
arrived on the scene.
Hey, Nick,
check this out.
Oh.
Guy was getting high.
Think that's the reason
he missed the curve up there?
You think?
Ah. We got a wallet.
Yeah, yeah.
Cory Demayo.
Fits the description.
No cash, no plastic.
This is a pretty
remote place
for an accident.
But you think someone saw it,
took advantage of the situation?
Maybe he wasn't alone.
Maybe the passenger
survived,
then emptied out his wallet,
took off.
Maybe.
♪ ♪
This guy really dress up
like Sherlock Holmes?
At least once a
week, evidently,
like those Civil
War re-enactors.
I, uh, never
understood that.
Yeah. In any event,
C.O.D. was no surprise.
Perforating
contact range,
gunshot to the
right temple.
SANDERS:
Got the tox.
Cocaine metabolites
in the vic's urine.
500 nanograms per M.O.
You only see levels that high
in chronic users.
Those are the
track marks.
SANDERS:
Yeah, but
there was also
morphine in his blood
and in the syringe.
Seven percent solution,
morphine sulfate
and water.
Sherlock went from crack
to smack.
Morphine metabolites
in his system
but no heroin
metabolites?
He wasn't on
street junk.
This is pharmaceutical-
grade stuff.
And at a pretty hefty dose, too.
How fast for the injection
to take effect?
Given his size,
he would've been
incapacitated
in a matter of seconds.
Not much time
to undo the works,
put away
his antique syringe,
pick up a gun
and blow his brains out.
Wait a minute.
The GSR test on his
hand was positive.
What are you getting at?
Well, maybe Sherlock
had some help.
BRASS:
Hey, when was the last time
you saw Cory?
Yesterday.
Just kicking it, like me.
How'd you get that
bruise on your dome, man?
Oh, uh, windsurfing.
Hey, you guys go
out there together?
Yeah. Well, he's got
the wheels, so...
So you drove
back together?
No.
I sort of hooked up
with this chick,
so I bounced.
Nice. You know
the chick's name?
Uh, Jennifer.
Jennifer who?
Jennifer, uh...
nipple ring.
( chuckling ):
Jennifer Nipple Ring.
Lawery, were you guys,
uh, getting
high yesterday?
You smoke some weed?
Nope.
No?
All right, let
me tell you
what I think happened.
You and Cory got stoned,
and you drove away.
Cory lost control
of the Jeep...
...at which point,
you couldn't wake him up,
so you decided to take
advantage of the situation,
and you rifle
through his wallet and leave.
Man, that is not what went down.
You're looking at robbery,
leaving the scene,
failure to report
an accident.
That's a lot of years, man.
I didn't get back in the car
with Cory, and if I had,
I wouldn't have left him!
Lawery, we're going to need
a DNA sample from you.
What? Why?
Just to prove
that, uh,
your lips weren't
on that joint
that we found
in the Jeep.
All right, man.
Let me just be straight
with you guys for a second here.
I admit,
Cory and I sparked up
at the lake, okay?
But then he took off.
Three weeks ago,
I was busted for pot, okay?
The judge gave me
diversion.
You guys file charges,
I'm screwed.
I will never get
into dental school.
The fragment you found
at the scene?
It's a mother of pearl.
It could be from an ornament
or a piece of jewelry.
It could be
from a lot of things.
Yeah, that it could,
Mr. Proficiency.
I also I.D.'d the ash
on the floor.
Perique tobacco,
grown in only one spot
on Earth:
St. James Parish,
Louisiana.
The same as the
umber of tobacco in
the victim's slipper?
No, completely
different make.
Cheap, strong,
low-grade stuff.
Shag tobacco.
Yeah. How'd you know?
That's what Holmes smoked.
Bad habit, even for
a fictional character.
You do have two suspects
with pipes.
Yeah... and, uh,
smoking kills.
MAN:
We got to stop meeting
like this, baby.
How was your game?
I'm swinging a hot
stick tonight, babe.
Can I get you something?
No, I'm just looking
for someone.
You're staring at me.
Oh.
Uh... I'm sorry.
I didn't recognize you
from last night.
Is that a friend
of yours?
( laughs ):
Give me a break.
Did that guy look
like a friend of mine?
Every time he touches
me, I want to kick
him in the scrotum,
but he's a big tipper.
I've got a sick mother
and rent to pay.
Well, I just have
a couple of questions.
At Denny Kingsley's,
you were smoking a pipe.
Yeah... a Meerschaum.
I'm going to need it.
Why?
Let me worry about that, okay?
Uh, J.J., can you hand
me my purse, please?
Okay.
Dr. Watson?
I'm Sara Sidle
with the Crime Lab.
Hello.
Do you have
a minute?
I'm here to collect
your Meerschaum pipe
as well as any other
tobacco products
you might have in
your possession.
I don't smoke
anything illegal.
You haven't been
accused of that.
Anyway, my pipe
is at home.
No problem. Let's go.
Look, I'm working.
We've already talked
to your boss,
and I have a warrant.
Let me get that for you.
Were you wearing
those shoes
at your last
club meeting?
Yeah. They're
not technically right
for the period,
but black leather shoes
are black leather shoes.
I'm not the same stickler
for detail that Denny was.
Apparently not.
Vic was physically fit.
Scratches and abrasions
are antemortem,
unrelated
to the accident.
The contusion on the
forehead was, uh,
superficial, right?
You are right.
Okay, so what's the cause
of death, Doc?
Undetermined.
But you're still working
on it, right?
Unless some other evidence comes
to light, I'm done.
Sometimes I can't tell you
why they die.
What you got?
Passenger door latch
is busted.
It could've happened
during the accident.
Well, that is consistent
with the roommate's story.
Says he wasn't in
the passenger seat
during the time
of the crash.
What'd you get
back from Tox?
Tox came back positive
for low levels of cannabis.
I know marijuana slows
your reaction time,
but based on the lack
of skid marks
at the scene,
the position of the vehicle,
I don't think this guy
ever hit the brakes.
Well, maybe he did
hit the brakes.
Did you check 'em?
Come on, you're
a bigger boy than me.
Yeah, you can't do
anything yourself,
can you?
You ready?
Yeah, yeah, put
your back into it.
( grunts )
Brakes work.
Brake lights are working,
so that means
the battery's okay.
Yeah, but the gauges
are all off.
The panel's not even working.
Okay, ignition was on,
but the engine wasn't running,
so... what?
No gas?
( grunts ):
That tank is full of fuel, man.
Cory was in good shape.
The Jeep seems to be in
decent condition, so...
( sighs ):
what happened
out there?
Swing shift's short
a couple of bodies.
Yes, and when is
that going to change?
Not anytime soon-- Catherine,
there are budget constraints.
You'll have to prioritize.
Should we come back?
No, no, no,
come on in.
So, how's your,
uh, your surfer dude case?
Uh, the victim's
roommate admits they
got high together,
but denies being
in the Jeep at the
time of the accident.
At this point,
we can't place him there.
Brakes on the Jeep
were functioning.
The driver should've
been able to stop.
Any signs of foul play?
STOKES:
No.
Something's not right.
ECKLEY:
All right, nothing suspicious
and no crime's committed?
Put the case to bed.
I'm sure your supervisor
can keep you busy.
Close it.
Sounds like he's more concerned
with getting it done
than getting it right.
Are you guys satisfied?
We don't have an answer.
Then get one.
What about Eckley?
( sighs ):
My problem, not yours.
♪ ♪
( sighs )
You nervous?
A little.
Relax.
Just two law enforcement
professionals talking
to one another, that's all.
I'm a security guard.
Don't patronize me.
I bet you always wanted to be
a cop, am I right?
So what happened?
Flunk the physical?
Huh?
That's okay;
lot of guys do.
No?
What was it then, psych?
I was on medication.
You can't be a cop
if you're on this medication.
But you can be Sherlock Holmes.
I was Dr. Watson...
in our club.
Denny was Sherlock Holmes.
"There can only be one."
So, when Denny wasn't there,
you could be Sherlock.
I suppose.
That why you killed him?
I didn't kill him.
Denny was a friend,
and if I wanted to be Sherlock,
all I had to do was wait.
Denny was quitting.
We talked about it a lot.
He said he was going back
to his wife.
So you went
to his house, you shot him,
and then you left,
and you came back later
with your pals and acted
like nothing happened.
I went straight home after work.
His blood on
your shoe,
tobacco ash from your pipe
on the carpet next to his body--
that puts you
where he was killed.
No way.
Look, there are two kinds
of stories: fact and fiction.
I know that.
Sherlock Holmes:
fiction.
Dennis Kingsley's murder: fact.
Your story: fiction.
No, I swear. God help me,
I'm telling the truth.
I-I wasn't there.
I didn't kill Denny.
DNA confirms that the blood
on Watson's shoe
is a match to your vic.
We got him.
Feel like celebrating
after shift?
I'm buying.
These blood drops
aren't uniform.
Some of them
are clotted red cells,
but others are pure serum.
It takes at least 20 minutes
for blood to clot and separate.
If Watson killed Sherlock,
the blood drops on his shoe
would all be the same.
The killer takes some of the
victim's blood at the scene...
...the red blood cells
in the serum separate
and get sprayed
on the shoe later.
Somebody's trying
to frame Watson.
SANDERS:
Jeez, all his stuff
is up for auction.
This is Dennis Kingsley's
entire collection.
He's getting rid
of everything.
Might have needed the cash?
I don't know.
Maybe he was just trying
to get back to reality.
Hold it.
Murder weapon
was a Colt .45 revolver,
current whereabouts unknown.
Huh, I thought
you were looking
for a book.
We are. We ran DNA
on this blood stain.
It's not the victim's,
and there's no hits
through CODIS.
You think
it's the killer's?
Maybe.
Come on, let's keep going.
There it is--
The Hound of the Baskervilles.
( beep )
When he photographed it,
there was no blood on the pages.
Can you pull up
the bidding history?
Yes, I can.
Let's see who's
interested.
JOHNSON:
Huh.
Reichenbach.
What's the big deal about that?
Reichenbach Falls?
It's where Professor Moriarty
killed Sherlock Holmes.
( beeping )
MAN:
The 1902 first British Edition
of The Hound?
Of course
I wanted it.
I'm a doctoral
candidate in
English history.
I helped
Denny create
that astonishing
verisimilitude
of Sir Arthur
Conan Doyle's
Britain. Order!
( bell dings )
SIDLE:
He was selling
the collection
off in pieces.
It must have
pissed you off.
He was a self-destructive
narcissist.
If he had to give it up,
we all had to give it up.
And you weren't
willing to do that?
As you can see,
the modest stipend I get
from my graduate studies
doesn't go far.
What I offered
for The Hound
is every penny
I had. Order!
SANDERS:
But then he put it up
for auction,
and made you bid for it.
When the price got too high,
you confronted him.
( laughs )
That is empty speculation,
my friend.
Hold out your hands for me,
please?
My hands?
Yeah.
Your hands.
Fine.
SANDERS:
Ooh, that looks like
a paper cut to me.
Are we gonna find your blood
on that book?
If you can't pay me
what it's worth...
Oh, come on,
you owe me as much.
Come on. Come...
Give it!
Ow!
Bloody hell, Dennis.
Fine, fine, fine.
Yes, I stopped by Dennis's house
earlier that evening
to make my case,
but I didn't kill him.
If I had, believe me,
I would have taken that book.
Tow truck will be here
in about an hour.
All right, we're
on the clock.
Let's take this
thing apart.
Hey, I've got
some blown fuses
and some fried wiring up here.
Yeah?
Yeah.
I've got some burn marks
on the undercarriage.
And I found something similar
on the roll bar, as well.
Well, that would indicate
some sort of electrical shock.
Well,
if an electrical charge
traveled through the Jeep,
and shorted out the wiring,
it would have shocked Cory,
as well.
Like what, lightning?
Yeah, but
it was clear yesterday.
Whatever it was, it zapped
the hell out of his Jeep.
Let's go back out there
and check it out.
Cory was coming from Lake Mead,
which is that way.
Let's walk.
Yeah.
( birds singing )
Wire trimmings.
They look fresh.
( camera shutter clicking )
Looks like a new splice
on those wires.
Well, the power company
originally called
that Jeep in.
They must have
been out here
fixing the lines.
Maybe it was a down line.
That would give us
the high voltage power source
right there.
Yeah, but even if a live wire
struck the roll bar,
the tires would have insulated
the vehicle.
Right. Without a path to ground,
electricity is harmless.
What about that road marker?
It's bent in the direction
Cory was driving.
Black transfer.
Wasn't the undercarriage
of Cory's Jeep black?
( tires screeching, squeaking)
This marker would
have grounded the Jeep.
Completing the circuit,
and theoretically,
electrocuting the vehicle.
I want to go back
to the crime scene.
The grips of Dennis Kingsley's
antique Colt .45
were mother of pearl,
consistent
with the chip collected here.
I identified trace
on the edge of that chip,
and it's red clay dust.
( sighs )
The fire's fake,
but these red clay bricks
are real.
So, what are you looking for?
Well, the killer
obviously left
with the gun.
And if there was some kind
of struggle,
maybe the killer
left behind
some skin fragments
or a strand of hair.
( groaning )
Was there any evidence
of a struggle in this room?
Not really.
Well, so much for the obvious.
SIDLE:
He committed suicide?
The man was a
credit to his genre.
He runs a loop
of surgical tubing
through the weapon
secured inside
the chimney.
A shot of morphine
a few minutes
earlier takes the edge off.
And it provides extra insurance
in case
the gun doesn't finish the job.
( gunshot )
It would have been easy for him
to plant Watson's brand
of tobacco ash
on his floor.
I figure,
Sherlock drew his own blood
in advance
and then sprayed it
on Watson's shoe
at their
last meeting.
The world's greatest detective
makes suicide look like murder?
Why would he try and frame
his best friend in the process?
Well, Watson said
they were friends,
but who knows what kind
of relationship they really had.
Maybe they hated
each other.
Maybe Dennis
couldn't stand the thought
of anyone else being Sherlock.
Besides, I thought
motive wasn't our business.
It's not.
Write it up,
give the report to Grissom.
Way to go.
All right.
What...
What is going on?
We're finishing
up the case.
( scoffs )
Do you know
how much Ballistic Joe costs?
I didn't know you did.
I just thought
you guys were gonna
go over your notes,
look over the case file.
Well, hold on now.
We found electrical burn marks
on the roll bar
and the Jeep's undercarriage.
And we found
blown out fuses
on the
instrument panel
and the starter.
That would explain
why the Jeep wasn't running.
Yeah, we called Nevada power,
and they confirmed
there was a downed power line
the day of the accident.
So, you're saying
the victim was electrocuted?
Yeah.
BROWN:
So we replaced
the fuses,
we connected the Jeep
to a power source,
and we hooked up
Gelatin Man here
to a hand meter.
Watch it
wiggle, see it jiggle, I get it.
Well, you're gonna need at least
six milliamps
to prove your theory.
I'm on it.
( engine starting )
( engine revving )
( electrical sparking )
WILLOWS:
Congratulations.
You killed the Jeep,
but the victim's still alive.
The current never even made it
past zero.
So,
either your theory is wrong,
or you've got a problem
with your experiment.
Are there any variables
in the case
that haven't been
duplicated here?
Same vehicle,
power's good.
So, why isn't Mr. Wiggles
connecting?
He's naked.
Well, let's dress him up.
( engine starting )
So, the current came
into the vehicle
from the roll bar,
and it went out through
the undercarriage.
It needed an entry point
and exit point.
Entry through the, uh,
the watch on his wrist
and then exit through the rivets
in his shorts.
Right across his heart,
stopping it cold.
♪ ♪
So I know that I've never said
this to you guys before,
but... hide the evidence.
Thanks for getting our back.
We're a team, guys.
Oh, since we're a team,
you gonna help us clean up?
Yeah.
( laughing )
No. I'm the boss.
I thought you told me you
closed the Cory Demayo case.
Catherine, nothing
happens in this lab
that I don't know about.
Then I'm sure you know
the case is now closed.
Did I make a mistake
promoting you?
Yeah, you should have
given me the day shift.
But I'm making it work.
( punk rock music
playing faintly )
Greg.
Hey, MTV boy.
I have a question
about your report.
Okay.
According to autopsy,
the victim showed
long-term effects
of cocaine abuse.
That's right.
But according to Tox,
the substance
in the victim's syringe
was a seven percent
solution of morphine.
Yeah.
The victim was
an obsessive compulsive.
In the stories,
Holmes' preferred stimulant
was a seven percent solution
of cocaine, not morphine.
Evidence out of context.
Did you ever consider
the possibility
that the victim
didn't realize
what he was injecting
himself with?
No.
You think someone
switched his coke with morphine?
You found the victim's
fingerprints on the gun,
but you found no prints
on the surgical tubing,
no epithelials either.
Does that make sense
if it was a suicide?
I guess not.
Do you have any other suspects
who have access to morphine
or surgical tubing?
I can find out.
I would do that.
SANDERS:
I went through
the medical records
for all of our suspects.
As far as I can tell,
none of them have
ever been prescribed morphine.
I think Watson's
our best bet.
The guy is a security guard
at Desert Palms;
he was certainly
around morphine.
GRISSOM:
Tobacco leaves.
Run a quick comparison.
This has to belong
to one of our suspects.
BRASS:
Do you like your life?
What kind of question is that?
Well, I mean, I've seen how
happy you are at work.
And then I know you
come home to Mom
and I guess she has
terminal cancer.
That's got to be tough.
Yeah, well, you try
giving enough attention
to someone who
never gave you any.
But the Sherlock Holmes club,
that's got to be
one bright spot, hmm?
The one place I could go
every week where no one
was grabbing my butt
or staring at my breasts.
The one place
I could talk, think.
You must have been pretty
devastated when Dennis Kingsley
decided to break
up the club, huh?
It was a disappointment.
Next week will be the final
meeting of our society.
But I give you my word,
it shall be an evening
none of you
will ever forget.
I think it's
a lot more than that.
I don't know what you mean.
Well...
the tobacco--
your blend is Cavendish.
Okay, why don't
I tell this
like a story, you know,
like the end of a story,
all right?
Because I like the part where
the detectives solves the crime.
So here goes.
On the day of the murder,
you broke into
Denny Kingsley's house.
That's easy enough,
the lock's crummy.
You snuck downstairs.
You replaced his cocaine
with morphine,
because you knew he
was a creature of habit.
So now all you had
to do is wait.
So you sprinkle
some of Dr. Watson's
pipe tobacco in the carpet.
You scoop up
some of Denny's blood,
to splash
on Watson's shoes later.
Why the elaborate
frame-up of Watson?
He had as much
to lose as you.
Because he's the one
that told Denny
to give it all up and go back
to his family.
Because he's the one that wanted
to be Sherlock Holmes,
because he didn't care
what it was doing to me.
( sniffling )
You see, Detective...
( in British accent ):
Denny would have wanted
his murder
to be the perfect puzzle.
A mystery worthy of the master.
Hey, Greg, Grissom
wants to see you.
Like now, in his office.
Grissom.
You wanted to see me.
Yeah!
Yeah.
Well done.
I'm proud of you.
Congratulations, Sanders.
Good work.
Thank you.
Okay, gang, there's
people to put in jail.
Let's get back
to it, shall we?
Come on,
come on, now.
Party's over. Let's go.
Good job.
I don't get it.
I got the wrong guy,
the wrong manner of death.
I don't expect you to be correct
in all your interpretations
all the time.
You collected the evidence.
You thought there
was something missing,
you went back
and found it.
Hey, that's the job.
Congratulations, Greg.
Thank you.
( all laughing )
Cheers. To you.