Say it loud
and say it proud!
Omega Zeta Pi!
Say it loud
and say it proud!
Omega Zeta Pi!
( sucking sounds )
Dude...
( spitting )
what's crawling on my face?
WOMAN:
It's Fraternity Hell Week.
A pledge slipped and fell
in this pile of maggots.
School of Agriculture is in
charge of campus landscaping,
so Security called me.
You were the first person
I thought of.
Well, thank you, Eva.
I'm honored.
You make
your own mulch?
The university
is self-sustaining.
A city within a city.
State institutions
are encouraged
to practice Xeriscaping.
"Xeri" meaning dry?
Landscaping using
drought-tolerant plant life.
Conserves water.
There's no reason
for these maggots
to be here.
Dr. Grissom, your tea.
Hold the tea bag?
Thank you, Brian.
Do, uh...
do you use scraps
from the dining halls
for your compost?
No. Why?
Well,
if the devil requires
a pound of flesh,
this many maggots would
require over a hundred.
Pounds of flesh?
Were you aware
that the average college student
weighs 135 pounds?
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
MAN:
How long is this going to take?
If something happened
to one of our students,
don't you want to know?
Sure.
But on a campus
this size,
there's a thin line
between satisfying
curiosity
and creating panic.
This stopped being
about my curiosity
the minute we found
a human tooth.
We're now investigating
a possible homicide.
Hey, Grissom, why is it hot?
Maggot digestion can generate
heat up to 125 degrees.
Heat increases the rate
of putrefaction,
which speeds up
the digestive process.
I don't see any tissue.
How long would it take for them
to pick a body clean?
Assuming it's just one body?
A few days.
Yeah, and that's another thing.
I have a hard time believing
that if a corpse was here,
no one saw it.
And these bones?
They're uniform.
Same shape and size.
Yeah.
Same size
as these wood chips.
( loud whooshing )
This thing always this loud?
Yeah, but we're, we're kind of
off the beaten path.
You use it every day?
Pretty much.
You think a human body
could fit through there?
You planning something?
Gil Grissom,
Las Vegas Crime Lab.
Walter Beerly,
Master of the Universe.
Six cylinders.
200 horse power.
Thing's got an engine
that would give most SUVs
a run for their money.
And it's got one job.
Chopping crap up.
So the answer's yes.
Would take about 15 seconds.
May I?
You want to stick your head
in there, be my guest.
What are you looking for?
Blood.
Oh, you're pretty much
out of luck,
'cause I've been chipping
all morning,
and if there was any in there,
it's probably gone.
See, wood absorbs moisture.
One of the reasons
they use it for mulch.
Pregnant?
It's human.
Remember, you're
on the clock, man.
About, uh, 24 hours...
all of these maggots
turn into flies.
What are you doing?
GRISSOM:
Day shift told me
you didn't get any results
off the tooth.
MIA:
Yeah, it was
a porcelain crown.
Root canal.
No viable pulp.
I still need a DNA profile
on our victim.
And since bone marrow extraction
can be difficult...
GRISSOM:
I figured I'd go straight
to the source.
Well, maggots are
eating machines.
They'll have DNA from the flesh.
It's genius.
There you go.
One maggot colada,
coming up.
WILLOWS:
What's with the tape?
The evidence
wasn't cooperating,
so I stuck it to them.
Cute.
Anything of interest?
Well, I haven't had much time
for analysis.
So far the only
inorganics
are these black
plastic shreds,
from a garbage
bag, I think,
and...
this.
Well, blue trace
is tacky.
It's a fingernail.
Uh, sorry, Sara.
I need the microscope.
Priority.
I got three more
samples to run.
When I'm done,
it'll be your turn.
This can't wait.
It can't?
Or you can't?
Both.
Go have a cup of coffee on me.
The coffee's free.
Thank you.
Oil-based blue paint
mixed with motor oil...
on a fingernail.
He's back.
Starting in 1987,
a series of murders
occurred on the WLVU campus.
Three women:
Janet Kent...
Marcia Reese...
and Charlene Roth.
Now, Charlene Roth's murder
provided us with enough evidence
to investigate a suspect...
John Mathers,
WLVU security guard.
He was arrested, tried
and convicted.
Two years ago,
this week, he was executed.
The night of his execution,
Debby Reston was murdered.
Copycat, right?
WILLOWS:
No.
We believe that Mathers
was the copycat,
responsible only
for Charlene Roth's death.
Which means the serial killer
is still at large.
And we have reason to believe
that he has killed again.
Our suspect's M.O.
is to apply blue paint
to a campus railing
that he has infused
with motor oil to retard
the drying process.
He then lays in wait
for a female victim
to touch the railing.
It's always near
a water fountain.
He then grabs them from behind
as they're washing the paint
from their hands.
Our suspect's prior victims
were all sexually assaulted.
No semen was found.
Cause of death: strangulation.
He stuffed them
in black plastic trash bags
and dumps the bodies
in plain sight.
Given that he has been killing
for around 20 years,
we approximate his age to be
at least 35.
He may wear glasses.
He may drive a Chevy
with black interior.
The latest victim was put
in a wood chipper.
Why the change in M.O.?
Serials have been known
to change their signatures
because they have to.
Fear of being caught...
interruption... or it could
just be an act of escalation.
BRASS:
So we're looking
for a sadistic,
ritualistic,
organized sociopath.
We'll be on 12 and 12s.
No holidays, no vacations
until this is solved.
Ms. Willows,
can you confirm
that the Blue Paint
Killer has claimed
another victim?
I haven't been cleared
for comment.
Ms. Willows,
was John Mathers
wrongfully convicted?
Did the State execute
an innocent man?
John Mathers killed Charlene
Roth and was punished for it.
Well, how can you
be so sure of that?
I double-checked the results.
The DNA from
the maggots is male.
Any possible
cross-contamination?
No, the samples
were pure.
Griss, this place
is crawling with press.
They want a statement.
Not now.
Well, if you don't
say anything,
they're just going
to fill in the blanks...
Screw the press,
'cause for all I know,
the dead body is
an auto mechanic
who just painted
his house blue.
WILLOWS:
What's this key used for?
Um, pledging.
Plebes are asked
to swallow it on the first night
of Hell Week.
Then "retrieve" it
and return it by the end
of the week, right?
You got it.
You know that hazing is illegal.
You could lose your charter.
Well, it's not hazing.
It's a voluntary loyalty ritual.
Political science major?
Pre-law.
!
Good.
Maybe you can explain why
the pledge who swallowed
this key ended up dead.
Wha-What're you talking about?
Has anyone from
Omega Zeta Pi
dropped out or gone missing?
Uh...
Yeah, Jo-Jonathan Avery
Haywood III.
Johnny.
Oh, kid was a shoe-in.
Dad was a member.
Granddad was
a member.
But we haven't seen
Johnny since Pledge Week.
So, he's been missing for days,
yet you didn't bother
to call anyone?
For all I knew
he was getting laid.
Look, I'm the fraternity
president, not his mother.
We're gonna need his toothbrush
and his hairbrush.
Get off of me!
Button!
I'm a loser.
I'm a loser. I'm a loser.
Why didn't Nick
find this before?
'Cause he was
working from
a schematic
the campus
security
gave him.
The railing's
not on it.
This cement is fresh.
So, now he's not just painting
railings; he's installing them.
We're going to need
to dig this up,
cement and all.
Get Brass. We have
another body.
So, he knew we would find this.
And now he's taunting us.
Two years ago,
DNA confirmed
a hair found
on Debby Reston
belonged to the serial's first
victim, Janet Kent.
Planted hairs.
It's part of his signature.
WILLOWS:
Well, DNA confirmed
that the hair found
in the doll's mouth
belonged to Debby Reston.
I tested the
note with ESDA,
because I saw
some indentations
in the paper.
He must've written "I have her"
on the underlying page.
Prior evidence
indicated
that the suspect was an artist
or had some connection
to the university's
Art Department.
Serials typically photograph
their crime scenes.
If we're dealing with
an artist here...
maybe he drew
his victims instead.
BROWN:
Looks like she's
in a small room.
What is that in the foreground?
Chair? Sofa?
What about behind her?
STOKES:
Windows, maybe.
Can we blow that up?
Some kind of signage?
And the lettering's backwards.
STOKES:
Cramped space.
Chairs in the foreground,
but no other furniture.
No shutters or curtains
on the windows.
Maybe it's not a room.
Maybe it's a... vehicle.
He was in
the front seat,
and he was looking at her
through the rearview mirror.
So, he can attack her,
abduct her,
rape her and strangle her,
but he can't look
directly at her?
Guys, those black
trilobal fibers
that we found
on Debby Reston's body
were from a Chevy.
And the size and shape
of those windows
are consistent
with a Chevy van.
I recognize the signage.
The Erotica Boutique
on Tropicana.
It's distinctive...
The font...
BRASS:
Okay, break it open.
( catches his breath )
So, this is
where he brought them.
The pump was probably
for the doll.
Beer bottles...
Tell Mia to check them
for saliva,
as well as other bodily fluids.
You're thinking she was raped
with a foreign object...
may be why we never found semen.
The police presence
on the campus
probably interrupted
his plans for her disposal.
I'll take the girl.
I'll take the van.
Huh.
I would've picked you
for a leather guy.
Has anyone, uh, bought
one of these Coed Cheerleader
Dolls in the last few days?
Most popular models are
the latex
love-'em-or-leave-'em cheapies
for bachelor parties.
But in the midrange,
Chrissy's not a bad choice.
Well, I'm more interested in the
clientele than the merchandise.
Oh.
I'd like to take a look
at your credit card receipts.
Surveillance?
Bad for business.
You know this artist?
Yeah, that is "Zippy Tee."
You have an address for him?
Dude, I don't know
where he lives.
How do you pay him?
It's not the Louvre.
It's the Love Boutique.
Local guys get
store credit.
Has he ever traded
for... a doll?
Yeah.
Can you describe him for me?
White guy.
Brown hair.
Little shorter than you.
40, maybe 45...
Average looking.
ROBBINS:
This all looks eerily familiar.
Blue paint on the hand.
Physical signs
of sexual assault.
Ligature marks
around the neck.
Prints turn up anything?
She's still a Jane Doe.
Height and weight?
Five-eight.
131 pounds.
Can you take down
her hair?
Sure.
Pretty.
Pretty boy.
Definite similarity.
None of the other victims
looked alike.
So, why these two?
Maybe he
was a mistake.
Mistaken for a girl?
WILLOWS:
But not just any girl.
This girl.
We thought he selected
his victims at random.
He didn't.
He chose her.
He hunted her.
And trapped her.
The TV said
you were looking
for information
on Kaitlin Rackish.
WILLOWS:
When was the last time
you saw Kaitlin?
Monday, but I've been pledging,
so I haven't slept in the dorm
the last couple nights.
I just thought
I kept missing her.
Can you tell me what the two
of you did on Monday?
All the details.
We went to the gym. Showered.
Went to the dining hall.
Monday's mac-n-cheese day.
It's Katy's favorite.
We picked up our orders
at the Campus Copy Union--
term papers.
We bought sodas
at the bookstore.
We went to the library to study.
A couple guys from Zeta Beta
Theta were at the same table,
so we didn't get that much done.
Then she left for her
7:00 class.
What class is that?
Monday's, um...
"Introduction
to the Female Form"
with Professor Lewis.
Cody Lewis?
He got me interested in art.
"Introduction
to the Female Form"?
Well, that's deep.
That's really deep.
I bet that brings in all
the 17-year-old pre-feminists.
This isn't mine.
Technique isn't bad,
but it's raw.
This person hasn't had any
formal training at all.
Well, maybe it's your alter ego.
You know, your bad-boy side;
the Mr. Hyde thing.
You know, I came in voluntarily.
You see, I want to help you.
But this is borderlining
on harassment.
Look, I'm trying to tie together
some loose ends,
so help me out, all right?
I appreciate your help. I do.
You got rid
of your Chevy van.
You got yourself a wife.
Does she know you dated
the first victim?
Your return to the campus
coincided with the murder
of the fourth victim?
And Kaitlin Rackish
was in your evening classes?
You see what I got?
No, I don't.
Your buddy Mathers
didn't talk much, either,
and look what happened to him.
He's at the wrong end
of a cold needle.
You know what it's like
to be told
you lead the life and fit
the profile of a serial killer?
No. I wouldn't have a clue.
You see, you make
all these assumptions,
and you're not asking
questions here.
You're attacking me to see how
I react to what you say.
Nothing I say is going to make
a difference with you.
So what's the point?
Why don't you just confess?
That's my point.
I didn't do it.
SANDERS:
WLVU parking pass.
Connection to the campus.
1986.
This guy's been doing this
a long time.
STOKES:
Two years ago, Debby Reston
broke her killer's glasses.
They were 20/80.
I'll run 'em.
See if they're the same.
STOKES:
VIN's been obliterated.
You better go ahead and
run that parking pass.
SANDERS:
Plate's expired.
Registration
sticker's a phoney.
How do you know?
STOKES:
Check out the serial number.
"0-0-0-0..."
Yeah, got it. Homemade.
SANDERS:
Hey, did you spill print powder
in the back of the van?
No.
No, I superglued. Why?
May have found something.
Anything from the prints
off the van?
Prints from the dash
and the rearview mirror
were a match to the partial
that we got off the trash bag
Debby Reston was found in
two years ago.
Same guy, but still
no hits from AFIS.
SIDLE:
Are the X-rated
comic books ready?
Nothing comical about them.
Look at this.
Double-D cups,
tiny waists, bondage.
Dehumanization.
I'm all for visual stimulation,
but these images
are about domination, not sex.
This artist gets off
on dominating women.
This is his sex.
BROWN:
Janet and Marcia both lived
in Dakin Hall.
Charlene and Debby
took Econ 101.
Marcia and Charlene
took English Lit.
Janet, Debby and Kaitlin all ate
at Macgraw Dining Hall.
Janet dated Cody Lewis.
Kaitlin took his art class.
All right, so, uh,
There's not one single thing
that all five women
have in common.
Right.
( woman groans )
( muffled ):
Please, help.
STOKES:
Dead plates.
Tampered VIN. Registration
stickers are counterfeit.
Killer did a good job,
though.
He used the right color,
changed them every year,
but no serial numbers.
So, we still don't
know who owns the van.
Well, Greg did find this
in the glove box.
It's from 1986.
So I called
School Administration.
It's parking spot 324.
Not a student, but an employee
executed two years ago.
John Mathers?
Yep. Ran Mathers
through the DMV.
The partial VIN number
on our van's a match.
So, our killer was driving
around in Mathers' old van.
I don't think these two guys
are an original and a copycat.
They were partners.
I don't deserve to die.
You think killing me
will solve anything?
I've prepared myself,
but I'm not ready.
This the John Mathers
interview?
Week before
he was executed.
JOURNALIST:
Charlene Roth's mother
testified at the Allocution
that your death would
mean her closure.
Not if you kill the wrong man.
JOURNALIST:
Forensic evidence
testified to at your trial
says that you're guilty.
Forensic evidence
changes all the time.
One day I'm innocent,
the next day I'm not.
Is there anything
in his prison file?
All those years on death row
he only had one visitor,
his lawyer.
Although he
did receive
a far amount of letters
from random women...
if he was in communication
with his partner,
nothing in the file shows it.
You've been in
prison for 15 years.
During that time
the murders stopped.
What does that prove?
The real killer's smart.
Watches the news, he reads
the papers just like you.
I'm... Man,
I'm the perfect patsy.
So you maintain
your innocence?
Absolutely.
I worked Campus Security.
I'm not the smartest
or the richest guy,
but do I look like I had
problems with women?
I'm not the killer.
Remember that when I'm gone.
SIDLE:
Well, the prints
on the comb bindings
from the comic books
are a match to the prints
recovered from the van
and the garbage bag
that Debby Reston was in.
GRISSOM:
Did you analyze
the comics?
Yeah, and the drawings
indicate a dominant,
disassociative sexual sadist.
Prison shrink diagnosed Mathers
as a psychopath
with a dependent
personality disorder.
Which means he was pre-disposed
to violent crimes
but he might have needed
some encouragement.
Well, to invite someone to join
you for torture and murder
would require
a great deal of trust.
You would only do it
if you knew you could completely
control your partner.
Mathers was the submissive.
His partner is the alpha male.
Sexual sadism can go hand in
hand with sexual dysfunction.
Mathers said
that he wasn't the killer,
but we confirmed that he had sex
with Charlene Roth,
based on the fact that we found
his pubic hairs on her body.
Mia was looking for saliva on
the beer bottles from the van
and found a vaginal contribution
on the neck of one of them.
Maybe Mathers was this guy's
surrogate penis.
WILLOWS:
Okay, the partner
kills on the eve
of Mathers' execution,
and again this week,
on the second anniversary.
Why the no-show last year?
Maybe life got in the way.
Nick, that black powder from
the back of the van is ink.
A toner made exclusively
for commercial copy machines.
OCE 3600.
Okay. Thanks, Hodges.
The most recent victim
went to the
Campus Copy Union
with her roommate
on the day she disappeared.
Janet Kent's...
pocket contents--
a receipt from WLVU Copy Union.
On Debby Reston's backseat...
catalogs with comb bindings.
Who'd you find?
Kevin Greer.
Works at the Copy Union.
Only employee who's been there
over ten years; since 1983.
BRASS:
Fits our profile.
Where's Kevin Greer?
He just left.
He works till 8:00.
Time for evening classes
to let out.
What's going on?
Look, we'd like to talk
to Kevin Greer.
You have any idea
where he is?
No. We don't hang out.
How many people work here?
Just me.
Okay,
we need to look around.
Okay.
Black plastic trash bags
with toner powder.
Excuse me.
Does Kevin Greer
use this machine
for any of his
personal projects?
Yeah. He binds his comic books.
Kevin Greer,
Las Vegas Police.
Hit it.
Clear.
( rattling )
Check its noice.
Clear.
( rattling grows louder )
A paint mixer.
WLVU Blue.
So he mixed his own paint
so we couldn't trace the origin
of his purchase.
( phone ringing )
( beep )
GREER:
Las Vegas's finest.
Nice job.
Impressive turnout.
Have a look around.
I'll be here at the station
waiting for you.
Gil, Jim.
Yeah, my rule was:
If you made it to my house,
you deserved to meet me.
I mean, how much time
did you guys spend
picturing the size of my hands?
Not very big.
You don't need big hands,
though, not the way I do it.
Just... just a little at a time.
Take life, give it back.
God-like.
KEVIN:
God-like?
No.
But there must be something
angelic in the way I look,
because even on
their last breath,
they didn't think
I'd actually do it.
Am I disappointing you guys?
I mean, are you looking at me,
wishing I was...
scarier?
No.
I was, uh, wondering what
happened to your glasses.
Stupid Lasik.
It's what got me caught.
Is it?
When that Debby bitch
busted my glasses...
I decided they were
a liability.
But the procedure didn't take.
Is that why you missed
last year's anniversary?
And my night vision still sucks.
( wry chuckle )
Johnny?
I don't want to talk about him.
Well, you, uh, kept him
for several days
before you chopped him up.
Were you having a good time?
I'm not into boys.
( hinges creaking )
GREER:
Kid was in my freezer.
Wait a minute.
There are six here.
We only know of five.
Tell us about Charlene Roth.
You had to bring her up.
You know, I tried to
talk him out of it,
but, uh, J.M wouldn't...
John Mathers.
He had something to prove.
See, he didn't
understand
that we were better together
than we would ever be apart.
He needed me.
Soul mates.
Contrary to popular belief,
even people like us have souls.
I spent 15 years looking
for a solid replacement,
but you only get that lucky
once in a lifetime.
You miss him.
I created him.
But you let him take the fall.
He got caught.
That's the price you pay
for incompetence.
Death.
That's what you deserve
when you make a mistake.
( knock at door )
There's a sixth victim.
A Brit or Brittany Mosscoe.
Her name was on a Ziploc bag
in Greer's freezer.
It contained a lock of hair.
Sara's looking
into Missing Persons.
And Mia's running
it through DNA.
Thanks.
Where is, uh...
Brit Mosscoe?
There's a lot of fight in her.
Is she old or new?
I'll take you to her.
Oh, we'll need
a full tank of gas.
( phone ringing )
Hello.
Yeah, I'm trying to confirm
that you have no record
of a Brit Mosscoe attending WLVU
in the last 18 years.
What about a night student?
Okay, thanks.
Hey, uh, can I go to
the bathroom before we go?
Yeah, okay.
Bobbie, pat him down.
Slow down.
Okay...
Okay.
I got it.
The sixth victim is a ruse.
He drew her off a calendar.
Brit Mosscoe
is an anagram for Miss October.
So where's he taking us?
Mr. Greer, let's go. Come on.
Mr. Greer?
Where is he, in there?
Come on, Mr. Greer, let's go!
Damn it!
Get a paramedic!