Welcome back, Mrs. Krell.
I told you, it's Martha.
Your room's ready
and I have your credit card
on file.
See you in the morning.
I'm beat.
CLERK:
Call me if you need anything,
Martha.
( screams )
Decedent's name is Martha Krell.
Flight attendant.
She checked in this afternoon.
Apparently, she was stabbed
to death.
The coroner's en route.
Weird... no sign of struggle.
No clothes,
no luggage.
SARA:
Bedspread's undisturbed.
Trashcan is empty
and the inside is spotless.
It's possible
a liner's been removed.
Take a whiff.
Smells clean.
Smells like a hospital.
Bleaches and deodorizers.
Killer attacked
the victim,
then cleaned and sanitized
the room.
Ah, but here's the smell
of the blood still,
and all the perfumes
in Arabia will not sweeten
this little room.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
( garbled radio transmission)
Her liver temp's 83 degrees.
She's been dead
approximately ten hours.
I'd like to get a clear photo
of her wounds.
Can we lay her out?
Oh, yeah. Grab her feet.
( joints crackling )
Defensive wounds.
Incised.
At least a dozen.
She did not want to die.
I just got the call.
Where's Grissom?
Bathroom.
Working the, uh, case.
Hey.
Hand me my multi-tool,
will ya, Greg?
I need a Phillips.
What are you doing?
Well, the stabbing
was brutal,
but the crime
scene is clean.
No cast-off, no spatter.
So, I want to know if the killer
washed blood down the drain.
Swab and phenol this,
will ya?
Blood.
Label it. Send it to DNA.
Usually in hotel rooms,
we find too many prints.
Not a single one.
Just wipes and swipes.
Ms. Krell was a real nice lady.
She brought me
a Dodger baseball cap.
Wow. So you were friends?
Not really.
Airlines buy a chunk of rooms
for their trolley dollies,
discounted.
She's been staying here
for a few months.
So you discovered
the body.
Her supervisor called
to say her A.M. flight
was canceled.
She wasn't
answering her phone.
He asked me to make sure
she got the message.
So you knocked
on her door,
and when she didn't answer,
you just went right in?
Yeah. I got a master key.
Yeah, I knew that.
Does the hotel have
surveillance?
Nope.
Thank you.
You've been a big help.
Right on.
Excuse me.
I'm Hayden Michaels.
I'm the manager
of the Four Aces.
I just got the call.
Anything we can
do to help?
Thank you.
I'll let you know.
Detective,
if this hits
the media,
this is really going
to hurt our business.
What are you asking me?
Anything you can do
to keep it out of the press?
Look, I'm trying
to catch a killer.
I got no control
over the press.
If this makes the news,
then it is what it is.
( garbled radio transmission)
Hey. Victim's
in the bedroom.
Ty Hawkins, 12.
Mother came in to wake him...
found him like this.
( sighs )
Beaten to death.
This many blows,
it was personal.
Liver temp makes T.O.D.
around midnight.
No sign
of forced entry.
nothing's missing.
All the doors and
windows were locked
except for
the screen door.
Parents claim
they keep that locked.
You find a weapon?
Negative.
Family's been transported
down to the station.
I'm gonna go down
and take their statement.
Hey, when you're
done here,
roll by.
We'll ink them.
You got it.
Boy's not even safe
in his own bed.
I'll take the inside.
Yeah, I could use the fresh air.
Found a pile of pipes
by the side of the house
One seems to be missing.
This is an exemplar
of a possible murder weapon.
And I cast a shoe impression
just outside
the kid's bedroom window.
Also some graffiti
on the window-- B-R-A-T.
Maybe somebody had it in
for the kid.
Well, I bagged the bloody sheets
from the bed.
Found boxers, a T-shirt
and a fitted sheet
in the washer.
ALS'd for blood, found urine.
Mm. Well, whoever killed the boy
knew how to get in and out
of this house
without waking the family.
No mystery here.
Ms. Krell was violently
stabbed to death.
C.O.D. exsanguination.
SAE kit?
She was raped.
Contusions to the
vaginal introitus
and an eighth-inch
hemorrhagic laceration
at the vaginal fourchette.
6:00 position.
The attack was brutal.
Aren't they always?
I don't know why people think
that rape has anything
to do with sex.
If a guy just wants sex,
he can hire a hooker.
What else?
Well, there is
some good news.
Motile sperm in the wet mount.
I've sent the kit
to DNA for analysis.
Ecklie, what's up?
I paged Grissom.
And he paged me.
How can I help you?
Five years ago, there was
this, uh, day-shift case,
Homicide. The victim
was a flight attendant
named Sue Stein
from Palo Alto, California.
She was raped
and murdered
in a local hotel.
Killer was never
apprehended.
Vic's clothing and suitcase
were missing.
Room was immaculate,
smelled like disinfectant.
Same signature.
One difference.
In the prior case,
body was found
in a first floor room.
Sliding glass door
facing the pool was unlocked.
Ms. Krell was killed
on the second floor.
There was only one way
into her room.
Was there semen present
in Sue Stein's SAE kit?
Yeah. Ran it through CODIS.
No hit.
I asked Mia to compare it
with the semen
from the recent attack.
Is that fingerprint
from your crime scene?
Only print we found.
Impressed in Sue's blood
on the bedspread
near her hips.
Underlying pattern
on the fabric
made it impossible to read.
That was then.
This is now.
My son's dead.
Why are you fingerprinting me?
The crime lab is going to
dust your house for prints,
so I need to know
which ones are yours.
Now, your wife said that you
both went to bed after the news.
I already told you that.
Twice.
You know, I... I got
questions, too, you know.
Why Ty?
Why not me?
How could my wife and
I sleep... ( sighing )
through it all?
Mr. Hawkins, would you
stand up, facing me,
so I can take some photos?
Is this really necessary?
Please, just let him do his job.
Sir...
( clears throat )
Open up.
I'll be needing
to take your shoes.
You can wear some booties home.
What now?
You and your wife
are free to go.
What about Matt?
He has to stay here
in protective custody
until this is resolved.
Yvonne.
Hey.
They're keeping Matt.
I know. He'll be home soon.
It's just procedure.
Right?
Right.
Can we at least
speak to him?
Can't allow that.
Come on, let-let's go.
Come on.
You just gonna let them go?
Neither has a record, no motive.
There's no blood on them.
Well, they could've showered,
tossed their clothes.
Their grief is not an act.
Yeah, based on what?
Years of listening
to the parents of dead children.
Let's go talk to this kid.
Hey, Mia.
Let me guess, you're
listening to something
classy like Jessica
or Ashlee.
( man speaking French
through headset )
It's... Jean-Paul Sartre.
"Huis Clos."
"No Exit."
It loses something
in a translation.
Oui, oui.
The blood from the hairy wad
that you found in the drain
is consistent
with the victim.
And what about the semen
from Martha's SAE?
That's consistent with the DNA
from the first attack.
You are looking
at the same rapist.
I want to show you something.
Really?
This guy's immune system
doesn't recognize his own sperm.
Antibodies are attacking
the little guys.
I read about this phenomenon
in a forensic journal...
November, 2003.
Killer had a vasectomy,
then had it reversed.
Oui, oui.
Thanks, Mia.
How could a boy have
made someone so mad?
COD is blunt-force trauma.
I counted 14 separate blows.
Several more were coinciding.
Cylindrical weapon,
about an inch
in diameter.
Consistent with a pipe?
Yeah. In fact, check this out.
Thread pattern's consistent
with the end of a pipe.
He's got no defense wounds.
Yeah. My guess,
he never woke up.
CAVALIERE:
You're not fooling me, kid.
The second I laid eyes on you,
I knew how it went down.
You took a pipe
from the backyard,
you went into Ty's bedroom,
and while he was sleeping,
you beat his brains to a pulp.
Now, what the hell's
wrong with you, kid?
Your little brother is dead.
What did he
ever do to you?
Now, don't look at him.
He can't help you.
Nobody can help you.
You're going to prison.
At 14, that means life.
I'm talking to you,
you little...!
Detective...
can I have a word
with you outside, please?
We don't have enough evidence
to suggest that
that boy killed his brother.
What are you getting at?
I'm saying I'm not sure
if threatening him
is the right tactic right now.
I found no blood
on his clothes.
The screen door could have
been the point of entry.
I mean, have you considered
asking him what he heard
or-or saw before you just put
the full court press on him?
I don't tell you how to
collect the evidence.
No, you don't. Look, there's
no disrespect here, okay?
We're all on the same team.
Then get to the lab and get
me something that I can use.
( sighs )
( electronic beep )
Hey.
Hey. Call me a geek,
but background subtraction
application software
is the bomb.
Only geeks still say "the bomb."
But it you ask me, geeks
should be revered.
Okay. Um,
the technology's pretty new.
You'll get hammered on cross,
but it definitely works.
Okay, check it out.
So the fingerprint is
blood-red-- that's the shade
we use for
the color identifier--
and now the preprogrammed
algorithm
is just removing all the
other colors from the fabric,
and we're left with
just the print. It's...
Mind if I watch?
Voyeur, huh?
I like that.
Geek.
( sighs )
( taps key, beep )
Wow.
Yeah.
Right.
( taps keys )
Scan this into I-AFIS,
and here we go.
Got yourself a hit.
"Jesse Acheson. 38.
"Multiple convictions, cocaine
possession, intent to sell.
"In and out of prison for
the past... seven years.
Was he in or out
on May 12, 1999?
Out.
What about last night?
Released six months ago.
Living in Henderson.
Geeks rule.
WOMAN:
Who is it?
Las Vegas Police.
We're looking for Jesse Acheson.
Hey, look, my husband
hasn't used
since he got out
of the joint,
so whatever you think
he did, you're wrong.
Do you know where he is?
No idea.
Well, your marriage is just
full of romance, huh?
May we come in?
Nah, I don't think so.
Just one more question.
Do you happen to know
where he was last night?
No. I, uh, I haven't
seen him in days.
Thank you.
( door slamming )
That was fun.
Brass,
you guys get in your cars,
drive around the block.
Pick me up in five minutes.
We'll be close.
( Touch-Tone beeps )
( car starting )
Jesse, cops were just here.
What the hell's going on?
No, I didn't tell them
where you are!
I don't know where
the hell you are!
When are you
coming home?
Jesse...
Damn you!
( phone beeps, sighing )
The shoe impression
outside Ty's window
matches the brother's
Yeah, I got a hair
off of Ty's T-shirt.
Also consistent with Matt.
Either of which could be related
to the murder or just a result
of two brothers
living together.
Yeah.
What's in the bindle?
Uh, Blue fibers.
Got them off
the vic's T-shirt.
Nobody in the family
was wearing anything blue.
No, but you know,
could be
from a blanket,
a carpet, towel.
I'll take them to Trace.
Hey, I am concerned
that Detective Cavaliere's
moving ahead of Forensics
on this one.
He can move as
fast as wants.
The D.A. won't file without
the physical evidence.
Right now, we got nothing.
Sandra Acheson called
her husband at exactly
3:03 p.m. today.
I secured a 2703-D court order
for the number she was calling.
It was a cell phone.
I contacted the cell phone
company and found out
that Jesse answered his phone
near Tower 8, phase West.
Given the signal strength,
he was within two blocks
of the tower.
His wife said that
she hasn't seen him
in several days, so I had
Homicide check registration
at all the hotels
within the yellow area.
He is booked at the Tangiers.
Well done.
Get this--
the rapist's semen came back
positive for cocaine.
We don't usually run
a panel for semen, Greg.
I know that, but given
our suspect's priors
for blow, I had a tech
run an immunoassay
specific to the drug.
Wow. You guys are
rendering me obsolete.
So, Jesse gets coked up,
he commits the crime,
he drives down
to the Strip
and he checks into
the Tangiers.
The Gift Show's in town.
There aren't any
vacancies on the Strip.
Well, his wife said that she
hadn't seen him in a few days.
Maybe he's back
in the game again,
selling coke
to out-of-town businessmen
from the comfort and security
of his hotel room.
So, he takes a break
from his job,
rapes and kills the vic
at another hotel,
and then goes back to work?
Even cokeheads need
a diversion now and then.
Hi, Stokes.
Solve the case?
( chuckles ):
I'm getting there.
Nothing definitive
as of yet.
Which means
you can't hold Matt Hawkins
for longer than his 24 hours.
Really? Well, you know, uh...
I got a signed confession.
Really?
Mm-hmm.
Sort of kicks the crap
out of your "evidence,"
now, doesn't it?
He confessed?
Signed.
Check it.
Did you beat it
out of him?
( chuckles ):
No, I used science,
kind of like you guys.
Mm, how's that?
I put him on a Computer
Voice Stress Analyzer.
Once I caught him lying,
he gave it right up.
That device has been
discredited for years.
Well, check their Web site.
It's still used in 1,400
state and local agencies.
Well, not in Las Vegas.
Or anywhere else
in this state.
Say, was an advocate
or a parent present
at the time of
the confession?
He didn't ask
for his mommy and daddy.
Long as he says
he understands his rights,
we don't have to have
anyone there with him.
He tell you why he did it?
No, but he will.
Hey, listen, Stokes,
thanks for trying to help,
but we got him.
Okay.
So, I just got back
from the Tangiers.
The GM won't let us
into Jesse Acheson's room
without a search warrant,
and the judge denied
our request.
I'll talk to the judge.
I'll bring Acheson in
for questioning, I guess.
Could you just keep him
under surveillance for now,
let Greg tag along
with your guy?
We might learn something.
Sure, I'll get him
a bag of donuts.
I was testifying today.
I ran into the D.A.
He filled me in
on your case.
Looks like
Matt Hawkins' confession
is gonna stand up in court.
Suspects are tricked
into confessing all the time,
but I'm telling you,
Cavaliere intimidated that boy.
Man, he would've signed
anything.
So you think he's innocent?
Could be. I checked
the crime stats
for the Hawkins neighborhood.
There's been a rash
of nuisance calls.
There's some homeless guy
running around out there
peeping in windows, urinating
in public, attempted B and E.
Sounds like a suspect.
I'm gonna go back out there,
see if the Hawkins know
anything about it.
Need some help?
You got that kind of time?
I'll meet you in the car.
Thanks, Warrick.
WOMAN:
You expect me
to invade Mr. Acheson's privacy
based upon
a five-year-old fingerprint
that was manipulated
on a computer?
It wasn't manipulated--
it was processed.
That's what we do.
Try getting that one
past a defense attorney.
It's one thing to send
a print through AFIS;
it's another thing to use...
a "background
subtraction algorithm"
to isolate the print
from a bedspread.
It's not my fault
that the courts
lag behind our technology.
Gil,
I'm sympathetic
to your request,
but if I grant a warrant
based upon this print,
and the print is later
thrown out of court,
then everything you
find as a result of it
would be excluded,
and your pattern rapist
could be back on the street.
Give me something else--
I'll be happy
to grant you a warrant.
Your Honor,
I need the warrant
in order to find something else.
You'll find another way.
Kind of like bird-watching,
ain't it?
I wouldn't know.
You bored?
( sighs ):
I'm bored.
( chuckles )
So, I got a question.
I hear the killer completely
wiped down the crime scene.
So why do you think
he left his semen behind?
Could've worn a condom.
Well, before committing a crime,
a typical serial rapist
will often masturbate to his
perfect rape-murder fantasy.
Didn't wear a condom then,
didn't want to wear one
during the act.
Besides, the DNA isn't on file.
It wasn't much of a risk.
Litterbug.
CSIs don't mind the bugs.
If the DNA on this cup
matches the seminal DNA,
Grissom won't need a warrant.
We'll be making an arrest.
We're not unfit parents.
Please, we just want
to speak with our son.
We called the detective,
but no one will
tell us anything.
Right now your son's
under investigation.
What?
Yeah, the detective
asked him
if he wanted a parent
or advocate present
at the interrogation.
He's 14 years old,
so it's his right to say no.
But he's just a kid.
I mean,
he just lost his brother.
YVONNE:
Matt's sensitive.
He doesn't handle stress well.
If we-we-we could
just talk to him.
He may need
a change of clothes.
Were those his clothes
in the washer?
Yeah.
Okay, we'll see what we can do
about getting him
something to wear.
In the meantime,
if you could just
answer the question.
You want to know
about that homeless guy?
Yeah.
He's nuts.
He-he scared the boys
once or twice, but...
How did he scare them?
Ty saw him writing
something on the window.
Was it "Brat"?
Yeah.
I chased him away.
Matt...
cleaned off the window.
That would explain
the shoe impressions
outside the bedroom window.
You're thinking
that that guy
had something to do
with what happened?
Well, that's what
we're trying to find out.
( crying ):
Oh, God. I knew
we should've called the cops.
When was the last time
that you saw him?
MARTIN:
I jog through that
park every evening.
Um, he's got this, uh...
makeshift tent thing
set up by the
playground.
( crickets chirping )
What? Hey! Stop it!
Come on!
Get up!
Let me...
let me go!
( grunts):
Let go of me! Stop it!
Hey, what's
your name?
What?
Tell the gentlemen
your name.
Walter! My name is Walter!
Walter, that's
a nice blue sweater.
Where'd you get it?
What?
I said I like
your sweater--
where'd you get it?
It's mine!
Oh, it's yours?
Yes, this is my sweater!
Whose blood is it
on your sweater, Walter?
We're gonna give you
a nice warm place
to sleep tonight, partner.
STOKES:
Suspicion of murder.
WALTER:
No! No!
( screaming )
Easy with
the sweater.
It's evidence.
So, I processed the DNA
from the coffee cup,
and it turns out
that there were two
contributions on the
lip, which means that
your coffee shop recycles,
and not in the good way.
Gross.
Bad news
is that neither
of the contributions
is consistent with the semen
that was recovered
from the crime scene.
If Acheson didn't
rape Sue Stein,
what is his print doing
on the bedspread?
Well, I certainly
didn't kill anyone, and...
I do not know
how my fingerprint got there.
We don't think
that you did rape
or kill anyone.
We simply want to know
how your fingerprint
ended up at a murder
scene five years ago.
Look, Jesse,
we appreciate
you coming down here
voluntarily,
but if you clam up,
we're gonna have to file an
obstruction of justice charge,
and that's not good...
for you.
Let's make it easy
on yourself.
What were you doing
in Sue Stein's hotel room?
You won't believe me.
BRASS:
Try us.
I did go to see Sue
that night.
( whispers ):
Sue.
Come on, girl, wake up.
You just took off?
You didn't bother
to report a murder?
Ma'am, I... I got a record,
and I was on probation.
If I'd done all of that,
I'd have been...
suspect numero uno.
BRASS:
All right,
let's cut to the chase.
You were there
to sell her blow, right?
I don't need a lawyer, right?
I mean, it's off the record?
We're just having
a little chat here.
That's why she left
the door unlocked.
We'd been doing it that way
for years.
Whenever Sue came to town,
I always took care of her.
I'm really sorry.
She was my friend.
I wish I could be more help.
Stokes.
Hey, man.
What the hell
are you doing?
Are you trying
to screw with my case?
I'm just following
the evidence,
and it led me to
another suspect.
I think you're gonna
want to talk to him
in the interest
of justice.
What, are you trying
to help the defense now?
You know any good defense
is gonna bring up
a "rush to judgment"
here. Come on!
Chris, you put another
interviewed suspect
on your list.
It shows due diligence.
Let's go.
Your sweater's been analyzed,
Walter.
Found bloodstains from
a murdered boy on it.
It's not my sweater.
You already told me
it was yours.
Finders keepers.
It wasn't always
mine, though.
Where did you find it?
On a bench.
By the basketball courts.
( dog barking )
I was cold.
Hey, man...
if you're lying...
I'm not lying.
I'm not lying!
So when did you find it?
Yesterday.
No, um, a few days ago.
I don't remember.
Put him in lockup--
maybe it'll help
his memory.
Stokes...
I got a signed confession.
You got a bum
in a bloody sweater.
What are you gonna do
about it?
Hey, Catherine.
Yeah?
DNA finished up with the blue
sweater and I processed it.
Anything probative?
I ran it under the UV light
and out popped one
of those invisible
dry cleaner
ID stamps, you know?
Yeah?
I called the dry cleaner,
they gave me a name.
Mr. Hawkins,
is that your sweater?
Yeah...
it looks like
my sweater.
Where'd you find it?
Did you give it away?
No, but I haven't seen it
n a while, though. Why?
It's got Ty's blood on it.
Do I need a lawyer?
That's your call, sir.
You called me?
Yeah, Mia sent me
that wad of hair
that you pulled out
of the hotel drain.
It's coated in bleach.
I'm thinking the killer must've
poured the stuff down the drain.
Really compromised the trace.
That's it?
A compromised wad of hair?
No, uh, I called you
to discuss the bleach.
The hairy wad smelled
a bit woodsy to me.
Which is odd,
considering
it should only
smell like bleach.
You sniffed it?
That disgust you?
No, actually,
it's the first time
you've ever done
anything to impress me.
Anyway, um,
I analyzed the bleach.
It contains
a cedar additive.
Thought you'd want to know.
Thanks, David.
Sure, Gil.
MAN:
I'm more than happy to help you
in any way I can.
So when I got your phone call
about the scent of our bleach.
I figured you should
to talk to Lucy.
Lucy is our
head of housekeeping.
The guests sometimes complained
about the bleach smell
after we cleaned the bathrooms.
A few years ago,
I started adding
cedar chips to the bottles.
Makes it
smell better.
Lucy, who else has access
to your bleach?
Just the maids.
Are they all female?
Yes.
You park your carts
in the hallway when
you clean the room,
so anyone could have swiped
a bottle of bleach, right?
LUCY:
No. We've had
problems with theft,
towels mainly,
but now our maids
take their carts into the rooms.
Those your kids?
Yeah.
Two eldest
are at UNLV.
And the baby?
Jake.
Jake is, uh, six months old.
Is that your second wife?
Mm-hmm.
So you must
have had
your vasectomy reversed.
Why are we talking
about my vasectomy?
You also
have access to the bleach,
so you won't mind
if I take a DNA sample.
Look.
If word leaks out
that you took my DNA
and I'm a murder suspect,
I will never work
in hospitality again.
I'm sorry, the answer's no.
Anything else?
We'll be in touch.
So we've got three
suspects, three scenarios.
Yeah, Matt could have worn his
Dad's sweater when he killed Ty.
Dumped it in the park
during the night,
where Walter found it.
Or Dad could have worn it
and dumped it in the park.
Or this sweater
could have accidentally
been left in the park,
and Walter, the homeless guy,
could have
picked it up and worn it
when he entered
the house
through the screen
door and killed Ty.
But none of the evidence
goes to motive.
Not our problem
at the moment.
Let's just stay
focused on the sweater.
It's tied
to the victim and this scene.
We need to tie
it to the killer.
Hey, how tall
would you say Matt Hawkins?
About five feet, why?
Dad is... 6'2".
What about Walter?
Mmm... 5'10".
About Nick's height.
What you getting at?
Meet me in the garage
in half an hour.
GRISSOM:
Mr. Michaels, in my work
over the last 25 years,
I've come to understand
the kind of person
who's a rapist-killer.
Is that an accusation?
Well, a woman
was murdered
in your client's hotel.
He has a right
to hear our theory.
The killer
is clearly a psychopath.
He's killed more than once.
I'm sure that before
his first rape and murder
he fantasized about
it for years.
( muffled screams )
Quiet!
During that time, he engaged
in behavioral tryouts.
Stalking women
and attempting
to coerce them
sexually, each time
moving closer and closer
to the actual event.
( crying )
Shut up!
I believe
that after
you consummated
your first attack,
you felt excitement
greater than you anticipated.
Your only regret was that
she died too quickly.
But you took solace
in the knowledge that, uh,
you could do it again.
In fact, your
subsequent victim
had similar characteristics
to your first victim.
No! No! No!
Shut up!
This is a waste of time.
You see, what
differentiates a psychopath
from a "heat
of the moment" killer
is forethought.
And you thought
about this for a long time.
Thank you for
the fascinating seminar,
but you have
no evidence,
so we are free
to go.
Actually, I have some evidence.
What is this?
What's going on?
Mr. Michaels?
She can't... You can't do that.
Do what?
No, I know my rights.
Hey, shh.
The bitch broke into my car.
I don't remember
seeing a warrant, Ms. Sidle.
I don't have a warrant.
I was following a hunch.
Well, then you
just set my client free.
On the contrary.
Western Airlines
issues this exact
type of "wheelie" to all
its flight attendants.
Since Martha's
wheelie wasn't in
the hotel room, we thought
maybe the killer took it...
as a souvenir.
This particular
suit case...
( unzipping )
...is not Martha's
wheelie.
GRISSOM:
And now that we
know where to find it,
and we have your client on tape,
I bet you
we'll get
a warrant.
Thank you.
CATHERINE:
Okay, Warrick,
you are approximately
the height of Martin Hawkins.
Nick, you and the homeless
dude are about the same,
and Judy, you're close to Matt.
The table
is the same height
as Ty's bed-- 43 and half inches
from the floor
to the top of the mattress.
The white sweaters, which you
all look so adorable in,
are the same fabric
as the bloody one.
The pipes
are the same
diameter
as the wounds on Ty's face.
I want each of you
to take a whack at our victim.
Just like
Chuckie Cheese.
Whack-a-Mole.
( chuckles )
Uh, spatter up.
Judy,
your sweater-- killer.
Like I told him, I did it.
You want a medal for figuring
out what I already said?
CAVALIERE:
You never told me why.
Why's it matter, anyways?
( crying )
Go ahead.
Dad.
I want to know why.
Dad...
Why?
Damn it.
Ty looked up to you.
He... he loved you.
He told.
He told everyone!
That you wet the bed?
Shut up!
( crying ):
Dad... I'm sorry. I...
Oh, Matthew...
Hey.
You owe me an apology.
I'm sorry...
that you feel that way.