JEFFREY SINCLAIR:
I need you to answer
the same questions
I asked you at the first trial.
And I need you
to answer them honestly,
just as you did back then.
On December 20, 1999,
you responded to a call
at 2028 Boulder Highway.
Is that correct?
Yes.
Can you describe
the crime scene?
It was a hardware store.
I entered
through the back door.
The victim had been
severely beaten.
And our forensics determined
that the murder weapon
was a wrench.
Exhibit A.
Do you recognize this object?
Yes. I bagged
and processed this wrench.
My initials are on the seal.
Where did you find it?
It was in a toolbox
under the kitchen sink
at Garbett's Gourmet,
which is a restaurant
next to the crime scene.
Now, are you certain
that this wrench
was used to kill the victim?
Yes. We found trace blood
in the metal grooves.
And the DNA matched
the victim's.
What, if anything,
did you find on the handle?
We found the defendant,
Mr. Garbett's fingerprints.
We also found his prints
at the hardware store.
What else did you find
at the store?
GRISSOM:
Well, it appeared
that the killer tried
to cover his tracks
by setting a fire,
a lack of sufficient
combustibles may have
thwarted his effort.
Dr. Grissom.
Exhibit B.
Do you recognize this?
Yes.
It's a matchbook.
Did you find this
matchbook at the scene?
Dr. Grissom, just
so we can be clear,
this is the matchbook
that you found at
the crime scene.
Is that correct?
Your Honor, may I take
a short break?
Um... prosecution requests
a ten-minute recess.
The defense asks that Dr.
Grissom answer the question now.
Answer the question,
then we'll break.
Yes, this is the matchbook
I collected at the crime scene.
All right, we'll take
a ten-minute recess.
So, you wanna tell me
what this is all about?
Grissom, the defendant
was found guilty
at his first trial.
The only reason
we're back in court
is because his new lawyer
convinced some appellate judge
the original jury instructions
were faulty.
This has nothing to do
with the evidence.
( sighs )
There's a fingerprint
on this matchbook.
So?
I don't remember it.
It's not in my notes.
The evidence seal isn't broken.
If the print's there now,
it was there before.
GRISSOM:
The defendant's fingerprints
are all loop patterns.
This is an arch.
It's not a match.
This is not
the defendant's print.
Are you sure?
You know, when the
defense hears about this,
they are going to call
every other piece of
evidence into question.
I don't need to tell you
what that means.
I've given them
reasonable doubt.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
Heard we have a problem.
The Middle East
has a problem.
You missed a fingerprint
on a key piece of evidence.
I'm trying to keep
an open mind.
Then how do you
explain it?
At the moment, I can't.
Could someone have substituted
a different matchbook?
Well, the evidence seal
wasn't broken.
The matchbook's
appearance
is consistent with
the crime scene photos.
Since your original testimony
differs from the actual
physical evidence,
I thought I'd inform you
I've opened
a supervisory inquiry.
Well, that's good,
Conrad.
You know, I can't recall
a lab director
as expeditious
as you.
( gunshot, glass shatters )
You okay, Bobby?
Been better.
What the hell
happened?
I was about to test-fire
the Mac-10
when it accidentally
discharged.
Don't know how it happened.
Should've been more careful.
Whose, uh,
whose case you working?
Uh...
Sara Sidle and Greg Sanders.
Gun was found
next to a dead body
at an off-Strip parking lot.
All right.
Make sure you file a report.
Yes, sir.
Everybody back
to work.
Just keep me posted.
WILLOWS:
I remember this case.
The Garbetts
owned a restaurant
that was next door to the
victim's hardware store.
Max Larson owned
the private alleyway
that was behind
both places.
STOKES:
That's right.
He blocked the alleyway
with a Dumpster.
Yeah, the guy was a jerk.
Well, he claimed the
restaurant's delivery trucks
were clogging the alley.
BROWN:
Didn't the Garbetts sue
to have the Dumpster removed?
GRISSOM:
They lost.
There was no easement
in their title.
WILLOWS:
And without access
for deliveries,
the restaurant business
just dried up.
GRISSOM:
All the physical evidence
pointed to Garbett.
And according to the victim's
business partner,
Garbett had an argument
with the victim
the day before the murder.
Garbett's appeal didn't call
the forensics into question.
Why are we here?
I'm calling the forensics
into question.
I printed
this matchbook.
There was no print.
Take a look at it now.
WILLOWS:
Well, the fingerprint's
pink-- so you used Ninhydrin?
Mm-hmm.
Well, I know that
on some surfaces,
Ninhydrin can take time
to develop a print.
It was in, uh,
last May's Journal
of Forensic Sciences.
I remember the article.
But I can't remember whether
the variables in the test case
are consistent with ours.
Well, if the print matches
the suspect, who cares?
It doesn't match.
So, you and Warrick
take over the file--
make sure all of the other
evidence is beyond reproach.
Catherine, you supervise.
To avoid
any appearance
of impropriety,
I'm going to be hands off.
( knock on door )
Sofia.
You do know that the Journal's
back issues
are available on-line.
The lab has a password.
When you read from
a computer screen,
you have to lean in.
I like to lean back.
Therefore, I prefer
a hard copy.
Is this
what your looking for?
GRISSOM:
May.
Yes. Thank you.
News travels so fast
around here.
Ecklie travels fast.
Look, in case
you're not up-to-date
on your QA/QC memos,
I've been the lab's
quality control officer
for the past year.
Congratulations.
That job requires
a detail-oriented person.
Grissom,
I've been assigned
to your inquiry.
I just wanted
to give you the heads-up.
I'll be impartial.
I'd expect nothing less.
Margaritaville?
That is still
the lab's password, right?
Warrick,
in your field report,
you documented
the collection
of several hairs
near the body,
but DNA
never analyzed them.
Well, the DA
had sufficient evidence
and filed charges before
I could give the hair to Greg,
so I moved on
to another case.
Process the hairs now.
Yeah.
Catherine, do you remember
why you were late
to this crime scene?
Eddie had a gig
and you couldn't find
a baby-sitter.
Actually, I kind of
made that up.
Eddie did have a gig.
It ended early and he and I...
Well, let's just say
that not all my memories of him
are bad ones.
Which reminds me
you, at the time,
were going out with
that assistant manager
of the Flamingo.
Oh, Susan.
Boy, did she have it
bad for you.
She kept calling
while we were working the scene.
You had to shut your phone off.
Yeah, well, now she's VP
of Food Services,
so I get free steak and eggs
every Sunday morning.
Free steak and eggs
means she didn't know
about the flight attendant.
Does everyone know
my business around here?
WILLOWS:
Okay, Nicky, since you have
such a good memory,
why don't you explain
the unidentified prints
that you lifted
from the murder weapon.
I lifted
six prints off the wrench.
I ran them through I-AFIS.
Five were a match
to the suspect.
One was unidentified.
Now, at the time,
we all agreed
that that print was irrelevant,
because the wrench was found
in the common area.
Okay, well, we're going
to have to compare
that unidentified print
with this matchbook print.
Will do.
Hey, Catherine...
...we didn't do anything wrong
here.
I agree.
But the prosecution
may not see it that way.
Hey, how's Bobby doing?
Shaken, but working hard.
Trying to figure out
why the gun discharged.
ROBBINS:
Well, fortunately,
Bobby dodged his bullet--
unlike our victim.
C.O.D's a single gunshot wound
to the leg.
And it severed
the femoral artery.
We processed
the guy's jeans.
Tight GSR pattern
around the entrance hole.
SIDLE:
So, he was either shot
by someone at close range
who left the gun behind,
or it was self-inflicted.
Why would the shooter
leave the gun behind?
He probably wouldn't.
ROBBINS:
And most suicides
are through the torso
or through the head.
So if it wasn't intentional...
It was accidental.
Greg...
insert this rod
into the hole.
Trajectory is up
to down.
Consistent with a
self-inflicted, accidental
injury.
( gunshot )
( groaning )
Have you been able to I.D. him?
No wallet.
Prints didn't hit.
No relatives came forward.
So, I'm calling him
John Doe Number 124.
( beeping )
A perfect match.
Someone other
than the suspect
touched the matches
and the wrench.
The wrench was found
in a toolbox
in the suspect's restaurant.
The murder happened
after closing.
Who else had access
to that restaurant?
STOKES:
Mrs. Garbett.
It's, uh, Mrs. Katz now.
I remarried.
Oh, okay-- Mrs. Katz.
Duly noted.
Please, have a seat.
I appreciate you
coming down here
and meeting with me.
Look, my ex-husband
called me from jail.
I know about
the new trial.
But this case has
nothing to do with me.
Not anymore.
He got a life sentence.
The crime lab testified.
You think he's guilty?
( sighs )
Jason was a quiet man.
Bottled everything up.
In 25 years of marriage,
he raised his voice...
maybe... a dozen times.
But when he
expressed himself...
the neighborhood knew.
Mom, I got
your voice mail.
Keith.
What's going on?
Uh, Mr. Stokes is
with the crime lab.
Hi.
Look, we'll help
in any way we can.
What I'd really like to do
is get a list of anyone
who had access to that
restaurant five years ago.
KEITH:
Sure.
May I ask why?
Recent evidence
has come to light...
What evidence?
Oh, now that
I can't discuss.
My father's innocent.
My son has never stopped
believing in his father.
He has sacrificed
everything for Jason:
Moved back to Vegas,
hired a new attorney,
poured all his money
into the appeal.
So you weren't living in town
at the time of the murder?
No, I was living in L.A.
Oh, okay.
Look...
whatever you need from us...
Mom...?
Um...
I have some old records
back at the house.
I could send them over.
Yeah, that'd be great.
( Avril Lavigne singing
"Don't Tell Me" )
You're listening to music.
It was Greg's suggestion.
No, it's good.
Well, maybe not your
music taste, but
we'll work on that.
You have my DNA profile for
the hair sample I gave you?
No.
No? Do you need more time?
No... the sample you sent me
wasn't human...
so I sent it over
to Trace.
Maybe Hodges can tell you
something.
All right. Thank you.
And Mia, Avril's fine,
but if you really want to
experience musical heartache,
you should check out, uh...
Nina Simone.
( song resumes )
♪ ♪
Grissom, Judge Witherspoon
wants me in her chambers
first thing
in the morning.
She's going to demand
a full update, Gil.
I can't explain
the appearance
of the print
on the matchbook.
That's what I'm trying
to figure out.
You're making the lab look bad.
SINCLAIR:
Word has it you've
reopened the entire case.
An unexamined hair and
an unidentified print
on the murder weapon?
Grissom, did we make a mistake
and arrest the wrong guy?
I don't know.
BRASS:
Hey. We gotta talk.
Ecklie's used his hot line
to the sheriff.
The whole department
knows about the inquiry.
There's nothing I
can do about that.
Yeah, well, I want to
give you a heads-up,
'cause here's how
it's gonna break down:
In order to appear
objective,
Ecklie's gonna follow
Sofia's recommendations.
The problem is, she's
Acting Supervisor of Days,
so she needs Ecklie to
sign off to keep her gig.
And you think she'll say
whatever Ecklie wants.
Yeah. And this isn't just
about the Garbett case.
He's looking into
your whole team.
And your ability
to lead them.
Poor Conrad.
I hate to tell you, but
when it comes to politics,
he whips your ass.
So watch your back;
it's gonna get ugly.
Thanks.
HODGES:
The hair on the right
is a human hair.
The hair on the left
is from your five-
year-old crime scene.
Given the big fat medulla,
I'd say canine,
and given
its coarseness...
I'd say it could be a poodle
or a Portuguese Water Dog.
( laughing ):
What?! A Portuguese Water Dog.
Mm-hmm.
They were found on fishing
vessels in the 1800s.
Are you serious?
Warrick, I thought
you were following
it up with DNA.
I am.
The hairs got kicked to Trace.
HODGES:
Yeah, they're from a dog.
Very obvious
under the microscope.
I will find out if the
victim or suspect owned a dog.
I'm on it.
Thanks.
Ecklie was so pissed when
I told him about these hairs.
You told Ecklie?
Yeah. He's a friend.
I sent him a card
for his promotion.
The guy was very touched
by my thoughtfulness.
Oh, we all are.
Oh.
Are you finished
with the gun?
Yeah, I figured out
what caused that A.D.
Some garage gunsmith
tried to turn this baby
into a machine gun.
That is a big-time felony.
Not to mention
dangerous.
Here, take a look.
See, the trip has
been ground down,
which prevents the
bolt from locking back.
( click, whoosh )
( groaning loudly )
Vic never even
pulled the trigger.
Did you get an I.D.
off the serial number?
It's also ground down.
Nearly halfway
through the metal.
Well, I love a challenge.
Well, it's all yours.
STOKES:
The Garbetts' restaurant
employed six waiters,
two cooks, and a busboy.
All of whom would've
had access to the kitchen
and to the wrench.
Right: Garbett's ex-wife,
three of the waiters
and both cooks prints
were in I-AFIS because
of work cards,
but none was a match
to the mystery print.
And what about
the other four?
I ran their socials
to get their addresses.
I'll grab a uniform,
go bang on some doors.
Hi.
I'm Nick Stokes.
Good day, sir.
My name's Nick Stokes.
I'm with the
Las Vegas Crime Lab.
I'm reinvestigating
Max Larson's homicide.
I was hoping to get
your, uh, your fingerprints.
It would help eliminate you
as a suspect.
Thank you, ma'am.
Max didn't like dogs.
We don't allow them
in the store.
How about you, Mr. Reeba.
Do you down a dog?
No.
Mr. Brown, what's this about?
I'm sorry, I'm not at liberty
to discuss ongoing cases.
Look, I have a right to know.
Max was my business partner.
Well, all I can tell you
is that the defendant
was granted
a new trial.
Based on a friggin'
technicality.
I talked
to the D.A. myself.
The crime lab
is reviewing the
case file now.
Garbett killed Max.
I was right here when he tried
to shake us down.
If you don't move that
Dumpster, I swear,
I'm gonna kill you!
Judge says I'm in the right.
You can go to hell.
You're gonna regret this.
So tell me: how many customers
did you have tonight?
Hey, Rick...
what's a number less than one?
This isn't over.
I guess he could've
handled it better.
But Garbett's delivery trucks--
they were always blocking access
to our parking lot.
We complained-- he refused
to do anything about it,
so we exercised
our legal rights.
A judge rules
in our favor.
Two days later, Max is murdered.
Can you imagine killing
over an incident like this?
I've seen people kill
for a lot less, sir.
Mr. Reeba,
you and your partner were joint
owners of this property, right?
Yes.
With right of survivorship.
Correct.
And when he died,
you got it all,
isn't that right?
What are you getting at?
Nothing.
It's just a question.
( machine beeping )
Hi.
Video Spectral Analysis.
I want to see if I can
bring out the image
on the matchbook.
STOKES:
We didn't have this equipment
five years ago.
That's why
I'm doing it now.
How was the door-to-door?
STOKES:
Good exercise.
Everyone volunteered their
prints but... no match.
Warrick, just the
guy I wanted to see.
Ecklie, you know
I'm real busy...
Ah, it won't take long.
My office.
Uh... I'll cut to the chase.
Did Supervisor Grissom
instruct you
to analyze the hairs
you found
near Max Larson's body?
It was my job
to bring the hairs to DNA.
Did you?
Yes.
Five years ago.
No, yesterday.
Look, if there
was a problem...
Have a seat.
In my capacity
as Assistant Director,
I'm now privy
to personnel files.
Um...
You've done outstanding work
over the years, Warrick. Truly.
I see commendations
from detectives
and D.A.'s...
I also see
you have a gambling problem.
I had a gambling problem.
What's your point?
Well, it appears
Supervisor Grissom
counseled you appropriately.
( sighs )
That's correct.
So...
he gave you access to
departmental resources
to help you deal
with the problem?
No...
he helped me, uh...
by being a friend.
Good.
You've been a big help.
Thanks.
Hey.
This is, uh, confidential.
I don't have an office, so...
The inquiry into Grissom.
Just reviewing
all documentation.
Case identifiers,
analysts' initials...
Your responsibility
is to confirm
that all conclusions drawn
are supported by the data.
They are.
Excuse me?
I worked on this case.
The conclusions,
they are supported.
I assume that's
what you're finding?
Catherine...
I appreciate your interest,
but I think it's prudent
to reserve my findings
for the Assistant Director.
Right.
Neil, you got a minute?
I don't think I have any work pending
for you.
I need your expertise.
Matchbook print.
Everybody's
talking about it.
Well, good.
Scientific discoveries arise
through discourse.
Now...
Ninhydrin works by reacting
to one end of a protein chain
to form Ruhemann's purple...
Which makes
fingerprints visible.
Protein chains
are made up of a series
of amino acids,
sometimes a hundred units long.
But only one end of the
chain has the H-N-H...
The N-terminus.
It's the only part
of the protein molecule
that interacts with Ninhydrin.
But fingerprints are subjected
to bacterial degradation,
which causes the proteins
to break down
into smaller amino acids.
Upping the number of N-termini.
And making
the fingerprint more visible.
But because new fingerprints
are sometimes composed
of fully intact proteins,
you could spray Ninhydrin,
and not see a result
for months, yes?
Or in rare cases,
years-- depending on
the rate of degradation.
My matchbook print was
inside a plastic evidence bag.
That could affect the rate.
Let's see...
plastic...
plastic traps in heat
and humidity.
Bacteria would continue
to break down over time.
So theoretically, the bag was
acting as a humidifying chamber.
I'd say you were processing
a print in slow motion.
Thank you, Neil.
I'm confused.
Do we think the dead guy
bought a defective gun,
or was he selling a gun
he'd already modified?
Maybe he modified it
for his own use.
If that was the case,
then why would he need to file
down the serial numbers?
Good point.
Okay, so you take
the polishing compound,
and you rub it on the
obliterated serial number.
And then you hit the spot
with the wheel
until it's mirror smooth.
Fry's Reagent.
It differentially eats away
at the compressed area.
SANDERS:
To expose the denser metal
of the serial number.
Take a look.
SANDERS:
Pop goes the serial number!
Run it through NCIC
and local pawn shops.
See if we can get an address.
All right.
ECKLIE:
How you doing, Greg?
Excuse me.
Sara.
You got a minute?
I guess.
Flitz's Compound.
I'm sure you're not polishing
your jewelry in the lab.
That would be unauthorized.
What can I do for you?
As you know,
it's my job
to review everyone's file.
I just want to make sure
you finished up with
your PEAP counselor.
That's none of your business,
Ecklie.
Well, not only
is it my business,
but I plan to speak
with your supervisor.
About what?
You have updated him, right?
Yeah, yeah, we've had an
abbreviated conversation.
I'm doing fine.
I completed my required number
of sessions months ago.
Huh. Grissom failed to note that
conversation in your file.
Um...
But I'll take care of it.
All right.
Thanks.
Expose the matchbook to white,
and that covers the spectrum.
I'll bring out
the illuminants
and contrast.
Rotate it 180.
"Club PCH."
"Los Angeles."
Is that probative?
Maybe.
Defendant's son lived in L.A.
So I did a background check
on Keith Garbett.
He has no record.
Moved to California
two years before the murder.
He opened a veterinary practice
in Encino.
He was a veterinarian?
Didn't I just say that?
We found some dog hairs
at the crime scene.
Out of context,
it didn't really
mean anything.
Well, now it does.
Mr. Stokes.
Keith.
Well, tell me you've
got some good news.
Dad's lawyer says the
case could get tossed.
I'm Detective Jim Brass,
Las Vegas Police.
We'd like to ask you
a couple questions.
Sure.
You ever been to Club PCH?
I did some clubbing in my 20's.
What does this have to do
with the investigation?
Keith, what we'd really like
to go ahead and do
is get a set
of your fingerprints,
if we could. Okay?
Why?
You know, I'm sorry, but
I don't exactly trust you guys.
You destroyed my family.
You let my dad rot in jail
for five years,
and now you're coming after me?
No way. Forget it.
I thought that went well.
There's more than one way
to get his prints.
Trash on the curb--
public property, right?
Don't need a warrant.
This conversation is
on the record.
Part of the official inquiry
into the Max Larson case.
Understood.
Five years ago,
were you part of a team
that processed a homicide
at 2028 Boulder Highway?
You know I was.
Specifically, what tasks
did Supervisor Grissom
assign to you?
Gil doesn't micromanage.
We all know
what needs to be done.
I photo-documented the scene,
I collected blood evidence,
and I brought the charred
newspaper to Trace.
In the analysis phase,
did Grissom review
your reports with you?
Are you asking if he performed
a supervisory review?
It's policy.
He must have.
I'm sure he did.
Are you doing all this
for the sake of the lab
or to indict Grissom?
Catherine,
there are a number
of talented CSIs, like yourself,
who have put in
to be supervisors.
I just want to make sure
the right people
are in the right place.
About my request--
I really would
like to supervise days.
Right. You're a single mother.
Better hours.
And I bet you could use
the extra cash.
No, this promotion isn't
about money.
Must be nice to be
independently wealthy.
We're done here, right?
Yeah.
Vacuum metal deposition.
Sometimes the evidence isn't
in the bag... it's on it.
( hissing )
WILLOWS:
Comparing unknown
matchbook print
to garbage bag print.
Game, set...
Match.
We're closed.
Hey, did you hear me?
I said we're closed.
Hey... Hey!
It wasn't my restaurant.
It wasn't my problem.
You lied to us.
Said you were living in L.A.
at the time
of the murder.
WILLOWS:
But while your parents
were in court,
suing to have
that Dumpster removed,
you were running
the restaurant.
In fact, you signed
the vendor checks that week.
STOKES:
They were in a box
of records
your mother sent over.
You saw the business
was going under.
Their marriage
was in trouble.
And when the judge ruled
against them, you snapped.
The evidence is
circumstantial at best.
WILLOWS:
You can play it
that way.
It's fine with us.
You and your father
can both stand trial.
I mean, after all, he was
the one who had motive.
He threatened Larson.
His prints were on the wrench.
You think the D.A. is
going to try two people
for the same crime?
STOKES:
Oh, yes, ma'am.
At minimum,
they're looking
at conspiracy.
WILLOWS:
As far as we know, they could've
been in it together.
It's easier to overpower a guy
when it's two against one.
Yeah, but I don't think
it went down that way.
After your father
was convicted,
you gave up on your
veterinary practice.
Moved back to Vegas--
spent every last dime you had
on his defense.
Now, that tells me you had
a guilty conscience.
It should tell you
that I love my father.
Your father spent the last
five years in prison, man.
If you love him so much,
why don't you tell the truth.
Set him free.
My father had nothing
to do with it.
Keith...
I never thought that
they would
convict an innocent man.
So... I kept quiet.
To protect yourself.
ECKLIE:
We'll convene in my office
at the end of your shift.
Regarding what?
This case is over.
Don't be late.
Hey.
What's going on?
Dispatch said to meet you here.
Well, three days ago
we found a John Doe
who was shot to death
in an abandoned
parking lot off Strip.
Uh, there was a Mac-10
near the body.
Gun is registered
to a Paul Turlock,
who happens to be
the owner of the house.
Oh, so you want to see
if Paul Turlock
and John Doe are
one and the same.
Yeah.
Okay.
Odds are looking
pretty good so far.
Police! Anybody here?
♪ ♪
Sara.
Any of these
look like your guy?
Guy on the end
with the "Rita" tattoo.
Think Rita's his mom
or his girlfriend?
If it's not crossed out,
it's definitely his mom.
Mac in the box.
Five of them.
Serials obliterated.
Files and grinding stone.
It's all the tools needed
to convert a semi into an auto
and then cover your tracks.
Each modified weapon's
a separate count.
Each filed-off
serial number's
a separate count.
This guy was looking
at ten felonies.
Actually, he already got
the death penalty.
( beep )
( on answering machine ):
Hey, Paulie,
we, uh, liked what we saw.
Deal's a go.
Five large for five units.
I'll call youse back
to arrange a time.
( beep )
Paulie. 9:00 p.m. Monday.
That's tonight.
"We liked what we saw"?
That tells me that
Paulie's already met
with the buyers--
probably to show them
the prototype of the Mac-10.
Maybe they met at the parking
lot where we found the body.
You know, most likely
they'd hook up
at the same location
to complete the sale.
Buyers don't know he's dead.
Lucky for us.
Hell of a job on
the Larson case, Nick.
If it weren't for you,
the son would've walked.
It was a team effort.
Team effort?
Just like the Westanson case,
right?
Last year,
that woman who burned
to ashes in a barrel
of diesel fuel.
Yeah. Yeah, I'm familiar
with the case, Conrad.
I reviewed Grissom's report.
It seems to me
that you were a...
one-man CSI machine.
( chuckles )
Grissom rejected
Fay Minden's testimony,
but not you.
No, Grissom
allowed me
to pursue a new lead,
under his supervision.
Did he offer you any other CSIs
as support staff?
D-Don't worry
about it.
I respect your independence.
Anyway, good work.
( door closes )
( siren wailing )
Keep your hands up.
No sudden moves.
ATF. I'm an agent.
Just keep your hands
where I can see 'em,
and you won't get hurt.
Special Agent John Calder, ATF.
He's an undercover agent.
I don't believe this.
You're involved in a buy
bust for some firearms?
CALDER:
You boys burned us bad.
We were gonna make
an arrest tonight.
SIDLE:
Suspect's name is Paul Turlock?
Yeah.
Mr. Turlock A.D.'d
a Mac into his femoral artery.
You guys are four days too late.
Wrap it up, boys,
let's go home.
If I understand you correctly,
the latent fingerprint
on the matchbook...
continued to process itself
after you were finished.
Theoretically, yes.
As I know you are aware,
I've asked Sofia
to review your handling
of the Max Larson
homicide.
Did Supervisor Grissom
violate any procedures
in mishandling the evidence?
I don't believe
he mishandled anything.
He followed
laboratory protocol,
and when he saw
that the evidence
didn't correspond
to his records, he
notified the D.A.
and recused himself
from case review.
Are you saying that, uh,
his handling of the discovery
of new evidence
while on the stand
is within our protocols?
As it applies to this case, yes.
In the, uh... in the process
of investigating this case,
your ability to supervise
has come into question.
Isn't that a little beyond
the scope of this inquiry?
Again, we have
no evidence that
Grissom violated
any protocols or proc...
Thank you for your input.
Okay, Conrad,
what do you got?
Let's hear it.
Well, taken individually,
there's nothing specific
that warrants
disciplinary action.
However,
my investigation
has led me to question
the effectiveness of your team
and your ability to lead it.
I'm breaking you guys up.
Excuse me?
I've already spoken
with the director.
Staff assignments
are under my purview.
Effective immediately,
Catherine Willows
will be promoted
to swing shift supervisor...
Wait a minute,
Catherine applied for days.
I do what's best for the lab.
I've decided to move
the swing shift supervisor
to days...
I've been
the acting supervisor
of days
for the past month-- I believe
I've proven myself capable.
Warrick Brown and Nick Stokes
will report to Catherine.
Greg Sanders,
pending his proficiency,
Sara Sidle and Sofia
will report to you.
You're demoting me.
I think
you and Grissom
suit each other.
Why are you doing this?
There's been a chronic lack
of supervision
on the graveyard shift.
Your people have been
covering for you, Gil.
For your shortcomings.
Before your mismanagement
jeopardizes this lab,
I'm rectifying the situation.
( chuckles )
My decision is final.
He kind of talked
to all of us.
It was more like he
ambushed all of us.
Real sorry, Grissom.
There's no reason to be.
Look, Ecklie doesn't
have a scientific
bone in his body.
He starts with
the answers he wants
and then devises
the questions to get them.
This sucks.
This guy has been kissing ass
all his life,
he's trying to tell me--
he's trying to tell us
what makes a good supervisor.
What makes a good team?
Well, if a team gets used
to doing things a certain way
just because that's the way
they've always done them,
then they start to lose
their effectiveness.
Oh, come on.
You don't really believe that.
No. I believe that the longer
a team works together,
the stronger they become.
But I'm not in
charge of the lab,
nor would I want to be.
I got this--
that's the kind of cash
I'm bringing down
right now.
( Brown chuckles )
I always knew
there'd come a time
when we weren't, uh,
working together anymore.
I just didn't think it'd be
under these circumstances.
( phone rings )
Brown.
Okay. All right.
No, I'll tell Nick.
We'll see you there.
Uh, congrats, by the way.
All right.
My new supervisor.
Catherine?
Yeah.
Good.
Well,
I got to get some rest.
Swing shift starts at 4:00
in the afternoon.
That's a big change.
Heracleitus once said,
"It is in changing
that we find purpose."
Well, thanks to you,
this job,
I already know my purpose.