♪ ♪
(line ringing)
(knocking softly)
Have a seat.
(recording):
This is Grissom.
How's the arm?
Please leave a detailed message
after the tone.
Fractured in two places.
(machine beeps)
Gil, Conrad again.
Um... message
number three.
Call me back please.
It's feeling better?
Yeah.
Good.
(drums fingers on desk)
So, you must know where he is.
Actually, I don't.
Really?
Okay, um...
Look, I don't want to play
any games here.
This is as difficult for me
as it is for you.
(closes door)
So let's just, uh,
get this over with, shall we?
Okay then, uh, this is an
administrative inquiry.
You and your supervisor
were in direct violation
of lab policy...
"Are."
"Are" in direct violation
of Lab policy
which states that members
of the same forensic team
may not engage
in a romantic relationship.
So when did you and
Supervisor Grissom
begin your
relationship?
We've always had a relationship.
I mean when did
you become intimate?
Two years ago.
I think
it was a Sunday.
♪ ♪
(object skipping along pavement)
(vehicle approaching)
(wind whistling)
HOLSTEIN:
Sagebrush Valley High School.
The Cobras.
He looks like he could
still be in high school.
Boy, football's gotten
a lot more brutal
since my playing days.
Yeah, where's the rest of
him, still on the field?
There's no high school football
fields around here anyway.
What do you think, Grissom?
"Ichabod was horror-struck
on perceiving
that he was headless.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
(phone ringing)
(indistinct radio transmission)
Blood pool tells me the helmet
must've been here for a while.
Vehicle tire rolled through it.
Helmet has black abrasions
on it
consistent with being hit
by a tire.
Probably got pinballed
down the road.
I checked with Traffic.
No reports of any traffic
accidents near here.
Uh, Holstein's getting
an absentee list
from the high school.
Head's over there.
Blood trail leads up from here.
We follow the blood.
He say anything about
what's happening with Sara?
No.
(camera shutter clicking)
Hey, did Sara ever
say anything to you
about her and Grissom?
Not in so many words.
So you knew about
the two of them?
Yeah.
(scoffs)
(camera shutter clicking)
Hey!
Where's the uniform?
If he's not a player,
what's with the helmet?
SANDERS:
Maybe he's a rabid fan.
There were all kinds
of high school games
last night.
Where's his hand?
Got to be around here somewhere.
(grunting)
The hand--
where did you find it?
20 yards away,
two hours later.
ROBBINS:
David, he doesn't
look prepped.
What's taking so long?
I can't get the helmet off.
I better get this ten-card
to Mandy right away.
You hold the helmet.
Hold it.
(squishing sound)
His face looks like hamburger.
(paper rustling)
I found the same black powder
on his clothes.
Hey, Mandy.
I got a ten-card
on our John Doe.
Well, let's see if it matches
the safe-kit
that Holstein brought in.
Only have one more kid
unaccounted for
at that high school.
Hey, if you had a kid,
would you collect
a safe-kit on them?
Why not?
It's better to be prepared.
Think of it
as a cheap insurance policy.
It's just a print card,
a cheek swab and a photo.
Then go to bed every night
hoping you don't have to use it.
Mm... well, there's a match.
Your John Doe
is Vincent Bartley.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Okay, good.
Thanks.
You're welcome.
Well, nothing.
I mean, it was dark.
It was really dark.
BROWN:
One minute we're married,
and the next...
You know what?
Good for you.
Divorces should
be like Band-Aids,
one quick yank and done.
BROWN:
You think?
Oh, what do I know?
Eddie and I stayed together
way too long.
Every decision was
an act of Congress.
It's the end of an era,
ladies and gentlemen.
Hampton Huxley,
publisher of Hux magazine--
where boys became men,
and men became
more manly-- has died.
That magazine
got me through Vietnam.
Oh, that would explains
the lookers out front.
They were Kitties.
Yes, Kitties, indeed.
He was dining with a couple
of them when he bought the farm.
Miss Summer
and Miss Winter, I believe.
Every male in the
Phillips family
gets a lifetime
subscription to Hux
for his Bar Mitzvah.
I guess my sons will have
to settle for a Cross pen.
I'm sure the magazine
will go on without him, Dave.
What are we looking at?
Puncture wound.
Um... no abrasion ring.
But I can reapproximate
the skin.
So it's probably not a gunshot.
Stabbing?
Maybe. Right through the temple,
into the brain.
Be lights out in seconds.
It's a crowded restaurant.
Somebody must have seen
something.
Not exactly.
Welcome to
the latest fad.
Dining in the dark.
Waiters are blind.
No one sees anything.
Piece of cake, huh?
(footfalls)
WILLOWS:
Did he just leave?
BROWN:
I think so.
PHILLIPS:
Guys?
I have a dead body here.
WOMAN:
Dining should be an experience,
like opera or art.
It should feed the soul
as well as the belly.
You should smell it, touch it
and let it rest on your tongue.
I'm selling sensuality here.
I encourage eating
with your hands.
Texture is crucial.
The salty, meaty flesh
of lobster
drenched in creamy,
clarified French butter.
The pulpy seeded flesh
and firm skin of a fresh fig
dipped in honey.
The tongue understands
four major taste groups--
salty, sweet, sour, bitter--
and has over 10,000 taste buds,
each with a direct connection
to the pleasure center
of the brain,
triggering endorphins.
The anticipation and the
release of eating good food
is chemically quite similar
to getting high on drugs.
And apparently
just as dangerous.
So tell me
what happened.
I don't know.
Each one of the waiters
has one of those clickers.
If there's an emergency,
the houselights come up
and a red light goes off
in the kitchen.
WOMAN:
Somebody help!
(alarm buzzing)
(screaming)
Help! Help him!
Are you okay?
WOMAN:
Hux!
Call 9-1-1.
Oh, so you didn't see anything?
I'm in the kitchen.
I have two sittings a
night, at 7:00 and 10:00,
average 25 heads,
ten courses per.
I have no time to pee.
April was here...
and Huxley was here.
(instrument beeps)
BROWN:
Okay.
Got blood on the chair.
Blood on the tablecloth.
Blood drops on the floor,
leading away from Hux's chair.
Stab him. Extract the weapon.
Drip, drip, drip.
And they end here.
Near Ms. Shasta.
WOMAN:
Shasta McCloud--
big "M," little "c,"
big "C," plus "loud."
McCloud.
(chuckles)
On TV, they never show anyone
bleeding from a heart attack.
Is that what
you think happened?
Well, yeah. I mean, all
that Prevalis and diet soda.
I just figured...
April, shh!
He was an animal
until the day he died, sir.
Uh-huh.
Wait a minute.
What did happen?
Well-Well, you're
the one with blood on you.
Maybe you can tell me.
I thought
he just fell asleep
like he always does
at the end of meals.
APRIL:
Come on! Wake up, Huxey.
(in animated voice):
Wake up, Huxey.
Wake up, Huxey-Hux.
Come on, it's time to go.
Meow, meow!
(kissing noises)
(whimpering)
Waiter!
Emergency!
April?
April, what's wrong?!
Call 9-1-1!
Help!
April! April!
Michael here.
Code red!
(screaming)
Help! Help us!
Okay. Um, look, I'm going
to need to take your sweater.
Yeah, like I haven't
heard that one before.
(giggles)
No. No, I don't mean
right now.
No, I mean, I... I'll need
to take it before I go.
You know, later, when I,
when I leave,
I have to take
your sweater then.
Mr. Bartley?
Matt. I'm Vincent's brother.
I'm... Nick.
Stokes.
Uh...
You don't need
to say it.
I knew when the detective
asked me for that safe-kit
that it was going to be Vinnie.
Shouldn't I be talking
to your parents?
Don't have any parents.
Mom skipped out
when we were little,
and Dad died a
couple years ago.
It's just the two of us.
Matt...
your brother wasn't
on the football team,
but when we found him,
he was wearing
a football helmet.
Why is that?
It was my old helmet.
Is that how you got injured?
No.
It was the last day
of spring break, and...
I was wasted.
Like a dumb-ass,
I dove into the Tangiers
wave pool headfirst.
Fractured my T-1 vertebra.
So why the helmet?
Well, I was a pretty good
football player.
He was proud of that.
That and my dad's dragon belt.
He got it when he
was in the service.
Vinnie wears
it every day.
It's just something
that he has to hold onto...
(voice breaks) ...to deal with.
(softly):
Yeah.
You know, one of these could've
been the murder weapon.
It's approximate
in size and shape.
And everybody had one.
Well, something dripped over
here that is not blood.
Well, could've been whatever
food was on the skewers.
ALS will pick up anything
that's fatty or dairy-based.
Could you turn off the
lights for a second?
(lights click off)
(Willows chuckles)
I'm sorry, but this is a stupid
idea for a restaurant.
I need to see what I'm eating.
BROWN:
I can see just fine.
Where are you?
Right here.
Oh.
(lights click on)
Hi.
Hello.
Night vision goggles?
Yeah, someone
left these behind.
Kind of defeats the purpose
of dining in the dark.
Unless you don't come
here for the food.
(indistinct voices)
BROWN:
Mr. Nivens.
Are these yours?
I'll take that as a "yes."
Wait, wait... I
didn't kill anyone.
Then why would your bring
military-grade,
night vision goggles
to the restaurant?
A hunch.
(man and woman
moaning erotically)
MAN:
Yeah.
Oh, that's so good.
Tastes so good
NIVENS:
Sweetheart, you want to try
some of my steak?
WOMAN:
No, thanks.
I'm all good.
Yeah...
(giggles)
Mmm...
Always be suspicious
when your wife wants
to dine in the dark
with another couple.
You brought night vision goggles
to spy on me during dinner?
Damn right.
(sighs)
Millions of tires
wear out ever year.
You ever wonder where
all that rubber dust goes?
No, I don't.
The black powder trace you found
in your victim's clothing
was tire rubber.
It's not surprising.
we found the body on
the side of the highway.
Of course
you would expect that.
However, I did find some very
interesting type of rubber.
Okay, Hodges, dazzle me.
Truck tires have 27% isoprene
and 14% neoprene.
That's what makes
them so hard.
Passenger tires have a lower
isoprene-to-neoprene ratio,
but they also have silica
for fuel economy
and wet traction.
Go-cart tires, or "slicks,"
to those in the know,
have much higher levels
of carbon black and oil,
resulting in extremely
high traction.
Guess I better
get my go-cart on.
You know,
just so you know,
I'm a bit of go-cart
enthusiast myself.
Oh, uh...
that's awesome.
Have you seen this guy before?
Day before yesterday.
Day before that,
and the day before that.
Oh, man,
did he get in trouble?
Are these the
race stats?
Uh-huh.
You keep record of them?
Yeah, all in here.
People ask for them every day
like they're
some sort of trophy.
Could you print out
Vincent Bartley's trophy
from the last time
he was here?
Yeah. But I'm not
getting him in trouble, am I?
No.
No, not really.
You know, when I was a kid,
we used to make these things
out of lunch trays
and old lawn mower engines.
When I was kid,
I used to make bombs,
and origami.
Oh.
"Vinnie Vroom."
Won all three of his races.
Beat out a guy named "Hot Rod."
Vinnie ran
circles around him.
♪ ♪
Yes.
Yes. Yes, is
that all you got?
Is that all you got?
Rodney went from being A-Rod
to being No-Rod.
Hey, there he is,
right there.
Aw, come on.
Hey, if you guys want to race,
then you guys have
to wear dresses, huh?
Get your skill
up, all right.
I need some
competition here.
Hot Rod!
(growls)
Get out of the truck!
Get out of the truck now!
Get out of
the truck now!
Nothing says
"I'm guilty"
like running from the cops,
dumb-ass.
Give me his wallet.
Rodney Banks.
We're with the Vegas Crime Lab,
Mr. Banks.
Hey, I didn't do nothing.
You got quite a mess here, Rod.
Mind if I take a look?
Where'd you get that belt?
I don't know.
Where?
Blood.
Looks like things just got
a lot hotter for you, Rod.
(camera shutter clicks)
All skewers accounted for,
none of them bloody.
We've got a
high-profile dead guy
in a locked-room
situation,
with 16 diners
and three blind waiters.
Give me something.
How about a Band-Aid
with petals?
It's not a Band-Aid.
It's a nipple flower.
What's it doing at a table
with four guys?
MAN:
Can I go to the bathroom?
Please, please, please?!
Again?
Yes, sir.
Yeah, okay.
(men laughing)
BRASS:
Okay.
What's so funny?
(laughing):
We slipped a laxative
in his beer in the dark.
It's his sixth trip
to the can.
It's freakin'
hilarious.
What are you guys,
like 12 years old?
Oh, hey, hey, Curly.
How come you're so pretty
in pink?
Huh?
(laughs)
MAN:
Breast exam.
(men erupt in laughter)
You know, doctors
without boundaries,
if you know what I mean.
(laughter,
piano playing soft melody)
You guys, come here.
It's total darkness.
There's two Kitties.
(grunting):
That's four...
They're all up for grabs!
I'm going on a
mission of mercy.
♪ ♪
Who is that?
Hux?
Stop it.
Save it for later.
What are you
talking about?
That's not you, Hux?
Somebody's touching me!
Sweet mother.
Guys, they're real--
both of them!
Waiter?
Waiter, we have a
problem over here.
(laughing)
Yeah, I lead Mr. Manducci
back to his seat.
He and his brothers had
had quite a bit to drink.
So it was the blind
leading the drunk, huh?
I could do it
with my eyes closed.
Well, did you, did you
hear anything unusual?
No. Everyone seemed to be having
a good time.
Until the woman
in the fuzzy dress shrieked.
I found Mr. Huxley
slumped forward.
Checked for a pulse,
and he didn't have one,
so I turned on
the emergency lights.
Then she really screamed.
Is she pretty?
She had
a pretty girl scream.
BRASS:
Oh, man.
She's a Huxley Kitty.
She's gorgeous.
Hey, uh...
Let me ask
you something.
Did you wash your hands?
Force of habit; I'm sorry.
Waiter.
Okay, we're going to have
to take your prints, okay?
Sure.
We're going to walk,
straight ahead.
Looks like there was
some kind of struggle.
Sticky.
What do you
think it is?
(sniffs)
MAN:
Honey?
The detective
needs to ask us some questions.
Hi, Nanci Katz.
Soon to be Ellis.
(giggles)
I'm Jim Brass.
Yes.
So, what happened, Nanci?
Oh, um... ask him.
Oh, uh, well, I-I thought
it would be romantic...
NANCI:
Mmm.
I have not ever tasted
a fig this juicy.
Oh, they're so good.
Mmm.
It's like they're, it's like,
it's better than the newtons.
Mmm. It's so
much better.
Oh, God!
Baby, are you okay?
Yeah, um...
What happened?
Yeah. Uh... a thing...
I'm, uh, okay.
It's Michael here.
Is... is everyone
all right?
Oh, uh, yeah.
Michael, I'm just...
I'm trying to get something
going here.
Oh, no problem, sir.
I'll leave you
two alone.
Okay.
Uh, baby, where's your...
Yeah?
Where's your hand?
(gasps)
Ever since I met you,
I've known
I wanted to ask you
this question.
Yeah.
One, two, three.
Would you be my wife?
Will you marry me?
(laughing):
Yes. Yes.
Oh, my gosh.
I can't even see it,
but it feels big.
The ring, I mean.
Sure, yeah.
Yes! Yes!
BRASS:
Oh.
Congratulations.
So how'd you bump your noggin?
It was dark; nobody, could see.
I wanted to say yes.
(chuckles)
Loud and clear.
There's a lot of metal
under those tables.
There really is, yeah.
Way too much.
It's not safe.
I bet.
HOLSTEIN:
Losing the race
was just the beginning.
Then, you killed him,
cut his body up.
and dumped it
on the side of the road.
Whoa, man.
I swear I didn't
kill anybody.
Or I didn't cut
anybody up or dump 'em.
All I did was ask
him for a rematch...
off the track, where
it really counts.
(tires screeching)
(car horn honking)
(horn honking)
(laughing):
Yeah!
(hoots)
So your statement is he just
spontaneously lost his head?
Yeah.
You know, one minute,
he's staring at me.
The next, I look back,
and the Headless Horseman
is driving his cart.
And then what happened?
So why you just didn't
ditch the carts?
Christin, that...
that girl at the track,
she let us sneak out with them.
You know, my
life was turning
into a horror movie-- I didn't
want to bring her
in on it.
You've been dodging me;
it's time to talk.
Gil, nobody wants to
hear about your love
life less than I do,
but since you didn't handle
this right, I have to take
a formal statement.
Should've been a conversation
between friends.
I mean, we could've found
some way around this.
Catherine could have done
Sara's evaluations.
Why didn't you just tell me?
We didn't want you to know.
Don't most women like the world
to know they're dating someone?
Where do you get your
information about women, Conrad?
Okay, so, when did you two,
you know?
Nine years ago.
You know what?
You two need to get
your stories straight.
(scribbles)
♪ ♪
There's road gravel
embedded in all these tires.
Yeah, but no visible blood
on that one.
Got a worn area
on this front bumper.
Some brown trace.
Same goes for the rear
of that one.
Well, if it turns out
to be leather,
it would confirm
Hot Rod's story that he
towed the second cart back
using Vinnie's belt.
Got what looks like...
blood on this wheel well.
This is the victim's cart.
Must have been movin'
when his head popped off.
Well, another one
for the scrapbook.
Boy, he looks different
without hair.
Never knew he wore a toupee.
Oh, uh, it had
something sticky on it,
so I bagged it for Trace.
But if you want, we could put
it back on for the photo op.
No, that's okay;
let's get to cutting.
(saw whirring)
ROBBINS:
Embedded horizontally
in the parenchyma
of the right temporal lobe
is a linear, silver-toned,
metal tube
that tapers to a point.
And in this case, David,
the pen may be mightier
than the sword.
BRASS:
Okay.
Okay, that
pen's not mine.
(chuckling):
Yeah. Nice try, sweetheart.
(sighs)
Excuse me.
Can I be Lucy Logic for a bit?
First of all, that
purse is designer.
There's no way I'm
ruining it with ink.
Second of all, I know
where my bread is buttered.
Hux was my meal ticket--
kill him, go hungry.
Unless you're in the will.
(both laugh, scoff)
Kitties don't get in the will.
Besides, if I had touched
that thing,
wouldn't I have ink
on my hands?
Hmm.
Whoever did it
ditched the pen in my bag.
It was on the back of my chair
the whole time.
It could have been anyone.
What about the guy
who assaulted me?
SHASTA:
Look, if you really
want a suspect,
you need to check out
little miss chef lady.
Little miss chef lady?
Why is that?
Hello.
Duh, she's...
Winter Issue?
1995.
You certainly weren't hiding
anything back then.
Hmm?
Ms. Sanchez, according
to your fellow Kitties,
you and Huxley
had a falling out.
It's curious that you
didn't mention that.
I didn't mention it,
because it's ancient history.
12 years ago, a misogynist
told me I should eat less.
And today, I now have a hot
restaurant on the Strip
and two contracts for
spots in L.A. and Chicago.
"Food Seduction"
is a best-seller.
I think I won that
battle already.
So, did you and Huxley speak
to each other last night?
His reservation was
booked under a pseudonym.
I didn't even
know he was there.
Mr. Brass,
do you know why
I started my restaurant?
No. Tell me.
Because I fell in love
with a blind man.
He would turn off the lights
and feed me.
When you deprive one sense,
other senses are heightened.
My only focus was on my tongue.
It was brilliant.
And then he died.
And this restaurant
is an homage to him.
To our love affair.
How nice for you.
I don't mean to be crude,
but a murder is,
quite frankly,
bad for business.
(paper rustling)
(typing)
♪ ♪
(computer trilling)
(paper rustling)
Hey.
So, Huxley had
honey on his hairpiece,
ink in his brain
and blood all over.
There were three people
who had honey on their hands:
the frisky couple
and Michael.
Two people who had blood
on their clothing:
April and Michael.
And there was a total of five
people moving around the room:
two Manducci brothers
and all three waiters.
Now, that's a lot of lists
for Michael to turn up on.
He does work there,
so there's reason for it, but...
Well, there's no
reason for this.
Michael's print in
ink, on a napkin.
What would he have
against Huxley?
His prints hit back
to an old work card.
The guy used to be a chef.
A blind chef?
He lost his sight
a few years back.
But before that,
guess who was his sous-chef?
"The man knew his way
around a kitchen,
"and his way into my heart.
"Michael would spend hours
teaching me,
feeding me... loving me."
So, you're the dead guy?
She seduces me,
steals my recipes, my
ideas, my investors.
And then she hires me
as a freaking waiter.
Night after night,
I listen to her
tell stories
of the tragic love affair,
of the poor, dead blind guy.
Last night,
I finally confronted her.
I deserve a piece of the action.
At $200 a head,
you're clearing at least
$1,000 in tips at night.
That's a lot of action
for a blind man.
I made you.
You're fired.
We're done.
But why kill Huxley?
Why not just her?
I'm blind. She's not.
But in that dining room,
everybody else is blind, too.
And when Huxley walked
in with his Kitties,
it was like a sign
from the gods.
I knew I could destroy
her and the restaurant.
I waited till
the oyster course.
The shells clanging,
and slurping,
the "oohing," the "aahing,"
I knew it would cover
any noise I was going to make.
(gasps)
I wanted her rotting in jail,
eating bologna sandwiches.
If you wanted to frame Pippa,
why did you plant the pen
in Shasta's purse?
I tell everyone to put
their purses and jackets
on the back of the chairs,
so I knew exactly
where her purse was.
Old cat frames young Kitty.
Kind of perfect.
SANDERS:
We found high velocity
blood spatter
inside the rear wheel well
of the victim's cart,
which means he lost
his head at high speed.
So how did Hot Rod
decapitate Vinnie
while racing down a highway
at 60 miles an hour?
Maybe he didn't.
Well, people's heads just don't
fly off for no reason.
Maybe we should check the scene
for some wires or branches,
or something he
could've run into.
If it would've
happened that way,
we would've found trace
from whatever did it.
The only trace in the neck
and arm wounds
was rubber from truck tires.
Which was present on both sides
of his wounds
but not on his clothing.
There were blown out tire
fragments all over the road.
But we found his body
off the road.
There shouldn't be any transfer
from truck tires.
Unless...
(machine humming)
What's going on here?
We're trying to determine
whether a steel-belted
truck tire
can decapitate a kid
driving a go-cart.
I thought that was
an urban myth.
Myths, legends, tall tales--
they all come
from something real.
If that go-cart was going
60 miles an hour
drafting a truck
going the same speed,
and that truck blows a tire
sending a two-pound projectile
into the driver's neck...
The combined speed of impact
would be 120 miles an hour.
Which is about...
962 foot-pounds
of energy.
All right, let's go, fellas.
Come on, Conrad.
There's always room for Jell-O.
It's expensive Jell-o.
(machine humming)
SANDERS (excitedly):
I love this.
(horn honking)
Well, it worked.
See if we can't reuse
some of that.
When did you tell
Ecklie we got involved?
Two years ago.
Why? What did you tell him?
Nine years ago.
(laughing)
The Forensic
Academy Conference?
Yeah.
(laughing)
You, uh, had too
many questions
about anthropology
for some reason.
Well, I was stalling.
I was trying to get the nerve
to ask you to dinner.
You had a ponytail.
I'm going to move to Swing.
We talked about this.
I know that you said
that you would do it,
but I don't want to do that
to the team.
Besides...
I am sure that I could use
more daylight in my life.
We should go.
Yeah.
(muffled shouting)
Whoo!
You, uh, you want a ride?
Wish I could.
What about you, Ricky Bobby?
No, thanks,
I like to watch.
Okay.
(laughs)
You should go.
Yeah?
Yeah, you should go.
♪ ♪