Previously on CSI:
GRISSOM:
Her name is Natalie Davis.
She works
for our janitorial service.
This girl holds me responsible
for the death of Ernie Dell.
I took away the only person
she ever loved
so she's going to do
the same thing to me.
DAVIS:
Sara?
Stop this!
Tell me where Sara is!
(thunder crashing)
(thunder rumbles)
MAN (over radio):
All units, 444 in progress.
Still no response from C-27.
WFA, five foot-nine,
120, brown-green.
Last known location:
parking structure at Imperial
and Las Vegas Boulevard.
SANDERS:
There are two cameras
on each level.
This eye has the best view
of Sara's car.
Great.
Now if we could just see
what it saw.
Where are the damn tapes?
Like I've been telling everyone,
this is a strip mall
not a casino.
The feeds go off-site.
My boss is bringing it
right now.
You recognize this woman?
(thunder crashing)
No.
What about her?
Yeah, she, uh, she eats
at the veggie place
a couple times a week,
downstairs.
When was she here tonight?
I don't know, like 7:30, maybe.
That's when she usually comes.
That gives us a time frame.
I'll take care
of the tapes.
(thunder crashing)
(thunder crashing
in distance)
A lot of desert
landscape drawings.
STOKES:
The whole city's a desert.
Could be anywhere.
Warrick, take a look at this.
In those photos of Natalie
observing Grissom and Sara
at the crime scene,
I never remember a sketch pad
or a camera in her hand
or anything like that.
You saying she drew this
from memory?
Well, maybe she's eidetic.
You know, a human camera.
The eyes snap a photo,
scan it to the brain.
Great.
Sara's location is probably
locked away inside of her head.
(speaking quietly
and indistinctly)
(cell phone rings)
Brown.
Great. I'll take it.
Keep it there.
They found Natalie's
car on Fremont Street.
All right, go ahead.
I'm not leaving here
till I find something.
(thunder crashing)
BRASS:
I just got off the horn
with Search and Rescue.
We have three choppers in the
air with night vision and IR.
The weather's getting cooler,
so a warm body
will be easier to find.
If Sara's under the car,
the metal will conceal her.
Maybe she got out.
MAN (on TV):
They've just issued
a severe weather alert
for north Las Vegas,
so let's go right to Gina
for the latest
on these thunderstorms.
GINA:
Three thunderstorms
are converging
and heading right for us.
So, up to three inches of rain.
They're expected to hit
in the next eight hours.
Flash flood warnings
have been issued for the city
and surrounding desert areas.
♪ ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
(thunder crashing)
(water sloshing)
(grunting)
(Sidle grunting)
(thunder rumbling)
(rain pouring)
(thunder crashing)
(keypad beeps)
(cell phone rings)
What do you know, Nick?
STOKES:
Compassroute.com.
Natalie's been spending a lot
of time in the desert.
About a dozen different spots,
all off the beaten path.
No roads,
just general locations.
Hang on.
Warrick,
how far was the last trip?
Give me a second,
I'm getting it right now.
34 miles, one way.
Nick, get all those locations
to Brass.
Tell him to focus his search
on any destination
within 34 miles.
Done.
(closes phone)
CURTIS:
She has wounds on her scalp.
Swab for DNA and trace.
No scumbag defense attorney
is going to make their
reputation setting her free.
DR. KACHLER:
A blow to the head
can cause many things--
memory loss...
delirium...
dementia.
But not psychosis.
(quietly):
They wouldn't understand.
She said something.
She's not talking to you.
Or anyone else here.
This patient is exhibiting
all the signs
of a psychotic break:
delusions, hallucinations,
disorganized thought.
How long is she going
to be like this?
Days.
Months.
Any longer,
we're looking
at schizophrenia.
(speaking quietly
and indistinctly)
(quietly):
I promise.
Your special girl.
(thunder rumbling,
indistinct radio communication)
(thunder rumbling)
Did you find something?
Taser barb.
It doesn't tell us where,
just how.
(rain pouring)
(cell phone ringing)
Hello, Gilbert.
GRISSOM:
Sara, we got an I.D.
on the miniature killer.
Her name is Natalie Davis.
One of Ernie Dell's fosters?
Yeah. Catherine and I just spoke
to the biological father.
He says he put Natalie
up for adoption
after she shoved her kid sister
out of a tree house.
Does he know where she is now?
No, but with a name,
it's just a matter of time.
All right, I'll be right there.
I'll meet you at the lab.
(closes phone)
Sara?
(electrical crackling)
(grunting gasps)
(computer beeps)
(computer beeping)
(typing)
She west on Imperial.
Jim.
Restrict your search to targets
in the western desert.
(computer beeping)
(car engine humming)
(grunting)
(engine revving)
(spits)
(grunts)
♪ ♪
(both grunting)
(tires screeching)
♪ ♪
(grunting)
(thunder rumbling)
(breathing heavily)
(bone snaps)
(screams)
(sobs)
Rain over our dry desert has
really caused a lot of problems,
one of the biggest storms we've
seen over the past few years.
Mudslides are already
a big problem
for the Valley and most areas
will be evacuated,
especially low-lying areas,
so stay tuned.
(beeping)
(thunder rumbling)
♪ ♪
(beeping)
(sighs)
(thunder rumbling)
Grissom.
A zip-tie...
unlocked.
I think Sara got
out of this trunk.
The speaker's completely
ripped out from the inside.
She could have
reached through
and released the backseat.
And there's blood on the glass.
There could have
been a struggle.
GRISSOM:
Yeah, but none of that's
going to tell us where she is.
We need a store receipt
or a parking stub,
something with a location on it.
If she got out of this car, she
might not even be in the desert.
We might be
completely off base here.
No.
Natalie completed the miniature.
I saw it in her eyes.
Sara is
under that car.
Pollen spores off the
bumper and Natalie's head
both overlap in
Red Rock Canyon.
Did you notify S &amp; R?
Yeah, they're
already on it.
(car idling)
(coughing)
(clears throat)
(shifting)
(engine revving)
Natalie.
Natalie Davis.
I know who you are.
I know a lot about you.
You make miniatures.
I've seen you before, right?
You work in the lab
on the cleaning crew.
So sorry
about hitting you back there.
I guess, uh...
I have a fear of trunks.
In my business,
you only find one thing in them.
(chuckles)
We actually have a lot
in common, you know?
I was a foster kid, too.
Happy, happy,
joy, joy.
I do know what it's like
to be alone...
afraid that nobody's ever going
to be there for you.
Ernie was.
Yes, he was.
That's true, Natalie.
I lost
my father, too.
I know that Ernie loved you.
He would not have wanted you
to do this.
Ernie loved me more than Grissom
could ever love you.
Grissom?
Oh, I know
what this is about.
Natalie.
What did you put in the water,
Natalie?
(breathing heavily)
Huh?
Natalie?
Natalie, what are you doing?
Natalie... what are you doing?
Natalie?
(screaming)
Don't do this.
(hydraulic hiss)
(groans)
Natalie?
Natalie.
(car door shuts)
(car starts)
Natalie!
(breathing heavily)
(wind whistling)
(thunder rumbling)
(coyote howling in distance)
(coyote howling, wind whistling,
thunder rumbling)
(panting)
(growling)
(thunder rumbling)
(whimpering)
♪ ♪
(breathing heavily)
SIDLE:
You think she's alive.
You're acting like you're going
to rescue a person,
not recover a body,
and on this job
that's just
not usually the case.
I was rescued.
It was not your day to die.
When it's your day,
it's your day, you know?
(breathing heavily)
♪ ♪
(tires screeching)
Hey, buddy.
I'm in a hurry.
This girl bought a red
Mustang off our impound lot.
Yeah, couple of,
couple of weeks ago, right,
for, for art.
Who the hell is Art?
No, she's an artist.
She thinks
all this stuff is art.
Yeah, where'd
you take it?
I don't know.
It was dark,
I followed the taillights.
Wait a minute, you
towed a 3,500-pound car,
you can't remember
where you took it?
Well, w-what's going on?
Look, you towed a car
for a serial killer.
That makes you
an accomplice.
You helped abduct
one of my people.
Now, you either tell
me where you took it
or you're going to end
up in the hospital
and after that you're
going to end up in jail.
What is it?
Come on,
focus.
Um... Ice Box Canyon.
All right, h-hey,
look, look.
Look, this is a map.
Show me on
the map.
(helicopter whirring)
(sirens wailing)
To the left.
Down there.
That's it,
that's it, that's it.
Control,
Air Three.
We are 20 miles
west of the 159,
near Ice Box Canyon.
Red-colored
vehicle spotted.
Fits the description.
(sirens wailing)
Sara! Sara!
(indistinct
radio transmission)
WILLOWS:
Nick!
She's not here.
Okay, that's good news.
Guys, park rangers said
there's some roads
on the other side
of this basin.
We're going to
go scout them.
STOKES:
All right, I'm
going with her.
Catherine!
I got shoe prints.
If there are
shoe prints,
that means she got out
from under the car.
Everybody
listen up.
We're searching
on foot.
(thunder rumbling)
(gasps)
(gasping)
(thunder cracks)
(grunting in pain)
(thunder rumbling)
♪ ♪
(wind howling)
I'm not seeing any more
footprints, are you?
No.
I think we just lost the trail.
Cath, look.
What?
This is better than a footprint.
(wind whistling)
Yeah.
Good girl.
(wind whistling)
You see another one?
Oh, no.
What?
(grunting)
Oh...
It's not her.
MAN (over radio):
HIs name is Mathew Hockman
Ranger
checked in editorial head 3 days ago
Okay, thanks.
Park Service issued
him a camping permit.
He was supposed to
hike out this morning.
Must have got caught
in the flash flood.
Couldn't make it
to higher ground.
(sighs)
Where is she, Catherine?
It's 110 degrees.
She's been out here all day,
without water.
She's disoriented,
she's dehydrated.
She's a survivor.
SIDLE (weakly):
Just keep going.
Don't stop.
Three times four is...
Okay, three times four
is 12.
(weakly):
Keep walking.
Keep walk...
Four times five is 20.
Four times six... is 24.
Four times four is...
What is it?
Sixteen. Sixteen.
Four times five...
(laughing)
(grunts)
(straining):
Four times...
four times five is 20.
(weakly):
Keep walking...
Keep walking.
Four times five is 20.
Four times six... is 24.
(mutters quietly)
(groans)
Get up.
(panting weakly)
Get up. Don't sleep.
Don't sleep.
(panting)
(quietly):
Don't sleep... don't sleep.
Stay awake.
(panting)
I... just don't sleep.
(gasping)
(vehicle accelerating)
Wait, slow down,
slow down, slow down.
CURTIS:
What is it?
Go that way.
Go.
Sara!
Sara, it's Nick.
Can you hear me?
I can't get a pulse.
We found Sara.
North on the 159
at Turtlehead Peak.
We need a medevac
out here right now.
Don't worry, we're going
to get you out of here, okay?
They're coming for you now.
You're going to
be okay, Sara.
Here!
MEDIC:
What have you got?
CURTIS:
Female, 35, unconscious.
STOKES:
She's been in the sun all day,
about 15 hours.
She's not answering me at all.
MEDIC 2:
Can we get a
blood pressure?
MEDIC:
What's her name?
CURTIS:
Sara.
Sara?! Sara,
can you hear me?!
MEDIC:
Get that oxygen going.
Put her on 15 liters.
Give me an I.V.
prep tag.
I.V.
Possible fracture,
left arm.
Copy that.
How's the back look? Anything?
Cervical's good,
spine's good.
Do me a favor.
Hold that piece of tape.
Get the arm in there.
(medics shouting
indistinctly)
On my count.
One, two, three.
Let's go...
(helicopter blades whirring)
Where are you taking her?!
Desert Palm!
Move over!
I'm going with her!
Switch off the oxygen.
PILOT:
Desert Palm, inbound.
Six minute ETA.
35-year-old female,
obvious heat exposure,
obvious fracture
of left radius ulna.
(speaking indistinctly)
I.V., O2 monitor in place.
♪ ♪