WOMAN:
You can tell by the
neuro-intergalactic vibrations,
the invasion's coming.
You know they're watching us
right now.
These other dimensions--
they're everywhere.
And string--
it's obvious--
string is the thing
that connects everything,
and I'm not talking about
the stuff you can see: protons,
photons, fig newtons,
electrons,
neutrons
and time...
and space...
Time and space?
All right.
I'm thinking
probable cause...
I see you,
turning your back on me,
shaking your head.
I can't help you.
Ignore the truth
at your own peril, sir.
At your own peril.
Hi, see, we can't
see the strings
'cause they're invisible,
but they can
'cause they're the
11th dimension.
Hey, you're ready
for them tonight, Evelyn.
The invasion's tonight.
Don't say I didn't warn you.
What's the matter? Can't look?
You know what that tells me?
That you did it.
You shot her, you
put a dress on her.
I mean, the trooper
saw you put the body
in the back of
your pickup truck.
Anything else you did,
we're going to find out.
That's what he's doing.
And the body is in
autopsy right now.
Oh, this must be
our Jane Doe.
Doe, a deer.
A female deer.
It's not funny.
It's a little funny.
Doc, I already
took photos.
Not for my scrapbook,
you didn't.
This is animal abuse.
The killing, sure.
The dress?
Pet owners put sweaters
on chihuahuas.
Just give me a hand
with the arrow.
Hmm, it's not an arrow;
it's a bolt
shot from a crossbow.
(sniffs)
Alcohol.
You think he had
to get her liquored up?
Okay, so you
got a DUI,
resisting arrest,
several new and unique
wildlife violations.
You're in a truckload
of trouble, Kyle.
I... I...
I found her like that.
In a cocktail dress?
(laughs)
I didn't put
no dress on her.
Oh, no, no, no...
see, I was...
I was taking her to the vet.
You sure it wasn't
a nightclub?
Then how do you explain
the crossbow I found
in your truck
there, boss?
Easy. Somebody put it there.
Okay, take a deep breath
for me now.
Blow into this.
Come on, guys. I mean, can't...
can't you give me a break here?
I mean, look,
no, here...
I... I... I just got a...
I got a divorce,
right, and my ex
just cleaned me out.
Let me guess: her name is Bambi.
Blow!
(inhales)
(exhaling)
Stop him!
(grunts)
Move, move, move!
Get out of the way!
(groaning)
Hey!
Hey, hey, hey, citizens arrest!
Light him up.
(screaming)
Now do you believe me?
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
Stun guns aren't
necessarily nonlethal,
just less lethal.
AFID tags confirm
it was Officer Choi's weapon.
You know, I
don't get it.
Suspect makes a break for it,
clocks a couple of unis,
gets pepper-sprayed,
and keeps going.
Pepper spray doesn't always stop
them when they're really drunk.
Suspect blew a .28.
Oh, well, maybe he
was a sloppy drunk.
Any alcohol
on his clothes?
He'd been in PD for hours.
Alcohol would have evaporated.
STOKES:
I'm gonna need your stun gun.
Am I in trouble?
When was the last time
you had this thing serviced?
Not since I've been
on the force.
That's only
six months now.
We'll have it analyzed,
see if it was malfunctioning.
That's the first time
I had to shoot it.
Relax, man.
You were following
captain's orders.
When you talk to IA,
just be honest...
and don't expect a hug.
That's when you said
to your officer,
I quote, "Light him up."
Poor choice of words.
We followed the
proper procedure
for escalation
of force.
I mean, at least
we didn't shoot him.
Of course, that
would have killed him.
As far as my office
is concerned,
we got an in-custody death
on your orders.
Doesn't get much worse.
Look, we use
stun guns
all the time around here;
this is the first one
that caught
on fire.
What do you think?
Maybe this guy had so much booze
it made him a Roman candle?
Well, unfortunately,
human blood is 83% water.
It's just not flammable,
no matter how
drunk you are.
That's too bad.
Might have let you off the hook.
Together in death,
as they were in life.
Guy abuses wildlife
and then bursts
into flames.
I call it karma.
There are no physical signs
their relationship
was anything
other than platonic.
I mean, we're the
ones encroaching
on their habitat--
you don't see them shooting us.
Consider this justice
for Bambi's mother.
Light him up.
This is the rest of the stuff
that we got
from the dead guy's truck.
One crossbow.
Same bolts we recovered
from the dead deer.
Couple of mason jars.
Whew! Moonshine.
Home brew.
Firewater.
Grain alcohol's 190 proof,
you know?
That's 95%
alcohol.
Who was he trying to forget?
Well, Brass said
that he'd just gotten divorced.
Welcome to the club.
You see any night-vision goggles
or, uh, spotlights in that box?
No, why?
Well...
I think he must have shot
the deer during the day
and then waited until dark
to put her in his truck.
That's a long time just sitting
out in the woods drinking.
Stun gun
checks out.
Operates
as designed.
Puts out
the standard
50,000 volts.
Well, that eliminates
one variable.
Leaves us
with the shirt,
the grain alcohol,
and the pepper spray.
Time to find out
if one of those
made him
catch on fire.
Don't tase me, bro.
Don't tempt me.
♪ ♪
What are we missing?
JOHNSON:
Either she's a 421-Adam,
or somewhere
a scarecrow and a lion
are looking for their friend.
STOKES:
That's Evelyn.
She's wearing
her deflector suit.
Every night,
she comes down
to PD at some point,
and she files a complaint
against them.
What did them do to her?
Everything,
from stealing her thoughts
to raping her,
but even if she
is crazy,
she's a variable in all this.
See, there may have been
some sort of transfer
between her
and burning man.
She didn't stick around
for the debrief.
Well, can you
blame her?
She just witnessed
spontaneous alien combustion.
And you didn't hold her.
No.
Did you get a statement?
Where is she now?
We don't know.
There's a lot you don't know.
You can count
on three things
happening
every day
around here.
The coffee machine's
going to break down;
some tourist is
going to swear
the hooker
was over 18;
and Evelyn's going to show up.
We got a broadcast out.
We'll find her.
She's very shiny.
It's gotta be getting hot
under all that foil.
She's going to cook
out here fast.
Aw...
Evelyn.
What happened?
The driver...
said his shift was over.
He was just taking the truck
back to the yard.
Said a flash of light
came out of nowhere.
(tires screeching)
The sun was
just coming up.
Reflection off of her suit
must have blinded him.
Okay, well, this tin foil's
evidence in two cases now,
so we've got to be
careful with it.
Butane lighter.
It's cracked.
Looks empty.
That could be what
lit the flame
in your deer hunter.
I'll check the foil
for butane.
Trouble is, it's probably
evaporated by now.
200 bucks.
Okay, turn her over, Dave.
Sure.
Guys. We got some
green fluid here.
It's coming
from the wound.
STOKES:
Damn!
I think that's blood.
♪ ♪
SANDERS:
Take a look.
You're not going
to believe it.
Another 419
with green blood.
What are the odds?
That he's not connected
to our first victim?
Astronomical.
Looks like blunt-force trauma
to me.
GRISSOM:
You know, Tin Foil Lady was
run over just a few
blocks from here.
I bet this area was home
to both of them.
(shutter clicks)
Three pairs of sunglasses?
Earplugs.
That, David, is how you make it
dark and quiet
when you sleep on the street.
(shutter clicks)
SANDERS:
Hey!
I think I found
the weapon!
We should be able to get
some good prints off it.
I've seen green blood before,
but only from bodies
in advanced stages of decomp.
What do you think
turned it green?
I suspect it might be sulfur.
Hmm, sulfur's
a naturally occurring
component of blood.
Yes, but in massive doses
it tends to turn the blood
a blackish avocado green.
When the sulfur atom joins
the hemoglobin molecules,
red blood turns green.
Which is why First Officer
Spock's blood
is green in Star Trek.
No, it's not.
Uh, yes, it is.
Trust me.
I'm an expert.
Well, apparently not,
because otherwise you would
surely know that
the oxidizing agent
in Vulcan blood is copper.
And that is why
his blood is green.
Well, it was that and the fact
that he had a Vulcan father,
since his mother
was actually human.
And furthermore,
he was promoted to Captain
just prior to Star Trek II
and then he retired
as civilian ambassador.
You're like a geeky, nerdy guy
trapped in a woman's body.
So are you.
Well, as I was saying,
here on Earth,
sulfur-containing compounds
could turn
otherwise normal blood green.
As I suspected.
What? Share.
She wasn't a Vulcan.
Thank you.
I don't want to take
all the credit,
but I do know why both
your victims
have green blood.
High levels of sulfur.
(sighs):
Yes.
Did you identify the source yet?
Not yet.
I'll get the blood
over to Henry and have him run
a tox panel
for sulfuric compounds.
Oh, and even if your
tin foil lady
was gushing blood,
it would not have contributed
to your stun gun guy's
immolation.
Did you find anything
on the foil?
Bacon grease and trace amounts
of ketchup.
Both things you would
find at a barbeque,
but not the kind that
you're dealing with.
(knocking)
Brass just called.
Our lonely
deer hunter's parents just
hired a lawyer.
The department's
going to be sued.
We haven't even released
the case details yet.
Our investigation's
still ongoing.
Well, they got something
we don't.
Move! Move! Move!
Get away! Get away!
(shouting continues on video)
Over 60,000 hits
since it was posted.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
STOKES:
Here,
on the PD surveillance,
this ambulance chaser
on his cell phone--
he's a regular.
Want to bet he's the one
that shot the footage?
Want to bet he's
the one filing suit?
Well, his cell phone
has a better angle
than the PD
surveillance camera.
Archie, run this back
to where he gets sprayed.
(typing)
Get away!
Wait a minute.
Tighten up on the can.
Nick, when we did
the experiment
with Jell-O Man,
we used pepper spray
from a red can, right?
Yeah. Yeah,
department-issue.
Got it through Logistics.
That one's yellow.
I've used my pepper spray half
a dozen times on the street.
All I had to do was write
a use-of-force memo.
BRASS:
Speaking of memos,
didn't you get the one
we issued
about five years ago?
I know what you mean.
Yeah, you know,
when the department
switched over
to water-based pepper spray.
STOKES:
This one uses isobutane.
Compressed gas,
highly flammable stuff.
Where's yours?
It's Murphy's Law, right?
I always got my gear together,
wired tight,
but last night
my girl takes
my pepper spray.
And I don't blame her
because she's got
a dangerous job.
Oh, yeah? What does she do?
She goes to WLVU
during the day.
She studies kinesiology,
but she dances nights
at the Acid Strip.
(chuckles)
What does she clip
the can to, her G-string?
It'd be a deterrent to stuffing
a tip in there, wouldn't it?
Come on; she walks
to the parking lot
alone at 4:00 a.m.
Okay, so she takes
your department-issue,
so what'd you do?
Pick up an old can
lying around?
No, bought one
at Catalani's Gun World
on the way in.
I didn't get a chance
to change it out.
Does it really matter?
It might.
(misting)
(laughs)
Hey, Greg.
I just ran your pipe
over to Prints
after I sampled it
for blood.
Yeah, did you find
something wrong?
I found something weird.
One end of the pipe
was covered
with blood
from the victim.
Yeah, the administrator
at the shelter
ID'd him as
Wayne Connor, homeless.
Well, then on the other
end of the pipe,
I found several small blood
smears from an unknown donor.
So the killer
was also injured.
Mm-hmm.
His blood's green, too.
GRISSOM:
"Once is happenstance.
"Twice is coincidence.
Three times
is enemy action."
HODGES:
Winston Churchill?
Ian Fleming.
I should know that.
I'm a huge James Bond fan.
What aren't
you a fan of?
I ran the green bloods
for sulfur-containing compounds.
Still working
on the third donor,
but Evelyn Polychronopolous
and Wayne Connor
both had high levels
of thiocyte in their systems.
Prescription medication
for migraines.
ANDREWS:
I checked with the
downtown pharmacies.
They don't dispense it.
154 nanograms per milliliter--
that's overdose levels.
Even if they were
in a clinical trial,
they wouldn't get that much.
It's not a typical
drug of abuse.
GRISSOM:
Yeah, but if you've got
a migraine, you'll do anything
to stop the pain.
How do you know
they had migraines?
Well, aside from the medication,
Connor was wearing
three pairs of sunglasses
and earplugs.
Photo- and phonosensitivity
are symptoms
of migraines.
Maybe that's why
Evelyn thought "they"
were invading
her brain.
She was killed only
a few blocks
from the vacant lot
with a couple hundred dollars
on her.
She could have been on her way
to a drug buy.
So if we can figure out
who's selling the drugs,
it may lead us
to who killed Connor.
(siren chirps)
Damn busy day.
Hmm, where are they?
Inside, end of the hall.
Mailman got worried
when they didn't come
to the door.
We did a welfare check,
found them both in the bed.
Doc.
ROBBINS:
Catherine.
No forced entry; no sign
of trauma;
bodies don't look posed.
No gas odor,
no petechiae.
No sign of suffocation.
So why'd you call CSI?
Couple in their late 60s.
What are the chances
they died
of natural causes
at the same time?
"Digoxin.
"Warfarin.
Amiodarone."
Those are all heart medications.
Mm-hmm.
"Zolpidem."
That's for sleep.
I know.
Bottle's almost full.
No foaming
at the mouth,
no note left behind.
I don't think
this is a double suicide.
Suspicious circs.
Good call.
They look like
they loved each other.
(knocking)
CATHERINE:
Looks like Caddyshack back here.
Invasion
of the ground squirrels.
(shutter clicks)
Yeah, I got a few casualties
out here.
I see.
What the hell is that?
Looks like
a close encounter, right?
"Atomic Dave's
Painless Removals."
Some kind of pest control gizmo.
Apparently, it works.
I don't think
the squirrels
would agree
that it's painless, though.
Shrodinger Martin?
(chuckles)
He had a cat named Shrodinger.
Must have been
into physics.
Cat grave.
(chuckles)
Dead cat, dead
critters, dead couple.
(clanking loudly)
(power tool running)
Imagine living next door
to that racket.
WOMAN:
Last night?
I was in my studio.
I'm an artist.
Didn't your neighbors
complain about the noise?
(chuckles)
I don't weld at night.
I work on my jewelry.
High-end stuff.
Nice.
Listen, how well did you know
your neighbors, the Martins?
Are they dead?
Yeah.
They passed away last night.
Hardly knew them.
Heard he was
a, uh...
(grunting):
...professor or something.
Yeah, we really didn't have
too much in common.
Well, apparently,
you both shared a
ground squirrel problem.
(sighs)
Could be worse, I guess.
I could still be
with my deadbeat ex.
There's a pest
I did get rid of.
ROBBINS:
Hey, Catherine.
Hi.
What a relief.
Two red-blooded Americans.
According
to his stomach contents,
he likes a glass
of red wine with his pasta.
Looks like suppertime
was about four hours premortem.
Take a look at
the light board.
Both Martins
wore pacemakers.
Mrs. Martin's
is in that bowl.
(ticking)
Takes a licking
and keeps on ticking.
Yeah, I hope mine's
still working when I pop off.
You wear a pacemaker?
Bradycardia-- slow heart.
Every once in a while, just to
make sure I don't skip a beat,
the pacer kicks in,
just like this one.
Well, obviously,
they didn't die
of pacer malfunction.
(beeping)
What you got?
Check this out.
It's like having a witness
to his death inside his body.
There's no interruption in his
pacemaker functions, but...
about eight hours
before he died,
there was a spike
in his heart rate.
His wife's
is almost identical,
so something got
their hearts racing.
Who knows?
Maybe they, uh,
enjoyed a little
afternoon delight.
Well, let's hope.
(chuckles)
Either way,
their heartbeats went
back to normal
and they died in their sleep
a few hours later.
(computer beeping)
(beeping continues)
(line ringing)
Okay, so I've been
thinking this over
and here's my advice.
If you want to get a real
relationship with a girl,
you are going to have
to move out of Mom's.
No girl wants the competition.
I'm sorry.
(beeping)
(man screaming)
Oh, God, no, no, turn 'em off.
Turn 'em off. Turn 'em off.
David Bohr, you're under arrest
for the murder of Wayne Connor.
No, no, it was self-defense.
He tried to kill me
over a couple hundred bucks.
He needed
some stuff.
He couldn't pay.
He said some money was coming.
I had to go to work.
I turned to leave and he comes
at me like an animal.
I have to go.
No, no, no, no.
(both grunting)
This is Captain Brass.
We need a Code 3 paramedic
response to my location.
(screaming):
No!
(door opens)
BROWN:
Thanks, man.
Hey, I got your page.
What's up?
I think our cases
might be connected.
Take a look at that.
So my green-blooded victim
from the vacant lot was buying
pharmaceuticals from the guy
who did pest removal
for your dead couple.
Looks like this guy was trying
to create radio frequencies
or something.
Well, I don't know
what kind of effect
that has on
household pests,
but radio waves can produce
"noise on the channel,"
which could interfere
with pacemaker function.
Thing is...
the Martins' pacemakers
are still ticking.
Ah, the luck of the Irish.
It makes sense,
though.
If his blood was green,
his organs would be green.
Well, frankly, I expected
something more in the...
dark avocado,
almost black range.
Yeah, this is more
artichoke.
(chuckles)
You know,
atmospheric sulfur levels
are on the rise.
Hundred years, we're all going
to look like spinach.
(sighs)
You guys didn't wait for me.
We're just about
to excise his brain.
I'll bet you five bucks, Greg,
that his brain
is not as green as his heart.
Keep your money
in your pockets, Greg.
There's a higher
vascular nature
to the heart
and lungs.
Only the blood vessels
in the brain
are going to be green.
It's a sucker bet
and you know it.
Well, thanks, Doc.
So, uh, Dave here did
some humane
rodent pest removal
for Desert Palm Hospital,
which is where he got
his hands on the thiocyte.
He was all about freedom
from pain.
Ah.
Sea foam.
A lovely shade.
Look at the size of that.
He had a brain tumor
pressing on the amygdala.
Well, this could cause
his migraines.
Absolutely,
and also aggressive
disruptive behavior,
paranoia.
As the tumor enlarged,
it impacted the arteries,
causing the cerebral hemorrhage
that you observed.
(screaming)
He was self-medicating
for the wrong condition.
No wonder he overdosed.
WILLOWS:
Let 'er rip.
(whirring)
In order to interfere
with pacemaker function,
it'd have to be putting out
between 50 and 60 hertz.
Okay, I'll input
that range.
(typing)
This thing isn't putting out
anything that's lethal.
Tox report showed that
the medications weren't lethal.
This thing's harmless.
I refuse to believe
it was natural causes.
It's too big
of a coincidence.
So we've got a dead cat
and dead squirrels.
Maybe what killed them
is what killed the Martins.
In an interview in the
San Francisco Chronicle--
October 31, 1996,
if I recall correctly--
one Professor Gilbert Grissom
revealed that as a boy,
he collected dead animals
he found in his Marina
del Rey neighborhood
and performed necropsies
on them.
Hodges...
I want you to stop stalking me.
(sniffing)
Bitter almonds.
Cyanide
crystals in the
stomach lining.
Yeah, any time you need
a sniffer to detect it,
my nose has
the cyanide gene.
What gene turned
your nose brown?
Go ahead.
You can sew him up.
Will do.
And I'll notify
next of kin, too.
(chuckles)
Ugh.
GRISSOM:
Cyanide is fast-acting.
If it killed
the squirrels
before the crystals were
dissolved completely
in their stomachs,
you'd expect the same thing
with the Martins.
I saw the Martins'
stomach contents.
There were no white crystals.
Yeah, but maybe
if it was ingested
in a different manner.
Squirrels will
eat anything.
If the Martins drank it,
then that would explain
the absence of crystals.
I already have Henry running
an expanded tox panel.
Any minute now.
It's cooking.
(beeping)
It's coming right up.
Yeah.
You hear Hodges is looking
for his own apartment?
Cut the old apron strings.
His mother finally
kicked him out, huh?
Good for her.
Lethal levels of cyanide.
You can't just walk into a
hardware store and pick some up.
What about pest control
companies?
Can they get it?
Yeah.
And mining companies,
uh, electroplaters,
photographers,
jewelry makers.
Thanks, Henry.
You can relax now.
(exhales)
Look, is this going
to take long?
Depends on you.
'Cause I'm dealing
with some really bad news.
I just found out my ex died
last night.
I'm sorry.
Yeah, apparently one of you guys
blew him up with a stun gun.
Kyle Planck is your ex?
Tell me, what is it
that you two have
against God's fur-covered
creatures?
Is this about that damn cat?
For starters, yes.
Look, I like cats, all right?
It was an accident.
You can't just relocate
ground squirrels.
Okay?
I mean, they're...
they're disgusting.
And I'm an artist.
I need a certain environment
to work in.
Does this environment give you
access to cyanide?
I use potassium cyanide
in electroplating.
All my work
is custom.
And also to poison
ground squirrels?
I mixed a little
with a can of tuna.
And I put it out back.
But only in my yard.
All right, who knew
the Martins' cat
was going to find it?
What? Is that against the law?
Actually,
irresponsible use of poison
is against the law,
as well as killing
ground squirrels
and killing
neighbors.
What?
I didn't...
I didn't kill them.
Look, we had neighbor issues.
Turn that damn thing off
before I torch it!
You're driving
all your squirrels
into my yard.
All right, look,
we're just trying
to be humane here.
Now you use poison.
And you-you killed
Shrodinger.
You should've kept
your cat on your side
of the fence, all right.
You're causing this problem,
not me.
Just leave us alone!
I killed the squirrels.
And possibly their cat.
But I am not a murderer.
(sniffing)
(exhaling)
I got nothing.
Try the bed.
(sniffing)
(laughs)
That's...
Sorry. I was thinking
of one of those, uh,
bloodhounds in the old
cartoons,
"Sniffing awound
to find da wabbit."
(imitating
Elmer Fudd laugh)
This is a gift.
Don't make it cheap.
(sniffing)
Trail's gone cold.
So, they died in this room.
In bed.
Give me a hand
with the mattress.
Now, get down and sniff the rug.
It's all they
ever want.
(sniffing)
(exhaling)
Pay dirt.
This carpet looks
kind of new, right?
Yeah.
Definitely
some combustion there.
It looks like they just
laid the new carpet
right on top of the old,
which clearly limited
the supply of oxygen.
The old carpet melted
without bursting into flame.
Ironically, older carpets
contained polyvinyl chloride
used as a flame retardant.
So, when it got hot,
it probably went into
quantitative decomposition,
which gave off gases,
including hydrogen cyanide.
(coughing)
Field work dirty.
Dirty, dirty, dirty.
(knocking wood)
(pounding wood)
(dog barking in distance)
Oh! Come on!
Your killer's a
ground squirrel?
In a way,
I'd argue self-defense.
(gadget humming)
(squirrel chittering)
(chittering)
(buzzing)
It was an old house.
The wood had
desiccated.
The short circuit smoldered
into the floor joists.
(buzzing)
(popping)
(gases hissing)
Is it bad
when you start thinking
none of this sounds
too weird anymore?
Oh, it's a bit too freaky
how these cases are connected.
Grissom,
you always say
that there's no such
thing as coincidence.
There isn't.
WILLOWS:
Oh, come on.
You got the guy that burst
into flames just divorced
from the woman
who was fighting squirrel wars
with the Martins.
SANDERS:
Who had hired the exterminator
whose drugs were turning
everybody's blood green.
STOKES:
And one of his green-blooded
customers was Evelyn,
Our Lady of Tin Foil,
the last person that Kyle
Planck touched before he died.
There's one more connection.
Evelyn had 200 bucks.
I'm thinking that
when she was run over,
she was
on her way
to buy more thiocyte.
I think
that Wayne Connor
was with David Bohr,
waiting for the money to arrive.
SANDERS:
Only Evelyn never showed up.
Connor lost his temper,
and Bohr killed him in a fight.
And it all started
with Kyle Planck--
lonely guy with a gut
full of moonshine.
String theory.
Grissom theory.
This is better
than a bedtime story.
GRISSOM:
String theory is
"the theory of everything."
Quantum mechanics tells us
about the very small.
The theory of relativity
explains
the immense.
String theory ties it
all together.
It proposes
that atomic particles
are made up of infinitesimal,
vibrating loops of energy--
or strings.
Each string vibrates
at its own frequency--
like on a violin,
producing "notes."
And these notes make up
everything in the universe.
Cosmic symphony.
These strings have been
combining and recombining
ever since the big bang.
So, the connections
between our victims--
or any of us--
are not that extraordinary.
But every one of them
thought they were alone.
BROWN:
Too bad they didn't know
about Grissom's theory.
In a parallel universe,
maybe they're all having
breakfast together.
In this universe,
maybe we are.
STOKES:
Yeah.
And you're buying.
No strings attached.