♪ ♪
MAN:
You may believe...
...that you have to die
before the Judgment comes...
...but I say the Fire...
...is not around the corner.
The Fire is not a-waiting.
The Fire is
not a-wanting.
The Fire
has already come.
As we mortals drink, gamble,
and fornicate our way
through this world,
deaf to Hell's Bells'
thundering toll, the clock
of damnation
has already struck midnight.
We're cooked... done!
Stick a fork in the ass
of the human race and...
turn us over on Satan's spit
because we all
are not going to Hell.
As surely as we stand
in Las Vegas,
Nevada...
...I say...
...we are in Hell now.
(garbled radio transmission)
WILLOWS:
Why are we parking in an alley
two blocks from the crime scene?
You know, Sanitation's
flushing out a sewer line
and we don't want
to block their trucks.
Whoa.
What do we got here?
Hey, guy.
Hey.
Looks like we got a male D.B.
I'll call it in.
You got it, Mitch?
I'll contain the scene.
(Spanish program
playing on TV)
Man was shot
execution-style,
.22 to the back
of the head.
Woman was shot as well,
bound and gagged.
Guest next door
complained about the noise,
manager finally called
the police, Unis found this.
Well, I don't see any luggage,
wedding rings still
on the fingers.
Probably rules out
robbery
but not infidelity.
One gets to watch
the other one die.
(gasping)
(woman screams, gun cocks)
Maybe someone was trying
to teach them a lesson.
Did you guys happen to see
the Fitzgerald's thermometer
on your way over?
Oh, yeah.
109.
Hot as hell.
Anything
under 110 is manageable.
Above that, the crime rate
always goes way up.
(siren wailing)
(woman screams)
Sounds like it's getting hotter.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
(indistinct radio transmission)
(siren chirps)
♪ ♪
Well, there's no wallet
or I.D. on this one either.
This looks like
a wet spot.
(beeps)
Semen.
There's no indication
she was re-dressed.
It doesn't look
like sexual assault.
WILLOWS:
So... middle class couple...
...takes a walk
on the wild side,
checks into
this dump for...
some fine dining and romance.
Somebody breaks in, kills the
man, and tortures the woman.
For what?
Maybe it's a drug thing.
Well, wouldn't be
the first time
some nice folks from Henderson
came east of Fremont to score.
Did you find any drug residue
or paraphernalia?
Not yet.
Maybe tox'll find it in them.
We have one too many Bibles.
I don't think they helped.
So you didn't hear or
see anything suspicious?
This job--
you kidding me?
That's all I see
and all I hear.
Is that the
register?
Give it to me,
give it to me.
Room 106.
Paid for the week, cash in
advance, signed 'em in myself.
We got a problem.
What's the problem?
Your handwriting sucks.
What the hell
does this say?
Oh, uh... oh, that.
That's the name here and that's,
that's a, well, that's an "A."
Uh...
and the license plate...
uh... that's an "N"
and-- oh-- that's a "V."
That's "Nevada."
You think?
SIDLE:
Green bloat stage.
He's been here
at least 18 hours.
Do you ever wonder
why ants don't crawl
up the nose, eat the brains?
I would. Protein.
Ants are scavengers;
they tend to stay
on the surface.
You think dead skin tastes
better than brains?
Well, they will go
for brains late in decomp,
after all the
skin is gone.
Do ants have taste buds?
Ronnie...
I'm going to have to limit
you to 20 questions per case.
Really?
Nineteen?
BRASS:
Hey, Sara.
Hey... Jim.
So... enjoying the sunshine?
Not really.
D.B. is a derelict.
I'm kind of surprised
to see you investigating this.
Oh, I'm not working this.
I'm working the double homicide
over at the Rancho
Center Motel.
We're just doing a
neighborhood sweep
for suspects.
You're new. I'm Jim Brass.
Yeah. Ronnie Lake.
Right.
Ronnie Lake.
Like Veronica.
You know, the actress?
Sullivan's Travels?
I think that's
my dad's favorite movie.
Right.
DISPATCHER (over radio):
203-Charlie, Control.
We have a few hookers
who used the motel.
They're willing to talk.
Yeah, 203-Charlie,
I'm on my way.
Got to run. Okay.
So I got a hit
off of the print
on the motel room's
"Do Not Disturb" sign.
Drug dealer with priors
for assault-- nice.
Yes, well,
don't get too excited
because I got another hit off
of the telephone-- pedophile--
and I got one off
of the dresser-- rapist--
and another one
off of the bed frame--
a prostitute, a pimp,
and another prostitute.
Is that it?
For felonies, yes.
You want
misdemeanors, too?
So the blood on the shirt
belongs to your victims.
The high velocity spatter on
the front is a mixture of both
and the blood drops
on the left sleeve appear
to solely belong
to the woman.
Probably cast-off
from the beating.
Now, the pattern on the sleeve
has a straight line
on the outside, and then
a matching band of spatter
on the inside.
So the killer rolled up
his sleeves?
He had a lot of work to do.
Speaking of which--
The wet spot.
The sex stain was a male-
female combo, both unknown,
but the female
shared alleles
at all loci
with both of the victims.
It's their daughter.
The parents weren't that old.
The girl would be
a teenager at most.
So the killer caps mom and dad,
rapes the girl,
and takes
her with him.
If you've got
a missing kid,
I've got
a pedophile.
Alistair Rhodes.
Busted in August '94
for child molestation.
That's pre-CODIS,
so there's no DNA
on file to match.
Alistair Rhodes.
I remember this guy.
He was a lounge singer, called
himself "Three Miles of Bad."
It was all over the news.
Well, according
to the sheet,
he served five years
and made parole.
A registered sex offender.
We know where he lives.
You think
those are your fingers
itching to pick up
the spike?
Your hands injecting
your veins?
"Satan finds mischief still
in idle hands."
BRASS:
Alistair Rhodes.
Most people around here
just call me "Reverend."
Hey, why don't you guys
go Super-Size those?
So, Reverend,
I hear that confession
is good for the soul.
You have anything to tell me?
The man you're looking for
no longer exists.
If you'll excuse me,
I have some chores to do.
You ever been to
the Rancho Center Motel?
Plenty of times.
With hookers, addicts,
drug dealers, pimps,
wife beaters, runaways.
I save people.
You ever save these two?
You know them, don't you?
There's nothing I can tell you.
These people have a daughter,
and she's missing.
And due to the fact that
you're a convicted sex offender
that means that
you better come up with
a lot more than these
corny priestly homilies
and you better
come up with them fast.
I don't answer to you.
I want to talk
to my lawyer.
That's a good idea
because you're under arrest.
Yo, Rambar, I have
some documents to...
Sh...
Piece of junk.
(slams lid)
Where's Rambar?
Where all state employees go
when they fail repeatedly.
FBI Lab?
Sucking down
taxpayer dollars
in Quantico as we speak.
Me, I like to think I'm
broadening my horizons.
Yeah, along with
your pay grade.
Oh, happy coincidence
indeed, sir.
What you got here?
Wow.
Somebody needs to switch
to decaf.
In there somewhere is a Nevada
plate number and a name.
Can you dig it out?
I could try.
BROWN:
The plate number is "something,
something, something, D,
seven, something, something."
Okay, well,
it's a fairly new model.
The four letter,
three number configuration
has only been standard
a couple years.
Ooh.
Well, uh... it's a start.
Well, can you cross-reference
these records
against the characters
in the vics' last name.
It's "M, A, blank, blank, blank,
I, blank, blank."
(computer trills)
Now that's a good start.
BROWN:
Alvin and Girlie Macalino.
Let's do it.
This makes what, the third power
outage since summer?
Fourth, actually.
If I didn't know any better,
I'd say the city was
trying to get rid of us.
That's a hundred dollar fine
right there.
That's not good.
BROWN:
Las Vegas PD.
Is anybody home?
It smells metallic.
Oh, man.
What the hell is that?
That looks like balut.
It's this Filipino
delicacy.
My grandmother's best friend
is from Manila.
Bet it tastes like chicken.
The Macalinos must've been
in quite a hurry
to leave their dinner out
like that.
Oh...
So much for the daughter.
No visible signs
of sexual trauma.
If it's any consolation.
It's not.
GRISSOM:
Burger Giant to go.
They were eating it at the motel
and someone had it here.
Possible connection?
Hey, maybe we can add robbery
to the list.
Wi-Fi card but no laptop.
Mom, dad...
and two girls.
They have another daughter?
(muffled buzzing)
Okay, so it's not just
the ringing in my ears.
(muffled buzzing continues)
(ladder clicking)
SANDERS:
One girl gets My Little Pony,
the other one ends up here.
That doesn't seem
fair, does it?
(muffled buzzing continues)
(insect buzzing)
(buzzing continues)
(bee buzzing)
(buzzing grows louder)
Greg?
Do you have any allergies?
No. Why?
Give me a hand.
(buzzing grows louder)
(bees buzzing loudly)
BRASS:
The Macalinos
had two daughters--
Amy and Elizabeth.
Elizabeth is dead,
and Amy is missing.
That is tragic,
but it has nothing to do
with my client.
Your fingerprints
were found at the motel
where the Macalinos
were murdered.
My client has already
explained that.
Back before
you were saving souls,
when you were
just molesting children,
you had a partner...
ATTORNEY:
Who died in prison
eight years ago.
We found male DNA
on the bedsheets
at the Rancho Center Motel.
You got yourself a new partner,
just like old times.
Only, this time,
the parents busted in on you.
That was bad for you,
but worse for them.
And now that mom and dad
are never going to come home,
you get yourself a whole new
playpen to party in
and a new buddy to party with.
The DNA at the motel--
was it my client's?
No.
Then why is he still in custody?
Because he's still lying.
You're not
an ordained minister.
You're not a part
of any recognized church.
You got nothing to hide behind.
So avoid the death penalty--
give us your partner,
we get the girl,
and you get... redemption.
Six years ago,
I was an alcoholic
and a crackhead.
This man pulled me
out of the gutter
and saved my life.
My firm is doing
this pro bono.
I guarantee
he will not do
another day in jail.
My partner...
is the Lord.
Well, I'm sure it's not His DNA
on those sheets.
LAKE:
So anyway, when I graduated
I got offers from both the labs
in New York and Miami.
Know why I picked Vegas?
SIDLE:
I know you have
nine questions left.
Crime rate's
growing faster here.
All of his... um... valuables
in a rubber-band wad.
No I.D.
Check the shirt pocket.
I was getting there.
Hah.
Driver's license. Expired.
Edward Kaye,
born 1-28-51.
SIDLE:
New socks.
Happy face sandwich wrapper.
It's got to be handouts
from a shelter.
Make some calls.
You get to ask some questions,
Ronnie.
You know, if I had to
gauge it by his apartment,
I'd say that Alistair Rhodes
is a regular guy.
Yeah, I'm sure that's what he
wants everybody to think, too.
Hey, Nick.
For a guy with his own
flip-down ironing board,
these shirts look
pretty wrinkled.
♪ ♪
Hey, Archie.
JOHNSON:
Yo.
Whatever
you're doing,
that's more important.
Roman numerals one through six.
All right, let me guess.
Star Wars bootlegs.
Child pornography.
Start with the
latest first.
Yeah.
(tape rewinding)
(backward yelling)
That's enough. Let it play.
(young woman screaming)
...bang you with
chains of iron!
Come from her now!
Back, Pandemonium!
Back, Confusion!
Leave...
this...
Stop it!
That's enough!
...girl!
MAN:
Hey, stop, stop!
RHODES:
Now, spirit!
WOMAN:
Why did you stop him?!
He was
hurting her!
No!
This isn't kiddie porn.
It's an exorcism.
This is your fault.
You didn't believe.
He has no knowledge
of the deaths
or of Amy Macalino's
current whereabouts.
BRASS:
Counselor, is this your idea
of cooperation?
L-Listen to me.
Listen to me.
The mother came to me...
at her wit's end,
heart in her hand, begging me,
begging me to free her child.
She said she'd tried
doctors and pills,
but nothing worked,
so I went to the house,
I saw it with my own eyes.
(growling)
(eerie, distorted):
Let...
me...
out of here!
(distorted screaming)
The thing in that house...
it wasn't Amy.
It wasn't human.
I had to cast it out.
Did it work?
The exorcism-- did it work?
No.
Amy's father broke
the rules:
never speak to it,
never interrupt,
and believe me completely.
Do only as I say.
And he didn't believe.
Mr. Grissom, do you believe
in a separate, living evil?
You're primitive
man on the savannah.
You see something move out
of the corner of your eye.
You assume it's a hyena.
You run, you live.
If you assume it's the wind
and you're wrong, you die.
We have the genes
of the ones who ran.
We're genetically
hardwired
to believe living forces
that we cannot see.
The Devil's slyest trick
is making us believe
he isn't real.
But call his name
loud and long enough...
...guess who comes
knocking on your door?
Usually guys like you.
Look, enough with the
Sunday school bull.
This meeting is over,
the deal is off.
We've answered your questions.
I told you
the truth.
You have to let me leave.
He's right about that.
If you're
not charging him
with anything...
We're charging
you with assault.
Fine. We'll make bail. You'll
be out of here in six hours.
Multiple contusions
on the face,
subdural hematomas.
This guy
was definitely roughed up.
C.O.D.?
Being homeless
in Las Vegas.
Cardiac arrest
due to dehydration.
Thanks, Doc.
Anytime.
Hi, Ronnie.
Hi.
I faxed
the D.B.'s photo
to various indigent
organizations.
Shelter on Rancho and Main
I.D.'d him as a regular.
Their special this week
was socks and sandwiches.
Rancho and Main is less than
a mile from where we found him.
Bum got into a fight--
business as usual--
and died of exposure, right?
(chuckles)
Oops, that was a question.
I know,
I'm down to four,
but, I mean, that's it--
case closed, right?
What does that look like to you?
Perimortem abrasions...
parallel, double rails.
It's handcuffs.
Cops must have picked him up
before he died.
Maybe that's not all they did.
Well, that's a guess.
What is the first thing
that the police do
when they question a suspect?
Check for I.D.
Standard procedure.
Eddie Kaye's only identification
was an expired driver's license
found separated from all
of his worldly possessions.
(sighing):
Print it.
Well, you're not seriously
going to go after the cops
over something like this?
You know what?
That question I will answer.
We're not here to
protect anyone, Ronnie,
not even the cops.
We're here to figure
out what happened.
If you can't do that, you
should get a different job.
SIDLE:
Officer Casella?
That's me.
I'm Sara Sidle,
I'm with the crime lab.
This is my partner
Ronnie Lake.
Hi.
Can you tell me
why your fingerprints
were found
on this?
Well, sure,
I touched it.
What else did you touch?
Uh...
(laughing):
I'm sorry, what do you mean?
Did you strike this man?
Okay, are you
trying to jam me up?
We're not trying
to do anything.
Where'd you get
the bruise,
Casella?
I got it doing my job.
A couple of train wrecks
were slugging it out
over this crap sandwich.
I try to save them
from themselves,
but no good deed goes
unpunished,
so, uh,
one of 'em takes a poke at me.
So I cuff him up,
I check his I.D.
I'm ready to run him in,
but my partner
says to drop it.
Mm-hmm.
He says
this is an
old bum trick,
right, like take
a swing at a cop,
you go to jail
where they have A.C.,
they have food,
they have water.
I can't believe
I almost fell for that.
I kind of wish you had.
The man died.
Wow.
What do you got
there, Greg?
.22 handgun.
Looks like it could be
the murder weapon.
You off the clock?
Yeah.
Good job.
Thanks.
How you doing?
Well, I've had better days.
You missing me yet?
A little more every day.
Grissom's
in the attic.
Still.
(buzzing)
Hey.
Bee frame.
Inside, I've got the queen,
the workers, the whole colony.
You're looting
the crime scene
of its bees?
I cleared it
with Animal Control.
This colony is healthy.
I need it to study
Colony Collapse Disorder.
Bees are dying in record
numbers everywhere.
You know, I did read that
if every bee on Earth died,
the human race would follow
four years later.
There's no hard evidence
to support that, though.
Oh.
But the world will end...
someday.
(indistinct radio transmission)
You don't think
that's cheating?
Anybody can get their
hands on that stuff.
My kid can get "the
Clear," the cream.
Dispatch, we have
plate number David-Paul
William-Robert-
one-eight-four,
multiple warrants,
parking violations.
Maybe we should juice up
all the players.
Level the field,
be more entertaining for me.
You are one sick twist,
my friend, you know that?
(monitor beeps)
MALE ELECTRONIC VOICE:
Stolen vehicle.
Hold up.
Dispatch, we have plate number
Paul-Robert-Zebra-David-
seven-five-zero.
Stolen vehicle,
outstanding homicide.
At Koval,
off Las Vegas Boulevard.
DISPATCHER:
Wanted for murder.
Back up.
Go, go, go, go!
(tires screeching)
Hands, let me see your hands!
Out of the car now!
Get your hands up!
Let me see
your hands!
Get out of
the car.
Hands!
You know who we're looking
for, scumbag-- Amy Macalino.
Where is she?
I'm Amy.
So you're sure you never
saw this guy before?
That guy?
Uh-uh, no.
Okay, but this guy,
uh-huh.
Uh-huh, he was definitely
at the Rancho Center Motel.
He was there, um,
three nights ago.
Had his little camera
with him and everything.
Camera?
Yeah, like video camera
and all that stuff.
That helps, thanks.
Thanks for your cooperation.
Um...
don't I get a reward?
Yeah, you
get to leave.
Hi, Amy.
I'm Catherine Willows,
I'm with the crime lab.
You here to probe me?
Swab.
No, no, Amy, this, this is,
um, this is in the mouth.
Staff tells me
that you've already gone
through the S.A.E. kit.
They tell you
I'm all banged up inside?
Not in those words.
Amy... the man that took you...
...he cannot
hurt you again.
We've got him.
Then can I go?
W-W-Where's my clothes?
Well, they're evidence for now,
but you'll get them back.
The clothes that you wore--
were they yours or...
did he make you wear them?
He made me do a lot of things.
BRASS:
Andrew Wolflynn.
Bet your friends
call you Wolf, huh?
So I'm going
to call you Wolf.
You can call me Jim.
You know, it's really exciting
to meet such a hyphenate.
You know what I mean?
I mean, you're a triple threat.
You know, kidnapper-
rapist-auteur.
Do you like
making movies?
What are you talking about?
Kiddie porn.
No.
No, n-no, no way,
no-not me, man.
No, not just you--
you and a partner.
He shoots, you score.
(crying)
It must be a really
good business.
Low budget,
high profits.
Unless you get caught.
I've contacted Child Services.
You'll have to stay there
for at least tonight.
Do you have any relatives?
Not anymore.
I've got a daughter.
She's almost your age.
Maybe we should hang out.
There'll be
some counselors there
that you can talk to and...
...take as much time
as you need and...
whenever you're ready,
to go back to school.
Where do you go?
Jefferson.
Jefferson High?
I don't know that one.
Jefferson Middle.
Amy, what grade are you in?
Sixth.
I'm 12.
We got your
fingerprints, your semen.
I mean, we got you in
the dead couple's car
working to bang their
kidnapped daughter.
We got... did I leave
anything out?
Oh, yeah, we got your gun.
I don't own a gun.
No, you know, we checked
the serial number.
It belongs to
your grandmother.
(chuckling):
But you know...
And you know, it must be
really hard to get that gun
off ol' granny.
What the hell
are you doing?
I'm just checking
your shirt size.
I might want to give you
a Christmas present.
17 1/2, 36.
You know what?
I was leaving
something out, Wolf.
We got your shirt
soaked not in one but both
of the victims' blood.
You see, this is what
we call a slam dunk.
You're going
to jail.
to do time.
But why do it alone?
Don't be a patsy.
Just tell us the
name of your partner.
Come on, share
with a friend.
And you know what?
You don't even have
to tell me his name.
All you have
to do... is point.
Hmm?
I've never seen
that guy before in my life.
Come on, you can do
better than that.
I want a lawyer.
♪ ♪
What are you doing?
Hey.
I'm trying to make some
sense out of the spatter.
Now, we've already
determined that the...
the killer rolled up
his sleeves
when he murdered
the motel victims,
but when I found the shirt,
the cuffs were buttoned,
and I'm not much bigger
than this guy.
And look.
This is as far
as the sleeves go up.
Would you give me the
shirt off your back?
Sure.
(quietly):
Here you go.
Okay.
Easy.
So Wolflynn wasn't wearing
the shirt, was he?
I guess Amy was.
A trophy after sex.
Hey.
I have something
I'd like you to see.
The Macalino
family computer
was recovered from
the stolen car.
Archie...
found the chat logs.
A lot of traffic
between Amy
and the "Wolfman."
Keep reading.
It looks
like Amy's luring the Wolfman.
What would you do
if you found this
on Lindsey's computer?
WILLOWS:
Ground her for life.
Take the laptop.
Lock her in
the attic, maybe?
Well, you push kids,
they push back.
Things can get
out of hand pretty quick.
The Macalinos were pushed
all the way to an exorcism.
Now, Alistair Rhodes
says that he left the motel
when his ritual failed.
The video shows the father
tried to stop it.
He probably untied her.
Right?
So Amy escapes,
she goes and gets
her knight in shining armor.
Yeah, Wolf and his .22 caliber.
They return to the motel.
The parents are gone,
but the room's still paid for.
They have sex and burgers.
And Amy calls her mom and dad,
who come back
because they still love her.
Dad gets killed first... quick,
but mom,
the true believer,
the one who wanted
to drive out the demons,
she has to suffer.
And Amy goes home
to get her computer...
...and kills her little sister.
I'll call Brass.
We'll go pick Amy up.
(knocking)
Amy, there's somebody
here to see you.
Could you come
with me, please?
Just wait in here.
WILLOWS:
We need to see Amy Macalino.
Popular girl
tonight.
She's upstairs
with her minister.
(cocks gun)
Her what?
Control, this is Willows.
I'm at C.P.S.
I need backup.
Code Three now.
(Amy screaming)
(Amy screams)
(thud)
(gasps)
Alistair, turn around.
Turn around.
Now!
Get down on
your knees.
I saved her.
♪ ♪