Are you afraid
of vaginas, Spencer?
No, I'm actually fine with them.
Are you?
Yeah.
Are you really?
Because these jokes stink
like someone who's
afraid of vaginas.
Okay, well, if you could
just point specifically
to the jokes you object to,
I'll try to freshen them up.
They all suck.
But Annabelle...
Don't argue with me.
Just make me funny.
And make me loveable.
(elevator dings)
(crowd clamoring)
Annabelle!
Can I have
your autograph?
Annabelle,
I love you.
Can I have
your autograph?
So, how'd it go?
Oh, great. She hates everything
and I'm afraid of vaginas.
I'm only afraid
of the ones with teeth.
Could one of you guys
do me a favor?
If you could
take my pencil
and drive it through
my eye into my brain?
No, then one of us
would have to take your job.
Sorry I'm late.
I was fixing the script.
We understand.
Thank you.
WOMAN:
Picture's up.
I need Bud.
Where the hell is Bud?
Take one.
Hold the roll.
ANNABELLE:
There you are.
(muffled yell)
I need you, Bud.
I need you, too.
I thought you were mad at me.
Oh, you know how I am.
The rewrites
are just horrible.
Why doesn't anyone
support me?
BUD:
I support you, doll.
Don't worry about it.
I'll take care of it.
Thank you, baby.
Annabelle wants it funnier.
Good note.
If I need water,
I'll ask for water.
You're a stand-in.
Do not get in my eyeline
when I'm preparing for a scene.
(with Southern accent):
So sorry.
How ever could I forget?
Inbred cracker.
Let's get this going.
I have a 7:00 brain aneurysm.
(blubbering)
Action.
Hit me.
Oh, damn.
What do you
want to do
after we've blown through
your ex-husband's cash?
I say we take his credit cards
and go lap dancing.
(laughter)
Giving or getting?
Doesn't matter, as long as I get
to have a party in my pants.
(laughter)
And... cut.
Cut it.
SPENCER:
Oh, geez, here we go.
Think happy thoughts.
Why did you give Megan the joke?
Yeah, why did
she get the joke?
They both have jokes.
She has the big joke--
the pants joke.
Yeah, the pants joke
is the killer.
The pants joke suits
Megan's character.
To hell with Megan's character.
Is this show
called Annabelle,
or is it Stupid Lucky Cow?
BUD:
It's not called
Stupid Lucky Cow, hon.
It's called Annabelle,
right, honey?
Yeah. See, he gets it.
That's why he is
co-executive producer.
Seems like just yesterday
he was your driver.
That was six
months ago.
What's the matter
with him?
I don't know.
Megan, honey, we got
to swap the lines around.
Why?
Fine.
Picture's up.
(clearing throat)
Okay.
Hit me.
(laughter)
Damn.
What do you
want to do
once we blow through
my ex-husband' cash?
(laughter)
I say we get his credit cards
and go lap dancing.
Giving or getting?
Doesn't matter to me.
As long as there's
a party in my pants.
(Bud tittering)
(baby crying)
Oh. (laughing)
Genius.
PHILLIPS:
Sorry for the delay.
It's a paparazzi
jungle downstairs.
Yeah, well, Doc Robbins isn't
the only one with a scrapbook.
You were saying?
My room is
down the hall,
and I was walking past.
Saw the door ajar.
Went inside and found her
lying like that.
So I called 911.
Do you know who
was up here with her?
No idea.
Almost all of the cast and crew
went back to L.A.
after we wrapped,
but Annabelle
won't travel
at night.
So she made me
stay behind.
"Made me"?
I thought you were the boss.
That's not how TV works.
No. No, well, sure,
I created the show.
When the show became a hit,
she became a star.
I became a highly-paid
butt monkey.
Well, it's a skill
like anything else.
She wanted me to ride back
in the limo with her
and give me notes
on the next script,
and... you know,
emasculate me
for a couple of hours.
Looks like she struck her head
on the edge of this table.
Possible struggle.
When was the last time
you saw her?
When we wrapped.
I got really drunk.
And then I threw up.
Got drunk again.
Went up to my room,
crawled into bed
and prayed for death.
Mine, not hers.
PHILLIPS:
Jaw flexibility
is minimal.
Just going into rigor.
Puts TOD
around midnight.
Uh... Grissom.
It's a rubber chicken.
Huh.
(shutter clicking)
BRASS:
What are you doing?
Oh, I thought it would make
a nice Christmas card.
Give me that.
Oh, sorry, my bad.
Aw, come on.
You got to say something.
Uh... I suspect
fowl play?
Or, uh, that's poultry evidence?
You know,
something.
Dying is easy.
Comedy's hard.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
And this just in.
Some unbelievable news
from Las Vegas today.
TV's favorite unwed mother
Annabelle Fundt
star of the hit sitcom
Annabelle,
was found dead in her hotel room
this morning.
At this time, we have no details
and authorities are refusing
to comment,
but, of course, we'll have more
details as this story develops.
There you go, Murph.
I'll get it to work.
Water,
sparkling water,
juice...
No booze.
Ditto on the minibar.
SPENCER:
Annabelle wasn't allowed
to consume alcohol
when she works.
Was there a problem?
(paper ripping)
You are all...
against me!
I can't take it
anymore!
You are trying
to sabotage me!
(grunts)
Hey, kid, want to
feel my new boobs?
(no audio)
It was an insurance issue.
I got it from
here, Spencer.
MAN:
Grissom, this guy
just flew in
from L.A.
on the studio jet.
Name's Stewart Little.
It's pronounced, "Lie-tell."
Gil.
We got a closet eater.
(eating loudly)
Was Annabelle bulimic?
Oh, you bet she was.
Spencer, there's
no need to get into...
It's all right.
She can't
hurt us anymore. Yeah.
Yeah, she did
the two-finger dessert,
but at least
the vomit
seemed to take off
what the camera put on.
It's a terrible,
terrible scourge.
Gil.
Found a bottle of urine
in the closet as well.
Did she also
have a drug problem?
Uh, define "problem."
The kind that requires
using other people's urine
to pass a drug test.
Then, yes.
(door opening)
BUD:
Annabelle!
Please, I just want
to kiss her good-bye.
We can't let you
do that, sir.
But she's my wife!
Your what?
Ah, geez.
Mitch.
Yeah, Annabelle and I
were married two days ago.
Oh, I don't
believe that.
Oh, no, it's true.
We had a deal.
She said if I gave up coke,
then we could get married.
But you never
gave up coke.
She didn't know that.
STEWART:
Gentlemen!
The studio--
and both of you--
have a substantial
investment
in Annabelle's image,
so perhaps this discussion
could take place
elsewhere.
(beeping)
Hey, Jim, you're up.
BUD (mouthful):
There it is.
Signed, witnessed and notarized.
BRASS:
You know, it's a
tragic coincidence
that she died two days
after you qualified
for half of what she's worth.
Really? I thought
that was the bright side.
SPENCER:
Are you kidding me?
He's a parasite.
He's a barnacle.
He is the pimple on the ass
of a mediocrity.
(pops lips)
(exhales)
She picked him up
three years ago
in a comedy club
at Sioux City,
hired him to be her driver,
then a writer,
then a producer,
but all he really did
was push his weight around,
get loaded and bang extras
behind Annabelle's back.
I didn't kill her. I love her!
You know, when she called me
to come to her room last night,
she was alive.
But you were newlyweds.
Why'd you sleep
in different rooms?
Well, she had kind of a rule
about that.
She didn't like to look at me
after we had sex.
What do you know
about the chicken?
She didn't like to look
at me during sex, either.
Are you a bad boy?
I'm a bad boy!
Who's your mama?
You're my mama!
Say it.
Mama!
(laughing)
All right,
now make that sound.
(Bud gobbling like chicken)
This is a classic comedy prop.
Goes way back probably
at least to vaudeville.
But you probably
want to know how this ended up
in Annabelle's
throat.
I got no idea.
Last time I saw it,
it was on a stage in L.A.
Are you kidding me?
You put a rubber chicken
in my show?
Do I look like a prop comic?
I am not a prop comic!
Ow!
That was humiliating.
Yeah, you must have felt
like... like an ass.
Of course we're gonna
finish the episode.
Just a couple of second unit
shots to pick up on the lot.
That's it.
Uh-huh. Annabelle Fundt's
final performance.
It's ratings gold.
30 share easy unless they
throw that dancing crap at us.
This way, Mr. Lietel.
Sir, please.
Stay with me, okay?
Beautiful people doing
high-tech police work.
There might be
a series in this.
Oh. Hey, Mr. Little.
have a seat.
"Lie-tell."
Oh. Sorry.
Okay, here we go.
The elevator security cameras
confirm Annabelle's presence
at 11:01 p.m., and
according to the hotel's
key card access log,
she entered her room immediately
after exiting the elevator.
Now, all you need to do is
let us know if you recognize
anybody getting off
on her floor.
Okay?
Okay.
That'd be Bud.
SANDERS:
At 11:06.
Suite was entered
at 11:07 p.m.
He stayed in there
for roughly 20 minutes.
That's consistent
with his statement.
But that's still plenty of time
to kill her.
You know, that might be
one of our writers.
What? You don't know for sure?
LIETEL:
They're writers.
She hires 'em and
she fires 'em.
Who can keep track, right?
STOKES:
And there's Annabelle going out.
Wait a minute.
We never saw her going down.
No, no, no, that's...
Natasha Something-or-other.
That's Annabelle's
assistant/stand-in, whatever.
Quite a resemblance.
Annabelle made her
get plastic surgery
so they'd look more alike.
Paid for it out
of her own pocket.
That's very generous.
Sure.
Let's call it generosity.
Well, Natasha
came back down
at 11:57 p.m.,
carrying a garment bag.
and that's it
until the next morning
when Spencer found the body.
What the heck is she doing?
Going on a midnight laundry run?
You're not asking me
that question.
I mean... that's your
job, right? Because I...
Cap'n, do we have
to do this right now?
I'm on my way
to the airport.
We have surveillance
that places you
in Ms. Fundt's room
around the time of her death,
leaving with a garment bag.
Of course you did.
That's one of my jobs.
I knocked real quiet-like,
and when she didn't answer,
I let myself in, got the bag,
and tiptoed out of there.
What was in the bag?
Wardrobe, silly.
I had to put it on the truck
to go back to L.A.
Did you see Annabelle?
Cap'n.
Miss Annabelle
had a firm rule.
If she's asleep,
don't wake her.
If she's awake,
don't talk to her
till she talks
to you first.
I don't know who
in their right mind
want to talk to
that bitch anyway.
Whoo. That's kinda harsh...
coming from her assistant.
And stand-in,
and photo double
and all-around
whippin' girl.
You have any idea what
that woman put me through?
Tell the doctor to make yours
feel like these!
See? Nice, right?
Okay.
Right and left breast implants.
Check... check.
There are abrasions in
the upper esophagus,
but no vital response
in the tissue.
Then the rubber chicken
was inserted postmortem.
And, thus, not
the cause of death.
It might have been a gag.
Sorry.
Right and left
buttock implants.
High and firm.
That's right. Go ahead.
Cheek... Cheek.
COD subdural hematoma
is the result of a sharp blow
to the back of the skull.
If she hadn't gone quickly,
she'd would have gone slowly.
There's cirrhosis of the liver,
and near perforating
stomach ulcers.
What's the matter, David?
She's got no lady parts.
She had a hysterectomy.
Okay. Um...
Then why was she
using one of these?
Nostalgia?
♪ Extra! Extra! ♪
Just one day after
the tragic and untimely death
of TV superstar Annabelle Fundt,
Extra caught up
with some cast members,
including Emmy Award-winning
costar Megan Kupowski.
This is a profound tragedy.
Annabelle had a huge
impact on all of us,
and she will be deeply missed.
Godspeed, Annabelle.
(dog growling)
Oh. You miss her, too,
don't you, Binky?
Wave good-bye to Annabelle.
Bye-bye.
That time of
the month, huh?
I know. Picking out the
right feminine product
can be so hard.
You gonna mock me
or help me?
I have to choose?
I can't get this to work.
Well, that's probably 'cause you
don't have the right equipment.
You don't, do you?
Ha-ha.
Ha.
You're lucky you're cute.
Annabelle Fundt was dosing
her tampons with vodka.
Does that even work?
Kinda. Even at their
most absorbent,
tampons only hold about
19 grams of fluid,
or about 20 milliliters.
Well, that's enough
for Aunt Flo,
but that is not gonna get
an alcoholic drunk.
Who's Aunt Flo?
Oh. All right.
Well, maybe she was just
doing it to take the edge off,
but what I can't figure out
is how she managed it
because every time
I throw one in here,
it turns into
SpongeBob SquarePants.
You don't take it out
of the applicator first.
Gimme.
Thanks.
All right.
Watch and learn.
There.
That's why they call it
an applicator.
I always wondered
how that worked.
All men do.
So, if Annabelle was using
vodka-soaked tampons
to get drunk,
where was she
getting the booze?
There was none in her suite.
GRISSOM:
According to Henry,
it was full of pure vodka.
Oh.
Possibly a way
of imbibing
without aggravating
her ulcers.
God, I hope she wasn't gargling
with vinegar and baking soda.
Wouldn't do much for plaque.
No.
(shutter clicks)
Hey.
What does this
look like to you?
Hermaphrodite
on roller skates.
A puppy.
(laughs):
No.
Not this. This.
See that?
Shoe impression.
WILLOWS:
Triangular ball, narrow heel.
Looks like a woman's shoe.
Yeah, somebody
stepped in the blood.
I doubt it was the vic.
We got a suspect.
(phone ringing)
Grissom.
Are they willing
to hold the scene?
I'll meet you at the airport.
♪ ♪
Pull the cover off.
Sure thing, Detective.
So much for movie magic.
The show was trying to
finish up the episode
using Annabelle's
photo double.
Simple drive-by.
Second unit stuff.
Car went out of control.
She wrecked.
Paramedics
were on the scene
in minutes.
She was dead
when they pulled her out.
GRISSOM:
She was our prime suspect
in the Annabelle Fundt case.
We wanted to talk to her
when we got the call from you.
You got a Ouija board?
I got something better.
Help!
(crashing)
WOMAN:
Oh, my gosh, is she okay?
So who had access to the car?
Well, actually, it was
Annabelle's personal car.
She leased it, then made
the studio pay her a rental fee
to use it on the show.
A Ferrari?
I thought she played
a struggling single mom.
Oh, they had her
win it
in a radio contest.
For me, that's when the show
jumped the shark.
In any event,
it was on a locked truck
since before the company
left for Vegas.
They were supposed to shoot
that scene in Vegas.
So Annabelle was supposed
to be driving this car.
Yep.
We'll take it to Impound.
The body will go
to Mission Road,
and I'll let you know
what we find.
Thanks.
Hey, Jim.
Yeah?
What does that mean,
"jumping the shark"?
Well, remember the Fonz?
The Fonz?
(woman screams)
Binky! No! Binky, wake up!
Wake up! (sobbing)
Oh, God!
Why, God, why?
Binky! Binky!
(sobbing)
What is happening?
WILLOWS:
I'm sorry. What's a Binky?
Oh, okay. How sad.
L.A. crime lab found
an after-market chip
inside the Ferrari's engine
control system, but no prints.
Well, anyone with a laptop
who knows how to flash an EPROM
can get a car
to do anything they want.
Street racers do it
all the time.
Chips are easy to obtain,
virtually untraceable.
Detective Flores
is keeping us in the loop.
We're gonna do breakfast.
Okay. Don't go all Hollywood
on us, all right?
I'll see you soon.
HODGES:
Hmm, check this out.
This is Bud's wedding
from a couple days ago.
They went for
the "Breath of Nature" package.
WILLOWS:
And you know
this because...?
She's wearing a veil.
There's ivy on the trellis.
That cost extra, you know?
God, it's nice to know
that Annabelle was a romantic.
Mm, I'm not so sure about that.
Oh, and just so you know,
I'm considering this
a working lunch,
so I did not clock out.
Take a gander at this.
Next guy up to be married
catches this on his cell phone,
then he sells it
'cause he realizes what he has.
But he caught more
than he thought he did.
(computer trilling)
Annabelle didn't have
a mole on her chin.
Always a stand-in,
never a bride.
Bud didn't marry Annabelle.
He married Natasha
pretending to be Annabelle.
Well, one thing's for sure.
Neither one of them's
pretending to be dead.
I guess that makes Bud a liar.
Then he's moving up.
A few short years ago,
Bud Parker was just
another Iowa barback
slinging drinks in Sioux City.
Annabelle Fundt
was his ticket out.
It was love at first sight,
Hollywood-style.
Bud climbed from the bottom rung
to the top of the heap
in record time.
Annabelle and me
were made for each other.
You know, she's got my back,
and I've got hers.
More, but less
and funnier!
We share a love
of animals, ThighMasters,
long walks on the beach,
poor people, stuff.
We're very spiritual,
right, Bud?
Oh, yeah.
Dalai Lama.
BRASS:
Nice office.
Yeah, thanks.
Whoa! Hey,
easy on the Emmy there, buddy.
Is that what this is?
Yeah.
Whoa, don't you need
a search warrant for that?
Are these yours?
What was I supposed to do?
She was a mean drunk, but she
was worse
when she was sober.
So you kept her
liquored up
while you schtupped Natasha?
What?
L.A. Coroner's Office
found semen
in Natasha's vaginal canal.
What's the L.A. Coroner's Office
doing
in Natasha's vaginal canal?
Is there something
you want to tell us, Bud?
All right.
That's probably my,
you know, in her...
We know.
So you faked
your wedding;
you used Natasha
as a photo double;
Annabelle dies;
you inherit everything she had;
split it with Natasha.
Nice plan.
No. No, no, no, no.
Well, yeah, that was the plan,
but we didn't kill her.
When Natasha went up to her
room, she was already dead.
Damn!
I was looking forward to this.
(squishing)
Oops.
I think Natasha found her dead
because you killed Annabelle.
Then you killed the only person
who knew about the plan:
Natasha.
Why would I kill Natasha?
Doing her
was like doing Annabelle,
except she didn't yell at me
when I couldn't get it up.
Why'd you reprogram
the computer chip
in her car?
There are computer chips
in cars?
Look, I don't know
who you killed
or who you didn't kill,
but I do know we can hold you
for conspiracy to commit.
You can?
You just admitted it.
I did?
Mike.
I thought these guys
were extras.
Wow. That went
really badly.
So you like him for it?
There's nothing about this guy
I like.
But if he's smart enough
to pull off a double homicide,
he deserves one of these
'cause he's a better actor
than anyone on the show.
SIMMS:
Care to guess what was
on that rubber chicken?
Other than Bud's ass?
I found one unknown
male contributor,
but this guy's DNA
matched the urine
from the water bottle
in the closet.
Okay.
Honey, why don't you
take ten
and go get minty fresh?
ANNABELLE:
I think I will.
Thanks.
Okay, Greg, what do you got?
Well, I was working
my way back from the
time of the murder
to earlier in the day.
Check this out.
WILLOWS:
It's the writing staff?
Around 7:00, four guys go up.
After about a half hour,
three come down,
followed a couple minutes
later by Annabelle.
What happened
to the fourth rider?
I think he's the one
who came down alone
close to midnight.
WILLOWS:
He's drinking
Titan Springs water.
That's the brand bottle
I found at the murder site
filled with urine.
So this guy might have been
waiting for Annabelle
when she came back.
(man panting)
(Annabelle screams)
Looks like a comedy writer
came out of the closet.
I doubt if it's the first time.
I hear Boston Legal's
looking for writers.
How is that a comedy?
It's not. That's why
you'd be perfect for it.
Hmm!
Funny.
Anybody have a contact
at Two And A Half Men?
Ugh! I'd rather sleep with
Annabelle than write that crap.
Annabelle's dead.
I'm saying.
Can we help you?
I'm gonna need to collect
a DNA sample from all of you.
Doesn't sound good.
BRASS:
It's really
not so bad.
Now, we know that the three
of you went up
to Annabelle's suite
around 7:00 P.M.
the night she died.
It's kind of a ritual
on the show.
6:00 to 7:00 is cocktails.
7:00 to 8:00
is bend over and take it.
But there were four of you
in the elevator.
Yeah, me, Don, Eddie,
and the new guy.
Hey.
I'm sorry. Who are you?
Jimmy, new writer.
Hey, Jimmy.
Welcome to hell.
Annabelle and Bud
would hire anybody:
friends, bartenders,
drug dealers.
They'd last a couple weeks,
suck down a few paychecks,
then disappear.
So how do we find
the new guy Jimmy?
Come to think of it,
uh, I haven't seen him
since Vegas.
We figure he snuck
out of the hotel room
while Annabelle
was reaming us out.
You think he's the one
who killed her?
It's kinda looking that way,
isn't it?
Does that, like, make us
accessories to murder?
Not likely.
Aw, damn.
Is it against the law
to tell people we are?
Because we would really like
to do that.
Yes.
(computer trilling)
Excuse me.
If you see that man,
call the number, please?
If you see this guy,
would you call PD for me?
Thank you.
Sir, if you see this man,
call this number, please.
(makes whirring sound)
Sir, see that man,
call that number, please.
(whirring)
If you see this man,
call this number.
(whirring)
Call that number if you see
that man, miss. Thank you.
Call that number
if you see that man.
(whirring)
Rick.
Richard Langford?
(whirring)
You're under arrest.
A mime is a terrible thing
to waste.
♪ Extra! Extra! ♪
One of the main suspects
in the investigation
appears to be Richard Langford,
an actor who, strangely enough,
played a memorable
bit part on the hit TV show.
All right,
good as new.
Are you sure?
Maybe you should
check it again.
No, really, it's completely
totally fixed.
Check it.
Okay.
But Richard Langford's
appearance
on The Annabelle Show
would be his last.
For more than three years,
the fledgling actor was off
the showbiz radar until now.
Oh, listen, man.
I can explain.
Can we talk about this?!
I did not...
No! Stop!
Oh, God!
No! I am an artist, man!
I'm an artist!
I was on television!
They were gonna
make me a regular.
You know...
the funny plumber?
Hmm.
So what happened?
She wanted to have
sex with me.
Who did?
Annabelle.
Then when I told her that
I was married and couldn't,
she had me fired.
And then I couldn't
find any more work
and my wife left me
and I'm living in my car
which is what I wound up
trading to the dude
that owned the robot guy
franchise on that corner.
It's a franchise?
Yeah, yeah, yeah,
we're all over the country.
What were you doing
in Annabelle's closet, Richard?
Well, I-I saw
the show was in town,
and I thought that if maybe
I could talk to her
that she'd give me
another chance, you know?
(laughs):
I mean, what the hell?
I'm not married anymore.
I'd do her
if I absolutely had to.
I know you snuck up the elevator
with the writers. What then?
They barely noticed I was there.
What did I tell you
about this goddamn chicken, huh?
I do not want a prop chicken
in my show.
Did you see the name
on the script?
Ann-a-belle!
Annabelle,
not dumb ch...
I was gonna talk to her
after the other writers left,
and then she left, too,
so I just...
hid in the closet.
(chuckles)
Eating candy bars
and peeing in a bottle.
I know that, too.
What happened
when she got back?
She called Bud.
Are you a bad boy?
I'm a bad boy!
Who's your mama?
RICHARD:
There's some stuff,
once you see it
Mama!
you can't ever unsee it.
I-I-I guess he couldn't
get the job done.
(chuckles)
Sorry, baby. I tried.
Get out.
Get out, you useless
waste of skin!
Get out!
Good night.
Finally, she was alone.
(panting):
Annabelle...
Do I know you?
(unzips zipper, drops pants)
(laughs)
Ah...
plumber guy!
(laughs)
The next thing I know,
she grabs my...
(loud crunch)
Oh...!
It was an accident, man.
I swear to God.
What about the chicken?
What chicken?
(chuckles)
The rubber chicken
with your DNA on it, man.
That chicken.
Yeah, that-that was less of
an accident than the accident...
was an accident.
I-I thought maybe
I could blame it on...
on Bud or one
of the other writers.
If her death was really
an accident, Richard,
why didn't you
just call the police?
Oh, come on, man.
I snuck into her suite.
I-I hid in her closet,
and then she dies?
How's that gonna look
on my resume?
Like premeditated murder.
You know anybody who wants
to buy a robot guy franchise?
So that's it?
Robot-man-closet-stalker guy
gets his package grabbed
and the TV star dies?
It is the classic story.
You wanted to see us, Doc?
Yeah. I was disposing
of Annabelle's medical waste,
and I noticed
something strange.
With hematomas, there's almost
always some fibrous tissue,
but the blood in her brain
never clotted.
She was an alcoholic.
True, but the show
required a physical
every six months
for insurance purposes,
so I went through
her medical records.
Clotting function was normal
even at the height
of her alcoholism.
So no hemophilia, either.
Nope.
(thick Southern accent):
What we have here is
failure to coagulate.
Her blood tested positive
for hemadin with an INR of 4.0.
That's slightly higher
than clinical levels.
Are you sure that
there's no other reason
why she might have been
taking blood thinners?
Uh, she had ulcers.
Blood thinner
would never be prescribed.
STOKES:
Hemadin's not
really a recreational drug.
How'd it get into her system?
I retested all the food
and drink in her suite,
and there was hemadin
in her vodka-filled
mouthwash bottle.
So somebody was poisoning her.
Yeah, somebody
who knew
she was doing more
than swishing her mouthwash.
If Annabelle hadn't have had
these high levels of hemadin
in her blood,
could she still be alive?
Well, her head injury
was serious.
But I'd have to say
the blood thinner in her system
could well
have been the difference
between her living and dying.
So the clot doesn't thicken,
but the plot does.
Get this.
L.A. Coroner's
Office called.
There was hemadin
in Natasha's system as well.
Probably from drinking
Bud's tainted vodka.
So Annabelle and Natasha
were ingesting the same poison.
Other than Bud,
who knew Annabelle
was drinking her mouthwash?
I know who.
BRASS:
Working late?
No. Just saying good-bye
to a wonderful part of my past.
We'd like to talk to you.
Oh, of course.
About what?
GRISSOM:
Hemadin,
among other things.
Oh, a miracle drug.
It's what kept Binky alive.
Well... until yesterday.
It also killed
Annabelle and Natasha.
Really?
How odd.
We checked
with your vet.
He said you ordered
extra refills of hemadin
because your dog
spitting it out?
Yes. Fussy, silly,
sad little Binky.
Oh, I miss him so.
Not Annabelle?
Not so much.
Take a look at
this, will you?
WOMAN (on video):
Rolling. Rolling, rolling.
Honey, why don't you take ten
and go get minty fresh.
I think I will.
Thanks.
DIRECTOR:
And action.
Minty fresh.
You knew about the alcohol
in Annabelle's mouthwash,
and she knew
you knew about it.
But what she
didn't know
is that you were spiking it
with your dog's blood thinners.
Bravo, gentlemen.
You should register that,
because around here,
the walls have ears.
That's going to end up
in somebody's script,
and guess who won't get credit.
You.
BRASS:
Yeah, we're not done.
So when Annabelle
wouldn't kick off
soon enough
to suit you,
you tampered with
the computer chip in her car,
knowing that even
a minor accident
would cause her
to bleed out and die.
But the scene kept
getting pushed,
and in the end,
it was Natasha, not Annabelle
who was at the wheel.
This is utterly fantastic.
And this malevolent
second banana knows
how to do this because...
she's a child genius--
National Honor Society,
Mensa, Yale summa cum laude,
all that crap.
I didn't say that.
No, I'm coloring
the character in for you.
Okay, yeah, so she's a brainiac
and blah, blah, blah,
but that still doesn't explain
how she got
the specific expertise
to program
the car's engine control chip.
(sighs)
Oh!
I've got it.
She has
a degenerate
Uncle Giuseppe
who works as an automotive
software engineer in Rome.
She does?
You do?
And he showed her how to do it
in exchange
for certain unsavory favors.
Oh, wait a minute.
That sounds like a, uh...
what do you call it?
Writers' contrivance.
Yeah, yeah,
it's a bit of a reach,
but you get one per episode.
So they send Interpol
to arrest the guy.
How did they know
how to find him?
Could you please not get
bogged down in details?
Anyway,
so they're escorting the guy
in handcuffs
onto the plane at da Vinci
International Airport,
and, and... kaboom!
He's killed
in a terrorist attack
by Basque separatists.
Shouldn't Basque
separatists be in Spain?
Oh, it's great.
It's got everything you'd want:
narrative propulsion,
memorable characters,
a felicitous intertwining of
the random and the deliberate.
Just one question.
What's that?
What's her motivation?
Maybe she was tired of all the
constant abuse and humiliation.
GRISSOM:
Yeah, she's not
getting any younger.
She knows how Hollywood deals
with aging actresses.
BRASS:
Yeah, she knows time
is not on her side.
She figures
she'll bump off the bitch
and move herself up
to number one.
You're very good,
but you've still got a problem.
What's that?
No hard evidence.
No fingerprints, no hairs
you can stick in a machine
that spits out
the kind of truth
juries lap up
like a saucer of warm milk.
How do you know we're not saving
the best for the last act?
Are you?
Because if you've got it,
bring it on.
Just as I thought.
Bubkes.
So you figure,
"What the hell? Give it a shot."
You cook up this weak gruel
of spindly circumstances
and wild conjecture
just to see if you can rattle
Banana 2.0's cage,
just to see what she gives up,
but she's way too cool
and in the end
reveals nothing.
She simply smiles and says,
"Gentlemen, if you'll excuse me,
I have a 13-episode commitment
from CBS to attend to."
It's called Megan's Family.
And with that,
she and her lover-
slash-executive producer turn
and make their grand exit.
Hey.
We'll be watching you.
Mondays-- 9:30,
8:30 Central.
Forget it, Gil.
It's Burbank.
(grunts)
Uh, whoa, oh.
Oh.
Ooh, whoa.
Whoa, ugh.
Ugh.
Ugh, that looks bad.