♪ ♪
BRASS:
Guy in a boat spotted him
this morning.
No witnesses.
STOKES:
How did he get up there?
I think maybe somebody
gave him a lift.
Okay, Super, I'm ready to cut.
(grunts)
Lacerations to his chest.
Stabbed and then hanged.
I guess he wasn't
dead enough.
Rope burns
on both palms.
He probably tried
to pull himself up.
Lift his shirt up,
will you, David?
Whoa!
PHILLIPS:
I... thought this...
guy was a guy.
Check the plumping.
Full male genitalia.
Mutilated tranny strung up
in a tree.
(yelling and screaming)
MAN:
Go! Go! Go! Go!
Bet I know how he got up there.
and TOYOTA. Moving Forward.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
♪ ♪
Lacerations aren't deep enough
to have killed him.
Ligature furrows canted upward.
Scratches... consistent
with struggling to get free.
Preliminary C.O.D.'s
suffocation from hanging.
GRISSOM:
18 years old.
(camera shutter clicking)
Brian Towne.
Lived in Verdant Glen.
Hmm. 20 years ago, my wife
wanted to buy out there,
but there was no 215 freeway
back then.
The commute
would've killed me.
No physical signs
of Klinefelter syndrome.
So he's not an XXY.
ROBBINS:
No, he's all skin and muscle.
These can't be fatty deposits...
This is glandular tissue.
His mammaries are swollen.
Gynecomastia.
Pre-op transsexuals
take a lot of estrogen.
I'll run
an expanded tox panel,
send out
for a hormone screen.
LILY:
It wasn't easy
being a Copa girl.
When the curtain came down,
we had to stay and decorate
the Sands Casino
into the wee hours.
Ugly guys do gamble more
when there's pretty girls
to look at.
They weren't all ugly.
And your father,
in that tuxedo...
giving me the eye,
trying not to grin,
'cause he thought floor managers
had to be tough.
So, Mom,
who made the first move?
Sam.
Stuck this five-dollar chip
in my hand
and said, "Take it,
you can't miss."
I shot craps all night with
Peter Lawford and cleaned up.
I was right here the day
Sam opened the Rampart,
his first casino.
(crowd cheers)
And we were going to be
right here again
when he opened the Eclipse.
I know you wanted
to be buried with this,
but I just couldn't let go.
I can now.
They're going to build
your dream on it, honey.
Take it.
You can't miss.
(car horns honking)
(lively swing music playing)
(explosions)
(sirens wailing)
I don't care if it's
Jimmy Louise Hoffa.
FOREMAN:
I want you to grab
that jackhammer
and bust up this concrete.
Supervisor Willows
from Crime Lab.
What's going on here?
Worker found a body.
MAN:
I'm just following protocol.
You find a body,
call you guys.
Yeah.
How do you know
this is one
of the Marquis Chimps?
'Cause they played the Frontier
in Ronald Reagan's act.
And only humans
have a saddle joint.
In fact, that's how
we were able to swing
out of trees and end up here.
Opposable thumbs.
Well, these casinos weren't
built by saints, you know.
Oh, I know.
My dad built this one.
(keypad beeps)
MAN (on phone):
Las Vegas Crime Lab.
Yeah, this is CSI Willows.
I need to hand a case off
to Swing.
Conflict of interest.
(camera shutters clicking)
(objects clattering in drawer)
(objects rattling in box)
(camera shutter clicking)
I want to know who did this.
Well, that's what we're
trying to find out.
Mrs. Towne, it
would be of help
if you could tell me
a little bit more
about your son Brian.
He was kind... and sweet
and... didn't have
an enemy in the world.
What about friends?
Not really.
He was always so busy
putting in overtime
down at the...
water treatment plant.
He loved to take long runs.
Exercise is a natural cure
for depression.
Was he depressed?
I mean, there's a lot
of medications here.
Are these Brian's?
No. These are all mine.
I had a mastectomy
eight years ago.
Cancer came back
three months ago.
Oh.
I'm... I'm sorry to hear that.
I never thought
I'd outlive my son.
Is there anything else?
Did you know a person
with the last name Cyden?
C-Y-D-E-N?
Paul Cyden.
He's a family friend;
he lives a couple blocks over.
So Brian knew him, too?
Oh, he was like a father to
Brian after my husband died.
Why are you asking
about Paul?
Ma'am, your son had
a good deal of cash
stashed away in his bedroom.
Was he saving up for something?
I don't know.
What's going on here?
Mrs. Towne, we think
Brian was saving up
for a sex change operation.
Were you aware
of this?
My son was not a freak.
No, I didn't say that.
Ma'am, we're not trying
to upset you in any way.
I volunteered to let you
in my house!
And now I want you to leave.
I want you to leave right now!
In college, I wanted
to be an archeologist,
until I did a summer
on a dig in Tunisia.
Hot. But that got me
into Forensics.
What made you
pick Vegas?
Well, it, uh,
it kind of picked me.
(camera shutter clicking)
Hey, check this out.
Turquoise and silver beads.
I got the matching necklace at
the Indian market in Santa Fe.
SIDLE:
Everybody stop!
Stop what
you're doing!
What is the problem now?
We have just
found evidence
that this might be
a Native American burial site.
We have to notify the
Inter-Tribal Council.
Until they say so,
nobody touches anything.
Hey, Grissom.
About your
hanging victim.
The one with
the "chesticals."
The man boobs...
Uh, the...
gynecomastia, sorry.
Quant hormone report.
Androgen's low.
Estradiol's high.
It's 250 picograms
per milliliter.
Arogesterone, too.
Estrogen level
is five times
the normal amount
for an adult male.
It's consistent with
a pre-op transsexual.
Yeah, but there's no other
pre-op drugs in his system.
No spironolactone,
no flutamide, progesterone.
Maybe he's a
"do-it-yourselfer."
Okay.
(phone ringing)
Hello?
BRASS: Paul Cyden?
This is he.
Paul Cyden.
I'm Detective Jim Brass,
this is Catherine Willows,
from the Crime Lab.
I'd like to ask you
a couple questions
about Brian Towne.
What a great kid.
I can't believe he's gone.
When was the last time
you talked with him?
Oh, uh, honestly,
I don't remember.
Oh, you don't remember
yesterday?
Calling him? Texting him?
Brian occasionally does odd jobs
for me.
How odd?
(nervous chuckle)
I, uh, study water.
I'm a hydrologist, retired,
but I still
do consulting.
Brian was helping me
with a project.
Well, it seems to me,
according to your messages,
Brian was the project.
You're way off base.
Then you won't mind giving us
your fingerprints and DNA?
Not if you have a court order.
(cell phone ringing)
Look, you can do this
the hard way or the easy way.
But trust me,
we're going to get this done.
Yeah, what's up, Doc?
Yeah, Brian Towne's mother
is here.
She wants to see the body.
Okay. If anything of interest
pops up,
why don't you text me?
ROBBINS:
All right.
He needed a haircut.
(sniffles)
(sobs)
(various mechanisms
whirring, beeping)
Are you lurking
around here for results?
No. No, no.
I wouldn't do that.
I was just, uh... I was
getting a cup of coffee.
Actually.
You can come in.
Why, do you got something?
I do.
I got a two-fer.
I got epithelials from the rope
from multiple contributors,
and one of them...
drank from the
bloody beer bottle.
STOKES:
Larry Ludwig.
Convicted of aggravated assault
and DUI.
Bring up his
parole record.
Okay.
(computer trilling)
STOKES:
There you go.
He works at the same water
treatment plant as my victim.
Thought you were getting coffee.
Right.
You sure you fellas
don't want masks?
The smell in here makes
some people puke.
Mr. Ludwig, can we
see your palms, please?
What, you gonna tell me
my future or something?
Depends on what I see.
I don't think so.
Gentlemen?
Hey, I was just getting
back to work, Mr. Quinn.
Jonah Quinn.
General Manager.
I'm Warrick Brown.
And I'm Nick Stokes, we're
with the Vegas Crime Lab.
We're here investigating the
death of one of your employees,
Brian Towne.
I told them I had
nothing to say, sir.
QUINN:
You have my permission
to question and search
any of my employees.
They don't have warrant,
Mr. Quinn.
They're just... they're
just fishing around, sir.
Anybody who doesn't
want to cooperate
with the police in
trying to find out
who killed Brian can clean out
their lockers and search
for another job!
Weren't they asking
you a question?
Go ahead and
take off your gloves.
Show us your palms.
BROWN:
Well, now,
they look like rope burns.
Did you know that there's
a Paiute reservation
in the heart of Las Vegas?
It's only an acre, but it's
right up on North Main.
Do you think that we
found the bones
of one of their
ancestors?
Well, the fusing
of the plates
and shape of the skull
indicate a 30-year-old
of the Mongoloid race.
Which does include
Native Americans.
And Southeast Asians,
Pacific Islanders.
But take a look
at the teeth.
I don't see any dental work.
But there are caries.
Cavities.
Right.
Teeth from ancient tribal graves
usually have
distinctive wear marks,
uh, grooves from pipe-
smoking, rope-making--
but no cavities.
You look disappointed.
I was... hoping, just once,
Vegas would have
to honor its past.
STOKES:
These tire treads were under
a tree where Brian's
body was found.
They're from a
Chevy Colorado.
Isn't that what you drive?
Yeah.
You're putting a nice polish
on that wedding band.
Hey, this is between us, right?
Yeah, absolutely.
Oh, yeah.
All right... I did see
Brian last night.
Me and my buddy,
we started out at a bar,
threw a few back, you know,
met some ladies.
And the hot one, she said,
"Let's go swimming."
(indistinct talking, laughing)
Brian. What's shaking?
Not much.
Anybody want one?
Yes, please.
So the girls, they wanted
to play Tarzan,
so I pull my pickup truck
underneath the tree,
I grabbed a rope
out of my utility box,
and we all started stripping
down and everything...
(laughing)
Whoo!
Come on,
it's fun!
(whooping)
Oh, my God.
What?
(laughing)
I mean, the guy had boobs, man.
I mean, you could see 'em
right through the T-shirt.
I mean, we were all kind of
cracking up about it,
but um... uh...
it kind of broke the
party up a little bit.
No, you kind of broke up
the party, man,
when you cut him up
with a beer bottle
and you hanged
him in a tree.
Hey, man, I mean...
he ran off and we left.
All right, I-I-I
don't know what else
I can tell you.
I mean, you can ask Tony--
he works with me, too.
Where did you go?
I went to the...
I went to a motel with
one of, one of the girls.
These girls have names?
Yeah, mine
was, uh...
She was named after
some city in Texas.
I don't know, like, uh...
Dallas or Houston or
something like that.
The other one, she really
wasn't that hot,
so I don't know
what her name was.
You better hope
we find these girls.
STOKES:
We better not find
any of Brian's blood
in your flatbed.
Wow!
The original plans
for the Rampart.
Opening day,
New Year's Eve, 1964.
Half of the hotel tower
was still under construction,
but Sam decided
to have the party anyway.
He's got the Midas touch,
and help from the
boys in Kansas City.
This is the ultimate.
Don't you have work to do?
Deal me in.
Well...
the workers found
the bones here...
which corresponds to this area.
Bottom of the
construction shaft.
Wonder if it's Gus
"the Beauty" Finkel.
Snitch, disappeared in '64.
The skull shape is Mongoloid.
Maybe it's Eddie Chang,
the Peking Pimp.
Caught Dean at the Sands,
went out for eggs,
never came back.
Did the Peking Pimp
ever wear anything like this
on his arm?
Nope. Just French cuffs
and platinum blondes.
Careful with those.
They're like the Dead Sea
Scrolls of Las Vegas.
I have to go back to the scene.
I'm off the clock.
You, uh, need a hand?
67.5 inches.
(sighs):
Not the Peking Pimp.
He was only five-two.
It looks like every bone
in his body is broken.
(camera shutter clicking)
Check out the third
vertebrosternal rib,
left side.
Isn't that a bullet hole?
Exit wound.
Good call.
Document it.
Nothing says "Mob hit"
like shot in the chest, thrown
down a construction shaft,
and tucked in under
a concrete blanket.
For real?
My first Mob hit.
Cool.
You know,
only the bones at the point
of impact should be broken.
Then the implosion
must have busted up
the rest of him.
Hey, Ronnie?
Will you take a picture of this
for me, please?
Yeah.
(camera shutter clicking)
It looks like...
treated hide.
Buckskin.
Maybe your M.E.
was wrong.
Well, only if the ancient tribes
used sewing machines.
The stitches are uniform.
SANDERS:
You know, the showroom had this
Wild West Revue
with cowboys,
and horses, and rifles,
a real stagecoach.
And Indians
who shot flaming arrows
that ripped off
the dance hall girls' clothes.
It ran from the day
the Rampart opened
until 1976.
An Indian playing
an Indian?
When I was growing up, there
weren't any lakes in Vegas,
just hotel swimming pools.
(knocking on door)
I think Mr. Cyden
might be dodging us.
Call in a 419.
(camera shutter clicking)
So you think that's a message
or his dinner?
Well, that's carp.
Nobody really
eats those.
Body's in full rigor.
Been dead at least ten hours.
Appears to be...
one, two, three gunshot wounds
to the torso.
Probably rules out suicide.
(grunts)
No exit wounds.
STOKES:
I don't see a gun
or cartridge casings anywhere.
He has some fairly dense
gunshot residue patterns.
Shooter was only
a couple of feet away,
practically face-to-face.
No signs of forced entry,
no signs of struggle.
I bet he knew his killer.
Maybe the same person
who killed the tranny
killed the boyfriend.
Offer to buy his house
dated... yesterday.
Who tears up an offer
in this tough market?
"Purchaser: Jonah Quinn."
That's Brian's boss.
I met him.
This notebook charts
hormone levels.
No names, just numbers.
There's over 40
test subjects here.
If this guy was running some
kind of underground clinic here,
then where are the drugs?
These could be hormones.
Warrick found vials like that
in Brian's bedroom.
Check that freezer.
Carpe diem.
Lots of them.
Numbered and dated.
Shoot me a number.
"R-41"
"June 20, 2007."
Why would he be giving
hormones to fish?
SIDLE:
Hodges?
Here's the problem...
You know, that's just
what Mom says
when all I ask is to come home
for Thanksgiving.
My John Doe is from 1964.
Well, to quote Sherlock Sanders,
"This town was built
on dead bodies."
The National Missing Persons
Database
only lists four persons in '64,
none of which are a match.
It might help if we knew
where he was from.
Do I look like
the Ghost Whisperer?
Every geographic area
has specific levels
of oxygen isotopes
due to rainfall,
climate and vegetation.
And you can identify
those isotopes in bones.
You do know that those isotopes
will only tell you
where he spent the last three
years or so of his life.
I'll take it.
It's more then we have now.
If this works,
I write the paper
for the Forensics Journal,
sole credit.
Deal.
Me and my big mouth.
♪ ♪
(machine whirring)
Sara told me
to document the detritus,
but I see you beat me to it.
Oh, sorry, yeah, I kind
of got carried away,
but look at this-- it's
the vic's right hand.
He was holding on to
something and when they poured
the concrete
on top of him,
it made kind of a fossil.
Whatever it was, we must have
collected it, right?
It's definitely not a gun.
No, you didn't
find one of those.
Cigarette lighter?
No.
Hey.
It's film.
Uh, 35 millimeters
used to come in
a screw-top metal
can like this.
Whatever's on it
must be important enough
for Mr. Bones to hang on to
it while taking a header.
Later.
JOHNSON:
Black and white
Tri-X stock.
It's pretty grainy.
Photographers like it
'cause you can shoot fast.
It's like finding pictures
of Lincoln at Ford's Theatre.
The party was
on the rooftop.
Bring up that last shot
on the roll.
Hmm.
Let's see if we can take
a better look at that.
(typing)
Looks like the casino take
on opening day.
Everybody got a cut--
the feds, the state--
and something called Fergus.
GRISSOM:
I love it when
you dress up.
(Sidle laughs)
Well, you know,
whatever it takes to
get some time with you.
How's the study going?
Any sign of Colony
Collapse Disorder?
Nope, so far it's healthy.
(clearing throat):
Nothing too healthy
about smoking.
(coughs)
Well, the scent confuses
the guard bees.
They won't emit
the pheromone
that tells the colony
there's an intruder.
Don't worry, he's harmless.
Who's who?
These are
the workers--
infertile females.
They don't sting?
No, not unless you swat one,
or close one up in your hand,
or freak out.
Go ahead, take off your glove.
Eh... all right, I trust you.
See?
It's cool.
(weak laugh)
The worker bees
defend the hive,
procure the pollen,
make the honey,
nurture the larvae and pupae
in each of these
brood cells.
You know,
maybe we should get married.
SIDLE:
Ouch!
Oh, oh...
Ow.
I'm sorry.
(laughs)
No, no, don't, don't,
don't pick it out.
Makes it worse, releases the
venom into the bloodstream.
It's better
to scrape it.
So, uh... what do you think,
you know, about...
Yes.
Let's do it.
Yeah?
(laughs)
Hi, Sara.
You look
like you're having a good day.
Thanks.
Got your
isotope results.
My John Doe lived
in Southeast Asia?
Yeah, uh, more specifically,
southern Vietnam.
Like I said,
this test only dates back
to the last three years
of his life.
In '64... soldier?
Consultant, refugee?
Thanks. Hm.
Let me know if you get an I.D.
It'd be a great touch
for the article.
Hey, what are you up to?
Nothing.
Why?
What's in the cooler?
Carp.
Paul Cyden died
holding one.
He had a freezer
full of them,
some kind of an experiment.
Huh.
I can process those
fish if you like.
Do I know how
to turn you on or what?
Hey.
Heard you were
looking for me.
Yeah, our friend Larry Ludwig--
he's sharp as a marble,
but his alibi checked out.
We found the motel
and the girl.
Really?
(sighing):
What's her name?
Tucson.
Ah, yes.
Tucson, the capital of Texas.
(both chuckling)
Well, Paul Cyden's DNA and
fingerprints finally arrived.
Well, I'll run it, but
I don't think it'll matter.
I think Brian killed himself.
You think he just climbed that
big ol' tree all by himself?
Yeah.
Okay, yeah.
What about the mutilation?
Self-inflicted.
It took a while,
but Mandy was able to recover
some prints
from the beer bottle,
but it came back to Brian.
So this was a hate crime.
Yeah.
He hated himself.
(machine beeping)
Yes?
Oh, sorry,
just a bad habit
from when we worked
the Miniature case together.
That was fun, wasn't it?
I thought so.
What do you see?
Well, those are
eggs-- it's a girl.
And those white organs
would be gonads.
Male and female parts.
Simultaneous hermaphroditism?
Stop me if you
already know this,
but some fish do change sex
naturally.
Not carp.
I heard of a study
when I was attending
a forensics consortium in D.C.
Feminized male bass were found
in the wastewater effluent
of the Potomac River.
It's the water.
Yeah, it was full
of excreted pharmaceuticals
and what they called
"personal care products,"
all of which supposedly altered
the endocrine system
of the fish and their young.
Good, Hodges.
Well, now that we're
working together again...
...take at least
two organ samples
along with blood.
Send them with
these water samples
to our clinical lab
for hormone quants.
You got it, partner.
LILY:
Melvin Fergus.
He was
a gaming commissioner.
"Honest Melvin."
Well, it looks
like Honest Melvin
was on the take.
Bribing a public
official could cost you
your gaming license.
Maybe our dead guy
found out about it
and somebody found out about
him finding out about it.
Who was this dead guy?
Some wisenheimer with
extortion on the brain.
Maybe a reporter.
Hi, Lily.
Hi.
Uh, Wendy ran that tooth.
Pre-CODIS, but DNA confirms
that our John Doe
was Native American,
so it was
one Indian's burial ground.
There was a reporter
and I'm pretty sure
he was an Indian.
Lee George.
He'd just come back
from Vietnam
for Life magazine
and he was doing
a piece on Vegas.
Do you remember if
he was at the party?
Yeah, in this little
Indian costume--
bracelets on his biceps,
and boy,
did he have biceps.
Trust me.
If anybody hurt him,
it was Benny Dunbar,
Sam's bodyguard.
That lump in his jacket
ain't a heart full of love.
(lively swing music playing,
crowd cheering)
I'll take that camera,
kemosabe.
(yells)
Either Benny tossed him
or he jumped.
We'll never know.
This is great
stuff for my book.
Your what?
Oh, this little piece
on Vegas history--
stories that didn't
make the papers.
Honey, if you need
to know anything, just ask me.
I was there.
Well, how about if I take
you to dinner tonight?
A bottle and a bird.
We'll talk about
the Peking Pimp.
LILY:
Eddie Chang.
They shipped him
home in pieces.
GRISSOM:
20 years ago, Verdant Glen
was far enough outside Vegas
to get the right to use
well water for drinking.
They also got approval to remove
waste water at a private plant.
There, it was cleaned,
creating "grey water,"
which was used for
secondary purposes--
watering lawns,
washing cars,
everything but drinking.
The treatment plant then
stored excess grey water
in the reservoir.
Where they let the kids
fish and swim.
GRISSOM: It passed
every water quality test.
WILLOWS: And the carp
from Paul Cyden's freezer had
high levels of estrogen
plus other prescription drugs.
GRISSOM:
Brian's level and tox panel
correlate to the carp.
Cyden was collecting
water samples
from the reservoir,
the tap,
and the treatment plant.
Thanks to Brian.
According to Cyden's
research, the hormone levels
in the tap water are
nearly equal to the water
in the reservoir.
I thought they drink
ground water.
They do.
Cyden was convinced
that the ground water
was contaminated.
How?
He discovered
that the reservoir
was improperly lined,
allowing the grey water
to leech
into the ground water.
STOKES;
Well, if that's the case,
then why didn't the other boys
develop breasts?
There's a
good chance
that others have been affected,
especially children
who were born
to women who were living there
while they were pregnant.
Because the womb
is the only place
a human lives
in fluid...
like a fish.
That reservoir
is supposed to be lined
to prevent contamination.
Obviously,
it's not.
Or the lining's defective.
Which is the decision I
think Cyden had come to
right before he was shot.
You don't know
where he got those samples.
Cyden could have pulled them
from raw sewage for all I know.
And just
for the record,
that reservoir
was built to code.
You show me one complaint,
one documented illness
from that water.
What about Brian Towne?
Listen...
it's a tragedy...
but his mother
has breast cancer.
You don't think it's that gene
pool that might be polluted?
BRASS: Let me ask
you something.
Why did you offer to
pay such a big price
for Paul Cyden's house?
He's a nut.
He was trying to sink me.
His research was wrong,
but perception
is reality these days.
I admit it.
I was trying to buy him off.
Would have been money
well spent.
But he turned you down.
Is that why you shot him?
I mean, with Brian gone,
you're in the clear.
Look, I don't need a gun;
I've got lawyers.
And I would like
to speak to them now.
Here's the bullets
pulled from Paul Cyden.
Thanks.
Mm-hmm.
Well, all three
are jacketed hollow points
with a center post.
Hydra-Shok.
Only one company makes them--
Federal.
You know what?
Cath, I found a box
of this same ammo
in Brian Towne's bedroom.
Five bullets missing.
Got five lands and grooves,
right-hand twist.
Could've been fired from
a Smith and Wesson,
Ruger, or a Taurus.
Brian bought a Ruger SP 101
revolver two weeks ago.
Damn.
The mother had
access to that gun
and motive.
LYNN TOWNE:
I was too busy
taking care of me...
to see what was wrong with him.
The signs were there.
Mrs. Towne,
don't blame yourself.
You had a teenager who was
depressed and not communicating
and you push too hard
and they pull away...
I should have pushed.
If I had gone through his
room before he died...
maybe then...
Is that when you found his gun?
I was trying to understand why.
I went through
his e-mails.
Paul was taking him to L.A.
I trusted him, and
all those years
that he pretended
to be our friend...
He killed my son.
Mrs. Towne...
he was trying to save your son,
not hurt him.
We found this letter
on Paul's computer.
You need to read it.
PAUL CYDEN:
"I have decided to alert you
"to this grave matter
prior to contacting the EPA.
"It is
my professional conclusion
"that the water
in this community
"contains unsafe levels
of pharmaceutical contaminants,
"which have caused
irreparable harm
"to wildlife and humans.
"One specific example
is the case of Brian Towne.
"His endocrine system
and physical body
"have been 'feminized'
due to chronic ingestion
of the water at Verdant Glen."
He was going
to blow the whistle.
I think that's what Paul
was trying to explain to you
when you went over
to confront him.
I worked two jobs
to keep us in our house
because...
because Brian loved it so much.
And being there
is what killed him.
WOMAN:
The feds
have already swooped in
to investigate
the water problem.
Do they plan
to prosecute Jonah Quinn?
They'll try, but Quinn
isn't the only one involved.
Verdant Glen is now
owned by a conglomerate--
the Altimera World Group.
They'll bring in experts
to contradict the research,
discredit witnesses.
They'll say that
there are chemicals
in everything that we
eat, touch, breathe.
It'll be in
litigation for years.
What about Brian's mother?
Are you going
to prosecute her?
Did you recover
the murder weapon,
find her prints
in blood at Cyden's house,
or get a signed confession?
Her son's gun
plus motive--
that's not enough?
She's a widow
with breast cancer
who lost her only kid.
(sighs)
No way I'd get her
in front of a jury
and ask them to convict.
Nice work though.
Lynn Towne goes free.
It's all
out of our hands now.
That's not enough for me.
If their lawyers can
hog-tie the EPA for years,
someone's got to
go around them.
They've got to take Brian's
story and the research
to the press.
I mean, if... if
it's happened here,
what's to say there aren't
other Brians out there?
You can't give information
about a case to the media.
You'll get fired.
As a mother, maybe I don't care.