♪ ♪
(shutter whirring)
We've got two entry wounds...
...and two exit wounds.
Through-and-throughs.
Any ID on her?
No wallet,
no purse,
no cell.
Brass is tracking down
the lease.
None of the neighbors
seem to know her.
Buildings like these
get a lot of transients.
People who tend to keep
to themselves.
Looks like the drawers have been
rifled through.
Maybe she walked in
on a robbery in progress.
Yeah, except there's no sign
of forced entry.
One, two, three, four,
five, six,
seven casings,
which means
there's seven bullets
to look for.
Got a strange blood drop.
It's pretty far
from the vic.
Could belong
to the suspect.
It's circular.
No directionality.
Suspect would have had to be
standing perfectly still.
It's gravitational.
Greg, could you get
the Hawkeye, please?
Here you go.
Mitch, could you check
the apartment
immediately above this one?
You got it, Doc.
Mack, James,
upstairs.
(footsteps on stairs)
MITCHELL:
LVPD. Open up!
(banging)
Open the door!
Get the ram.
(door crashes open)
It looks like this crime
has a second story.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
(garbled radio transmission)
Maria Espinosa,
organ donor.
Heart was in the right place.
Unfortunately, her head
was in the wrong place.
No exit wound.
Bullet probably hit bone
and fragmented.
Okay.
So a stray bullet rips
through the floor and
Mrs. Espinosa winds up
collateral damage.
SANDERS:
Hey, guys.
I found something.
What do you
got, Greg?
I said
what do you got?
Urine.
There's no sign
of any pets in here.
(flashlight beeps)
Maybe the shooter freaked out
and wet himself.
Not exactly a hardened criminal.
♪ ♪
You know, the bullet trajectory
and the location of the
facial wound suggest
that she was in this position
when she was shot.
She was probably trying
to hear
what was going on downstairs.
MAN:
Shut up!
Guess it doesn't pay
to be a nosy neighbor.
Yeah, but Brass said that the
neighbors heard the gunshots,
but they didn't hear
any raised voices
or arguing.
What was she listening to?
Tramp stamp.
Looks more like a tramp belt.
Help me roll her.
So, hot girl
with dollar-sign tats
and a mostly empty apartment.
Prostitute, right?
Maybe.
Maybe she just
loves money.
You know, it's the love of money
that is the root
of all evil.
Most people think
it's just the money.
Oh, sage.
(phone rings)
Washroom.
Hey, Catherine,
are you collecting trace
from Blondie's body?
As we speak.
So I've collected seven bullets
and seven shell casings
from the apartment
where she was shot.
So what's the problem?
One of these bullets is supposed
to be in Mrs. Espinosa.
Well, maybe you recovered a
bullet from a different event.
Maybe.
Have you checked Blondie
for GSR?
Hang on-- not yet.
Sodium rhodizonate test
on right hand.
Positive for GSR.
She had a gun of her own.
(siren wails in distance)
Ballistics confirms
that all these
nine-millimeter casings
were fired in the same weapon,
but Doc Robbins pulled
this bullet fragment
from Mrs. Espinosa.
It's cannelured.
So...
Blondie had a revolver.
Hence no shell casings.
Okay, so she goes back
to her apartment
packing heat,
and somebody's already there
waiting to light her up.
(two gunshots)
She gets off a couple
of desperate rounds and...
one shot goes
through the ceiling,
accidentally killing
Mrs. Espinosa.
Welcome to the O.K. Corral.
(phone rings)
Yeah, Jim?
I just got off the phone
with the apartment manager.
Yeah?
Did you get an ID on Blondie?
It's not her apartment.
The name on the lease
is Kellen Tyford.
Drops?
The nightclub promoter?
Yeah, and get this.
He leases
the upstairs apartment, too.
That's a lot of apartments
for a guy who's getting
free room and board.
Well, well, well.
What's a convict to do?
Check and mate.
Whoo!
He played
right into it.
(chuckles)
MAN:
Oh, man,
that was...
Did you see that?
I totally got him.
Looks like something
more than forensics
be jamming a brother
up in here.
Man, y'all some
jinxes, man.
You know,
this is a setup.
Don't you get it?
Ivy League
college student
versus a high school dropout
convict.
You got no chance.
And so said a jury
of your peers.
Look, eight months on a
weak-ass weapons charge?
It's a vacation.
Vacation, huh?
So who's this?
Your house-sitter?
We found her at your apartment
over on Vegas Valley.
What's her name?
Jessica Jaynes.
J.J. everybody calls her.
But what happened to her?
She drowned.
So what was she doing
at your apartment?
Don't know.
You pimping her out, Superfly?
Pimping her out?
Nah, pimping ain't easy,
and you know I'm all
about the easy, okay?
J.J. used to come
to my club.
She was a club rat.
Sometimes she
worked atmosphere.
Oh, atmosphere.
What's that, like turning
into a smoke machine?
No, more like
an ATM machine.
You sit her
on a couch,
tourists start
to buy her drinks,
she makes me money.
Yeah, especially when
the tourist leaves with her.
So what's your cut, Easy?
Look, if the customers
like the atmosphere...
(chuckles)
...then I try to
Chuck Woolery that.
Okay?
I want my customers happy.
You know any unhappy
customers, Chuck?
Look at her.
She even looks good
in that picture.
Yeah, I admit,
she looks a whole lot better
than Mrs. Espinosa upstairs.
Who did it?
If I knew that,
I wouldn't have driven
all the way out here
to this frying pan
in the desert to ask you.
This woman took care of me
when I was a kid.
Went homeless a couple
of years ago...
...so I moved her into my house.
When the tax dudes took that,
I had to rent the apartments.
Top bunk was hers,
bottom was mine...
Figured it was the least
I can do,
being as she had to wipe
my snot nose all the time.
What was J.J. doing downstairs?
I told you.
I don't know, so unless
you want me to start lying...
You never stop.
If that's the way you feel,
I'm out.
Mr. Jaynes, we'd be happy
to have someone watch
your son while you're
doing this, you know?
He stays with me.
Mr. Jaynes, is that your wife?
Yeah, and his mommy.
Do you have any idea
what your wife
was doing
at the Glanville Apartments?
She has lots of friends.
She always came home
every night... to me.
To our baby.
Sir.
We almost got all the way
around, girl.
(baby cries)
Maybe these will
help out a little?
Or would you two
prefer to be alone?
Ah, very funny.
So, Grissom comes up
with a theory,
and we get
to do the reenactments
and the photo docs.
Yeah.
Well, it's...
good to be the king, I suppose.
Sure is.
Perfect.
Mm-hmm.
Oops.
Damn it.
Hey, Nick, hang on.
What?
That look like
a bullet hole to you?
Yeah. It sure does.
(shutter clicks and beeps)
.38 cannelured revolver round.
I like it
when the king gets it wrong.
Keeps him human.
STOKES:
The bullet we found
in Mrs. Espinosa's ceiling
was fired from the same revolver
as the bullet that went
into her cheek.
Yeah, but there were
two bullets in the apartment.
And only one hole in her floor.
Which means the kill shot
had to be a separate event.
I think we got
the timeline backwards.
Looks to me like
J.J. shot Mrs. Espinosa first.
Then went downstairs where
somebody returned the favor.
(multiple gunshots)
Yeah. Who's the somebody?
'Cause the only
name on the lease
is Drops,
and he has
a really good alibi.
Yeah and even
if he knew who it was,
he's not going
to just give them up.
He may not have to.
So that urine sample
that Greg found in the
downstairs apartment,
had female epithelials in it.
Now, I ran it through CODIS.
I didn't get any hits,
but the suspect has
half her DNA in common at
every marker with Mrs. Espinosa.
It's her daughter?
Mm-hmm, Dana Espinosa.
Dana's got a record.
She was charged
with attempted murder
for something involving
a Japanese businessman
with his nose full of blow,
skydiving out of the
eighth story of The Palms
without a parachute,
but the point is this:
there was a defense witness
whose testimony exonerated her.
Care to guess who?
Drops.
I don't know, Kellen.
I'm having trouble
with this idea
that you're
such a nice guy.
I mean, renting
your apartment
to a little, old lady
and her daughter?
You're right.
I'm not a nice guy.
But you plant your seed
in a woman,
you got to take care of it.
Dana's pregnant?
Due next month.
That explains
the urine at the scene.
No bladder control,
especially in a gunfight.
So make a ho a housewife.
I saw that movie.
Look, man, first of all,
Dana was no ho.
I scooped her out the atmosphere
before she could get touched.
You sure about that?
STOKES:
Why would J.J. kill
Mrs. Espinosa
and then try to kill Dana?
I mean, they roll
in the same clique.
I-I can't explain these women.
One minute, they're sending
each other cupcakes on Facebook,
the next, they're
trying to kill each
other over a broken
curling iron.
But I do know...
that if J.J. tried
to creep on Dana,
Dana ain't just
gonna just sit there.
She a bad bitch.
If someone's gunning for her
or she's gunning
for somebody else,
we need to find her.
You ain't gonna get her.
She badder, sneakier,
more dangerous.
I'll warn the SWAT team.
Let's give her a call.
What's her phone number?
Phone call?
Yeah.
From your cop phone number?
No chance.
And she won't answer
an unknown caller either.
I'll text in "sugar daddy."
No, this is the kind of girl
you have to find in person.
Then give us some addresses.
What are you going to do?
MapQuest her ass?
That's not going to work.
There's only one way
to find this girl.
Let me out.
(laughing)
No, for real.
I mean, I can have her
to you today.
You think we can just
pop you out of jail?
Yeah. Like 48 Hours.
You know, the flick.
Nolte busts Eddie out of jail.
They get the bad guy.
Everything's cool.
You think this is a joke, man?
Dead bodies are piling up
around your new family.
Now, that would worry me.
But if you want to angle
for some weekend pass
instead of helping us out,
that's fine, man. I understand.
Let's get out of here.
Hey, we out.
Are these the
text messages
that came from
Jessica Jaynes phone?
Yep. No physical
phone required.
Everything's stored
on the server.
You ever worry that you could be
replaced by a computer?
Every day of my life.
Last text she sent
was to her husband's number,
about a half hour before
the apartment shootings.
"Wit Val she knows where
D stashed our money.
"Yay! Be back
soon wit phat pockets.
Kisses to you and Bebe."
Sounds like this girl
was looking for a big score.
We didn't find any money
in either of those apartments.
Well, maybe that's what got
the old lady killed.
"D" for Dana or Drops?
Pull up her voice calls.
Yep.
Okay, the last call she got was
from Valinda Carlisle.
Val.
Let's see what Val has to say.
(touch tone dialing)
(line rings)
MAN (on phone):
Hello?
Uh, yeah.
Hey, uh, is Val around?
Catherine?
Warrick?
I'm afraid she's unable
to come to the phone now.
Permanently.
How'd you get this number?
Valinda called
my apartment homicide vic
last night.
Are there any witnesses?
Unis talked to a couple of guys
that went to the strip club
across the street.
I think they said
they saw a pregnant woman
getting into the vic's car
from the passenger side.
We've got a BOLO out
on Dana Espinosa
in connection
with the apartment homicides.
She's considered
armed, dangerous and pregnant.
Ooh, raging hormones and a gun?
We've got to get that
off the streets fast.
What's the plan?
♪ ♪
Look who it is.
Mom and Dad.
(handcuffs tightening)
(clicking)
One big happy family, huh?
Yeah, sort of.
Get in the car.
I got a feeling
I'm going to regret this.
I already do.
(phone line ringing)
You have reached the voice mail
of Bruce Zagberg,
Registered Financial Planner.
Please leave a message.
(phone beeps)
Voice mail again.
DROPS:
It's 'cause
you don't call
Zig-Zag Bruce.
He calls you, man.
Is there a burger joint
or something around here?
No, but what makes you so sure
Dana would go
to this guy Bruce anyway?
If Dana's on the run,
she gonna need some
on-the-run money.
Let's say Zig-Zag handles
certain aspects of my finances.
What, like laundering
the street vig?
No. Actually, my 401k.
Why are you always tossing
the pimp card at me, man?
I guess to you,
a black man in a suit is a pimp.
Oh. Did I hurt your feelings?
So, is this the place?
What?
You just gonna leave me here?
BRASS:
Yup.
Zig-Zag Bruce ain't
gonna tell you squat.
Wonder what
the schools are like
around here.
What?
DROPS:
You know, seems like
a nice neighborhood.
Yeah, probably
some sweet little
foreclosures
coming up soon, too.
Sounds like you're thinking
about settling down.
Looks like you
were finally right
about something.
(garbled radio transmission)
Single nine-millimeter
shell casing.
Consistent
with the other murders.
GRISSOM:
How about the neighbors?
Nobody at home.
Parents at work,
kids at school,
and nannies don't like
talking to cops.
What about Drops?
He give us anything
besides more bodies?
STOKES:
No, not yet.
I'll process.
Okay.
(garbled radio transmission)
So, who else
would Dana go to for help?
Zig-Zag doesn't seem
to be a very big talker.
You're a lot funnier
than I remember, Crime-Lab.
You been going to
cop comedy school?
BRASS:
Answer the question,
Kellen.
I got a stepsister, Sherry.
Her and Dana are pretty tight.
If Dana's not with
her, Sherry should
at least know something.
Jackson and D.
Let's go.
Jackson and D. Yippee.
We're going to the hood.
Yeah, that's her right there.
The round one.
Check this out
here, fellas.
Y'all gonna have to let me
do this one solo.
Sherry's allergic to badges.
Okay, look at this.
Instant
antihistamine.
Look, man, the cop entourage
just ain't
gonna cut it. Nah.
I need to be alone.
I mean, come on.
Where am I going?
You got your
game boy on me.
Okay, check it out.
I'll cover the street.
What about the cuffs, yo? Cuff?
(sighs)
Now, why the hell
would anybody talk to someone
that's already arrested?
Okay.
Okay, Kellen, give me that.
Give me that.
(laughs)
What about a business card?
You know, just in case
Dana ain't around,
Sherry can get
in contact with us, you know?
Okay.
Don't make me look bad.
Do the right thing.
(laughs)
Cool.
The Church on the Move.
(car door closes)
(sighs)
Hey, Sher.
Oh, uh-uh.
You escape from jail?!
No. Hell, no...
Oh, so they just
let you out, huh?
Well, I mean...
Lying sack!
You don't think I see 'em?
You trying to get everybody
you know arrested,
or maimed, or killed?
Huh?! You a snake now?! A rat?!
Wait a minute.
Miss me with the BS,
all right, Sher?
I'm just looking for...
For what?! For another
damn shortcut?!
Dana's mother was killed.
J.J. was
killed, too,
and Dana's missing.
Now, the cops got me out
to help find her.
I thought maybe you
might know where she is.
Last time I talked to her
was the night before last.
She wasn't feeling too good.
Had to cancel her regular
Bingo night with her mama.
Well, listen, all right?
If she does come
around here,
or calls you, I
need you to call
Captain Jim Brass,
or Nick Stokes...
...at the Crime Lab.
Don't look at
me like that,
Sherry, please, all
right? Just do it.
SHERRY:
Hold on.
Stop where you are, Kellen,
and drop the bag!
Why?!
Drop the bag!
What did I do...?
Drop it!
I didn't even do nothing.
Drops.
Okay.
Hands above your head.
Don't move.
Oh, that is funky.
What is that nasty stuff?!
Chicken gizzards!
Hey, we're not
on a lunch break here.
At least in jail, I got one.
What'd she tell you?
Nothing.
She told him nothing.
All right, come on, Kellen.
We're going to jail.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, wait a minute.
No, no, no, no, no!
There's one more place
to go.
Where?
The office
at my after-hours spot.
Why would Dana
go there?
Maybe to check out
the big-ass safe I got.
Let's go. Ugh!
♪ ♪
AUTOMATED MALE VOICE:
Display last destination.
Huh.
(beeps)
Hey!
Hey.
Got the autopsy report
on Valinda Carlisle.
Thought I'd save you
a trip to the morgue.
Nice.
I found Jessica Jayne's purse
in the glove compartment.
Really?
And address to the Glanville
Apartments on the GPS.
Okay.
(sighs)
So they were in it together.
Valinda drives J.J.
to shake down Drops' family
for some cash.
It goes bad.
J.J. kills
the mother,
Dana kills J.J.,
Valinda flees the scene,
and, the next night,
the pissed-off
pregnant chick
tracks down Valinda
and pays her back.
That seems plausible,
but there's something still off.
The bullet entered
through the back of the skull,
and it exited
through the forehead, and...
(grunts)
...out through the open window.
I think you got lucky.
The bullet grazed
the window frame
on its way out.
Gives you a trajectory.
Well, that's good,
but the witnesses say
that Valinda was
in the driver's seat
when Dana got in the car,
and if that's true, then,
Dana had to shoot Valinda
like this,
not like this.
(gunshot)
That seems
kind of
awkward, don't you think?
Yeah, but awkward or not,
it definitely lines up the shot.
Well, it seems to me
that the shot came
from the back seat.
There was someone else
in the car.
(upbeat pop music plays)
(woman singing,
loud crowd chatter)
Yeah, Dana was here
about an hour ago.
She was with some
NASCAR-looking dude.
STOKES:
And what exactly does
a NASCAR-looking dude look like?
Kind of like you.
But this guy's
all inked up.
He's got that
loco look.
You just let a complete stranger
into your boss' office?
I thought you were
a smart businessman.
I mean, it was
Dana, your girl.
I didn't ask questions.
What is this?
And where's
the DJ?
That's Mini-Britney.
It's what the people want.
Anybody hungry?
I'm going on a sandwich run.
At least let me get that.
Fine.
Warwick,
take me back to jail.
Yeah, see, I got cameras
all over this place, man.
Let's see who she's with.
Let's run this
back an hour.
Looks like
Dana cleaned you out, man.
Nah, wasn't nothing
in that safe, man.
Only Dana didn't know that.
So, how come
you never told us that before?
You guys sprung me to help
find her, and that's
what I'm doing.
There she is.
(typing)
(tape whirring)
BRASS:
Wait a minute.
That's Jessica Jaynes'
husband, Walter.
What's Dana doing with him?
Beats the hell out of me.
Walter's J.J.'s pimp.
Your favorite word.
(sighs)
He all about the cash.
Dude's a man-bitch.
Takes care of the kid
while she goes out
and makes the money.
Even tattoos her waist
every time
she pulls a high-roller trick.
(typing, tape whirring)
Another notch
on her belt, I guess.
STOKES:
I think
he's got a gun on her.
J.J. was after your money.
Now Walter's after it,
and he's taken
your girlfriend
hostage to get it.
BRASS:
Where's the
money, Kellen?
'Cause I'm betting that's where
we're going
to find the both of them.
Well, talk to my lawyers.
Better yet,
talk to the tax dudes.
They know where it is.
House special, times three.
BRASS:
Oh, come on, get
out of here, man.
What's this look
like, a party?
STOKES:
Okay, I'll check
the outside cameras,
see if we can see
where they went.
(beep)
(trilling)
(beeping)
I need to put a BOLO out
on Walter Jaynes.
I'm gonna put
some more mayonnaise
on this dry-ass sandwich.
(woman singing in club)
♪ ♪
(grunts)
Kellen!
LVPD.
Move! Move!
(tires squealing,
car horn toots)
(tires squealing)
Suspect was seen leaving
the scene in a, uh...
A piece-of-crap
blue station wagon.
Nevada plates, K-C-Z.
That's all I got.
A blue station wagon,
partial plates,
Kilo-Charlie-Zebra.
(garbled radio transmission)
Dale?!
What did you give Drops?
Turkey sandwich.
You want to play around
with me, huh?
You're under arrest.
For what, serving sandwiches?
Aiding and abetting. Cuff him.
Hey, man. Hey, hey, hey,
hey, hey, hey, hey.
Look... Look, um...
Look, it was a GPS jammer melt.
A what?
(garbled radio transmission)
DROPS:
I need you to call
Captain Jim Brass,
or Nick Stokes
at the Crime Lab.
Don't look at
me like that,
Sherry, please, all right?
Just do it!
Get him out of here.
Come on, man.
I told you everything.
(phone rings)
You still gonna
arrest me?
I was just taking
orders, man.
(phone beeps)
Hey, Grissom, don't worry.
We're gonna get him.
The undersheriff will be pleased
to know that.
The nine-millimeter casing found
at the business manager's
apartment,
and the one
from Valinda Carlisle's car
were fired in the same gun.
No surprises there.
Yeah, but it's not the gun
that was used
to kill Jessica Jaynes.
I think Walter Jaynes is the one
who's on a rampage here,
and he's dragging Dana Espinosa
with him.
Any idea where?
No. No, not yet.
You might want
to work on that, Nick.
We got a lead on the station
wagon that scooped up Drops.
The registered owner
is Walter Jaynes.
He must have had Dana
in the car with him.
Walter wouldn't just let him
in the car to protect the girl.
Drops must have something
he wants.
The money.
What we have here...
is a misunderstanding.
Hmm. I understand
it just fine.
My J.J. bangs
one of your whales
24-7 from Christmas
to New Year's,
and you stiff us.
Wait. Wait. Stiff you?
I got busted.
I went to jail.
Technically, I'm still in jail.
And my baby doesn't
have a mother.
Neither does Dana.
I'm sorry. I thought
she was gonna kill me, too.
Shut up!
DROPS:
Calm down.
Look, look, look at me.
Walter, look at me.
Don't even listen
to her. Walter!
Walter, look at me!
See this here? Look.
50 Gs, baby.
I won't even take my cut.
That's very generous.
So, uh,
we good to go?
You owe me something else.
What? The vig?
What's that, 25 more?
You can take the whole couch
if you want to.
No, no, no, no.
I got my pay.
I need my payback.
I lost my wife.
I'm going to let you choose
which one you lose.
Either your girl...
...or your baby.
(sobbing)
(panting)
(beep)
(beeping, sirens blaring)
Drops' GPS just came back up.
(trilling and beeps)
He's definitely
at the apartment.
Well, either
the jammer died, or...
Yeah, or he's calling
for help.
Okay, listen up.
We got a hostage situation
at the Glanville apartment,
6555 Vegas Valley.
We're gonna make
a silent approach.
Everybody copy?
(trilling)
Look... I can't choose.
Either you choose,
or I choose.
Choose!
(fussing)
Okay.
The choice is made.
(sobbing):
No!
(approaching footsteps running)
(Drops grunts, Dana cries)
(grunting)
(gun cocking)
(gunshot, Dana screaming)
Get that scumbag
out of here!
(groaning)
Oh, man! Oh, Damn!
BRASS:
We have two
gunshot victims
at the Glanville Apartments.
Code Three.
(groans)
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Damn. Her water broke.
Trauma from the shot.
One of the victims
is a pregnant woman.
She's going
into labor.
That's all I got right there.
Oh, the baby's coming!
Just keeping breathing, Dana.
Just keep breathing, okay?
Paramedics are on their way.
Here. Relax.
That's it. That's it.
(Dana whimpers)
(panting)
(sirens blaring)
(rhythmic beeping,
machine whooshing)
(baby crying)
He looks healthy.
How are you?
You good?
Sore.
I want to hold him.
No.
No?
That's my son.
I don't want you
to hold him, Kellen.
Because of you,
I heard my mother die.
J.J.:
Where's the money?!
MARIA:
What money?
I don't have
anything!
Drops' money!
MARIA:
Who?! Just take what
you want and leave,
or I'm calling
the police!
(gunshot)
DANA:
I didn't even know it was J.J.
What was I supposed to do?
(gun chamber cocking)
I shot her and ran,
and then Valinda called.
She said she heard
what happened.
Said she wanted to help me.
Thank you, Val.
I am so freaked out right now.
I am so sorry.
DANA:
Walter made Val call me.
She was just bait.
(gunshot, Dana screams)
(rhythmic beeping)
Walter said
you owed him some money.
You told me you
didn't have anything.
So I took Walter to Zig-Zag,
thinking he would help.
And when he didn't,
he killed him, too.
And for what?
So that you could hide
all the money
and keep it for yourself?
I had to.
The tax dudes
would have taken it.
And, technically,
I didn't hide it.
I left it with your mother.
Don't BS me, Kellen.
Babe, listen,
okay, seriously.
Seriously, you would
have spent it.
Then, where would we be?
Hmm? Hmm?
That was for our future, Mommy.
We don't have a future.
When you get out, we'll be gone.
You can't do that.
We're not married,
and you're a convict.
I can do what I want.
STOKES:
Okay, Drops,
that's it.
Time to go, man.
We got to get you transferred
back to the prison
hospital, okay?
Is Dana gonna do any time
for offing J.J.?
Oh, I doubt it.
Sounds like a
pretty good case of
self-defense to me.
What about the money?
I'm not expecting anything.
Just wondering.
Well, technically,
it's the mother's.
It was her apartment.
Dana's the only beneficiary,
so the money's really hers.
And my kid's.
Yeah.
For once, I did something
good in my life.
Oh, your life ain't
over yet, Kellen.
It ain't over yet.