(guys yelling)
(thunder rumbling)
(loud music playing)
(yelling and laughing)
Hey, bro, I'm driving drunk,
and you're lighting up a J?
Maybe we should wait
for those... hell, dude.
Man, we're in Vegas.
Sweet potato Vegas!
Whoo!
(loud music continuing)
(all talking at once)
(yelling)
(sirens blaring)
Hide that!
Hide it! Hide it!
Get it out of here!
(sirens blaring)
Hey, hide that liquor!
Hide the liquor! Hide it!
Throw that joint out!
Get him! Get him!
Shoot him! Shoot him!
(sirens blaring)
Get out of the way!
(phone ringing)
Hello?
Unknown caller. No call list.
Probably disposable.
Where's Warrick?
We've been calling him.
There's no answer.
BRASS:
See what happens
when you get in
a high-speed chase
with a garbage truck
and end up with two dead bodies.
Where's the other one?
I take it
he came out of the truck?
He flew out.
At least that's what
every eyewitness tells us.
WILLOWS:
Well, city landfill is a couple
of miles down the road.
What's the TOD, David?
Nine, maybe ten, hours.
I got no ID on
either of the bodies.
No ID on the truck.
I ran the VIN number
and the plates.
They're not
in the system.
Good luck.
Control Sanitation
is the only waste company
in Vegas.
If the garbageman works
for them, his prints
would be in
the system.
All right. Catherine,
you and I got the bodies.
Greg, since Warrick's MIA,
you have a choice:
the truck or the trail.
I'll go for the fresh air.
Do I get
a choice, too?
Because, if you don't mind,
I'm going to take
the garbageman.
Be my guest.
I thought I told you
not to call me on this line.
Maybe that's because
I don't want to talk to you.
Are you kidding me?
Why don't you ask the father
of your unborn child?
No. That's stupid.
Don't call the lawyers.
Tina, don't call... Tina! Tina!
Don't call... Tina!
Damn it.
Hey, Gris, I'm sorry I'm late.
I had some business
to take care of.
This is your business.
You were first up.
That means you're supposed
to be here first.
You get to process
the trash truck.
No problem.
But get it off the street.
Tow it to the impound yard.
and TOYOTA.
Moving Forward.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
These coveralls are brand-new.
Your garbageman
was in excellent shape.
COD is as expected.
Massive BFT due to his
unfortunate collision
with the T-bird.
And your other vic
was in his late 20s.
He was definitely
crushed by something.
Most likely,
the garbage compactor.
Which happened postmortem.
Oh, it's always better
to be compacted dead
rather than alive.
WILLOWS:
What's his COD?
Suffocation. He had
petechial hemorrhaging.
I found white fibers
in the nose and mouth.
Sent them
over to Hodges.
He called back,
confirmed they were silk.
I tried to trace
garbageman's cell phone.
Like we expected,
it's disposable.
So I tracked down
the distributor.
It was paid for in cash
under a bogus name.
But I did get an AFIS hit
off his print.
Brody Biggs. Former cop.
GRISSOM:
When was this taken?
1975, police academy graduation.
I contacted LVPD.
They said he quit the force
back in 1980
with a perfect record.
Then what?
Social came back to several
different garages around town.
He was a freelance mechanic
for 20 years.
All right, we got to get
his personnel file.
What about the other vic?
(typing)
It's Jason Crewes.
27. Got a hit
off his work card.
He's worked at five
different casinos
over the last six years.
Well, it doesn't look like
Jason planned on going anywhere.
I know a lot of people
in this phone.
You do not.
Knows some
famous people.
Or uses famous nicknames
for his friends.
♪ ♪
(bird tweets)
Did you see anything?
(squawks)
♪ ♪
Nick!
I think I just found
ground zero.
I think Jason
was killed here.
(groans softly)
(muffled cries)
STOKES:
Well, this would have been
the perfect murder
if Jason's body would have
actually made it
to the landfill.
Would have been incinerated.
At least now his mother
has someone to bury.
WOMAN:
He was alone last night.
We talked at about 3:00
in the morning.
He said he got off work early
and was going to bed,
and he'd call me
when he woke up.
But he never did.
BRASS:
Have you ever seen this man?
His name is Brody Biggs.
He's a mechanic.
Are you sure?
We think this is the man
that killed your son.
If he's a mechanic,
maybe he worked
on some of Jason's limos.
I thought Jason
was a club owner.
He was a limo driver
before that, long time ago.
Well, couldn't be
that long ago.
Jason was only 27.
You have to be 25
to be a limo driver.
He had all kinds of fake IDs.
Drove his first
long one at 18.
The owner of the limo
company liked Jason.
Made him a VIP driver.
Celebs liked Jason.
He could take his clients
to a Motel 6
and it'd be
the hottest spot in town.
Wasn't long before the club
owners invested in Jason,
made him a group partner,
gave him his own spot.
Then two, then five.
Suddenly, he's running
the whole club scene.
I guess I should say
he ran the club scene.
He's not going to be running
anything anymore.
BROWN:
I'll be damned.
Look at that.
GRISSOM:
The good old days.
BROWN:
Yeah.
Here's an ad for the Silver
Slipper Casino-- buffet.
Back when they had real
eggs, not powdered ones.
Hey, Gris, listen.
About me being late...
You have a cell phone
paid for by the department.
You call, you say
you're running late.
What's going on
with you?
I don't know. This, uh...
This whole divorce has taken
the wind out of my sails.
You know, I used
to have the team
to distract me from all this,
but even that's changed
with Sara being gone.
I feel kind of disconnected.
You've got your work.
Don't screw that up.
Van Halen, 1984.
Either this truck was
delivering merchandise
for a memorabilia store
or it's just plain old.
Maybe that's why Brass
couldn't find the
registration record.
These old blue license plates
were issued in the '80s.
I don't think this truck's
been on the streets since.
I think this guy was
disguising his truck.
It was orange
before it was green.
They used to use orange
garbage trucks in the '80s.
The hydraulic
cylinder blew.
GRISSOM:
Maybe when he crushed the body.
That's why all
the garbage flew out.
Found this .22 in the
parking lot near the crash.
Check these bullets.
Shorts.
Usually used
for shooting small animals,
but in some cases
they're used on people
in place of a silencer.
GRISSOM:
Less gunpowder, less noise.
BROWN:
Look, if the garbageman
had this gun,
why didn't he just
shoot the vic?
GRISSOM:
He found Jason sleeping.
Why make a mess
if you don't have to?
Sounds like a
professional hit man.
GRISSOM:
Well, if he was,
we still have to find
the guy who hired him.
BROWN:
I traced the VIN on the garbage
truck back to The Regency,
the company that made it.
The only model of that truck
sold in Nevada
was to a company called
The Regal Sanitation Group.
They shut down in '83.
GRISSOM:
That explains the garbage.
SANDERS:
Regal Sanitation was owned
by Anthony Pezzulo.
I'm studying mob history
for my book.
Pezzulo? Wasn't he the mob boss
who owned the Starfly?
SANDERS:
They called Pezzulo "Whacko,"
not so much for his
wacky personality
as for his love
for whacking guys.
GRISSOM:
Until he himself
got whacked at
the Wisconsin Dells in 1983.
Every mob-owned business
in Vegas shut down
when Pezzulo died.
These scumbags lay roaches.
Just when you think
they're gone,
they pop back up again.
Somebody put a hit
out on Jason.
It couldn't have been Pezzulo
'cause he's been dead
for 20 years.
Pezzulo's wife Kate got rid
of Regal Sanitation
right after he died.
She still around?
She fell off the radar.
All I could find
was this old photo.
WOMAN:
I told you the truth.
You lied about your name.
The feds told me to forget
I ever had the Pezzulo name.
I wasn't about
to remember it for you.
My husband had more cops
than capos on his payroll.
So you went into
witness protection.
You changed your identity.
And then you stayed
in Vegas?
Feds felt we'd actually
be safer here.
They thought if we left,
we might
suffer the same consequences
as Anthony.
BRASS:
Did Jason have any mob ties?
Jason was three years old
when Anthony died.
He never even knew his father.
The last time we talked you said
you didn't know Jason's killer.
What about this guy?
That's B.B.
That's the same guy.
B.B. is short for Brody Biggs.
B.B. didn't kill Jason.
There's no way.
He was Anthony's friend.
Friend?
B.B. was driving one of your
husband's old garbage trucks.
Your dead son was in the back
with the rest of the garbage.
How did B.B.
get the truck?
I haven't seen B.B. in 23 years.
You got rid
of the business.
What happened
to the trucks?
I gave that stuff to Lou Gedda.
The owner of
Pigalle Boulevard
Strip Club.
So did Gedda and B.B.
know each other?
Of course, they were both
on Anthony's crew,
but they would never...
Never what?
Never kill your son
and dispose of him in one
of the trucks you gave him?
When was the last time
you saw Gedda?
(sniffles)
I haven't had any contact
with him since Anthony died.
So you're telling me
you haven't seen or spoken
to Lou Gedda in 23 years?
Gedda and I had an agreement.
He was to keep away
from our family.
Forget Jason and I ever existed.
Obviously, Lou Gedda is not
a man of his word.
This place has always
been bad news.
My guys are in here
at least twice a week.
Yet there's always a line.
Never underestimate
the power of the ass.
Look out. Coming through.
Excuse me, gentlemen.
(rhythm and blues playing)
Looking for Lou Gedda.
MAN:
Yeah, come on in.
Who let you two up here?
Just so I know
who to fire.
Gold card.
Oh, yeah, those seem
to work everywhere.
Got to get me one.
Ahh...!
I know why you're here.
And I don't know
what to say.
I can't control these girls.
They want to leave
with customers
and do whatever it is
they do, I can't prevent that.
Believe me,
I don't like whores.
I like dancers.
When I find out they're whores,
I kick them curbside.
We're not here
about your girls.
We're here about this guy.
B.B.
Yeah, works
at my auto detailing.
But I tell ya,
he's in here more,
getting drunk and checking out
the breast-est-es.
Well, you don't have
to worry about him
anymore. He's dead.
Oh. Well...
unless you invite me
to the funeral,
what's this got
to do with me?
Tell me about
Jason Crewes.
He brings me boatloads
of celebrities,
which equals
boatloads of money.
I love the kid.
Oh, don't tell me.
You think Jason killed B.B.?
We think B.B. killed Jason.
Now, see, that
makes more sense.
When is the last time
you saw Jason Crewes, sir?
Last week.
How long have
you known him?
A couple years at most.
I still don't understand
what this has to do with me.
You missing a garbage truck?
Go again?
Regal Sanitation Group.
Your buddy Pezzulo's
old company.
You inherited
the trucks.
So what?
Jason Crewes' corpse flew
out of one of your trucks
earlier this morning.
Do you know how much this club
made last year?
30 mill.
You think I'm still messing
around with trash?
And that's
the end of this.
You want to continue
asking me questions,
you're going to have to do it
with my dream team present.
BROWN:
Here you go.
Thank you.
So you're the talented
Mr. Raykirk,
agent to the stars.
Uh-uh, manager.
What's
the difference?
Uh, well, an agent
gets ten percent
and a manager gets 15.
Listen, I'm here in town
for a film festival
and I have to get
to a screening,
so you can you just, you know,
cut to the chase?
Jason Crewes is dead.
Okay.
Um...
So he took you
to Pigalle Boulevard in August.
Do you remember that?
How do you know about that?
I'm an investigator.
Some things I do know, but
there's a lot that I don't.
Somebody put a hit
out on your friend.
You want to help us
out here?
I have an agent friend
who I work with
who had a bachelor party
out here,
and Jason hooked us up
VIP-style.
He took us to Moon
and LAX and Drai's
and then of course, naturally,
we ended up at a strip club.
And everyone knows the best
girls are at Pigalle Boulevard.
It couldn't get any better
until the check showed up.
Ten grand?
The manager said $800 a bottle.
We ordered five.
I hear you don't want
to pay what you owe us.
No. No, no, no, no.
I just think
you overcharged us, man.
No.
This place is a rip-off.
And your girls?
They're beat, overrated,
and oversized.
Get it?
I'm not paying.
Let's take a walk.
I'm gonna give you
a minute
so you can figure out
what you want to do.
I'm cutting something.
But I'm gonna give you the
choice of what it's gonna be.
No.
Oh, yeah, yeah.
I can slice you here
or I can slice you here.
(sobbing)
Come on, no, no, no.
Shh, shh, shh.
Come on, you choose.
I mean, I was never
more scared in my life.
You know, he was so sweet enough
to give me the choice
of my throat or my genitals,
so I chose the latter...
so I'd live.
Then he charged my card
and escorted us out
to the parking lot.
Oh, here's something
really cool.
I left with a broken nose,
some sore wrists,
and some really nice bruises
underneath my arms.
And I just should've given him
the ten grand
because I paid
my plastic surgeon twice that.
And you told Jason
about all this?
Oh, yeah.
I mean, he gave this guy Gedda
a call right in front of me.
Then he cursed him out
and he told him he would never
take anyone to Pigalle anymore.
Listen, I'm really sorry
about all this.
But, um, thanks
a lot for your time.
Oh, yeah.
By the way, if you're
gonna prosecute this guy,
I'm not a witness.
There's a reason that
I didn't press charges,
if you know what I mean.
Four shots.
(computer blips, bleeps)
(beeping)
Got an IBIS hit
off that gun.
Unsolved murder in '93.
Victim was found
in the desert.
His car was found
at Pigalle Boulevard,
the last place
anyone saw him.
GRISSOM:
Our hit man's good
for two murders.
The unsolved in '93,
where he actually used a gun,
and Jason Crewes,
who he suffocated.
So, who hired him?
I have a good feeling
he works for Gedda.
Yeah, but we don't work
off feelings, do we?
According to Mr. Hollywood,
Jason cost Gedda a lot of money,
and he dissed him,
which is more than enough
for Gedda to order out
a hit on someone,
even if Jason
is Pezzulo's son.
Any evidence?
I ran Pigalle's address
to find out
if there are any more crimes
linked to it over the years.
I found hundreds:
416s, 413s, 411s...
The list goes on.
Any consistent suspects?
Only thing consistent
is that the victims refused
to file charges
and the witnesses refused
to give statements.
And it's funny enough the cops
lost interest in pursuing it.
What are you saying?
I'm saying it looks like Gedda
is running an old school
extortion racket,
and you can't do that without
having cops on the payroll.
(water spraying)
Hey!
I just want to talk!
I got warrants, man!
I'm not a cop.
I don't care.
You got a piece.
Calm down. I'm not
going to hurt you.
You live here?
Pretty much.
What do you want?
You ever see anybody
get beat up inside?
No, no, I never seen
none of that.
Don't make me pull
those warrants, man.
Yeah, I seen guys get beat up.
This is Strip Club Strip.
Guys get beat up
and down this block.
You ever see the owner
beat up anyone?
Hey, they let me stay here.
They're real good to me.
I didn't ask you that.
Lot of troublemakers,
they come out of there
and they get hauled off.
That's all I know.
What do you mean
by "hauled off"?
♪ ♪
(metallic clacking)
You got a warrant?
Do I need one?
I own this block.
Unless you're lookin' to get a
detail job, you're trespassing.
What do you do with this?
I burn meat.
♪ ♪
Hey.
What's up?
Trying to get this warrant
for Gedda's property.
I'm getting close though.
Check out these
bruise patterns.
Hey, what are those?
What?
Those pills?
Oh, they're supposed
to keep me alert.
Really?
Yeah.
How long you been
taking those?
I don't know,
for a couple months.
Aren't you still taking
those sleeping pills, too?
What's it to you?
So now... you're taking
uppers and downers.
Gimme a break, man.
No, you need to give yourself
a break, Warrick.
Hey, let it go, bro.
No. No, I'm not going
to let it go.
(pills clattering)
What are you doing, man?
You need to take a look
at yourself, Warrick.
And I care
because I'm your friend.
(chuckles softly)
(pats shoulder)
All right?
Yeah.
(pats shoulder)
All right, tell me
about these bruises.
BROWN:
The 415 vic claims he got
beat up inside the Pigalle.
Couple days later, he
dropped all the charges.
And then there's
the unsolved murder.
They find a vic
out in the desert,
but they find his car
outside of Pigalle's.
Same bruise pattern.
Now we got this Hollywood agent
who mentions that he also
has bruises under his arms.
He claims that he was strapped
to a barber's chair
in Gedda's office.
That should be enough
for a warrant.
BRASS:
The judge doesn't think
the bruises are enough
probable cause
to issue a warrant.
BROWN (on phone):
What judge?
Greene.
When I was running bets
for Judge Cohen,
she was in on the action.
I have no comment.
You know, these club owners--
they pay a lot of taxes;
they fund campaigns;
they hand out free drinks,
all in exchange for protection.
I mean, what can I do?
Go to the Undersheriff,
see if he can use his influence.
But I doubt it.
(line disconnects,
dial tone humming)
Excuse me.
BROWN:
McKeen!
Excuse me a moment.
Judge denied me
the warrant.
What do you
want me to do?
Get me the warrant.
Lou Gedda is getting
away with murder.
All right, say that
I get you the warrant.
What are you looking for,
something that made
armpit bruises?
The barber's chair in Gedda's
office made the armpit bruises.
I'm agreeing with the judge.
McKEEN:
Grissom!
You need to save
your CSI here.
What he has is
circumstantial
based off of weird bruises
and a barber chair.
Brown needs to get
better evidence
and leave the rest in our hands.
I'm sorry, leave what
in your hands-- Gedda's money?
Listen to me.
Putting Gedda in jail is not
gonna solve your problems.
You just got the rest
of the night off.
(crickets chirping)
(door opening in distance)
(duffel bag sliding heavily)
Hey!
(gasps)
What's in the bag?
All my stuff.
I'm just cleaning out my locker.
Show me.
(zipper opens)
(sighs)
Here, let me help you with that.
Thanks.
I'm sorry.
(sighs)
♪ ♪
What can I get you
tonight?
Got any Dom Perignon?
Mm-hmm.
What about Cristal?
We do.
We also have DP Rose.
I'll take one of each.
♪ ♪
Hey...
Hey!
I'm sorry about earlier.
I thought you were carrying a
dead body in there or something.
You're a cop, right?
I'm Warrick Brown.
I'm Candy.
Nice to meet you, Candy.
So, you work here?
Yeah.
What do you want?
Everything.
Hey, cheers, girl.
Hey, let's get out of here,
you and me.
I'm working.
Come on, I just want
to ask you a few questions.
I don't go home
with the customers.
Pay the bill and let's go.
How'd you know I was here?
You've been here twice
already today.
We're leaving.
Come on, Gris,
why don't you sit down
and have a drink with us?
I'm on the clock.
So am I.
So you want to get fired.
No, I want to let
them know I'm here.
I figured I'd order
a couple bottles
and not pay for it
and see what happens.
You think he's that stupid?
It's worth a try.
Here you go, sir.
Thank you.
Well, now you gotta
pay for it,
'cause we're not allowed
to accept gifts.
BROWN:
I left my car.
I gotta get my car.
You gotta admit, though,
once I get this done...
Get in the car, Warrick.
Go on.
Go home. Sleep it off.
I'll see you in my office
in the morning.
(people talking, laughing,
music throbbing)
Hey... follow that girl.
♪ ♪
(jaunty jazz playing)
(sighs)
Thanks.
You don't give up.
Not tonight.
Irish whiskey.
Neat.
What's your real name, Candy?
Joanna Krumsky.
Joanna.
I'll stick with Candy.
(both laughing)
So, now that we're out
of the Pigalle,
you can help me out
with a few questions.
Good luck.
Anybody ever get heavy-handed
with you over there?
Not with me.
I'm a black belt.
Nice.
Not even the owner, Gedda?
Not even him.
Thanks.
So what about the customer?
They ever get beat-downs?
When the guys get drunk
and start groping the girls.
That's not tolerated.
You ever see a barber's chair
in Gedda's office?
No, but I heard
about one.
It's supposed to
be Al Capone's.
Al Capone.
Yeah, but that
has to be a rumor.
Mob guy with
Al Capone's chair--
it's so cliché.
Gedda's like the last
wise guy left in Vegas.
Guess that's his way of
keeping his culture alive.
Scumbags like him
don't have culture.
started Vegas.
None of these lights would be
here if it wasn't for them.
What's a hot young thing
like you doing
working in a nasty place
like that?
Money.
The hours.
The dancing.
How about you giving me
that last dance of the evening?
♪ ♪
JOANNA:
Relax.
It's just for your protection.
It's just for protection.
(distorted laughter echoing)
♪ ♪
Just for your protection.
(currency crinkling)
Thanks.
(distorted police radio
communication)
No, no, no!
You can't cross the tape!
Not this time.
This is your car.
No! No!
No, this is wrong!
She didn't do anything!