WOMAN:
♪ ...and the rockets'
red glare ♪
♪ The bombs bursting in air ♪
♪ Gave proof through the night ♪
♪ That our flag
was still there ♪
♪ O, say, does that
star-spangled banner yet wave ♪
♪ O'er the land of the free ♪
♪ And the home of the brave. ♪
(cheering and applause)
♪ ♪
ANNOUNCER:
Welcome to PBR Finals
in Las Vegas.
For two weekends,
we have 45 riders
competing in a race
for the world title.
The world champion goes home
with a million bucks.
You want to talk about pressure?
It's all in Las Vegas.
Next up, Cody Latshaw
riding Wintwister,
one of the finest bovine
athletes in the world today--
a champ among champions.
(crowd cheering)
ANNOUNCER:
Ladies and gentlemen,
right in your seat, right now,
do what you can,
spiritually, to help Cody.
Cody. Hey, Cody, you all right?
You okay?
Get a stretcher.
Get a stretcher!
I don't need a stretcher.
You sure?
I'm okay.
Just give me a hand.
All right. Here we go.
(crowd cheering)
Re-ride!
(cheering)
ANNOUNCER:
This is why we call him Lazarus,
ladies and gentlemen.
Knock him down,
and he rises again.
What an athlete!
What a hero!
So, who found him?
Security.
We have a tough time
finding guys to wrangle a bull.
Cowboys like to party
when they come to Vegas.
Did you see anything?
No, we just put the bull
back in the pen.
Ty Murray,
PBR president.
And seven-time world champ.
Okay, Dustin.
Jim Brass, Vegas PD.
Nice to meet you.
Gil Grissom, Crime Lab.
BRASS:
What can you tell me
about this guy?
Cody Latshaw,
a real institution.
Most guys his age hung up
their rope a long time ago.
What about the bull?
Wintwister-- he threw Cody
earlier tonight,
but he got up and was fine.
He even asked for a re-ride.
"Re-ride"?
Well, if a bull
doesn't buck good enough,
they can ask
to get on another one.
That wasn't the case.
Wintwister had a good day.
Cody must not have been
in his right mind
to think he'd get
a second shot.
Is this the rope
they tie around the bull?
That's one of them.
That's the bull rope.
Looks like it's got rosin on it.
Yeah, it helps the rope
stick to the glove
so they can get a good grip.
Do all the riders
wear a glove?
Yes, sir.
He's not
wearing one.
Guy was living
the American dream.
Every kid wants
to grow up to be a cowboy.
Not a dead cowboy.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
(camera shutter clicks)
Catherine.
Hi.
PBR Sports Medicine
just sent this over.
Taken after Cody's fall
in competition.
Hmm.
He was held together
by every kind of hardware
but roofing nails.
I can relate.
Yeah, it's a
violent sport.
Check out his hand.
Riders live with constant
injuries and pain.
They always get
on that next bull
and try like hell to hang on
for the next eight seconds.
You sound like a fan.
I used to date a bull rider.
Cowboy up.
PHILLIPS:
Here you go.
Hey.
These are the ones I took.
Thank you.
So there's just a few
bills in his pockets.
David, why don't you give
me a hand here?
Oh, sure.
Some guys keep valuables
in their boots.
Cody's little doggies
are right fragrant.
Catherine, take a look at this.
This X-ray shows
he walked away
from his earlier fall
with a hairline fracture
of the C1 vertebra.
(cheering)
In bull riding,
the rider's spine must sustain
vertical, horizontal
and diagonal thrust,
together if they put tremendous
force onto the spinal column.
(bull grunting)
That guy was
a walking time bomb.
Any trauma with sufficient force
would snap that vertebra
and sever the
spinal cord.
It did.
The film David just took
shows a complete fracture.
That's your COD.
Consistent with getting
thrown a second time.
Hey!
You got anything to do
with taking my bull
off tomorrow's day sheet?
Do you own the bull?
Yeah, I'm Nancy Twicker.
And I want my bull
in the finals.
The more he bucks,
the more he's worth.
So whatever you got
to do to clear him,
get it done.
Your bull gave Cody Latshaw
a pretty brutal beating.
It's not the bull's fault.
I blame Cody for taking
him out after hours.
Is it true that some riders
tie the bull's testicles
to get them to buck more?
Well, sure, we always
want the bulls to buck.
That's why we tie a flank
strap across their back.
They're trying
to shake it off.
Think about it.
If I tied a rope
around your testicles,
would you feel like
jumping up and down?
Could a guy
get a bull out of this chute
without any help?
Well, one guy
could get a bull
all the way to the
bucking chute, sure,
but well, then he'd have
to tie on the bull rope
and the flank strap.
Then he'd have
to get on the bull.
And open the gate.
TWICKER:
Not without help.
The chute only opens
from the outside.
I'm going to need
to process your bull.
Can you do it in eight seconds?
Even confined like this,
these are not the most
cooperative creatures.
So if my flank man
says get back, you jump.
Hey, Cash.
Howdy, Cash Dooley.
And my name's
about the only cash I got.
And this
is Wintwister?
What, uh...
What would be
the safest way
for me to handle
his hooves?
There ain't one.
Too dangerous.
He's a kicker.
Do you think I could get him
to step on something?
Sure. But you better
let me do the bending.
Think you could get him
to step on this?
TWICKER:
Cash knows bulls like nobody.
Heck, before these kids
could even walk,
they're out riding sheep,
then calves and baby bulls.
And finally these one-ton,
back-jerkin'
snot-slingin' monsters.
Now, they get
all busted up
and quit ridin', but they
just can't quit these animals.
HODGES:
Cotton fiber.
Appears to be bloodstained.
I need another piece
for comparison.
Forget how to use
the scissors?
Put your fingers
in the holes and squeeze.
Yes, ma'am.
This looks like semen.
Cowboy had a roll in the hay.
Either he's messy
or, uh, we could have
a Brokeback Mountain situation.
Oh, God, that movie made me cry.
Me, too.
You know, it takes
a big man to admit that.
And I am that man.
You don't say?
Fibers from the bull
are consistent
with Cody's shirt.
Looks like
Wintwister's a killer.
(garbled radio transmission)
Found her body
on patrol,
called in the 401AB,
apparent fatal.
If there were
any eyewitnesses,
they didn't
stick around.
Okay, thanks.
Here's the point of impact.
Threw her that far, he must
have been going at least...
45.
Tiffany Rigdon, 27, local.
OFFICER:
I'll run her for you.
Thanks.
Radiator fluid.
Bunch of empty
liquor miniatures.
Card key
from Pike's Gambling Hall.
(camera shutter clicking)
Hit-and-run.
Hit back there...
...ran over here.
RO is Cody Latshaw--
Durant, Oklahoma.
Isn't that
Grissom's dead cowboy?
Yeah.
Boy, he had a hell of a night.
He gets humiliated...
...hits a pedestrian...
(tires screeching)
...he ditches the car, walks a
couple of blocks to the arena,
joyrides a bull, and then ends
up getting stomped to death?
Here's another card key
from Pike's Gambling Hall
right here.
MAN:
First one's for room 810,
registered to Cody Latshaw.
Here you go.
Second one's also to room 810.
Cody knew the girl he ran over.
Lucky for us, housekeeping's
a little slow on the uptake.
Riding glove.
So he wasn't planning
on re-riding Wintwister
when he left here.
Threw back a bunch of beers,
some liquor.
I don't see any drugs.
Bed looks used.
Maybe he partied with Tiffany.
Bet it cost him.
I ran her priors.
She's got a couple
for solicitation.
"I can't help now but wonder
"what your brown eyes
were concealing.
"They just showed me reflections
of all that I was feeling...
"Our bodies close together
like my ride hand in my glove.
"Hearts pounding
with excitement
And, dare I say it, love."
Nobody ever wrote me a poem.
"I know
I'll never own you.
"It's your nature
to run free,
"but I pray
the Lord above
that one day
you'll come back to me."
(sighs)
That's sweet.
"By the time you read this,
I'll be married.
"He's a great guy.
"Honest, Cody,
I'll always be thankful
"for everything
you did for me.
"Love,
Tiffany."
Sounds like it was more
than a money relationship.
Mm-hmm.
Broken bones--
he gets up and rides again.
Broken heart and he's a killer.
GRISSOM:
"Then we'll ride off in glory
until our time
"is done
And I will be your hero,
your cowboy in the sun."
It's not
Shakespeare.
I'm actually a fan
of cowboy poetry.
Are you really?
Yeah, it's just a way
of organizing your thoughts
and feelings
so that you can make sense
of them.
Well, it sounds like Cody
was trying to make sense
out of his girl
leaving him.
Yeah, well, poetry can help
you with that, too.
Rib fractures,
multiple lacerations,
pulmonary contusions,
lacerated aorta,
lacerated liver.
I could go on,
but you get the idea.
COD was multiple
blunt force trauma.
Right, but not all of it
was from the hit-and-run.
You see the coloration
of the bruises?
Yellowish.
They're from an event at least
12 hours before the accident.
Maybe Cody had
rejection issues.
Could be why
she was leaving him.
SANDERS:
Lot of tools back here.
It's an equipment-
intensive sport.
What have we here?
Some kind of
cattle prod?
They don't use those
in professional bull riding.
Buckaroos,
have you seen Catherine?
'Cause I just got the results
from that semen stain
on Cody Latshaw's jeans.
Come up with a match?
I did. I had to run
an Ouchterlony test on it.
So not from a human donor?
No... no.
Bovine.
Yeah...
I took a psychobiology class
once and we studied
a very interesting case.
Okay, there was a guy,
he lived on a farm,
and literally the only way
that this guy could get
sexually satisfied
was when he was
with livestock.
That's okay. I'm good.
Well, see,
apparently,
the whole thing started
one night
because he was in the barn--
it started snowing.
He got stuck in there.
He couldn't make his way
back to the farmhouse,
so he decided that
he would try and stay warm...
well, with a sheep.
But then the horses
were jealous, so...
you know, and I
think there was
a cow in there
as well.
You know,
I think we got the picture.
I wish I didn't.
(buzzing)
I think I know what this is for.
TWICKER:
It's called
an electroejaculator.
It's used on bulls
that have back trouble.
It looks, uh...
pretty persuasive.
Yeah.
So, uh, was Cody helping you
collect from Wintwister?
Hell, no.
First of all, you don't
collect during competition.
Right, right, so like
an athlete before a game.
Now you're talking.
And when I do collect, I bring
a service out to the ranch.
You know, one collection
from that old boy
gives you about...
500 breeding units.
At a hundred bucks a
pop, you do the math.
Well, if the stuff
is so valuable,
maybe Cody was doing a little
moonlighting, you know,
collecting on his own,
making a little extra money.
Cattle rustling?
No, not Cody.
We found bull semen
on his jeans.
Cody wouldn't
steal from me.
Besides, it's a
two-person job,
no matter which
method you use.
There's more than one?
In addition
to your electroejaculation,
you got what's called
an artificial vagina.
Now, you get a teaser animal
in there, like a steer.
See, bulls go homosexual
in captivity.
You get that bull
to mount that steer,
then you get that AV in there
right before th...
Yeah, I get the point.
Do you know this girl?
We think
she's Cody's girlfriend.
(scoffing):
Yeah.
I thought he had a new
girlfriend in Vegas
from the way
his mood was changing.
She's younger, probably...
does whatever he says.
Mm-hmm.
Listen,
if you need anything else,
I'll be at the arena all day.
I thought Wintwister
didn't compete tonight.
Well, Captain,
I'm not a one-bull kind of gal.
Here you are, sir.
Can I help you?
Saw a woman get
killed last night.
BRASS (over phone):
Hey, Cath, listen, it's Jim.
We got an eyewitness confirming
that Tiffany's TOD
was after 2:21 A.M.
Well, that's over an hour
after Cody's body was found.
Thanks, Jim.
Hey.
STOKES:
I got prints from the truck,
but half of them are Cody's.
Well, it is his truck.
So... get this.
There's a witness that puts
Tiffany's TOD after Cody's.
He didn't kill her.
I think he had a partner.
There's a set of unknowns
both on the truck and on the,
uh... electro-love machine.
So... say
this partner
thought Tiffany knew something
about the semen-rustling
and he ran her over
to keep her quiet.
So who's the partner?
We've got Cody's phone.
Find out who he's
been talking to.
JOHNSON:
Most of Cody's calls were to
a number in Durant, Oklahoma.
He lived on the
family ranch.
He was probably letting his
folks know how he was doing
in the finals.
All other calls were to
PBR staff and to Tiffany.
What about
her records?
Well, they're a little
more interesting.
Check out...
last night.
A dozen calls after midnight
from Eric Hong.
Precious Ricky.
You know this guy?
Yeah,
he's a pimp,
and he quit calling her
after 2:00 A.M.,
like he knew she
was already dead.
(laughs)
All right,
I don't want nobody hitting me.
All right?
Nobody's going
to hit you, Rick.
Good.
This is about
Tiffany Rigdon.
Beautiful girl,
skin like butterfly wings.
Did you beat her up?
I'm a lover, brother.
Let me tell you something, man.
You play around with me, I'm
gonna throw your ass in jail.
You feel me?
Yeah, I feel you.
Good.
So she said she
was leaving you,
going to get married, right?
(grunts)
Oh, come on, at least
admit I'm right about that.
Yeah, okay, sure.
Is that when you took
her boyfriend's truck
and ran her over?
Wait. Wait.
It's a good plan, Rick:
you get the boyfriend
and a little revenge to boot.
I mean, it's...
Okay, I didn't like
the girl quitting on me,
especially during one
of my busiest freaking weeks
of the year,
and I wanted
to talk her out of it.
Is that all you did: talk?
No, I couldn't even talk
to her.
She wouldn't take my calls,
so I quit trying.
Where were you making
all these phone calls from?
From a country-western bar.
I hit them all
when the cowboys come to town.
Mm-hmm, all right, all right,
I'll check it out.
Yeah, you do that, please.
I didn't take you
for a country music fan.
Yee-ha.
(band plays
upbeat country song)
♪ This ol' wheel
keeps on rollin' down the road ♪
♪ This ol' wheel keeps on
rollin' down the road ♪
♪ Oh, gravel and dust fly up
off of truck drivers ♪
♪ Down a dirt road
in Nashville ♪
♪ In the summertime in 1996 ♪
♪ I was listenin' to my dad ♪
♪ And Johnny Cash
doing "Chain Gang" ♪
♪ And talkin' trash
with Savannah ♪
♪ And smokin' cigarettes ♪
♪ But it wasn't that long ♪
♪ Till I tasted
the salt of the sea ♪
♪ But she was still in love with
the guy she left for me so ♪
♪ She stood there cryin'
as I packed my pack ♪
♪ And I knew that I was lyin'
when I said that I'd be back ♪
♪ This ol' wheel keeps on
rollin' down the road ♪
♪ This ol' wheel
keeps on rollin' down the road ♪
♪ Now fast forward
to about 2003 ♪
♪ I'm standin' on the corner ♪
♪ Of Hollywood and Vine,
just a six-string and me ♪
♪ And that Capitol building--
lookin' up at that thing ♪
♪ Wonderin' when am I gonna
get my chance to sing ♪
♪ But faced
with that kind of predicament ♪
♪ It'd be pretty hard
not to get choked up ♪
♪ When every hero I had has died
and every band I had broke up ♪
♪ ♪
(unzipping)
♪ This ol' wheel keeps on
rollin' down... ♪
(zippering)
STOKES:
Shotgun.
At close range.
STOKES:
Would have been pretty loud, but
everything is
in a place like this.
Cowboys, cattle rustling,
and now a shooting
at the dance hall.
Welcome to the Wild West.
BRASS:
So, Coco,
you didn't see anyone
threaten Precious Ricky?
I was trying
to put the nine ball
in the corner pocket.
Yeah, right.
You know this girl?
That's Tiffany.
She got married
last night.
Lucky bitch.
Do you know who
the groom was?
Troy? Troy something?
Know anything about him?
No. She just met him.
Sweet kid.
He, uh, took her side
when that cowgirl trash
got all up in her face.
♪ All I need is a woman's warmth
and that's where you come in ♪
♪ I wanna get high ♪
♪ And then get higher ♪
♪ Every city is just a little
bit different in the same way ♪
♪ I want to get drunk ♪
♪ And then get drunker ♪
♪ Live every minute to the limit
till the end of my days... ♪
Hey, cowboy.
Hey.
Like that hat.
Thank you.
What's underneath
don't look too bad, either.
(laughs)
I'm Tiffany.
I'm Troy.
We know what you are.
Whore.
Excuse me, Miss,
but we're having a private
conversation here.
Why pay that cow
when others would give you
the milk for free?
I think you owe
her an apology.
We don't want
your kind
in here.
Oh, yeah?
♪ When after the show
in the back of the bus ♪
♪ Oh, sweetheart, I know
what you wanna do ♪
♪ You wanna get high
and then get higher ♪
♪ Every city is just a little
bit different in the same say ♪
♪ You wanna get drunk
and then get drunker ♪
♪ And spend every minute
to the limit ♪
♪ Till the end of my days ♪
♪ Oh, yeah ♪
(screaming)
(glass breaking)
♪ Now sit down, honey ♪
♪ I'm gonna tell you the truth ♪
♪ For the first time ♪
(glass breaking)
(crowd clamoring)
♪ Oh, no dinner, no movie,
no flowers, no malls ♪
♪ No suit, no tie,
no cell phone calls ♪
(screaming)
♪ No promises, popcorn,
roller skates, diamond rings ♪
♪ Or making cakes ♪
♪ No brand-new fast cars,
ice cream, candy bars ♪
♪ Checkin' in,
callin' back, no... ♪
WOMAN:
♪ Do you think I'm fat? ♪
♪ Kiss me once, kiss me twice ♪
♪ Damn, you feel nice ♪
♪ Do you think
I might see you next year? ♪
She came back last night
and said that she was going
to marry the guy.
It's kind of impulsive,
isn't it?
Hey, Cop, somebody says
they want to marry you,
take care of you,
pay all your bills,
give you a nice place to live,
why would you even wait?
WOMAN:
It's always crazy busy
with the cowboys in this town.
You know, I think it's being
around all these bucking bulls.
Gets them all worked up.
Brings out their animal instinct
to mate.
(laughs)
According to the
marriage bureau,
Troy Birkhart
and Tiffany Rigdon
got their license
just before midnight.
And then, what,
Troy came over to your chapel
to set up the service?
Yeah.
He said his girl was changing
at the hotel.
It's the old story, you know.
She gets cold feet,
he can't face the truth,
keeps thinking
she's running late.
♪ Walk through this world
with me ♪
♪ Go where I go ♪
♪ Share all my dreams with me ♪
♪ I need you so ♪
♪ In life we search ♪
(chattering excitedly)
♪ And some of us find... ♪
Ooh, Vegas!
♪ I've looked for you... ♪
How long did he wait?
Hours.
He shows me the prize buckles
he's won for bull riding.
Tells me he's going
on the pro tour next year.
The little ranch they're going
to settle down on...
(laughing):
where the wind comes sweeping
down the plains.
And what time
did he end up leaving?
A little after 3:00 a.m.
Frankly, if she's not going
to make a go of it,
I say, better now
than down the road
before all the lawyers and
the property and all that mess.
Wedding chapel's only a couple
blocks from the crime scene.
Yeah, and she was killed
at 2:30.
Mm-hmm.
Killed?
Yeah, on the way
to her own wedding.
I'll get a BOLO out
on Troy's vehicle.
(garbled radio transmission)
WOMAN (over dispatch):
...1000 Chestnut, a 918X.
1000 Chestnut,
a 918X.
(garbled radio transmission)
MALE DISPATCHER:
Attention, all officers:
attempt to locate yellow
Ford Ranger 2005 pickup,
Texas plates Charlie Nora Baker
Queen Seven Five Zero.
Troy Birkhart, white male adult,
wanted in connection
with a 415A, Eric Hong homicide.
Dispatch, this is C-21 Brown.
The pickup
that you're looking for
is on level 3 of the PD garage.
Suspect is in the vehicle,
armed and agitated.
I repeat:
suspect is armed and agitated.
Copy, C-21.
Units responding.
Code Three.
(breathing shallowly)
Hey, buddy.
Hey. You must
be Troy, huh?
(elevator bell dings)
Just be cool, okay?
All right?
BRASS:
Hey, Troy,
listen to me.
We don't want anyone
getting hurt, okay?
So put the
gun down.
Come out of the truck
with your hands up.
Put the gun
down, Troy.
Just let it
fall away.
Now.
He moves
on that gun,
don't wait.
Hang on, Jim.
Let me... Let me
talk to him real quick.
Okay,
but we're not taking
any chances.
STOKES:
Yeah, yeah, okay.
Hey, Troy, when's
the last time
you got down
to Big Bend?
Huh?
You-You got the plate frame.
Man, I used to go to
summer camp down there.
Stay back!
Hey, take it
easy, Troy.
Look, I got no
weapon on me.
Okay, I just want to talk
to you for a second.
I killed somebody!
Yeah, I know.
You came out to Vegas,
and you got in over your head,
but this is getting
out of control.
If you don't put
that gun down,
these cops are going
to start shooting,
and that could turn out
very bad for both of us.
You know what I mean?
(breathing shallowly)
I'm just... I'm just doing
the right thing.
Making sure you know it was me.
And I'll pay
for what I did.
Eye for an eye, man.
Hey.
Stay back! I'll do it, I swear!
I'll do it,
I swear!
No, Troy, just wait.
Hang on now. Listen to me.
I know about Tiffany.
I know why she stood you up
at the wedding chapel.
(voice breaking):
That Ricky.
Thought he owned her.
Hey!
Hey, what you doing, man?
(gunshot)
He wouldn't let her come.
Hey, man, look at me.
Look at me.
(garbled radio transmission)
I know she wanted
to be there for you.
Come on out of there, man.
I'll tell you all about it.
You don't want
to do this.
(garbled radio transmission)
Give me that.
Come on, give me
that thing.
Give it to me.
(inhales and exhales loudly)
It's going
to be okay.
(sighs)
(garbled radio transmission)
You didn't go
to summer camp.
Missed you around here.
Welcome back.
Thanks.
(garbled radio transmission)
Well, we know that Cody
wasn't alone when he died
because he couldn't have opened
the bucking chute by himself.
And we know that someone
other than Cody put
the electroejaculation equipment
into the truck and drove away.
Killing Tiffany.
Whoever that someone was
knew how to get into the arena,
and also how to use
the equipment.
More cowbell!
I processed these
for you.
And?
Well, as you can see,
they're bull ropes.
These are the kind that the
riders hold in their hands.
Every rider has one, and
they're usually custom-made.
I mean,
look at that craftsmanship.
Yeah, it's exquisite.
Now, that's the rope that I
collected from Cody's room?
Yes, it is.
Uh, you'll note
that it is polynylon.
Now the rope that was collected
from the crime scene,
though, was long sisal,
a type of hemp.
Very old-school, and they
stopped making it years ago.
That means the rope found
with Cody's body
belonged to someone
who's been around for a while.
How'd you like to go
on a roundup?
Hey, Ms. Twicker,
how's it going?
It'd be going a lot better
if my bull Wintwister
was in there bucking.
Is Cash Dooley here?
Cash!
Cops want to talk to you.
(bull lowing)
BRASS:
Hey, Mr. Dooley.
So, where you staying
when you're here in Vegas?
Here.
He's got the
sleeper cab up front.
Oh, right here.
Is that where you
keep your clothes,
the rest of
your stuff?
What's this about?
I'd like to take a look
in that cab.
No. It's private.
NANCY:
Now hold on.
I own this rig.
If you guys want
to search it,
go ahead.
BRASS:
Well, bull semen is property,
and that property isn't yours
so it's theft.
Now, here's what I think
happened.
You know Cody.
He's at the end
of his career.
He's a little down
on his luck.
Never put any money aside.
Wintwister's output goes
for 20 grand a pop
on the open market.
So you and Cody,
you get together,
you do the deed and, uh,
sell it on the sly.
If you knew Cody,
you'd know he'd never do
anything like that.
And then when he told his
girlfriend, you took his truck.
He always let me
borrow his truck.
Even when it was
to hunt down his girl?
Jim?
We ran his ten-card
against the prints
from the truck
and the equipment.
They don't match.
So, there is
a third guy?
Right. So now,
I'm convinced
that Cody Latshaw's death
was not an accident.
Okay, so who is working
with you on this, Cash, huh?
Who was at the wheel
of Cody's truck
when you ran down
that girl?
Was it someone
in the arena?
What's this,
a cowboy code of silence?
Look,
you want to make me
compel fingerprints
from everyone working
in that arena,
I can do that.
(crowd cheering)
We got a match!
Dustin Lightfoot.
Dustin? He's a bullfighter.
(announcer shouting)
I got a 440 exiting the east end
of the arena.
Head him off.
Hold it.
Freeze. Right there.
Don't move.
Hands behind
your back.
Well, howdy, partner.
This is a new experience
for me.
First time I caught me
a cattle rustler.
LIGHTFOOT:
Look, Cash and me was just
trying to make
a little extra money.
BRASS:
Then Cody Latshaw came in drunk
and itching for a fight.
Hey! Quit that!
Hey, Cody.
You hear me?
Cody, relax.
Ain't nobody hurtin'
anybody.
That ain't your property.
Cody, Cody, just...
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa.
He ain't breathin'.
We wasn't tryin'
to kill him.
He had a cervical
fracture
from his earlier ride.
It didn't take much
to snap his spine.
Then you tried to make it
look like an accident.
But you didn't have
to run over his girlfriend.
That girl we hit--
that was...
that was Cody's girlfriend?
Yeah, you didn't know?
We was racing
to get the product
to our buyer.
And we took Cody's truck
'cause, well,
mine ain't air-conditioned and,
and he wasn't gonna be usin' it.
(tires screeching)
BRASS:
Well.
WILLOWS:
It's kind of a lonely life,
these cowboys,
every weekend a different town.
That's part of the tradition,
you know.
Solitary man out there
trying to find himself.
Yeah, but no man is an island.
I mean, obviously, he had
feelings for Nancy
or he wouldn't have
written her that poem.
Nancy? I don't know about that.
Tiffany's the one
that broke his heart.
I don't think it's
about either girl.
"I can't help now but wonder
what your brown eyes
were concealing."
Did you read
Tiffany's autopsy report?
Oh.
Yeah, her eyes were blue.
So were Nancy's.
Then who did he write
the poem for?
Wintwister.
The bull?
I think
that's why he went back
to the arena that night.
Wordsworth
once wrote,
"Through love we feel
we are greater than we know."
My guess is, riding that bull,
Cody felt like a greater man.
"Our bodies close together,
"like my ride hand
in my glove.
"Hearts pounding with
excitement, and dare I say it,
"love.
"I know I'll never own you;
it's your nature to run free.
"But I pray the Lord above
"that one day
you'll come back to me.
"Then we'll ride off in glory
until our time is done.
"And I will be your hero,
your cowboy in the sun.