Ecklie's been
on me
to finish
the monthly stats,
so I need a list
of all the Lab call-outs
from Dispatch
as soon as you can.
You'll have it by the
end of shift tomorrow.
Thanks.
So, you've been pulling a
lot of doubles this week.
Yeah, it's
about all I do.
Have you been in
touch with Sara?
We've talked a little.
So where's she at?
San Francisco.
Visiting her mother.
No, I mean--
that's nice.
No, but I meant where's
she at emotionally?
You know, with respect
to the two of you.
I can't speak for her.
So speak for
yourself.
I can't talk,
I'm really busy.
♪ ♪
(fire alarm ringing)
(manically laughing)
So Archie's
in the Garage,
he's documenting evidence
from a drug bust,
he picks up a thing
of coke,
and then it blows up
in his face?
No. He picks up
a cellophane
and duct-tape-wrapped
kilo of coke,
and the third one from
the top of the stack
blows up in
his face.
Oh.
It's important to be specific.
Okay, well,
this game is not as much fun
as I thought
it was going
to be--
It's not a game,
it's a thought experiment.
If you want to be
a good criminalist--
I am a good criminalist.
If you want to be a better
criminalist,
then you have to learn
to train to--
Learn
to think like a criminal.
I know.
Look, I'm sure Grissom's
told you...
well, maybe not you,
but he's told me many times:
that we speak for the dead.
Think of this
exercise as a way
for the dead to speak
for themselves.
SIMMS:
But that's not actually
what this is--
HODGES:
It's a chance
for you to be a CSI.
The only thing you need to do
is answer two simple questions.
Whodunit and how?
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
HODGES:
After HazMat cleans up
the scene...
the coroner does his thing...
No sign of
sexual trauma.
SIMMS:
What?
HODGES:
I believe he's legally
required to check.
What the CSIs realize is--
I can't believe
Archie's gone.
He was too good
for this world.
(both sobbing)
What?
They would be very upset.
Can we at least stipulate
that they heroically contain
their bereavement?
Yes, I suppose Archie
could live with that.
So to speak.
Thank you.
Mm-hmm.
HODGES:
What the CSIs realize is...
It's gotta be
the dealer.
Yeah, he booby-trapped
the stash
so if the cops got
the drugs...
Then they would
get the boom
along with it?
Right?
Am I right?
No, you're wrong.
Just let me finish the setup,
okay?
Sorry.
HODGES:
What the CSIs
finally realize is...
SIMMS:
They sorted everything already?
That was quick.
HODGES:
Can you just let me finish!
According to this,
20 bricks of coke were logged
into evidence
just past midnight.
The explosion occurred
about a half an hour later.
But there are 21
wrappers here.
And since no one entered
or exited the Lab
during that time frame,
it means the explosive
was planted
in the suitcase here.
Which means...
The killer is someone
in the Lab.
Well, if the killer is someone
who works in the Lab,
then he could just tamper
with the evidence.
Which means that there's
really no way for me
to solve this thing,
this a trick question.
No, no, no, that's
not what I want...
My shoelace is untied.
Excuse me.
Okay.
Okay, um...
wouldn't, how
about this.
Since it would be
pretty risky
for the killer
to tamper with evidence
during a full-on
investigation in the Lab...
Mm-hmm.
let's just say,
for the purposes
of this exercise,
that can't happen.
Okay.
Now what?
That's up to you.
You have the setup.
You run the investigation
from here.
Simple Q &amp; A.
You ask, I answer.
Truthfully?
Absolutely.
No lying-- call that a rule.
Well, what if I get close
to actually figuring it out,
you're not just gonna change who
did it or something like that?
No revisionism-- also a rule.
For something
that's not a game
it sure does have
a lot of rules.
You want to do this or not?
All right.
Okay.
I guess the first thing
that I would do
would be to examine
the actual bomb mechanism
to see if there's any clue
as to who might have built it.
Good idea.
Because there are a lot
of clues.
Chemicals have been sent
to Trace for I.D.,
but the bomb appears
to be a binary explosive.
Killer hides the loaded brick
amongst the others...
A little pressure arms it...
Liquid "A" in ampoule mixes
with solid "B",
creating an unstable
chemical explosive...
all you need to do is move it.
Ooh, I have an idea.
HODGES:
What?
SIMMS:
What about the blasting cap?
HODGES:
Ah, well, what do you know?
The leg wires are color coded.
SIMMS:
Good, 'cause the color
coding is manufacturer
specific.
So now we can track down
the source.
Indeed we could.
Hey, people.
What's going on?
Nothing.
You look... better.
Let's say you learn
that LVPD recently
seized one dozen
commercial grade
blasting caps
in an arson-explosives
raid,
and that the Lab
was processing the
case evidence.
Well, then, I know exactly
where I'd go next...
'Course I know
where those blasting caps are.
They're right in here.
SIMMS:
No, no, no, no, no.
Not so fast, cowboy.
Give me those keys.
Looks like
you're one blasting cap shy,
Bob.
That's not possible.
Wait...
Y'all don't think
I had something
to do with...
Are there any prints
on the lock?
Excuse me, we're--
Playing a murder game.
I know, I get it.
I wanna play.
He says
it's not a game.
Well, I wanna play anyway.
No.
Why not?
You're the dead guy.
Oh.
Well, then I'd have
a vested interest
in the outcome then,
wouldn't I?
Oh, come on,
I'll fill him in
as we go along.
Fine.
Yup. So.
Are there any prints
on the lock?
HODGES:
No, no prints.
Looks like this lock's
been slipped.
So somebody stole the blasting
cap from Ballistics
to make it look
like Bobby did it.
Nefarious, don't
you think?
What about the chemicals
that were used
to make the explosive?
Did we get anything back
from Trace?
You always get something
from Trace.
The explosive was
liquid nitro-acetate
and solid ammonium nitrate
packed in baking soda.
To blend in with the rest
of the cocaine bricks.
Cute.
Explosive liquids are
generally pretty volatile.
Did you ask Hodges
if nitro-acetate has any special
storage requirements?
HODGES:
It needs to be refrigerated.
Yeah, he said it needed
to be refrigerated.
Well, there's only so many
refrigerators in the Lab.
Maybe "where" can get us
to "who".
What are you guys
looking for?
I'm sorry, we can't
tell you that, Henry.
Nitrogen
tetra-hydride...
Sodium nitrate.
Wait, what happens
when you mix
those two compounds?
They produce nitro-acetate.
That's a high explosive binary,
Henry.
Really?
I didn't know that.
Look, just 'cause I
have those compounds
in my fridge
doesn't mean
I used them to make
nitro-acetate.
You can't
prove that.
Baking soda was used to conceal
the explosive, smartass.
It's also used to
absorb odors.
Nice smell is a priority
of my life.
I think the baking soda was used
to absorb a lot more than odors,
Henry.
Okay, I confess,
I did it!
Henry?
Why would Henry kill me?
We're not supposed to care
about the why.
Whatever.
...with us
for that.
Hey, fellas.
Hey.
Thanks for giving me
justice at least.
Yeah, you're welcome.
Man, I don't know
if I'm more tired
or hungry right now.
You wanna get something
to eat?
Yeah.
Actually, I felt like
a little Pai Gow
or some Blackjack.
Let's hit the Strip.
After the shift
we just pulled?
Yeah.
I just drank one of
those energy drinks.
I probably won't sleep for
another couple hours.
I don't think so,
man.
Maybe another time,
huh?
All right.
I'll catch ya later.
All right, Grissom.
That's it for me.
I'm out of here.
Have a nice day.
Yeah, I'm going over to Frank's
to grab something to eat.
I'll probably be there
for at least an hour
if you want to...
if you want to join me.
You know, we don't have to talk
about anything in particular.
Just two guys
having breakfast.
I just don't think
it's good for people
to be alone too much.
If you want to, cool.
If not, cool.
Whatever.
Hi.
Rack 'em up.
Excuse me?
Well, word on campus is,
there's a murder game going on.
Oh, no, no, no,
it's not a game.
It's a thought experiment.
Sounds like the late
Archie Johnson
has a big mouth.
Come on, please, it's been
really slow at Prints all day.
Who we killin'?
Henry, I need the tox
on that lady, um...
(screaming)
Henry!
No sign of
sexual trauma.
Thank God for small favors.
You know, David,
our job is never easy,
but this is a colleague.
If your emotions are too raw
and you feel you need
to excuse yourself...
Look.
(crunching)
He's crunchy.
Um...
(crunching)
Frozen sweat stains. Yuck.
He was trapped in a small space
at minus ten degrees centigrade.
So it's fair to assume
he was exerting himself
in a state
of mind-numbing terror.
How long do you think
he was stuck in there?
(sharp crack)
Well, several hours at least.
Time of exposure
in extreme cold
is difficult to gauge
physiologically.
Why don't you let me know
when he softens up
and we'll start cutting.
So we're just going to
wait for him to thaw?
What do you want me to do,
stick him in a microwave?
(microwave beeping)
Ooh...
Hot... hot, hot, hot.
So, then, okay,
Henry froze to death.
Well, maybe not.
Because if the autopsy
hasn't been performed yet,
then we can't be sure
that's COD.
Well played, Simms.
So it takes a few turns
for the autopsy results
to get back.
Turns?
Hours. A few hours.
So, while you're waiting
for the autopsy results,
what do you do
in the meantime?
Well, the CSIs would
process the freezer.
Did they find anything?
A virtual cornucopia.
(digital camera clicking
quietly)
WILLOWS:
The condition of the interior
could be the result
of a struggle,
or the simple,
understandable panic
of a man trapped
inside a freezer.
In any event,
the emergency release handle
appears to have been bent
and rendered inoperative,
and several chemical containers
broken in the process
possibly releasing chloroform
and methyl ethyl ketone
into the space.
I'm sending samples to Trace
to confirm.
(laughs):
Trace.
Is there anything you can't do?
Hodges.
Sorry.
This could be a case
of lab geek humor gone wrong.
Hello?
Hello!
Hello?! It's not funny!
(grunts, glass shatters)
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God, help!
(panting)
(yells in frustration)
Help me!
(muffled):
Please help!
So the merry prankster
comes back later,
sees the joke gone bad,
then he just yanks the pin
and scrams.
You said that the emergency
release plunger was bent.
Mm-hmm.
Well, that thing is made
of solid steel.
How could Henry do that?
Adrenaline kicks in
when he finally realizes
that he's dying.
So, maybe in the moment
of crisis,
Henry has the strength
of ten men.
Ten small men.
(chuckles)
"Maybe."
That word always looks
so good on a case report.
Was there any evidence
on the handle
on the outside of the freezer?
Just a schmear.
Sugar, soy protein,
partially hydrogenated
vegetable oils,
roasted nuts.
Peanut butter?
WEBSTER:
Well, killer's got to eat, too.
SIMMS:
So, CSIs would check
every trash can
and every bio hazard disposal
unit in the whole Lab.
HODGES:
Yes, the would,
and they would find...
What, no jelly?
We found the peanut butter
from inside your glove.
It matches the stuff we found
on the freezer door handle.
Chunky, right?
I didn't kill Henry.
Well, not on purpose.
No, not even by accident.
I only had a couple of minutes
for lunch,
and I had a bunch
of photo emulsion sheets
that needed to be stored.
And I store them in the freezer.
You seem very tense.
You know, I don't really like
being persecuted.
Yeah.
Get used to it, punk.
No, I don't know about that.
What?
Well, Bobby's a gun guy.
Gun guys shoot people.
Gun guys don't shoot people.
People shoot people.
Actually, bullets shoot people,
shot from guns
which are usually in the hands
of gun guys.
Can we get the autopsy results?
Well, I guess Henry's had
enough time to defrost.
COD was not, in fact,
due to hypothermia.
Ooh, wait, no, I can guess
what they found in Tox.
It was chloroform.
Nope.
Methyl ethyl ether?
PCP.
What?
Massive, overdose amounts
of PCP.
Commonly known as phencyclidine,
or angel dust.
PCP blocks the brain's
NMDA receptors,
hypothalamus goes nuts,
resulting in anxiety,
confusion,
and fever-like overheating.
(yelling)
WEBSTER:
So Henry goes into the cooler
to cool off...
SIMMS:
And with the PCP stimulating
his adrenal glands,
he has the strength
of the Incredible Hulk.
(frantic yelling)
ANDREWS:
A duster?
You made me a lousy duster?
That is totally bogus.
Aside from the 10,000
other reasons
why I'd be crazy
to even try that junk,
if I were a closet PCP freak,
I wouldn't do it in the Lab.
That's very professional.
Archie told me
about your sick
little thought experiment,
and I want to play.
But I still can't believe,
even hypothetically,
you'd do something
like this to me.
Well, Henry, I hypothetically
called your mother
and I explained everything.
That woman is a crier.
Your autopsy didn't mention
powder in
his nasal passages
or PCP damage in his lungs.
That's because it wasn't there.
So Henry didn't inhale it,
or smoke it, or snort it?
No, he didn't.
Then how did the PCP
get into my system?
You tell me.
Oh!
Crusty pits.
Sweat stains.
You said that Henry's lab coat
had big sweat stains
on the collar
and on the armpits.
So that's it--
somebody dosed the coat.
(crackling)
Lab coat tests positive
for PCP.
Combined with body heat
and sweat,
the drug must've entered
his system transdermally.
Like a nicotine patch from hell.
Well, Henry would've died
of an overdose no matter what.
So, all the trapping him
in the freezer
with the
chemicals spilling,
that was all
completely incidental.
It was the logical outcome
of the initial crime.
And it's quite funny.
Hey.
Well, we're not done yet.
Who did the deed?
Well, taking lab coats
off the premises
is against regulations.
So the PCP would've had to have
been applied in the Lab,
right under our noses.
And that stuff reeks.
I have to crank
my fume hood up full
whenever I work with it,
I still go home with a headache.
Fume hoods. There's fume hoods
in the Garage,
and DNA and Trace.
So we would have to test
all the sinks for PCP.
HODGES:
Excellent.
That's a good approach.
(crackling)
HODGES:
But you would find nothing.
SIMMS:
Really?
Yeah, there's no trace of PCP
in any of sinks.
Squeaky clean.
Damn it.
Oh! Wait.
I got it, check the plant.
HODGES:
You got it.
The killer cleaned up,
but he left one witness.
Wendy.
Me?
Oh, drat.
Well, it's not a slow day
for me after all.
Ecklie wants me to pick up
the backlog from Swing.
Somebody please tell me
who dies next.
And how.
Thank you.
So...
You got time for one more?
Well, someone's having fun.
Maybe a little.
You're not bad at this.
SIMMS:
Thanks.
I've been thinking about taking
the CSI field test.
This is actually really good
theory and practice for me.
The field test?
Yeah.
What?
Why?
Nothing.
Nothing?
That's right.
A great big pile of nothing.
From me, to you.
Oh, hey.
How are you?
Why?
I can't ask how
you're doing?
I'm sorry.
I've just had
a lot of, uh...
I've been busy.
Oh.
Well, maybe you should
take a few days off,
for once in your career.
I mean, you've got
enough stored up.
Go after her.
It's not what she wants.
What do you want?
I want her to be happy.
Field Agent Simms.
Stop it.
Hey, I think it's got
a nice ring to it.
Thank you.
Here she comes,
flashing her badge,
taking down perps.
Why is even potential
advancement
so threatening to you?
Hey, Sanders left the lab,
he got his ass kicked.
I'm just saying.
All right, come on,
let's do another one.
Okay. Fine.
Let's.
SIMMS:
Well, now, that's a little
passive-aggressive,
don't you think?
(camera shutter clicking)
No kidding.
It appears as though
the vic struck the edge
of the table.
The evidence
on the floor is...
well, evidence.
Brown paper bindle
must have opened when it fell.
Looks like the contents
of a woman's purse.
And here's the vic's other shoe.
SIMMS:
Square toe, low heel,
stylish but affordable.
Flirty, not whory.
You will be missed.
There's an oily residue
on the sole.
SANDERS:
The evidence appears to lead
to an inescapable conclusion.
This tragedy might have just
simply been the result
of an accident
in the workplace.
SIMMS:
I fell off a ladder?
Well, you are kind
of little clumsy.
Since when?
It's endearing.
HODGES:
Are you satisfied
with the explanation?
SIMMS:
Uh, no.
What about the oily residue
on the ladder?
There are bristles in the oil,
which means
that somebody brushed it on.
ANDREWS:
What exactly is the oily stuff?
Well, thank God...
...for trace analysis.
Hmm.
Hodges, who is a genius
and tragically underpaid,
used the powers
of his brilliant mind
and the scientific method
to discover that the oil
that was brushed
on the ladder was a Teflon-based
two-part oil.
A gun lubricant.
So?
So you're the gun guy, Bobby.
Yeah, which is exactly why
I would never use
Teflon-based two-part oil.
Real gun guys hate that stuff.
If it separates in the can,
it separates in the gun.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Whoa. You are tense.
So, where do you think
you're going?
Back to work.
This is ridiculous.
Oh.
Sit down.
(whipping)
Ow!
No, no. Captain Brass
is not the kind of cop
who smacks a suspect around.
Really? Scares me.
Oh, well, look
who's the clumsy one now.
Excuse me.
Okay, so we don't have nearly
enough to hold Bobby, right?
No.
All right.
Who's up for an autopsy?
ROBBINS:
The carotid-jugular complex
was transected,
and based on the placement
and size of the wound,
I'd say she had at...
Hey, it's a neck wound.
Based on the placement
and size of
the neck wound,
she was conscious 30
to 60 seconds
before blood loss was fatal.
That's a long time.
No one reported her screaming
or calling out for help.
We have to get back
to the case file.
There was no blood
on her hands at the scene.
Unless she was unconscious,
she would have at least tried
to stop the bleeding.
Well, there was no blow
to the head.
Do you think it's possible
she was dead
before she hit the table?
You mean like
a cardiac event?
I can't rule that out,
but a healthy, 36-year-old
having a heart attack?
SIMMS:
35 in October,
thank you very much.
She has a oval, perimortem burn
on her wrist.
Wait a second.
That's familiar.
(electrical sizzling)
Singed right off
her barely
35-year-old wrist.
That bracelet wasn't
old evidence.
I was wearing it.
Correct.
So, what
melts silver
and stops your heart
at the same time?
A bolt of lightning.
In the lab.
Electrocution.
From what?
Something
in the Evidence Locker.
SIMMS:
There was a motorcycle battery
in the ventilation duct?
ANDREWS:
Wired to the ladder
and the evidence box?
HODGES:
Precisely.
(electrical sizzling)
Devilishly clever,
wouldn't you say?
No.
Well, who's the killer,
Wile E. Coyote?
What do you mean?
ANDREWS:
It's ridiculous!
Anyone could have walked
in there.
So, what, the
victim's just random?
Uh, no.
How'd the killer get me up there
in the first place?
What did he do, pass
me in the hall and say,
"Hey, Wendy, go
climb up that ladder
"and check out the case evidence
you had absolutely nothing
to do with?"
Not in those words exactly,
but, uh, yeah.
That's completely
unverifiable.
This is so lame.
Scenario requires
further revision.
Okay, what is that?
Nothing.
Is that a tape recorder?
You are so paranoid.
This thought experiment
has now concluded.
Thank you.
Why were you
recording us?
I wasn't recording you.
Why would I record you?
That makes no sense.
"Lab Rats."
"The Game of Science
and Murder."
It's a prototype.
"Two to four players,
ages eight and up."
You're making a board game?
Well, it's not just
a board game.
Gets people to think.
Why were you
recording us?
(sighs)
I needed your help
to flesh out scenarios,
and I figured that
if I hid the recorder,
your answers would be candid
and honest.
Look, see.
It's like Clue,
only CSI-ier.
Hodges, this is, uh...
This is kind of impressive.
In a painfully sad,
geek type of way.
Well, painfully sad geeks
have a lot of spare time
on their hands
and loads of disposable income.
Lab Rats could be a gold mine.
Oh!
(laughs):
Little Lab Techs.
Mm-hmm.
"Sandy Baxter,
fingerprint fanatic."
"Reggie Chang,
eagled-eyed A/V expert."
"Andrew Henries,
top-notch tox tech."
"Hodgkins."
Hodgkins.
Mm-hmm.
You named yourself
after cancer.
Oh!
"Mindy Bimms,
"the clumsy
yet buxom DNA tech."
Clumsy yet buxom?
It's a redeeming feature.
It's-It's a prototype.
So, tell me, do you think
that Mindy Bimms is clumsy
because she's top-heavy?
Or do you just mean clumsy
like this?
Oops.
Okay, are you...
are you allergic
to being honest with me?
'Cause the thing is,
if you had actually asked me
to help you with this game,
I would have.
But, no, you had to hide
a tape recorder under a table
and engage us all
in this great big
thought experiment!
When in reality, it doesn't
even matter, apparently,
what I think because
I'm just Mindy Big Boobs
to you, and I...
You are the dumbest
smart guy I know.
You think I'm smart?
(sighs)
Night, Greg.
Yeah, whatever.
HODGES (high-pitched voice):
Oh, Hodges, I'm so sorry.
It's just that I'm jealous
of your intellect.
But Wendy, you have so much
to live for.
Don't do it.
You're too close to the edge.
Oh, and now I'm drowning!
Oh, God!
Oh, God, help me.
Help me.
What are you doing?
Oh, uh...
(sighs)
I was, uh, just trying
to... develop a board game
based on this place,
but not in any
legally actionable sense.
You get evidence,
scenarios, analysis.
Try to solve diabolical murders.
I like games.
Really?
Yeah.
Okay. Let's play.
What makes it hard
to catch a killer?
Is it the sheer
destructive power
of the murder itself
that obliterates evidence
as it snuffs out life?
Or is it the chain of events
the murder sets into motion
which obscure the true crime?
(gasping)
That was good.
Or is it a mechanism
so complex and diabolical
that it
borders on the incredible?
In truth,
it is all these things,
and all these things
are the same.
Because the only real way
to catch a killer,
is to outsmart him.
And hope that he's
not smarter than you.
(gunshot, thudding)
So you're rehearsing
your "speech"
in front of your computer,
and you take a
bullet to the head.
No witnesses.
Nobody heard the shot,
and the killer
is somebody in the Lab.
Am I eligible?
In this scenario, no.
Okay.
So during the basic
process of the scene,
what do I find?
HODGES:
A single nine millimeter casing
at the doorway to Trace.
Then my first blush theory
is a walk-by.
(shell casing clinks,
body thuds)
I'm going to need the bullet.
Then I'm going
to need an autopsy.
Get it out of your system.
No sign of sexual trauma.
Out! Now!
All right,
trajectory of the shot
was roughly 90 degrees
from vertical,
straight through
his noble skull.
Bullet didn't exit.
GRISSOM:
Is it intact?
More or less.
IBIS.
HODGES:
The bullet's nose
is significantly deformed
and the lead base is pitted.
But there are sufficient striae
to get a match
for what little it's worth.
(beeping)
The gun came through the lab
about a week ago
in a buyback program,
and was subsequently destroyed.
So you were shot by a weapon
that no longer exists.
Apparently.
Okay, let's go over
your snuff film, shall we?
I want to see
exactly what you did.
In truth,
it is all of these things,
and all of these things
are the same.
(rewinding)
Because the only real way
to catch a killer,
is to outsmart him and hope
that he is not smarter than you.
(gunshot, laughter)
Do it again.
One more time.
Wait, wait, wait--
they all want to watch?
Professional curiosity.
I guess.
(on monitor):
In truth, it is
all these things,
and all these things
are the same.
Because the only real way
to catch a killer,
is to outsmart him and hope
that he is not smarter than you.
(gunshot, body thudding)
GRISSOM:
You took the shot straight
into your head,
but according to the video,
you were not facing
the hallway.
Which means the bullet
didn't come from there.
It must've come from here.
HODGES:
Yes, it did.
A zip gun.
HODGES:
With an unrifled barrel.
And a remote trigger.
What model year is the pager?
Pre 1990.
So no call-back numbers.
Pre-1990 pagers
didn't store them.
HODGES:
So, you're at a dead end?
I'm just getting started.
Do I have to walk over
to the GCMS
or will you just tell me?
The barrel of the zip gun
contains traces
of black powder.
Okay, but the bullet
was pitted on the base,
which is the result of exposure
to smokeless gunpowder.
Which means that the bullet
that killed you
was fired twice.
GRISSOM:
The killer test fires the gun,
knowing it will be destroyed,
and keeps the bullet
and the casing.
He puts the bullet
in a metal tube
on a wad of black powder.
With a pager trigger,
it's essentially
a remote controlled musket.
Call the number from any phone
or through the internet and...
(explosion)
Impressive.
Can you tell me whodunit?
Well, Bobby Dawson
is an early
19th century
firearm enthusiast.
He, uh, loads and fires
muskets for fun.
Oh, yeah.
Big gun guy.
I didn't do it!
I didn't do anything!
I swear!
Hey!
Whoa.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
(sighs)
(cocks gun)
Gun.
What do you got
against Bobby Dawson?
Nothing.
Running gag.
So, you think Bobby Dawson
did it?
No.
Bobby was framed.
You drew me a map.
The path
of the bullet,
if not stopped
by your brain mass,
would have continued straight
through into
ballistics.
Where Bobby works.
Now, Bobby's a real gun guy,
and no gun guy would ever
position himself
down-range
of a shot.
You're more than a victim,
Hodges.
According to your video,
you straightened up just before
the fatal shot was fired.
You knew it was coming.
And you made sure that you were
in the perfect position
to catch it.
I am a mere Padawan
in the presence
of the Jedi Master.
True.
Let's play another.
Sure.
You weren't ready.
To leave.
This.
The challenges,
the puzzles,
the job.
No.
But Sara was.
Yeah, she was.
You can't stand in the way
of that.
When it's time
for someone to move on,
you just gotta let them go.
Let's play the game, shall we?
Okay.
Oh!
Mind if I record this?
Scenario 12,
Hodges and Grissom.
Okay, you walk
into the AV lab.
You find Archie slumped
over his computer
with a knife in his head...