WOMAN:
Nobody knew he was coming.
Nobody knew his name.
Well, if you'd stop talking
for a minute, you'd understand.
The investigation's been
compromised.
Lives are at risk.
How many people
do the right thing anymore?
Have a conscience?
Don Cook didn't even know
what he saw.
El Matocho doesn't kill
for the thrill
or because he was abused
as a child.
He kills because
it's his answer to everything.
I had him eyewitnessed.
It was enough
for an indictment.
No indictment, no trial.
He goes free
and La Tijera gets stronger.
So don't patronize me by saying
this might be an accident.
I don't care who's on call,
Conrad,
or about your stupid protocol.
I want Grissom.
1000 Chestnut
and 918...
Maybe the reception sucks
out here.
I said I want Grissom.
Say I asked for him personally.
I don't want anyone
touching anything.
Thanks for all
your help, guys.
Case is reassigned to Grissom.
He's home sick, Maddy.
Yeah, I heard all about it
from Ecklie. Blah, blah, blah.
The point that he and you
seem to be missing
is that I have 18
grand jurists sifting
through evidence,
trying to help me indict one
of the deadliest gangs
this city has ever...
Who's in charge of the scene?!
I am.
For God's sake.
Madeleine Klein, Deputy DA.
Albert Robbins,
Clark County Coroner.
BRASS:
Talk to me, David.
Confirms it's Don Cook.
This is on us.
What do you got, Doc?
Other than the obvious burns
over the better part
of his body,
there's this.
He was shot.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
WILLOWS:
Let me run it down for you.
Isolated stretch of Route 2,
burned car on the shoulder,
burned male victim
out of the car 20 feet away.
Single gunshot wound
to the lower back.
Passing motorist called it in.
Fire department arrived
within 12 minutes.
Fire burned so hot,
they had to use foam
to put it out, which, of course,
is never good for us.
Where is he?
I've been waiting
over an hour for you.
What, are you walking here?
How many times have
I gotten out of bed
in the middle of the
night for you, Gil?
Yeah. Yeah, well, I'd like
to phone it in, too.
I left an AA meeting
for this.
Trumps walking pneumonia.
Here you go,
Eyes-and-Ears.
We'll keep in touch.
So the Deputy DA got out of bed
for you?
Whose bed?
Talk to me about the road.
All right.
The debris path starts
approximately 100 yards
from where the vehicle
came to rest.
Show me what you see.
What are you doing,
a catalog shoot?
Where's your matching hat
with your pom-pom?
Leave me alone.
I have a cold.
So, based on the
debris pattern,
the victim was driving the car
when the blaze started.
Swerving all over
the road.
Probably because he was on fire.
(tires squealing)
(crashing)
What do you think?
Sounds about right.
(shutter clicks)
(loud sneeze)
Gesundheit.
Thanks.
Boy, I hope
I'm not getting sick.
I'm not finding any pour
patterns on the exterior.
The hood
and the front quarter panels
are down to the primer
and the front tires are
burnt down to the rim.
Think the fire
probably started in
the engine compartment.
New car engines
don't catch fire,
not by accident.
Now we'll have to get it back
to the lab for a closer look.
And guys on fire don't stop
to close doors.
No, no, I talked to the
battalion chief about that.
He said the driver's
side was open
when his boys showed up,
and that the pressure from
the hose probably closed it.
Probably?
Hosers.
Nick, come here.
Clear that off, would you?
"L-A-T." That's La Tijera's tag.
Boy, you look like hell.
I need sugar. You got a soda?
Nice to see you, too, Maddy.
Six months' worth
of investigation;
two months working
with the grand jury;
five low-level indictments
against the LATs.
Why you? 'Cause you're the only
one who won't screw it up.
My team won't
screw it up.
Oh, right.
Your team.
Warrick Brown got mixed up
with a crooked judge.
Sanders ran down a civilian
while on duty.
Ms. Willows lied about
being at a crime scene,
among other things.
And who can forget Stokes,
your straight arrow?
Suspected of killing
his hooker girlfriend.
How does the song go?
"You call me up,
I get 'em out of it"?
If it weren't for me,
you'd have no team.
Are you done?
(soda can opens)
Sorry. You have a...?
This was recorded two weeks ago.
This guy had no idea
that what he saw
was the key to bringing
down La Tijera
and their leader
El Matocho.
MAN:
Okay, I know this
is my third violation,
but I was not speeding.
I-I blew past that light because
I had a fight with my wife.
BRASS:
Listen, you're not here
for a traffic violation, okay?
Now, after you ran
the red light,
the street camera
didn't pick you up
at the next intersection.
Where'd you go?
Okay, look, I, I cannot have
my license suspended.
I have a vending machine
business.
You're not here
for a traffic violation.
Let's get that straight.
Now, did you see anyone
in particular?
You remember that night?
Yeah, yeah, no. Um, yeah,
there was, there was a guy
who walked past my car.
Okay.
I thought I was gonna get robbed
on top of everything else.
Can you identify
him, hmm?
Sure, yeah.
He walked under a streetlight.
I saw him. I saw him real clear.
He, um...
He was Hispanic, uh, I don't
know, bald, scary-looking.
"LAT" carved into the cheek
of the victim
is the signature
of El Matocho,
La Tijera's number one.
He killed this guy--
Little Gordo,
but he was a ghost;
no face, no name.
Until Don Cook ID'd
Emilio Alvarado
coming out
of Little Gordo's house
around the time of the murder.
Turns out Alvarado
was caught up
in a gang sweep
day after the murder.
Parole violation.
He got 30 days.
PD thought
he was just another lowlife.
Due to be released in 52 hours.
Can't indict Alvarado
with a dead witness.
We need to prove conspiracy.
You need to prove that Alvarado
ordered a hit on your witness.
How long do you think
it'll take you
to bone up on these
and put a suit on?
Can I smoke in here?
Uh, no.
It's a... it's a
government building.
I'm very sorry
for your loss.
So when was the last time
you saw Don?
Last night.
We go to my folks' house
every Sunday.
Mrs. Cook, did you know
that your husband was going
to testify before a grand jury?
We talked about it.
I told him
I didn't want him to do it.
But he found out about this
girl, what the gang did to her.
Did he confide in anyone else?
He said it was a secret.
Did you tell anyone?
No.
Well... sort of.
I told my mom and dad
and my best friend Jenny.
She's my hairdresser.
I tell her everything.
I'm gonna need
their phone numbers.
Did I do something wrong?
(camera shutter clicking)
Oh, hey, Dave,
nice haircut.
What gives?
Oh, Mrs. Phillips.
An extreme makeover.
Mm. Oh, make sure you get
those photos to Grissom.
I'm all over it.
Sign of a good marriage.
Wife still wants to change him.
So your vic's burns are
concentrated on the face, hands,
knees and feet.
It's consistent
with an engine fire.
(man screams)
Jacketed hollowpoint.
One cannelure.
Looks like a .38.
Yeah.
Entered through
the right renal artery.
That's COD.
(grunts)
(coughs)
(groans)
Wow. I bet it
reeks in here.
I wouldn't know.
Thank God for stuffy noses.
Yeah.
DA Klein asked Grissom,
who asked Catherine,
who told me to tell you that
we need to figure out
if the victim was shot
before he got in the car,
while he was in the car
or after he got out.
Okay, uh, there was
no blood trail at the scene.
Fire pretty much
took care of that.
And I doubt you're gonna find
any trace of blood
in that burnt-up driver seat.
Wow, I've got to give her
more than that.
Be my guest.
(coughs)
(sneezes)
Skin on a seat belt buckle.
You know,
if I got shot
and I'm trying to get away,
I'm not gonna take the time
to put my seat belt on.
Eliminates the first scenario.
So either the shooter
kidnaps him and shot him
while he was driving...
I don't know.
Greg, I think
we would have found evidence
of somebody else
inside the vehicle.
Which leaves us
with the last scenario.
(gunshot)
I think I just found my reason
for getting out of bed
this morning.
Check it out.
The same guy that
tampered with the car
could have followed.
Made sure the job was done.
Who killed him?
Do you have evidence
that the witness
was murdered?
How did they kill him?
One at a time, Miss Leahy.
Do you know who killed him?
We don't know yet.
Our investigation
is still ongoing.
What was the guy gonna tell us?
Until Dr. Grissom can
corroborate Mr. Cook's
testimony,
I can't tell you
the content.
Mr. O'Shea.
We've been locked up in here
ten hours a day,
two months,
all cloak-and-dagger.
La Tijera doesn't know
we're investigating them,
so they couldn't know
about the witness.
Well, we found their signature
at the crime scene.
So it's possible
they do know.
If they got to this witness,
could they get to us?
I have a family.
So do I.
I want to know how the gang
found out about Don Cook.
O'SHEA:
Me, too.
Or else I want
off this jury.
Hey, I, uh, brought
some more files on the case.
Got any coffee?
I got lots of tea.
Good.
You know, when we first
asked Cook to testify
he said no,
and, uh, but...
you know, I couldn't let it go.
So I called him up
about a week later
and, uh, took him to lunch
and I showed him a picture
of, uh... of a girl
that they had killed, you know.
She was 16, innocent, beautiful.
She was raped, shot,
and urinated on.
And when that
didn't kill her,
they slit her throat.
So I had him on the hook.
When I told him that,
uh, you know, if he testified,
I'd protect him and his family
if the case ever came to trial.
On Friday, he called Maddy,
said he changed his mind,
he'd testify.
And on Sunday...
he was dead.
I couldn't protect him.
Thanks.
(coughing)
(sneezes)
Hey, buddy.
Hey.
Oh, man,
you look beat up.
I feel beat up.
Why don't you, uh,
take a break. I got this.
No, no, I'm cool.
I can push through it.
Yeah.
(chuckles)
You're, uh, breaking
the Lab's budget
for rubber gloves
here, dawg.
Listen, get some rest, man.
You'd do the same for me.
Yeah, okay.
I processed the driver's side.
I was about to get to the
passenger's side glove box.
I owe you one, man.
Yeah, you do.
(sneezes)
Ooh.
(rattling)
♪ ♪
(knocking)
Mr. O'Malley?
Detective Jim Brass.
Can I talk to you?
Sure.
Ballistics has confirmed
that your son-in-law
was killed with your gun.
Wait a minute.
You told me this morning
he died in a car fire.
I know what I told you,
but why didn't you
tell me about the gun?
How did it end up in his car?
Go inside.
I gave it to him.
Why?
Because he asked me for it.
All right, look,
it's got five rounds in it.
There's no safety on it.
So all I got to do
is just point it and shoot it?
Yeah. Now look, if you think
you're being followed,
don't be a hero.
Call the police.
Hey, look, I begged Donnie
not to testify.
He and Cody had
everything to lose.
They were doing great with
their vending machines.
No grandkids yet,
but that's probably
'cause their marriage
was shaky already.
Cody has her
mother's temper.
She loved him though.
We all did.
Look, as long as I'm
out here, do you mind
if I look around?
My wife and daughter
are pretty upset.
I don't want you guys in here
bothering them anymore.
♪ ♪
GRISSOM:
CSI Sanders
confirmed that the trajectory
of the gun lined up
with the victim's body as he
tried to exit the vehicle.
The engine fire would have
reached approximately
800 degrees within two minutes.
Enough heat was transmitted
to the glove box
to cause the gun inside
to discharge.
Witness was killed
by his own gun.
Do you know who set the fire?
No, Your Honor, not yet.
KLEIN:
CSI found La Tijera's tag
painted on the car's
rear bumper.
You can't charge the
entire gang, counsel.
Alvarado's set to be
released in just
over 24 hours.
If he gets out...
we lose him forever.
We need a warrant
to search his apartment.
I can't give you
a warrant just because
she doesn't want him
to get out of jail.
Where's your
probable cause?
You saw the video.
Cook placed Alvarado
at the house
at the time of the murder.
Mere presence.
Counsel, I got to get
back to my trial.
Your Honor, Alvarado is
an admitted member of La Tijera.
Their initials were carved
into the cheek
of the murder victim
in the house that
Alvarado was seen exiting.
We need the clothes that
Alvarado was wearing that night.
Hopefully, he didn't have time
to do his laundry.
The grand jurors
are on board with this?
They will be, Your Honor.
Hey, Griss.
Restocked your case.
You were low
on batteries and pheno.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Apartment 5967.
GRISSOM:
Alvarado's crib.
Hey, Grissom, I got tickets
to the Rebels tomorrow night.
If you're feeling any better
and you want to check it out.
I'll be in bed.
(explosion)
(car alarm blares)
GRISSOM:
You feeling okay?
Yeah. My ears are
still ringing, though.
This place reeks
of sulfur.
(camera shutter clicks)
I found about
ten of these butane cans so far.
Any evidence that's here
is gone.
(camera shutter clicking)
Yeah, well,
there's burn patterns
all over these walls.
They must have splashed butane
all over everything.
And butane dissipates quick.
The other guy was probably
watching us the whole time.
There's nails
all over the place.
Grissom, I think I found
the point of origin.
(camera shutter clicking)
Green plastic.
Sugar, butane,
and nails.
Add some
egg whites in a soda bottle.
You got a MacGyver bomb.
Crude, but it works.
I think they were looking to do
more than just destroy evidence.
You running for
warrants, Mitch?
Yeah.
Impound their cars.
You got it.
Mitch, I want to see
this guy's hands.
You ain't a cop, fool.
He's bigger than a cop.
Show him your hands, princess.
They're clean.
Want to lick 'em
and find out?
You think
this is a game?
Huh?
This one's clean.
What about this one?
Clean.
Turn his pockets.
Sugar.
What's this?
You been baking cookies?
BRASS:
So, who gave you the order
to torch that apartment?
I don't know what
you're talkin' about.
And why that
apartment?
Who do you know lives there?
Nobody.
I got a mental illness.
I'm a firebug.
I'm loco.
You're loco?
Who knows?
Maybe I'll set the lawyer
lady's house on fire.
Hey, little man
with the big mouth.
It doesn't matter
what you say,
'cause all your boys
are going to hear
is that you rolled on Alvarado.
Just bought yourself
another ten years.
I'm going to hand-pick
your cell mate.
Well, that didn't help.
That kid wouldn't roll
if I gave him a night
with Jessica Alba.
You're pretty good
at making enemies, Maddy.
That's why I'm unlisted,
divorced and carry a gun.
Did you take Cook back
to Little Gordo's house?
You know, maybe
to verify his story?
Yeah, I always take
my secret witnesses
on a bus tour
of the "hood."
You know, when Don Cook
first refused to testify
that he saw Alvarado come
out of Little Gordo's house,
you know what I did?
I took him to an
out-of-town diner
and bought him
a cup of coffee.
What'd you do?
I went to Little Gordo's.
Damn it.
Good job, Maddy.
They saw me.
I can't even blame it
on the booze.
All they had to do was trail me
back to the courthouse
and watch me go
into the security entrance
with 18 escorted jurors.
That's how they knew grand jury.
Damn it!
(sighs)
This is where you're
supposed to say,
"It's okay. It could
happen to anyone.
It's not your fault
Don Cook is dead."
Like hell it isn't.
(coughing)
Hey, Nick!
You've got an artful tagger.
What?
Don Cook's car bumper.
Gangbanger blended his green
with another color.
Not visible to
the human eye.
Of course,
I caught it.
You mean
the GCMS caught it?
Well, if that's a hair
you want to split.
Suspect used green paint
with a hint of cerulean blue.
Probably for impact.
(coughs)
(clearing throat)
You know, in China
people wear masks
when they're sick.
It's considered impolite
to infect your coworkers.
Maybe you should go
work in China.
Maybe you should wear a mask.
Now, this is everything
Alvarado had
and was wearing
when they arrested him?
Thank you.
GUARD:
He's been in isolation
for two weeks.
I could tell you everything
he's got in his cell.
They assigned
me special.
Does he get
any yard time?
Nope.
I take him
for hall walks.
Not allowed any contact
with anybody but me.
Why do you need to see him?
Just want to rattle
his cage a bit.
That cool
with you?
Good luck.
Hey, Alvarado,
get up.
Cell check.
(camera shutter clicking)
So, you always clean your boots
with bleach, El Matocho?
(laughs)
Something funny?
Matocho.
Nonsense word.
You know where
this name comes from?
There's a legend
in Central America.
This man,
he woke up in a bad mood.
Killed eight members
of his family with a machete
and then went and had breakfast.
Matar.
To kill.
Ocho. Eight.
"To kill eight."
El Matocho.
(laughs)
(chuckles)
That's great.
The way I see it, you're going
to have lots of time
to tell all kinds
of great stories.
Tick-tock.
Tick-tock. Tick-tock.
SANDERS:
Alvarado is a suspect
in three cases.
First, he allegedly
kills
Little Gordo.
Then,
the only witness who could
identify him is killed.
And last, but certainly
not least,
he allegedly
orders Raphael Gomez
to blow up
his apartment.
La Tijera
is responsible
for all three crimes.
Tags at both scenes,
and Gomez is an admitted
member of the gang.
According to Hodges,
the tagger didn't
use spray paint.
He used an oil-based
specialty paint.
Well, that doesn't
make any sense.
You got photos?
(coughing)
Here you go.
This "L" looks
like it was stenciled.
Then, it looks
like the tagger
painted over it
a second time,
to make it look freehand.
What?
Yeah, those, uh...
those do look
like brush strokes.
Well, gangs don't
use paintbrushes.
I assumed the tags
were authentic.
We've been moving in
the wrong direction.
Cody, come on out here.
So, you think this gang
messed with Don's car
while we were
having dinner?
That's what we're
here to find out.
Cody, Mr. Brass wants
to talk to you.
Hi, Cody.
Where was your son-in-law's
car parked that night?
Right over there.
Those are nice.
Did you make those?
Yeah, a hobby of mine
after I lost my job.
Forced retirement.
You know
how it goes.
Mmm.
Want to buy one?
(chuckles)
You keep the garage door closed
when you're not working?
Well, it's not like
we have any neighbors.
Anything ever gone missing?
Sure, Cody's taking stuff
all the time.
She'd rather spend
her money on clothes.
Kids.
Mind if I take this crate?
What for?
Fingerprints.
Well, you're going
to find mine all over.
That's why I'm going
to get yours, too, sir.
So I can exclude you.
Follow me.
BRASS:
So, let me get this
straight.
You come to your parents'
house for dinner
and Don's the only
one that leaves.
I already told you
why I wasn't in that car.
My husband and I
were arguing.
He was yelling at me.
Okay, I'm having a hard time
keeping it straight.
You do like my dress?
You don't like my dress?
Can we please just not talk
about this now?
When should we talk
about it?
Cody, get
in the car.
No, I'm not going
to get in the car.
Listen. I loved the dress till
I found out it cost 300 bucks.
You have a closet full
of dresses...
Get in the car.
No. Not until you apologize.
Apologize to my parents!
I'm not apologizing.
CODY:
I told him not to call me
until the court thing was over.
I needed to cool off.
My dad says I was lucky.
Ma'am,
I'm going to need to get
your fingerprints, too.
I don't like
where this is going.
It's going downtown.
So you killed him.
And made it look
like a gang did it.
And then you could buy all
the expensive dresses you want.
I loved my husband.
I didn't kill him, okay?
You don't know me.
You don't know my life.
STOKES:
I found your fingerprints
on a stencil.
It was the one
with green paint all over it.
And the paint from one
of your paintbrushes
is a match to the car.
Your daughter said
you disappeared
into the garage
right after dinner.
That's when you stuck the rag
in the engine
between the catalytic converter
and the heat shield.
I think we all know
what that did. Hmm?
Hey, you don't want to say
anything, fine.
Write him up.
Process him.
STOKES:
You think the daughter
had anything to do with it?
No.
CODY:
How could you?!
Cook was her
meal ticket.
You son of a bitch!
You were gonna kill
your own daughter?!
Over money so you
could get our business?!
O'MALLEY:
I would never let you
get in that car!
Well, you didn't try to stop me!
You just stood there!
How many Sundays did you come
over and bitch to your mother
about that selfish,
ungrateful bastard?!
Don wanted to give you
the money; I said no!
And all those nights Mom
and I stayed up talking--
it was about you!
You owed me!
I hate you!
I did you a favor!
(knocking)
Never thought
I'd be disappointed
that we solved a case.
Hmm.
Court personnel files?
Reading upside down is a talent.
What are you looking for?
The leak.
90 minutes
after the warrant was issued,
Alvarado's apartment went up.
So you're looking at the judge,
his staff,
the clerk that issued
the warrant,
court reporter,
any cops who knew...
Yeah, but according to this,
everybody cleared.
The only ones left
are the grand jurors...
and Maddy Klein.
Thanks for coming in, Arch.
I appreciate it.
All right. No worries.
Wasn't sleeping anyway.
Big surf movie marathon
on cable right now.
Ah.
Yeah, Big Wednesday,
Endless Summer,
Local Boys.
Dude.
Yeah.
So we need to review
some phone records, and fast.
Okay. It's going to be tough
to go fast with that many names.
Oh, no.
I can narrow it down.
It's a 90-minute window,
yesterday,
at 12:00 noon to 1:30.
Just cell phone calls.
Okay.
Give me a name and a number.
Timothy O'Shea. 702...
He called two numbers.
Do a reverse lookup.
Looks like he called his wife
and his home line.
Next.
Cole Zampas...
702-555-014...
Jessica Varge...
Darby Vance,
555-013...
Marie Leahy.
Okay.
Huh. No user information.
It usually means
disposable cell phone.
Has she called
the number before,
within the last two weeks?
Monday through Friday,
both weeks,
she called a different
disposable cell phone.
That's weird.
Okay. Try the text messages.
Yeah.
(computer beeping)
See the pattern?
Every night
around 11:00 p.m.,
someone texts her a number,
which she then calls
the next day.
GRISSOM:
How did they contact you,
Miss Leahy?
Uh... a few weeks ago,
at a gas station near my house,
this, uh...
this woman comes up to me
and, uh...
she knows everything
about Peter.
That's my little brother
in Chicago.
He's only 19.
Got ten years
for something he didn't do.
And she said they'd get him out.
And they did.
Guy just confessed
and my brother's set to go free.
Did that witness die
because of me?
Can you give us a description
of the woman?
She was white,
uh, short brown hair...
I'm sorry.
I only seen her once.
BROWN:
Alvarado gets out
in the morning.
It is the morning.
Exactly.
(slams table)
(sighs)
You know, none of these
people make a move
without a direct order
from Alvarado,
especially not torching
his own place.
What are you saying?
Well, think about it.
When Marie leaked
the warrant information,
it had to have gone in and out
through him somehow.
He's the boss.
I don't see how; the guy's
in complete isolation.
They even assigned him
a special hand-picked guard.
Look.
There's no privileges
in isolation.
Things still move
in and out of his cell:
laundry, food.
The only thing I saw
from the outside was a book.
They say he's a big reader.
But I looked it over;
there's nothing.
What about all the other books
he's been reading?
How does Alvarado
get his books?
It's like a regular library.
When a book's checked out,
a trustee writes down
the inmate's name,
booking number and date.
Gets checked back in
the same way.
I need to see every book
that Alvarado checked out.
GUARD:
What Is the What?
The Infinite Plan,
and Herzog.
Oh... and The Inferno.
Alphabetical by author?
Mm-hmm.
David Eggers.
There's pages missing.
Allende.
How many books has he read
in the last 48 hours?
Two.
He said he didn't like this one;
returned it
yesterday afternoon.
Where's The Inferno?
(metallic clanking)
GUARD:
Hold up a minute.
GUARD 2:
Orders to process him out.
Just hold him.
GRISSOM:
This is a good book,
Mr. Alvarado.
Which Circle of Hell
would you be in?
The Seventh, the outer one.
Those who commit violence
against others.
Souls plunge into a river
of boiling blood.
(sniffs)
Officer, do you have a lighter?
No pen, no paper...
so you used what you had, huh?
A book for paper,
and for ink, urine.
Once the urine dries,
the writing becomes
invisible....
until it's heated,
making the acid in the urine
turn brown.
Then you, uh, put the book
back in the library,
another prisoner checks it out,
tears out the page,
gives it to a visitor,
and you get your message out.
Yes?
Put him back
in his house.
Mira, usted se va a morir.
(door clanking shut)
(sighs)
Well, I was right
about Alvarado:
he was leaving Vegas.
Otherwise, he would have
killed me himself.
You okay?
Yeah.
Guess now,
I owe you one, huh?
I don't keep score,
Madeleine.
You know what, Gilbert?
You're the only man I know
who's never let me down.
Which means that you're either
a classic enabler
or my soul mate.
(sighs)
(phone rings)
Hi.