(party music playing)
Drink! Drink! Drink! Drink!
Drink! Drink! Drink!
Yeah!
Drink!
Drink! Drink! Drink!
Drink! Drink! Drink! Drink...!
(woman moaning ecstatically
(moaning and grunting)
(laughs)
(sighs)
(moaning grows louder)
(laughing)
(man laughs)
(both panting)
(woman moans)
(man sighs contentedly)
(camera shutter clicking)
(garbled police radio chatter)
(crowd clamoring)
(camera shutter clicking)
Sorry, no ID.
It's okay. Brass
has a line on the
resident director.
WOMAN:
Lanie!
Oh, my God, no!
My God, Lanie, I can't
believe it. You really did it.
Hey! Let her on through.
Monica!
Lanie!
Don't you ever
die on me! Promise!
I won't.
I promise.
(garbled police radio chatter)
It's the third jumper
on campus this year.
Maybe it's contagious.
I saw this documentary once
on suicides
off the Golden Gate Bridge,
and they
interviewed
a survivor
and he said the moment
that he let go of the railing,
he realized that all of
his problems were fixable,
except for
having jumped.
(rattling handlebar)
Hey, Catherine.
(radio beeps)
Uh, yeah, Nicky,
what you got?
Chains and padlocks.
There's no roof access
from the dorm.
Well, the body landed
close to the building,
so if she didn't
come from the roof,
she must have come
out of a room.
Okay, I'll work my way down.
BRASS (over radio):
Nick, you in the dorm?
That's affirmative.
I'm with the
resident director.
He's ID'd the victim
as Kira Dellinger.
She's in Room 807.
She's a freshman
from McLean, Virginia.
I guess I'm going to go
notify the parents.
STOKES:
Perks of the job.
Yeah.
(garbled police radio chatter)
Hey, Catherine, do you see
any wounds on the body
inconsistent with the fall?
Hang on.
I did find this.
Yeah, there's a
long perimortem abrasion
on the lower back.
I think I know
how it got there.
(screaming)
(yelling frantically):
No!
Drag 'n' drop.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
♪ ♪
BROWN:
Oh, ooh!
Oh...
Ooh, where's the fire?
Oh, sorry.
(sighs)
Ah.
"Zopidem"?
That's good stuff.
Yeah, it's to help me sleep.
I've been having
the hardest time lately.
Me, too.
Well, just coming off of grave
after all these years,
you know, takes
a while to adjust.
You're a tough cookie.
I'm not worried about you.
Take care of yourself, huh?
Thanks.
Yeah.
Sweet dreams.
Thanks.
Oh...
LAKE:
Hey.
Sara, you done with your scene?
Yeah.
Great, because
we just caught another one.
425 off Craig Road.
Busy shift, but you
know I like that.
I'll see you outside, okay?
Okay.
OFFICER:
Neighbors called in
a domestic disturbance
between Adam
and Kim Jimenez.
I responded, knocked
and didn't get any answer,
so I looked
through the window,
and this is
what I saw.
Nobody's home, so
I called you guys.
Blood but no body.
No sign of the couple.
OFFICER:
No.
Nothing.
SIDLE:
Lots of blood activity here.
LAKE:
Then someone ran out the door.
Stop right there.
Hands where I can see 'em.
This is my house.
Mrs. Jimenez?
Where have you been?
My husband and I
had an argument.
I went on a walk.
Where's your husband now?
I, uh...
I don't know.
Mr. Jimenez,
are you okay?
Bad back.
LAKE:
Sara,
she's got a very bad back.
This is CSI Lake.
We need paramedics
right away on location.
(camera shutter clicking)
Hey.
What do you think this might be?
Well, possibly a tooth fragment.
High fall?
Yeah.
We think she was pushed.
So, between her knuckles--
suggests a struggle.
No!
(blow lands)
(groans)
Ah!
(screaming)
Was she raped?
There's no trauma,
but the wet mount indicates
that she definitely had sex.
Oh, no condom. Good for us.
Yeah.
Such a scary thing,
sending your kid off to college.
Is Lindsey looking already?
Yeah.
In fact, we looked at WLVU
last month.
Well, at least
she'd be close to home.
She's free on campus,
might as well be
a thousand miles away.
(soft trilling, beeping)
Hey.
Any luck with dorm security?
Nope.
There's no cameras,
only key cards,
but according
to the residence director,
the door's propped open
all the time anyway.
Okay.
(computer beeps and trills)
SANDERS:
Kind of hard to tell
the difference
between a struggle
and a typical
college dorm room.
Yeah. You should
have seen mine.
It was really bad.
Hmm. "X" marks the girl.
Symbol for a "straight edge"
lifestyle.
Abstinence from drugs,
tobacco,
alcohol...
...but not sex.
Sexual lubricant.
Give me that.
So, pretty brave
for college.
Yeah, or just another way
to get attention.
Looks like our vic
was in a Goth band.
You know, I used to be Goth.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah, the Goth thing
was just an act.
Chicks dug it.
How does that work?
You act depressed to get chicks,
you get depressed chicks.
(chuckles)
(door opening)
Baby, are you okay?
Are you all right?
You doing okay, huh?
You all right?
You okay? Yeah?
Did you call
these cops on me?
(weakly):
No...
Did you call
the cops on me?!
(shouting)
I didn't call the cops!
(shouting becomes
slow, distorted)
(distorted, indistinct
yelling continues)
It's okay now.
Sara?
Why don't you
finish up here?
Wait a minute.
How are we going
to handle this?
Well, the guy's
under arrest.
He'll be free
by tomorrow.
Her husband is obviously
abusing her.
(sighs)
There's got to be something
we can do.
We'll be back
for her body next month.
Or his. Or both.
There is nothing
you can do about this, Ronnie.
Don't kid yourself.
♪ ♪
Sara, I've got
something really good
on that defenestrated
college kid.
Oh, that's
Catherine's case.
Or, you know what,
talk to Nick.
No, no, no, you're really
going to love this.
A print on a lube tube matched
a print on her windowsill.
AFIS got a hit.
Ever think you'd
see that guy again?
STOKES:
Marlon West was on trial for
the murder of Stacy Vollmer.
He confessed.
It was later thrown out
on a technicality.
We really didn't need it.
The prosecution's case against
Marlon was very strong.
Until Marlon's
little sister Hannah
got on the stand and confessed
to the murder herself.
Marlon didn't kill Stacy.
I did.
And I was wearing this
when I did it.
Oh, yes, I remember this case.
A high school senior
at age 12.
She's a prodigy.
She's a pint-size
Machiavelli.
She manipulated events,
fabricated evidence,
and in the end...
We, the jury, find the
defendant, Marlon West
not guilty.
STOKES:
...snowed the jury.
SIDLE:
And me.
Hannah, you are smart.
But you have to be really smart
to make people think
things happened that never did.
What do you mean exactly?
I didn't kill Stacy.
Marlon did.
She claimed that she did it
because she
loved Marlon.
Some warped
sense of justice...
She graduated
later that summer,
became legally emancipated
from her parents
and went off to Harvard.
Pre-med.
You keeping tabs on her?
Not recently.
Look, accident or no accident,
Marlon killed before.
Hannah sunk this case;
Marlon got a free pass;
and now he's killed again.
Well, we don't
know that just yet.
I mean, we don't have
Marlon's DNA
to compare with the semen
that was found in the victim.
All the old evidence was
expunged with the verdict.
I want this case.
The one that got away?
We're not supposed to let them
get away, right?
GRISSOM:
Okay.
I'll see if I can clear it
with Ecklie.
Catherine has to
supervise, though.
You report to her.
(indistinct conversations)
Hello, Marlon.
What are you guys doing here?
We here to talk to you
about Kira Dellinger.
Kira committed suicide.
Actually, she was murdered.
Somebody I know ends up dead
and I'm automatically
a suspect?
History has a way
of repeating itself, Marlon.
You've killed before, you know?
That was an accident.
And I admitted I was responsible
from day one.
Kira was forced out
her dorm window.
Your prints were there.
My prints were there
because I've been in there
a million times.
Kira and I were in a band.
Your prints were
also found on a tube
of sexual lubricant.
Were you having
sex with her, Marlon?
Yeah, we were having sex.
Last night?
No, we had a gig last night.
We... We got into a fight.
Did she give you
that fat lip?
No, not exactly.
Kira! Kira!
Keep your hands off her!
I'm done!
From now on, you stay
away from me, psycho!
I don't know who the guy was.
I had never seen him before.
After that, I just...
wandered the campus
most of the night by myself.
So you don't have an alibi.
I guess I don't.
Well, I'll tell you what.
We will give you
the benefit of the doubt
in exchange for this.
You remember this.
I assume you have
a DNA warrant, Sara.
Because if you don't,
you certainly
don't have his consent.
Isn't that right, Marlon?
Hannah, I heard
you were
studying back east--
what are you doing here?
Graduate school.
Excuse me.
You are not going to muddy
the waters this time.
Are you sure
you'd know if I had?
You're welcome to stay.
You might learn something.
Please turn to page 187,
the Clausius-
Clapeyron equation.
Oh, by the way, Professor Costin
said it'll be on the exam.
BRASS:
I don't know, Sara.
It's going to be tough
to get a warrant.
I need Marlon West's DNA.
If his semen
is in Kira Dellinger,
it puts him at the murder.
Look, they had a known
sexual relationship,
so there's no
evidence of rape.
And I don't know
if you know this,
but Marlon's mother
and father
were killed in a car
accident last year.
Judge Bowman is going to be
very sensitive to that.
It could look
like harassment.
Jim, are you going to talk
to the judge or not?
Wow, you really
got it out for this kid.
What's the deal here, Sara?
Marlon West has killed before.
Not according
to a jury of his peers.
Did you have fun talking
to Kira Dellinger's parents?
Excuse me?
Must've been a lot of screaming
and crying and despair.
Yeah, there usually is.
What's your point, Sara?
My point is, if we had done
our job right the first time,
Marlon West would be in jail,
and Kira Dellinger
would still be alive.
Talk to the judge.
ANDREWS:
HPLC found high levels
of gamma-hydroxybutyric acid
in Kira Dellinger's blood.
GHB does occur
naturally in the body.
You sure she
was drugged?
Pretty sure.
Started to metabolize in her
blood and urine when she died.
That typically
indicates dosing.
Okay, so then maybe she was
roofied, raped, then murdered.
And no vaginal trauma because
she was too numb to resist.
It's possible.
You know, some people
take GHB recreationally.
I didn't find any drug
paraphernalia in her room.
It was pretty consistent with
a "straight edge" lifestyle.
You know, that just
sounds like something
a girl tells her parents in
order to make them feel better.
I mean, we know she had sex.
There was GHB in her system...
I think you just need to test
everything in her room
that she may have ingested.
(sighs):
Okay.
JOHNSON:
So this is her Twitter page.
Got e-mails, IMs,
text messages.
A minute-by-minute diary
of Kira Dellinger's life.
With the last post a couple
hours before she died.
What made you think
to check her Twitter page?
Well, most date rape victims
know their assailants,
and Kira was an active blogger,
so I figured
if she was having trouble
with anyone,
she'd probably
talk about it online.
Some people just
don't value privacy.
They don't expect privacy.
They value openness.
Whatever.
(typing)
Hmm.
"It shouldn't suck when two boys
fight over you, but it does.
"Drummerboy19 won't be a man.
"And TorchX wants
what he can't have.
They both bug."
Looks like a virtual
love triangle to me.
My guess is
DrummerBoy19 is Marlon.
Well, TorchX responded to that.
"KiraEdge, you know
I never give up."
That could be a threat.
Let's see
if this "TorchX"
has a real name.
(typing)
Jordan Rockwell.
I guess he values
openness, too.
BRASS:
Mr. Rockwell,
do you know this girl?
Yeah, sure.
It's Kira Dellinger.
When was the last
time you saw her?
Uh... last night.
Hmm. Where?
At her place.
We had sex.
Nice. How did that happen?
We used to date
in high school.
Then we reconnected
online, and, uh...
I came down to the campus
to check out her band.
So she gave you a roll
for old times' sake.
Well, I, uh...
I kind of helped her out
with a boyfriend problem.
Is this the problem?
Yeah.
Yeah, that's the guy.
He was, uh...
he was into her,
you know, but she...
she was not into him.
And he started
giving her static,
so... I knocked the little
douche's teeth out.
I guess she
kind of liked it,
because she took me
back to her place after that.
Then what?
I want to know everything
up until the time
when you wrapped your car
around that telephone pole.
She fell asleep...
and then I started feeling sick,
so I, uh, got my car
to drive home.
Then I got
really dizzy
and, uh... wham.
That's it.
So she was alive
the last time you saw her.
Wh-What do you mean,
"she was alive"?
She's dead.
SANDERS:
According to Brass,
officers at the crash scene
suspected that Jordan Rockwell
was under the influence,
so the hospital
ran a tox panel.
Positive for GHB.
Really?
So this guy roofies
himself along with Kira?
Did they share a drink?
Well, if they did,
it wasn't in anything
we tested.
Hodges ran all the water
bottles and soda cans
we collected
from the room--
no GHB in anything.
Wait a minute.
I think I know
what they shared.
Kira and Jordan had
unprotected sex, right?
SIDLE:
Yes.
That means...
they both came in contact...
with this.
HODGES:
Kudos to you.
The lube was indeed
laced with GHB.
Not hard to do if you
know a little chemistry.
Marlon takes chemistry.
Hannah teaches it.
We know Marlon's fingerprints
are on the lube tube.
We know he was jealous.
Maybe the GHB-lube was his way
of getting back at her.
You know? Give a drug-free girl
a bad trip.
Which became a
really bad trip.
STOKES:
Yeah.
But still, that doesn't
conclusively put anybody
at the crime scene.
There's one thing
we have that does.
We can get a warrant for this.
(sighs):
I'm telling you,
I didn't kill Kira.
I've never lied to you.
Not once.
You just never believe me.
When I'm guilty,
you want me to be innocent.
When I'm innocent,
you want me to be guilty.
Hey, you know
what, Marlon?
You can save it.
'Cause unlike most people,
you're not going to get me
to underestimate you.
I already know you're every bit
as smart as your sister,
especially when it comes
to creating confusion.
Open up.
Bite down.
Let it sit.
He didn't kill Kira.
He cared about her.
Hannah, what
makes you think
that I would believe anything
that you tell me?
I suppose I'm an optimist.
College has been a difficult
adjustment for Marlon,
especially after
we lost our parents.
I'm sorry about that.
You're not really, though.
When will Marlon
be able to leave?
Well, we're going to keep him
here as long as we possibly can.
At least that's honest.
It also seems
a little vindictive.
Given your brother's history,
I think it's pretty sensible.
What's wrong, Sara?
You're different
than you used to be.
You're angry.
And a little sad, too.
Why?
If you want to spend more time
with your brother,
I recommend you invest
in a good lawyer, Hannah.
(monitor beeping)
It's a physical match.
Puts Marlon
at the scene.
That's probably not enough
to put him in jail.
I think I might be able
to help you out there.
I found a Friend Agenda page
for Kira and Marlon's band,
The Death Crusade.
Seems like a lot of pictures
for a college band.
Well, TDC, as
they're called,
has quite a solid
fan base on campus.
SIDLE:
Hannah was there.
SANDERS:
Yeah. Marlon must've
been thrilled.
What guy would like
having his little sister around
to watch
as he gets his ass kicked
in front of his girlfriend?
(camera shutter clicking)
From now on, just stay
away from me, psycho!
(hard rock playing)
Marlon, Marlon,
it's okay.
Kira, don't do this to me!
So this new guy
pops Marlon in the mouth,
chips his tooth.
Marlon's humiliated,
decides to take it out on Kira.
Kills her, then tries to make it
look like a suicide,
and in the midst
of their struggle,
his tooth fragment
ends up in her fist?
What are you looking for now?
I'm not sure.
♪ ♪
What are you doing?
I'm just, uh, taking a closer
look at Marlon's chipped tooth.
Look at the orientation
of the fragment in the mouth.
And now look at the way
the tooth ended up
in Kira's right fist.
Looks like it's backwards.
I don't think
Kira punched Marlon.
I think Hannah picked up
the tooth from a fight
that Marlon had earlier
in the evening.
And I think
she planted it on Kira.
That's crazy.
It's possible.
This kid is spinning me
in circles again.
You know, Sara, some cases,
some suspects
can get under your skin.
Like this tooth.
But you can't let it
make you feel bad.
If you want,
we can put Nick on this.
No. No, I, um...
I need to finish this case.
I'll be okay.
Okay.
What is that
in your hand?
I think it was
a gum wrapper.
It's wrong to litter.
It's a piece of a tooth.
The one that Kira Dellinger's
new boy-toy
knocked out of
Marlon's head.
You had already spiked
Kira's lube with GHB.
All you had to do was wait.
A piece of his tooth
in her fist.
A little bit of leverage.
And your brother's
a killer again.
That's a highly unlikely series
of events.
You don't expect me to confess
to something I didn't do?
I am just putting you on notice.
You are not fooling me anymore.
I think I know
why you're so angry, Sara.
I did some research.
I read about what
that serial killer did to you
out in the desert,
under that car...
We're talking about you, Hannah.
It must've been so terrible
being trapped like that
all alone.
Did your life flash
in front of your eyes?
That is none of your business.
You must've been so sad
knowing that you were
gonna lose everyone
who mattered
to you.
Stop it, Hannah.
Look, I know how it feels.
One moment
my parents were alive,
and the next
they were gone.
Answer the question!
My life changed in that moment.
All that I have left is Marlon.
Why would I do
anything to hurt him?
(bangs table)
Stop playing games with me.
You're the one
who's playing games.
Hey.
What are you doing here?
I was going to ask you
the same question.
Listen, I'm worried
about you.
That just makes this worse.
I-I can't talk about
this right now. I can't.
(Ronnie speaking
indistinctly)
Just stay in touch, okay?
What happened? Her husband
attack her again?
No. She came in
voluntarily.
It took some convincing, but
she's agreed to go to a shelter.
She won't stay.
Maybe not.
But at least now
she has a chance.
Look, I did it all
on my own time, no OT.
I know it's not the way
you do things,
but I think it's
part of the job.
At least, that's how
I want it to be. For me.
Why would Hannah
want to frame me?
I don't know, Marlon.
She's your sister.
Hannah's always
been kinda weird.
But since the trial...
and after our parents died,
she's started
getting really weird.
Like how?
Really clingy, I guess.
Always wanting to hang
around with me.
And that changed
when you met Kira?
Yeah.
But not for Hannah.
Get out of here,
you little freak!
Aren't you gonna
get her out of here?!
Oh, I hope you two are really
happy together. Freaks!
MARLON:
After that, Kira said
she was done with me.
Marlon... don't be sad.
She doesn't deserve you.
You're right. She doesn't.
You want to help me
teach Kira a lesson?
I asked Hannah to teach me
how to make GHB,
and how to get
it into Kira.
I just wanted
to mess her up a bit.
I snuck it into Kira's room a
few days ago; I still had a key.
Hannah must've made a copy.
I believe you, Marlon.
I really do.
But the only thing
that a jury's going to see
is your prints on the lube,
your prints on the windowsill,
and another dead girl.
Why is Hannah
doing this to me?
I don't know.
All I know is...
you don't deserve
to take the fall for this.
And the question is...
are you going to let your sister
get away with this
and spend the rest
of your life in jail?
If Hannah wants me in jail,
that's where I'm going to be.
There's nothing
I can do about it.
There is one thing.
One foot away from the bars
at all times.
And no contact,
you understand?
Yeah, I understand.
(sighs)
Thanks for coming.
The police said
you needed me.
Yeah, I do.
I need to know...
what I did to deserve this.
You killed Kira.
We both know I didn't do that.
You look a little flushed,
Marlon.
Are you feeling all right?
No, I'm not feeling all right.
HANNAH (over speaker):
Kira always brought out
the worst in you.
Hannah, they're going to put me
away for the rest of my life.
The evidence is against you,
particularly given
your history of violence.
Please...
after everything
I've done for you,
after everything we've done
for each other,
at least tell me why.
Because I love you.
And I love you, too.
No.
You don't.
But you will.
I promise,
I'll visit you every week.
We're done.
(sighs):
Well, he gave it a shot,
but she is way out
of his league.
She's out of mine, too.
Hi.
Okay, what's up?
I'm sorry.
I've been, uh...
(cell phone ringing)
This is Sara.
I'll be right there.
Guard found him
about an hour ago.
Said he didn't
even make a sound.
You need to talk
to me again?
I do.
I know that you killed
Kira Dellinger.
I just can't prove it.
That must be
frustrating for you.
Hannah, Marlon's dead.
Wow.
That's a really sad
and desperate ploy, Sara.
It's beneath you.
He was doing well
here, wasn't he?
Making friends,
joining a band,
falling in love.
But you're still a freak,
just like high school.
You're lying.
No. This is a lie.
His world got bigger,
and yours stayed the same,
and you killed Kira
so you could keep him
all to yourself, didn't you?
It's a lie!
(sobbing):
No... it's a lie!
It's a lie!
This is a... lie!
Stop it!
(sobbing)
(sobbing):
Marlon...
he-he-he can't
leave me all alone.
♪ ♪
Judy, have you seen Sara?
She left a few minutes ago, sir,
but she did leave
something for you.
Thank you.
SARA:
Gil...
You know I love you.
I feel I've loved you forever.
Lately...
I haven't been feeling
very well.
Truth be told, I'm tired.
Out in the desert,
under that car that night,
I realized something, and I
haven't been able to shake it.
Since my father died,
I've spent almost
my entire life with ghosts.
We've been like close friends,
and out there in the desert,
it occurred to me that it was
time for me to bury them.
I can't do that here.
I'm so sorry.
No matter how hard
I try to fight it off,
I'm left with the feeling
that... I have to go.
I have no idea where I'm going,
but I know I have to do this.
If I don't, I'm afraid
I'll self-destruct,
and worse, you'll be there
to see it happen.
Be safe.
Know that I tried
very hard to stay.
Know that you are
my one and only.
I will miss you
with every beat of my heart.
Our life together was the only
home I've ever really had.
I wouldn't trade it
for anything.
I love you.
I always will.
Good-bye.