(laughter)
MAN: I would never
hit my kids.
'Cause, you know,
my father used to beat me.
Whatever. He didn't beat me
too much.
He beat me just right.
I remember the last time
he really slapped me around
just getting up off the ground
and thinking...
perfect.
He really nailed it,
you know just...
Any more would have been
barbaric.
And yet any less,
I wouldn't be seeking
the approval of you drunks.
So, thanks, Dad.
'Cause parenting is hard
and expense.
I just read the other day
if you were to have a baby today
and raise that kid all the way
through college,
it would cost you $1 million.
And that's why I feel like
no woman should ever walk out
of an abortion clinic with her
head hung down in shame.
You walk out and they're like
you just hit the lotto.
I'm a winner!
MAN:
You suck!
You think abortion's funny?
Hey, come on.
I don't think abortion's funny.
Especially the ones that try
too hard to get a laugh.
You know what I mean?
You'd know about that
wouldn't you?
Sir,
do you have kids?
That's none
of your damn business.
I'm trying to connect, sir.
I-I feel like we got off
on the wrong foot.
I hate to see that.
Let me make it up to you.
Let me baby-sit next week.
(audience laughs)
Come on.
Seriously. I love kids.
Did you hug your kid today?
Can I hug your kid?
Can I hug your kid, sir?
You touch my kids, I kill you.
Dude, it's a comedy show.
I'm kidding.
This is a joke.
(audience oohs)
What? What was that?
Oh, I see why you're so angry.
That's your wife.
Whoo!
Hey, baby.
The kids asleep?
How's Katie's stomach?
Do you need anything?
Okay, all right, I'll see you
in like 15 minutes.
(engine revving)
All right. Love you.
(tires squealing)
Hey man, you were great!
Thanks.
No, no,
I mean it, man.
I was laughing my ass off.
Anybody finds a size 54 ass,
I'll make sure we keep it
on ice for you.
(laughing):
He said 54...
(car alarm blaring)
(alarm chirps)
(sighs)
(garbled radio transmission)
I'll put up some screens.
Don't bother.
I'm going to take it
back intact.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
No rigor present.
TOD is probably less
than 12 hours ago.
Victim is a female child,
Caucasian,
approximately
three to four
years old,
and she was found
in a packing box
in a parking lot
at the intersection
of Cordelia
and Tamsin Streets.
The box
appears to be in
good condition,
and shows no indications
that the child struggled,
which may suggest
that she was unconscious
or even dead
at the time she was placed
inside the box.
ALS reveals no blood
or bodily fluids on the box.
There are
multiple hairs
embedded in the packing tape.
There is a viscous residue
on the underside
of the box.
The guy who found the box
said he's sure it wasn't here
when he arrived
to do his set.
You know it's
too bad
that there's no exterior
surveillance cameras
on any of the businesses here.
Mm-hmm.
No skid marks,
which means the box
was probably placed,
instead of being tossed out
of a moving vehicle.
Most likely
someone on foot.
There's got to be hundreds
of shoe prints
crisscrossing
this lot.
Yeah.
I better get started.
(reporters clamoring)
All right, all right, okay.
This is an ongoing
investigation,
we're not giving out any more
details at this time.
All we're asking is anyone with
any information about this girl,
to please come forward
and contact the authorities.
(clamoring continues)
Let...
I'll answer the questions,
but one at a time, all right?
Okay.
Has anyone claimed
responsibility?
No.
REPORTER:
How old is the baby?
Are you offering
any reward?
BRASS:
No. Not at this time.
She's got abrasions
on the knuckles of both hands.
Reddish blisters
on both palms,
and on her legs
and buttocks.
Bruises on her back,
arms...
...and base of
the skull.
Is there anything
you could tell us
about the cause of death?
Come on,
like I said, this is an ongoing
police investigation.
(clamoring continues)
I'm not going to comment
about that.
But do you suspect
foul play?
She was found dead
in a box in a parking lot.
Draw your own conclusions.
COD is atlanto-occipital
disarticulation,
consistent with a single
blunt force trauma
to the back
of the head.
Any signs of
sexual trauma?
No.
Trace is running
the samples,
but these burns are
most likely chemical.
There's blistering in
the nasal passages
and esophagus,
which indicates
inhalation
of caustic fumes.
There's four-and-one
bruising on both arms.
Any indication
of previous breaks
or healed injuries?
Nothing to suggest a history
of prior abuse.
Well, you don't need practice
to kill a kid.
You got something?
Jude.
Patron saint
of the desperate.
Yeah.
He's got an alibi.
Who abuses
and murders a child
and then tenderly
wraps them
in a blanket and leaves them
in a parking lot?
The disposition of the body
suggests contrition.
Or remorse even.
A kidnapping
gone wrong?
Except, if she'd been taken, the
parents would have come forward.
Not necessarily.
Maybe she was taken
a while ago.
Grabbed somewhere else,
dumped here.
Maybe her parents have stopped
looking for her.
Unless the parents are involved.
Abusive husband kills daughter,
guilt-stricken wife gives
her a "decent" burial.
Or maybe the
killer's just
sticking his thumb in God's eye.
Or practicing to
be a mortician.
Or...
Got your chemical
burn agent:
it's sodium hydroxide
with traces of machined
aluminum shards.
Household drain
cleaner.
The powdered hydroxide
reacts with water
to generate near-boiling
temperatures,
which in turn
churns up the shards
which cut the hair and the gunk
to help break up the clog.
WILLOWS:
And it burns like hell
if it even touches
your skin.
It's hard to believe that
anybody could do something
like this to such
a beautiful little girl.
So, if she had been
plain or homely,
it'd be easy for
you to accept?
No.
But, uh,
maybe it's just me,
that when something
like this happens
to a kid with a face
like that, it...
just seems a little
more tragic.
Maybe that'll work
in our favor.
Did I just piss her off?
Yeah.
But she was heading that way
when she came in.
NEWSCASTER:
Sadly, there is perhaps nothing
that brings together
a community more quickly
than the loss of a child.
And it is clear that Las Vegans
have been profoundly moved
by the death of a little girl
known only as Baby Cordelia.
If you have any information
on her identity
or the circumstances surrounding
this case, please call
the L.V.P.D.
at 1-800-555-0133.
That work for you?
Nah, a little bit more
to the left.
My left or...?
No, no, you know what?
Never mind, that's,
that's perfect.
Walk away.
Uplink's pretty good.
We should be able to see it all
from the comfort of the lab.
I've seen a lot
of these shrines
over the years.
I don't think I've left
any flowers at any of them.
It's hard for most
people to mourn
for somebody they
didn't even know.
The only one
I'm interested in
is the guy who has a real reason
to be leaving flowers.
♪ ♪
SIMMS:
Okay.
This one has a tag.
And now...
tag, you're it.
Is that what passes for
DNA humor around here?
Never thought
I'd miss Sanders.
Hair is inconsistent
with the vic's.
Mark that as unknown.
Okay.
Well, that's odd.
What?
Grissom!
What's our rule, Dave?
"It better be good,"
and this is. See?
The vic's blonde hair
has a very short,
dark root.
The baby's not a natural blonde.
Who dyes a toddler's hair?
The undyed portion
of the hair shaft
is 0.90 millimeters.
Which indicates?
Well...
Wendy?
Well... human hair grows
at an average rate
of half a millimeter a day,
with a slight deviation
for age and for health.
So based on the length
of that hair root,
I would say that her hair
was probably dyed
within the last...
48 to 72 hours.
Very good.
Do you have a cross-section?
Of course.
Naturally curly hair,
the sheath is flat
like a ribbon.
But this cross-section,
the sheath is round.
So?
Well, the girl
that we're looking at
has naturally
straight, brown hair.
So maybe
she was abducted.
And then, somebody curled
and colored her hair
to try to hide her identity.
Nicely analyzed.
♪ ♪
(printer humming)
(knocking)
BRASS:
Nora O'Toole?
Yes?
I'm Detective Jim Brass,
Las Vegas Police.
This is Catherine Willows
from the Crime Lab.
Can I help you with something?
WILLOWS:
Yes.
Did you receive
an Emmerdale 2100
vacuum cleaner recently?
Yeah!
My mom gave it to me
for my birthday.
It's here somewhere.
Come on in.
It totally rocks.
It's got this whole
electrostatic
micron fiber filtration thingy.
And it's, like,
30 percent quieter.
Is it being recalled
or something?
Isn't it weird to send cops
to do a recall?
Oh, I know! Is it hot?
Did it fall off a truck?
No, no.
Nothing like that.
What did you do with the box?
The box?
Hey, Dean!
Yeah?
What'd you do
with the box?
What box?
The box the vacuum cleaner
came in.
These guys want to know
what you did
with the box.
DEAN:
I don't know.
I probably threw it out
with the trash.
That your husband?
Not yet.
This is my fiance,
Dean James.
Like James Dean,
only backwards.
You know,
Rebel Without a Cause,
he's more like
cause without a rebel.
I made that up.
Is that funny? I can't tell.
Are you nervous about something?
Me? No, that's
just my personality.
I was born this way.
Dean's the funny one.
Say something funny, honey.
I don't think these folks
are here for funny.
You live here?
Actually, I got
a place of my own.
Not for long.
Oh, you know, he spends all
of his time right here with me.
Living in sin and loving
every minute of it!
So, Mr. James,
do you remember
what you did with the box?
Sure. Yeah, I just chucked it
right out back.
(beeps)
(keyboard clacking)
I think I got something.
Got a hit?
I don't know, maybe.
JOHNSON:
Bashira Sayeed,
born April 10, 2005.
Parents are Lebanese,
in the U.S. on a tourist visa.
They lost her
in an amusement park
in Nye County three weeks ago.
Think that's her?
Could be.
Height and weight
are about the same.
Better bring the parents.
Mr. and Mrs. Sayeed.
My name is
Warrick Brown.
Would you come
with me please?
(speaking foreign language)
Yes, okay.
(sobbing loudly)
I'm sorry for your loss.
No, this is not our little girl.
This is someone else's child.
(knocking on door)
Hey, you're back!
Find the box?
Ooh, brought
reinforcements, huh?
Your boyfriend at home?
Dean?
Honey?
These guys are back.
Oh, hey, guys.
Listen, I'm late for work...
Leo Finley, you're
under arrest.
Hey!
What are you doing?!
Who's Leo Finley?!
Let go of him!
Tell them, Dean!
Tell them who you are!
Nora, baby, don't listen
to anything they tell you!
Okay, I can explain everything!
WILLOWS:
Nothing you say
will change the DNA, Leo.
That's your hair in that box.
I already explained that.
The problem is, we
still don't believe you.
Look, I told you.
I opened the box for Nora,
I assembled the vacuum cleaner,
and I threw it out back.
My hairs must have gotten
stuck in it then.
End of story.
Why the alias, Leo?
Who're you hiding from?
All right, okay,
one night, ten years ago,
I did a hit of Ecstasy,
and I threw in a hit
of peyote for good measure.
By the time morning rolled
around, I was so high
I thought I was inside
a living cartoon.
I went outside naked
and performed a joyous,
impromptu dance
to the Egyptian Sun God Ra.
That sounds really beautiful.
I'm sorry I missed it.
Well, unfortunately,
20 preschoolers
playing in the yard
next door didn't.
I was convicted
of lewd and lascivious behavior,
public nudity.
They forced me to sign up
on Megan's List.
And my life went
right down the crapper.
I've been hounded out of every
neighborhood I've moved into.
Got my tires slashed.
Someone...
someone nailed
my cat to my door.
I wouldn't worry about your cat.
You've got bigger problems
right now.
Who is she?
She the one they found
the other night?
Found dead in your box, Leo.
The one that your vacuum
cleaner came out of.
The one that you got
your arm hairs stuck in.
(sobbing):
I didn't have anything to do
with that little girl.
I never saw her
before in my life.
You're living
in an unregistered apartment,
under an assumed name,
in violation of your parole...
No! That's not true!
I still have my own place...
Which we're going to go through
with a fine-tooth comb.
Your own fiancé doesn't
even know who you are.
Please, please... You're not
going to tell her, are you?
Let's say that ship's
already sailed.
Put him in the tank.
You've never...
done anything you've regretted?
More than there are stars
in the sky.
Good-bye, Leo.
SANDERS:
This is Leo Finley's apartment,
where he claims
he threw away the box;
which, somehow ended up
three blocks north
and two blocks east--
with Baby Cordelia dead in it.
Do you really believe
he killed the girl
and carried her five blocks
before dumping the body?
In that neighborhood, who would
notice a guy carrying a box?
Leo Finley was never even
charged with child molestation,
let alone abuse.
WILLOWS:
Sex offenders escalate.
GRISSOM:
He has a reasonable
explanation why his hairs
were in the box,
and there was no evidence
of the victim
at either
of his residences.
I know.
So why is he still in custody?
Because he lied to us before,
and he's still lying now.
HODGES:
Analysis of the oily residue
from the cardboard box.
It's oil.
Yeah, mostly 10-W-40,
transmission fluid,
a little bit of axle grease
and some dirt mixed in.
Well, that could be from any
parking lot or street in town.
Yeah, but site-specific
impurity levels could
narrow that down a bit.
Let me know if you find
any suspicious oil slicks.
♪ ♪
Excuse me.
Sir?
How you doing?
My name's Nick Stokes.
I'm with the Las Vegas
Crime Lab.
You mind if I ask you
a few questions?
I'm innocent.
Do you, uh,
recognize this?
I see all kind of boxes, son.
How about this guy?
Do you recognize him?
I see what you driving at.
This fellow brought a busted
cylinder head in here
in that box, to be fixed.
One of them get-
the-job-half-done-
then-bring-it-in-here-for-
me-to-fix-it kind of guys.
You know the type?
Thinks he good with tools.
Hopeless.
Like a woman.
Worse than a woman,
a woman you might expect...
Do you remember what you did
with the box?
I took the part, he
tossed the box outside.
I got the paperwork
inside.
(sighs)
He came in
last Thursday.
Guy's name is, uh...
Dean James.
Hey, that's like, uh,
like James Dean...
Only it's backwards.
Yeah, right, we know.
Thanks, man.
Okay, yeah, I didn't throw
the box out.
I used it to take an engine part
to my mechanic. Okay?
Why did you lie, Leo?
Because I saw the thing
on the TV.
It was you, in fact, saying
about how they found
that dead kid out back there,
and I-I thought you wouldn't
believe me
if I told you I took the box
so close to the scene.
You lied to us, Leo,
and now you're changing
your story... again.
What is it with you
and the truth, Leo?
Look, I swear to God...
And now we have both you
and the box
within a hundred yards
of the scene
on the night it happened.
How do you think
that makes us feel?
I... I used it
to take a part in.
Talk to my mechanic.
He'll tell you.
We already have.
So... what?
You think I...
You think I brought the part in
and then...
came back later and put
the little girl in the box?
Does that make sense to you?
What makes sense to me,
what doesn't make sense to me
is none of your business.
But I will tell you this:
Every time I turn around,
you get closer and closer
to the scene.
Why is that, Leo?
I don't know.
Coincidence?
So what's it going to be
next time?
That... no,
that's the whole story.
There's not going to be
a next time.
Las Vegas police have exhausted
the few leads
they had in the tragic case
of Baby Cordelia Doe;
yet her identity and the
circumstances of her death
remain a mystery.
But desperate to find out
who she is
and who killed her, forensic
experts have reconstructed
the little girl's appearance
as she would've looked
before she was murdered
and left for dead.
They're hoping the image
will look enough
like the real girl to shake
loose someone's memory...
That's my baby!
(indistinct shouting)
(yelling)
That's my daughter!
Get back!
(screaming)
(indistinct announcement
over PA)
That's Inez.
That is-is... my little girl.
I wasn't there
to protect her.
You guys put her
in the ground yet?
Not yet.
I would like to go
to the funeral.
We might be able
to arrange that.
Yeah.
Do you know anyone
who wanted to harm her?
Yeah... I know exactly
who did it.
It's the guy I used to share
my cell with-- Boyd Waldrip.
I told him about my wife Grace,
what a good woman she was
and how lucky I was
to have her.
When Boyd got out,
I asked him to look
in on Grace and Inez...
to take care of them
if they needed anything.
He took care
of her all right.
The bitch filed for divorce,
and...
then she married Boyd.
How could I have been so stupid?
He killed Inez.
He killed...
(sobbing):
my little baby girl. He...
Why would he do that?
I don't know.
Maybe he did not want my face
staring up at him
every morning, reminding him
what a piece of crap he was.
Well, if he killed
your daughter,
why didn't your wife
come forward?
Maybe she's... dead, too.
Maybe he killed her, too.
When, uh, you guys
find him,
will you send him
back down here?
And then we'll save the state
a lot of money on him.
(sirens wailing)
(tires screeching)
(helicopter whirring overhead)
LVPD! Open up!
Clear!
(cartoons playing on TV)
DISPATCH:
Attention all officers,
attempt to locate white male,
Boyd Waldrip, possibly
in the company of his wife,
white female, Grace Waldrip
and/or two young children,
descriptions to follow.
Suspect's vehicle of record is
a yellow '78 Mercury Zephyr.
Nevada tags: Zebra, George,
Nora, Paul, Three, Nine, Zero...
Apparently when Waldrip got out,
he gained custody
of his two kids
from a former marriage.
First wife died of hepatitis
while he was inside.
Maybe Inez's mother dyed
her hair
so she'd fit in better
with her new siblings.
Or else she was trying to make
Inez look less like
her real father?
To protect her?
TV's still on, food
left on the table.
They left in a hurry.
(Willows coughs)
(coughs)
ANCHORWOMAN:
Tonight we have
new developments
in the tragic death
of Inez Balboa,
the child we've come to know
as Baby Cordelia Doe.
Authorities are currently
engaged in a statewide manhunt
for the child's mother
and stepfather...
If they're traveling
with their kids,
they might be looking
for a place
to leave them for awhile.
Well, Waldrip has a sister
in Modesto,
and Grace's mother lives
in Salt Lake City.
We staked out both
of their residences.
NHP is patrolling all the major
roads leading to them.
(phone rings)
Hold on a minute.
Brass.
I'm on my way.
We got 'em.
(robot whirring)
OFFICER 1 (over bullhorn):
Boyd, listen!
Let's find a way out of this.
We've got to deal with the
safety of your kids first.
OFFICER 2: We got
a hostage situation.
A customer ID'd 'em
in there eating.
They called the locals,
but he burned us
and opened fire.
BRASS:
Anybody hit?
I'm not sure. We got him
locked down there
with his family
and some customers.
How many inside?
I don't know.
OFFICER 1:
Nobody's been hurt yet;
nobody's gonna get hurt.
That's the idea.
That's the most important thing
right now, okay?
Raise that camera higher.
(robot whirring)
OFFICER (over bullhorn):
So why don't you work
with me here?
Let's ease the kids out of this.
BOYD:
Okay!
Okay, I'm going to let
the kids out.
Just put your weapons down.
You got it, Boyd.
Nice and easy.
(indistinct radio transmission)
BOYD:
You're all right.
You're okay.
(Boyd grunts and mumbles)
Go.
Come here, kids.
Come on.
NEGOTIATOR:
Let's get everyone else
out you got in there.
They didn't do
anything, Boyd.
You got
to let them out, too.
Work with me
here, Boyd.
We're gonna
work it out.
BOYD:
All right, let's go.
Come on, you guys go first.
Let's go. Let's go.
Come on, come on, come on!
I'm letting you go.
Come on...
They're coming out!
BOYD:
Nice and easy.
(garbled radio transmission)
Go, go. Move,
move, move, move!
NEGOTIATOR:
All right, let's see this
through to the end.
Now, you've got a choice.
You both can
come out together,
or you can send your
wife ahead of you.
BOYD:
Come on, you got to go.
GRACE:
No! No!
Come on. Listen to me.
Don't argue.
You got to go.
BOYD:
You're going.
No.
Go, go, go.
I don't want
to go without you!
Just go!
Don't argue
with me.
Hold you fire! Hold your fire!
Hold your fire!
(screaming)
No!
BRASS:
So you beat Inez,
then you locked her
under the sink.
If you say I killed Inez,
that must have been how it was.
You know, however you want
it put, that's fine with me.
BRASS:
Oh.
I-I'm just... I'm just trying
to do you justice here, Boyd.
Just write it out,
and I'll sign it.
So, you're waiving your right
to counsel?
I don't need no lawyer.
It's over.
Can we just get this thing done?
All right.
I want
my daddy!
Okay, come on.
Just leave him alone!
Come with me now!
I want my daddy!
He wants his daddy!
It'll be okay.
Excuse me?
Could you give me a minute
with them, please?
Thank you.
It's going
to be okay.
But you got
to be brave.
Can you do that?
Is this because of us?
No, no.
No, it's not because of you.
Is it because
of what happened to Inez?
What do you think
happened to her?
We were playing a game.
(Faith cries)
A game?
Hide and seek.
Hide and seek?
Dad was asleep on the couch.
You said that you were playing
hide and seek?
He was it.
He found me right away, but...
but Inez won.
(Faith crying)
I showed her the best hiding
place in the whole house.
Four, five, six,
seven, eight,
nine, ten, 11.
12, 13...
Did your dad tell you
to say this?
No. You're not supposed
to wake Dad when he's sleeping
because he gets tired a lot.
(Faith sniffles)
(sighs)
Why don't you tell me
what really happened?
You got my confession.
Yes, but I don't believe
that's what happened anymore.
(sighs)
I told you, that's how it was.
Your kids are telling me
something different.
It was an accident,
wasn't it, Boyd?
All right,
think about this.
Think about
your children.
What would their lives be like
with everyone believing
that their father's a killer?
I came home from work
like I always do,
fell asleep on the couch,
waiting for Grace to get home.
Where's your sister?
Inez?
BOYD:
I went outside looking
for Grace,
but she had the car,
she wasn't home from work yet.
I was scared.
I didn't know what to do.
CATHERINE:
So you're telling me that
you had your little girl
in your arms
with her heart still beating,
and you took the bus
to the hospital?
BOYD:
I thought if I let her go,
she would die.
But she died anyway.
If it was just an accident,
why didn't you just report it?
(sighs)
Look at who I am.
If I reported her death,
who would have believed me, huh?
At the very least,
they would have taken
my children away from me,
probably sent me back
to jail, too.
What would the point
of that have been?
She was dead, and...
breaking up my family
and leaving my children
without a daddy
wasn't gonna bring her back.
So you ran?
See how well that turned out.
(sighs)
Catherine?
You should see this.
(computer beeps)
(beep)
GRISSOM:
It seems they
loved her.
I think it
makes it worse.
(beep)
(trilling and beep)
(keys jingling)
(glass bottles clinking)
(quiet sigh)
CATHERINE:
Oh.
(sighs)
What are you doing here?
I was waiting for you.
How did you get in here?
Can't we talk about
something interesting?
Me, for instance.
I'm interesting.
Yeah, let's do that.
Let's talk about you.
For starters, Nora left me.
Actually, she threw my
stuff out in the street,
got a restraining
order on me, notified
the neighbors
and called my boss.
"Hey, scumbag,
don't bother coming in.
We'll mail you your last check."
So, in one fell swoop,
as it were,
I lost my girlfriend,
my livelihood
and my place to live.
I thought it was going to
be different this time.
Frankly, I blame you.
I didn't create
the circumstances
of your life, Leo.
You grind up the innocent
with the guilty.
Just take it easy.
I was just doing my job.
I was just
doing my job?
Yeah, I was just
doing my job.
I was just
following orders.
Blond Nazi bitch!
You get in there
with your big boots,
and you kick it all apart,
and you don't care who you hurt,
whose life you destroy
in the process.
Calm down.
No.
It's not fair!
Just calm down!
Calm down...
Don't tell me
to calm down!
Just stay back
and calm down.
You're going
to shoot me?
Would that help you to forget
how completely
you screwed my life up?
Would you sleep
better at night?
Maybe I should just
save you the trouble
and blow my own brains out, hmm?
What do you think?
I think you need
to talk to somebody.
I am talking to somebody.
I'm talking to you.
So how about this?
If I do decide to kill myself,
I'm going to come over
to your house
and blow my brains out
right on your front lawn,
as a gift to you
and everything
you stand for.
How does that work for you?