Previously on CSI:
Lou Gedda's getting
away with murder.
BRASS:
Warrick's a loose cannon.
He was in Gedda's strip club
conducting his own
police investigation.
What do you want?
Everything.
BROWN:
No!
I did not kill her.
Grissom, you and I both know
Gedda killed that girl.
Take the suspension
or you're fired.
BRASS:
Guys like Lou Gedda
don't skip on murder
and extortion by being lucky.
I've got an update for you.
Good work.
CHOIR:
♪ The storm is passing over ♪
♪ Oh, Lord ♪
♪ Oh! ♪
♪ The storm is passing over ♪
♪ Hallelu... ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ The storm is passing over ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ The storm is passing over ♪
♪ Hallelu... ♪
♪ Be still my soul ♪
♪ My soul ♪
♪ The hour is hastening on ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ When we shall be ♪
♪ Be ♪
♪ Forever with the Lord ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ When disappointment, greed ♪
♪ And all fear is gone ♪
(onlookers gasping, screaming)
Oh...
(camera shutter clicking)
STOKES:
Crime scene at a funeral?
Can't get much
deader than this.
Liver temp
certainly couldn't.
He's been dead
more than 24 hours.
Any indication
what he died from?
No. No sign of trauma.
I spoke with Mrs. Bell; she has
no idea who the other D.B.
from the casket is.
Okay.
Thanks.
That has got to be the biggest
casket I've ever seen.
GRISSOM:
This is the Elvis model.
We're a fat country, Nick;
here's our proof.
Yeah, I don't think they come
out of the factory
with room for two, though.
No, the extra compartment
is a custom addition.
This board is what separated
the two bodies.
The top guy was just too heavy.
♪ With the Lord ♪
♪ Ooh! ♪
(gasping, screaming)
Maybe it's a scam to save money.
Mortuaries are obligated
to bury indigents
at no charge.
Maybe save a burial plot
by burying John Doe
with John Smith.
MAN:
Go ahead, man,
put him in the van-- I dare you.
Guys, I'm just
a coroner's assistant.
Coach Bell,
he not going nowhere, man.
You got that right.
Hold on.
Hold on, now, fellas,
he's just doing his job.
Mr. Bell is our
first priority.
We're gonna have him back here
as soon as we can.
Okay, are you guys gonna help us
with the funeral again, too?
And buy another casket?
'cause that was donated
by the community.
We'll pay for
a new casket.
We will?
Come on, man, this is a disgrace
right now, man.
Hey, whoever put that
other body in the casket
is the one you should
be angry with, not us.
If you let us do our job,
we'll put him in jail.
This isn't right!
Guess you're gonna have
to move us yourself then.
Yeah, man!
Coach ain't going nowhere!
STOKES:
Hey, wait a second.
Easy, guys!
WOMAN:
Please, please, please,
stop this!
Stop this now, please, just...
Let my husband through.
(gurney clacking)
CHOIR:
♪ The storm is passing over ♪
♪ Oh, Lord ♪
♪ Do-do-do-do ♪
♪ The storm is passing over ♪
♪ Hallelu... ♪
♪ Ooh, yeah. ♪
and TOYOTA.
Moving Forward.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
BRASS:
You're the mortician.
You're the one putting bodies
into coffins.
So what, you have
a two-for-one sale?
Who's the extra stiff?
You don't want to say anything?
That's fine.
I'll just shut down
the mortuary.
Maybe I'll book you
on suspicion of murder.
For all I know,
you killed the guy
before you stuffed him
in the coffin.
Got to admit it's a pretty
clever way to dispose of a body.
Who's going to look
under somebody else's tombstone?
Well, it's not exactly
a new technique.
In the 1920s, Joe Bonanno
used to dispose of his hits
in a double-decker coffin.
So what is this,
more research for your mob book?
I hope you're not starting
to admire those thugs.
(scoffs)
I don't admire them.
But I'm grateful.
For what?
Well, my, uh,
book is done.
I have meetings with three
different publishers in L.A.,
and I fly out the
day after tomorrow.
(camera shutter clicks)
I heard you
were in here.
Need any help?
Hmm?
Not really.
I've already collected trace
off the body,
and I'm almost done
with the coffin here.
Chaparral High
football coach, huh?
Mm-hmm.
Hey, by the way,
how much do I owe you?
I don't know, Warrick.
Don't worry about it.
Man, come on.
I always pay my debts.
This should cover it.
(laughs)
What exactly about
the Chaparral High state champs
reminded you to pay me?
Football always reminds me
of money.
It's not football season.
It's baseball,
but I don't bet baseball.
Pure paycheck, baby.
(clicks tongue)
Hey, doc, you figure out
what killed this guy yet?
Yeah, found some petechiae
consistent with suffocation.
Yeah, this should do it.
You okay?
Yeah.
I know this guy.
Or I knew him.
He was a P.I.
You just saved yourself
some work.
His prints
will be in the system.
Thanks.
Lenny Harper.
We were in patrol together
20 some-odd years ago.
Class cop.
You sure we're talking
about the same guy?
This guy's got a list
of complaints
going up right until
about the day he retired...
at age 33.
Vegas was a different town
back then.
You ruffled feathers,
you got the boot.
But soliciting prostitutes,
extorting businessmen,
insurance fraud.
Kind of looks like he deserved
to get the boot.
Lenny always said those
complaints were trumped up.
This file doesn't change the way
we treat this case.
Lenny was a cop.
Cops are a priority.
I want every man you got
on this.
Either this guy is a neat freak
or he's got one hell
of a cleaning lady.
Left his computer;
that helps.
Hey, Nick?
Is there a trash can
under that desk?
Yeah.
Is there a liner in it?
Yeah. Why?
There's no liner in this one.
And the paper shredder's
been emptied.
Looks like somebody cleaned up
after they cleaned up.
♪ ♪
This car is clean
as a whistle.
The floor mat's
still damp.
I think it's just
been detailed.
What if the killer
used the victim's car
to transport the body?
He drives the victim's
own vehicle
back to the funeral home,
stuffs the body
in a double-decker coffin,
hits a car wash,
comes back,
cleans out the office...
and leaves us the keys?
It's pretty considerate.
Or very smart.
(device beeps)
♪ ♪
(cell phone rings)
(phone beeps)
How did you get
this number?
Is this some
kind of a joke?
What the hell do you want?
Should I bring
my own shovel?
(hangs up)
Hey.
Hi.
Get anything off that computer?
No. Hard drive's
been wiped clean.
What about the shredder?
Nothing but a couple of strips
from a folder
and a few receipts.
But I got a court order
on Mr. Harper's email accounts.
He had quite a few.
One that handled
mostly family stuff.
new customers.
And a work account.
The work account had an
online back-up system.
That's what I'm in now.
So you've basically gotten
everything that was on his
computer?
I even have
stuff he erased.
There's a file in here that you
might think is interesting.
P.I.'s like to use a lot of
audio and visual surveillance.
Insurance policy.
This one was even taping
his own meetings.
Really?
HARPER:
All right,
so it's March 17, 2008.
Meeting with Client #333.
This was from inside
his Escalade, yesterday...
GEDDA:
She did it with a cop.
I spit on her.
She deserved what she got.
HARPER:
That's as close to a confession
as you're gonna get.
BROWN:
I'm gonna bury that guy, Lenny.
I'm gonna bury him.
Warrick couldn't
investigate Gedda himself,
so he had the P.I.
do it for him.
Archie tracked down
thousands of photos,
sound byte files, videos.
Everything's connected
to Lou Gedda.
I think Gedda caught Harper
spying on him, killed him
and had the mortician
put the body in the
double-decker casket.
(dialing)
(recording):
This is Warrick Brown.
Leave your name and number.
Warrick.
Call me now!
(phone snaps shut)
Anybody hears from him,
I want to know.
You got it.
(cell phone rings)
Where the hell have you been?
Grissom...
I gotta talk to you.
Something... something
bad happened here.
Where are you?
Pigalle.
What are you thinking?
I don't know. I don't know.
You don't... you don't
know what?
I don't know what I did here.
I don't know what happened.
I just woke up and...
I don't know...
I don't know what's
going on here!
Drop the gun,
show me your hands!
Warrick?
Show me your hands!
I'm a CSI!
Warrick?
I'm a CSI! Don't shoot!
Get on your knees!
♪ ♪
Warrick?
Grissom, I...
I don't know
what happened.
Local merchant heard gunshots,
called 9-1-1.
I responded code 3, with backup.
There was no
one else in
the building.
Thanks. Listen, uh...
could you give us
just a minute?
What happened?
I don't know.
My head is throbbing.
Is that your gun?
Yeah.
Are those your cuffs?
I guess so.
We need to get you a lawyer.
WARRICK:
Grissom...
Don't say another word.
Jim, listen to me.
Just get on your feet.
I don't know
what happened!
Look, hey, it's for
your own good.
Keep your mouth shut
till we get to the station.
You couldn't just
let it go, huh?
Come on.
♪ ♪
The 419 went out
as officer involved. No details.
Yeah, we got here
as quick as we could.
What the hell happened?
Gedda's dead.
Put your kits away.
Day Shift will be processing
the scene.
I.A.'s taking the case
from here.
(flashbulb popping)
Turn around.
You can put your
hands d... No-- GSR. Sorry.
Get a lawyer.
I don't want one.
This isn't going away, Warrick.
In 48 hours,
they're gonna
charge you.
I wouldn't know what to
tell a lawyer, anyway.
I'm gonna have to
take your clothes.
(indistinct whispers)
Were you just
talking to I.A.?
Yes.
And what'd
you tell 'em?
I'm not supposed to talk about
it; I signed an admonishment.
I don't care.
What'd you say?
I said that I saw Warrick
sitting alone
in Grissom's office
in the dark.
So what?
So, he got a phone call,
and he got really pissed
at the person he
was talking to.
So what?
Then he was found an hour later
in a pool of Gedda's blood.
You don't know what
happened in there.
Look, Nick, all I did was
tell the truth as I saw it.
That's what we're
supposed to do. Right?
I don't remember what happened.
Is that what you're
going with? Really?
That's what the truth is.
Okay.
Uh, for the record then,
are you claiming memory loss
from a possible concussion,
or hysterical
amnesia following
a traumatic incident?
Like I told you, I just don't
remember what happened.
You remember hiring Lenny Harper
to investigate Lou Gedda...
in violation
of direct orders?
Yeah.
You think Gedda was responsible?
I'd bet on it.
I've heard
that about you.
Is that why you went to Pigalle?
I went to Pigalle
because Lou Gedda called me.
(sighs)
Your coworkers
corroborate a call,
so we pulled
your cell records.
It came from a disposable phone,
which means it could've come
from anybody.
No, it came from Lou Gedda.
I suppose that's possible.
But we do seem to be jogging
your memory.
Let's keep that ball rolling.
What happened next?
I went down there.
WAGENBACH:
Alone?
BROWN:
Yes.
Unarmed?
BROWN:
No.
Gedda!
You called me!
Next thing I remember...
I don't remember anything
that happened after that.
Uh, you left out
the best part.
But I guess
that's the...
amnesia.
You want me to fill in
the blank?
Your gun...
with blood, tissue and hair
at the scene.
Your handcuffs
on the vic.
You...
covered in blood.
You went to Pigalle
to get revenge
by giving Lou Gedda
a taste of his own medicine.
♪ ♪
You're a CSI.
What's the evidence telling you?
The evidence is...
...the evidence is suggesting
that I did it.
Okay.
You think this is some
kind of a joke, eh?
You think this is
a joke, right?
You're making
a mistake.
I don't know what happened.
You're digging
a hole.
You understand
what I'm saying?!
I don't know
what happened!
I know that.
Okay, the rods are in place
according
to the autopsy report.
Conrad.
Gil, we're processing
Warrick's case evidence.
You shouldn't even
be in here.
I'd like to see the files.
Well, they're
not done yet.
We're still finalizing
our conclusions.
Yeah, but if I could see
the raw test data,
I could draw my own conclusions.
I'll get you copies
of the reports.
You'll have them
in a couple of hours.
Thanks.
Excuse me, Detective.
May I have a few minutes
with CSI Brown?
Why?
I'm a friend.
Well, he sure needs
one of those.
Be my guest.
Thank you.
How you holding up?
Hmm.
That depends.
Do you think I did it?
I can't discuss the case.
Yeah.
I don't know, I think
I'd just feel a lot better
if I had a change
of clothes.
I hate being dressed
like a convict.
I'll take care of it.
Stay strong.
(knock at window)
DETECTIVE:
We're not
through yet.
Okay, um...
Let's... let's back
up a little bit.
You get involved with
a pretty young thing.
You go away to do
your business.
She winds up dead.
You ever think about that?
I think about Joanna
every day.
There's not a day that goes
by I don't think about her.
No, I'm sorry.
I was talking
about Holly Gribbs.
You remember
Holly, don't you?
Rookie CSI you left alone
at a crime scene eight years ago
to go place bets
for a crooked judge.
Suspect came back and shot her.
I remember.
Poor innocent girl
just trying to do her job.
She winds up dead
because of you.
That has nothing
to do with this.
Do two points make
a straight line?
It's a pattern of behavior.
Reckless, obsessive,
compulsive, self-destructive
behavior.
What are you
doing here?
I just stopped by to get Warrick
a change of clothes.
All right, take something
out of the drawers--
nothing laid out
or in the laundry.
DETECTIVE:
You get Holly killed,
then you get
Joanna killed.
You just can't take
any more, so you kill Gedda.
That's how a jury's
going to see it.
There's nothing I can do
about that.
Sure there is.
Look, Lou Gedda was a slimeball.
That's common
knowledge.
Nobody's going
to miss him.
In fact, the world is arguably
a better place without him.
And so if I just
admit to killing him,
they'll take it easy on me,
and you're just trying to help
me out, right?
You know how many times
I used that on a suspect?
Don't waste your game, pal.
Okay.
You're a betting man.
Given the circumstances,
what do you think your odds
are right now?
I want a lawyer.
SIMMS:
There were numerous
high-velocity blood stains
on the front of CSI
Warrick Brown's shirt.
Seven of these stains
were typed
using 13 STR loci.
All samples match
blood collected
from Lou Gedda at autopsy...
DAWSON:
The five expended
cartridge cases
recovered at
Pigalle Boulevard
were all fired in Warrick
Brown's service pistol...
The bullets recovered
at autopsy
and from the barber's chair
were fired from the same
firearm, as well...
ROBBINS:
Based on the clotting
of the facial lacerations
and development of the bruises
on the victim's arms
and wrists...
it appears he was bound
and beaten at least an hour
prior to death...
Okay, if this were
any other suspect,
what would be our conclusion?
That he did it.
Which is what Warrick told
Internal Affairs.
He confessed?
No, but he didn't deny it.
He says he can't remember.
We've all heard that one before.
What's that supposed to mean?
It's not supposed
to mean anything.
We're just talking.
We can't just sit her
and watch him go down.
WILLOWS:
We're not going to.
He's asked for an attorney.
We'll get him a shark.
The only thing
the jury's going to see
is a rogue cop
with a vendetta.
I've been there before.
They're going to crucify him.
Hey, guys, I'm sorry
to interrupt,
but you need
to see this.
There was chloroform in Lou
Gedda's blood and tissue.
Chloroform gets metabolized
in the body pretty quickly,
and it's excreted by breathing.
Gedda must have been killed
soon after he was dosed.
Warrick went in there
with a gun.
Why would he use
chloroform if he was
going to shoot him?
Maybe to subdue him
into the barber's chair.
So he intended to torture him?
No, not Warrick. No way.
You know, chloroform
exposure can result
in short term amnesia.
Warrick says
he can't remember anything
after going into Gedda's office.
Where's the tox on Warrick?
His blood wasn't drawn.
Why not?
The arrest report didn't note
any intoxication at the scene.
I guess nobody saw
any reason to do it.
Well, now there's a reason.
Here, put this on.
Okay.
Henry did a comprehensive
drug test
for chloroform,
along with a head space run
for volatiles
and solvents.
Everything came
back negative.
HODGES:
Half-life of chloroform
in a human being
is about 1.5 hours.
It's virtually undetectable
in seven to ten hours.
We drew the blood too late.
It's still possible
Warrick was dosed.
We just can't prove it.
Nick, come here.
Take a look at his shirt.
See the voids in
the blood spatter
around the armpits.
STOKES:
Fabric must have been
folded when the blood
was deposited.
Looks like he had
something under his arms.
Mm-hmm.
Grab Hodges from behind--
under the armpits.
Turn around.
Dead weight, Hodges.
Slump down.
Let him
hold you up.
Okay, Nick...
Raise his right arm.
Pretend he's got
a gun in his hand.
STOKES:
It's possible.
I mean, if Warrick
were unconscious
or semiconscious,
he would have had
to have been supported.
Well, based on the
high-velocity spatter
on the shirt,
the shooter would have
had to be within three feet
of Gedda when
he fired.
(hissing)
(clearing throat)
Take off the shirt.
Thanks.
Similar void
in the spatter pattern.
STOKES:
It's consistent,
but not conclusive.
There's probably a dozen
different ways
to explain those voids.
Doesn't rule Warrick out
as the shooter.
But it gives an alternative
explanation of the evidence.
And if we're right...
Warrick was framed.
I talked to a detective
at organized crime.
He's sending over a
list of all the people
that wanted Gedda dead.
It's a long list.
Cross-reference it to any
of Warrick's convictions
who might have it
out for him.
Maybe somebody's trying
to kill two birds
with one stone.
Okay, I'm on it.
Hey.
Any unknown contributors
from the blood at the scene?
No. They're all coming
back to the vic.
Wendy and I are working
as fast as we can.
We're striking out.
There's no new evidence
from the scene
that points to any
additional suspects.
You got something?
Handcuffs?
Take a look
at the ligature marks.
The width of the rails
on Warrick's cuffs
are three millimeters narrower
than the ligature marks.
The ligature marks on Gedda
didn't come from
Warrick's cuffs.
So somebody switched
the handcuffs
after Gedda was dead?
Brass always suspected
that there was a mole
in the department
that worked for Gedda.
I bet we're looking
for a cop.
A P.I. investigating Gedda
gets killed...
then Gedda gets killed...
Maybe this dirty cop
did them both.
Yeah, but we can't prove it,
'cause we're not allowed
to investigate Gedda's murder.
We're still investigating
the P.I.
If the cases are linked,
we solve one,
we solve the other.
Do your client and this
department a favor--
make a deal.
The district attorney said
he might consider manslaughter.
I can't do that.
Are you telling me
you're innocent?
Because I.A. said those words
never crossed your lips.
Are you charging me?
Not yet.
But in about five hours, it's
gonna be first-degree murder.
We got the link.
Tox confirmed
traces of chloroform
in the P.I.'s body.
Had to have been the same
guy who killed Gedda.
Well, that helps.
Okay.
We got evidence logs
and police files
from both scenes,
but if a cop left trace
at either murder scene,
we'd just write it off
to normal investigator
contamination.
Yeah.
After he killed his victims,
he could've even stayed
and handled the scene,
made sure that he
hadn't missed anything.
(sighs)
Day Shift found prints
from three officers
at Gedda's office.
Well, all three were
assigned to the scene.
Mandy I.D.'d
fingerprints from five officers
at the mortuary.
Okay, but only four
signed the log.
The unexplained print...
belongs to...
Officer Daniel Pritchard.
His fingerprint was found...
on the casket.
How does his
fingerprint
get on the casket if he wasn't
at the mortuary?
I'm sorry, Captain.
No one's seen Pritchard
since day before yesterday.
Open it.
No cuffs.
Maybe we don't
need them.
(handcuffs clicking)
McKEEN:
So it's all on Pritchard.
Is this gonna
hold up in court?
It will.
You know what
the defense
is gonna say, right?
who better than a CSI to make
a murder look like a frame?
He was framed.
And I'll prove it.
Listen, Grissom, um...
I'm so sorry
about all this.
Warrick.
Yeah.
You were framed.
Framed?
(sighs)
By who?
Gedda has a mole
in the department.
I'm ready to talk.
He's on the way.
BROWN:
Gedda!
You called me?
A cop?
Daniel Pritchard.
We think that
he had him kill
Lenny Harper,
Probably Joanna Krumsky,
as well.
Then why would
he kill Gedda?
Who knows?
Old mobsters... crooked cops.
It's a long history.
I don't know. I mean...
Come on, Grissom.
Gedda's been killing
and barbecuing people
for 25 years.
It'd take more than a beat cop
to get over on that fat bastard.
There's got to be somebody
higher up than that.
Probably.
But Pritchard's
all we got for now.
He's in custody?
Not yet.
Hey, everything can't
go our way.
The D.A.'s gonna
drop the charges.
But there's still the question
of administrative violations.
So Ecklie and I
are recommending
to the undersheriff
that you be
suspended and demoted
but not terminated.
I still have a job?
Well...
the undersheriff says he
has to think about it,
but he just wants
to make you sweat.
I've sweated enough, man.
I imagine.
Thank you.
Thanks.
Come on.
Brass is gonna
process you out.
Don't ever forget
how lucky you are.
Let's go.
But at least mine was with
Lana Turner, not Aaron Spelling.
(laughter)
WILLOWS:
That's pretty lame, I know.
This just reminds me,
what does it take
to get them
to serve turkey bacon
in this place?
Turkey bacon's not gonna make
the food any better here.
Yeah, well, fortunately
we don't come here for the food.
No.
Well, as far as I'm concerned,
there's no place I'd rather be.
WILLOWS:
Aw...
Anything else?
See you next time?
Yeah.
Thanks.
You still there?
Hmm?
This one right here.
I'll take this.
Well, thank you, Warrick.
♪ ♪
Thank you.
GRISSOM:
Okay.
I'm going home.
STOKES:
Yeah, me, too.
Get some sleep tonight.
Oh, yeah.
Thanks for breakfast.
You got it, man.
See you at the lab.
If you ever need anybody
to talk to, you know
how to get a hold
of me, huh?
Yeah.
Thanks.
♪ ♪
Well...
it's just you and me, Serpico.
Let's get a beer.
Oh, no.
Come on. You're
a free man now.
This free man needs
a free shower.
I think, uh...
you need to, uh... take
a hard look at that redhead.
You know, I might
just do that.
Yeah. You need to.
Hey.
I'm really glad you're okay.
I'll call you later.
All right.
♪ ♪
(grunts)
(starts engine)
(radio playing,
car device beeping)
(radio volume lowers)
Warrick.
Hey.
I wanted to join you
for dinner.
I'm sorry we missed you.
Yeah, well.
I just wanted to congratulate
you in person.
You sure made
a believer out of me.
Thanks.
Look, uh...
I don't want to fire you.
I just need to know that you're
through running the streets
on your own
looking for bad guys.
Look...
I'm done being a rogue
in the streets, you know?
But there's...
there's one son of a bitch
still out there.
And I promise you,
we're gonna get him.
Well... Grissom taught you well.
I like to think so.
You never give up.
No.
That's what makes you
a great CSI.
♪ ♪