♪ ♪
She-bang!
That's pretty cool, right?
Mm-hmm.
That doesn't happen
very often, you know.
I know.
You won.
You beat me!
Uh-huh.
You want to play again?
(die rattling)
(sighing):
Fine.
Whatever.
Knock yourself out.
(cartoon music playing on TV)
(wacky laughter on TV)
(water running)
(running water stops)
(water splashes gently)
(weary sigh)
(train wheels clacking,
horn blowing)
(glass containers
clattering gently)
(loud thud in distance)
Evan?
(thud)
(latch clicks, hinges squeak)
(train engine rumbling,
horn blowing)
(hinges squeak)
(screaming)
(thudding,
train horn blaring)
(indistinct police radio
transmission in background)
(train wheels clacking
in distance)
How long have you been here?
About six hours.
Why haven't these bodies
been released?
Good question.
David was in Henderson
on another call,
so, when Greg and I got here,
we just started processing
the house.
Found the victim
in the bathroom,
covered with a towel.
We got a plastic print
on the bathroom door.
It's the strongest piece of
evidence-- I photographed it
and transmitted the image
back to the lab;
Mandy got a hit
to an unknown palm;
case info was in ViCAP.
And then,
Dispatch called,
telling me
to stop processing immediately,
by order of the FBI.
The FBI field office
is right next to the Strip.
What's taking them so long?
Oh, beats the hell out of me.
(train rumbling)
(rattling, clinking)
(helicopter approaching)
Jack Malone, FBI.
Jim Brass.
I'm based in New York,
but I was testifying
in a case in San Francisco.
When I heard about
the ViCAP hit,
I got here
as fast as I could.
Chopper from the Strip?
That's nice.
That's my tax dollars
at work?
You get a positive ID
on the boy?
No, but we have an
ID on the female--
name is Carmen Davis.
According to neighbors,
she lives alone.
Apparently no kids
of her own.
But if I find
anything out,
I'll let you know.
Thank you. You're up.
You-- you get enough photos?
Definitely.
Roll the body over.
What's going on?
Jack Malone, FBI,
New York City.
This boy was kidnapped
from his babysitter's
apartment six years ago.
Babysitter was killed.
The only evidence at the crime
scene was a bloody palm print.
Well, there may be
a resemblance,
but kids change a lot
in six years.
JACK:
Mm-hmm.
GRISSOM:
DNA will tell us
if this is your kid.
But it does look like
your killer came to Vegas.
and TOYOTA. Moving Forward.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
PHILLIPS:
Based on lividity and rigor,
TOD-- roughly 24 hours ago.
And he's got perimortem bruising
on the back of the neck.
And a single sharp-force
injury to the forehead.
Looks like he hit his head
on the table.
Or somebody slammed it
against the table.
Well, we don't know that yet.
Agent Malone,
why don't I fill you in
on what else
we do know.
There are no signs anywhere that
the boy actually lived here.
The sleeping bag
on the couch indicates
that he was probably
a house guest.
Why don't you follow me
into the kitchen.
Let me know when you're ready
to transport the body.
PHILLIPS:
Yes, sir.
WILLOWS:
Bring us up to speed, Greg.
Okay, sure. Um...
Carmen Davis's keys
were still in her purse;
the car's outside.
No cash in the wallet, and the
credit cards have been removed
and neatly stacked on the table;
it appears as though
they've been wiped clean.
The killer was smart enough
not to take anything
that could be traced.
Which suggests that
he was an experienced criminal.
What do you know
about this guy?
Including everything
you just told me?
Everything you just told me.
Six years ago, the killer took
the murder weapon with him.
It was a baseball bat that
he found in the apartment.
Well, this time,
we think it's a hammer.
The round indentation wounds are
consistent with hammer blows.
Do you see any similarities
between this victim
and the babysitter
who was killed six years ago?
Just that they were both
bludgeoned to death.
The babysitter was a lot older,
and she wasn't covered.
Covering a body usually
indicates remorse
on the part of the killer.
So you think he felt remorseful
about this victim
and not the one
from six years ago?
Maybe he knew Carmen Davis.
There's three toothbrushes,
two of them in travel cases.
My guess:
the killer was staying here
with the little boy.
There was no sign
of forced entry.
PHILLIPS:
Agent Malone?
We're ready
to take the boy out.
Okay.
(sighing):
So, I assume
we'll be sending over
the case evidence to Quantico?
We can't process the evidence
from every case
we're involved in.
We have a massive
overload already.
This will be
joint jurisdiction.
You do your thing,
I'll do mine.
(siren wails in distance)
COD is multiple
blunt-force trauma.
Based on the development
of the contusions,
it appears the blow
to the back of the skull
was the first impact,
but the ones on the face
came about half-hour later.
Half an hour?
Yeah.
Was she raped?
I, uh, did a wet mount,
found semen
in the vaginal vault,
and I collected an SAE kit.
This guy is some piece of work.
I'll get it to DNA.
No birthmarks.
Our missing boy didn't
have any, either.
So the only way to
confirm the identity...
I've had the original DNA report
electronically sent to your lab.
Well, then you'll just have
to wait for your answer.
You know, maybe now
would be a good time
for you to brief us
on the original case.
JACK:
His name was Jason Taylor.
(glass breaking)
He was at his babysitter's
apartment.
He'd been home sick
from school.
That's when it happened.
(camera shutter clicking)
An unidentified male entered,
most likely through an open
window on the fire escape,
murdered the babysitter
and took Jason with him.
We never got a decent
description of the perp.
Nothing was stolen?
Cash was still in
the babysitter's purse;
the only thing missing
was a baseball bat.
Which, based on her wounds,
you figure
that was the murder weapon?
Mm-hmm.
Baseball bat there,
hammer here--
weapons of convenience.
Guy seems to grab
whatever's handy.
WILLOWS:
And takes it with him.
Was the
babysitter raped?
No.
STOKES:
Why kidnap a kid,
wait six years, then kill him?
WILLOWS:
Most four year olds will do
what you tell them.
Most ten year olds
will do what they want.
BROWN:
Kid starts asking
the wrong questions,
talking to
the wrong people...
Tons of possibilities.
Yes. Way too many.
According to this,
the kid was adopted.
Did you take a look
at the biological parents?
Jason was adopted
as an infant.
There was no way
we could track his records.
BROWN:
Adoptive parents
had no contact
with the kidnappers?
They were not given
any ransom demands?
There was no motive.
I couldn't even give
the parents a reason.
Maybe there isn't one.
Most children are
abducted by somebody
who's associated
with the family.
Random kidnappings
are extraordinarily rare.
Except in the U.S. last year,
there were almost a hundred.
Some things are just random.
Have you ever tried telling that
to the parents of a child
who's been kidnapped?
Yes, actually, I have.
And how'd that work out for you?
(equipment whirring)
Hey, guys.
Found an empty jewelry
box in the bedroom.
Maybe the killer
swiped the jewelry
in addition
to the cash.
Easy to fence in
this neighborhood.
Was the dead girl wearing any
jewelry when you found her?
Nope.
Then that's
a good call, man,
'cause she's wearing some
in just about
every one
of these pictures.
I wouldn't doubt if she kept
a lot of it in that box.
I'll check with
the local pawn shops,
see if anything's
been hocked.
Hey, Greg, you see any books
on the shelf over there
on gambling or poker?
No, just a lot
of romance novels,
mysteries and
women's health.
'Cause I got poker player stats,
and multiple websites
on online gambling.
Seems kind of out of place
to be the victim's.
I think we got
a mystery houseguest
who is a card shark.
(indistinct talking)
MAN (over speakers):
Welcome to our annual
poker tournament.
The first of the elimination
rounds are over
and we're down
to our last 100 players.
Good luck, everyone.
(slot machines beeping)
(coins clinking)
Got him!
You know what this is?
Huh?
This is police brutality.
Yeah, whatever.
We're not done yet.
BRASS:
Well, he doesn't
look like much,
but then again,
they never do.
JACK:
If you don't mind,
I'd like to talk to him first.
You don't have
to be polite, Jack.
This is a federal case,
you don't need my permission.
BRASS:
How you going to go at him?
I don't know.
I usually just make
it up as I go along.
BROWN:
All done here.
Thank you.
You can leave, too.
Mr. Michaels.
Jack Malone. FBI.
Huh.
FBI.
Mm-hmm.
Why'd you run back there?
Oh, I don't know.
I was scared, I guess.
Of what?
Um... of getting caught.
Being embarrassed.
Right.
So it's probably a good idea
not to do anything that
would embarrass you.
Yeah, I know.
But you never really think
you're going
to get caught, do you?
Yeah, but you did.
You want to talk
about it?
I got nowhere I have to be.
And you got nowhere to go.
(sighs sharply)
I don't know what
the big deal is.
I mean...
we've all thought
about it, right?
Sure. It's natural.
Right.
I had a plan.
It was simple.
I take it...
I play with it
for a little while...
"It"?
Like it's property?
Yeah, yeah,
it's nothing personal.
I didn't even think Brother
Willard would even miss it.
Brother Willard?
You want to talk to me
about Brother Willard?
(sighs)
Brother Willard
is my spiritual advisor.
He's supposed to talk me out
of doing things like this.
But you know what?
Sometimes I just...
I just feel like listening
to that little voice
inside my head.
Hmm.
Right.
And what is that little voice
inside your head
telling you right now?
Just take it.
"Just take it."
This is not the first time
that you've taken something
that doesn't belong
to you, is it?
What do you mean?
Six years ago, in New York City.
I don't know anything
about New York.
Six years ago, in New York City,
you took something
that didn't belong to you.
I don't know anything
about New York.
Look, I told you--
I was going to give it back.
Really, I just had
some bad luck.
Is that what you call it?!
You abducted and murdered
a four-year-old boy!
I don't know what
you're talking about!
Hey...
JACK:
Just bad luck?!
Let him go.
Look, you want
to rendition him
to Gitmo, be my guest,
but in this house,
we play by the rules.
Now get your hand
off the suspect.
What's that?
That's...
That's Evan. That's...
This is my son.
This is Evan.
Guy's not the murderer.
I know.
We ran his palm print.
Doesn't match.
He's a Mormon from Utah.
Stole $10,000 from the church,
entry money into a poker game.
Figured he'd win the money,
replaced it before they noticed.
And decided he'd
bring his kid with him?
Single parent.
Carmen Davis
is an ex-girlfriend.
Dropped the kid off with her.
And while he's playing cards,
they both get murdered.
I got your DNA results.
The dead boy was confirmed
as Tom Michael's son.
So he's definitely not your
kidnap victim from New York.
However, the results
of the SAE kit
on the female victim
showed two semen donors.
One was Tom and the other
unknown, but that unknown
was connected to two unsolved
rape murders in CODIS.
Excuse me.
(typing)
Two years ago in Wyoming,
11 months ago in Idaho.
Okay, one victim was 23,
the other one 54.
One blonde, one brunette.
Both female.
Both with their faces covered.
GRISSOM:
Both single,
with no kids.
Breaks the pattern.
If there is a pattern.
There's a big gap between
Vegas and New York.
Now, this guy
has been involved
in four murders
in the last two years.
There's got to be more.
Well, if there are,
then there may not be any
associated DNA in the system.
Small towns usually
can't afford to run it
if they don't have a suspect.
Doesn't mean
there's not a pattern.
Just means we haven't
found it yet.
(typing)
Special Agent Malone.
David Hodges.
The granular powder
that you found
on the dead boy's
neck and shirt
was largely ammonium
nitrates and sulfates--
commercial grade
fertilizer.
(sighs)
Great, so the
killer could be
from any farm in
the United States.
Yeah, or any backyard.
Thank you.
So, I was curious
about opportunities
at the federal level.
Pay scale,
working conditions...
You want
my honest opinion?
Absolutely.
There's a lot less competition
in Vegas for a guy like you.
The FBI has enough
ass-kissers already.
I'm looking
for Tom Michaels.
Yeah, he's in there.
You might want to give him
a minute, though.
He's, uh,
saying good-bye.
Do you have any kids?
Yes. I have two daughters.
Um, Mr. Michaels...
I wanted to apologize
for my behavior earlier.
You're afraid I'm going to sue?
The same man
who murdered your son
kidnapped another
boy six years ago.
He's here in Vegas, right now.
And this is closest that I've
ever been to him.
You thought it was me.
I promise you...
that I will do everything in my
power to catch this man.
Is that what you told
the other boy's parents?
Those the items?
Yep.
Damn.
This always happens to me.
Is that the surveillance?
Yeah.
That's the guy.
Okay.
I almost didn't call
you guys, you know.
What about me?
I'm out 350 bucks.
You'll live.
The woman these items
belonged to is dead,
along with a kid.
Oh.
Is there a reward?
Shut up. You saw him
the night before last.
You talk to him?
He say anything to you?
Not much. He showed me the
jewels. I gave him his $350.
Uh, he asked me for directions
to the Tangiers.
Hmm.
I showed him how
to get there.
Recommended that
Let It Ride game.
It's been pretty
lucky for me.
(phone dialing)
Good for you.
MAN:
Tangiers Hotel.
This is Captain
Jim Brass, LVPD.
Would you connect me to the
surveillance room, please?
(beeping)
JOHNSON:
That's definitely not a guy
you want to go home with.
That cocktail waitress doesn't
know how lucky she is.
We need a shot of his face.
(typing)
Well, I think he knows that.
Just... hold on.
Zoom in on the ball cap.
There's a logo.
(beeping)
"Hargreen Harvest."
He had commercial fertilizer
on his hands
when he killed Evan Michaels.
He's a migrant worker, perhaps.
Well, Tangiers sent over more
than 12 hours on this guy.
It's gonna take some
time, but of course
I'll let you know the
minute I find anything.
Okay, great.
I'll call in
some additional AV Techs,
help Archie get through the
footage, but you know,
I've learned that sometimes you
can go faster by going slow.
Yeah, well, I like to go
faster by going fast.
Waiting around is not
exactly my best thing.
I gathered that from
your interrogation technique.
You know, maybe you should go
back to your hotel, take a nap.
Is this your office?
Really? By choice?
It's not some kind of, uh,
surplus overflow issue?
What's wrong with my office?
Oh, I don't know.
Uh... why don't you tell me?
That's an irradiated
fetal pig.
I used it to determine the
effects of radiation on tissue.
For what?
For fun.
SIDLE:
Hey, Gil, I, uh...
Oh, I'm sorry. I didn't
mean to interrupt.
No, no, it's fine. Jack Malone,
FBI. Sara Sidle, CSI.
(mutters):
Hi.
Hello. I hear your abduction
case is now a serial murder.
Uh... yeah.
Well, uh, I got called
into work early,
but I did pick up Hank,
and I took him to the sitter.
Thank you.
I'll see you when I see you.
Pleasure.
Hmm.
Is Hank your kid?
Hank's my dog.
She walks him for me sometimes.
Oh, yeah, that's
how it starts.
Oh, I have some experience
dating in the workplace.
Really? And, uh...
how'd it work out for you?
Undetermined.
(children shouting and laughing)
(train passing nearby,
horn blowing)
(low moaning)
(gasping):
Please, help me, help me...
(dogs barking nearby)
Kid who found the old man says
he lives here with his wife.
She doesn't answer.
You think the suspect's
still in here?
We'll know in a minute.
You better wait here.
♪ ♪
Sara...
Does the victim have circular
indentations on her head?
Yeah. You want to do the
autopsy, too? Just let me know.
My guess is, this
is the hammer
we didn't find at
the Davis house.
Why take the murder
weapon from one scene,
walk around with it
for more than a day,
use it to kill again, but this
time leave it behind?
SIDLE:
Maybe he found
something better...
Colt .45 auto.
Case is empty.
(camera beeps, clicks)
Huh.
He lost the proceeds from the
Vegas murders at the Tangiers.
So, he probably
needed more cash.
Double murder ATM.
Driver's license is
on top, like before.
He likes to know their names.
I heard the husband
died at the hospital.
But the killer was definitely
here awhile.
According to liver temp,
she died a couple hours before
the husband.
So the husband was here
and alive while his wife
was being raped
and killed?
It looks that way.
(indistinct police radio
transmission)
Sara?
You okay?
I don't know.
Do you have any idea
how he selects his victims?
No.
He picks houses with no
security systems, or dogs.
Enters at night when
most people are asleep,
through open
doors or windows.
Easy targets.
So, basically at random.
They were spending a night
on the sofa, watching a movie.
(voice breaking):
It's just, uh...
It's just wrong.
(train whistle blows nearby)
(indistinct police radio
transmission)
(cell phone rings)
Grissom.
You at the Boulder City house?
No, I'm at
a railroad spur about a quarter
of a mile from the house.
You taking a trip?
Carmen Davis's house was next to
the tracks, too.
So?
Freight trains carry
bulk fertilizer.
I think your killer
is riding the rails.
All the previous
murders were committed
within about a mile
of an active railroad spur.
Right, so he gets off the train,
finds his victim,
kills them, rapes them
if he feels like it,
then just takes off.
So, I cross-referenced
similar-patterned unsolveds
in ViCAP by proximity
to rail spurs.
There's at least a dozen cases.
You know, you have the authority
to stop all the trains
coming in and
out of Nevada.
Well, I'm not gonna do that
unless I got a face.
If these are the work
of your guy,
he's piled up
one hell of a body count.
JOHNSON:
Guy kept his head down
the entire time.
STOKES:
Mm-hmm.
Oh, check out what happens
when he runs out of money.
He starts hitting
on the waitress,
been doing it to every one
of them that walked by.
And this...
is the last good image of him
before he leaves the casino.
He stops to look at this poster
and quickly makes a phone call.
STOKES:
Three numbers?
I don't know too many serial
killers that dial 911.
He's calling Information.
(dialing cell phone)
Uh, yes, this is CSI Nick Stokes
with the Vegas PD.
I need to get
the telephone number
of one of your pay phones
on the casino floor.
Near the, uh,
Let It Ride tables.
Yes, ma'am.
So, why was he so
interested in this poster?
Oh, great. Okay.
Mm-hmm.
Very good.
Thank you.
Look at this.
What is it?
South Point Casino,
just outside Boulder City.
Might be a reason
he went there.
(sighs)
(dialing number)
Hey, it's Nick.
Uh, I need to get an AG waiver
to get ahold
of some phone numbers.
Yeah, exigent circs.
Mm-hmm.
702-555-0177.
At, uh...
17-41-33.
Yes, ma'am,
day before yesterday.
Well, we know this guy
likes waitresses,
so maybe that's what
he's looking at.
Is that a "D"?
No. "G," "G-I-R"... "N"?
Okay, thanks.
Gina.
Gina Farentino.
He called Information to get
her number in Boulder City,
but it's unlisted.
Maybe that's
what pissed him off.
He knows where she works.
Yeah, Gina works here;
she's off today, though.
Probably at home.
We checked her house;
she's not there.
When was the last
time you saw her?
Not since yesterday.
What about this
guy, seen him?
This is the best
picture you got?
What do you think?
There was a guy...
I don't know if it's him.
He was was on those slots
when Gina came on her shift.
(slot machine beeping,
bells ringing)
Guess it was his lucky day.
Must've thought the jackpot
gave him a shot at her.
He started chatting her up.
Oh...
Where are you going?
No, no, no, no.
Hey, come here, come here.
What time do you get off?
She blew him off and left.
Said she wasn't feeling well.
And when did he leave?
He cashed out
and left a few minutes later.
How much did he win?
Um...
$2,500.
I need to take a look
at his W2-G, okay?
If you make over
twelve hundred bucks,
Uncle Sam gets
his cut, you know?
That's how
we stay in business.
Mm-hmm.
It's got name,
address, social...
The whole thing
has got to be bogus.
Yeah, the cashiers don't really
seem to care, no offense,
as long as you have
a picture ID.
And even when that's fake...
you can't fake one of those.
(intermittent siren blast)
DISPATCH:
Chevy Impala, Nevada license
Adam-Robert-Charles-Boy-4-2-1.
No wants or warrants.
Welfare check only.
License owner
is a Gina Farentino.
Copy, Dispatch.
License and registration, sir.
I got it right here.
(gunshots)
(tires squealing)
(indistinct police radio
transmission)
.45 auto.
Same caliber as the one taken
from the Boulder City double.
You can see the whole thing
on video if you want.
Was the waitress
in the car with him?
He was waving at somebody
in the passenger seat
when he got shot.
According to the time code
on the dash cam,
it was about 33
minutes ago.
That's a pretty good head start.
Yeah.
I don't want to lose this guy.
(cell phone ringing)
Grissom.
We ran the fingerprints
that Nick lifted
from the casino IRS form.
Got an AFIS hit.
Terry Lee Wicker.
Served two years in Sing Sing
for burglary.
He got out four months
before Jack's original
kidnapping,
and get this,
when he was sent up,
he was married
to Gina Farentino.
Brass put out a broadcast.
Listen, do me a favor.
Take a look at the map,
find the nearest railway spur
to our location.
Meadowood.
It's off the 93,
and it looks to be about...
16 miles northeast
of your location.
(intermittent siren blasts)
What the hell's going on?
Did you see
who drove this car here?
No, but I called
the tow company.
You can't park here.
(train whistle blowing)
Where's that train going?
The Fresno 211.
Chicago bound.
Any other trains pass
through here in the last hour?
No, and nothing else
is scheduled for another hour.
Can you stop that train?
I don't have
that capacity, no.
Who you guys looking for?
♪ ♪
(panting)
You starting
to miss the lab?
No, I like a
good field trip.
Right. Stay behind me.
♪ ♪
Freeze! Put your hands
where I can see 'em!
You Wicker?
No. The name's Baxter,
and I ain't got no ticket.
Where'd you get that hat?
Oh... from a man.
He gave me a hundred bucks
to get on this train.
I don't want
no trouble.
I mean... don't shoot.
GRISSOM:
Maybe, uh...
he came here
to kill his ex-wife.
(sighs):
Why?
(cell phone ringing)
Grissom.
It's Brass.
Listen, the Boulder PD
got a call from the principal
at the local elementary school.
Gina Farentino was supposed
to pick up her son,
only she didn't show up.
Yeah, there's a reason for that.
She had a son?
The kid's name is Kobe.
Yeah, according
to the principal,
a guy fitting
Wicker's description
came and picked him up
in the mother's car.
He said the kid
seemed to know him.
Thanks, Jim.
(phone beeps off)
(opens car door)
Hey, Jack.
I don't think that trooper
was waving at Gina.
License and registration, sir.
I got it right here.
You said the kid
who was kidnapped
was six years old
when he was adopted,
birth parents unknown.
That's right.
Terry Wicker was looking
for his ex-wife...
And his son.
A family reunion.
MAN:
♪ The wheels on the bus
go round and round ♪
♪ Round and round,
round and round ♪
♪ The wheels on the bus
go round and round ♪
♪ All round the town. ♪