(whimpering)
(faint slicing, gurgling)
(screams)
(hacking)
(coughing)
MAN:
Cut!
Cut! Damn it!
(bell ringing)
Can somebody please
get her a glass of water?!
What happened? Babe?
(coughing continues)
What are you doing? Are
you choking on the blood?
I did what you
told me to.
Yeah, but this time, get it
on her face, not in her mouth.
The mouth is part
of the face.
Yeah, I know, I know.
But hit her from
the side, from the side.
And get plenty on the rack.
We're dying here.
I'm going to go ring it.
All right. Hey,
grab me a bear claw.
How long have I known you, huh?
This is you and me.
Get the shot--
not too tight.
Wide enough to fit
in the fun bags.
Baby-cakes...
Where was I?
Want me to laugh?
Don't laugh.
You were scary. Get away.
Honey, this time, don't
inhale the blood, okay?
All right, let's
get her cleaned up.
Let's shoot this bitch.
Oh...
Not you, baby. The shot.
The shot's a bitch.
I love one-ers.
And you know what else I love?
I love sushi.
Me, too.
Do you want to go for sushi?
MAN:
Our lead actress,
Weatherly Adams,
had her dressing room
violated last night.
BRASS:
So she's the one you
suspect is missing?
She missed her call
this morning.
The woman is nothing
if not professional.
She's predictably precisely
35 minutes late every day.
You could set
your watch to it.
She's already... three hours
late and still no sign.
Okay.
(loud popping)
Nothing to worry
about, gentlemen.
It's just a bad bulb.
If you will, please,
follow me.
Here we are.
Check out the flowers
in the vase.
"Congratulations
on your last film."
Any idea who sent her these,
Mr. Vespucci?
Stalkers, creeps,
cranks, nut balls, degenerates--
we get them
all here.
Weatherly attracts
them like flies.
These are, uh,
some of the guys we've had
trouble with in the past.
I'll take that.
When was the last
time you saw her?
At wrap yesterday.
We shot all night, finished
about 4:00 in the morning.
Did anyone see her
leave the building?
Her car's still
parked out back.
This hers?
Yeah.
(recording):
Hi, it's Weatherly.
Leave a message or I'll scream.
(giggles)
Wallet, keys, and cell phone
still in there.
Still no answer
on her home phone.
I'll send a patrol car
to her house.
You said there was a break in,
why don't you show me?
VESPUCCI:
Ah, Weatherly...
how has she died for us,
let me count the ways.
Bludgeoned, boiled, filleted,
defenestrated,
decapitated,
disemboweled,
oh, yeah, and strangled
with her own intestines.
Autopsied while
still alive.
Made to eat her own liver,
fed slowly through
a tree chipper,
roasted and served on
a bed of Belgian endive.
When Weatherly Adams dies,
it's money in the bank.
Here you are, gentlemen.
Looks like somebody
broke the glass,
reached in, unlocked it
and opened it.
Yeah, that's the way
I found it
when I got here
this evening.
Uh, Jim...
I got her.
And I believe she's died
for the last time.
and TOYOTA. Moving Forward.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
STOKES:
Whoever stuck her
under this poster
was trying to send
a twisted message.
Either that, or the killer's
got a wicked sense of humor.
(camera shutter clicks)
Lividity is fixed along
the anterior aspect, and...
she is still
in full rigor.
She was last seen alive
about 15 hours ago.
No panties.
I'll do an S.A.E. kit.
(inflecting):
"The horror."
(exaggerating):
The horror...
Huh?
Bra-Brando?
Brando from
Apocalypse Now?
Oh, yeah, yeah.
I know, Dave.
Everybody knows that.
Oh.
I'll get the gurney.
WILLOWS:
Looks like the lady lost a heel.
There's a whole lot
of something here,
but it doesn't really
look like blood to me.
No, it's, uh,
it's the wrong color.
It's too red.
Smells sweet.
Karo syrup and food
coloring-- it's prop blood.
And I am not seeing any prints.
It's been wiped clean.
The question is, where does
the fake blood end
and the real blood begin?
(tearfully screaming)
(crying)
Now, I know this may come
as a shock to most of you,
and I'm sorry
for your loss.
I understand that Weatherly
Adams was a long-time member
of this company...
Well, do you
have a suspect?
Uh, sir, we just found
the body about an hour ago.
We're just beginning
our investigation.
Yeah, I get it, I get it.
I mean, it could be anyone.
BRASS: Now, I'm going
to have to look at your IDs
and I'm going
to take statements
and fingerprints
from all of you.
And I thank you in advance
for your cooperation.
Anything we can do to help.
So what am I supposed
to do today?
Edit.
VESPUCCI:
Excuse me, Mr. Brass.
Do you think that it
would be all right
if we were to...
continue to shoot...
No.
I want that little twerp Zarco
found and locked up.
Uh, who are you?
Vincent Lafoon.
This is my brother Mason.
We own this place.
Who's Zarco?
Oliver Zarco.
He used to work here.
He had a thing for Weatherly,
and then he got hurt, blamed it
on us, went a little nuts.
He was the one who got...
He was the one who sent
the flowers and the note.
So he's done this before.
Yeah, like, three times.
Would you shut it?
Three times. He's your guy.
Do you have video
surveillance by any chance?
Yeah, only on the exterior,
but the video system's
been on the fritz lately.
I had it repaired three days
ago-- I'll get the tapes.
Oh, good.
Look, just find Zarco, okay?
MAN:
Everyone,
come together.
Um, I can't, I still can't
believe she's gone.
I mean... she was a...
she was a real beautiful lady.
Let's form a circle
and touch hands with
someone you care about.
Yea, though I walk
through the valley
of the shadow of death,
I will fear no evil,
for thou art with me.
Thy rod and thy staff,
they comfort me...
♪ ♪
(camera shutter clicking)
How's it going in here?
The vase is clean.
I've got a
spiral notebook
filled with dates,
times and weights.
Looks like she was a bit
concerned about her size.
(chuckles)
Actors.
You really don't
recognize her?
(grunting):
No.
You've ever seen
Chop Chop, Fizz Fizz?
No.
Can I Lick The Spoon?
Please, David.
They're classics.
Those are not classics.
(grunts)
The Exorcist.
The Shining.
Rosemary's Baby.
Those are classics.
You know what
I loved about her?
She really made you
feel the terror.
When she was scared
for her life, I was scared, too.
Interesting.
BRASS:
Mr. Zarco...
tell me about you
and Weatherly Adams.
ZARCO:
It was the happiest time
in my life.
I had realized my dream.
I was working in the movies.
Though I was only in
an entry-level position,
Weatherly and I were
already an item.
Just like...
Julia Roberts
and what's his name.
(indistinct cast
and crew chatter)
We were in love.
And then it was
all over in an instant.
(screams)
Oh, God!
(screaming):
Oh, my God!
I was in rehab for six months.
That slime ball Lafoon
convinced me
not to file
a Worker's Compensation claim.
He said that
he'd take care of me.
And you trusted him?
Yes. And then, when the deadline
passed to file my claim,
Vincent offered me two grand,
take it or leave it,
and then he fired my ass.
And I could have lived
with that, but...
But what?
Weatherly...
dumped me.
She felt we
were no longer
compatible.
The truth was, she couldn't
stand to look at me.
She cried when she told me.
Actresses
can do that.
The smell of her skin...
like fresh lemon poppy seed
scones baking in the oven.
Gold flecks that
danced like Valkyries
in the emerald
depths of her eyes.
Her hair-- oh, God...
Her hair...
So you started stalking her.
I brought her gifts
from time to time,
to let her know
that I still loved her.
Is that against the law?
It is if you break in to do it.
They wouldn't let me
in the front door.
So you came in
through the window.
Only this time,
you got caught.
You argued. She told you where
to shove your flowers,
and you thought to yourself,
"You know, do I really need this
aggravation?"
So you killed the bitch.
I think you killed the bitch.
Why would I kill her?
How should I know?
Do I know you?
Listen, Zarco,
you whack job,
you'd better focus!
You focus.
I'm trying to explain to you.
I haven't been near that place
in over a year.
You got the wrong guy.
I don't do that anymore.
I'm in therapy now.
Lots of therapy.
Freudian, Jungian, Gestaltian--
all that crap.
I've let go of my anger.
Have you seen
Catherine around?
No, why?
'Cause I just got
the DNA results
for Weatherly Adams, and
the skin under her nails
and the semen from her
S.A.E., they both belong
to Vaughn Krunty.
Who?
Vaughn Krunty,
aka "Zack Putrid."
Who's that?
The Titan of Terror,
the Sultan of Slash.
He's the movie director.
I just... I found him in CODIS
for a statutory rape charge
in Laughlin when he was 18
and the girl was 16.
Can you believe that?
What's the matter
with you?
Nothing.
Go tell Catherine what you
found, make sure that you pull
all the old evidence out of
storage in case she needs it.
Okay.
(screaming)
(scoffs)
Please.
That looks pretty
stupid, doesn't it?
Well, you could cut out earlier,
maybe go to
a wide exterior shot, you
could carry the scream over
a big flock of birds taking off.
Yeah?
Or... yeah...
Or not.
Or not, just...
Bad idea.
All right, okay.
(Putrid chuckles)
Detective Brass.
(chuckling):
Man, I love that.
Detective Brass.
You're a detective,
and your name is Brass.
I can use that.
That's like a cop
named Officer Copper.
Or a tin horn sheriff named
Sheriff Tin.
You cannot write
that stuff.
Listen, buddy...
Dude, I know
why you're here, okay?
Weatherly and I, yes,
we were knocking boots, man.
So, you acknowledge
having sex with her?
Well, yeah, I just
said I had sex...
Why would I deny it?
Hey, I bang all
my stars.
It builds trust.
It's part of my process.
We found traces of your skin
under her fingernails.
Maybe she wasn't into your
"process," so you raped her.
(chuckles)
You find that funny?
Dude, you gotta see this.
You're gonna love it.
Bring up Double D.
Yeah.
Here goes.
Hi, baby. Hi.
(man laughing)
PUTRID:
Check it out.
Money. Money.
Oh, yeah.
You're a star.
I can't believe this is my life.
Oh, man, oh, man...
Come over here, baby.
(sighs)
Okay.
(both sighing and moaning)
This what you do all day?
Does that look like a woman
being taken against her will?
That still doesn't explain
how your skin got under
her fingernails.
Weatherly was...
how can I put this
delicately?
She was an ass-scratcher, man.
She liked to
scratch my ass.
She wasn't pushing me away, man,
she was pulling me in.
Brass, look at my ass.
Freaking claw marks.
Are you trying to make me
throw up, Mr. Putrid?
(purrs)
(device beeping)
(beeping continues)
(panting)
(motor revs)
(screams)
(laughing):
Oh, my God.
How awesome.
That is so cool.
I can't believe you worked
for Repulsion Pictures.
Well, I did it on a whim.
I was supposed to be an extra,
but then they liked me, so they
gave me this whole featured bit.
I got 600 bucks
for that. What?
What?
I was fresh out of college.
I really needed the money.
I don't get it--
what's the thrill here?
It's always hot babes
with huge breasts
falling out of their
shirts, getting hacked up...
I don't have huge breasts.
Mine are kind of... medium.
But perfect...
...ly adequate.
Better, in fact.
Okay.
Uh, I'm out of here.
Hey, let's watch it again.
ROBBINS:
When I removed the axe,
I noticed that the dermis
along the margin of the wound
showed no vital response,
except in a small area
on both sides of the center
of the track.
The cause of death
was perforation
of the liver,
spleen, and pancreas.
But the injuries
are inconsistent
with the position
of the axe wound.
The axe isn't what killed her.
Exactly. The perforation
was caused
by a sharp, hollow,
cylindrical object
entering through
the lower back,
and then passing upwards
into the organs.
Like a spear,
or a pipe of some kind?
Perhaps.
If the axe was planted
in her back postmortem
to conceal the original
puncture site, then...
we don't have a murder weapon.
JOHNSON:
The only thing I found on the
surveillance tapes was this.
That guy looks familiar.
Oh, that's Vincent Lafoon.
He and his brother
own the place.
Well, here's
where it gets a little weird.
(beeps)
He's trying to make it
look like somebody broke in.
I think he's framing Zarco.
If he owns the place,
he must have known about
the surveillance cameras.
Right? Why would he let
himself get caught on tape?
I don't know,
but according
to Brass' notes, he thought
the system was down.
So, we found
no physical evidence
linking Zarco to the scene.
Vincent knew
he had an easy fall guy.
He's been playing us
the whole time.
(whirring, beeping)
Hey, you're making a big
mistake; you got the wrong dude.
Yeah, a lot of guys
tell me that.
But I didn't do anything.
Why would I kill Weatherly?
She was my company's best asset.
Plus, I liked her.
She was my friend.
That's him.
That's Zarco.
That's your guy.
What happened, Lafoon?
She get too old, so you
killed her for real?
Where's he going?
I don't know. Probably
out for a nice dinner.
You're letting him go?
Are you out of your mind?
We've got nothing
on him.
But I'm the one
getting set up here, me!
Don't let him go-- I'm telling
you-- you'll regret this.
I never touched her.
You know it,
I know it,
and they know it.
You killed her,
and you're going down.
(grunting and groaning)
Can I go now?
Yeah, get out of here while I'm
still in a good mood.
So long, Lafoon.
I hope they tear
you a big one.
(chuckles)
What's up?
You know, in the slasher movies,
when they go after
the dark-haired girl,
she always dies?
Yeah. And the blond
always lives.
Aren't you glad it
wasn't a movie?
(giggles)
I think, um...
I think I am sick of having my
face shoved in death every day.
The murder rate has
gone up every year
since I've been here.
It's totally
out of control, and...
we're not even
slowing them down.
After examining the crime scene,
I determined there were between
200 and 300 milliliters--
that's less than a cup--
of Weatherly's actual
blood outside of her body.
Originally, we had
assumed that the axe
blade had sealed the wound,
that the position of
her body had caused her
to bleed internally.
But if she had been gored first
by another weapon
and then axed, there would have
been a lot more blood.
Right, right. So, I compared
the initial coroner's report
with the last entry
in her weight loss journal--
which was taken no more than
an hour or two before her death.
And guess what?
Her body came up light?
Six pounds light.
That's six pints of blood
at a pound each nowhere
in or around the body.
She was moved.
Hey.
The trace from the
puncture wound came back.
It's zinc, which is electrically
coated onto steel
to make galvanized pipe.
Well, we should go back,
expand the search perimeter,
try to find
the actual murder site.
Okay. I'll get a
hold to Swing.
We're going to
need some help.
Okay.
(vehicle approaching)
I heard you're
holding Vincent Lafoon
on suspicion of murder.
His lawyer
called me.
I'd be surprised.
Yes, the guy is a bit
rough around the edges,
but I don't think
that he, uh...
Hello.
Nick.
Why don't you, uh,
take the offices,
and Ronnie and I will start
in the storage area.
My name is Stanley.
But you call me Stan.
(sighs)
♪ ♪
STOKES:
Hey.
Hey, Nicky,
what do you got?
I've got the hat Lafoon
was wearing
in the surveillance video.
The wear on the strap
indicates
that's it's been set larger...
like it was adjusted
for somebody with a bigger head
or something.
So I'm going to get it back, see
if I can get some prints off it.
Okay, I'll, uh, meet you
back at the lab.
Howdy.
Dickie Jones.
And you are?
Busy.
How about after your
shift, I take you out
for a cup of coffee?
And I could tell you
my whole life story.
No, thanks.
It's just a cup
of coffee, doll.
I'm not asking
you to make love.
(sucks air through teeth)
Not right away, anyway.
You know, I could open up
new worlds to you.
Have you ever had
the back of those thighs
kissed by a man...
who's standing up?
(laughs)
So you find dwarves funny?
(continues laughing)
Sometimes, yeah.
Come on, what do you say?
Is it because
of my receding hairline?
I don't go out with persons
of interest
in an ongoing investigation.
Well, I just think you might
be missing out, Pookie.
Don't call me Pookie.
But you haven't told me
your name.
(softly):
Catherine.
Well, Catherine,
we little people see things
from a different perspective--
things other people might miss.
If you're implying
that you know something
about Weatherly's death,
and you're not giving it up,
that makes you,
at a minimum,
an accessory after the fact,
and that buys a long stretch
for a stubby guy.
I'm just talking, doll-face.
Dickie.
Why don't we leave the nice
woman alone to do her work?
Here's my card.
If there's anything
that you want to tell me
as it pertains
to the case...
uh, call me.
♪ ♪
Hey, Archie,
could you bring up
the surveillance video
from Repulsion Pictures, please?
Yeah, got it over here.
(clears throat)
(computer beeping)
What's the best you can get me
on the face?
(pushes buttons, computer beeps)
He seems to be
deliberately looking away
from the camera.
Take him to the window.
(computer whirs)
Freeze that.
Zoom in on the sleeve.
Does that jacket look a little
small for that guy to you?
Maybe.
I measured the height
of the window.
It's five feet.
How tall is the guy?
Well, he's a head
taller than that window.
Vincent Lafoon's
only five-foot-ten.
This guy's six-foot-two,
six-foot-three, easy.
And a lot rounder.
The only guy that big
in the bunch is Mason.
Catherine, it's Nick.
Listen, the surveillance
video footage is a fake.
I think we got
the wrong brother
in custody.
I think Mason set up Vincent
to set Oliver up.
It's getting complicated.
(thunder rumbling)
Hey, Ronnie, anything?
LAKE:
No.
(thunder rumbles)
This place is creeping me out.
WILLOWS:
It's supposed to.
(rain beating down steadily)
(thunder crackles)
(thunder rumbling)
(squeaking)
(chuckling)
I think we just found
our murder weapon.
Hidden in plain sight.
Catherine?
I've got something else here.
Looks like Weatherly's
missing heel.
(grunts)
(Weatherly whimpers,
attacker grunts)
This is where
she died.
(thunder booms)
(whirring)
WILLOWS:
Ah, damn.
Oh, good.
Auxiliary generator
just kicked in.
And I don't have any service.
Mine's dead, too.
I'm going to get a dolly
for you to move this thing.
Photo it and get it
back to the lab.
Okay.
♪ ♪
Can you help?
Thanks.
Damn it.
Control, this is C-147 Lake
for C13 Willows.
DISPATCH:
Copy, C-147.
Stand by.
C-147, you have C-13. Over.
This is Catherine.
Hey, Catherine,
I left my cell phone
at the studio.
I need to go back
and get it.
Yeah, you'd better.
They're department issue.
And if you lose it,
you replace it.
Does that include the
cost of the contract?
Oh, yeah.
Damn.
I'll see you later.
(engine starts)
(thunder rumbling)
(thunder cracks)
WILLOWS:
We found the pipe
that killed Weatherly.
It's in the print lab
being processed.
She was killed
on the soundstage
and then dragged over.
BRASS:
We've got a warrant out
for Mason Lafoon.
We're looking for him now.
Okay. let me know
what you find out.
(call waiting beeps)
(sighs)
(phone beeps)
What do you want?
DICKIE:
Pookie, it's me, Dickie.
I know.
I've got information I think
you might be interested in.
Okay, shoot.
No. It has to be in person.
Where are you?
I'm at the studio.
I thought there was no phone
transmission from there.
There wasn't.
Now there is.
That's how it is with phones
and electrical storms.
Look, it's urgent.
Get here as soon as you can.
I just came from there.
Why didn't you tell me then,
you annoying little man?
The situation is evolving.
If you're screwing with me,
I will to string you up
and beat you senseless.
I look forward to it.
Just hurry.
BRASS:
That's you, Mason.
All six feet, three inches
of you
impersonating your brother,
which makes you good
for Weatherly's murder.
You did that one,
too, didn't you?
No, no, no.
Nobody killed
Weatherly, okay?
She killed herself.
Oh, really?
What, she axed herself
in the back?
No, you don't understand.
She... she...
It was an accident.
She tripped.
Good night, Weatherly.
Good night, kid.
Yeah, great stuff tonight.
Have a good night.
See you tomorrow.
See you tomorrow. Okay.
Whoa, ah!
(shrieks)
(body thuds)
Call 911!
Wait, let's
think about this.
No, but Stanley...
Mason, she's dead!
This time she's
not coming back.
We've got so many health
and safety violations.
If we report one more
set-related accident--
especially one
resulting in a death--
we will lose our bond,
our liability insurance,
OSHA will shut us down,
we'll get our asses sued
for wrongful death,
and that will be the end
of Repulsion Pictures!
Is that what
you want?
Is that
what you want?!
No!
He... he said
"the show must go on,"
th-that Weatherly...
would have wanted it that...
I don't...
We... we didn't kill anybody.
But you made it
look like a murder,
and then you framed
your brother.
Well, he's been treating me
like crap my entire life.
(chuckles)
Yeah, but for that,
you're going to send him
to jail for the rest
of his life?
This was all...
this was all Stanley's idea.
Do you realize
how much trouble you're in?
Look, Stanley was the one who
wanted to frame Vincent, okay?
All I was supposed
to do was clean up
the accident scene
and pretend to be Vince
and buy the roses
and that was it.
The rest was him.
If you don't believe me,
talk to the dwarf.
Why? What did he have
to do with it?
Dickie saw the whole thing.
...and that will be
the end of Repulsion Pictures.
Is that
what you want?
Is that what
you want?!
No!
MASON:
And he's been trying to shake
down Stanley ever since.
Well, that would explain
the animosity.
(thunder cracks)
(thunder rumbling)
(gasps)
(thunder cracks)
(thunder rumbling)
Control, this is C-13 Willows,
trying to contact C-147 Lake.
DISPATCH:
C-13, Control. Copy.
Stand by.
(thundering)
Hello, Dispatch?
Hello?
DISPATCH:
C-13, Control.
C-147 is not responding.
Okay, thanks. Over and out.
(three rapid beeps)
(two gunshots)
(phone ringing)
(ringing continues)
(ringing stops)
(rings)
(gasping)
(whispering):
Catherine,
it's Ronnie.
I'm stuck
at Repulsion Pictures.
I need backup.
Ronnie... uh,
I'm, I'm coming.
Just... just stay
on the line.
Ronnie?
(line clicks and goes dead)
Ronnie!
Hello?
(three rapid beeps)
Dispatch, this
is C-13 Willows
requesting backup to meet
me at Repulsion Pictures.
(siren wailing)
(thunder cracks)
(screams)
You gotta help me.
I'm shot!
You gotta get us out of here.
It's gonna be okay.
Keep your voice down.
(gasping)
Do you know how many people
I've killed in this place?
Shh!
The irony is exquisite,
but the pain is more formidable,
you know?
I think the pain is preventing
me from enjoying the irony.
Shh!
(softly):
Shut up!
But I...
For the love
of God,
stop talking.
(siren wailing)
(weakly):
Oh, that's not good.
(coughs)
I should really
stop talking
and-and try and relax.
That's good.
Yeah, stop talking.
But I can't stop talking.
I've got that
thing that...
It's a syndrome.
It's a word...
There's a word for it.
Shh-shh-shh!
People have it. It's a syndrome.
I can't stop talking.
STANLEY:
Zack.
(whimpering)
Stanley...
Stanley, don't shoot me again.
I don't want
to die, okay?
You already
shot me twice.
I learned my lesson, okay?
Sir,
I'm a CSI.
Think about what you're doing.
(thundering)
Put down your weapon.
I'm sorry, I don't think
I can do that.
(gun cocks, Putrid sobbing)
(gasps)
Are you okay?
Yeah.
(Zack weeping)
I really loved her.
(thunder rumbling)
(sighs)
(thunder cracks)
ZACK:
I'm editing late,
like I always do,
and I hear a shot.
So, I go outside
and check it out.
(crank clicking)
Stanley!
You gotta help me
hide the dwarf
before the cops
come back.
Dickie was blackmailing us
about Weatherly's accident.
He wants to bring
the whole company down.
But you killed him!
You killed Dickie!
What's it gonna be, Zack?
You gonna help me here or what?!
Next thing you know,
I'm running for my life.
And the nut job is chasing me.
He shoots me,
and then I see the hot...
you.
And all I can think
the whole time is,
"Man, this is great.
I could use this stuff."
I mean, this is life
imitating art imitating life.
You are so beautiful.
You are... Your, your
face is so expressive.
It-it emotes.
You do terror so good.
I wasn't acting.
I know.
I'll see you.
Well, hey, listen.
If you ever get tired of
fighting crime, you know,
there's always a future for
you in the horror business.
I mean, I'll
take you there.
Thanks, but I like
what I'm doing.
Oh, hey,
the offer's still good.
Okay, thanks.
No, I'm serious.
I could build an entire
franchise around you.
Bye.
Seriously.
Give me a call.
(man screams, maniacal laughter)
(woman screams)
(horror movie climax music
playing)
(maniacal laughter)
(woman screaming)
(horror movie climax music
grows louder)
(door hinges creaking)
(screaming and maniacal
laughter grow louder)
That is impressive.
As the woman's throat
is being slashed,
you can actually see the entire
transverse view of the trachea.
That's all you've got to say?
I believe I can see
the epiglottis.
Epiglottis?
What about the pathos?
I mean...
what about the humanity?
This may be Weatherly's
finest performance.
Oh, just watch
the movie.