♪ ♪
(sighs heavily)
WILLOWS: That's quite a kit
you got there, Ray.
(chuckles)
Well, it's my first
official shift.
I want to be
prepared.
Your training coordinator said
that you were very thorough.
Add this to
your checklist--
whenever you're on call, have
a pen and paper near your bed,
along with a
change of clothes,
a ball cap,
bottled water,
sunblock, and make sure
you got a Thomas Guide
inside your vehicle, in
case your GPS crashes.
You don't want
your evidence degrading
as you're scrambling
to get your act together.
Got it.
Hey.
WILLOWS:
Ready to roll?
STOKES:
Oh, yeah.
Dr. Langston,
welcome aboard.
Thank you.
406 on the east side.
Ray's with you.
Okay.
WILLOWS:
Enjoy.
406-- burglary.
Yeah, a little
bread and butter crime'll be
the perfect thing
to get your feet wet.
Come on.
You know
you're not required
to wear a tie unless
you're in court, right?
Yes, I know.
Something wrong
with wearing a tie?
No, no.
STOKES:
What's going on, Akers?
Owner got home from work
an hour ago,
found the window smashed.
His wife's jewelry is gone,
along with a laptop
and his watch.
Where's the wife?
Out of town with their daughter.
(explosion thunders)
The husband's inside.
(car alarms blare
in distance)
What the hell was that?
You'll know
as soon as I do.
Why don't you, uh,
go ahead inside
and get started on
the overalls, yeah?
DISPATCHER (over radio):
Repeat the 20 on the 445 call.
Dispatch,
this is Charlie 0-5 Stokes.
(sirens wailing
in distance)
MAN:
No, no, there's
nothing to worry about.
I'm fine.
Okay.
I do,
I feel violated,
but the police are
taking care of everything.
That fireball was
a private residence
near Sunrise Mountain.
Arson-Explosives is
already on the way.
Are we on our
way there, too?
Oh, yeah,
we'll be done with this
before the fire's even out.
Just, uh,
print the point of entry
and collect
everything else.
MAN:
I love you, too, honey.
Sir, you want to show me
where those stolen items
were taken from?
I got to go.
Right this way.
(sighs)
My laptop was right here,
my watch right there,
and my wife's jewelry box--
they completely
cleaned that out.
They didn't even bother
to ransack the place.
Just went straight
for the good stuff.
And my wife's grandmother's
ring was in there,
her mother's cameo.
They really cleaned
the thing out.
Write down everything
that was stolen
and fax that
form back to us.
Be sure and keep a copy
for your insurance, okay?
Okay.
What'd you do,
try to use all of 'em?
In the field, you really
only need three powders:
black, magnetic,
and dragon's blood.
If you can't get a print
off one of those,
you're better off just taking it
back to the lab.
It just kept breaking up.
All right.
Doorknob's already toast;
let's work on the glass.
Now, don't do this if
you ever need touch DNA,
but in a pinch...
The water vapor
from your breath
will adhere to the salt
and lipids in a latent print.
It revitalizes it.
(exhales)
Then you take a little dust--
just a little.
Gently.
It's all in the wrist.
A colleague of mine once told me
if I found myself
in this part of town,
I should drive very fast.
Well, that's pretty good advice.
We get about half a dozen calls
out here a week.
There is a little
no-tell motel
around here somewhere.
We found a corpse
underneath a bed.
It'd been there
for about four days.
(chuckles)
People just went
right on using the room
till it was too ripe
to ignore.
Did you catch
the guy who did it?
Yeah, yeah, we did eventually.
Then that's a good story.
Dispatch,
Charlie 0-5 Stokes
and Charlie 0-8 Langston,
reporting
402-419 Sunrise Mountain.
How's the first day of school
going, Professor?
I'll, uh, tell
you at recess.
The arson investigator
ran dogs through the scene.
They didn't find
any accelerant.
STOKES:
Doesn't rule out arson.
What's with the construction
equipment out front?
Were the owners
remodeling or something?
Well, the place belongs
to Don and Paulla Kingsley.
They live here alone.
I got a call out
to both of them.
I bet only one of them
calls me back.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
ECKLIE:
So where'd it all go?
I can't imagine Grissom
being entirely happy
without his irradiated
fetal pig.
He asked me
to send a couple things
to the research station
in Costa Rica, and...
the rest is just going
into storage at his place.
Hmm, so he didn't sell
his home?
A condo in Vegas?
That's 50 cents on the
dollar at this point.
Yeah, tell me about it.
Well, you got a blank canvas.
You're senior supervisor.
It's your office now.
Oh, I like the one I have.
Catherine,
if you don't want it, fine.
But you can't leave it empty,
all right?
We don't have the space
for a shrine.
Paulla Kingsley?
It's gone.
It's all gone.
Paulla Kingsley?
I'm Mrs. Kingsley's
assistant Carla Banks.
I didn't want her
to drive herself.
I need Don.
W-Where's Don?
We're not sure, ma'am.
He's, he's not--
Was he inside?
We found
someone inside.
It's going to
take a while
before we find
out who that is.
Mrs. Kingsley, I'm Detective
Jim Brass, Las Vegas Police.
Do you mind if I
ask you a question?
According to the
fire department,
this isn't their
first time out here.
You called 911
about six weeks ago
when your husband overdosed
on secobarbital.
Is that right?
(sobbing):
Oh, my God.
Don.
This looks like it was
the laundry room.
Everything's
displaced outward...
from this point.
Blast originated here.
Sooting indicates
that the water heater inlet
was unhooked during the fire.
Maybe it was torn off
by the blast.
If that were the case,
these threads
would be stripped
and they're not.
That's the natural gas line
hookup right there.
See if that valve's
open or closed
for me, would you?
It's open.
If at first
you don't succeed...
(hissing)
BRASS: So would you say
that Don Kingsley
was having
emotional problems?
Yeah, Mr. Kingsley
was depressed.
They'd been having
some difficulties.
What kind of difficulties?
Financial.
Where was Mrs. Kingsley
last night?
At the gym.
Buff &amp;amp;amp; Tuff Fitness Center.
Well, the fire started
just after midnight.
Does she usually work
out that late?
No. She owns the franchise.
Six locations across Vegas.
Open 24/7.
So we're going to
need the name
of Mr. Kingsley's dentist.
Can you help me with that?
Yeah, sure.
LANGSTON:
Aren't we required to
run DNA on the victim?
No. We're only required
to confirm I.D.
Fires sometimes destroy
known exemplars.
Dental records are
just quicker.
Boy, I bet you've never seen
one of those
in the hospital
before, huh?
Once.
He was still screaming.
PHILLIPS:
Okay, we're ready.
Now remember,
lift with your legs.
On three.
One, two, three.
(flesh crackling, body thuds)
(coughs)
Here you go.
I'll take that.
(coughs)
PHILLIPS:
You okay?
I'm fine.
Again?
Let's go.
One, two, three.
Whoa, the bones
feel... crumbly.
Like they were...
(groans) shattered.
That's what happens when
they're in the oven too long.
Uh...
What should we do about that?
It could have trace
from the body?
Yes, sir.
It's evidence?
Do you have a pair of scissors
I could borrow?
Thanks.
Excuse me.
David Hodges, right?
I need to, um...
You need to log that in
with the evidence clerk first.
And then he will
distribute it
to the appropriate lab.
Right-- the evidence
clerk isn't there.
Yeah, he never is.
And that's your problem.
Okay... fine.
So, now, I'll do his job.
(Hodges clears throat)
May I help you?
Just check it in.
Fill out this form.
Well, you certainly
have a doctor's handwriting.
Next time, print.
There you are, Professor.
Nick stuck me
with your 406.
Doesn't get you off of it.
I'll meet you in the A.V. Lab.
The laptop on the
stolen property list
has a cell phone
card in it with G.P.S.
That means we can track it.
Yeah, well, we are in luck.
This laptop's on
a mesh network right now.
You bought my book.
Yeah.
Did you read it?
Guess that makes you
one of the few.
(computer beeps)
ARCHIE:
I got an address.
If you're looking for drugs,
you're not going to find any.
My son's not into that stuff.
Right, Alex?
ADAMS: We're not looking
for drugs, sir.
(Wi-Fi detector beeping)
Mr. Palento, what's back here?
His bedroom.
(detector beeping faster)
(beeping rapidly,
then stops)
Yes, it's on the list.
Where'd it come from?
I don't know;
I found it.
Where?
I can't remember exactly.
Oh.
Alex, if you're
screwing with me,
you're in serious trouble.
You find these things, too?
Some kids in the neighborhood.
They gave them to me.
Like who?
I can't remember.
Your son could easily
be going out at night
and having other people come
in without your knowledge.
No, no, no, I keep that
alley gate locked.
He doesn't have a key.
Where'd you get that stuff?
What difference does it make?
That's not an answer!
LANGSTON:
Hey.
That's not necessary.
Oh, you don't approve?
As a matter of fact, I don't.
Do you have any idea
what it's like
to be a single father
in this town?
I got two friends who had
their kids O.D. on them.
Don't you tell me
how to handle my son.
We wouldn't
dream of it, sir.
ADAMS: I apologize
if we overstepped.
MR. PALENTO:
Come on.
In the house.
I'm not done...
(door closes)
What, it's not our job
to protect him?
His father let us in here
without a warrant,
and he wasn't
breaking any laws.
We're here to
collect evidence.
We're not social workers.
You see the "Ma..."?
My guess is the glass
came from a Mason jar.
My wife uses them
to make fruit preserves.
Oh, well, I doubt this guy
was canning explosive peaches.
I hope I haven't missed
all the fun stuff.
Hello, Doctor.
My name is--
Ray Langston, I know.
Albert Robbins.
Always happy to meet
a fellow sawbones.
You've already met
Don Kingsley.
And that is shrapnel
from the explosion.
And what's this
yellow residue?
That's not my department.
I sent a sample to Hodges.
He's in Trace.
We've met.
Glass shards are only
in his feet and lower legs.
I was just about to
dissect his trachea.
Care to do the honors?
It's been a while since I cut.
Eh, it's like
destroying a bicycle--
come on.
Oh... no soot.
This man wasn't breathing
while the fire was burning.
So, he croaked before he cooked.
Well, that would
explain the calvarium.
It's cracked along
the sutures.
Is that from the fire?
Well, it gets hot enough
to boil a brain,
the, uh, steam
has to get out somehow.
(sizzling)
That's not what
I was going to show you.
Subdural hematoma.
ROBBINS:
Mm-hmm.
So, he was clocked
before he croaked and cooked.
Congratulations, Ray.
Your first arson
has become your first homicide.
Somebody could've
hit him with this.
Yeah, that or just about
anything else in here
that didn't get burned up
or washed away.
Okay, we should bag everything
that might have been used
as a weapon or a remote
or a delayed ignition source.
Since it's pretty obvious
the arsonist wasn't in here
when this place went up.
All right.
Piece of cake.
Excuse me, sir?
You, uh, mind if I ask
what you're doing here?
Documenting my losses.
Your losses?
I'm Josh Barston.
The Kingsleys' contractor.
All that gear is mine.
Luckily, it's insured.
Did you do all
the construction here?
Yep.
Everything's up to code.
I got all the permits.
Well, that's good, 'cause
I'm going to need copies
of all your plans and
construction photos.
As well as
contact information
for you and your crew,
if you don't mind.
Sure, whatever you want.
♪ ♪
That's a lot
of concentration
for a property crime.
I think it just paid off.
This is
a pawn shop receipt
for an antique cameo
and a diamond ring--
the only two items left missing.
Our suspect is, what,
14 years old?
He didn't pawn these things
by himself.
WILLOWS: You sure you don't
want to give this a shot?
LANGSTON: I'd prefer
to watch you.
Magnetic powder works best
on porous surfaces,
because it doesn't smear.
I hear it's all
in the wrist.
WILLOWS: Actually, I think it's
in the fingers, but that's me.
Nice!
Mm! The scanner's
behind us.
Diane Palento?
The kid's mother.
Priors for shoplifting and...
ah, narcotics possession.
ADAMS: That's your mother
pawning stolen property.
You didn't get
that stuff
from the
neighborhood kids.
Your mother gave it to you,
didn't she, Alex?
She didn't steal it.
She bought it
from a garage sale.
You've been seeing her?
Taking presents from her
and lying to me about it?
So what?
You lied to me.
Said that she moved
to New York.
She didn't love me anymore.
I did it to
protect...
It's not true!
I did it to protect you, Alex.
Your mother
has problems,
(over speaker): and she's not
doing anything to help herself!
Yes, she is.
Yes, she is!
ALEX: She's getting her
act together, okay?
Saving up for a
nice apartment
so she and I can
live together.
You are not going anywhere
except juvenile hall,
because receiving stolen
property-- that's a crime.
Stealing is a
bigger crime.
I know you're not
a thief, Alex.
You're a good kid.
You made some
bad decisions.
I know you two
love each other,
but your mom made some
bad decisions, too,
and I can't help her
unless you help me.
That duffel bag
is hers, isn't it?
When does she come around?
She sleeps there
at night.
She stays
on the floor.
Look, it's just
for a while, okay?
She's gonna get her own place.
We're gonna live together.
ADAMS:
It won't be much
of a stakeout.
I doubt we'll have
to set up on her
more than one night.
She'll show up.
Bad parents crave
unconditional love.
Well, I know I do.
I'll put a couple guys on it.
I really think you broke
through to him.
I was just trying to get him
to give up his mother.
Thanks for
the uni's, Captain.
Sure thing,
no problem.
STOKES:
Hey, Jim.
I got the crispy critter's
cell phone records.
And get this--
the wife's assistant
called 23 times in the 48 hours
prior to his death.
BRASS:
Sounds like more
than a working relationship.
Yeah, I'd say so.
You're gonna love
the voice mails she left him.
(dance music playing)
Good.
That's impressive, Carla.
So, tell me,
where were you
on the night of the fire?
I was here working.
You don't have
to take my word for it.
There's surveillance
all over this place.
No, I'm not going to take your
word for it-- check this out.
CARLA:
Don, I'm standing
outside your house,
and once again, you're not here.
I warned you not to pull
another no-show,
you gutless son of a bitch.
I want to see you tonight.
Okay, I was at Don's house last
night a little before 11:00,
but I left
right after that.
What were you doing
at my house last night?
Trying to get the 20 Gs
your husband owed me.
What are you talking about?
You know those
herbal supplements he tried
to get you to sell here?
Yeah, the ones
that give you diarrhea?
I fronted him
the money for that.
He said it might be
a good way for us
to earn some money on the side,
and like an idiot,
I believed him.
Did you sleep with him?
I don't sleep with losers.
Don wasn't a loser.
Come on, Paulla.
He was a nice guy...
Complete airhead.
You outgrew him
years ago.
You just couldn't admit it.
BRASS:
Hey, hey.
L-L-Ladies, ladies...
Bitch!
What's wrong with you?
Let's go down to
the police station.
We can make your statements
on record, okay?
I'll give
you a ride.
A power cord to nowhere.
I don't
remember seeing
any appliances
missing their cords.
Greg, will you come
take a look at this, please?
We found residue like
that on glass shards
taken out of Don
Kingsley's body.
SANDERS:
Looks like galvanized metal.
Maybe a piece of roof flashing.
Did you I.D. the residue
on the glass?
Hodges is working on it, I hope.
SANDERS:
Grid 13.
Well, we found it
about seven feet
from the origin.
These marks look like the result
of an electrical arc.
And in a room filled with gas,
an arc is as good as a spark.
Okay.
But there's got to be more
to a timed detonator than this.
I agree.
Looks like we're
working a double.
HODGES:
The residue on the metal disc
is indeed what was found
on the glass shards.
Zea mays.
Well, my botany's
a little rusty, but I'd say...
corn.
I call it maize.
Are you trying to impress me?
Did I?
So, we've got
corn, a Mason jar,
a piece of metal
roof flashing
and an electrical cord.
How do you make a
detonator out of that?
I don't know.
You don't know.
That's not your reputation,
Mr. Hodges.
(murmuring)
I'm telling you, every time
I turn around,
one of these uni's
is giving us
the stink eye.
Come on now,
you're imagining that.
No, I'm not.
That's what happens when you
make a lab geek undersheriff.
Oh, that job is
punishment enough.
I actually feel sorry
for Ecklie.
(laughing)
You like burned toast, Ray?
Occasionally, but, uh...
I've seen enough charcoal
for one day.
Oh, man.
WILLOWS:
What?
Look at that.
You see that?
Yeah, I do.
(all groaning)
See that?
No wonder why Grissom
loves this place.
(all groaning)
WILLOWS:
You didn't just
do that, did you?
What?
(laughing):
Ew!
Check, please.
It's on me.
The new guy pays, right?
Only if he's smart.
Thank you.
SANDERS:
It's my shift
on the Palento stakeout.
You coming?
Yes.
Oh, hey, Ray, I'll, uh,
I'll give you a lift.
Okay, thanks.
So, Nicky, Mr. Eater-of-Flies...
Hmm.
(sighs)
...I want you to have
Grissom's office.
I thought you were
gonna use it.
I hate moving.
I don't know about that.
Doesn't really feel right.
Well, it may not
for a while, but...
Make it your own.
(doorbells jingle)
Maybe she won't show up.
Kind of sounds like
you're hoping she won't.
She's not helping her son.
Maybe not.
But...
he's making choices here, too.
Yes, he is.
Mommy's home.
We're moving now.
LVPD. Hold it right there.
Leave me alone!
Get her!
Ray?
No! No!
Let me see my kid!
ADAMS: Diane Palento,
you're under arrest.
Let me...
Let me see my kid!
Alex! Alex!
Don't take her!
It was me!
I took that stuff!
Don't take her!
Alex, baby!
Get off her!
I'm coming back.
I love you, Mom.
I love you, Alex!
(sobbing)
I love you!
♪ ♪
(machinery beeping,
whirring quietly)
What is this?
Corn, glass jar,
metal disk--
a chance to salvage
your reputation.
(engine sputters)
(engine starts)
What the hell is this?
A corn meal bomb.
Apparently, it's an old
military trick.
As the corn meal
absorbs the water, it expands,
pushing up the metal disc.
But the process is pretty slow,
which gives you time
to fill the room with gas
and leave.
Eventually, the metal disc
touches the two
exposed wires and...
An explosion
and an alibi.
All in one.
Okay...
I'm impressed.
I had to cut the
metal disc by hand
to get it to fit
in the Mason jar,
which means the
suspect did, too.
I think we should go
back through the evidence
from the Kingsley garage
and do tool mark comparisons
on anything that could have
been used to cut the disc.
Well, that can take
a couple of weeks,
assuming the tool's
even there.
And even if it is there,
you still have
to connect it directly
to a suspect.
Well, one step
at a time, right?
Right.
Let's see what Archie
has for us.
Hey, man,
I got your text.
What's going on?
Hey. Check this out.
This is earlier,
the day of the murder.
STOKES: Where did
you get this?
Brass pulled it
from Paulla Kingsley's gym.
JOHNSON:
10:07.
That's about two hours
before the fire.
You know what that means...
Yeah, it means he had motive,
and time to set the detonator.
It's always sad
when a husband gets in the way
of his wife's
blossoming relationship
with their contractor, hmm?
It was strictly platonic.
I was in crisis,
and Josh was a good listener.
Oh, I'm sure he was.
I'm sure he listened
to you complain
about your
financial situation,
and what a loser
your airhead husband is.
So, whose idea was it
to kill Don?
Was it yours or Josh's?
What are you saying, that
Josh killed my husband?
Oh, my God.
I'm going to be sick.
We were in love.
She was going to leave him,
so we could be together.
She lost her nerve.
PAULLA: I told Josh
that I couldn't leave Don.
That I...
That I still loved him
despite his flaws.
JOSH:
That loser.
He was taking her down with him.
I realized there was only
one way to save her.
So I built the detonator.
And after I took her to work,
I took care of the problem.
Told Don there was a problem
with the gas line
in the garage.
(chuckles)
Check out the pilot light.
(gas hissing)
He was holding her hostage.
(inhales deeply)
And I set her free.
(exhales)
Brass just closed
your arson-murder.
Contractor confessed.
Nice work.
Thanks.
I thought
that this one was closed, too.
It is.
Then why are you wasting
the taxpayers' money?
I'm kidding.
(wry laugh)
Um...
a rock...
Mm-hmm.
...through a window.
Don't you think Diane Palento
was a little too street smart
to make that much noise
breaking in?
The owner came home,
said he...
discovered he had been robbed.
So why was his laptop
still in the house?
Wouldn't that have been
at work with him?
And look-- his watch.
Most guys take their watches off
to shower, or to...
to swim,
to, uh...
Have sex.
Except his wife was out of town
that weekend.
So, I checked his web history.
Take a look at this.
"Diamond."
AKA Diane Palento.
Very classy.
The husband hires himself
a hooker,
and after, when he passes out
or takes a shower,
she rips him off.
He might be able to explain away
the laptop and the watch,
but not his wife's jewelry.
I think he decided to stage a...
fake break-in.
(rubbing hands together)
Shall we go bust him now?
The only thing that
we could get him for
is filing a false report.
It's a misdemeanor, and the
D.A. would never prosecute,
so, you got to just
return the property
and call it a day.
A good day.
My grandfather gave this
to my grandmother
in McKeesport, Pennsylvania,
in 1914.
Never thought that
I'd see it again.
I can't
thank you enough.
Tell him how
you lost it.
What, does that matter?
Tell him.
That's not really
necessary, ma'am.
Would you...?
Can we please
just go?
Don't you touch me,
you diseased pervert.
Oh, come on, I made
a mistake, honey.
A mistake? You brought
a whore into our bedroom,
and you had disgusting sex
with her on my bed.
No, I did not have
disgusting sex-- I told you--
I got drunk and passed out,
because subconsciously,
honey, I could not
go through with it.
Well, subconsciously,
I can't stay married
to a degenerate sleazeball.
I've never done anything
like this before.
I've never done
anything like...
How can I even trust you?
Come on! I didn't even
get to do anything.
Oh, so now
you're disappointed
you didn't get
to foul our sheets...
Alex, listen,
I know you feel as if
you betrayed your mother,
but believe me,
it may be the best thing
that ever happened to her.
Your mother's going
to need your help.
You may be the
only person
that she'll listen to.
I know it's
not a fair thing
to ask of a
14-year-old kid,
but you've got to
be strong for her.
Try to get her to go
to a rehab program.
I can get you a list
of places, if you like.
You sure you're
okay with this?
You can still
change your mind.
ADAMS:
No, you can't.
I said I'd kill for an office,
and I meant it.
Even a shared one.
Wow. This is a very
classy move, Nick.
Very classy.
Seriously.
Well, you're welcome.
There's good energy in here.
It'll be nice to share it.
This belongs here.
♪ ♪
We're off the clock.
I know.
I'll see you tomorrow.