(weakly):
Help...
(louder):
Help.
I need, I
need... brains.
Brains.
I smell your brains.
(laughs)
RILEY:
Halloween's tomorrow, Nick.
Yeah, in Vegas, we
celebrate all week.
Yeah, we're just
getting some coffee.
We'll be there
in five.
We need to process
another 407.
Liquor store,
Landston and Fifth.
Let me guess:
robbed by a cop?
Yeah, third one
tonight.
Great costumes.
That's what I wore
last year.
Me, too.
(door bells jingle)
Hey!
Stop that guy!
That cop
just robbed me!
(glass bottles clattering)
Stop!
Police! Stop!
(panting)
(gunfire,
bullets ricocheting)
Down! Down!
(glass shattering)
(grunts)
He's going inside.
I'm going after him!
What?
You go around front.
Call for help!
Are you sure?
Go!
(beep)
Control, CSI Adams.
I got a 443 in the alley behind
the liquor store on Industrial.
Shots fired.
I repeat: shots fired.
Suspect is wearing
a blue police uniform.
CSI Stokes is in foot pursuit.
Hey!
(gunfire blasting)
(steam hissing)
(panting)
(grunting)
That's it!
That's it! It's over!
Stay down.
Come on, man. Don't.
(screaming)
(crash)
(sirens approaching)
Guy's robbed
his last liquor store.
He's got company.
(indistinct radio chatter)
GRISSOM:
You know, Nick. You're lucky
you're not in here, too.
STOKES:
Understood.
Well...
I guess a broken mirror
does bring bad luck.
Guy died for small bills,
beef jerky and a porno.
ADAMS:
Hard up, hungry
and dumb.
It's no way to go
through life.
GRISSOM:
Yeah, well, at least
he helped us find
this poor dead girl.
Dumpster belongs
to the glass
and mirror place.
Patrol company said
the owner closed up at 5:00.
She smells fresh.
Well, this was
a dark alley.
Maybe she was
a working girl.
Picked up a john
with a bad temper.
Yeah.
Trick or treat.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
♪ ♪
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa. Hold it.
Take a look at this.
STOKES:
Is that a tattoo?
A fish.
It's temporary ink.
Could be a transfer or a stamp
from a club.
Back in St. Louis,
Vice always kept
a database of club stamps.
Our guys will know
where it came from.
Maybe if we can
figure out
where she was,
it will lead us
to who she is.
(dance music blaring)
I hate Halloween.
Looks like a bunch
of adults
going as teenagers
this year.
Hey!
She's underage.
Touch her again,
you're going to jail.
Whatever.
Mom!
What do you think
you're doing here?
Dancing.
What does it look like?
Where's the I.D.?
Want a urine
sample, too?
Draw my blood?
Jasmine Davidov?
Don't the police have
anything better to do
than chase me down?
You bet we do,
Lindsey.
A girl your age
was here last night.
She was murdered.
Just take her home.
You moonlighting
as a bouncer now?
When you have kids, you can
talk to me about it then.
Well, we won't be talking
soon then.
Vic was definitely working
the VIP section.
She wasn't wearing
a wristband.
She must have been juiced in
through the back.
You only get a wristband if you
pay the cover at the front.
Okay, next.
There you go.
Owner's over there.
Finish puberty
somewhere else.
Me and Mr. Big here
need to talk.
See you in a bit, ladies.
She was found
in a Dumpster
about two blocks
from here.
She was wearing one of
your slut-of-the week
stamps on her thigh.
Recognize her?
No.
But I don't get a good look
at every girl
who walks in through the door.
Anything else I can
help you with?
Yeah, as a matter
of fact, there is.
I found my underage daughter
on your dance floor.
I could card
everyone
in the place right now
and shut you down.
If your daughter
got in here,
she was using a fake I.D.
That's not poor club management.
It's poor parenting.
You don't want
to blame yourself,
so you slap
a fine on me.
A fine is going to be
the least of your worries.
You know, it's one thing
when kids dress up
as a cop on Halloween,
but when grown-ups do it--
it never ends well.
Mm-mm.
Got an I.D. yet?
Gun's unregistered.
I dusted it.
Nothing but smudges.
So, how did Rocky the Flying
Squirrel get his uniform?
The patch is a Reno city seal,
but anybody can get one
of those at a swap meet.
Hand me the ALS, will you?
What?
It's just
been a while
since I've seen you
use one of those.
Just like riding
a bicycle.
What, you don't want
to share your toys?
Please.
Mm.
(beep, whirring)
This is the pocket
where the cops keep their pens.
And they're always forgetting
to retract the points.
You know, I don't think
this is a costume.
Okay, but real cops
don't wear prom shoes, man.
So everything's fake
except the uniform.
Which means, somewhere
a real cop was wearing it.
Well, I'll
contact Reno.
See if anybody was down here
on official business.
SANDERS:
Sexy kitty, sexy nurse,
sexy hula dancer,
guy dressed
like pimp.
These guys have
no imagination.
Club's using monochromatic
daylight cameras at night.
And they're all pointed
somewhere pretty much useless.
Except for the front door.
Now we don't have
our girl arriving.
Consistent with her
not having wristband.
Right.
But here she is leaving.
She starts out
pretty upset.
That's the club
owner, Craig Hess.
Instant attitude adjustment.
This is approximately
four hours
before we found her.
She's a VIP,
and they bounced her?
What did that guy
say to her?
(camera shutter clicking)
♪ ♪
(Willows speaking, muffled)
(muffled, distant):
Does it look that way
to you, Gil?
(Willows speaks
indistinctly)
Did you hear
anything I said?
(clearly): The wounds
from the glass...
they appear to be superficial?
Yeah.
No vital response
in the tissue.
Postmortem.
(sighs)
You getting any sleep?
Me, neither.
What do you hear
from Sara?
I don't know where she is.
She's got needle marks
in both arms.
No scar tissue.
This has to be recent.
Drug users
don't usually start off
shooting it.
Snort it or smoke it first.
White powder in the nose,
most likely cocaine.
Hives.
Histamine reaction,
maybe from the drugs?
Wonder if she told her parents
she was just going dancing
and they
believed her.
(knocking)
Grissom, got something for you.
Your female victim
popped up
in the Homeland Security
database.
Angela Marie Carlos.
19, going
to college
in Salt Lake City--
from Cali, Colombia.
She's here on
a student visa?
Yeah, but it gets
even better.
Father is Juan Ramon Carlos.
He's on a lot
of Top 10 lists:
FBI, CIA, DEA.
He's a major drug lord.
So maybe somebody was trying
to get to him through her.
What do we know
about his Vegas connections?
Besides every
drug dealer in town?
He's got a sister
in Henderson.
I'm on my way
to make the notification.
I'd like to go.
I was there
the day she was born.
That day
and every day since,
I prayed to God
to protect her.
But I think our family
has tried his patience too long.
Miss Carlos,
I know there are no words
that could possibly make this
easier to bear,
but maybe helping us
find who took her away
might bring you some comfort.
When was the last time
that you saw Angela?
Two months ago. (sniffles)
When she went
to college in Utah.
Until then,
she was living with me.
(sniffles)
Going to school here.
Why Utah?
Because it's
not Las Vegas.
She's like her mother.
She likes to party.
Juan did not approve.
Did you know
that she was
back in town?
No.
Did she have many friends?
Money buys you a lot of people,
but... but not a lot of friends.
Except for one
girl, Sylvie.
They went
to high school together.
They were
like sisters.
They would talk all
night on the phone...
Sleepovers and shopping and...
You can...
you can love someone
with your heart and your soul,
but you can't protect them
24 hours a day.
You can catch
whoever did this,
but it doesn't matter.
Juan will never forgive me.
(sighs)
STOKES: So why'd you
bring your uniform to Vegas?
BRADY:
I brought it because I
was testifying in a case.
Held over a couple
days for cross.
Thanks.
Yeah.
So I thought I'd
see the sights.
What happened
to your uniform?
Well, I'm walking
through the casino
just minding my own...
Hot girl comes up,
wants to buy me a drink.
You know the type.
Donut Dolly.
Wanted to wear
my uniform, use all the tools.
You're a bad cop.
(Brady chuckling)
You've been a bad boy,
and I'm really gonna punish you.
Yeah, you like that, don't you?
(both laughing)
I've been a
bad officer.
I had to send my uniform out
to the hotel cleaners.
That's smart.
Juries do find you more credible
when you're not reeking
of champagne.
So, when I didn't
get it back,
I called housekeeping.
They said they hung it
on the door.
Okay.
What hotel?
Palermo.
Room 914.
I am gonna get hell
from my department.
Mm-hmm.
But it was worth it.
See what I can do,
Casanova.
If Angela's in trouble,
I'm talking to her
before I'm talking to you.
Well, she's more
than in trouble.
She's dead.
(sighs)
Were you with her
the night before last?
Ange said Salt Lake
was lame for Halloween
and she was road-tripping it
to Vegas.
We changed
at my place.
Then Ange wanted to go
get some party supplies.
Party supplies?
I had friends
who could get us
into the Dark Water Bar.
Ange said she could take it
from there.
She said the owner was a friend
of her family.
(dance music playing, laughter)
Here's to us.
You trying to
get me killed?
Come on.
Just help me out.
Whatever you want,
I'll give you.
What I want
is you out.
Get your hands
off me.
So, did you leave with her?
No.
I hooked up with this guy.
Texted her to meet up
with us at some party.
Weren't you worried
about what might happen to her?
Nobody touches Angela.
Now what?
You lied.
It means I like you.
We have a witness...
and surveillance footage.
Angela Carlos was here
the night she died,
and you talked to her.
Okay.
Somebody who's not
working here anymore
let her in through the back.
As soon as I saw she was
in the club, I sent her out
through the front.
So, you do know her?
Did I say that?
I think you do business
with her father.
And that kind
of business
can put you out of business.
Who is her father?
It's clear
on the video
that whatever you said to her
got her to leave.
What was it?
Rendezvous at your place,
drugs for sex?
'Cause it wouldn't
be the first time.
Arrested for statutory rape,
assault, and drug charges
with a 17-year-old girl.
I was 21 years old.
Those charges were dropped.
Girl wants to party,
get a little bit rough--
it's a date.
She doesn't get flowers
in the morning--
it's rape.
Look, that's it.
I'm done talking to you.
PHILLIPS:
There's still something
in this wound.
Glass.
It's different from the other
shards in the dumpster.
What do you notice
about the wound?
It's red,
which suggests
a vital response
to the incision.
Appears to be
perimortem.
Go for it.
I'll get it to Trace.
David.
Gil.
You've got something
I've never seen before.
Said the chorus girl
to the bishop.
GRISSOM:
No separation
between the blood cells
and the serum.
Her blood's hemolyzed.
You usually only see that
when the body
is in advanced decomp.
An unknown chemical imbalance
triggered a pressure change
in the red blood cells,
which caused them to rupture.
What could cause this?
Number of things.
Autoimmune hemolytic anemia.
Certain blood diseases.
Transfusion reaction.
Even chemical
warfare agents
like sarin or ricin.
Worth the trip, wasn't it?
Hives associated
with any of those?
Most of them.
I've requested her
medical records, tox and DNA,
and I'm waiting on those
before I certify C.O.D.
Let me know.
I will.
And, uh,
yes, it was worth the trip.
♪ ♪
(computer beeps)
(computer chirps)
(beep)
(trilling)
Please tell me you got a hit off
my Dumpster-diver's print.
Yeah, I'm running them now.
Hey, my timing's perfect.
Isn't it always?
"Thomas Taylor,
Bakersfield, California."
Ooh, he's an angry guy.
Kind of like
two assaults,
B&amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;E, DUI...
Add DOA to the list.
(footsteps approaching)
Oh.
(beep)
You're supposed
to be at home.
That's what being
grounded means.
I wasn't doing
anything wrong.
I wasn't even drinking.
Breathalyzer results.
I made the cop
who drove me home test me.
I know I shouldn't have
been using a fake I.D.,
and I'm sorry.
But you overreacted.
I'll be the judge of that.
I know you're dealing
with a lot right now,
but you don't have
to worry about me.
Thanks... but I will.
And you're still grounded.
(beep)
Oh, hey.
Gil.
So, I scored two tickets
to this Alec Knight lecture.
He's, of course you know,
challenging the Russian claim
that the Romanov remains found
in Ekaterinburg are authentic.
Open bar.
Are you asking me out?
Is that a yes?
Do you have the results
of the white powder
that we found
in Angela Carlos' nose?
Yes. It wasn't cocaine.
Here, take a look.
(clears throat)
HODGES:
It's atropine.
It's a stimulant often used
to cut coke or methamphetamine.
But her tox report came
back negative for both.
And atropine has a
paradoxical reaction
as a tranquilizer
used on fish and other animals.
So, how did it get in her nose?
So, we're still on
for that lecture, right?
Gil?
I checked with the Palermo.
Your Reno cop has a Tower room.
Takes a special room key
to access those elevators.
So, if the dead guy
swiped his uniform,
he was either a guest
or an employee.
We checked. He doesn't work
there, and he wasn't registered.
What is a lowlife
from Bakersfield doing
in patent leather shoes anyway?
Who wears those things?
Maybe he stole those, too.
Yeah, or maybe he was in town
for a wedding or reunion
or something,
and they were rentals.
I'm gonna check around.
I'll get back to you.
Hey, where's
Catherine?
Driving her daughter home.
Back any minute. Why?
I was just running
the dead girl's phone records.
Got a GPS hit on her cell.
If the killer's got it,
we've got him.
Yeah.
And it's on the move.
(siren whooping)
(sirens blaring)
Riley Adams, Las Vegas
Crime Lab.
Dump your load.
Well, Angela's cell phone
is in there somewhere.
SANDERS:
What's the number?
555...
0122.
(phone rings faintly)
(phone continues ringing)
Here.
(ringing stops)
Bloody glass
and the victim's purse.
If this truck stopped
at the Dark Water Bar,
Craig Hess is looking dirty.
Looks like crime scene cleanup.
Got the garbage truck's route
from the company.
We stopped the truck there.
We found Angela Carlos
just off of Newall Street.
Hmm.
WILLOWS:
Not on the route.
She was last seen
at the Dark Water Bar on Harmon,
which isn't
on the route,
either.
Hey, what about
the club owner's home address?
"Craig Hess.
"617 Cheery Bird Court,
Henderson."
Oh. Well, that's
way off the map.
So, other than the fact
that he lied to us
about knowing the vic,
we've got nothing on him.
Wendy, what brings
you to my store?
Well, I'm here on
the Angela Carlos case 'cause
I just ran her exemplar blood,
and it came back a mixture.
Oh, that's impossible.
I drew it from the heart.
I don't know.
I ran it twice, and both times,
it came back as a mixture
of one female
and two male bloods.
It's definitely
contaminated.
Well, then it was contaminated
on your end.
No, I don't...
I don't think so.
(wry laugh)
Well, regardless, I'm going
to need to get a clean exemplar.
Fine.
Would, uh,
deep tissue from the quadricep
work for you, Ms. Simms?
Yes, that'd be fine.
Good.
(horns honking)
BRASS:
Barry Wunderlick?
That his real name?
Real enough to get him
a couple of tuxedoes
and two pairs of
patent leathers.
He rented them
three days ago.
They were due
back yesterday.
And Barry's from
Bakersfield, too.
Oh, just like
our fake cop.
Yeah, so I checked with
the Palermo, and get this.
Wunderlick still has the room
right across the hall
from Officer Brady.
He was supposed to
check out yesterday,
but his stuff's
still in there.
And he did
get two keys.
Oh... Let me get this straight.
So, two guys from Bakersfield
come to Vegas, rent tuxedoes,
steal a policeman's uniform,
so that one of them can hold up
a couple of liquor stores.
Is that the deal?
That's what
the evidence says.
I'll flag his credit cards,
put a broadcast out.
SIMMS:
So I ran the tissue sample,
and it's clean.
It's purely Angela Carlos.
GRISSOM:
So the first
blood test was contaminated?
No. It...
No.
It was a mixture.
Three people's blood.
It started me thinking,
maybe her results
explain the hemolysis.
So, then I ran the blood stain
from the glass
that you pulled out
of the victim's wounds,
and I used that
as a secondary standard.
Same results.
Confirmed the mixture
of a female victim
and two unknown males.
The only way
that could have happened
was if she'd received
a blood transfusion.
From multiple donors.
With no medical
necessity.
The victim was B-negative.
One of the male donors
was O-negative.
The other one-- A-positive.
Then that's your COD.
A-positive would cause
a major reaction
with her blood type.
Transfusion explains the, uh,
needle marks on her arms
and the hives.
If somebody was trying
to kill her,
there were far easier ways
to do it.
(sighs)
Girl goes out
for a night on the town.
Wants to score some drugs.
Ends up with a snout
full of atropine
and a double transfusion.
And unfortunately, it's
impossible to separate
the two male types
from each other,
which means that I can't run
the DNA through CODIS.
Which now leaves us
with two unknown suspects.
Mr. Barry Wunderlick.
This whole time we've
been looking for him,
he's been our
house guest?
Arrested three days ago,
drunk and disorderly.
Couldn't post bail.
I was just having me
a bachelor party
at the Acid Strip.
How did you run up a tab
of over five grand, Barry?
Duh!
It's Vegas.
You want 'em to touch you,
you got to tip.
There's a four-drink minimum.
What?!
No, there isn't.
Well, that's what
she said, bro.
And you believed her?
She was smokin'.
Pushin' her junk up
in our face. Ooh!
Then, they come
up and tell me
that my credit card's
no good no more.
They wanted cash.
Is that how the manager
and two bartenders
ended up in the ER?
They were trying to screw us.
(laughs and sniffles)
They didn't realize
that they were messing
with an ultimate fighter.
Then, uh...
Then you guys show up
and arrest my ass.
What happened
to your friend Tommy?
I told him, "Work up some cash
and bail me out
before the wedding."
My best man leaves me hanging.
Eh...
I don't even know if Candy Jean
will have me now.
Your best man gave it
his best shot.
For real?
For real.
First, he stole
a policeman's uniform
from your hotel...
then went on to commit four
armed robberies in one night.
Put the money
in the bag!
(shrieks)
He did all that for me?
I guess my nine-mill
did come in handy.
(laughs)
What?
Mm...
Didn't end too good, did it?
I'm just curious.
Why rent a tuxedo
for a bachelor party?
It's Halloween.
Casino Royale's
my favorite movie.
I, uh... I kind of look
like the guy who plays him.
Huh?
Bond. James Bond.
You get it?
BRASS:
Oh, I get it.
Wunderlick. Barry Wunderlick.
(trilling)
(chirping)
(blipping)
♪ ♪
(knocks)
Broke your case... again.
Go.
Fish.
I examined your vic's purse
for trace
and found what I thought
to be a piece of skin.
Turns out I was right.
Fish skin.
Well...
anything that swims
gets me closer to Hess.
Carassius auratus,
to be exact.
Goldfish.
Good job, Hodges.
Thank you.
(inhales)
And there's more.
I analyzed the glass
from the garbage bag
and from the incised wound
on your victim's scalp.
They're both lead crystal.
I took the pieces
and used an approximation
of their original shape.
I know what this is.
A "fishus abowlus."
(chuckles)
That's very funny.
Sam bought Lindsey
an aquarium
for her ninth birthday,
filled it with exotic fish,
and she loved it
for all of 24 hours
until she realized
that the...
fancy fish eat the goldfish
for dinner.
Hmm... the circle of life.
You gotta be
kidding me.
(door closes)
What do you feed your fish?
I don't feed my own fish.
I hate fish.
It's worse
than owning racehorses.
Nothing
but problems.
They're, they're always
getting sick.
You know how much
it costs me to replace
one of those big orange
and white ones?
12 grand.
So if you don't feed
your fish, who does?
My boy Goya.
He's got a warehouse
over on Corville Street.
Las Vegas PD.
Whoa, whoa.
LVPD.
Put your hands up.
You got a warrant?
Turn around.
Huh, you got a warrant?
(all chattering)
(handcuffs click)
What's in the box?
Can't you read?
Sand.
What's it look like?
Sand, huh?
So how much would it run me
to fill my tank with blow?
Probably
what Angela
was here to find out.
So Craig Hess
sent her to you,
didn't he?
We ain't got nothing
to say to you.
Right, Joe?
Well, we've got a tank
for both you guys.
It's just your size. Come on.
There's enough atropine here
to sedate all of Sea World.
♪ ♪
This place is
on the garbage truck's route.
There's blood on the table,
glass underneath.
Angela came
for the cocaine
and ended up snorting
atropine instead--
pure atropine,
which is used to cut coke.
(gasping)
(grunts)
What's that?
Angela had blood
from two different males
in her system.
I'm thinking they transfused
her Frankenstein-style.
Why?
Settle the score
with Dad?
But she came to them.
She didn't come
for this.
MAN:
I sell fish.
I distribute cocaine.
I'm not a murderer.
Then why did you kill
Angela Carlos?
I didn't.
DNA confirms
that she received
a blood transfusion from you,
and your blood type
is A-positive.
That's what killed her.
And now she killed me.
Last year, Angela hooks up
with this sports book guy.
They get wasted.
She totals her car.
They walk away
without a scratch.
The next day, he's got
a bullet through his head.
Nobody messes
with Daddy's little girl.
The moment she came
through my door, I'm a dead man.
So you understand why me and
Goya would never give her drugs.
But you gave her atropine.
That'd be stupid.
I was going to give her pot
out of my own stash.
It's not like
it's even a real drug.
But when I went
to my car to get it,
the bitch pulled
a Pulp Fiction on me.
I was cutting the coke
before she got there.
She decided to help herself
and made the wrong choice.
(gasps)
(glass breaks)
Joe calls me in a panic.
When I get there,
she still has a pulse.
So you don't do
the smart thing--
call 911 or dump
her at the ER?
What made you think
a transfusion would
wake up Snow White?
Keith Richards.
The Rolling Stones'
Keith Richards?
Everyone knows the story.
When he hit the smack
too hard,
he'd, you know,
go to Europe or someplace
and get his blood swapped out.
That's an urban legend.
Whatever.
It makes sense.
And I know
about tubes and pumps.
That's all
a transfusion is, right?
GOYA:
She can't die, man.
It's okay, it's okay.
Look, I got it.
Come on, man. Come on.
Okay, all right, all right,
now we give her our blood.
We're freaking
losing her.
Let's go.
(Angela breathing)
No, no, it's okay.
Here you go, man.
Take this.
(Goya groans)
Leave it in there, man.
Leave it in there.
GOYA:
We were trying to save her.
She died anyway.
Yeah, she died.
But then you drove her body
halfway across town
and threw her
in a Dumpster.
Not any Dumpster.
That bastard Hess.
He sent her to our house,
so we gave her back to him.
(indistinct yelling)
I could just guess
what he told her.
Your father's boys
will take care of you.
Goya's Aquariums--
Corville Street.
But she wasn't in his Dumpster.
But it was
close enough
to Hess' club that Mr. Carlos
would make the connection.
Blame Hess.
I do.
(distant siren wailing)
(phone ringing)
(Hank whimpers)
(Grissom sighs)
(ringing continues)
Grissom.
(sighs)
(Death Cab for Cutie's
"Pity and Fear" fading in)
♪ I have... such envy ♪
♪ For this stranger
lying next to me ♪
♪ Who awakes ♪
♪ In the night ♪
♪ And slips out
into the pre-dawn light ♪
♪ No words,
a clean escape ♪
♪ No promises
or messes made ♪
♪ And chalks ♪
♪ It all up ♪
♪ To mistake, mistake,
mistake ♪
♪ And there are no tears ♪
♪ Just pity and fear ♪
♪ The vast ravine ♪
♪ Lying in between... ♪
(song ends)