Is that the expanded
tox report?
Yes, it is.
Searched 600 metabolites
and nothing unusual.
Makes Mr. Kelly our third
undetermined in three weeks.
ROBBINS:
Chief coroner's
gonna be on my butt.
Conduct a review,
cut the budget.
I was at the scene.
Pretty standard:
mother came home,
found him convulsing, tried CPR.
ROBBINS:
No prior history of seizures,
only trace amounts
of meth in his system,
not enough to kill him.
Put him in the meat locker
next to the other two.
I'm gonna figure this out.
I'm doing you
a solid here, Doc.
Technically,
I can't investigate
until you rule Mr. Kelly's
death either a homicide
or suspicious circs.
I'll give you
my tickets to Love.
I've seen it, twice.
All right.
(phone ringing)
I've got a call--
I'll meet you up there.
All right!
(thunder rumbling)
Okay. Sure.
Mrs. Kelly, this is
Catherine Willows
Yeah...
from the Crime Lab!
We spoke earlier!
(knocks)
(door creaks)
Mrs. Kelly?
Yeah?
Mrs. Kelly, I'm, uh, Catherine
Willows from the Crime Lab.
I left you a message.
(groans)
(crazed grunting)
(both grunting)
Catherine!
(grunting)
(both grunting)
(screaming)
(sighs)
(panting)
ROBBINS:
Catherine!
(pounding on door)
Are you okay?!
Thank God.
She jumped me.
I pulled my gun
and she just collapsed.
(sighs)
She's dead... and
you're bleeding.
That's better
than the other way around.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
(siren whooping)
BRASS:
So I talked
to the neighbors.
Nobody had anything bad
to say about Mrs. Kelly.
In fact,
they all called her a saint.
She's a special ed teacher;
she's a friend to kids,
stray dogs,
and anybody with a problem.
Well, I must have
met her evil clone.
BRASS: You know,
there's a reason
there's a protocol.
You should have called me first.
I was doing this
as a favor to Doc.
Yeah, this thing
could have escalated easily
and got out of hand.
Next time, you call me.
Yes, you're right.
I'm glad you're okay.
(sighs)
Thank you.
How is she?
Vitals are stable,
but the attacker bit her,
and she's not sure when she had
her last tetanus shot.
Let me see.
I just called you so that
you could work the case
'cause I'm a witness.
Nick's already inside.
Catherine, don't be a tough guy.
Jeff, get her
to the hospital.
Yes, sir.
Evening, Professor.
Nick.
"Extending deep and heartfelt
sympathies in the death
of your son Brent."
Darla Kelly's son
died six days ago.
Thinking that's probably
what drove her over the edge.
(camera clicking, whirring)
Hey, check it out.
Found a baggy of meth
in Brent's dresser
and an empty one
in the trash can.
Hmm.
Looks like he was a tweaker
living in Mama's trailer.
Meth can make you stronger,
meaner, angry, paranoid.
Maybe she was using,
too, which would explain
her behavior.
(indistinct conversation,
birds twittering)
Hey.
I found her alive
but unconscious.
Possible sexual assault.
Got an I.D.?
No purse,
no wallet.
My guys are still
knocking on doors.
Found her pants and shoes
next to the body,
and the paramedics took
this off her.
Who called it in?
Uh, Mr. Murphy.
Claims
that he found her
lying under
his truck
when he was leaving for work.
His wife corroborated
his story.
We'll see if
it holds up.
Got some abrasions
on the back
of the shirt.
Couple of buttons missing
on the front.
White substance
on the pants.
Could be semen.
Dried blood pool.
She was probably out here
for a while.
Some blood drops on the box--
mostly horizontal,
more than eight inches
off the ground.
Somebody hit her
when she was already down.
Maybe she was kicked
under the truck.
SANDERS:
Got a drag trail.
See where it leads.
(cracking)
(crackling)
Mrs. Kelly was such a nice lady.
She lost her health insurance
when she went part-time
at Marshall Creek Elementary.
Poor thing was
always getting sick.
The warrant includes
her son.
Was he a patient here
as well?
Brent?
Mm-hmm.
Yeah, he came in a few times,
feigning a back injury.
Why is that, you think?
He was trying to
score some oxycodone.
Mm.
A couple weeks ago,
Dr. Shaw had to
forcibly remove him.
Really?
I have his file, too.
He was
a terrible human being.
I used to
suspect
that he was abusing his mother,
but when I asked Mrs. Kelly
about it, she clammed right up.
It says here that Mrs. Kelly
called the clinic three days ago
complaining
of flu-like symptoms,
and someone told her
to take an analgesic
and get some rest.
Does that sound right?
Do you think that contributed
to her death?
I don't know yet,
but I'm gonna find out.
("Dead Shrimp Blues"
by Robert Johnson playing)
♪ I woke up this morning ♪
(Robbins singing along):
♪ And all my shrimp was dead ♪
♪ I woke up
this morning ♪
♪ Ooh, all my shrimp
was dead... ♪
(chuckles)
"Dead Shrimp Blues"--
Robert Johnson.
Recorded Friday, November 27,
1936, San Antonio, Texas.
The Gunter Hotel, three blocks
from the Alamo.
You're a blues man!
Is fat meat greasy?
(laughs) I got this
record in Chicago
at the M.E.s' convention.
Guy let it go for 50 bucks.
The man didn't
know what he had.
(music stops)
Is that the tox report?
Yes.
No drugs in
her system.
Henry ran the
panel twice.
ROBBINS:
I don't get it.
This is my fourth undetermined
this month.
Mrs. Kelly lived
with her son.
Maybe you're looking for
some kind of pathogen.
Something infectious--
a virus, bacteria,
microorganism?
I've already ruled out
gonorrhea, viral hepatitis,
syphilis, staphylococcus,
atypical pneumonia,
meningitis, endocarditis,
influenza, West Nile, and SARS.
Then it has
to be an exotic.
Hmm.
Did you hold the
rest of the bodies?
Walk this way.
Brent Kelly, 22,
died Friday night
after an
unexplained seizure.
Leeland Jacobs,
33, ex-con, died alone
in his apartment,
two weeks ago.
Says here he displayed
aggressive behavior
prior to his death.
Found cocaine in his system,
but he didn't OD.
Depending upon
your genetic disposition,
cocaine can trigger
schizophrenia and heart failure.
It wasn't a heart failure.
I can't tell you
if he was schizo.
We couldn't find
any medical records.
Scotty Belinsky.
27. Died three weeks ago.
Found in his bathroom.
Another ex-con.
I had Brass run backgrounds
on Belinsky and Jacobs.
No apparent connections.
Well, do we know
if either of them
was connected to Brent Kelly?
No.
The only thing that brings
these three men together
is body modification.
I see Mr. Kelly
had ear gauges.
But you ain't seen nothing yet.
Help me roll him.
That is some
serious modification.
Transdermal implants.
It's done via a process
called "dermal punching."
Technician makes
an incision,
separates subcutis and fascia
using a dermal elevator,
creating a pocket
where an implant's inserted--
typically steel
or silicone bead.
The skin fuses
around the bead,
creating the design,
kind of like a Braille tattoo.
So, maybe...
all three of these men
visited the same tattoo parlor.
Can't be many of them
that do this kind of work.
(camera shutter clicking)
(grunting)
MAN: So, you want me to
take care of that?
Hey, Lou, did you do a knock
and talk at this house?
I'm just on my way
over there now.
LVPD.
Yeah, uh...
What's going on?
Ladies,
I'm Detective Vartann.
This is Greg Sanders
from the Crime Lab.
A woman was attacked
on your street last night.
We believe the victim might have
come from this house.
Oh, my God. Kayla.
She was here last night.
Is, uh, this Kayla?
Is she okay?
She's in the hospital.
What is Kayla's last name?
Nootens.
When was the last time
you saw her?
Around 10:00.
We had our diet club meeting,
me, Diana,
and Kayla.
You know,
we all entered
the GME bikini contest.
GME?
God Made 'Em.
No fake boobs.
First prize is
a trip for two to Hawaii.
Yeah. Well, we meet here
twice a week.
We do our weigh in,
and then we have
our support dinner.
So, I lost another
two pounds.
I was craving ice cream,
but I went for a run instead.
And it worked.
Rub it in, why don't you?
I lost zero pounds this week.
I'm never going to fit
into my bikini.
Don't say that.
We can do this.
And I am going to go to Maui.
DIANA:
If you win,
will you take me?
You said that Kayla left here
around 10:00?
Did either of you walk her
to her car?
I was going to drive her home,
but then it stopped raining,
so she decided to walk.
They say if you walk
after dinner,
it burns more fat.
Yeah.
Um, do you know anyone
who might want
to hurt her?
Her ex...
BF.
Yeah, they fought
all the time.
D-bag.
He dumped her 'cause
she gained 15 pounds.
And then he said that
he would take her back
if she won the contest
and took him
to Hawaii.
Do you know her
ex-BF's name?
Um, Elvis Rodriguez.
(monitor beeping slowly)
(Willows groans)
The tetanus shot hurt more than
the crazy lady attacking me.
You going to turn into
a vampire now?
Well, I already
work nights,
so I don't think anybody's
going to notice.
(chuckles)
I can't work the
other case,
so fill me in here.
Doctor says death is imminent.
Mmm.
Wet mount was positive
for semen.
And they found signs
of sexual trauma.
Do you want to help me roll her?
She's got road rash
on her back, shoulders,
and buttocks.
Based on the depth
of the abrasions,
it looks like she was
dragged a long way.
That's consistent with
what we found at the scene.
Now, this neck injury
looks like a stab wound.
You swab it?
Nurse did. Found some trace
inside the wound track.
It's with the SAE kit.
(alarm beeping)
(flatline tone,
staffers clamoring)
Excuse me!
(panting)
STOKES:
He does know you can't undo that.
Mmm.
Doesn't he?
Self-mutilation
trips me out.
LANGSTON:
It's a form
of rebellion.
I've witnessed a couple of
botched tongue forkings
in my time.
STOKES:
Yeah, and even
if you make it through,
you wind up with a...
(slurring):
speech impediment.
Hey, guys.
Walk-ins always welcome.
We're actually running
a special right now
on matching
tattoo hearts.
Or are you guys more
into rough trade?
Dude, we're CSI.
We're here
on police business.
Are you the owner?
I wish.
It's Jack's Body Shop,
and my name is Eric.
Eric Tobin.
I'm the manager
slash receptionist.
The man-ceptionist.
We need to speak with Jack.
Jack is in the back making
one of his magic potions.
Thank you, my man.
(needle buzzing)
Boy, this is all
kinds of wrong.
(Stokes clears throat)
Bathroom's in
the front.
Are you Jack?
Crime Lab boys.
Dr. Jack Shaw.
What can I do for you,
gentlemen?
Are you the same Dr. Shaw
that works the free clinic
on Janville?
Guilty.
I assume you also know
I'm a retired coroner from Reno.
I do now.
So, how'd you go
from being a coroner
to owning this place?
Natural transition, actually.
Used to spend all day
cutting up dead bodies
and sticking them with needles.
Today when I cut 'em,
they bleed.
Tell me, Doctor,
do you know
if any of these men
has been in your shop
recently?
I don't recognize the faces,
but I do know the work.
There's sunflower yellow
and iris blue in these tats.
That's "Van Gogh."
He mixes his own ink.
And he's the only one
that does dermal implants.
What's his real name?
Carl Van Goe.
Spelled G-O-E.
I swear to God.
Had it legally changed.
I fired him two weeks ago.
How come?
Artistic differences.
Customer would want
a certain design.
Van Goe would give them
what he thought was right
for their "canvas."
You guys going to tell
me what's going on?
These three men all died
of an infectious disease.
Seems that this place--
your shop-- is the only
common link.
Hey, I run a clean shop.
I give an antibiotic shot
to anybody
that's had an invasive
procedure.
But Van Goe brings his own tools
and needles.
We'd like to check him out.
In the meantime, we're going
to need your tools, needles,
inks, and, uh,
the biohazard bin.
Supply cabinet's
up front.
Biohazard's out back.
It's all in the
warrant.
Uh, what pathogen
do you suspect?
Did I say it was a pathogen?
Retired coroner.
I'm assuming.
SANDERS:
So, Elvis, how'd you
get these injuries?
I'm a landscaper.
Got a lot of cactus orders
'cause of the drought.
Or maybe
they're from
when you raped your ex,
Kayla Nootens.
I didn't rape Kay.
We had sex.
Open up.
You had the kind of sex
where she said "no."
Hold up. This is crazy.
Me and Kay broke up.
Yeah.
Because you thought she was fat.
You ever seen her?
She used to look like
a little coke bottle.
Then she got all messy
in the middle.
I couldn't have that on my arm.
So, when Kayla dropped a few
l.b.'s, you wanted her back?
No, remember, he wanted
a free trip to Hawaii.
Oh, right.
That's why I had sex with her.
To seal the deal.
She was easy that way.
And I needed a vacay.
What time was this?
Around 6:00 maybe.
Then she went to go see
some friends,
and I had to go pick up my new
girlfriend's kid from day care.
(sighs)
VARTANN:
Where did you
go after?
I dropped the kid off,
but my girlfriend was tired.
So I went home.
Well, that means
you don't have an alibi.
Why do I need an alibi for?
Because
I'm charging you
with the rape and murder
of Kayla Nootens.
Congratulations.
You may have just won
a 20-year vacay.
(beeps)
Hello, this is--
Don't say "hello."
(beeps)
Okay.
This is the first solo autopsy
of Assistant Medical Examiner
David Gregory Phillips.
Me.
Decedent is a Caucasian female.
Kayla Nootens.
Early 20s.
63 inches.
144 pounds.
(beep)
I don't have
C.O.D. yet,
so please don't ask.
You want some help?
No.
I have to do
this myself.
It's my first solo.
Sorry.
Didn't mean to lose my temper.
That was you losing your temper?
My wife calls me a
"snapping alligator."
Well, your bad temper is
better than my good one.
Did you examine
her neck wound?
Of course I did.
She was stabbed.
I excised that
from the wound.
What is it?
I have no idea.
Maybe you could ask Hodges.
(sighs)
(groans)
So, Mr. Van Goe,
how come you still have
both your ears?
Got the name
'cause I cut off
someone's ear lobe.
Accident.
It was my first year on the job.
Of course.
So, where do you keep
all your tools?
No, hey, hey, hey.
Where do you think
you're going?
Stuff's in there.
(chuckling): No.
He'll go look.
I need you to stay here
and paint me a picture.
Did you do any work on these
guys at Jack's Body Shop?
VAN GOE: I don't know.
Why don't you ask Jack? I quit.
So, you telling me that
Shaw didn't fire you?
He's a jackal and a philistine.
I quit.
I took my clients with me.
I'm going to need
a list of your clients.
I don't write anything down.
Excuse me, Mr. Van Goe.
You been working out of
your shed these days?
You do know that's
against the law, don't you?
Okay, let's start again.
Did you work on
any of these guys?
Either here, there, or anywhere?
Maybe.
No,
this is not multiple choice.
It's either yes or no.
Or.
BRASS: Okay, it's gonna be
one of those days, I guess.
All right, look,
Scotty, wrap him up.
Come on, let's go.
We'll do this
some other place.
♪ Don't sit there mumblin' ♪
♪ And talkin' trash ♪
♪ If you wanna have a ball ♪
♪ You gotta go out
and spend some cash ♪
♪ Let the good times roll... ♪
Damn it.
Virology results
from the tattoo parlor.
No detectable contaminants,
poisons or pathogens.
Maybe something will turn up
in the Van Goe shed.
Can we go over it one more time?
Yeah.
Starting with the
most recent victim.
Darla Kelly gave her
dying son CPR.
Three days later she
complains of a sore throat,
fatigue and a low-grade fever.
Three days after that,
she attacks Catherine
and drops dead.
Right, her counts are normal,
white blood cells unaffected,
which tells us
it's not bacterial.
If it's not in the blood,
it has to be the tissue.
Certain organisms
have different rates
of crossing the
blood-brain barrier.
Histology was negative.
Muscle, tissue,
brain, organs.
But the lab only checked
for common pathogens.
Let's take a look at
Darla Kelly's brain tissue.
LANGSTON:
Bottom right quadrant.
Is that a Negri body?
That's what I'm thinking.
I haven't seen one of those
since medical school.
I have another one
here, Doctor.
There are Negri bodies in
each victim's brain tissue.
It's rabies.
Yes.
No one's died of
rabies in Nevada
in over 90 years,
and now we have four in a month.
Rabies would explain Darla
Kelly's flu-like symptoms.
It was raining
that night.
Rabies can cause hydrophobia,
intense fear of water.
Maybe it triggered
her violent behavior.
And rabies is carried
in the saliva.
Mrs. Kelly had a cold sore.
ROBBINS:
The virus travels through
connective tissue
into the muscle,
goes up into the neuronal
cells of the brain stem
and into the limbic cortex.
The most common form of
rabies virus transmission
is through the bite or
the virus-containing saliva
of an infected host, which is
almost always a rabid animal.
Now, none of the victims
had bite marks,
and no one reported
being bitten.
Someone was bitten.
Catherine.
What's wrong?
Uh, we have C.O.D.
on Darla Kelly.
It's rabies.
Okay, uh, so, what?
I'll get a shot and be fine.
Human rabies cases
are very rare.
The treatment is
extremely expensive,
which is why the state
doesn't have any available.
Okay, so, you're telling me
that there aren't any
available shots
in the entire state of Nevada?!
If the treatment is administered
within the first
72 hours of transmission,
you should be fine.
It's already been
more than 24.
And we've located a supply;
it's in Atlanta.
Atlanta?!
Georgia.
You'll need a test
to confirm whether
you've got it.
And I'm taking you to
the hospital right now.
I... I need to call Nick.
Let him know he's the
acting supervisor.
Use your cell phone.
At least give me a hint.
I wish I could.
But Dr. Robbins has to review
and sign off on my work first.
Okay, well, where is he?
The hospital.
Visiting Catherine.
He must be feeling
really guilty.
Okay, the rape victim
who was dragged.
Uh, Kayla Nootens.
Go.
Okay, uh, decedent sustained
a half-inch deep stab wound
to the right side
of her neck.
It nicked her vertebral artery.
C.O.D. is exsanguination.
This wound is minor, David.
She's a young woman.
Blood would have
clotted within minutes.
Yes, sir, however,
I discovered that she
was severely anemic
and had excessive levels
of caffeine in her system.
Both of which contributed
to blood thinning
and compromised
her clotting factors.
Common indicators of anorexia.
Or extreme dieting.
Her and her friends
were trying to win
a bikini contest.
So, my proposed C.O.D.
is exsanguination
with additional complicating
factors preventing clotting.
Well described.
I concur.
Catherine just got her
prophylaxis shots.
She's doing fine.
That's good to hear.
What have you got?
Well, virology confirmed
that all four victims died
of a, uh, rabies virus
variant associated
with T. Brasiliensis.
The Mexican Free Tailed Bat.
We didn't find any evidence of
bats at the mobile home park.
And two of the victims died
in apartments off the strip.
So, what's our theory?
I mean, did all these
people go spelunking
in Lehman Caves or what?
They charge admission there.
So, I checked their guest books
and their receipts.
None of our victims
were there.
I called CDC,
I asked for all their files
on rabies transmissions.
Most of it was,
uh, straight-up
"hunter bitten by fox" stuff.
But this one did stand out.
STOKES:
That's redacted.
That usually means
there was a lawsuit
with a confidential settlement.
Doc Robbins says there
hasn't been a rabies death
in Nevada in nearly a century.
But from what
I can piece together,
that may not be true.
A patient up in Reno
tested positive
for rabies after
a liver transplant.
But doesn't say
if she died or not.
If her liver was infected,
she's dead.
If the donor was local,
that means that the
Reno Coroner had to
clear the body
before they could
harvest the organs.
I guess he must've
missed it.
Yeah.
What about Dr. Shaw?
He's a coroner.
I know this happened
three years ago.
I don't know how many they
had working in Reno back then,
but we do know him.
Brent Kelly, Scott Belinsky
and Leeland Jacobs
all went to this
guy's tattoo parlor.
And both the Kellys
were treated by him
at the Free Clinic.
Your victim was a messy eater.
Not too proficient with a fork.
The white substance on
the clothes is not semen.
It's potatoes, butter,
milk and a pinch of garlic.
Mashed potatoes?
Mm-hmm.
She was cheating on her diet.
More like a food orgy.
The trace on the neck wound
showed apple, cinnamon
and grease.
What about the fragment
David extracted?
Well, that would be
the main course.
It was animal bone.
Although it was too small
for me to identify the species,
I think we know
it's pretty obvious.
Babe.
Wilbur?
Pork.
Yes, the other white meat.
That's the only type
of flesh that you would
season that way.
Suddenly, I'm very hungry.
Break time.
Hold on there, spuds.
How much do you weigh?
Uh, excuse you.
That's not public
information.
I'd say a buck 45.
Same as our victim.
We know Kayla Nootens
was dragged face-up
because her back
was abraded.
So, if the killer
(grunting with effort):
dragged her like this...
Her back wouldn't be abraded.
Right.
Okay, what if
the killer
dragged her like this?
Ow, hey!
Easy, killer.
Hodges' calves are
touching the floor.
Vic had no abrasions
from the knees down.
There must've been two of them.
Yep.
Elvis had a friend.
Um... if I may...
Wouldn't two men, one of whom
being a cactus-hauling
desert landscaper,
just be able to pick me up
and carry me?
Or... her?
First rule of diet club...
Don't talk about diet club.
The whole thing
was Rhonda's fault.
She was sabotaging
Kayla's diet
because she'd lost
the most weight.
That is so not true!
Kayla was fatter than me.
So, of course she
lost more weight.
Anyway, Kayla is
the one that started it.
These mashed potatoes
are amazing.
What kind of butter
substitute did you use?
Mine suck.
(Rhonda clearing throat)
Hers are watery.
Oh, my God.
You bitch.
You are the bitch!
You were going to
ditch me for your
ugly ex-BF and
take him to Hawaii!
You're both bitches!
(women screaming)
Kayla would still
be alive if
Rhonda hadn't whipped that
pork chop at her.
(girls screaming)
(gasping)
You are going to jail!
And you will always
have a fat ass!
Rhonda lost it,
chased her down.
She dropped dead right there.
I didn't know that you
could kill somebody
with a pork chop.
But it was
Diana's idea
to drag the body under the truck
and then pin the
whole thing on Elvis.
Kayla wasn't dead
when you were
kicking her
under the truck.
She bled to death
because you left her there.
I'm telling you,
I didn't kill anybody.
Okay, we got it,
Doc, let's go.
Want me to call
your girlfriend?
Hey, hey, hey!
Back off, back off.
Hey, I got your back,
I believe you!
Stay strong.
Hey, take it easy.
(groans)
Call 911.
Hey, bud.
Huh?
Did I just pass out again?
Stay, stay back.
How you feeling?
I'm fine.
I just... I haven't
been feeling too good
since I got my nipples pierced.
Dr. Shaw gave me a shot
of antibiotics,
but I probably just got
an infection anyway.
When did you get the shot?
A couple days ago.
I don't know-- it's a setup.
I'm being framed.
BRASS:
Who framed you?
Roger Rabbit?
Maybe Van Goe.
He's a crazy bastard.
He threatened me
when I fired him.
So, how does this
frame-up play out?
Van Goe breaks
into your shop
wearing a
Dr. Shaw mask
and pokes Tobin
with a rabid needle?
I'm not denying I gave Eric
an antibiotic shot.
He had a piercing--
that's SOP at my shop.
You know, somebody's lying
in this room.
And it's not me,
and it's not him,
'cause he just
got here.
Three years ago,
in Reno,
a transplant recipient died
from a donor liver
that tested positive for rabies.
SHAW:
I was the M.E.
on the donor's autopsy.
I ruled it a natural.
There was an
investigation.
I was cleared.
Rabies detection is not part
of the organ review.
So, this isn't
your first dance
around the rabies game.
Did you give the donor
an antibiotic shot, too?
The victim's family
later admitted
that he had been bitten
by a raccoon
six weeks before he died.
Well, maybe Rocky Raccoon
framed you.
I'd like to end this interview
and call a lawyer.
♪ Hey! ♪
(White Stripes'
"Baby Brother" playing)
♪ My little baby brother used to
play down on the floor ♪
♪ But now he's not satisfied
to do it anymore ♪
♪ He's got a funny habit
and I don't know why ♪
♪ He walks around the ceiling
now, steppin' on the flies ♪
♪ Baby brother ♪
♪ Yeah, baby brother... yeah ♪
♪ Well, you're learnin' to crawl
on the kitchen wall ♪
♪ Baby brother ♪
♪ Although he's out
in outer space ♪
♪ I can still see his face,
baby brother ♪
♪ Although you're out
in outer space ♪
♪ I can still see your face,
baby brother! ♪
STOKES:
Miss Schiff?
Hi.
Can I help you
with something?
Uh, no, but I think
I can help you.
I found this in the trash
at Dr. Shaw's house.
What were you doing
at his house?
Mr. Stokes, I'm...
embarrassed to admit it,
but we were dating.
I-I didn't see it.
I had no idea that
he's this monster.
I saw him take it out
of his briefcase.
These are the same bags
we use at the clinic.
I don't think it belongs
to a patient.
Did you ask him about it?
He gets angry
if I ask him any questions.
Just please
don't tell him
that I gave it to you.
All right.
Thanks.
(clears throat) Hi.
I need to know
what this is,
and then get the bag
to Prints right away.
Well, it looks
like it's
some kind of tissue.
Yeah, you might want
to double-glove.
I think Dr. Shaw's been
cutting up rabid animals,
making some sort
of a rabies potion.
I will sample DNA
and run a species determination.
Also, I found
Eric Tobin's needle,
and virology
confirmed
that it tested
positive for rabies.
Any DNA on the syringe?
Yeah.
I just don't know
if it's a match to Shaw yet
'cause Langston
just dropped off the exemplar
on his way out of town.
Out of town?
(blues music playing
over stereo)
Did you tell Nick
what we're doing?
I did not tell Nick
what we were doing,
just in case things
don't go according to plan.
Gives him plausible deniability.
Correct.
You know, we're kind of screwed
if the hospital doesn't have
hard copies of the documents.
Mm-hmm.
Good thing being a doctor
has more advantages
than just getting hot chicks.
(chuckling)
♪ ♪
Is that Mississippi John Hurt?
No.
Recorded January, 1932.
Grafton, Wisconsin.
Shoot me a title.
My dear doctor, we are traveling
to Reno on the Gone Dead Train.
King Solomon Hill.
Ah.
Born...
Joe Holmes.
Thank you.
(both laughing)
Hello.
Uh, Frank,
how are you today?
Never seen you guys before.
Are you attendings or surgeons?
We're researchers.
ROBBINS:
Yeah, we're from,
uh, Saint Ann's.
Uh, we're doing
research for the, uh...
for the cardinal.
Not the, uh, team in Arizona.
The, uh, guy who wears
the pointy red hat,
cardinal.
Medical I.D.'s, please.
You're not allowed to remove
any files from this room,
photocopy any files
without permission,
mutilate or destroy any files.
Got it...
Ebony and Ivory?
ROBBINS:
Yeah, we...
we got it, Frank.
Next time,
you don't talk.
I don't talk?
I don't think you should talk.
So, we have a liver transplant.
Recipient was Sandra Williams.
This patient
did well
immediately
after transplantation.
Discharged on
postoperative day five.
21 days after transplant,
she was readmitted
with tremors,
lethargy and anorexia.
During the next
48 hours,
her mental status
deteriorated.
She subsequently died.
Initial diagnosis
was encephalitis.
Hmm.
Well, it says here
that the recipient's husband,
Eric Tobin,
filed a lawsuit
against the hospital
and its medical personnel.
Not surprising.
Did you say Eric Tobin?
Mm-hmm.
ERIC:
It's, uh,
Jack's Body Shop,
and my name is Eric--
Eric Tobin.
What, you don't think
he's some sort of mastermind
that framed Dr. Shaw, do you?
I mean, come on,
Ray, you met him.
He's not even the master
of his own mind.
He has motive, Nick.
He blames Shaw
for his wife's death.
Tobin won a malpractice suit.
That's big bucks.
The only reason he'd work
at the shop
is for revenge.
Well, gentlemen,
all of the physical evidence
points to Dr. Shaw.
Wendy found his touch DNA on
the syringe that infected Tobin.
And while you two
were out playing
Smokey and
the Bandit,
his girlfriend,
who's also a nurse
at the clinic, brought me
something he was trying
to get rid of:
a salivary gland
from a rabid bat.
I think that's
what he used to make the virus.
Rabid bats are easy to spot
because they stay within reach,
even when a human
enters their cave.
All he had to do
was extract the saliva
and add a preservative to keep
the rabies virus viable.
Look, I don't know
how Tobin plays into all this,
but Shaw is still
our best suspect.
Besides, it takes technical
skill and knowledge
to extract the rabies virus
like that.
Then Tobin isn't working alone.
He's partnered
with a mastermind.
You said Shaw's girlfriend
is a nurse,
and she brought you
that evidence.
I'm suspicious of anybody
who brings me anything.
I ran Susan Schiff
through the system.
There was no criminal record.
She could still be lying.
Maybe there's
another connection.
Did Susan Schiff live in Reno?
Run her Social.
(computer beeping)
Susan Schiff...
also known as Susan Williams.
The woman
who died in Reno...
her name was Sandra Williams.
My daughter was on
the transplant list for a year.
Sandy was so excited
when her name finally came up.
She and Eric started planning
for their future.
She wanted to have a baby.
But because of Dr. Shaw
and his negligence,
what she got
was 21 days of hell.
You ever seen somebody die
of rabies?
I've seen people die
all kinds of ways.
I understand he made
a fatal mistake-- I really do--
but that doesn't
give you the right
to kill four innocent people.
Those men weren't innocent.
They were a different kind
of virus.
I told you
when we met,
Brent Kelly
was a low-life drug dealer
who beat up his own mother.
And the other two, Eric chose.
Those guys would come
into the shop and brag
about selling drugs to kids
and having sex with minors.
Where were you guys?
You know,
I'm a little confused, Batman.
Was your mission
to avenge your wife's death
or rid Gotham of scumbags?
STOKES:
What about Darla Kelly?
She was innocent.
I thought you liked her.
That one's on Brent.
I always knew
he'd kill her someday.
What about your son-in-law?
I volunteered.
You hadn't arrested Shaw yet.
Plus...
Sue wasn't going to let me die.
I'm not stupid.
Not anymore.
How did you pull it off?
I got a piercing.
I knew that Dr. Shaw
would give me a shot
of antibiotics.
That's his SOP.
Sue gave me a vial
of the virus.
I slapped on a label.
Susan, you don't
get to play God
because your daughter died--
that's not the way it works.
Dr. Shaw didn't just kill
my little girl.
He killed my whole family.
My sons, my parents,
my marriage.
Eric.
We all died
that day.
And Dr. Shaw
didn't lose anything.
And that's just wrong.
You wanted to see me.
Wanted to thank you.
What for?
For believing in my innocence.
I just didn't assume
you were guilty.
You know, I was good--
really good-- at my job.
I just wasn't good enough.
I understand, Doctor.
I've been there.
Remember that solid you owe me?
(sighs)
It's going to take more
than show tickets, isn't it?
Oh, yeah.