♪ They asked me how I knew ♪
♪ My true love was true ♪
♪ Oh, oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ I, of course, replied ♪
♪ Something here inside ♪
♪ Cannot be denied ♪
♪ They said someday
you'll find ♪
MAN:
Stop. Stop.
You're killing me.
Are you
freaking deaf?
I said stop!
Kill the playback!
(music stops)
Look,
this might win second prize
at the talent contest
at Spiro Agnew High School
in Bad Limp, Arkansas...
Hey, Drew.
It's not my kid's fault.
Who let Daddy Dearest
on the stage?
I gave specific orders...
Everybody's
moving around
like there's nothing
important going on.
How about
a little respect, okay?
Except for your kid
doesn't deserve respect.
Lazy little prima donna.
Maybe you should sit
with the losers.
SINGER:
Let me try it again.
You don't care.
I do so care--
this isn't a game
to me, all right?
I'm a good singer.
It's all I've ever wanted to do,
and you have no right...
There! That passion.
That's what I want to see
when you sing.
Now, let's
do it again.
And watch your pitch, baby.
Too early in the day
to be that flat.
I know I wasn't flat.
Hang in there.
DREW:
Oh, yes, you were.
The name of
this show
is Overnight Sensation.
For God sakes,
show me something
sensational!
Playback!
(accompaniment track resumes)
♪ When you're... ♪
Flat!
Pitch, baby, pitch.
♪ You must realize ♪
♪ Smoke gets in your eyes... ♪
Pitch!
(crying):
I can't take this!
You tell us
to feel everything,
but you don't feel anything.
I can't... I can't do this.
Layla.
(crying)
What?
DREW:
Rehearsal's
not over.
WOMAN:
Layla, wait!
DREW:
Playback!
(accompaniment track resumes)
♪ They asked me how I knew ♪
♪ My true love was true ♪
(fading away):
♪ Oh... ♪
(indistinct radio communication)
(siren whoops)
Liver temp puts T.O.D.
between 2:00 and 4:00 a.m.
She was Lindsey's
favorite on the show.
We voted for her
six times last week.
(sighs)
They make it to Vegas
for the finals.
Every kid watching wants
to be them.
It just... it
shouldn't end like this.
GRISSOM:
Glamorous makeup.
Fancy lingerie.
Sex fetish
that went too far?
Perverted idol worship?
Wholesome all-American girl.
Did you do an SAE kit?
Not yet.
GRISSOM:
She may have gotten
what she wished for--
she's an overnight
sensation now.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
It's part of the gruesome
perversity of this business
that the ratings
will be through the roof
on our final show.
So as a tribute to Layla,
let's do what
she'd want us to do.
WOMAN:
Yeah.
Let's make it
our best show ever, okay?
Rehearsal!
BRASS:
Excuse me?
You're Drew Rich, the producer?
Who are you?
I'm Detective Jim
Brass, Las Vegas Police.
We're trying
to confirm the whereabouts
of Layla Wells last night.
Can you help us?
She left rehearsal
last night around 7:00.
Went back to her room,
as far as I know.
Chaperone says she
called at midnight,
said she was going to bed.
Where's the chaperone?
Fired her this morning.
Obviously, she wasn't
doing her job.
Okay.
Layla's an
emancipated minor,
but her chaperone's supposed
to be looking out for her,
not pumping per diem into
a slot machine all night.
This means
you won, Kip.
You're the champion.
No, he's not.
Ajaya!
Last one voted off.
You're back on
against Kip.
BRASS:
We're gonna need
contact information
from Miss Wells's family.
Michelle can get it to you.
Now, I have a show to produce.
Call editing.
I want a DVD of every frame
we have on Layla
on my desk, one hour.
Okay.
If this was a killer
that fetishized her,
why not just
dump the body?
Why bother to wrap her up?
To conceal the body
during transport
from the primary.
It's consistent with those knots
being tied into a handle.
You know, the looping here
looks like a reef knot.
Might be looking for somebody
with some sailing experience.
(quiet whirring)
"Rancho Linen Service."
They deliver
to every hotel on the Strip.
Been around since
Bugsy Siegel's days.
Which is probably the last time
this tablecloth was washed.
These discolorations
suggest that
this has been
on somebody's table a long time.
ADAMS:
What was Layla doing here?
She had a great room
at the Palermo,
people waiting on her
day and night.
You ever been in
one of those suites?
Just to get evidence.
I sure wouldn't
leave there for...
whatever this is.
Couple of blood drops.
There's no trail.
Probably dripped
through the cloth.
These wheel tracks
are 11 inches apart.
It couldn't have been
a grocery cart.
The front wheels are
narrower than the back,
so it would've left two
different sets of tracks.
Something tells me a guy pushing
any kind of cart in this area
wouldn't be that unusual.
(shutter clicks)
ROBBINS:
That blunt-force trauma
just below the rib cage
is your C.O.D.
Lacerated the liver.
Hangs lower when
the body's upright.
Since no ribs
were impacted,
she was standing when
the blow occurred.
(gasps)
Death would have occurred
fairly quickly.
Any indication
of sexual assault?
No. However, when I was doing
the internal exam,
I found an embryo implanted
in the uterine wall,
maybe 20
millimeters long.
She was pregnant.
About eight weeks.
I sent cord tissue to DNA.
So maybe this isn't just
a case of negligent chaperone.
Maybe it's motive.
Got a reading?
Yeah.
BRASS:
So, the Lock
Interrogator says
that Layla last used
her key card
to enter her room
at 7:12 p.m.
That's right after
she walked out of rehearsal.
Hm.
Now, according
to the hotel phone records,
she made two calls--
one to Drew Rich's room
around 7:34 p.m.
Probably to apologize.
And the other one
to her chaperone
to say good night
around midnight.
Went to
voice mail.
Casino surveillance
says that the chaperone
stayed up all night trying
to win a progressive.
From about 8:00 on,
she was looking up
abortion clinics.
It looks like
she had a change of heart;
started checking out
adoption agencies.
Huh.
Sounds like a confused kid.
Well, it looks like they're a
cute couple, I'll give you that,
but what I don't get
is why anybody wants
to watch that
show-- I don't.
It's a talent contest?
It's more like a
humiliation ritual.
Well, you'd know
about that.
(chuckles):
All right.
So, you want to know
why that kid Ajaya
with the fluffy hair,
sings like a hinge,
why he got into
the semifinals?
Hm?
Me and 10,000 other guys
vote for him every week
on the Internet.
But if you don't watch,
how do you know about him?
Oh, you know, water
cooler talk, gossip.
Mm. Right.
(clears throat):
Well...
here's something
the gossips don't have.
Okay, there's
the humiliator.
Layla left
the Palermo, too,
just after midnight.
Two minutes later...
Kip follows.
BRASS:
It must've been pretty hard
for you and Layla
to find some time together.
You know, can't get
your mojo workin'
when Daddy's lurkin'.
So what did you do?
You waited till midnight,
Dad's asleep,
and you take separate
elevators down.
Then what?
Layla was found
in a pretty tough neighborhood.
What were you
doing over there,
scoring drugs?
He doesn't do drugs.
Or maybe it was to get
a back-alley abortion.
What?
Layla was eight weeks pregnant--
am I right?
And who's the daddy?
You?
The hell it was.
I'm not
talking to you.
Kip...
Just shut up.
Just... shut up.
We're going to
need a DNA sample.
No way.
You're done abusing my kid.
And so are you.
Sit down. Take him
out in the hall.
You can't do this.
Dad...
Hey, check
it out.
I've got you and Kip
returning to the hotel
after the time
of the murder.
You're like a
team, right?
You're in it
together,
50-50.
You know, the contest,
the career,
and future
earnings.
It's a lot of money.
And that's what this
is about, right?
The money?
30 million people
tune in to hear
my kid sing every week.
How many people want
to watch you?
So you're on the
road four months?
How'd you work that out
with your job?
I took a leave of absence.
Come on, sailor,
you abandoned ship.
You quit your job, got a
second mortgage on your house.
If Kip screws up,
you're wiped out,
so I can understand how
you'd cover up for him,
and maybe you're
even desperate enough
to kill her yourself.
SIMMS:
So I ran that fetal cord tissue
that Doc Robbins sent over.
I subtracted out the
mother's profile,
leaving what has to be
the father's contribution,
and it didn't match the
sample from Kip Westerman.
So he's not the father
of Layla's baby.
No, but then I ran those
alleles through CODIS and...
I got a hit.
Marvin Fleck.
In the system from charges
in North Carolina in 2002.
Mm-hmm.
Do you recognize Marvin?
Drew Rich?
Yeah, he had sex
with a minor--
she was 15
years old--
but then she
changed her story,
so the charges
were dropped.
Want to bet
he paid her off?
DREW RICH:
Talent and ambition ran
in Layla Wells's family.
Her grandmother Jasmine
was a Las Vegas showgirl
who gave Layla her first
figure-skating classes.
Sadly, Layla's grandmother
didn't live
to see her come
so close to becoming
America's next
Overnight Sensation.
LAYLA:
My mama didn't approve
of show business.
We were always fighting
about it, so I went
to live with my grandma.
Trim the ice ballet,
give me some more shots
where she's crying.
We need to see some
more emotion, man.
BRASS:
Mr. Rich.
Later.
Marvin.
I left rehearsal
around 7:15.
I went back
to my room alone.
I needed some time
to think.
Is thinking what
got Layla pregnant?
These kids might seem
like innocents,
but they're not.
They are first-class
manipulators
with the survival instincts
of a coyote.
I told Layla I'd pay
for an abortion,
and she agreed,
as long as she won
the competition.
I don't like
being blackmailed.
Sounds like motive.
Doesn't mean
I killed her.
We know you
left the Palermo
around midnight.
About 20 minutes later,
your credit card was used
at the Blue
Madonna Motel.
I wasn't with Layla.
Her body was found
three blocks from there.
You beat rape charges once.
Maybe you thought you wouldn't
be so lucky a second time.
This is ridiculous.
Look... I was with a hooker.
All right?
Layla was pregnant
with your child.
That's statutory rape.
Age of consent
in Nevada is 16.
No, have your lawyer look
at the statute again.
There's an exception
when a person
is in a position of
authority with a teenager--
like "executive producer."
Come on, let's go.
Spermaceti.
An oil found in the heads
of sperm whales.
Mm-hmm, and when it
cools, it becomes a wax.
The lipstick that the
dead girl was wearing
had a spermaceti
wax base.
There's been a ban
on sperm whaling for 20 years.
Yeah, which means that
the lipstick is very old.
You know, spermaceti is
not the weirdest thing
found in lipstick.
The ancient Greeks made
theirs out of saliva,
sheep sweat, and
crocodile excrement.
Did any of the makeup in her
hotel room contain spermaceti?
No, but there were intriguingly
analogous results from,
believe it or not...
the tablecloth.
Take a look.
Asbestos?
Specific type of asbestos
called amocite.
Its particles are
bound together by
vermiculite and cellulose,
a combination found
in spray-on ceilings.
That type of ceiling material
hasn't been used
in 20 or 30 years.
You know, it's as if
your victim found a hole
in the time-space continuum
and was murdered decades ago.
Brilliant theory, Dave.
Thanks.
Thank you.
STOKES: So this was
the Strip 50 years ago.
The Vegas my dad came to.
Now, any one of
the big hotels
has more rooms than
all these put together.
Nearly all the old casinos
that Rancho Linen serviced
have been torn down.
Except for this one,
on the west side.
Where Layla's body was found.
Le Château Rouge.
Man, last time I was
this deep in the hood,
I was on a case with Warrick.
(car alarm sounding in distance)
Got some track marks here.
11 inches apart.
Same as the other
ones I found.
Layla was wearing a pink sweater
when she left the Palermo.
(grunting, fabric ripping)
We have a crime scene.
No warrant needed.
If Layla did get inside,
somebody locked up after her.
STOKES:
Wow.
It's like someone
yelled "fire"
50 years ago,
and nobody came back.
Yeah.
You can still feel it
in the air.
Legends walked here.
Louis Armstrong,
Nat "King" Cole,
Dinah Washington.
First integrated casino
in town.
Place was smoking
so hot every night,
they added a 2:30 a.m. show.
Sinatra, the Rat Pack--
all the white headliners
and tourists
came down from the Strip.
Place was swinging till dawn.
Then, six months
after it opened,
the joint closed
overnight.
How come?
Rumor has it
the Kansas City Mob
didn't like the East Coast boys
poaching their pigeons.
Back then, there were only eight
or nine casinos on the Strip.
700 or 800 people were here
instead of there, well,
do the math.
This cart can match
the tracks I found.
Rancho Linen Service.
Hey, give me some light
over here, will you?
That's the only table
without a tablecloth.
We've got blood.
Better call P.D.,
track down the owner
of the building.
It's time to reopen
Le Château Rouge.
Whose car is that, man?
Building owner.
Château Rouge, man.
My parents came here.
They still
talk about it.
Good evening.
My name's
Gil Grissom.
I'm with the Crime Lab.
Well, I hope your people are
taking care with my property.
I understand it has
quite a history.
You're too young to remember.
I've heard stories.
Wasn't there a night
when Sammy Davis sang,
and the only way
they'd let him off the stage
was if he took the whole crowd
to breakfast?
More than once.
Come on in.
Have a drink.
Thank you, but I'm working.
Well, then you can
watch me drink.
In Rome, they illuminate
the ruins every night.
The Italians see beauty
in what... what used to be.
It's been 50 years since
I've seen lights on the Rouge.
She walks in beauty,
like the night.
My husband, Jules Rosenthal,
built this.
Do you know it was
the first casino
where blacks weren't
turned away at the door?
Your husband was
a brave man.
Oh, he liked making money.
He gave it the best
of everything.
The decor, the food, the music.
It was exciting.
Magical, really.
As long as it lasted.
But it died with him.
I haven't been inside since...
since he was murdered there.
Why didn't you
sell the property?
There's no such thing
as sentiment in Las Vegas.
They would have torn it down,
and I... I couldn't,
I couldn't bear that.
Would you like to go in now?
Mm-mm.
You can only wake up once
from a dream.
SANDERS:
Wow, you know
I have a glitter fetish,
don't you?
Lots of recent
activity over here.
"Jasmine."
Wasn't Layla's grandmother's
name Jasmine?
I think so, yeah.
I think that Layla
was trying to connect
with her roots.
I think I got a bullet
in the floor.
Impact blew the dust back,
so it must be recent.
Got something else
that wasn't here 50 years ago.
Cell phone.
It's Layla's.
That explains why
we didn't find one on her
or in her room.
Last function
was "video camera."
Hey, Greg.
Check this out.
KIP (on video):
Ladies and gentlemen,
Miss Layla Wells
will now be singing for you.
♪ Here I go again ♪
♪ I hear the trumpets
blow again ♪
That costume's
in the dressing room.
♪ Taking a chance on love ♪
Looks like Kip's
working the flashlight
and the camera.
♪ About the beats... ♪
(saxophone plays,
Layla screams)
GRISSOM:
Surprised by the sax man?
So he kills her,
wraps her up,
pulls her body out
of here on a cart,
comes back,
puts the cart back.
Puts the costume back.
Put everything back the way
it was 50 years ago.
(floorboards creaking)
(weak, raspy breathing)
GRISSOM:
Sir...
You're in custody at
Desert Palm Hospital.
You're being treated
for dehydration
and malnutrition.
Could you tell us
your name, please?
(deep breath)
Don't matter.
How long have you lived
at the Château Rouge?
Everybody wants a piece of you.
Drew and, and...
managers and fans.
But...
but Layla and me, we just...
we just gave to each other.
She, uh, (sniffles)
I looked out for her.
I cared about her.
I, I tried to make her
feel... safe.
Nobody else loved her.
Not like me.
Nobody.
I, uh...
I found out online about
where her grandma danced.
I thought it'd be a cool
surprise to take her.
Didn't you read
that part where it says,
"Don't go in after dark"?
I just wanted to get
a picture of her
in front of the place and get
back in the cab, but she...
(deep breath):
she was, like,
insane to get in there.
She pulled apart a fence.
She found some door
that wasn't locked.
(both laughing)
KIP:
Ladies and gentlemen,
Miss Layla Wells
will now sing for you.
OLD MAN:
She was so beautiful.
We were making sweet music.
Sweet music.
He was jealous.
Came at me.
(screams)
Shoved her.
(grunts, thuds)
(gunshot)
So you ran away not knowing
if Layla was dead or alive?
I looked for her for hours.
All around that place,
and up and down every street
in that neighborhood
for blocks, but...
she wasn't anywhere.
Guess she was still inside.
With him.
A young girl is dead.
I did it.
You got me.
♪ ♪
NARRATOR:
Inspired by Harlem's
famed Cotton Club,
New York restaurateur
Jules Rosenthal
created Le Château Rouge.
The casino flourished
until tragedy struck.
Former Sheriff
Claude Montgomery
recalls what happened.
Mrs. Rosenthal said
she thought she heard a ruckus
in the musicians' dressing room.
She went in there,
found her husband shot.
INTERVIEWER:
There were rumors
it was a Mob hit.
CLAUDE:
That's a good story, but no.
He was killed by one
of his employees.
A musician-- a guy named
Melchior Wilson,
a drug addict.
Took the money and ran.
Found his prints
all over the wallet.
Confessed to the whole thing.
(chuckles):
You actually
found a file
this old that rodents
hadn't nested in, huh?
Yeah.
The guy they arrested
evidently died in prison.
"Melchior Wilson."
Tenor saxophone player.
Yeah, the old guy we caught
had a .32 long Colt.
Nick ran it through IBIS.
Matched it to the bullet
from the Rosenthal homicide.
WILLOWS:
Maybe Melchior Wilson
ditched the gun at the Rouge,
and our squatter
discovered it 50 years later.
You know what we need?
Hm?
Exemplar wallets
made from reptile skin.
Somewhere a swamp
is in mourning.
Lizard, snake...
Alligator.
In the 1958 case,
Sheriff Montgomery
lifted a print
from an alligator wallet.
He matched it to a print
from a suspect
named Melchior Wilson.
That's the lift card
from his file.
That's a nice, clean print.
No serious flaws.
Compare it to this one.
Well, the one you
just lifted has voids
from the alligator skin.
The old one doesn't.
That print was
never on that wallet.
Melchior Wilson was
a musician at the Château Rouge.
His prints
could have been lifted
from anywhere in that room.
I think he was framed.
(distant siren wails)
Hey, Grissom.
(indistinct conversation,
mellow jazz playing)
Where on earth have you been,
stranger?
Hey, Nicole.
Hey, look who's here.
Hello, fellas.
Well, I'll be damned.
You're two years late.
George, deal him in.
Feeling lucky?
No, I can't, Sheriff,
I'm working.
What are
you doing here?
I was hoping to talk
to you actually.
About the Château Rouge.
One hand, you win, I'll talk.
$500 will buy you in.
Big blind's $20.
BRIDGES:
Chateau Rouge...
When I was playing the lounge
at the Dunes,
I used to make that my last stop
on the way home.
Lived on
the west side, then, huh?
Yeah, Sheriff,
you know.
We had to.
Vegas was known as
"Mississippi of the West."
Pearl Bailey,
Nat King Cole,
Sammy Davis, Lena Horne,
the Mills Brothers--
I booked them all into
the big rooms on the Strip.
But they could not stay
in the hotels.
They couldn't even gamble
in the casinos.
As a matter of fact,
they came in and out
through the kitchen.
You remember
beautiful Dorothy Dandridge?
There was something about her
going in for a swim
at one of the hotels.
They drained
the whole damn pool.
Sheriff,
it's up to you.
Twenty.
I'm gone.
Grissom?
BRIDGES:
The women at the Château Rouge--
mm-mm-mm!
They had such
tiny waists.
And cakes, too.
Ponytails was
the big thing then.
They all had cute
little ponytails.
Lord have mercy.
SCHLATTER:
And the flop.
Check.
No $20?
Raise to $50.
SCHLATTER:
Matter of fact, when they
whacked Jules Rosenthal,
they shuttered
that place so fast,
they paid the stagehands
in sugar bags full
of quarters and nickels,
and they were gone.
Melchior Wilson's arrest
must have set a speed record
for closing a homicide,
huh, Sheriff?
Those were the days.
SCHLATTER:
Turns a five.
MAN:
I fold.
Sheriff?
Twenty.
You in or out?
Check.
Twenty.
You haven't raised once.
Either the county's
still not paying you enough,
or you're bluffing.
All in.
Call.
Now is when
you show your hand, Sheriff.
Dead man's hand--
aces and eights.
Straight.
Hell...
I used to be able
to bluff better.
Wilson signed a confession.
Yeah.
But they say some of you guys
used to drive suspects
out into the dessert,
show them a hole in the ground,
give them a choice
to sign a confession
or get in the hole.
We got a good, clean print.
The file says that
you lifted the print
from Rosenthal's
alligator wallet.
Now I examined it.
Alligator skin
would've left voids.
You know, in the old days,
the criminals were afraid of us,
now it's
the other way around.
Does he look
familiar to you?
He's been squatting
at the Château Rouge.
Now, I ran his prints
against the unidentifieds
that you lifted
from the scene in '58.
This man was
all over the place.
With all the crime that's
going on in Vegas these days,
you got time to poke around
in my old cases.
Good to see you, son.
Thanks for the drink.
♪ ♪
And we know Drew Rich
didn't do it.
His alibi checks out.
Apparently, he's a big spender
on the hookers.
So, how did Layla get
punched in the gut?
She came out
of the dressing room,
sang for Kip on stage.
Then the old man came out
from somewhere
behind you.
To the left.
Layla screamed
and ran this direction.
Then Kip dropped
the flashlight,
so she probably
couldn't see
where she was going.
WILLOWS:
Matches her costume.
I think she ran into this.
It does match her bruises.
♪ About to beat
the band... ♪
(screaming)
Her death was an accident?
Why did the old man
confess to it?
Why won't he tell us
who he is?
What you doing?
These are from
the souvenir program
you collected.
We still don't have an I.D.
on the suspect.
But I'm thinking,
given his age,
and the fact
that he plays the sax--
maybe he worked there
back in the day.
Melchior Wilson
died in prison.
RILEY:
Which leaves these two--
Harry Bastille
and Stanley Brown.
We don't have anything on
either of these guys after '58.
No recordings,
no credits, no death records.
Well, hello, Harry.
GRISSOM: Mr. Bastille, we know
you didn't kill the girl.
But why did you
move the body?
Why didn't you call for help?
Didn't want anybody
coming in my space.
Wanted to spend my time in
the last place I was ever happy.
We were all like
a family back there.
A beautiful moment in time.
(door closes)
MAN:
Right this way, please.
Thank you for coming,
Mrs. Rosenthal.
Is the name Harry Bastille
familiar to you?
Um... there was a musician...
Would you take a look
at the man in this room,
and tell us
if you think
it could be Harry?
Well, that was
a very long time ago.
Please.
That's not Harry.
I'm sorry I
couldn't help you.
Mrs. Rosenthal,
that is Harry Bastille.
Well, you knew.
Why did you ask me
to go and look at him?
We think he may be the man
that murdered your husband.
He didn't shoot Jules.
I know, because I was there.
Do you know
Sheriff Montgomery?
Very well.
Well, I promise you there is
no evidence incriminating Harry.
You seem to me to be a woman
who doesn't change
her tastes very often.
I noticed last night
you had a fine bottle
of pink champagne
in your car.
It's the same rare champagne
that was found in the room
where your husband
was murdered.
Now... champagne usually
suggests a celebration.
Or, maybe, in this case...
a romance.
We had nowhere to be together.
So we took a chance
after the last show.
Baby,
you sure we're safe?
Everybody's gone home.
BASTILLE:
We were making sweet music.
Sweet music.
(door opens)
He was jealous.
You son of a bitch!
Came at me...
This is how you repay me?!
No! No!
Shoved her.
Harry wanted to say
that he did it.
And I... I couldn't
let that happen.
I took the cash
out of Jules' wallet
and gave it to him
and told him to run...
and never come back.
And then you
and Sheriff Montgomery
framed Melchior Wilson.
No.
I confessed.
The town was very
different then.
And the men who ran it
forced the sheriff
to arrest Melchior.
You see...
a white woman
could get away with murder...
but she couldn't love
a black man.
(playing
"Smoke Gets In Your Eyes")
♪ ♪
KIP (on TV):
♪ They asked me ♪
♪ How I knew ♪
♪ My true love was true ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh! ♪
♪ I, of course, replied... ♪
WILLOWS:
There's the people
who come to Vegas
wanting to become
rich or famous,
and then there's the people
that are from here.
And we know that
the odds are always
in favor of the house.
It's what built this town.
You didn't come here
to become famous, did you?
I came to play cards.
No, for real.
I did-- I came
to play cards.
I needed the money.
I thought I was in love
with this girl, in college,
but I kept
getting into debt
buying cadavers
and fetal pigs.
There was no money
left for the girl.
Science took the pot.
Well, maybe it just
wasn't the right girl.
Plus, poker allowed me
to be a loner
and still make money.
Oh. Right.
When was the last
time you played?
I can't remember.
You know, to most people,
risk is a bad thing,
but in Vegas,
it's a good thing.
See? You paid
for your pigs,
you got roots,
friends, family...
Well, a work family anyway.
Maybe it's time
to up the ante.