(door slams shut)
JEREMY KENT:
I never did get to tell
my side of the story.
I was accused of a crime
I did not commit,
I was held without bail
in the East Clark County
Detention Center,
awaiting trial.
I'd never been to jail before.
It's not a place
you want to be.
(door buzzing)
(door slams shut)
The prosecution
called on my cellmate
to testify against me.
He told them that
I had confessed to the murder
of Thomas Harrot.
It was a lie.
In exchange for his testimony,
my cellmate got
a suspended sentence.
I wanted to take the stand,
but my public defender
told me it was a bad idea,
and I trusted him.
(chuckles)
I thought jail was hell.
Then I got to the state pen.
I've been there for 18 years.
After being denied parole
in 2000,
I began studying the law.
I figured if nobody
was gonna help me,
I had to do it myself.
And I discovered there were
a lot of other innocent men
like me in prison.
There were new ways
to prove that.
Then two years ago,
I ran into my cellmate again,
and he revealed to me
that the testimony against me
had been his lawyer's idea.
(groans)
(clamoring voices)
GUARD:
Everybody on the ground!
That's when I discovered
that we had the same lawyer--
the late Benjamin Tripp,
Esquire.
Your Honors,
my court-appointed lawyer
conspired against me,
and the county prosecutor
just looked the other way.
Now, this was more
than a conflict of interest.
This was collusion.
18 years ago,
I was denied my constitutional
right to a fair trial.
Under the law, I'm entitled
to have my day in court.
WILLOWS:
It was 1991, the night
of the Rampart Casino fire.
My first solo.
The victim, Thomas Harrot,
called 911 to report
an intruder in his house.
He was 91 years old
and he lived alone.
First officer on the scene
found him down on the floor.
Blunt-force trauma to the head.
A rock was used
to break a window,
and that appeared to be
the point of entry.
The State Supreme Court
has granted Jeremy Kent
a new trial.
The standards and documentation
have changed substantially
since '91,
so we're going to reexamine
all my old evidence.
The house was demo'd
six months ago,
but I still have
the crime scene sketch,
so I can walk you through it.
The house is dark.
There's no car
out front.
Mr. Harrot
hadn't driven since he was 85.
So, to Kent,
the place must've
looked empty.
STOKES:
Well, it says here
two nearby houses
were also burglarized
around the same time.
The first one
was on Crawford,
and the second one
on Skidmore.
Lights out.
No cars.
And a rock used
to break the window.
A witness on Crawford
saw a man
running down the driveway.
Recognized him
as a neighborhood kid
and picked Kent out of a lineup.
Other than the rocks,
was there any evidence of Kent
at the other two houses?
No. The only physical evidence
that led to the suspect
was the print on the rock
that I found
right here.
Kent came here
to burg the place.
Yeah, and his plans changed
when he ran into Mr. Harrot.
Get out of my house!
(grunting)
Old man.
Half deaf. Half blind.
Mr. Harrot wasn't a threat.
There was no need to kill him.
I always thought
that tipped the jury.
Did you recover
a murder weapon?
No.
But the depression fractures
on the victim's skull
suggested a hammer.
Follow me.
So, there's
an alley here.
There was obviously a number
of shoe impressions
that evening, but this
particular one
was right here.
It was unique because
it was fresh
and it was facing the fence.
Now, Harrot's
neighbors
reported that their motion light
came on.
So, I figured that
maybe the suspect
jumped the fence.
So, I searched the yard.
I didn't find any shoe
impressions
on the other side of the fence.
So, all you had was
an eyewitness
who was a half a mile away,
testimony from Jeremy
Kent's ex-cellmate,
and a single fingerprint
from a rock.
Back then it was enough.
You got it figured out?
Legal just put
this on my desk.
(wry chuckle)
I've been subpoenaed
by Jeremy Kent.
He's requesting
a pretrial conference.
Yeah, he probably wants
to talk to you
about how he got life
based on a rock.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
(loud bang, glass shatters)
OPERATOR:
911. What's your emergency?
Someone tried
to get in my house.
Are they still there, sir? Sir?
(door opening)
I hear someone
in the other room.
I need the police.
I'm all alone.
What is your address?
HARROT:
901 West Westcroft. Hurry.
OPERATOR:
I'm dispatching a unit.
Please remain on the phone, sir.
HARROT:
I'll be right back.
OPERATOR:
No, sir...
HARROT:
I'm going to see
who's out there.
Be right back.
Sir!
Stay with me, sir...
When the first officers arrived,
the phone was still
off the hook.
Does that mean we have
the murder on tape?
No.
The victim's bedroom
faced the street,
so all we've got
is a lot of sirens passing by.
Figure they were going
to the fire.
Fortunately,
audio analysis
has come a long way since '91.
(video rewinding)
Be right back.
(phone clunks,
distant sirens wailing)
Play it again.
Be right back.
(phone clunks)
OPERATOR:
Sir?
Stay with me, sir...
Listen to the low end
of the frequency.
Does that sound
like an engine to you?
Yeah.
I think I can isolate
and amplify that.
(beeping)
(engine idling)
It's closer to the phone
than the sirens.
So, it had to be right outside
the bedroom.
Three minutes
into the call?
Cops didn't arrive
for almost 25.
Can you match that engine
to a specific
make and model?
Like the, uh, suspect's
1984 Pontiac 6000?
I can try.
(groans)
Two depressed
circular fractures
of the frontal skull.
Sam Barnard conducted
the autopsy.
Minimal documentation.
Listed COD
as intracranial hemorrhaging.
Can we call Dr. Barnard
for a consult?
Passed away in '98.
Loved chili dogs,
but his arteries didn't.
All right, two fractured ribs
on the left side.
A third fracture
on the right,
and a dislocation
from the vertebral column.
Barnard attributed
all of these other injuries
to the fall after the attack.
That's ridiculous.
A 90-year-old man may have bones
like eggshells,
but he can't possibly fall
on his left side and his right
side at the same time.
Logic dictates
that the thoracic injuries
were sustained
prior to the head blow.
Beaten, then killed.
You couldn't get away
with this quality of work today.
Hey.
I dug up the original
ME's notes.
And what did the good doctor
have to say
about the hairline fractures
to the femur and the tibia?
He described them
as age-related, osteoporotic
degeneration.
They could've just as easily
been caused by a struggle.
At the time you investigated
the Harrot murder,
how long had you been employed
by Las Vegas PD?
18 months.
Oh, that's all?
Prior
to the Thomas Harrot murder,
you always worked
under a supervisor?
Yes.
So,
this case was your first
unsupervised investigation?
It was my first solo case.
But all my casework was reviewed
by my supervisor.
Well,
regardless, it was in your best
interest to get a conviction?
I don't deal in convictions.
That's for the jury.
Still...
worked out pretty good for you.
Better than it did for me.
Is that a question?
Oh, I'm sorry if I'm wasting
your time here.
It's just I've been in here
for 18 years
for something I didn't do.
So, all I've got is time.
You know, I met
a drug dealer
in here who knew your husband,
Eddie Willows.
Apparently, he was a
very good customer.
I heard he died.
My condolences.
I'm sorry,
what was the question?
Were you taking any drugs,
legal or illegal,
at the time you were processing
this crime scene?
No.
Was it
because you were pregnant?
How is your daughter?
How is that relevant?
Oh, I'm laying a foundation.
That's how we refer to it
in the legal community.
Now, having a child
is a life-altering experience.
Did your pregnancy influence
your judgment?
No.
So, your condition didn't impose
any-any limits to the chemicals
you could use
in processing the crime scene?
No, all the evidence I collected
was bagged and tagged,
and all the tests were conducted
by the experts.
Who, like yourself,
are all employees
of the Las Vegas
Police Department
and, therefore, inclined
to give their employer
the answers they want.
I don't trust your lab results.
WILLOWS: Which is why you can
exercise your right
to hire the expert
of your choosing
to reexamine the evidence.
KENT:
Right, at my own expense.
You see, I haven't earned
that much money
in the last 18 years.
Hey.
I got the blood exemplar
for Thomas Harrot
from cold storage,
but the lab wasn't
doing DNA back then,
so Catherine's got to get a
buccal sample from the suspect.
What are you looking for?
The blood stains
that Catherine analyzed
are consistent with the victim,
but the lab didn't have ALS
until 1995.
So, I'm thinking
it's possible
that there was an area
of non-visible blood
from the suspect
that Catherine couldn't see.
Hmm.
What does that look like to you?
SIMMS:
A giant sperm cell.
Maybe a big comma.
Catherine never recovered
the murder weapon,
but she always suspected
that it was a hammer.
KENT:
Speaking of evidence,
per the ASCLD regulations,
all current evidence
examinations
must meet the 2009
forensic standards.
You've done your homework.
Which brings me to the only
physical piece of evidence
we have in this case,
which is item number CW-2,
the rock which you claim
you found
in Mr. Harrot's living room.
Now, I was convicted
on a five point of minutia
match,
which,
per ASCLD regulations,
is far from conclusive today.
Which makes the print
more prejudicial
than probative.
I maintain that
that print belongs
to the real killer
of Thomas Harrot.
And I am filing a motion
with the court
to have the rock excluded.
Have you got anything else?
Yes or no?
(car door shuts,
car remote chirps)
Hey, we got a big problem.
Bigger than "crime is up,
and our budget is down"?
Jeremy Kent
is filing a motion
to throw out the only
physical evidence
linking him
to the crime scene.
Ah, the infamous
rock, huh?
Yeah. ADA says that
it could be up to the judge.
Was your ridge structure
faded or broken?
How strong are your points
of identification?
Well, strong enough to confirm
an ID and get a conviction.
Catherine.
Okay.
It wasn't a road map.
It was a difficult comparison.
Then let's not take a
chance on losing this.
Oh, I know. I know.
Go back to the rock.
(camera shutter snaps)
(computer trilling)
(beep)
(typing)
(beeps)
(beeping)
I reexamined the rock.
Enhanced the ridge detail
in Photoshop,
which we didn't have in '91.
I developed a unique pattern
within the core
and matched it
to Kent's ten card print.
Is that a smiley face?
You don't see
those every day.
He lied. He was there.
I have something, too.
It's a theory.
Um, we'll need to go back
to the scene.
LANGSTON:
The toe end of the impression
was deeper than the heel end,
which tells me...
that the toe exerted
more pressure than the heel.
Which wouldn't have been
the case
if Kent was just
standing here.
How tall is he?
He's about your height.
I can't see
over the fence, unless...
I missed that.
The neighbors'
motion sensor light
went off, right?
Yes.
But you found no evidence of
the suspect being in their yard?
Right.
Yet something had
to set it off.
Maybe he...
Maybe he tossed the weapon.
Well, I searched the yard,
and I went back the next day
and searched it again, and...
The first thing
Grissom taught me--
people never look up.
(leaves rustling)
♪ ♪
Ray!
I've seen some crazy stuff
in my day,
but this has got
to take the prize.
Smoking hammer
in a tree.
Yes.
(sirens blaring)
(crackling)
LANGSTON:
You remember how tall
this tree was
back in '91?
I think it was just
below the roof line.
Jury's never gonna
believe this
No.
unless we document
the hell out of it.
So, let's go back
and get the video camera
and the chain saw.
LANGSTON: I sent a
copy of the videotape
over to the DA's office.
I think we may have Kent's
prints in the victim's blood.
Over time,
the bark must have encapsulated
the prints
like a fossil.
Ray, if this is
the murder weapon,
we have Kent
dead to rights.
(camera shutter clicking)
(computer chirps)
♪ ♪
HODGES:
According to Wendy,
the blood on the murder weapon
was from Thomas Harrot.
It's all coming together.
Just give me
the results.
I get it.
You're a little touchy
because you missed something
the first time.
Murder weapon,
which was your whole case.
But, as of now,
Catherine Willows,
you are a rock star.
Am I going to be able to
explain this to the jury?
You know, I'm available
for court testimony, if needed.
Okay?
Now, first, I chemically tested
the metal part of the hammer,
and I found ferric oxide.
While not specific,
it does indicate
that the hammer was exposed
to the elements
for a long period of time.
Next, I documented
the growth of the tree
around the hammer
using photos
from the original crime scene,
and the photos
that you took today.
Quercus agrifolia--
desert oak-- grows about
six to eight inches
a year, which means that
your tree probably grew
about nine feet in 18 years.
A bark collar
grew around the hammer
during that period of time,
which confirms
that the hammer was in the tree
for many years.
And therefore, no one can
accuse you of planting it.
Pardon the pun.
Unfortunately,
the scientific improbability
of getting a viable print
or DNA is a completely
separate issue,
but... I'll back you.
Good to know.
Hey, Catherine.
Did you get any
usable prints
off the hammer?
Yeah. Two.
Neither one of them is a match
to Jeremy Kent.
What?
Yeah, I did
a visual comparison.
Mandy peer reviewed.
I'm sorry, Catherine.
It just... It isn't him.
ECKLIE:
When Kent discovers
you found the
murder weapon
with someone else's
prints on it,
he's going to fast track
himself to an acquittal.
We have the print
on the rock,
which still puts him
at the scene.
But Kent's prints
aren't on the hammer.
So, clearly,
there was an accomplice
who probably committed
the murder.
Yeah. Who we still
need to identify.
Obviously.
Okay, pretrial hearing
is in 48 hours.
You're gonna have to
reveal the prints then.
It would be nice if Kent
would give us a name.
Yeah, well, why would he?
He's kept it a secret
for 18 years.
Then ask
without asking.
Sweat him with
the rock evidence.
VANDERPOOL:
The judge denied your motion.
The rock's back in play.
WILLOWS:
I reexamined the rock.
I enhanced the fingerprint
and photoed it.
And this time around,
I found several
highly unique points
of comparison, including this
happy face pattern,
which is an exact match
to your print.
VANDERPOOL:
And that print puts you
at the crime scene.
You were there.
You killed Thomas Harrot.
WILLOWS:
Mr. Kent, if there's
another explanation,
other than the obvious,
now would be a good time
to come clean.
(scoffs)
Once you're wearing these,
nobody believes
anything that you have to say.
Try me.
(sighs)
I was there,
but I didn't kill the guy.
I needed
to make some fast money.
I broke into those
other two houses.
I picked them
because it looked like
nobody was at home.
The old man's house
was my third stop.
I went inside,
there's a body on the floor.
I got the hell out of there.
Why not just call 911?
(scoffs)
Yeah, "Hello, I just
broke into a house,
"and I found a dead
body on the floor.
Oh, yeah, yeah, I'll just
wait right here for you."
Look, I was a reckless punk,
and I messed up
big-time.
I broke the law.
But I did not kill that old man.
Somebody else did that.
Why didn't you
mention this
18 years ago?
Because my lawyer advised me
not to admit that I was
at the scene of the crime.
It was the only honest piece
of advice he ever gave me.
You know what would give
your story more credibility?
If you could ID
the other suspect.
Lady, if I would've seen him,
that would've been the
first thing out of my mouth.
But whoever killed Harrot
was long gone
by the time I got there.
We're done here.
Oh, sure, yeah.
Why would you admit
to making a mistake
that cost me
the last 18 years of my life?
All I want is my life back.
Is that asking too much?
Hey.
Jim.
Thanks for coming by.
Sure, you bet.
So, we're all
just passengers
on the time train.
(chuckles)
Well, you got that right.
So, you hit a snag.
Well, Jeremy Kent now admits
that he was at the Harrot house.
And when he got there,
the old man was already dead.
I call that "perp fiction."
The problem is, is that
his story is consistent
with the new evidence
I have yet to disclose.
Oh, come on, Catherine,
you know...
I had this guy pegged
as the bad guy
the minute I laid eyes on him
18 years ago, and so did you.
(sighing)
What if he's telling the truth?
Wrong place, wrong time.
Oh, you gotta
tune that out.
That's all bull.
All that matters
is what you got on him.
Now, these guys lie because,
well, because they're good at it
and because
they're hiding something.
And the thing they're hiding
is usually
the thing
that makes them guilty.
A million years ago,
uh, back when Eddie and I
first started dating,
we, uh, went to a party
and, um, you know,
we drank our fair share
and it was time to leave
and he tosses me the keys
'cause I'm the responsible one.
So, you know, I'm driving
and he starts singing
this stupid song,
which I've completely
blanked from my memory,
and one moment I'm just
laughing hysterically
and the next he has grabbed
the wheel from my hands
because I almost ran over a man.
And in that moment, my life
would've changed completely,
because of a bad decision.
So...
What makes me any different
than Jeremy Kent?
You know, Eddie was right.
You are the responsible one.
And if you had
hit that guy,
you would've called
the cops.
Because you would've
taken responsibility
for your actions.
Now, Jeremy Kent
is a jailhouse lawyer.
He's a scumbag.
His freedom, his whole life
depends upon getting you
to doubt yourself.
Don't let him live
rent free in your head.
WILLOWS:
I need your help.
I want to run
the case.
The question:
Does the evidence support
my initial conclusion
that Jeremy Kent
killed Thomas Harrot?
I'll start.
The print on the rock
is even stronger than before.
The broken window was
the only sign of forced entry,
and Kent admits to it.
Unknown shoe impression
at the victim's yard.
Same size but
never matched
to any of Jeremy Kent's shoes.
That makes it equivocal.
SANDERS:
Archie is still
working on the 911 tape,
trying to match
the engine noise
to Kent's car.
STOKES: Two unknown prints
on the murder weapon.
Neither one is a match to Kent.
Sounds like that
would exclude him.
What if...
What if... he really
did kill the old man
and a second suspect tossed
the hammer over the fence?
An accomplice
would make sense.
Seven out of ten
breaking and entering cases
in Las Vegas involve
multiple suspects.
That would mean that
the second suspect
probably touched
it last,
which is why we
only got his prints.
If there was an accomplice,
why didn't Kent give him up?
Because sometimes there
is honor among thieves.
If he knew he
was going down,
why drag someone else
down with him?
STOKES:
I don't know about that.
If any of these guys thought
they could cut a deal,
they'd roll over
on their mother.
I think you're both right.
People are motivated
by self-interest.
But there are certain
human bonds
that trump
even our base instincts--
love, blood, fear.
Right, there's people I love
but I wouldn't go to prison
for any of them.
My money's on fear.
SANDERS:
So, what would Kent
have to be afraid of?
He wasn't connected
to a gang or organized crime.
What about his family?
He was living on his own.
His closest relative
was an uncle.
Sometimes your friends
are your family.
Did you check
the prison visitor log?
The DA said that he's never
had any visitors.
SANDERS:
Kent never made it
to college.
Most of his friends
were probably from high school.
Okay, I'll call the high school,
get his yearbooks, see if any
of his old teachers
still work there.
We find the accomplice,
we find the truth.
Hey, Arch.
Hey.
Got your text.
Check this out.
A forensic auto expert
sent me over an engine
signature database.
So, I compared the noise
on the 911 tape
to a Pontiac 6000.
No match.
That's okay.
We have a new theory
that Kent had an accomplice.
Maybe the car on the tape
belongs to him.
Well, that explains a lot.
(engine idling)
Hear that jingling sound?
Yeah, like, uh,
keys shaking together.
Mm-hmm.
That's a heat riser from a
'60s- or '70s-era Dodge engine.
Now...
from zero to 27 seconds,
that jingling is constant.
Tells me the car was idling.
Maybe one of them
went into the house
while the other one
waited in the car.
JOHNSON: Look, at 27 seconds,
the engine revs up and down.
Somebody's hitting the gas.
At 27 seconds,
Thomas Harrot
was on the phone
with the 911 operator
saying someone was
already in his house.
Listen to this.
At two minutes and 45
seconds into the tape,
the Dodge revs and drives away.
And then 10 seconds
before that...
(two thuds)
Wait, slow that down.
Play it again.
(two thuds)
Car doors slamming?
Two separate doors.
There was definitely
two of them.
So, we know at some point
they were both out of the car.
Question is,
were they both in the house?
Something about
the hammer prints
wasn't really sitting
right with me,
so I reexamined it.
Now, the full print
on the shaft,
that's a no-brainer,
that's clearly not Kent's.
But the partial?
That's a different story
altogether.
Check out the, uh,
the top edge here.
That's not print surface,
that's regular skin.
I think the suspect was
holding the hammer like this.
You can see the inside edge of
my pinky is covering the base.
There could've been
other prints,
but they weren't in blood
so they wouldn't have been
preserved over time.
You only got a ten card on Kent.
That doesn't include
the inside of his fingers.
Need to get some major
case prints on this guy.
That partial could be his.
Thank you, Nick.
You're welcome.
ADAMS:
Let me guess--
you still go through
your high school
yearbooks?
Like you don't?
I can't. I burnt them.
It was very cathartic.
Oh, look, here he is.
Jeremy Kent
and Sabrina Littee.
You know, Archie identified
a Dodge from the 911 tape.
This could be it.
That's not just
any Dodge.
That's a '68 Super Bee.
Classic muscle car.
We got the license.
Yeah.
Okay, the car
was registered
to an Arthur Littee
from 1988 to 1993.
Want to bet she's his daughter?
Maybe Sabrina took Daddy's car
out for a night out on the town.
I'll call Brass.
(doorbell rings)
BRASS:
Oh. Hello, young man.
I'm a police officer.
I'm looking for Sabrina Owen.
Hey, Mom,
somebody's at the door!
And tell Sam and Katie
to hurry up!
Hi.
Oh, uh, hi.
I'm I'm Detective Jim
Brass, Las Vegas Police.
Are you Sabrina Owen,
used to be Sabrina Littee?
Yes.
Can I help you?
Yeah, I'd like to ask you
a few questions
about Jeremy Kent.
Hey!
Hey, hey, hey, guys.
Uh-uh, slow down.
You're on the pink team.
Sorry.
Yes, yes.
Jeremy Kent.
Wow, I haven't...
I haven't heard that name
in such a long time.
I'll bet.
Isn't he, um,
isn't he in prison?
Well, he's trying to get out.
He's been granted a new trial.
I'm just doing
some routine follow up.
I know the two of you
went to high school together.
What can you tell me
about him?
Oh, um...
I remember he liked to
play up his bad boy rep
to impress the girls.
Did it work?
Did it work on you?
Uh, no.
(laughing):
No.
I mean, he definitely
tried, so.
I mean, the truth is,
I didn't really know
him that well.
Then how come he was driving
your father's Super Bee
the night he killed
Thomas Harrot?
Mom! We're going to be late!
Just a minute.
Okay, look...
Jeremy and I were dating,
but nobody knew.
We kept it a secret.
Why?
Because I wanted
it that way.
He wasn't my type, and
that was the appeal.
You know how it is.
Hmm. What about the car?
So, yeah, yeah, I-I let Jeremy
use the car sometimes.
I didn't know how
to say no to him.
Where were you
the night of the murder?
I was at home with my parents
watching news coverage
of the Rampart fire.
KATIE: Mom!
(horn honking)
I'm going to need some contact
information on them.
Mom, we're going to be late!
Just a minute!
Mountain View Cemetery,
plot 921.
Look, I'm sorry.
Look, my husband's
an attorney.
So, don't talk to
me, talk to him.
No, no, I understand.
I understand.
I totally understand.
Listen, this is a, uh...
this is a warrant
for the Super Bee.
According to the DMV,
it's currently registered
to you now.
So, we're going
to take the car.
Enjoy the game.
♪ ♪
(whirring)
We've got something.
(camera shutter snaps)
WILLOWS:
That look like blood?
What are the odds that's window
glass from the house?
About the same
as finding a hammer in a tree.
(high-pitched whirring)
The elemental composition
of the glass
that you found in the car
is indistinguishable
from the exemplars that
you collected 18 years ago.
Also...
both had traces of diazinon.
Insecticide?
Yes, indeedy.
Which was banned in 1999.
So...
I'll give you
a money-back guarantee
that this piece of glass
was once part of the victim's
living room window.
Hey, I just got your results.
She's fast,
but she's thorough.
Um, the blood on the glass did
not belong to Jeremy Kent.
It was female, and
it wasn't in CODIS.
Okay, so, we know
that Kent and his accomplice
both entered the house
through the broken window.
Didn't the getaway car
belong to his girlfriend?
Yeah.
(sirens blaring)
(groans)
(engine idling)
BRASS:
We have
DNA that puts your wife
at the crime scene.
You were there with Jeremy,
weren't you?
Don't answer that.
You better come up
with some answers
or you're not going anywhere.
Jeremy got me pregnant...
Don't say a word.
Listen.
My client was
a 16-year-old kid
who got mixed up
with the wrong guy.
But she got herself
straightened out.
We've been married
for 15 years.
I adopted our
son Tyler.
There's no conspiracy here.
And we are here
as a courtesy.
So, either you
charge her
or we walk.
Who are you-- the lawyer
or the husband? Which one is it?
(clears throat)
I want to talk.
Not until we have an agreement.
No, honey, I want to talk.
Jeremy got me pregnant.
I couldn't tell my parents
about the baby.
He said we could move to LA,
start over.
We didn't have
the money.
He promised me that he was
going to get the money
and I was naive, you know.
I was naive to believe him.
So you were with him
when he robbed those houses?
MR. OWEN:
Sabrina, I am advising you
not to say
anything else.
I waited in the car.
You didn't wait in the car
at Thomas Harrot's house.
I did.
At first.
The house was
supposed to be empty.
But then,
I heard Jeremy's voice
and I knew something was wrong.
So what happened
when you went inside?
I saw the old man
lying on the floor.
And Jeremy was standing
over him holding a hammer.
He was already dead.
We have your fingerprints
in blood
on that hammer.
You're lying.
Get out of my house!
(thud)
(grunting)
(Sabrina screams)
(thump)
I didn't kill him.
No, no, no. No.
Jeremy gave me the hammer
to throw away.
Honey.
You believe me, don't you?
Counselor, why don't
you explain
to your client
the felony murder rule?
Why don't you explain it to her?
'Cause I don't know
who you are anymore.
Baby...
Honey, don't leave me.
Honey, please don't leave me.
Baby, I'm begging you.
Baby, please don't leave me!
(door closes)
(crying):
Oh, God!
Sit down.
Relax.
(crying):
Oh, my God!
The felony murder
rule states
that when a murder
is committed,
(sobbing)
during the commission
of a felony,
like a burglary,
all the participants
can be charged
with first-degree
murder...
regardless of who actually
swings the hammer.
Let me lay out our case
that we have against you
and your accomplice.
Due to the granting
of your new trial,
the lab reopened
your case.
We found the murder weapon,
a claw hammer.
And we found
your print
on the base of the handle
of that hammer.
And we found your accomplice's
print in blood
on the body
of that handle.
We've identified your accomplice
as Sabrina Owen,
formerly Sabrina Littee...
your girlfriend
at the time
of the murder.
And she's made a full
statement implicating you
as the killer
of Mr. Thomas Harrot.
You're freaking lying to me.
These are copies
of all pertinent documents,
as well as a transcript
of Mrs. Owen's
sworn confession.
"I saw the old man on the floor.
"Jeremy was standing over him,
holding a hammer.
He was already dead."
I can't believe
she would do this to me.
Yeah,
you protected her
for 18 years and she sold you
out in five minutes.
I kept my mouth shut
so my kid would have a mother.
Everything I've done
I did for them.
Why did you ask for a new trial?
You had to have known that we
might find out about Sabrina.
No, I didn't.
Not after all this time.
Then why?
'Cause I'm entitled
to a fair trial.
But you're still guilty.
(sighs)
I just think
it was more than that.
I mean, you've been in here for
18 years, she's been out there
with your kid,
living a normal life.
I think
you just got tired
of having to pay for the
crime all by yourself.
All I think about in here
is that kid
who has no idea I even exist.
Sabrina never visited me once.
She never wrote.
She never even sent a photo
of my girl or boy.
I don't even...
I don't even know a name.
Your son's name is Tyler.
Did Sabrina cut a deal?
No deal.
She's been charged.
She'll stand trial.
So, she'll testify against me.
That's up to the DA.
Well, you tell the DA
to make sure that happens.
You're hoping that your son
will be there.
Might be the only chance
I have in my life to see him.
That's not right.
Maybe not.
But...
you had a choice.
Thomas Harrot didn't.
my sympathy for him.