(water dripping)
♪ ♪
(unzips pants)
(door opens)
(footsteps approaching)
(breathing sharply)
(knocking)
Open the door, please.
Come on, open up.
Come on, man, please!
Open the door!
(loud banging)
Oh...
(man screaming, clattering)
(crash)
(man screaming)
(liquid sloshing)
Whoa.
(thud)
(loud banging)
(man screaming, clattering)
(liquid sloshing)
(man screaming)
(door opens)
(grunts)
You seen The
Incredible Hulk?
This dude was
this big, man.
And he comes
out like that,
but he was
all red.
And he comes out, and
he gets in his car...
(sirens in distance,
indistinct radio transmissions)
Three detectives
for one homicide?
Callout was for
an officer down.
Usually brings in
more help than we need.
Don't believe
they're LVPD.
MAN:
He was kicking this door,
and he was pounding...
David?
Hey.
Um, there's not
much room in there.
I'm more than happy to wait.
♪ ♪
(camera shutter clicking)
(shutter clicking)
Catherine,
this man's arm is gone.
No, it isn't.
(camera clicking)
Tissue is ragged.
It's not dismembered,
it's disarticulated.
Takes an awful lot of rage
to tear a man's arm off.
Or an awful
lot of PCP.
Try not to get too far
ahead of the evidence.
(shutter clicking)
Department of Justice.
Actually, he's FBI.
Meet Agent William Ray Hatford.
So those suits you
were talking to...?
Yeah, they're all in
from D.C. on a case.
They stopped here to get gas,
Agent Hatford came in
to take a leak, never came out.
They found him like this.
They notified
their field office,
and then
they called us.
They acknowledged
our jurisdiction.
That's refreshing.
BRASS:
Yeah, whoever did this
took his gun,
his badge and his wallet.
I mean, this doesn't feel
like a simple robbery.
He's supposed to get ahead
of the evidence.
BRASS:
So I'm gonna take
the agents down to the station,
get their statements.
They're kind of shook up.
Feds are human, too, I guess.
(shutter clicks)
Ray, I know you're not doing
what it looks like
you're doing,
so what are
you doing?
LANGSTON:
This man lost more than an arm.
The stoner outside
said a big red hulk did this.
Maybe he was right.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
♪ ♪
I don't think this hunk
of flesh came from him.
Maybe it came from the killer.
There are no defensive wounds
on the victim's body
suggesting a sign of struggle.
Maybe it came
from another victim.
Witness on the scene
didn't mention anyone else.
Another argument for DNA.
All right, I'll call PD
and have them check
all the hospitals.
I'll get his prints.
Actually, would you mind
if I did that?
Not at all.
(beep)
(trilling beeps)
Um, is-is there
a problem?
Actually, there is a problem.
There's no ridge detail
on any of his fingertips. See?
This looks surgical.
Maybe microdermabrasion.
What kind of FBI agent
doesn't have fingerprints?
Agent Hatford had been working
undercover for several years.
His fingerprints were removed
as a security measure.
See, these days, the bad
guys can run prints, too.
They've seen Donnie Brasco.
They know how we work.
Well, I presume the Bureau
requires a confirmed ID.
That's the procedure.
Since we don't
have fingerprints,
we'll have to run DNA.
I'll get an STR
profile to Quantico
for verification
as soon as possible.
Fine.
Where are you
on a suspect?
Oh, well, right now
all we have
is the eyewitness report
of a guy who looked like
the Incredible Red Hulk.
But CSI's got some
surveillance video
from the gas station,
and they're analyzing it now.
Is it possible that this
case is somehow connected
to the case
you're working on?
Of course it's possible.
We work with scumbags every day.
Like who?
If I had a name,
I wouldn't be standing here.
Agent Stanley,
would you give us
a moment alone?
Please?
How long have you two
been working together?
It feels like forever.
(chuckling)
All of our active files
are at our command post.
I can assure you, Captain,
you will have the full
cooperation of the FBI.
Great.
SANDERS: All right,
that is Agent Hatford
making his last trip
to the can.
And that is
a class two misdemeanor.
Well, the FBI does not
concern itself with state
fire codes, Greggo.
SANDERS:
Okay...
almost there...
Now.
Take a look at the mirror.
Looks like a vintage muscle car.
And that face...
It's a bloody mess.
Yeah, you should've
seen the bathroom.
I'll have Brass
put out a broadcast.
AGENT:
Investigation's been focused
on human trafficking.
Underage women in
the Vegas sex trade,
smuggled in from
South America,
Brazil, primarily.
Yeah, there's been
a little chatter
about that on the streets.
But, uh,
nothing really concrete.
They've only been operating
for a few months.
Low key, select clientele,
contacted directly
by email only.
Agent Hatford was
on source-targeting
and recruitment.
He did most of our
field interviews.
Hookers, pimps,
mid-level scumbags.
We're just starting to put
the network together.
Who'd you piss off
to pull this duty?
This is important work.
We requested this.
Homeland Security
gets lion's share
of the Bureau's resources
these days.
What do you think, we
just run around and
chase terrorists,
spy on Americans,
and investigate
paranormal activity,
is that it?
Sorry.
No offense intended.
I hope your taxes are in order.
I think you just
bought yourself an audit.
Our case files
and suspect interviews.
Anybody in there
with the physical
strength to do what was
done to Agent Hatford?
I doubt it.
Did Agent Hatford wear a wire?
Sometimes.
I don't know if those tapes
were transcribed yet.
We haven't been able to ID
the head of the operation.
He's referred to
on the street as "Os Punho,"
which is Portuguese
for "The Fist."
Anybody look familiar?
I don't know.
ROBBINS:
Gradual application
of dry heat
is generally
the best way
to bring a muscle
out of rigor.
And the man can cook.
The question is: What are
we having for dinner?
This muscle has
two heads
and a shared, single point
of insertion.
Judging from size and weight,
uh, we can rule out
Biceps femoris.
Biceps brachii, then.
The tissue is clearly
infected.
In fact,
it looks necrotic.
What do you make
of these, uh,
linear streaks?
Well, I think
they're hemorrhage lines.
I bet this guy was
shooting steroids.
With a dirty needle?
That seems pretty stupid,
even for somebody stupid enough
to kill an FBI agent.
I guess he neglected
to swab his skin.
Contaminants could've been
pushed in with
the injection.
The muscle looks like it fell
right off the bone.
Like a piece
of well-cooked chicken.
You know, I found some pieces
of mirror glass
inside the muscle.
(screaming)
Maybe this guy was
in so much pain
that he had to rip it out
right then and there.
HATFORD:
You listening to me, Vinnie?
I asked you a question.
What are you doing
on Hill Street?
Agent Hatford taped
this interview
the night before
he was killed.
I guess those muscles make you
deaf and dumb, huh?
The suspect at the gas station
was heavily muscled.
Which is why I figured
this could be the guy.
Oh, don't eyeball me like that,
Vinnie.
I am the F-B-friggin'-I,
are you feelin' me?
Now put your hands
on the hood.
We know about all those
little sweet ass
Brazilian hos
you be running.
And we don't
like it.
But you know who
bothers us more?
That armpit
you work for.
That sewer rat.
Where is he?
How would I know?
I don't work
for no one.
"Os Punho."
You don't know who I'm
talking about? "The Fist"?
You tellin' me you know nothin'
about "The Fist"?
How would you like
a fist up your...
Unfortunately,
Vinnie was only referred to
as "Vinnie."
No last name.
And Agent Hatford
never had a chance
to write up a full report.
Tox on your orphaned
biceps.
Nandrolone decanoate,
methenolone enanthate,
oxymetholone,
and HCG.
That's quite a cocktail.
Maybe
this "Vinnie" is
a bodybuilder.
It could be.
This specific mix
was very popular
with the local weight-
lifting community
a while back.
The VELCORE Lab
was supplying it
to all sorts of athletes.
Before we shut them down.
You know, there is someone who's
very familiar with this case.
And he's real easy to get to.
BRASS:
He's a murder suspect,
he's using your juice.
His name is Vinnie.
If you know
his last name,
we'd appreciate
the information.
Let me get this straight.
You guys bust my company
for selling roids,
give everybody else a chance
to plead out for easy time
so the D.A. can make
an example out of me,
because I'm-- me personally--
I'm corrupting the very fabric
of American sports.
You ruin my life.
And now you want
me to help you?
That pretty much sums it up,
yeah.
Screw you.
Yeah, I figured you'd have
an adverse reaction to that.
I've only got 22 days left
of a 16-month rap,
which means there is nothing
you can do for me or to me.
Yeah, that's
why I decided
to bring in an associate.
Agent Bechman, would you
come in here, please?
You work much
with federal agents?
Actually, this is my first time.
I'm a CSI-1.
Were you held back?
Career change.
I was a physician.
And screw you,
too, Fed.
I... would prefer
to just educate you.
For instance,
did you know
that many people
convicted
of drug offenses
continue to engage in some form
of drug trade while in prison?
Now, United States
v. Delgado held
that if you so much
as speak to someone for the
purpose of dealing drugs,
even while incarcerated,
that's Conspiracy to Conduct
a Racketeering Enterprise.
Doesn't matter whether or not
you handed out the drugs.
Your business activities
from prison
violate the RICO statute.
Even if I did something
like that--
and I am not saying
that I did--
I already got busted for it.
That is double jeopardy.
Not according to Garrett
v. United States.
The double
jeopardy clause
does not bar
cumulative punishments
for continuing
criminal enterprises
and underlying predicate
offenses.
Your man knows the law.
That's our Miles.
If we determine that you do have
some information
regarding this suspect
which you choose not to share,
then I can promise
that the full weight
of the Department of Justice
and RICO section 1963
will be brought
to bear upon you,
and your 22 days
in Clark County Prison
will become 20 years
in a federal penitentiary.
Oh, and we get to take
everything you own.
His name's Vinnie Mingus.
He's one of those
Supreme Force Fighters.
He's supposed to be
fighting today.
(crowd cheering)
(groans)
Yeah!
♪ ♪
(cheering)
(grunting)
BRASS:
Well, it sure ain't
the Mandalay Bay.
Welcome to human cockfighting.
Man, this is as real
as it gets.
It's like
a bar fight
spilled out
into the alleyway.
Like the Marquis
of Queensberry,
I prefer boxing--
the sweet science.
There's Mingus.
BRAS:
Somebody around here
must have seen him.
Let's take
a look around.
(cheering continues)
WOMAN:
Yeah.
Scotch, rocks.
MAN:
Vinnie, please.
You've got
to sit down.
VINNIE:
Get out of my way!
(retching)
(snorting and coughing)
Hey, Brass, I got him.
(coughing)
Didn't I get the message across
with the last guy?
I'm sorry,
you can't come in here.
LVPD, clear everybody
out of here.
I want to have a word
with Mr. Mingus.
Please,
I'm his doctor.
What kind of getup is that?
Don't touch me.
We both know that
gun's not loaded.
Las Vegas Police.
Mr. Mingus, you're
under arrest.
You're gonna have to shoot me
before you arrest me.
Come on, go ahead.
Shoot me.
I've got backup coming.
He's not going anywhere.
(screams)
STOKES:
Don't make it
harder on yourself!
(grunts)
(breathing heavily)
They're all fake!
They're fake!
(cheering)
They're all fake!
They're fake!
(cheering continues)
(laughing)
Vinnie, you're making
a fool of yourself!
I'm making a fool
out of myself?!
Whoa!
Hold your fire!
Put the gun down!
These guns are not even loaded.
You see?
(gunshot)
(gasps and murmurs)
Chaos erupted today
at the Delos Auditorium--
home to the Supreme Force
Fighting Championship--
after a police chase
through the crowded theater
ended in the bizarre apparent
suicide of Vinnie Mingus...
BRASS:
Thanks for your
cooperation, Doctor.
Thank you.
Okay, so the fight doctor says
that Mingus came to him
with his arm all torn up.
He's infected and feverish.
So, the doctor
wraps up his arm,
tells him to go
to a hospital,
Mingus refuses.
So he gives him a bunch of
antibiotics, hopes for the best.
Clearly, Mingus was involved
in some kind of assault.
Why didn't the doctor inform
the authorities?
He says he knows Mingus
and he's afraid of him.
Says Mingus is half psychotic
on a good day.
You know, maybe the
Agent Hatford interview
spooked him--
Mingus goes nuts, follows him,
takes him out.
Well, thank you,
Captain,
for all your
hard work.
Sure. So what's next?
"Os Punho"?
We're going to finish
what we started.
Keep me in the loop.
All right?
All right.
We will.
LANGSTON:
In Mingus's gym bag,
we found Agent Hatford's
notebook, his badge
and his gun.
It's empty.
A Davis P-380.
It's a weird gun
for a fed to carry.
Oh, my bad.
It's a street piece.
Uh-huh.
Must be Mingus's.
Which means Agent Hatford's
weapon is still unaccounted for.
Hmm.
Roid Boy was sending out
a lot of pictures.
They're all
of the Feebs.
Looks like he
was conducting
an investigation of his own.
STOKES:
Track down that number.
Run fingerprints, DNA.
Swab last for trace.
We always save the best
for last.
Yes, David,
that's already getting old.
Hey, Catherine.
Yeah?
Do you remember a Jane Doe
we found off of Spencer Street
about three months ago?
Sadly, you're gonna
have to be
more specific
than that.
Pretty brunette,
caught up in
prostitution, underage.
Gunshot wound to the head.
Okay, yes, I do remember her.
I saw a
picture of her
on a board
in the FBI command post.
She's mixed up
in this human trafficking ring.
Did the feds talk to her?
Yeah.
And they got it on video.
WILLOWS:
That's quite an
assembly line.
STOKES:
Out with the old,
in with the new.
ADAMS:
Yeah.
Watch this.
STANLEY:
Everything that you say
in this room
is confidential.
Now, do you know
what "confidential" means?
My speak is not good,
but...
I understand good.
Okay, how old are
you, sweetheart?
Twenty-one.
No, I know that that's what
they told you to say.
Sweetie, how old
are you really?
Sixteen.
It's okay.
You know,
we've seen
a lot of young girls
like you on Hill Street
being shoved
into limos
and forced to do
God-knows-what
with dirty, old men.
Who brought
you here, Rio?
I can't.
He will kill me.
I will be dead, you understand?
You won't be dead,
because we will protect you.
But you need
to help us.
Who is he?
HATFORD:
Look, we're trying to
help you out here.
We're giving you the
benefit of the doubt.
But you're a prostitute,
a criminal.
Unless you help us,
you're gonna go to jail.
(sobbing):
No more talk, no more.
I go to jail, okay?
Please take me to jail.
Please take me
to jail.
BECHMAN:
Let her go.
Their files indicate that
they never reinterviewed her.
Three days later, she was dead.
ADAMS:
Maybe Os Punho
found out that she was picked up
and questioned.
Had her killed on the street
as a warning to the other girls.
♪ ♪
(phone ringing)
What's happening, Professor?
LANGSTON:
I just printed
Vinnie Mingus's gun.
At least, I thought
it was his gun.
What do you mean?
It appears to have
Agent Hatford's prints
all over it.
Now, why would an FBI agent
be carrying a street gun
with a filed-down serial number
on it?
He wouldn't--
maybe it's a drop gun.
Are you saying Agent Hatford
was dirty?
It happens.
Maybe Agent Hatford was mixed up
with Mingus or Os Punho somehow.
Yeah, it happens.
WOMAN:
Excuse me, sir.
Hold on.
Captain Brass,
you have a 420
on Hill Street.
(sighs)
Hooker or pimp?
Agent Bechman, I was
actually gonna call you.
What are you
doing here?
The operation
was undercover.
Okay, David, what have you got
for me tonight?
(beeping)
Oh, man.
It's Agent Stanley.
(phone ringing)
Yeah, Wendy?
Captain, I just got this e-mail
from FBI Quantico,
and there is no record
of any agent
by the name
of William Ray Hatford.
They're saying this guy
was a fake.
Okay, thanks.
ROBBINS:
There's stippling and
powder burns around the wound.
It was a close-range shot.
Somebody
probably walked
right up behind her
on the street.
Looks like Emma was suicidal.
Those are old scars.
Yes, but vertical,
which means she was serious.
Guess she finally got her wish.
PHILLIPS:
Hey, Live Scan
got a hit
on her prints.
Her real name is Emma Mosler.
She's got a record.
She did two years
for prostitution.
So, she was a prostitute
posing as an FBI agent
posing... as a prostitute?
To bust a prostitution ring?
Okay, take everything,
and we'll figure out
what's real and what's
not real later.
There was this trucker
in Gerald, Missouri,
who rolled into town
and told everybody
he was a DEA agent.
Started busting
every meth head in town.
It was months before
somebody finally caught on.
Don't try to make
me feel better.
BRIGGS:
Can I give it
a try, Jim?
I've been
with the Bureau
15 years.
This would have fooled me.
Well, it didn't fool
Vinnie Mingus.
He knew they were fakes.
He thought we were fakes, too.
Blew his brains out
trying to prove it.
Be nice to find Agent Bechman
before Os Punho does--
we anywhere on that?
No.
All we have
is a lease made out to...
I Can See For Miles,
Incorporated.
All right,
Nevada tags.
Alpha, Charlie,
David, Foxtrot,
three, four, eight.
Registered owner is
I Can See For Miles, Inc.
Same address
as their command post.
It looks like Miles
covered all his bases.
Yeah, well, maybe Emma
didn't cover hers.
We know when
and where
she swiped her card.
The bill's got
to get sent somewhere.
LANGSTON:
A halfway house?
BRASS:
Yeah...
well, we think
she was stealing identities
from the residents.
How hard
could that be?
I'm Detective Jim Brass,
Las Vegas Police.
This is Ray Langston
from the crime lab.
Is there someone in charge here
that I can talk to?
That would be me.
Until 4:00.
Do you know
this woman?
Yeah, sure, I know her.
Emma.
You know, most of
the ladies here
are pretty nasty,
but man, oh, man, she is sweet.
I seen her in
the shower once
shaving her pits.
High point of my life.
Is she a resident?
Uh-huh.
Okay.
Let's see.
Says here that Emma
signed out two days ago.
Never signed
back in.
And nobody noticed?
Look, this isn't
a lockup facility.
Everybody
here is free
to come and go.
They're just supposed
to sign in and out.
How about this guy?
You seen him?
Yeah, sure, um, Miles Gelson.
Uh, he came to us
courtesy of CNPH.
Central Nevada
Psychiatric Hospital.
Very good.
LANGSTON:
What about this man?
Hmm.
Billy Ray Salvy,
another resident.
He's been MIA for three days.
Another resident.
So, we've been working a case
with a couple of...
Crazy people?
It's okay to
call them that.
That's what I call them.
Look, um,
you're welcome
to talk to Miles if you'd like.
He's here?
According to this.
Here we go.
No, no, no, hold on.
We'll take it
from here.
Thanks.
Hello, Miles.
We have some
questions
that need to be answered.
(whispers):
I'm undercover here.
All the people,
they think
I'm with them.
So... if you want to talk...
...put handcuffs on me,
and take me outside.
Got to be careful,
very careful,
'cause I can't,
I can't blow this cover.
I understand.
Just one second.
Captain,
the man is clearly
a fantasy-prone
personality type.
I think it's best if we...
go along with it.
You're the doctor.
(shouting):
Miles Gelson,
we have a warrant
for your arrest.
Stand up.
Put your hands
behind your back!
Let's go.
MILES:
You're probably wondering
where I was when
Agent Stanley was...
uh, was, uh...
I, uh, I received a call from...
Gun!
(glass breaking)
Dispatch, this is Brass.
Shots fired, my location.
Suspect down.
He's dead.
Dead?
Yes, sir.
Code four.
(horn blaring)
(horn stops)
Good work, Detective.
I'm putting you in
for commendation.
Shut up!
Shut up, you whack job!
You see this?!
Captain...
You see this?
This is real. You see this?
People are dead here
because of you!
Stop it.
Jim, I've got it!
Because of you!
You're a fraud!
I got it!
Get him out of here.
(sirens approaching)
BRASS:
The driver's cell phone
was recovered at the scene.
Clearly, Mingus was spreading
the word about the phony feds.
I figure the shooter
was one of Os Punho's
lower level punks,
finishing what
Mingus started.
How much time is
he looking at?
Let's see-- impersonating
a federal officer,
at least two counts
of accessory murder,
and every person
he hauled off the
street to "interview"
would be an additional
count of kidnapping.
15 to 20, minimum.
His best bet
would be to plead
diminished capacity.
He's got that covered.
This is all
from the fake command post?
Huh.
Uh-huh.
What are you doing?
That is a good question.
This is the
evidence ledger
from the fake
feds' locker.
It's filled with dates
and corresponding
alphabetic codes.
This is the date that
that girl, Rio, was killed.
So it stands
to reason that...
This code could identify
the murder weapon.
That is a perfectly
logical conclusion.
It's also wrong.
That code isn't on
any of these weapons.
In fact, none of the
codes on the ledger are.
I've tried to
decipher it using
simple shift and substitution
codes, no luck.
Unless we find a cipher key,
we may never figure it out.
Maybe Miles is the key.
Hello, Miles.
I'm truly sorry
about your friends.
I'm here
because I need your help.
This, uh, entry
in your evidence ledger
corresponds to the day
that girl, Rio, was killed.
What does it mean?
All right...
Miles, um...
I think I know
what happened, Miles.
I think you and Emma
and Billy Ray...
were trying to clean up
your corner of the world,
do some good.
To do that, you had
to reinvent yourselves.
All I did was get them killed.
Look, they died fighting.
Trying to help people
who couldn't help themselves.
Now let me help you
finish what you started.
L-G-D-G-D-S
dash U-A-P
means "Little guy dropped
gun down sewer."
"Unable to
apprehend perp."
Corresponding
evidence tagged with
G-T-L-B-D
dash G-N-H-A-S:
"Gun little
"bastard dropped.
Gonna nail his ass someday."
SIMMS:
Now, have you tried this before?
Have you screened a weapon?
No.
Want to try?
All right.
Okay,
you take the gun,
and I want you
to swab the grip.
Right in here.
Perfect.
I'll hit it with phenol.
Nothing.
All right.
Now, we're going
to swab the magazine.
'Cause that gets
a lot of handling action.
Okay.
No.
So now, we're going
to try the opening.
And I want you to swab
right here
underneath the lip.
Great.
SIMMS:
Looks like our killer
caught his thumb
when he was loading the weapon.
LANGSTON:
The fight doctor
is wanted on a long list
of open trafficking
indictments.
And Interpol's been
after him for years.
We believe he's the one
who shot Rio.
It's over, Miles.
It was the doctor posing
as Os Punho.
He was running
the operation the whole time.
A fake cop taking down
an imaginary villain.
Not imaginary.
The suffering,
the death he caused, was real.
And you put a stop to it.
I did?
He's in jail.
I don't believe
he'll ever get out.
That's good.
I brought you something
to pass the time.
As I recall...
Quixote regained his sanity
in the end.
But his melancholia persisted.
He died emotionally broken
and alone.
Well, they didn't have
antidepressants
back in those days.
Chapter one.
"At a village of La Mancha,
"whose name I do not wish
to remember,
"there lived
a little while ago,
"one of those gentlemen
"who are wont to keep a lance
in the rack,
"an old buckler, a lean horse
and a swift greyhound."
they really were giants.