(engines revving)
(whooping)
(riders clamoring)
(cackles)
Ready for a good night?
You know I am, baby.
(rock music playing)
Watch out, fellas. Watch out.
Hey, Rudy!
How's it going,
brother?
Hook us up with two.
Here you go, Joey.
Yo, Death! You wanna shoot?
I'm broke.
I'll spot you, brother.
Ha-ha, brother!
Huh!
(indistinct conversations)
Joey, check it out.
Talk about easy rider.
Hey, you got a ride
like this, man,
you got to stay on it.
(man chuckling)
I'm going to kick
your ass, Hooper!
(grunting and groaning)
(clanging, glass shattering)
(laughing)
It's all family love here.
Come on, Jackass,
Get in there!
(grunting and groaning)
(sirens blaring)
(clamoring)
(engines revving)
(tires squealing)
(weapons locking and loading)
(officers shouting commands)
(tires squeal)
OFFICER:
Let me see your hands! Up!
Let's go, keep it moving.
BRASS:
So, a radio car was
in the neighborhood.
Picked up a 911 call
from dispatch.
A 911 call
for a biker bar fight?
(chuckles) Did you
run the number?
Untraceable cell.
MAN:
Yo, pig!
Don't you touch my hog!
Close the door.
LANGSTON:
What do we have,
David?
Liver stick's 98.
No rigor.
Lividity
isn't fixed.
They don't get much fresher.
(camera shutter clicking)
"Vegas Blasters."
BRASS:
He's flying his colors.
That means he's a sworn member
of the gang.
David, would you
turn him over for me, please?
Sure thing.
Whoa.
Multiple knife wounds.
Takes a serious blade to cut
through leather like that.
(groaning)
The knife's sheath
on his belt's empty.
He was probably trying
to defend himself.
Do we know who he is?
No wallet, no ID,
and apparently,
there were no eyewitnesses.
We have a packed club.
Nobody knows what happened?
When nobody knows nothing...
somebody knows something.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
This is my first time
in a biker bar.
(sniffs)
Mmm, what's that scent?
Beer, urine,
sweat, vomit...
And death.
A lot of people think these guys
just run holiday toy drives
and host rallies
for kids
with cancer.
In a magic act, that would
be called a misdirection.
I'd call this a slaughter.
All this blood, one victim?
I'm thinking it started
back there
by the second pool table,
moved up
through this blood pool,
where I found the chain,
and ended about here,
where we found the body.
I still can't make any sense
of all these bloody footprints.
SANDERS:
We'll compare them
to the shoes
of our guys in custody.
Meanwhile, I'll start
collecting blood samples.
The police arrived minutes
after the 911 call,
so the weapon or weapons
may still be here.
I'll check the kitchen.
Good place to ditch a knife.
(sighs)
I want to go take a look
at the bikes
before they go
to impound.
Longhorns, nice.
Beautiful.
Beautiful machines.
Okay, thank you.
First time
I've ever
coveted physical evidence.
Well, I ran
the plates
on all of them, and they
all came back matched
to the people
we have in custody,
except for
this one here.
The victim's bike?
Possibly.
R.O.'s come back
a Joseph Niagra.
Do we have a home address?
You're standing
in front of it.
But I'll run him
through the system.
All these guys
have records.
I tell these kids,
"You want to join a gang?
"You should join us.
"We're more powerful.
We got bigger guns...
and we got dental."
Sold me.
♪ ♪
Hmm.
How's it going here?
Well, every single one
of these knives
tested positive for blood.
These are animal,
and these are human.
SANDERS: You should get
these back to the lab.
They need you
at PD.
(water running)
Oh, Tonya.
You should have listened
to your mother.
(camera shutter clicking)
When I was in high school,
there was this guy, Mark.
He had a motorcycle.
(camera shutter clicking)
Let me guess.
Your mom told you
to stay away from him,
but you were Romeo and Juliet,
riding around
on 600 pounds of steel.
Oh, we had fun.
(chuckles)
But I moved on.
In fact, I didn't
give bikers another thought
until, years later,
I'm in the ER
with a hit-and-run victim.
Guy on a bike.
Just a piece of meat
in search of a pulse.
The entire time
I'm processing him,
I never realized
it was my Romeo.
He was that beat up.
Final stab wound tally: 24.
Multiple abrasions,
hematomas.
This one's got
a looping pattern.
Ray said that he found a chain
at the scene.
It's a good way
of slowing somebody down.
Maybe he needed
slowing down.
Take a look
at the teeth.
This is your mouth on meth.
(beeping)
Joseph Niagra.
Same as the R.O.
on the unclaimed bike.
(murmuring)
HODGES:
Right hand.
(indistinct voices)
WOMAN:
Turn around, please.
Thank you.
MAN: Yeah, yeah,
I heard you, I heard you.
Okay, would you please open
your mouth, Mister...
Jackass.
MITCHELL:
Shut up.
Get off me!
It's my name.
Okay.
Would you please open
your mouth, Mr. Jackass?
WOMAN:
Next in line?
Thank you.
Right hand.
(sighs)
WEBSTER:
There's so much grease
on these paws.
I can't get a clean print.
MAN: I work in a
body shop.
What do you expect?
Excuse me.
All right, you know what?
Could you just...?
Okay, here.
Could you
maybe just...
Okay, Badger,
what happened last night?
Did Joey Niagra
do something to piss you off?
What is this,
the biker code of silence?
You're the
only member
of the gang who wasn't
carrying a weapon.
They're not a gang.
They're just a bunch of guys
that like to ride together.
But you're the only bartender
in South Vegas
who doesn't carry protection.
(chuckles softly)
Man...
you got to start looking
for a better class of bar.
You're going to be looking
through bars for a long time.
Get him out of here.
And now your boots.
When you're done
with fingerprinting,
the officer will take you
to another room
where he'll collect
the rest of your clothing.
I ain't stripping.
I promise you, jail scrubs are
much cleaner and more flattering
than the blood-and-grease-soaked
homicide evidence
that you're currently wearing.
Let's go, Jackass.
SIMMS:
Tonya Charles?
Would you open
your mouth, please?
Stick it in your
own mouth, bitch.
Hey! Hey!
You're out of line.
Bite my out-of-line ass.
You owe Ms. Simms
an apology.
No, Hodges, it's okay.
No, apologize.
(Hodges groans,
spectators laughing)
Uh-oh.
TONYA:
Get your hands off me!
OFFICER: Settle down!
WOMAN:
Yeah, girl!
That was stupid.
(handcuffs click)
Ugh, chivalry is not dead.
No, but its nose
is bleeding.
(grunting)
Hold on a second.
(panting)
"Property
of Joey."
Is it Joey Niagra?
The victim's bike?
Yes.
Lots of greasy prints.
Look, I found this iPod.
It's got an
AM-FM receiver
and a very interesting playlist.
What do you got
for me?
Joey Niagra popped up in CODIS.
He was connected
to an open homicide:
dead hooker.
I guess
he was her last trick.
Definitely.
Sex was postmortem.
Some kind of initiation rite,
no doubt.
Kill the hooker;
have sex with the body;
get your colors
on your bike.
I'm almost done processing here.
What is that?
Huh.
Well...
"J.N."
Joey's missing knife.
He didn't put it there.
It's been wiped clean.
Someone's trying
to send us a message.
Yeah.
"Shove it."
ECKLIE:
Jim.
Yeah, what's up?
Got an alert
from Records Bureau
you ran prints
on Joey Niagra.
An alert?
Yeah.
His real name's Jack Nettles.
Vice recruited him two years ago
from Indianapolis
for an undercover job.
So what's going on?
The Vegas Blasters homicide.
He's the victim.
What kind of cop is a
tweaking necrophiliac?
It's tough giving
this kind of news
to the wife
of a victim.
Yeah, well,
I'll try to spare her
too many details.
Well...
Rita.
What are you...?
Mrs. Nettles, I'm
Conrad Ecklie,
Las Vegas Undersheriff.
Oh, uh, please come in.
I'm sorry
to have to
inform you that,
uh, your husband...
(sobbing):
No.
Oh, God.
Oh, my God!
Oh, my God, no!
Your husband
was killed
during an undercover operation.
Captain Brass is in charge
of the murder investigation.
(sniffles)
I'm very sorry
for your loss, ma'am.
My loss?
This...
This is who I lost...
...over six months ago
when he turned into someone
I didn't recognize anymore.
Jim, when did it happen?
Last night.
It happened
last night.
I tried to see his captain
He's got to help me.
He's got to get
my husband
out of that gang.
Ma'am, ma'am, ma'am.
I need his help.
Captain Collins
is not available.
Wha...?
Take a seat.
You've had a
few too many.
I'll have an officer
drive you home.
(groans)
Okay?
I'm sorry. I have to... I...
(sobbing)
You going to tell me
how you know her?
No.
SANDERS:
According to DNA, none of this
blood over here is the vic's.
This is
from the biker named Hooper
and this...
is from Jackass.
This could be
from a fight
unrelated to the murder.
Okay, well, I'm all set up here,
so let's try to confirm
that those prints are
from our victim.
(beeping)
(groaning)
It looks like he was
trying to get away,
but we still don't know
who tried to kill him.
Or how they found out
he was a cop.
TONYA:
Back off.
See if you like
being strip-searched
as much as you like
shooting off your mouth.
Good work, Willows.
Ever work undercover?
We can always use
another tough bitch.
Okay.
So with you
on the inside,
when they threw
women at Nettles,
he could always say
that he didn't cheat
on his old lady,
right?
Except for dead hookers. Right?
Joey-- Jack-- had to do that.
Had to be trusted enough
to become a member.
Well, obviously something
happened to that trust.
Jack was trying to learn
who the guy at the top is--
the guy calling the shots
in the drug racket
and the murders for hire.
Only a couple in the inner
circle know his real identity.
They don't use his real name.
He goes by Scratch.
Scratch...
All right,
so what happened last night?
We-We're in the clubhouse
after an all-day ride.
C-Couple of fights,
nothing unusual.
Then the bartender
takes a phone call.
(snapping fingers):
Like that, atmosphere changes.
It's real tense.
♪ ♪
(whistles)
My guess: it's Scratch calling.
Then, one of the "hangers"--
guy who's not a member yet--
he takes all the old ladies
and the rest of the hangers
and he takes us all outside.
Members only.
Outside.
What time?
About 10:00,
minute or two after.
I'm cold.
I got to pee.
Find a bush.
(man groaning)
(gasping)
They just killed a guy
inside the Blasters' clubhouse--
Rancho Destino,
south of Barston.
Hurry... hurry.
What are you looking at?
Anybody see you make
that call?
I don't think so.
According to Vice,
Nettles' last report said
there's a truckload of cocaine
coming in from Mexico.
Yeah, only the West Side
bike gang Righteous Dogs
got wind of it.
It's going to be a war.
Do you know where and when
this shipment is gonna
take place?
Yeah-- no-- I-I'll find out.
No, you won't, 'cause Ecklie
took you off the detail.
What?!
No!
No.
No way in hell, man!
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
Hey.
Hey!
What are you on?
What do you think?
You picked me up
partying with bikers.
Calm down. Calm down.
What do you want me to do?
I want you to get Ecklie in here
so I can tell him
I ain't quitting.
I'm not letting
Jack die in vain.
C.O.D. was exsanguination.
Found significant amount
of internal hemorrhage
to the lung
and pleural cavity
from stabs to the liver
and mesentery.
So he was alive and his heart
was beating the entire time?
Until it was lacerated.
It's one of the final injuries,
along with this one.
Stab wound
to the left temple
about, oh... two inches deep.
Quite a lot
of stab marks.
We need to compare these with
the weapons we've collected.
I'll cut them all out
and send them upstairs.
23 stab wounds.
Twenty-four.
I was thinking of Julius Caesar.
Ah... history's
first recorded autopsy.
Doctor named Antistius
did the honors, if I recall.
On the body of a man betrayed
by those he knew well.
♪ ♪
SIMMS:
The blood on the knife
that you found in the motorcycle
seat was the victim's.
STOKES: And I was able
to match that knife to
two of his wounds: the stab to
the sternum and the left temple.
What about the other knives?
Double-edged,
serrated,
smooth blade--
none of which was a match
to the tool marks
on the body.
SIMMS:
And none of the blood on those
knives came back to the victim.
But I did get two CODIS hits
from the knives that
Hodges collected.
These guys were both members
of the Righteous Dogs,
and their body parts
were found
scattered across
two miles of the Mojave.
Probably carved them up
in the kitchen.
The Blasters
and the Dogs are rival gangs.
There's been a war
over drug turf escalating
over the last year.
We still only have one
of the knives
used to kill Nettles.
There had to be others.
All right, the police arrived
one minute, just one minute,
after the 911 call.
Those other knives
couldn't have gone very far.
No. I appreciate that, Conrad,
I do,
but there's no need
for me to recuse myself, really.
No.
If the situation changes, yeah,
I'll, uh, I'll let you know.
Okay?
(tapping on window)
I got to go. Thank you.
Rita.
Hi.
Can I come in?
Oh, sure, sure.
I hope
this is okay.
No. It's fine.
Uh, they asked me to come down
about some paperwork.
Sure.
Come on in.
I hope
this is okay.
Come in.
Please, come in.
Sit down.
Please, sit down.
(clears throat)
(sniffles)
Can I get you anything?
Do you want anything at all?
Oh. A shoulder?
Oh, Rita.
No. I know. I know.
This isn't the place
for that. I'm sorry. I just...
That's not it. That's
not it. That's not it.
Why didn't you ever tell me
that you were a cop?
What? I didn't?
I-I thought...
No, I guess not. I...
I told you that I was married.
Uh, kind of.
Let's not, um...
We don't really have
to talk about that now.
That's not important, all right?
Look...
We've been over that.
No, I want...
I want to ex...
explain to you. I...
You don't have to
explain anything to me.
I was calling
his captain every day
because weeks are going by,
and I'm not hearing from Jack.
I woke up once
in the middle of the night.
He had snuck in,
and he was stealing some money
out of my purse.
He was on drugs or something.
I don't know.
He started hitting me.
And I was... I was pulling
on his shirt, trying to get him
to stop it, and I...
I see the name Tonya...
Yeah.
...tattooed on his chest, and...
How could he ever
be my husband again
after he'd had
another woman's name burned
into his skin like that? I...
Rita...
I didn't tell you the truth...
...because I was afraid.
I'm sorry.
Because I, uh...
I handled it badly.
I was not very
graceful about...
(knocking)
(clears throat)
Jim? I'm sorry.
Excuse me.
Yeah. No.
What? What's up?
Said you wanted to know
when Tonya Charles is released.
Right.
Rita?
Yeah?
We are doing
everything we can to find
the killer of your husband.
(motorcycle engine purring)
(engine revving)
(brakes squeak)
You lost?
I don't think so.
(chuckles)
Where's your car?
I'm working a theory.
Now, there are multiple
murder weapons.
We only have one.
I checked the perimeter
again. They're not here.
All right, first responding said
that a couple of bikers got away
just as they showed up.
Okay. Yeah, maybe they took
the knives with them.
All right, I'm one of them.
I know the police are rolling.
I don't want to get picked up
carrying the weapon,
so I'm going to ditch them
as quickly as possible, right?
Right. But you know,
you can use your
department vehicle to look
for that stuff.
You want to catch a rat,
you move like a rat.
Okay. Yeah.
Yeah, responding units came in
from the east and the west.
All right, south of here
is residential.
Too many eyes, too many ears.
I'll start looking north.
Good luck.
(chuckles)
(engine revving)
♪ ♪
(engines revving)
(dog barks in distance)
(metallic jangling)
All the knives I found match
tool marks on the victim's body.
And the prints we lifted
match five of the bikers
we have in custody,
but none of them are talking.
Well, if we don't
find evidence on the
rest of the bikers,
the D.A.'s going to
start releasing them.
I'm on it.
Thanks.
You paged me?
Yeah. I got the call records
from that phone at the bar.
There was an incoming call
at 10:02 p.m.
Okay, well,
that's consistent
with the undercover
officer's statement.
Where did it originate?
Looks like it was
from a pay phone.
The call to the bar came
from our police department?
Was Nettles dimed out
by another cop?
BRASS:
They're checking
surveillance footage
from the time of that call.
Jim, I've heard
you got a potential conflict
of interest in this case.
No, I don't.
Okay, what do you got?
Have a clean shot
of the caller.
All right,
let's run it.
That's Rita.
I'd say you got
a conflict now.
I don't know
why I'm here.
I didn't kill Jack.
Tell me about your call
to the Blasters' clubhouse.
How did you get that number?
Jack gave it to me.
In case of emergencies,
I'm supposed to call
and ask for Joey Niagra,
and say that I'm his mother.
So, that's what you're doing
in the photo?
Yes.
Why did you use the phone here?
So that we'd think
a cop made the call?
No.
What did you say?
I-I asked for Jack.
I... For Joey.
I-I... I just...
I just wanted to hear his voice.
ECKLIE:
No. No.
You told them he was a cop.
Isn't that right?
No!
You admitted
you'd already lost him,
but if you got a divorce,
you'd end up with, what?
A pile of debt, and a house
worth less than the mortgage.
Right?
What are you doing?
With one phone call,
you got his death benefit
and his pension.
That's not true!
(sighs)
ECKLIE:
Tonya managed to get word
back to Vice.
A cocaine shipment's
in from Mexico.
Where?
She doesn't know.
Wherever Scratch told
them to drop it off.
So, we got to find out
who Scratch is.
He'll lead us
to the drugs.
In the meantime, Righteous Dogs
are cruising the streets.
We need to find that
coke before they do.
Looks like they released
some more of the old ladies.
Yep.
There goes the
victim's girlfriend.
(ignition turns)
This is Charlie-05-Stokes.
I'm on Rancho Destino
south of Barston.
One of our U.C. vehicles
just exploded
with a U.C. officer
inside the vehicle.
Send Fire and paramedics.
I repeat: U.C. officer
was inside the vehicle.
Looks like the
incendiary device
detonated fast and big.
Red paper, wax-coated.
This is dynamite.
They must've known
Tonya was undercover.
And from the
moment the cops
responded to the 911 call,
we had this lot and the street
under control.
This bomb's too
sophisticated.
Must've been planted
before Nettles was killed.
Whether or not they
knew Nettles was a cop,
they were on to Tonya.
And the order had to have come
from the head guy, Scratch.
Makes sense. That's
the guy she was after.
I'll head back with the body.
WILLOWS:
According to the blood
evidence, the fight started
here at the bar
and moved forward.
Probably the first injury
came from the tire chain
to Nettles' left knee.
I'm Nettles.
I see what's going down
and I make a run
to go out the back.
I'm Smitty.
My prints were on the chain
that was collected here.
I hit his left knee.
Nettles was facing
in this direction.
(rock music blasting)
(yells)
WILLOWS:
So, now, you're down.
But you still
have a weapon:
your knife.
I think he was reaching for it
when Jackass got in
on the fight.
Hodges, you're Jackass.
And don't I know it.
All right, your
knife matches cuts on
Nettles' right arm.
Okay, so, I'm over him.
(yells)
All right, that cast-off
over there could have been
from the repeated stabbing
of an area that bleeds heavily,
such as the two clavicle wounds
that match Hooper's knife.
All right, in order for Hooper
to reach the clavicle,
I'll have to get down
on my right knee...
(groans)
(grunts)
And at this point, his right
arm is pretty much useless.
So, he pulls himself
with his left hand.
But they didn't stop.
Judge Death here...
stabbed him in the kidneys.
(grunting)
(pained yell)
And then he somehow managed
to try to get to the front door.
And they let him
because they knew
he wasn't going to get very far.
(groaning)
And then they use
Nettles' own knife on him.
But I think it was
the stab to his temple
that finally stopped him.
(sharp inhale)
(short exhale)
LANGDON: And that's how
we found him, and that
proves a bar fight,
but not a setup.
You're right.
We know that Rita Nettles
called here at 10:02 p.m.,
and the fight started
right after that.
LANGSTON: It's unlikely
that they would kill
a member of their
own gang or a cop without
direct orders from Scratch.
So, either Scratch was here,
or whoever took the call
contacted Scratch.
But there weren't any
outgoing calls after 10:00
on any of the bikers' cell
phones or the bar phone.
Wait a second.
There's a bug in here.
There was nothing in Nettles'
case notes that mentioned one.
Nettles' iPod had
a radio receiver.
If he was able to
install a transmitter...
RITA:
Let me talk to Joey!
BARTENDER:
He's with his old lady.
RITA:
Tonya, is that her name?
Huh? How young is she? Hmm?
She's real young?
He's a cop! You know that?
A cop!
His name is not Joey!
BARTENDER:
Hey, who is this?
RITA:
I'm his wife!
Okay, all right, all right.
Jim...
Vice sent over
another surveillance
wiretap where a man identified
as Scratch was recorded.
JOHNSON:
I was able to
grab enough to make
a comparison.
BARTENDER:
Hey, who is this?
SCRATCH:
Yo, what is this?
Hey, who is this?
So, Scratch is the bartender.
Nice chopper.
If this paint is scratched,
you got a problem.
(engines revving)
They all just left.
(beeping)
JOHNSON:
I've got them.
They're moving east
on Sunset Road.
Just turned south
onto Hasbrook.
They're stopping behind
an industrial building.
Number 2106.
It's Kenny.
(guns cocking)
(chuckling):
Sorry, Scratch.
Dogs found it first.
(sirens blaring)
Las Vegas Police!
OFFICER:
Put your hands above your head!
Las Vegas Police!
Put your hands up!
Put your hands
where I can see 'em!
(engine revving)
(tires squeal)
Stop!
(gunshots)
MAN:
Not moving!
I'm not moving!
Hey, don't hate me, man.
(chuckling)
That bitch cop
was easy to make.
And your boy Joey should've
took care of his wife.
Shut up.
I know this is your favorite way
of wrapping up a tough case.
Little scotch... little talk.
You feel like talking?
All right, then.