(clicking)
(motor whirring)
(tires squealing)
(grunting)
The call did say 419
at Choozy's Chicken.
BRASS:
Not him.
Him.
Oh, careful, guys.
It's real slippery back here.
BRASS:
Manager Bob Graham,
Salt Lake City, Utah.
Had a whopping $42
in his wallet.
Make that $62.
Who found him?
Well, a patrol car
went by and saw
the broken window
around 12:15 A.M.
Place closes
at 11:00 P.M.,
so a call went out to
the night manager,
Kiwi Long.
Floor's covered in oil.
Probably
from the fryer.
It does look a bit low.
And it's still on.
Looks like somebody interrupted
closing time.
LANGSTON:
I have a backpack here.
PHILLIPS:
Vic has multiple
lacerations,
contusions
and fractures.
All confined to his
face and skull.
Razor's still wet.
A little personal hygiene
at the dish sink? Yum.
A pair of jeans.
Men's.
Too small to be
the victim's.
This stuff's got to be
an employee's.
Somebody's using this place
as a motel.
Maybe Big Bob caught them
checking in
and things went
very wrong.
If Backpack Dude
had a key, then why use
the mascot as a battering ram?
I'm Choozy Chicken,
the chicken of choice,
but you can just call me
delicious!
(crowing)
(audio powering down)
Maybe he can tell us.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
(camera shutter clicking)
Registers are empty.
Robbery?
Not sure.
You know, back in high school,
I used to work
at a fast food place.
We would put the cash
in a drop safe
and leave the registers
open to show
that there wasn't
anything to steal.
I'm gonna go check
the manager's office.
You find something, Ray?
Will you kill
the overhead
fluorescents, please?
Yeah.
Drag marks.
Starting from the fryer...
leading to the back door,
diminishing
as they go.
Possible second victim?
Possibly.
And the blood...
tell you anything special?
LANGSTON:
Tails on the blood drops
establish directionality.
But these tails indicate
that the blood is going
into the kitchen.
Drag marks
lead outside.
Oil out,
blood in.
Good observation.
Nick.
LANGSTON:
Can't be full of oil
if it's full of body.
Nothing.
This drum doesn't belong
to Choozy's Chicken.
It says, "Mr. Hu's
Mandarin Kitchen".
What, do you eat a lot
of Chinese or something?
I wrote a journal article
about dengue fever.
Most of the research
was in Mandarin.
Oh, well,
that's good.
Then, you and
Mr. Hu will have
a lot to discuss.
My Mandarin's a little...
a little rusty.
Skid marks.
Somebody was
in a hurry.
Scuff marks on the pole.
I have something.
Mirror.
Looks like transfer.
Looks like the killer
and whoever he was dragging
made a not-so-clean getaway.
I'm Kiwi Long, manager on call.
BRASS:
Captain Jim Brass.
Mister--
Captain Brass, I don't know
why the alarm didn't go off.
I-I was supposed
to close last night,
but I've been having
some trouble
with my son's babysitter.
Bob said that he was going
to cover for me,
and he's a regional manager,
so I figured
the place was in good hands.
Oh, my God, that could
have been me last night.
BRASS:
Who else, uh,
closed up last night?
Elizabeth Martin.
She's one
of my best employees--
really responsible.
I'm going to need
to get in touch with her.
I already called her.
It went to voicemail.
Something must be wrong.
She always takes my call.
Okay, uh, who else has the
combination to the drop safe?
LONG:
Only me and Bob.
It's the day I got my promotion,
the day my son was born,
and the day we got
our cat Zoey-Omega.
So... 23-31-12.
BRASS:
Okay, I-I'm gonna need
all your surveillance.
LONG:
Oh, you have to call corporate.
It goes straight to them.
Some clips ended up
on YouTube that were,
um, unflattering
to the franchise.
Not on my watch, but, um,
ever since, all the
surveillance cameras are wired
to a digital feed
in the manager's office.
BRASS:
I'm gonna need
contact information
for all your employees,
both former and current.
Okay?
Oh, are you going to be
contacting Bob's next of kin,
or should I?
Because...
I don't know who they are.
(indistinct radio transmission)
VARTANN:
The husband's
blood alcohol level
is through the roof.
The wife's dead in the bedroom.
Mailman tried
to deliver this
when he found them.
(reading)
Nice house to lose.
MAN:
Mr. Tucker's a mortgage broker.
His wife's a real estate agent,
so they probably got
first pick.
There's no sign
of forced entry,
but the place is a sty.
Yeah, looks like he's been
living on the couch.
PHILLIPS:
Thready pulse.
BP's 90 over 60.
He's wasted.
He's gonna need
a stomach pump.
I'm good.
Rigor's begun to set.
And her liver temp is
93 degrees,
which means she's been dead
three to five hours.
You want to bet that
that's about the time
the husband started drinking?
(chuckles)
Okay, I'm on my way
to the hospital to
get his statement.
I'll get back to you.
Looks like some kind
of a struggle.
Yeah.
But it wasn't a fair fight.
She was handcuffed.
Which under the right
circumstances can be fun.
You got a C.O.D. there, Dave?
Undetermined.
Catherine,
I apologize for the overshare.
Thank you for the overshare.
♪ ♪
ROBBINS:
Whoa, you have
your hands full.
Uh, yeah.
Just put your stuff
down over there.
Thanks.
I'm, uh, I'm still
trying to get organized.
Trying to figure out
when's a good time to eat lunch.
Lunch--
which, I just
turned into...
a biohazard.
Your vic had
quite a night.
Ante-mortem,
fractured cheek bones,
broken nose.
And I have
some sort of a...
circular trauma
to the cerebellum.
I think he might have gotten
whacked in the head
with a "wet floor" sign.
(screaming):
No!
So much for safety
in the workplace.
This is your C.O.D.
High-speed impact
to the base of the skull,
at the atlanto-occipital
junction,
dislodged the C-1
vertebrae,
severing the spinal cord.
Hit, fall, kick. Who knows?
But death
(phone ringing)
swift and certain.
Stokes.
Really.
Thanks.
We'll pay him a visit.
Mandy got a hit off
of the side-view mirror.
He's a former Choozy's
Chicken employee
who's already in the system
for assaulting
dear old Bob here.
Let's go check him out.
Okay.
Thanks, Doc.
Uh, you can
just leave it.
Come back later for it.
Thank you.
STOKES:
Where were you
last night, Max?
Here.
Studying.
Can anyone
confirm that?
Sure.
32 other frat brothers.
We were all here.
Studying.
This side-view mirror is
from your truck.
We found it
last night
at the Choozy's Chicken
on Tropicana.
Hey, maybe we should take
all 32 brothers
downtown, what do you
think? Yeah?
Why not?
Okay.
Look, um,
the damage was an accident.
It was supposed to be
a smooth operation.
You know?
Tie him up, throw him the truck,
bring him back here.
But he fell, and he was
too heavy to lift.
And I was working
with a new crew.
So, I guess
I miscalculated.
I talked to my dad,
he said he'd pay.
You can't buy your way
out of this one.
You've already assaulted him
once.
Were you trying to finish
what you started?
What the hell?!
How does it feel to
be my chicken bitch?
Oh, where you going?
Come on, fatty!
(laughter)
You embarrassed me.
Forgot friendliness.
And service.
That's why people
choose Choozy's.
(groaning)
No, no, I was there last night,
but I didn't run into Bob.
I didn't see anybody.
The place was closed.
Come on, Max.
Your record
kind of speaks for itself
here, man.
Look, that guy was an asshat.
That assault charge is bogus.
Ask anybody who
was there.
The dude went berserk
on me-- it was self-defense.
Is that what got you fired?
Oh, no, I wasn't fired.
I just quit.
I only took the
job for recon.
Recon?
Choozy's Chicken
was the only one I didn't have.
(TV playing indistinctly)
Good-looking couple.
You could blind yourself
on these incisors.
Ting!
Looks like we have a runner.
WILLOWS:
Didn't know that wine
had electrolytes.
They say it's good
for your heart.
Yeah, a lot
of good it did her.
Now we know how they got
those whites so pearly.
Home from a run.
More than halfway through
an afternoon
cocktail.
They haven't been
getting along,
he's drunk,
and he won't take no
No!
for an answer.
Romantic.
I do like the extra money
working at Choozy's gives me,
but mainly, you got to keep
busy when you're my age.
WEBSTER:
Sure. Sure you do.
Can I just get
you to keep your
fingers straight?
Dude, I can't lose
this job
or my dad's gonna take
my car away.
Well, if you didn't do
anything wrong,
you don't have anything
to worry about.
Well, Jackson's always
doing something wrong.
I can't believe
this is all over Bob.
Probably choked
stuffing Choozy's
down his pie hole.
Jabrone.
You just didn't like him
'cause he wouldn't let you
throw ice cubes in the fryer.
It's the best thing
about the job, Marge.
Okay,
has anybody seen
Elizabeth Martin
or Gary Comstock?
No, I haven't seen
either of them.
(mocking woman's voice)
"Ooh, Gary.
Gary, could you give me
a ride home?"
Dude, shut up, okay?
He's just a nice guy.
Yeah, for a homeless junkie.
Look who's talking.
You're, like, one spliff
away from rehab,
moron.
Thousands in the safe.
A stack of loose cash,
and only $200 missing?
That's not much of a robbery.
Well, it could be.
Elizabeth Martin was closing up
with Big Bob last night.
I ran down her address
from her license.
I mean, it's Ann
Elizabeth Martin.
She's a Seven Hills
desperate housewife
with 2.5 kids
and a Nordic silver SUV
and a recurring victim
of identity theft.
Little lie, big lie?
Could be an illegal.
Someone with priors.
Maybe Bob caught her
with her hand
in the cookie jar.
Excuse me,
Captain Brass.
Wendy.
Um, we just finished
getting the fingerprints
and DNA from all
the Choozy's
Chicken employees,
but there were two no-shows:
Elizabeth Martin
and Gary Comstock.
Now, I actually got a CODIS hit
from one of them
'cause the epithelials
from the razor came
back to Gary.
In the system
for felony drug charges?
Last-known address
was a rehab center?
I called it, but they said
they hadn't seen him
in six weeks.
Yeah, that's because he's living
out of a backpack at Choozy's.
Well, easy to do when you have
a friend with a key
to the back door.
So, Gary's on crack time.
He comes back there to crash.
Only Bob's still there,
catches him in the act,
and all hell breaks loose.
What are you doing here, Gary?!
(growling)
Well, where's Elizabeth?
Probably in an oil drum
somewhere.
No honor among thieves.
Okay, but wouldn't a drug addict
grab up all the loose cash?
Anything come back
on the SAE kit?
Negative.
No sign of sexual
activity, forced
or consensual.
So he cuffed her to the bedpost
in her underwear,
but they didn't have sex.
Excuse me.
I just wanted to get my kit.
How's business
with Choozy's Chicken?
A little confusing.
How's your case going?
A bit confusing.
You, uh, want
to stick around?
Yes, I would.
What do we have, Doctor?
Eh...
Did this woman have
a highly stressful job?
Why?
Gastric ulcer.
Pretty advanced.
Thanks.
Sure. Here.
Death by Smurf?
Have you ever seen anything
like this?
Nope.
Minty.
Fresh.
Shouldn't that be
in an evidence bag?
That's not the one
from Choozy's Chicken.
I took that out of our bathroom.
But first I'm going
to give you the bad news.
That bloody handprint
on the countertop
that was all smudgy?
I got a useable index
fingerprint off of that,
but it's not a match
to anyone, including Gary.
Measures about ten
inches from the tip
of the middle finger
to the wrist,
which is quite large for a guy
and it's huge for a woman.
So we're looking for a guy
who doesn't work at Choozy's?
Right.
Damn.
Okay.
Then I got
a lot of incidental
prints on the sign,
all of which were
eliminated to the employees.
However, there was a set
of prints that got my attention.
Eight fingertips
on one side of the sign,
two thumbprints on the other.
That is an attacking grip.
Right. And I found a matching
fingerprint for that
on Elizabeth Martin's
register receipt.
But I can't say
for sure it's hers.
So I need to see
Elizabeth.
Or, um, one of her fingers.
(laughs) You're sick, Mandy.
So it says here
that that blood drop
that I collected
from the manager's
office is menstrual blood.
It's weird, right?
And weirder still,
it's not even Kiwi's.
According to this, it's not
any of the female employees.
Well, I don't have an exemplar
for Elizabeth Martin,
so we can't exclude her.
Pants off
in the manager's office
during that time
of the month?
Assault?
No blood smears,
no semen, no torn clothing.
It didn't look
like a rape scene.
Maybe it was consensual.
With Bob?
Or Gary.
Or both.
Hmm.
Love triangles can be deadly.
Don't I know it.
(speaking Mandarin)
Wow. That was...
well said.
(speaking Mandarin)
(laughs)
The owner
of the restaurant is upset
because his drums
keep getting stolen,
and he's not getting
his energy rebate.
Oh. I didn't know restaurants
got rebates for recycling.
That's why he has security
cameras pointing straight
at his drums.
Well, lucky for us,
we have Mr. Hu's footage.
Now, this is just
after midnight,
same night your guy was
killed at Choozy's.
Hmm.
(laughs)
Sweet ride, huh?
Chevy Corvair.
(chuckles)
Take one,
leave an empty.
At least
our barrel bandits recycle.
Can you get a read
off the license plate?
(beep)
Yeah.
(beeping)
This is Timothy
Rand's vehicle.
Hmm. You know, I missed
the whole hippie thing.
I was too busy
in Southeast Asia keeping my
head down and my feet dry.
I'm surprised you didn't
drop a little acid
or smoke a little T.
Well, things did get
a little wild.
(clears throat)
Namasté.
I'm Silver.
Police. I'm Brass.
And this is Ray Langston
from the
crime lab.
Is Timothy around?
Oh, yeah, he's in his workshop.
Here, follow me.
Oh.
Can you feel that?
Feel what?
High ratio
of positive to negative ions.
Ooh! Unfriendly air.
But you can't let it
bring you down.
Scientifically proven.
The Santa Anas,
the Siroccos.
(laughs)
You know what I'm talking about.
(coughing)
Timothy Rand?
Oh!
I know why
you're here,
but this is not a crime, man.
They put this valuable
resource out with the trash!
Some restaurants are, you know,
pouring it down storm drains,
or dumping it in the desert.
If one good thing could come out
of all those caged animals
hopped up on hormones,
who are then slaughtered
and then frozen,
only to be deep fried
and wind up as plaque
in our arteries, it is this,
biodiesel.
It only cost
me 200 bucks
to convert my van!
You know what
I'm saying?
One man can...
Make a
difference!
Look, this planet is our mother,
and we're all her children.
That's right, baby.
Where'd you get
the Choozy Chicken barrel?
RAND:
The one on, uh,
Tropicana.
I always return them.
I just haven't processed
this one yet.
BRASS:
Well, congratulations.
It's a boy.
(shutter clicks)
David, you have
the touch of a surgeon.
Thank you.
Looks like there's a blood stain
on the boxers.
I'm going to need
to get those to DNA.
Will do.
Ante-mortem abrasions
on the second and third knuckle.
Could be from busting
up Bob's face.
Extensive
third degree burns here.
I'm gonna need to, uh, take
a look inside his mouth.
Go ahead.
DR. ROBBINS:
There are full thickness burns
on all exposed surfaces
of his face.
There's damage to the nares
and nasal mucosa.
So his breathing
was compromised.
That's your C.O.D.
Asphyxia due to inhalation
of hot oil.
Prints just
confirmed I.D.
It's Gary Comstock.
Hmm.
Ouch.
Tox panel came back clean.
So he wasn't using anymore.
The man had
a second chance at life.
Till he was murdered.
Hey.
Nope. Any news
on blue goo?
The blue goo
was toothpaste.
Approximately
12 ounces worth.
Equivalent to two full tubes.
Yeah, we collected
a couple of empties
in the trash at the house.
I'll compare them.
Is it possible to O.D.
on toothpaste?
Definitely, if it's
fluoride toothpaste.
Each tube comes with a warning--
"If swallowed, please contact
the Poison Control Center
immediately."
Never had a cavity.
No joke.
How much fluoride would
it take to kill a person?
Depends on the person.
Uh, female victim,
110 pounds.
With a pre-existing
stomach ulcer.
Which means it would get
into her system faster.
The P.T.D.--
"Probably Toxic Dose"--
is five milligrams
per kilogram of body weight.
A regular tube of toothpaste--
you're talking 170 grams
.25 percent of which
is fluoride, so...
(mumbling):
170 times...
.25 is 425...
She's 50 kilograms.
Yeah. So...
she would need 250 milligrams
for it to be toxic.
And if there's 425 milligrams
in one tube...
So one tube would do it.
Assuming she absorbed it all
and didn't throw it up.
Well, then, for sure, two
tubes would get the job done.
She would experience
what I like to call
a catastrophic
symptom train.
Wicked muscle spasms
would give way to...
decreased heart rate,
lowered blood pressure,
decreased respiration
and, eventually, death.
Death by toothpaste.
You know, I got something else.
I found trace amounts of
diphenhydramine hydrochloride
in her tox panel.
Maybe she had allergies.
Someone slipped it to her.
I analyzed her wine.
It was cheap a California merlot
with an antihistamine mickey.
Why?
Well, diphenhydramine
hydrochloride
is both a soporific
and an antiemetic.
It makes you sleepy
and it keeps you from puking.
VARTANN: Paramedics found
this in your pocket.
It's the key to the handcuffs
that we took off your wife.
SANDERS: We checked your
Pay-Per-View selections.
You've been
watching a lot
of bondage porn lately.
Strap Daddy.
Silk Cuffs One and Two.
What happened to my wife?
Scott, there's
not enough
booze in this town
to make you
forget murder.
Fluoride poisoning?
Are you kidding me with this?
No. See I'm thinking
you're a mortgage broker.
Your business is in the crapper.
The bank is trying
to foreclose on your house
and your wife had a very nice
insurance policy.
Nice enough for you to
pay off all those debts.
You see where I'm going, Scott?
Look, I'll admit things
weren't that great
between Melinda and I.
Okay? She blamed me
for losing the house
and... everything else.
But those handcuffs
are from better times.
We hadn't had sex in months.
We, uh, checked
your medical records.
You have
receding gums.
So what?
Who cares about my gums?
Well, you use a special,
high fluoride toothpaste.
We found your prints
all over these.
Yeah. Before Melinda
became a real estate agent,
she was a dental hygienist.
We had boxes
of that stuff
lying around.
Free samples.
We both used it.
Look, if I had tried to cram
toothpaste down Melinda's throat
she would have kicked me
in the cubes.
Hey, Ray. Did your
"Barrel Boy" wear glasses?
Not according
to his DMV record.
But Big Bob did.
Huh.
Halt. You can't bring
food in here.
Not my rules.
I found this in the fryer oil.
Along with two metal screws,
which was the giveaway.
Cheap plastic frames and lenses.
These don't look
like French fries.
That's because those are
bits of Gary.
And what were these?
Once upon a time,
those were $180.
How do we know that?
(chuckles)
All right, what am
I looking at here?
You are looking at
a plastic security strip.
It's embedded
in all U.S. bank notes.
Supposedly to prevent
counterfeiting.
Although I've heard that they
can be read by satellites,
so the "Man" knows how much
money's in your pocket.
And we still
can't find Bin Laden.
Nine plastic strips.
Nine twenties-- $180.
Plus the 20 we found in
the dead manager's pocket.
So all the missing money
from Choozy's Chicken
is accounted for.
Which means
there was no robbery.
STOKES:
We've got evidence
that isn't telling us
the whole story.
So... let's walk
through this again.
Shall we?
Bob was on the floor here.
There were oil drag marks
leading from the kitchen
to the Dumpster.
And we now know
that Gary was
dragged outside
and put into an oil drum.
There was also a blood trail
leading in from the Dumpster
as well as blood stains
on Gary's boxer shorts.
Now, DNA confirms that both
samples were "Dead Bob's" blood.
Bob bled on Gary
dragging him out,
and then bled on the ground
when he walked back in.
But did Bob kill Gary?
Or was there another assailant?
All right.
I'll be Gary.
You be Big Dead Bob.
Seriously.
Yeah.
Okay.
We struggle.
You shove my face in the oil.
(gasping)
That could explain...
how Bob's glasses ended up
in the fryer.
ADAMS: As well as
the missing $200
that could've slipped out
of his shirt pocket.
Let's do it again.
Look at
your left hand.
You're using it as leverage.
If Bob pushed Gary
into the fryer,
the handprint we collected
would be Bob's.
But it's not.
Well, the evidence
can't be wrong...
but we could be.
WILLOWS:
What you doing?
I needed to see
for myself
the volume of 340 grams
of toothpaste.
You know, unencumbered
by a tube
it is an awful lot.
Join in. I used to
do this as a kid.
(grunting)
Now we get paid for doing it.
Even with an anti-emetic,
how would you force
this much toothpaste
down someone's throat?
Mm.
Excuse me for interrupting
arts and crafts,
Ah, it's an experiment.
Well, maybe for you.
The toothpaste
that Mrs. Tucker ingested
contained a bleaching agent.
The tubes you collected didn't.
There were two empty tubes of
toothpaste in their bedroom,
but it's not the toothpaste
that killed her.
Arts and crafts are over.
Gotta go back
to the house.
Their life in garbage.
And no toothpaste.
STOKES:
Nothing on the ground
or in the planter.
Shoe rubber.
STOKES:
The gate was locked.
Homeowner's about 80.
Once I asked
loudly enough,
she gave us permission to
search without a warrant.
Fluoride toothpaste
with bleach.
Hey, Mandy.
Okay, you know what,
no more shotgun approach.
You need to start
prioritizing
your latents.
No, no, I'm only interested
in one print, the handprint.
O-kay, but I already put
that through the database.
Well, we're having
a little disparity
between context
and the evidence.
What are you asking me?
Is it possible
the print got distorted?
Well, you can only distort
prints with pressure
or body weight.
Well, we do now think
that the surface print
was left during a struggle,
and Bob Graham was a big boy,
so can you run that index
finger for me again?
Yeah, okay.
Thank you.
(computer trilling)
It's a reversal.
There must have been enough
pressure to invert the print.
I'm sorry,
I missed it. Okay.
Right. Do you see how
these appear to be ridges,
but there is no
sweat glands?
Mm-hmm.
Which is because
those are furrows.
(taps key, computer trills)
(Webster sighs)
It's a match. I'm sorry.
(cell phone rings)
It's okay,
you're human.
Stokes.
Hey, Nicky,
I got Elizabeth Martin
from her canceled
payroll checks.
The bank gave me her address.
STOKES:
So she's alive.
Oh, yeah.
Did her record kick
back any priors?
No record.
Immigration got wind of it.
They scooped up
her whole family.
She's an illegal
working here on a fake I.D.
She's in Interrogation now.
I'll let you know
how it turns out.
All right.
Hello.
I'm Detective Jim Brass,
Las Vegas Police.
Okay.
Let's start
with an easy question.
What's your real name?
Rosa Gonzales.
Okay, Rosa Gonzales...
tell me what happened
at Choozy's Chicken
the other night.
I didn't mean to kill him.
(calculator clacking)
You wanted to see me?
Your drop bag was short.
I checked it twice.
You want me to call
the police, huh?!
(whispers):
I'm gonna have to do
a strip search.
He made me take off
all my clothes.
Did he assault you?
Touch you?
He put his hands on me.
No!
(whimpers in protest)
(grunts)
What the hell is this?!
What are you doing here, Gary?!
I'm not the issue here, Bob.
(growling)
Then what happened?
I got dressed.
I could hear them fighting.
I went out into the kitchen.
(Bob yelling)
ROSA: Stop it!
(Bob grunting,
Gary groaning)
(Bob screaming with pain)
GARY:
Get out of here!
What the hell are you doing,
Bob?!
(grunting)
(gurgling)
I ran.
But I swear to the Virgin
herself,
I was just trying to help Gary.
Hitting him with the sign
isn't what killed him.
So I can go home?
Miss Gonzales, you see
the immigration agent
outside with your family.
They tell me that you're
in this country illegally.
I grew up here.
I work.
I take care of my family.
I believe you, I do,
but it's not my call.
Well, we've exhausted
every suspect,
and we still don't know
who killed Bob.
Well, at this point,
it's a locked room mystery.
Mm-hmm.
After all that
we've been through,
how can you guys
eat that?
Power of suggestion.
And because I can't help myself.
They're good.
It's 'cause
they put crack
in the fries.
Hmm?
Mm.
What if the room is the suspect?
According to his
insurance records,
Bob had twenty-eighty vision.
Without his glasses,
he was practically blind.
Elizabeth gave him
a pretty good whack
to the cerebellum,
which can affect equilibrium.
Add those factors
to a slippery floor...
(grunts)
It's a case of blind justice.
So when I'm filling out
the paperwork, who do I list
on the suspect line?
There is no suspect.
It was an accident.
STOKES:
The DNA from inside
the latex gloves was...
You ready for this?
Scott Tucker?
Related...
by marriage.
Melinda?
Wait a minute.
It was suicide?
Yeah.
With a nice, big frame
around it.
Otherwise, why not just
pop the diphenhydramine?
Why spike the wine?
Well, maybe she was
trying to frame
her husband
for attempted murder,
hoping for a poisoning,
not a death.
Doubtful.
I mean, she was a hygienist.
If that were the case,
she would've just stopped
at one tube.
Henry did say
that there was about an hour
between ingestion and her death.
SANDERS:
Plenty of time
to set up the husband.
She goes outside, she...
climbs the fence,
she ditches the evidence
in the neighbor's trash,
and then...
...cuffs herself to the bed
and then waits to dies?
What could you
possibly have done
to make your wife
hate you so much?
We used to be an amazing team
actually.
She'd find the
client the house,
I'd get them
financing.
Everyone was happy.
But I always told her--
don't get too friendly;
these are clients,
they're not friends.
But she goes to all the parties.
all the barbeques,
all the fund-raisers.
So, when the NINJA loans
flipped over,
and the banks kicked them
out of their homes
because they couldn't afford
to make their payments,
well, they called us,
screaming like it was our fault,
and I blamed her.
If she hadn't gotten
all buddy-buddy
with them in the first place,
they never would have
crossed that line.
That's when the marriage
went belly-up.
We couldn't
look each other
in the face after that.
I thought she was weak,
and she wanted me to feel bad
because I didn't feel worse.
I never thought she'd
kill herself, though.
Tried to kill me
a couple of times.
Couldn't sell the house,
couldn't afford
to get a divorce.
I can't believe
that bitch set me up.
ROBBINS:
Figured it's better
than nothing
till they find
you something.
ROBBINS:
You could put a desk in there.
It's perfect.
I should check
with Catherine first.
I already did.
All right.
Thank you, Doctor.
You're welcome.
I think I'll be
right at home here.