(thunder rumbling)
(cyclists panting)
(panting)
(groaning)
(gasps)
(grunts)
(screams)
Hey!
He's got my purse!
(grunts)
Call the cops, call 911.
My phone was
in the purse.
(sighs)
Ma'am, excuse me,
I need to use your phone.
Lady...
Lady?
(flies buzzing)
(camera clicking)
(indistinct background
radio communication)
I got here as
fast as I could.
My DFO in
Anthem took longer
to clear than I expected,
but that's what happens
when you don't have enough
bodies to cover the bodies.
Oh...
Uh...
she forget to fall down?
Lividity's fixed in
her ankles and feet.
Suggests she died
in this position.
I don't know if you saw
the weather report last night,
but there was dry lighting
in this area.
(Touch-Tone dialing)
A low voltage strike...
...could have caused
her arm muscles
to contract around the pole.
(thunder rumbling)
GRISSOM:
And then what?
Cadaveric spasms
in her shoulder
and hand
keeps the body
in position
until rigor sets in?
It's just a theory.
I'll tell Robbins
to look for signs
of electrocution.
Hi, guys.
The callout was a 419.
Where's the body?
Ask her.
Excuse me, ma'am.
Ma'am?
Hey...!
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
GRISSOM:
Nick can't help us.
He just got a call out
at the Monte Carlo.
In other words,
we're pulling another double.
Why should today be
any different?
There's no burn marks on the arm
or hand
where she was touching the pole.
Well, there's
no scoring
or blackening on the dome,
either.
No indication of a
lightning strike.
The bulb's burned out.
Maybe there's a short
in the wiring.
Liver temp's 98, but ambient's
pushing a hundred.
So the body could have warmed up
after death?
No T.O.D.
Sorry.
Rigor's starting
to break.
I'll take her prints.
Her phone looks new.
Hasn't even been
personalized yet.
Who was she talking to?
(phone beeping)
MovieFone.
She carrying I.D.?
She's not carrying anything.
Well, if someone
was going
to rob her,
why not take the whole purse?
Why waste time
emptying the contents?
WEBSTER:
So, lucky us-- the
lamppost lady's fingerprints
are in the system.
She has a record?
It's not that system.
It's the health care
providers database.
Name's Carla Peretti.
She's an LPN
at Desert Palm.
Captain Brass is
running background.
Good.
Where is everyone?
They're in the break room
waiting.
Waiting for what?
For you.
I know you got the memo;
I put it on your desk.
My name's Patricia Alwick.
I'm a peer counselor
for the Police Employees
Assistance Program.
I deal primarily
with law enforcement,
which means I know that none
of you wants to listen to me,
so I'll keep it short.
With the death
of Warrick Brown,
you've lost a colleague
and a friend.
I'm here to help you
through it.
Our conversations will be
informal and confidential.
Are the sessions mandatory?
No.
No, they're not,
but keep this in mind.
Right now,
you might feel okay
and that you can handle things
fine on your own,
but sometimes,
if you're not looking,
grief can sneak up
and bite you.
I've been doing this
a long time.
I know
what I'm talking about.
Ms. Alwick
will be up
in room 4-E.
If you'd like
to make an appointment,
call her at extension 2922.
All right, guys,
we're done.
Thanks for coming.
WOMAN:
What, no gun?
WOMAN 2:
Sorry.
Well, maybe later, then.
Thanks.
Hello.
Hi.
Would you like
to make an appointment?
No.
I'm new here.
Hence the new
guy manuals.
Excuse me.
You know, joining
an established team,
particularly under
these circumstances--
it's not going
to be easy for you.
Do you think I should quit?
It may not be easy
on your colleagues, either.
Well, there's nothing I can do
about that.
Of course
there is.
I'm happy to discuss...
Look, I'm-- this is day one.
I don't know
these people,
they don't know me.
It's going to work out
however it works out.
Uh-huh.
You seem a bit defensive.
(sighs)
Don't do that, okay?
Do what?
"You seem a bit defensive."
Both my parents are shrinks.
I don't do the talk.
Both your parents
are psychiatrists.
Interesting.
Are you Riley Adams?
Yeah, that's me.
I'm Gil Grissom,
your supervisor.
We're very busy.
Would you come
with me, please?
Yeah.
Good luck.
Another transit patron
called it in.
He was pissed the guy was taking
up the whole bench,
so he tried to shove him over,
which didn't work too well,
him being dead at the time.
Hey, everybody.
Oh, hi,
I'm David.
Riley.
He's all yours.
No wallet.
No cash or keys either.
Body's in full rigor.
Roll him.
I saw that...
and I'm not ever going
to forget it.
(laughs)
(anxious chuckle)
What does lividity
tell you?
That he was lying here
when he died.
How do you know that?
'Cause I'm a CSI level two.
And this is part
of your proficiency evaluation.
Yeah, but it's pass-fail.
Lividity's fixed
along the posterior aspect.
Pressure marks are consistent
with the bench slats.
Do we know how long
he's been here?
Bus driver's certain
the guy wasn't here
an hour and a half ago
when he made
his previous stop.
You see any problem
with that?
Yeah, full rigor takes
12 to 24 hours to set.
And if he's been here
less than 90 minutes,
how does he end up
in full rigor?
Well, he looks like
he was on a run.
Maybe he had a heart attack and
went into spontaneous rigor.
Intense physical activity
rapidly depletes
muscle fibers of ATP,
which gives them the energy
they need to contract.
If there's not enough ATP
at the time of death,
the muscles can lock up
and immediately go into rigor.
What's bugging you?
This is the second case
of rapid-onset rigor mortis
we've had
in the last 24 hours.
That's pretty weird.
Even for Vegas.
Brass checked Carla
Peretti's apartment.
No forced entry or any
signs of disturbance.
She was last seen alive
leaving Desert Palm Hospital
at the end of her shift.
Anybody know
where she was going?
Well, apparently, it could
have been a lot of places.
She was working a bunch
of jobs on the side--
model, club dancer,
convention booth babe.
You know, typical Vegas
pretty girl stuff.
Mm-hmm.
Autopsy report.
Cause of death:
cardiac arrest.
That's coroner speak
for "I can't explain
what killed her."
Yeah.
No signs of
conductivity burns,
no evidence of nuclear
streaming in the tissue.
There's no indications of
electrocution whatsoever.
There's other ways
for the muscles to seize up.
You know,
maybe she was epileptic.
Mm, sorry, no epilepsy drugs
in her system.
People go off their meds
all the time.
That's how they get seizures.
Uh, she had
no medical history of epilepsy.
But the disease doesn't leave
any physical record in the body.
The tox panel
ruled out poisons and O.D.'s.
She had a small
amount of zolpidem
in her system, but
that stuff's in most
over-the-counter
sleep aids these days.
It's nothing
that would kill her.
CATHERINE:
No organ damage.
No disease, no trauma.
This was a perfectly healthy
young woman.
Yeah, till she dropped dead...
without dropping.
Well, I always thought it was
cool that teeth fluoresced,
but veneers didn't.
How'd you get them?
Somebody bet me
that I couldn't jump into a lake
with a rope swing in my mouth.
And that pulled
the teeth out?
No.
(beep)
But it sure did hurt my neck.
On the way home,
I hit a fire hydrant.
And you bumped the steering
wheel with your mouth.
No, I was on my bike
at the time.
I flew over the hydrant
and smashed into the crossbar
of a chain link fence.
With your mouth.
My shoulder.
Broke my clavicle.
Okay, then how'd
you lose the teeth?
This one was a root canal.
This one, a post
and a crown.
And this one-- I, uh...
I was in college.
I woke up one morning,
and it was gone.
I don't know
what happened to it.
Al Robbins.
Riley Adams.
Pardon the latex.
Okay.
What do we got?
Uh, somebody
who liked to party.
Prelim tox showed traces
of meth, E and heroin
in his system.
Doesn't sound like someone who
would go for a run at midnight.
ROBBINS:
I doubt this guy could've
run a hundred feet
without stopping to rest.
He had pulmonary edema.
Fluid's backed up in the lungs.
Sometimes suggests drug abuse.
Is that C.O.D.?
I doubt it.
The edema wasn't acute.
Far as I can tell,
C.O.D. is cardiac arrest.
Same as the lady in the park.
Yeah, which brings us
to something interesting.
The victim's liver.
Note the slight
reddish
and pinkish coloration.
Very similar
to Carla Peretti.
Assuming
the cases are connected,
the condition of
the victims' livers
might suggest
an alternate C.O.D.
Gaseous asphyxiation.
I'll have Hodges do
a blood gas assay.
(sighs)
DETECTIVE (on phone):
We walked the photo
of the jogger
around the local
methadone clinic and got lucky.
Name's Harley Soon.
He has a sheet.
Drug abuse, solicitation,
some other petty stuff.
Juvie record, too,
but that's sealed.
Thank you, Detective.
No problem.
(hangs up)
You doing a
headspace assay?
Yes, which is,
I believe, your job.
Where have you been?
I was just, uh... nowhere.
You want me to finish up?
I'm almost done.
Um...
hold on a second.
What?
You added
the liberating agent.
Yes.
You added the sulfuric.
You skipped over
the sodium dithionite?
Yes, I think I did.
I think I must have done it
with all of these.
It's probably better to
redo the whole assay.
Um, listen, I can get it.
Should have been doing
it to begin with.
(laughs)
Don't worry
about it.
I know it's
been a long day.
Every day's a long day.
(two beeps)
(snaps phone shut)
I have to go.
Thank you.
(clamoring,
siren wails in distance)
MAN:
5:30 a.m. I don't pick up
"those people,"
if you know
what I'm saying.
I don't care
how nicely dressed they are.
Hey, hey, hey,
that's illegal.
Yeah, which is why I stopped
and told him to hop in,
but he just stood there
like that, stock still.
Creeped me out,
I don't mind telling you.
You're gonna love this.
CABBIE:
Uh...
(camera shutters clicking
nearby)
I've heard of dying
with your boots on, but, uh,
this is ridiculous.
(bones crunching)
(grunts)
Businessman
with an empty briefcase.
No wallet or I.D.
Consistent with
the other vics.
We got a serial killer, Greg,
and he's working at a pace
of one body per day.
Great. Something to look
forward to tomorrow.
Damn!
This thing is heavy.
He's got lead in the sole
of his shoe.
Must be what was keeping
him on his feet.
There's a coating
of dust on here.
GRISSOM: His fingernails
have been recently trimmed,
but they're filthy at the beds.
And he's got dirt in his ears.
His feet and ankles are
all scabbed and crusty
and his toenails are growing
back into his toes.
This guy's been cleaned up,
but I'll bet you
he lived on the street.
Yep. Head lice.
They're all dead.
Good.
I hate those little bastards.
So we've got three victims,
all stripped
of their identities.
A homeless guy dressed
like a businessman,
a hustler druggie dressed
like a runner,
and a nurse...
dressed like herself.
What do they have in common?
Tox found traces
of zolpidem in all three.
Other than that,
we're comparing
all the trace evidence
from the victims' clothing
and personal effects,
but so far,
nothing probative.
ADAMS:
PD is circulating photos
of the businessman around
shelters and soup kitchens
in the area,
but there's no I.D. yet.
This girl's an LPN.
Maybe her hospital's
the connection.
RILEY:
According to Harley Soon's
medical records,
he was never treated
at Desert Palm.
Well, Carla Peretti
is the one victim
who had a mainstream life.
That means e-mails,
phone calls, documents.
If there's anything
that connects these people,
the way to find it
is through her.
Looks like
she was an art student.
ADAMS:
Ah...
The naughty drawer.
What?
(sniffing)
Hydroponic,
medical grade,
put-you-on-your-ass,
send-you-to-dreamyland weed.
Nurses always get
the good stuff.
Uh...
take it you're aware
of the lab's
random drug testing policy?
Oh, yeah.
I've got a bottle
of clean urine in my locker,
just in case.
I'm kidding.
(forced laugh)
Good one.
Here, I'll bag it.
Check this out.
An original of Carla.
Bizarre. She looks kind of...
Dead?
Yeah, a little.
What's that say?
J... Skaggs?
Never heard
of him.
Me, neither.
I bet somebody has.
(beep)
What do you know.
He's a local.
Hey!
Jerzey Skaggs?
Jerzey? Skaggs?
Hey! Jerzey Skaggs?
Who are you?
Homicide.
This might look good
in my living room.
You can't afford it.
Your arm down,
and wake up.
Wake up!
What do you want?
Do you know Carla Peretti?
Who?
Carla Peretti.
Oh, yeah...
yeah, she was one
of my models.
She's a lovely girl.
It's a cheap
imitation of my work.
Well, you'll have to take it up
with the coroner,
because she's dead for real.
I'm sorry to hear that.
You paint these guys?
No. Never saw
those guys
before in my life.
You know, Harley Soon
used to crash at a buddy's
apartment in the neighborhood.
Relax.
And he seems
to be kind of your type.
Huh? So maybe you, uh...
maybe you bumped into him
at the grocery store
or something.
I don't go out.
I don't shop.
I don't bump.
But you do paint dead people.
I paint people
who look dead,
and you would weep
if you knew
how much I make doing that.
If you haven't noticed,
our culture seems to be obsessed
with sex and death.
I've noticed.
Let me save you some time,
'cause I know
what's on your mind.
I don't kill my models.
I don't even bang them
much anymore.
Occasionally, of course, but...
oh, I find not
with the same gusto and verve
as in days gone by.
You bang Carla Peretti?
I'm not doing women.
Mind if I look around?
I'd like to paint you nude.
I don't do nude.
Where would I pin the badge?
Exactly.
(machine whirring)
Ms. Alwick.
Dr. Grissom.
Were you looking
for me?
No, just getting
some more tea.
I was hoping we might
get a chance to chat.
I'm right in the
middle of a case.
I know, I understand
that you're dealing
with a lot, but, um,
if you do find the time...
Thank you, I appreciate that.
This, uh, may be
outside your field
of expertise, but...
lately, I've been having
some problems with Hank.
HODGES:
Grissom.
Oh, hi, Patricia.
Nice to see you again, David.
The headspace assay came back
and showed levels
of carbon monoxide
in all the vics,
as well as the dead lice
on the businessman's head.
Excuse me.
STOKES:
Mostly simple hydrocarbons
and sulfur dioxide,
along with the
carbon monoxide.
That's consistent with
gasoline engine exhaust.
Yeah, and since the lice
on the homeless guy died,
it suggests that he
was completely surrounded
by exhaust fumes,
not suffocated
with a mask or a tube.
WILLOWS:
Or locked in a sealed car,
for that matter-- there
wouldn't have been
enough room to pose them.
Lividity says
the victims died
in the positions
in which they were discovered.
So, what does that mean,
that the killer
is using some sort
of gas chamber?
I think so.
He lures someone
back to his place,
slips them a sedative,
then redresses
and positions the bodies
inside a sealed container.
Waits for the carbon monoxide
to go to work.
Once the bodies
are in full rigor,
he's got about ten hours
to place them
and have them discovered.
Now that we know the recipe,
let's find the cook.
(chirping)
(gasping excitedly)
(whispering):
Hey...
I believe I just sighted
Aeronautes saxatalis.
Aeronautes saxatalis,
the white-throated swift.
They hardly ever range this far
south this time of year.
STOKES:
The elderly couple
was suffering from Alzheimer's.
They were on
a little field trip
from their
assisted care facility
day before yesterday.
Staff didn't even realize
they were missing
till bed check.
What, no surveillance cameras
on the bird-watching path?
No, but the unis
did turn up a crackhead
who said he saw
an average-height
white male
in a white panel van
near the trail,
about an hour before dawn.
MAN (over speaker):
Caught in their
quotidian routines,
these haunting figures,
frozen in time, seem to mock
the mundane blandness
that screams silently
beneath the sizzle
of Sin City.
What is this?
Local art blog.
Our psycho is the hot topic.
They call him
the "Mannekiller."
...perhaps, finally,
by using the flesh
of human beings
to replicate the flesh
of human beings...
this madman
who moves silently among us
has crossed art's
final frontier.
This is Langston Weller,
signing off
from mindscanvas.com.
This site's been
getting hammered.
Check out the comments.
STOKES:
"You're a one-man argument
against free speech."
"This is murder,
pure and simple,
and you're a moron."
"Hitler was right--
kill the artists first."
At least nobody's buying
this crap.
"Vibrant images
"of life culled
from the raw stuff of death.
These are works of art."
Apparently, there are some
who share this aesthetic.
SANDERS:
The dust found inside
the businessman's shoes
was actually undyed jute fibers.
The same fibers were
also found on tape lifts
from the other
vic's clothes.
Killer's probably
covering his vics
in woven jute--
i.e., burlap--
at some point
during the process.
Thanks, Greg.
You bet.
Dr. Grissom, may I have
a word with you?
Yes, of course.
Come in.
I wonder why it is
that you hold what I do
in such obvious contempt.
Excuse me?
The last time we spoke,
you mentioned
that you were having problems
with Hank.
Now, out of
concern for you
and because I take my job
very seriously,
I started asking around.
Oh...
And was met
by a mixture
of bafflement and
smirks by most
of your staff, until
David Hodges took pity on me
and informed me that
Hank was your dog.
I apologize.
It was
a serious question.
Oh, really?
For the last few weeks,
my dog's been listless.
Barely eats.
And I just, uh, wondered
if you thought it was possible
that pets could take on
the emotions of their owners.
Well...
companion animals were bred
to respond to human beings.
At some level, I do
believe that they resonate
with what their
owners are feeling.
So, what are you feeling?
I've just been...
a little distracted lately.
Uh, having a hard time focusing
on the details.
That's normal.
Not for me.
I wondered, uh, if you knew,
typically, how long this lasts.
There's no typical.
Days, weeks, sometimes years.
The important thing
is to acknowledge it.
But you do have
to talk about it.
And if not with me, then
with somebody else.
And soon.
(phone ringing)
Jim, got something?
BRASS:
Yeah, Harley Soon's
juvie record.
I got the court administrator
to unseal it.
He was arrested five years ago
in a drug raid
on a party at the art studio
of Jerzy Skaggs.
BRASS:
So, how do you
like my studio?
This is ridiculous.
No, what's
ridiculous
is you denying
that you knew Harley Soon.
What?
Party was five years ago.
The kid was 16
at the time.
You should have been
busted for that, too.
Listen to me--
everybody who was anybody
came to my parties.
And many like yourself,
who are nobody at all.
You know, I just...
I can't remember everybody
who came to my parties.
All right, so you
reconnected
with Harley Soon...
and you're connected
with Carla Peretti.
A lot of people you know
are turning up dead.
You're telling me these
are actual dead people?
Come on, it's been
all over the news.
I don't... I don't watch TV.
And I only use the Internet
to make money.
Man, that is wild.
Death just mocking life.
(making whooshing sounds)
Are you done?
You know, these look familiar.
Yeah, I bet
they do.
No, no, no, no, not the...
not the people, the poses.
Somebody... somebody
showed me drawings
like these,
months ago.
These people remind me
of those wretched sketches.
MAN:
Excuse me,
Mr. Skaggs.
If I could
have a moment,
would you mind taking
a quick look at these?
Uh-uh... uh-uh.
I can't stand looking
at inferior art.
It just...
it sears into my consciousness
like bad Mexican food.
Who was he?
No, I don't remember,
but he was, you know,
babbling about some insipid
municipal
sculpture...
competition
he was hoping to win.
Open... to the public.
Oh, okay, so he was an artist.
No, he was some kind
of contractor,
subcontractor,
sub-subcontractor,
sub-sub-subcontractor.
I think my... my
studio was, uh,
being renovated, and it was...
you know, it was a big job.
There was lots of...
lots of manual...
labor involved.
I need a name.
He was a laborer--
why would I know his name?
Because you hired him.
I didn't hire him.
One of those contractors
hired him.
And no, I don't remember
his name.
I... I barely remember
your name.
What is your name?
Eight months ago, the city
sponsored a competition
to create a series
of bronze lifelike statues
for its parks
and public spaces.
"Las Vegas: for the
rest of your life".
Yeah, and all the applications
were submitted digitally.
This is what the Parks
Department sent over.
Hey, take a look
at this one.
It's a submission
from an Arthur Blisterman.
Look at this.
Jackpot, huh?
The rules stated that...
the sculpture
should recreate the ethnic
and socioeconomic diversity
that make the city
so vibrant and alive.
This guy was following them
to the letter.
Yeah, except that he
was substituting bronze
with human flesh.
Guys, there's a, uh,
sculpture number six here.
We only found five bodies.
GRISSOM:
Oh, God.
He's not done.
So, we got Blisterman's house
staked out.
The neighbors
haven't seen him for weeks.
Now, the guy's unmarried,
got no criminal record.
He's an independent
plumbing contractor,
so he makes
his own schedule,
and he's not answering
his phone.
No, he has a white panel van.
We got a broadcast out.
GRISSOM:
He's got to have some kind
of work space
or studio, somewhere
he can come and go unnoticed.
Look, there's nothing on record.
We've released a picture,
we've notified the schools
and Child Services
to be on alert.
Right now,
that's all we can do.
Why do you think
people make art?
Self-expression.
Yeah, but I think
also to...
provoke or elicit
a reaction.
Maybe the killer's
into the controversy of it.
I think one of these blog
posters might be our guy.
Maybe.
Click on that photo link.
What?
There's no yellow tape.
No bystanders.
No crime scene.
Let me the check the metadata.
This photo was taken
at 5:49 a.m.
The body wasn't
reported till after 7:00.
I guess our "artist"
couldn't resist
a snapshot of his first
installation.
"Anonymous" is Blisterman.
WELLER:
How much trouble am I in?
VARTANN:
Well, that remains
to be seen.
But the way I see it, you
encouraged a serial killer
to kill on your blog.
I did no such thing.
Did I?
We'll leave that up
to a jury of your peers.
I swear to God,
I didn't want to hurt anybody.
I didn't do anything.
Except shooting
your mouth off.
Sometimes that's all it takes.
Look, right now,
you're going to do exactly
what I tell you to.
Of course.
What do you
want me to do?
The killer's been
posting to your blog
from different IP
addresses around town.
So, you're gonna
go on this computer,
get on your blog,
and post
another reply
to Mr. Anonymous.
You're going to get
him to respond and
when he does,
you're going
to keep him talking
until our people can
run an IP trace route
and find out where he
is now-- you understand?
No.
(sighs):
Just start typing.
Right.
What do you want me to say?
Just tell him
he's a genius, all right?
Tell him that, uh,
Michelangelo's
got nothing on him.
Whatever, just think
of something.
Come on.
Come on!
Right.
(whispering)
I'll be right back.
Keep typing.
Ma'am?
(gasps)
My boy, my Charlie.
Okay...
He's only nine years old.
He didn't come home
from school today.
We had a fight this morning
and I thought that he was
at his dad's house--
we're divorced--
and then the school
told me about
some kind of alert
that was happening.
Right. Do you have any idea
where he might be going?
No, no.
Okay...
Detective Vartann,
I got him.
I got him talking.
(beeping)
LVPD! Please remain calm.
I'd like everybody to stay
right where they are.
Where's the kid?
What kid?
Get up! Get up.
No...
Get him out of here.
What-what kid?
Hey, hey! Hey!
I didn't
do anything.
Come on!
VARTANN:
There was tan dust
on the guy's hands
like the other vics.
Burlap fibers.
Does it help?
I don't know.
Blisterman didn't
put himself in a burlap sack.
You know, maybe these
fibers are environmental.
Like they're present
in whatever space
he's keeping his victims in.
You know, there's a lot
of converted warehouses
and industrial properties
near this library.
If Blisterman
already has the kid,
he'd probably
stay close to home.
We've got city plans
for the area around the library.
Maps, building usage permits...
Okay, check every structure,
every single one.
(beeping)
He's willing to talk,
but only to someone who
"understands his work."
I'm ready
to slap him around.
I figured you could
show some restraint.
I'll try.
Okay.
Mr. Blisterman.
Can you please turn the monitor
so I can see it?
Could you tighten up
the frame up a little?
The composition is...
It's a bit weak.
Yeah. Thank you.
Look...
I'm here
to talk about the child.
I'm happy to talk.
I like to talk,
but I want my words
to be heard
the way I speak them.
I want the world
to see the words
coming from my lips,
so there can be
no misinterpretation.
Nobody's going to misinterpret
anything you say.
But if you don't start
cooperating...
Don't, don't... rush me.
I want to talk about
what I want to talk about,
and I don't want...
to be rushed, please.
That's the trouble
with modern life,
it's too much urgency.
It's too much speed.
Now I'm sweaty.
Do you have a handkerchief?
Thank you.
(beeping)
Aesthetics have always
been very important to me.
Life wouldn't
be worth living
without beauty.
It's what makes us human.
What about the people
you've murdered?
They were human.
Yeah, but...
they were nothing until I made
them extraordinary.
How about the child?
Has he become "extraordinary"?
I have been
alone my entire life.
I have tried and tried
to achieve some recognition
for my work,
and I have been repeatedly
and cruelly ignored.
And this has made me
feel very... bad...
about myself.
Arthur.
You're going to be
put to death
if you don't help us.
I'm not scared of dying.
I just don't
want to be forgotten.
I think I found it.
"487 Franklyn Street."
It's a warehouse,
formerly deeded
to a company
that manufactured
natural fiber bags
and shipping materials-- go.
I'll call it in.
I want something
of who I was left behind
so people will speak my name,
and know who I was,
after I'm gone.
Believe me.
No one will ever forget you.
You've made it.
You're a legend.
If I tell you
where the boy is,
you're going to turn
the camera off,
and then...
I'll be sad.
I won't turn the camera off.
I'm sorry.
Without the boy,
the piece is incomplete.
(sirens blaring)
(tires screeching)
487...
Franklyn Street.
You're far too late
to save him.
Anyway...
I got what I wanted.
You'll remember me.
Won't you?
(deep rhythmic pounding
echoing through hallways)
What the hell
is that?
Sounds like a motor.
Take that hall.
(pounding rhythm
increasing in volume)
(pounding continues)
(switch clicks,
air hisses)
(coughing)
All right, yeah,
I got him.
(gasping)
Patrol, this is
CSI Sanders.
We need paramedics.
(gasping)
Come on.
(panting)
Damn it, breathe!
Breathe!
ADAMS:
Come on.
Breathe.
(coughs)
Hey, it's okay.
ADAMS:
Shh. It's okay.
You're all right now.
ADAMS (quietly):
It's okay. It's okay.