♪ ♪
She's got a pulse!
Airway's clear.
Adrenaline's going in.
Heart's holding
steady at 60.
(siren wailing)
Give me the Ambu bag.
Oxygen to 15 liters.
Keep the pressure
on her.
Let's move out,
got to go.
Got to hand it
to the paramedics.
They keep things
interesting.
Yeah, well, life
does take priority.
I'll ask Riley
to stop by the hospital
and get their boots
for elimination.
Where do you want me
to start?
(scoffs)
Wherever you like.
(shutter clicks)
Her name is
Janelle Rowe.
Her daughter's
name is Nora.
Neighbor heard gunshots,
called it in.
Is the kid going to live?
It's touch
and go.
Food's still warm.
What's going on?
Sir, wait.
They must have just got home.
Sir...
My daughter.
Please.
Oh, my God, Janelle!
Janelle!
Sir, sir, sir,
you can't come in here, sir.
(grunting):
Get off me!
Hey, hey,
take it easy.
Take it easy.
Ow.
OFFICER:
You're under arrest
for assaulting
a police officer.
BRASS:
Get him up,
get him out of here.
No one should have
to come home to this.
Yeah,
but was it grief
or was it guilt?
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
BRASS:
CSI found a .38 revolver in the
glove compartment of your car
with empty shell casings
in the cylinder, which means
it was recently discharged,
and your hands tested positive
for gunshot residue.
So what if there was a gun in
my car? I have a permit for it.
You had no right
to search my car
without a warrant.
Wh-What, what are you
talking about?
You were agitated and hostile,
you attacked a police officer.
You fired your gun
tonight.
I was target shooting
in the desert.
I can show you where.
I appreciate the offer,
Mr. Rowe,
but unless someone was out there
in the desert with you,
it's not an alibi.
Why would I
need an alibi?
PHILLIPS:
Bullet entered the neck
below the chin...
and exited just below
the right occipital bone.
I'm guessing the bullet's
around here someplace.
Thanks for the tip.
This chair's
been knocked over.
Assuming the paramedics
didn't do it,
there might have been
some kind of a struggle.
Hey, Dave, does the vic have
any head wounds?
I don't see any...
but I heard the little girl
had a forehead laceration.
She might have slammed
her head here
unless someone else did it
for her.
(head bangs on table)
You think I did this?
I want to see my Nora;
I want to see my little girl.
She's in
Desert Palm Hospital.
Severe head trauma.
She hasn't even
regained consciousness yet.
I want,
I want to see her now.
We're going
to see her, okay,
when we're done.
Now, help me out.
Think about this.
Who would want to do this
to your wife and daughter?
I don't know.
So what do you think?
It's just a tragic,
random act of violence?
Why don't you tell me?
That's your job.
(hard rock playing)
(laughter and whooping)
STOKES:
Take a couple
of high school kids
and put 'em in a fast car.
Add a few beers
and a driver with a lead foot.
Yeah, baby.
Throw in an unexpected obstacle
and a little physics...
Whoa, dude!
(tires screeching)
(all screaming)
(glass shattering)
...and what you get
is a very abrupt end
to a party on wheels.
You just described my
whole senior year...
which admittedly ended
better than theirs.
From their D.L.s,
driver is Chase Bowman,
passenger
is Max Poole.
Varsity football
at Ridge Valley High.
At least he was
wearing a seatbelt.
The safer they
make the cars,
the more risks the drivers
are willing to take.
It's called the Peltzman Effect.
Man.
Tree practically
ate the car.
Anybody see anything?
Only after
the fact.
Somebody must have
heard something.
We're in the sticks.
Houses are
pretty far apart.
What do you got?
Splinters
in the wound.
There's no branches
on this side.
If a car hits a tree
and there's nobody
there to hear it,
it still makes
one hell of a sound.
♪ ♪
(gunshot)
(thud)
Hey, look what I found.
I let my fingers do
the walking.
What does that mean?
Never mind.
Lock's been forced.
This was probably the killer's
point of entry and exit.
I'm gonna go search
the perimeter.
MR. ROWE:
How many times do I
have to say this?
I didn't do this.
Let's,
let's go over this.
So a neighbor gets up,
she hears some arguing,
and she looks
out the window.
She sees a muzzle flash
and hears a gunshot,
and she hears footsteps
go out a back gate.
Now, this neighbor says
she hears arguing--
she says it's like a fight club
over there.
So I checked Dispatch,
and there are three calls
out for domestic violence
in the last three months.
I never laid a hand on Janelle.
You know, one call is,
like, a misunderstanding,
but three is a pattern.
I loved my wife, but she had--
she was a wannabe actress
with a flair for
the dramatic.
We fought a lot,
but it was only words.
Well, here's
an interesting development.
Well, good news.
We have a new suspect.
His name is Mark Redding--
the prime suspect
in a homicide
about 12 years ago,
but he went
under the radar
for a long time.
But, uh,
you must know who he is
because according to these
fingerprints, he's you.
Changing your name
is not a crime.
Okay?
No, it's not.
But let me tell you what is.
Your first wife Amy hired
a private investigator
named Trevor Murphy
to find out
if you were cheating
on her.
Of course, you were.
Isn't that right,
Mark, Peter?
Which do you prefer?
So, anyway, this
private investigator Murphy--
he proved Amy was right,
and she was, uh, disappointed,
so he consoled her, you know,
in her time of need.
He comforted her
in the biblical sense,
and you found out
about it,
and then Murphy was no more.
His car was found abandoned
at a gas station in the desert,
and you were
the prime suspect.
I was never even charged.
That's because
Trevor Murphy's body
was never found.
Maybe that's
because he's not dead,
which is what I told
the cops back then.
I didn't kill anybody.
Okay?
Yeah, but...
bodies keep piling up
around you.
Why is that?
You just having a string
of bad luck?
Listen, I think I know
who might have killed Janelle.
I think I do, too.
I don't have
a name, but...
I've been getting death
threats-- anonymous e-mails.
Here, I can show you.
"I promise death is coming.
"You will not know when,
but when it comes
"you will know why.
"You will rot like Trevor rots.
I will watch."
I've been getting stuff
like this for months.
Whoever killed
Janelle...
I think they,
they were gunning for me.
Driver's C.O.D. is
subdural hematoma as a result
of injuries sustained
in the crash.
Same deal with his
buddy, more or less.
Multiple skull
fractures consistent
with flying face-first
through a windshield.
C.O.D here is atlanto-
occipital dislocation.
So his skull just separated
from his spine?
Yeah.
Well, at least
it was quick.
Thanks, Doc.
Whoa, whoa, hold
your horses.
There's something
you should see.
About that shoulder
wound you found,
I found a cluster of related
injuries on the right arm--
fractured right
distal humerus,
dislocated shoulder,
and torn rotator cuff.
Come here.
The direction of
applied force in a break
is indicated by the
fracture plateau.
That's the flat section
of bone at the break.
The arm
must have been hanging
outside the car
something like this.
In this case, it indicates that
something bent the arm back,
snapping it
on the backside of the elbow,
which in turn caused
chain reaction injuries
to the rotator cuff
and shoulder.
That's an unusual injury
for a head-on collision.
Could have injured it
before the crash?
I don't think so.
Bruising doesn't suggest that
and all the wounds
are perimortem.
Well, maybe
the arm
just broke itself.
That'd be
a first.
Thanks.
(clock ticking)
♪ ♪
(tires screeching)
STOKES:
The EDR records vehicle data
for about five seconds prior
to the airbag's deployment.
This indicates
that the antilock brakes
activated four seconds
before impact.
Sounds like the car
lost traction.
Hmm.
Was it wet?
Nope.
Was there oil?
No.
(computer beeping)
STOKES:
According to the data,
looks like the driver
veered right
and then overcompensated left.
If the car veered
onto the shoulder,
then one tire is
on the asphalt.
The other one's spinning
in the gravel,
which would activate
the ABS, and...
you did find this gravel
in the soft top, right?
Mm-hmm.
But you do not
appear to be convinced.
The shoulder was undisturbed
at the scene.
We're still missing
something there, Colombo.
Logged onto Facebook
lately, Doc?
I've been a little busy.
That's too bad.
I just schooled
you in Logolous.
I played "quilt" across.
The "T" made
"ire" into "tire"
on a double word score.
36 points.
Very impressive.
You want COD
on Janelle Rowe?
Bullet to the head?
Exsanguination from transection
of the jugular
by a .38 caliber round,
if you please.
And I bet
there's something
you don't know.
This bruise was inflicted
perimortem.
Looks like a gun sight.
Maybe she was pistol-whipped.
(grunting)
Certainly
a possibility.
Is that it?
Yeah... oh, oh,
I'm almost forgot.
I played "quartz" off your "Q"
with a triple-word score
of 72 points.
So much for youth
and enthusiasm.
I look forward
to old age and treachery.
BRASS:
Thanks for coming in,
Ms. Murphy.
Thank you.
You said this
was about my father.
Did you find his body?
Unfortunately, no.
No, this is about a...
a murder suspect
we have in custody.
His name is Mark Redding.
Wacky guess:
he says he's innocent.
You know, I remember you
from when my father
went missing.
You bought me a soda
in the waiting room.
You were really nice to me.
Well, I'm glad I was able
to help a little.
You don't remember.
I wish I could forget.
What does this
have to do with me?
Uh, about nine
years ago,
uh, Mark Redding
changed his name to Peter Rowe.
He said he did it
because he felt like there
was a target on his back.
Couple of
months ago,
he started to get
death threats
from anonymous e-mails,
and all those e-mails
mentioned your father.
My dad had a lot
of angry friends.
Well, the e-mails
were sent
from an account that was set up
on your IP address.
You think I wrote them?
It's a wacky guess-- did you?
Of course not.
He probably sent them
to himself.
Do you mind if I ask you
where you were last night?
Do you mind
if my lawyer answers?
You guys
are unbelievable.
Uh, Ms. Murphy.
(sighs)
We have a warrant
for your computer.
(sighs)
Knock yourself out.
My dad has been dead
for a long time.
All I want to do
is get on with my life.
Just leave me alone.
JOHNSON:
The pink cell phone
belonged to Nora Rowe.
Maybe the killer took it.
SANDERS:
Why would the killer
take a kid's cell phone
and then ditch it
less than a block away?
Probably thought
they trashed it.
Most people don't realize how
tough these memory cards are.
Look at this.
Most of these pictures
were taken
within two hours of the murder.
Hold it.
That's Janelle Rowe's kitchen,
taken right around the
time of the shooting.
You know, the
neighbor said
that she saw a muzzle flash
when she heard the gunshot,
but what if it
was a camera flash?
(Touch-Tone dialing)
(clicking)
No, get away...
I bet the killer thought
his face was in that photo.
Got Ballistics
on Peter Rowe's gun.
It's not the murder weapon.
No IBIS hits
on it, either.
Well, I'm gonna go
out on a limb here
and say he
didn't do it.
SANDERS:
Okay... you know,
let's say
he was telling the truth,
that someone blamed him
for the death of Trevor Murphy,
and his wife and daughter
got caught up
in the revenge.
So, the death threats
were more than just threats.
So, let's find out
who really sent those e-mails.
HODGES:
On the left, the exemplars
from the aspen tree
found at the crime scene.
On the right,
the splinters from the
passenger's shoulder wound.
WILLOWS:
They're different.
Whatever stabbed him,
it wasn't that tree.
It was, uh, treated
hardwood and white ash,
known for its durable
bending quality
and hardness.
Not unlike me.
You didn't learn anything
in sensitivity training,
did you?
I took what I needed,
and I left the rest.
Where would you
find white ash?
It's found in
long handles,
such as garden rakes,
spades, shovels.
And it's also found
in some baseball bats,
because it's a lighter
wood with a long grain.
Mailbox baseball.
These guys were playing
mailbox baseball.
Yeah, that
would explain the...
the weird fracture
to his right arm.
(man whooping)
Yeah, right there, right there!
(smashing mailbox)
(laughter and whooping)
You're serious.
Oh, yeah, I'm dead serious.
It's really fun.
When you're a bored teenager
who's feeling destructive.
If you knock the box
cleanly off its post,
then it's a home run.
Everything else,
just a base hit.
That's pathetic.
Actually, it's awesome.
It's a release.
You know, in
high school,
in chem club, I once painted
iodide of beryllium
on the inside
of my best friend's desk drawer,
let it dry overnight,
so when he opened up
the drawer the
next morning,
he got this-- pa!--
explosion
of pink powder
in his face.
(chuckling)
For no reason.
WILLOWS:
Well, this is all
very fascinating
and really quite sad,
and while it might explain
the roots of violent crime,
it doesn't explain
why you didn't find
a bat at the scene
or how a mailbox
full of air
could shatter an arm.
Recess is over.
(chuckles) And it...
Did it go in his mouth?
Oh, yeah.
Went in his mouth-- he was
walking around school
like a lizard, like...
NICHOLS:
Natalie Davis.
You're a serial killer.
You crushed the skull
of a rock star
while he was eating breakfast.
You poisoned an elderly woman,
whose convulsions
sent her flailing
through a window.
(door buzzes, then opens)
You electrocuted a janitor
at a chicken slaughterhouse.
You gassed an undercover cop.
And when your foster father,
in an attempt to protect you,
confessed to your
crime in a video suicide,
you kidnapped
a CSI and trapped her
under a car,
alone, in the desert,
and left her to die there.
You were captured
and you were tried
by a jury of your peers
in a court of law.
What was the verdict?
I was found guilty,
but mentally ill.
And what does
that mean?
It means that
when I committed my crimes,
I knew that what I was
doing was wrong.
But after
I was arrested,
I suffered
a psychotic breakdown.
You were
diagnosed with
catatonic schizophrenia.
You don't seem
catatonic now.
I'm taking medications
that make it go away.
And how do you feel?
I feel like I used to.
Normal.
And that is why
you no longer need
to be treated
in this psychiatric
facility.
You are well enough
to serve the sentence
that you were lawfully given.
You're not mentally ill.
Not anymore.
You're just guilty.
WILSON:
I put Ms. Davis
on Risperidone to treat
the catatonic schizophrenia.
I'm quite pleased
with the results.
How are you treating
her psychopathic
compulsion to kill?
We're not really.
She's on a couple
of anti-O.C.D. meds, but...
Isn't it true that
as the catatonia lifts,
her psychopathic
tendencies will eventually
reassert themselves?
It's certainly possible.
That's because Natalie Davis
has an incurable disease.
Do we imprison
people with M.S.?
With cancer?
She is not
responsible
for her actions.
She needs help.
She needs to remain here.
Thank you, Counsel.
These proceedings will resume
at 10:00 a.m. tomorrow.
Until then,
we're adjourned.
(gavel bangs)
(door buzzes, then opens)
Come on.
NICHOLS (sighing):
Dr. Grissom.
Miss Nichols.
Glad to see you.
Is Sara coming, too?
I'm afraid
she's not available.
I see. You know, Gil, you were
the only person in the room
when Natalie had
her psychotic break.
It would really help me out
if you'd get up there
and testify.
I can't render an opinion
to her mental state.
I'm not a psychiatrist
or a psychologist.
I'd call you
as a percipient witness.
You'd only have to testify
about what you observed
with your own eyes.
How she was then,
and how she is now.
I can arrange a
meeting with Natalie.
Okay.
I would like to see her.
ADAMS:
Archie located
the e-mail server that sent
death threats to Peter Rowe.
I thought they were sent
from Kelsey Murphy's house.
The e-mail account
was created there.
The e-mails themselves came
from a halfway house downtown.
Oh. I assume
Brass is checking it out?
Definitely. I had them
fax over a resident list.
One of the names
jumped off the page.
Nathan Murphy?
Kelsey has a brother.
BRASS:
Making death threats
is a felony, Nathan.
So I go to jail for that
while Mark Redding gets
to walk for murder?
He's only a murderer
according to you.
How'd you find him?
My dad was a P.I.
And the Internet's
a beautiful thing.
Right.
Why should Mark
Redding live happily
after what he did?
New name, new wife, new life?
(sighs)
It makes me sick.
I wanted him looking
over his shoulder at night,
feeling afraid.
KELSEY:
I gave Nathan
my old laptop
six months ago.
He was staying with me
for a few days,
and that's when
he set up the account.
That's why it traced to me.
So, why didn't you mention that
earlier?
He's my brother.
I wanted to protect him.
So you two are close?
Not anymore.
Why is that?
(sighs)
When we're in a room together,
he doesn't see me.
He only sees Dad.
Somebody had to remind
Mark Redding what he did.
Did you do anything
other than write e-mails?
I wanted to kill him.
I think about it every day.
If anyone had ever laid a hand
on me or my sister
while my dad was alive,
he would have laid them down
like dogs.
If my dad saw me now...
...letting the scumbag
that killed him breathe air
for nine more years...
...he'd spit on me.
His son should have
been stronger.
Where were you last night
between 8:00 and 10:00?
(sniffles)
On the strip alone.
Come on.
Come on, Nathan.
You got to do better than that.
Why?
Because Mark Redding's wife
was murdered last night,
and his daughter is hanging on
by a thread at Desert Palm
Hospital, that's why.
(sighs)
I want my phone call
and a lawyer.
(distant car horns honking)
(tires screeching)
(whooping)
Yeah!
(laughing)
Yes!
Nicky! For God's sakes!
Are you trying
to break your arm?
Oh, no. Don't sweat it. I
tried it on the dummy first.
(wry chuckle)
STOKES:
If it didn't break his arm,
it's not gonna break mine.
HODGES:
It became clear
during our experiments
that it would take something
far more massive
than an aluminum mailbox
to generate the force necessary
to cause the fracture
of the victim's arm.
STOKES:
We're thinking telephone
pole, sign post.
I want to go back out
to the crime scene,
check it out.
Then why are you guys still
in here smashing mailboxes?
Because it's
fun. My turn.
STOKES:
I'm gonna go a
little bit faster
than you did last time.
HODGES:
Please go faster...
And I wonder
why I'm still single.
♪ ♪
(Touch-Tone dialing)
(phone ringing through)
Hodges.
Hey, it's Nick.
Did you have a chance
to process that gravel
I collected
from the convertible top yet?
Of course. It was concrete.
Why? Did you find...?
Thank you.
Nick?
(garbled radio transmission,
distant horse neighing)
Hey, I want to be cooperative
here and everything,
but, uh, you know, seems to
be a little bit intrusive.
Yeah. Well, we could get
a warrant, Mr. Jackmin,
but we'd have to keep you out
of the house if we did.
Seems like a real
big hassle
to me, you know, unless
you got something to hide.
Uh, no. You know, hey,
like I said,
feel free to look around.
Notice that your new mailbox
out there is removable.
Why is that?
Uh, old one
got smashed
a while back.
You know, kids.
I figured it was cheaper
to take it down every night
than to keep on,
uh, replacing it.
Kids, huh?
Yeah.
Did you do it yourself?
I'm a do-it-yourself
kind of guy.
It's a nice walkway.
Thanks.
This looks new.
(distant cow lowing)
Charlie, give me
a hand, will you?
What is this?
A concrete-filled decoy?
Man, you really taught
those boys a lesson, huh?
(whooping)
(yelling, tires squealing)
Four times those kids
trashed my mailbox.
Four times!
STOKES:
Yeah, there's a better way
to handle it.
Weren't you ever a kid?
'Course I was.
If I met myself now
the way I was then,
I'd kick my snotty nose ass.
I didn't mean
to hurt those people.
I heard the crash,
I went out there.
There was nothing
I could do for them.
Oh, no.
STOKES:
No, but you could still
do something for yourself, huh?
(panting)
(grunting)
What was I supposed to do?
Just roll over and let them
keep on doing it to me?
STOKES:
You could have
done something else.
Use cinderblocks,
set up a camera
to get their license plate,
but this?
I didn't make them smash
that mailbox.
No.
But I bet you were hoping
they would, huh?
(garbled radio transmission)
STOKES:
Mr. Jackmin,
you're under arrest
for two counts of
negligent homicide.
(washing machines and dryers
running)
(door slamming)
Hello, Natalie.
Hello.
I wasn't surprised
to see you yesterday.
You weren't?
You want to make
sure I go to jail.
I understand that.
People who do bad things
need to be punished.
Well, I think you're
already being punished.
Then why did you come here?
The only time
I ever saw you,
you weren't yourself.
I wanted to see the person
you really are.
Well... here I am.
Is Sara gonna speak
at the hearing, too?
No.
She doesn't work
with us anymore.
Because of what I did to her.
I don't know.
Occupational therapy?
By working
with the thing I fear the most,
I diminish its power.
I'm very sorry for
what I did to Sara.
And to you.
My foster father
killed himself because of me.
I was wrong
to blame anybody else for it.
Is that how you really feel,
or is that how
you think you should feel?
I understand
if you don't believe me.
Psychopathic personalities
are very often skilled
at mimicking genuine emotion.
But I'm truly sorry.
A year before Trevor Murphy
disappeared,
he was staking out a liquor
store for a client.
One night the joint
gets robbed,
Trevor storms in and drops
the suspect with one shot
It's pretty ballsy
for a P.I..
Yeah.
Well, the bullet was
still in evidence.
So, I compared it to the bullet
that killed Janelle Rowe.
Ballistics confirms
they're both
fired from the same weapon,
a .38 Special.
It's not uncommon
for a killer to keep
his victim's gun.
What if Kelsey and
Nathan are right?
Peter Rowe killed
their father,
used Trevor's own
gun to do it.
I'll call Brass.
We'll bring Peter
back in.
NICHOLS:
Dr. Grissom,
your department
pursued
the so-called "Miniature
Killer" for nearly a year
before you identified
her as Natalie Davis.
By the time she
was captured,
she had kidnapped a
member of your team.
You interviewed
her one time.
Why only that once?
During the course
of our interview,
she had a psychotic break.
Objection.
Witness has no medical
standing here
whatsoever.
Sustained.
Will you please
rephrase?
During the course
of our interview,
Ms. Davis became non-responsive.
So, one moment you were
having a conversation,
and then the next... ?
Tell me where Sara is!
♪ I've got a pain
in my sawdust ♪
♪ That's what's
the matter with me. ♪
She started singing.
NICHOLS:
To you?
GRISSOM:
No.
I believe she was singing
to her dead sister.
Objection.
Sustained.
Her eyes
were no longer focusing on me.
She no longer seemed to hear
what I was saying.
NICHOLS:
All right, Dr. Grissom,
you've been here with us
in this room
and you spoke to Natalie this
morning in the laundry.
How does she appear
to you now?
She makes eye contact.
She answers questions
in a logical manner.
She seems
very present.
She even expresses remorse
for her past actions.
In other words...
normal.
Thank you.
(Bentley clears throat)
I really only have one thing
to ask you, Dr. Grissom.
What do you hope to get out
of coming here?
I don't understand the question.
Let me help.
Are you trying to
punish Natalie
for what she did
to Sara Sidle,
your co-worker
and lover?
NICHOLS:
Objection.
I'll allow it.
During our interview,
I did become frustrated.
Oh, I know, I saw
the police video.
You violently shook Ms. Davis
when she wouldn't give you
Ms. Sidle's location.
If you'd been alone
and unsupervised,
you probably would've beaten it
out of her.
NICHOLS:
Objection,
this is hypothetical.
As I said, I was frustrated.
I was also afraid
for my co-worker.
Then you are here for revenge?
(sighs)
I don't care about revenge.
I have no stake in the outcome
of these proceedings.
Whether Natalie stays here
or goes to prison
is at the discretion
of this court.
I've been trying
to believe that people
can change.
Even people who are damaged.
But I don't know if they can.
I just don't know.
JOHNSON:
Brass went to Desert Palm
to look for Peter,
but he was already gone.
So, head of surveillance
sent me over
this security video for you.
Did someone tip him off?
Well, that's what I
would have thought
until I saw this.
Peter went down
to smoke a cigarette
every couple of hours.
That's Kelsey.
Look how she's standing
behind him,
with her hands
in her pockets.
Does she have
a gun?
That looks
pretty intense.
Where'd they go?
Let's see what she drives.
(typing)
Look at that.
Kelsey's car is equipped
with an Auto-Shadow
G.P.S. system.
We'll need an Attorney General
Waiver to activate it.
(sirens wailing)
(panting)
Please...
Dig!
(sirens approaching)
Let's put the gun down, Kelsey.
Tell them what you did.
Tell them!
(panting):
I killed...
I killed Trevor Murphy,
and I buried him.
If you do this, Kelsey,
I can't help you.
Give me the gun.
When Nathan told me
he found him, I...
I couldn't get it out
of my head.
I staked out his house
for a few weeks.
Just like dad would've.
Learned his schedule.
They weren't supposed
to be there!
(cocking gun)
(camera snapping)
(gasps)
Mom!
Get away from my daughter!
(pistol whipping)
(bangs head on table)
(gunshot)
Everything got so messed up.
We know you didn't mean
to hurt Janelle and Nora.
We know that.
Dig!
Now I talked to the hospital.
The little girl's
going to make it.
Really?
Good.
That's good.
Now all you
have to do...
is give me the gun.
We can still fix it.
Listen to them.
Please.
Shut up!
I confessed, all right?
Arrest me.
Just... I'll spend the rest
of my life in jail.
Shut up!
Just...
Come on, everybody,
just take it easy. Relax.
We don't have
to do anything.
So don't do anything.
Just calm down.
Daddy...
BRASS:
That's good.
Okay.
There you go.
That's okay.
Come on.
Give me the gun.
I really tried to forget.
(four gunshots)
(two gunshots)
(gasping)
Kelsey.
Come on.
BENTLEY:
Judge Brenner has ordered her
to be transferred
to the State Prison in Jean.
She'll continue
to receive her meds,
but as far as therapy goes,
they can't do much.
I'm sorry I couldn't
have been more help.
I'll take her
from here.
You're wrong about me.
I really have changed.
I have changed.
And I really do believe
that people who do bad things...
need to be punished.
(door closes)