LANGSTON:
I responded to a recovered
missing person's vehicle
at the Orpheus Casino.
When I opened the trunk,
I observed a rolled-up carpet
with a large dark stain,
which appeared to be blood.
Inside the carpet, I discovered
the body of Amber Jones.
I also observed
three gunshot wounds.
One to the right shoulder.
Two to the abdomen.
The Medical Examiner
was able to recover
all three of the bullets.
They were nine
millimeter caliber,
six lands and grooves,
right hand twist.
Consistent with the
following four firearms.
A Ruger, Luger,
Walther and Beretta.
WOMAN:
Dr. Langston, did you recover
a murder weapon at the scene?
LANGSTON:
No.
WOMAN:
Has it ever been found?
LANGSTON:
No, the weapon
is still missing.
Can you tell us
if the defendant owns a gun?
Yes.
Congressman Griffin has one
firearm registered in his name.
A Beretta 92.
WOMAN:
Were you able to compare
the congressman's Beretta
against the coroner's bullets?
LANGSTON:
No.
Why not?
The congressman stated that
his gun had been stolen.
So, he must've
filed a police report?
The congressman claimed that he
didn't know his gun was missing
until CSI asked him
to produce it.
Hey!
LVPD! Drop the gun!
Drop it!
Drop the weapon now!
(gunshot)
Everybody stay down.
Catherine!
There was just one shot.
It came from right
outside the door.
What happened here?
He had a gun.
He was headed
for the courtroom.
I tried to get him to stop,
but he just looked at me
and blew his brains out.
I did not fire
my weapon.
That's Dominic Humphreys,
the congressman's
Chief of Staff.
The prosecution's key witness.
And that...
is a Beretta 92.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
Congressman!
(reporters clamoring)
Congressman, how
do you feel about
Dominic Humphreys' suicide?
Why do you think he did it?
Dominic Humphreys was my friend.
His death is not only
a great loss to me,
but to the people of the state.
Then why was he a witness
for the prosecution?
That's all I want to say.
That's enough,
no more questions!
(indistinct yelling)
Get him out of here!
(clamoring continues)
The only reason a guy
eats his gun in a courthouse
is to make a statement.
Bullet looks like a
through-and-through.
A lot of times,
you'll find the bullet
in clotted blood
and brain matter.
So, that's where
you want to start.
Nine millimeter hollow point.
That'll get the job done.
Nick,
this was in his pocket.
Looks like it's signed
by Dominic Humphreys.
HUMPHREYS:
I'm the congressman's
Chief of Staff.
On that day,
he called me around 5:00.
And he said, "Oh, my God,
"Amber's dead.
Please... help me."
So, I drove to her house.
When I got there, she was...
She was on the kitchen floor.
Dead.
I saw that she was shot.
There was a lot of blood.
So much blood;
it was everywhere.
BRASS: Just tell me
what happened next.
I asked him what happened
and he swore he didn't kill her.
That he found her like that,
he had just
come over to apologize,
and she was already dead.
I believed him
because there was no gun.
Then...
I told him to leave.
That I would take care of it.
This was given
in exchange
for reduced sentence.
Counsel, obviously,
this plea testimony
is no longer admissible.
Mr. Whitten can't
cross-examine a dead man.
That doesn't preclude the people
from presenting
the physical evidence.
Your Honor, the
congressman
just wants to clear his name.
If the state's not
going to drop the charges,
we'd like to proceed
as quickly as possible.
Miss Willows, you said the
suicide gun might also be
the missing murder weapon?
How long will you need
to confirm that?
Eight minutes?
Eight hours?
Depends on how well
the bullets are marked.
Plus, we are still
processing the crime scene.
All right, then,
I'll give you
till tomorrow morning.
♪ ♪
Got anything?
Found fibers on your gun.
Where?
Bottom of the slide.
The bottom
of the slide
is exposed only when you're
loading or firing the gun.
Did you identify the fibers?
Uh, yes.
Blue-black dyed
wool cashmere blend.
Dominic Humphreys was wearing a
khaki suit when he shot himself.
So, they're not
from the suicide.
Fibers must've got caught in
there some time before that.
Which means
that if this is the gun
that killed Amber Jones,
and you can match those fibers
to the congressman's clothes,
we've got a slam dunk.
So, get the gun
to Ballistics.
I'll get a search warrant.
Vic left the keys
in the ignition.
I wouldn't call
a suicide a "vic".
All I'm saying is,
he knew he wasn't coming back.
This must've been
the last thing he looked at.
Which makes him
even more selfish.
If he really loved her, he
wouldn't have killed himself.
My husband was convinced
he was going to die in prison.
He was terrified.
He wrote a will,
took out life insurance.
I should have seen it coming.
Why? Did Dominic talk about
what was going on?
No.
He just kept talking
about what he had lost.
How his life was over.
Dom graduated top of
his class from law school.
He wanted to change
the world.
They were going
to do it together.
He idolized Edward.
So, you'd say
the congressman
was more than
just his boss?
He would've done
anything for that man.
I blame him.
This is Edward's fault.
Mrs. Humphreys,
did your husband
ever say anything
about Amber Jones, talk about
the murder?
No.
Did you know your
husband had a gun?
No.
If it had been in the house,
I would've known about it.
Fire two!
(two gunshots)
♪ ♪
Gun's registered
to the congressman.
It's his missing Beretta.
This is the gun
that killed Amber Jones.
Humphreys said there
was no gun at the scene.
He lied under oath.
WILLOWS:
"Dear Edward, I'm sorry.
"Sorry I wasn't
a better man.
"Sorry that I put you
through this.
"I was just trying
to protect you.
"Amber was going to destroy
all our dreams.
"That's why I shot her.
"I killed Amber Jones.
"Forgive me.
Please tell my wife
that I love her."
What does that say
about my conclusions?
The ones I testified to in court
that are part
of the public record?
There's nothing wrong
with your conclusions, Ray.
They were based on valid,
scientific investigation.
And they were signed off by me,
your supervisor.
But Humphreys had the gun.
He confessed.
My experience as a doctor
tells me, Catherine,
that people tend
to tell the truth when they know
they're going to die.
Humphreys lied under oath.
And his confession
is just words.
And the gun is
equivocal.
I mean,
we know that he cleaned up
the crime scene.
Maybe the gun was there, too,
and he lied about that.
Or maybe he stole it from
the congressman's apartment,
killed Amber with it,
and the congressman is
telling the truth.
Well...
the ADA is moving
forward with the case.
They haven't declared
a mistrial?
The judge is going
to allow the jury to hear
about the gun
as well as Humphreys'
suicide confession.
Which means I'll be back
on the stand.
Ray, you testified
that congressman Griffin
was the most
likely suspect.
Which was true
based on the evidence
that we had
at the time.
And now, we have new evidence.
And when the evidence changes,
we modify our theory
to make it fit.
All right.
What's our theory now?
I don't know yet.
LAWYER:
Dr. Langston,
I want to revisit
the autopsy results.
The defendant claims he never
had intercourse with Miss Jones.
Did you find any evidence
to the contrary?
Objection! Leading.
Sustained.
But the witness may answer
the question.
Yes.
We discovered that the victim
had occluded fallopian tubes.
Our tests confirmed
that Miss Jones had
advanced chlamydia.
Because chlamydia is
highly contagious,
it provided us
with a method to confirm
whether or not there had
been sexual contact.
The congressman
tested positive for the same
strain of chlamydia
as the victim.
Which means he
lied again.
Objection.
Withdrawn.
WILLOWS:
There were dark fibers
found in the gun slide.
No match to what
Humphreys was wearing
when he killed himself.
So they could be from
Amber Jones' shooter?
Yep.
That'll be a good thing to know
before the trial's over.
We searched the congressman's
apartment before,
but we weren't looking
for fibers.
The judge has limited this
warrant to just his clothing.
One of his attorneys
will be there for you.
Great.
So, I get a baby shark
as a chaperone.
That'll be fun.
Let me guess,
I get the suicide
closet.
No lawyer.
Just the widow.
I'd rather have
the lawyer.
Nick.
This is going
to take a while.
Well, we don't
have a while.
Langston is back
on the stand.
So, you got some fresh eyes
on this one.
Could Dominic Humphreys
have killed Amber Jones?
Let's start with opportunity.
Did he have time to kill her?
We've only got
approximate TOD.
We found her body on a Saturday.
And she died
sometime Wednesday.
BRASS:
Okay, here's
what I got.
Amber's last phone call
was at 10:07.
She called in sick
to The Tassel Room.
She's a dancer.
Now, phone records also confirm
that the congressman called
Humphreys at 5:03 PM.
And the call lasted
three minutes.
WILLOWS:
And according
to both men,
the congressman made the call
after he discovered
Amber's body.
(stammering):
I need your help.
No, Amber's dead!
Oh, my God.
I'm at her house.
What do I do?
That puts TOLD.
sometime between
10:07 AM and 5:03 PM.
Humphreys was
at a high school with the
congressman from 9:30 AM...
...until noon.
Okay, and then,
he chaired a hearing
from 2:30 till 5:00.
He has no alibi
from noon
to 2:30.
He claimed he went to lunch.
Alone.
Well, then he had plenty of time
to kill her.
So,
how much do they pay you
to stand in a closet?
I get it,
they don't pay you to talk.
MRS. GRIFFIN:
What the hell is
going on here?
This is harassment.
Ma'am,
I gave the search warrant
to your attorney.
I'm here looking
for evidence.
You don't have
enough evidence?
Well, you're not going
to find anything here
because my husband
isn't guilty.
Ma'am, if you don't
let me do my job,
I'm going to have to get
a uniform to remove you.
From my own apartment?
You people never stop.
You've already
destroyed our lives.
Haven't I lost enough?
I'm all done here,
Mrs. Humphreys.
Thank you for your cooperation.
Do you think Dom killed her?
Please.
My husband's
already dead.
I need to know.
Look, I'm sorry, I can't talk
to you about the case.
No one will talk to me.
Not the police,
not my friends.
They don't know
what to say,
what to think.
My advice,
get out of this house.
Go stay
with your family.
Dom was my family.
On the news,
they said there was a note.
What did it say?
He said he loved you.
Did he say why?
Mrs. Humphreys...
Please.
You don't understand.
Actually, I do.
Your husband's note...
whatever it says, it's...
it's not going to take away
your doubts
or your questions.
Some people just can't be saved.
Dr. Langston, you testified
that you discovered
Miss Jones was killed
in her kitchen.
Now, how did you figure
that out again?
I searched for latent
and cleaned up blood stains
using luminol.
The luminol revealed
a torso-shaped blood pool
that was on the floor and had
recently been cleaned up.
It also revealed
high velocity blood spatter
on the walls
that was consistent
with a gunshot...
Thank you, but
I'm not interested
in that right now.
Let's move on, shall we?
Now, you testified
you found
one fingerprint from my client.
Where did you find that?
I found the congressman's print
on the tilt rod of the blinds
covering the front window.
Now, wasn't that
in the living room?
But the murder happened
in the kitchen,
so aren't the two unrelated?
Which question would you like me
to answer?
Can you tell the jury
what chemical you used
to determine when my client
touched the tilt rod?
There isn't one.
So are you
saying that
that one print proves my client
pulled the trigger?
No, but it does prove he lied.
Until I found that print,
the congressman denied
he was ever
in the house.
STOKES:
Okay, Humphreys admitted
cleaning up the scene,
but why a casino parking lot?
Why would Humphreys dump
Amber's body there?
He had to know
about surveillance.
I mean, that's how
you caught him, right?
He was setting
up a fall guy.
Figured it was
worth the risk.
Humphreys was trying
to frame Amber's stalker
ex-boyfriend.
Tommy Ruby.
He's a limo driver
at the casino.
Now, he was our
prime suspect.
But we couldn't
talk to him.
He blew town right
after the murder.
How did Humphreys know
about him?
Because Humphreys helped Amber
file a TRO
against Tommy a few weeks
before she died.
All right, I get the picture.
Humphreys was the congressman's
little bitch.
One of Humphreys' jobs is party
planning for the congressman.
The night before Amber died,
Humphreys called her up.
Amber, he wants to see you.
Get over here
as soon as you can.
Get this-- the congressman keeps
two apartments in his building.
One is for him and the Missus,
the other
is for "entertaining".
So we know they had a date
that night,
but it wasn't all fun
and games.
I mean he even admits
they had an argument.
Now he claims he got so drunk
he passed out.
But he saw her trying
to steal his wallet,
so he hit her so hard
he split her eye open.
Which he only owned up to
because Langston
found Amber's blood
in the apartment.
Now, Humphreys drove her
to the emergency room,
and he signed her out.
STOKES:
He did everything the
congressman asked him to do,
so if the congressman ordered
Humphreys to kill Amber,
then why did he show up
at her house that afternoon?
WILLOWS:
He wouldn't.
So, killing Amber
is all Humphreys' idea?
Is that what we're concluding?
Are you familiar
with a suicide note
left by Dominic Humphreys?
Yes.
But I can't testify to it,
because I...
I didn't process the scene.
No, that's right.
You're still a rookie,
aren't you?
That has nothing to do with it.
I'm handing you a copy
of the note,
which is marked
as defense exhibit M.
Allow me to summarize
the contents.
Mr. Humphreys confessed
to the murder
of Amber Jones.
Now, didn't you testify
that my client
was the most likely suspect
in her murder?
Yes, I did-- however...
You still stand
by your own conclusion?
In light of the new evidence...
Yes or no?
No... I can't.
(gallery murmuring)
JUDGE:
All right,
settle down, quiet.
Thank you.
Hello, Matty.
My name is Ray,
Ray Langston.
I know.
Seen you on the stand.
You're a very brave
girl, you know.
I think your mother
would be very proud of you.
I'm not even sure who
my mom really was.
She always used
to say she was...
a real dancer, an artist.
First, she dies,
and then I find out
she's full of crap.
She was just
a stripper.
Well, whatever the truth is
about your mother's life,
she didn't deserve to die.
You must be hungry.
Would you, uh,
care for this?
Oh, no.
Really, I can get
another one.
I probably shouldn't
be eating this anyway.
My stomach's
upset.
How long have you
had that rash on your arm?
I don't know,
a couple days.
May I see
if you have a fever?
Just need
to touch your neck.
I'm a doctor--
it's okay.
Matty, I'm going
to ask you a question,
and I apologize
if it seems a bit awkward.
Um, have you noticed
that you haven't
been urinating a lot lately?
I'm not like my mother.
I don't have any diseases.
I know, I know,
but I think you may
be very sick.
We should get you to a hospital
as soon as possible.
Tommy, Tommy, Tommy,
Tommy, my man!
Bad idea to get in a bar fight
when every cop in the county
is looking for you.
(stammering):
I've been out of town.
All right, I just
got back yesterday.
Look, I just stopped by the club
to say hey to my girls.
The Tassel Room.
Amber Jones was one
of your girls-- remember her?
You left town
the day she was murdered.
Kind of makes you
look guilty.
Yeah, but they caught the guy
that shot her.
That, uh... the congressman.
Look, I didn't
do nothing.
You were stalking her.
That's her side of the story.
According to Amber's daughter,
you were parked
outside her house the day
before her mother was murdered.
Amber filed a temporary
restraining order against you.
She was afraid for her life.
Leave my mom alone!
You're not supposed
to be here!
Hey!
I'm calling the cops
and getting your ass arrested!
Matty's got it all wrong.
All right, I was just trying
to make amends.
See, I'm in the
12-step program.
Making amends is part
of my recovery.
Okay, I'm on step nine.
Oh, I think you missed a couple
of steps there, Tommy,
'cause you're drunk.
You smell like a brewery.
Can't walk in a straight line.
I took Amber's death
really hard.
All right, it set me back.
See, I never got a chance
to tell her
that I truly forgave her
for ruining my life.
Look...
you're either a stalker...
or you're the best
eyewitness ever.
What's it going to be?
Oh, that's easy.
What do you want to know?
When was the last time
you saw her?
The day after her kid
kicked the crap out of my limo.
I was in between pickups,
and she received a package
from Worldwide... World...
World-Send.
That's when I saw her.
She looked like hell.
She was always such a tease.
Got a kick out
of making guys want her.
It was 4:01 P.M.
I remember,
because I got a call
from my dispatcher.
Uh, I had to bounce
'cause I was running late.
That's the last
time I saw her.
Hey, wait a minute--
what about me?
Can I go?
No.
You're not going anywhere.
What do you think?
Well, we never found
a World-Send package,
but we didn't process the house
until four days after the fact.
If we can confirm
that she got a delivery
just after 4:00,
that narrows the TOD
to between
4:00 and 5:00.
That means that Dominic
Humphreys didn't kill her.
Brings us back
to the congressman.
PROSECUTION LAWYER:
Amber Jones was a single mom,
struggling to support
her teenage daughter.
Congressman Edward Griffin...
is a married man.
He seduced her.
Took advantage
of her.
He admits being
physically violent.
And when Amber
became a liability
to his marriage and his career,
he murdered her.
The defense would
have you believe
that Dominic Humphreys
committed this crime.
After all, Mr. Humphreys
confessed to it
before taking his own life.
But that's another lie
in a giant web of lies.
The evidence proves beyond
a reasonable doubt
Mr. Humphreys had an alibi
and could not
have killed Amber Jones.
The defendant needs to be held
accountable for his actions.
Find him guilty.
DEFENSE LAWYER:
Amber Jones lost her life,
and that's a tragedy.
But she's not
the only victim here.
My client lost
his life, too.
Now, this man
is not perfect.
He had an affair.
He and his wife have dealt
with that privately,
and she's forgiven him.
But I'm going to tell you
what really happened.
My client went
to Amber Jones' house
to apologize
for losing his temper
and to end the affair.
He found her body.
And that's when he made
a mistake he will regret
for the rest
of his life.
He didn't
call 911.
He called Dominic Humphreys.
He made a mistake.
But he's not killer.
Well, your suspicions
are correct.
Matty was being
poisoned.
Boric acid.
50 micrograms per milliliter.
ALT levels
over a 1,000.
BUN levels 86.
Her kidneys are shutting down.
Based on the level
of organ damage, I'd say
that she's been ingesting it
for about eight weeks.
Do you know
the source?
Not yet.
You're putting her on dialysis?
That's about all we can do
at this point.
Can you tell me if there's
any permanent organ damage?
Not yet.
Thank you.
Okay.
♪ ♪
(whirring)
WILLOWS:
How's Matty?
She'll live,
but they haven't
ruled out
permanent damage.
Langston.
I found trace levels
of boric acid
in Amber Jones' blood
and organs.
Consistent
with a one-time dose.
Well, low levels
don't rule out
chronic poisoning.
Right, the only way
to confirm how long
she was being poisoned
is through hair analysis.
And the only way
to do that
is for us to get
some of her hair.
I'll get a warrant
to exhume the body.
I think Amber
was the target
and her daughter
was collateral damage.
Well, if poisoning was
the weapon of choice,
why change weapons
and shoot her?
All right, let's say
I'm the killer.
I decide to poison Amber.
She doesn't die,
so I panic.
And I shoot her.
Okay.
Amber's been dead
eight weeks,
yet her daughter is still
being exposed to the poison,
so the source has got
to be in their house.
Got to be hard to sleep
in the same house
where your mom was killed.
Well, they say
kids are resilient.
Nobody's that
resilient.
She's probably
blaming herself.
SANDERS:
Voice of
experience?
Boric acid can be ingested
or absorbed through the skin.
I'm gonna go check out
the shampoos and body washes.
All right.
Is Riley all right?
I think this whole case has,
uh, hit a nerve.
Well, she's not shy.
If she wanted to talk about it,
she would.
Source of the poison
has to be something
that's been around
for at least
two months.
I'll start with
any open items.
♪ ♪
We have a winner.
Looks like somebody tampered
with their drink mix.
Purchased at Skadden Pharmacy.
Well, it looks like
she usually shopped
at Nathan's Market.
You don't buy food at a pharmacy
unless you're there
picking something else up.
Hey, did you find any,
uh, prescription meds?
Just an antibiotic
and a hydrocodone.
You got something?
Yeah.
This prescription was filled
the night
before Amber was murdered.
Thank you.
David, would you hand me
a rubber band, please?
Yeah.
Thank you.
(sighs)
I'll get this
to Henry stat.
Good.
Matty looks just like
her mother.
Did you note this at autopsy?
If I had, no way
I would have cut through it.
It must have developed later.
Embalming fluid can enhance
discoloration.
(mechanical whirring)
(liquid sloshing)
(mechanical clicking)
Contusion had
to have occurred perimortem.
Otherwise, the bruise
would have blossomed
earlier.
It's a shoe impression.
Jurors, have you reached
a verdict?
MAN:
Yes, Your Honor,
we have.
JUDGE:
Will the defendant please rise?
"In the matter
of State of Nevada
"v. Edward Griffin,
"we the jury find
the defendant guilty
of murder in
the first degree."
(gasps and scattered applause)
Settle down.
(bangs gavel)
Quiet!
Please remand the
defendant into custody.
(shocked murmuring)
(sighs)
MAN (on TV):
We're live at the courthouse,
where, just moments ago,
Congressman Griffin
was remanded into custody
after he was convicted
in the murder
of local resident Amber...
(sighs)
Oh, we got
a conviction.
Jury came
back quick.
Well, this case
isn't over yet.
I called the pharmacist
at Skadden's.
On the night before Amber died,
the emergency room doc
called in two prescriptions--
an antibiotic
and a painkiller.
They were picked up and paid for
by Dominic Humphreys.
Well, he took her to the
E.R. and then drove her home.
Yeah, but the meds
weren't the only thing
he picked up.
Check it out.
Bandages, medical tape,
antibiotic ointment,
energy drink mix,
crackers, soup.
Roach poison?
Humphreys was the one
trying to poison her?
And then the congressman
decided to shoot her?
That's what it looks like.
Obviously,
he didn't care that
he poisoned her daughter, too.
We found new evidence
on Amber Jones' body.
You got to be kidding me.
Shoe impression bruise.
Developed after
the embalming.
It's only seven inches long.
Well, it has to belong
to the killer.
Can't be the congressman's.
Seven inches-- that's
got to be female.
The only female with access
to the murder weapon
is Mrs. Griffin.
(groaning)
Did the wife have an alibi
from 4:00 to 5:00?
I remember Mrs. Griffin
telling Brass
that she was in bed recovering
from a miscarriage.
Her hormones are already
in overdrive,
and then she catches
her husband cheating.
She might have caught more
than that.
Amber gave the congressman
chlamydia.
I think he gave it
to his wife.
Chlamydia can cause
a miscarriage.
Well, that's one hell
of a motive.
WILLOWS:
This bruise is
not specific enough
to identify the shoe.
STOKES:
No, but we can
get a warrant
for her clothes.
Maybe we can match the fibers
from the gun slide.
Call the ADA
Let her know that she won't
be taking tomorrow off.
All right.
(sighs)
WILLOWS:
We found these gloves
in your closet.
Blue-black dye,
wool and cashmere blend.
It proves you
killed Amber Jones.
WHITTEN:
You two need
to watch the news.
Her husband
was just found guilty.
WILLOWS:
Hey, I get it.
You lost your baby
because he couldn't
keep it in his pants.
BRASS:
Your husband's
conviction will be overturned.
That's the good news.
The bad news
is, unless you talk to us,
you'll be the one on trial.
You don't have
to say a word to these people.
I can't go through this again.
I had... just come back
from seeing my doctor,
and I needed to talk
to my husband.
But he wasn't home.
I saw his wallet on the dresser.
That meant he was downstairs.
He had cheated before.
But when he ran for office,
we made a deal.
He could look, but not touch.
I'm the one who hit
the little bitch, not him.
(screams)
But you didn't stop there,
right?
The next morning...
...my doctor called
and told me...
...I had chlamydia.
(crying):
That's what killed my baby.
I'm 40 years old.
We had been trying
to get pregnant
for over three years.
It was my last chance.
Yeah. My last chance
to be a mother.
Then I...
I found my husband's
cell phone bill,
and I just started
calling numbers
until I found hers.
Do you want something
to drink?
Yeah, thank you.
I told her I was there
to apologize.
That I'd been thinking
about it all night.
No! (groans)
(panting)
(whimpering)
Please. Please
don't kill me.
Please. Please!
I have a daughter!
(grunts)
Because of you,
my daughter is dead.
(gunshots)
So you left,
but you forgot the gun?
You figured Dominic would
clean up after you, too.
No, Dominic didn't know anything
about it.
He would never help me.
He always thought
I was a liability
to my husband's career.
So when did your husband realize
that you... killed Amber?
(inhales deeply)
As soon as you told him
his gun was missing.
You have an STD.
You should go to the doctor.
WILLOWS:
I don't know.
I would have killed him,
not her.
(crowd chatter and laughter)
All right.
Matty's going to be all right.
No permanent damage.
Glad to hear it.
Ray.
You deserve this.
Thank you, Catherine.
Talk about
baptism by fire.
Yeah, but you made
it through it.
You never quit.
Do you think
she really dropped the gun?
Or do you think
she left it there to frame him?
My money's
on the frame.
I think
she dropped it.
Heat of the moment.
Or maybe both things are true.
She accidentally
dropped the gun,
and then decided to leave it
there to punish him.
WILLOWS:
Well, we'll
never know.
But what we do know--
Ray got it right.
Yeah.
Ray had a lot of help.
(laughter)
WILLOWS:
Teamwork.
SANDERS:
Makes the dream work.