(indistinct whispers)
Happy Birthday, Nicky.
Happy Birthday, Nick.
Oh!
Your favorite.
Oh, wow, thanks.
There you are.
Didn't know if you were
a stripe or solid man.
I told him to let it ride
on paisley.
You can wear it
to your next arson scene.
Fair enough, thanks.
(phone rings)
This is Catherine.
ADAMS:
Hey, you know,
Pancake Hutch has a free
breakfast on your birthday.
My treat.
Uh, not tonight.
Maybe another time.
They know you're lying
when you try it any other night.
(chuckles)
Guilty.
You've done it, too.
WILLOWS:
Okay.
Got it.
Uh, got a 419, East Fremont.
A place called
Park Pines Motel.
I'll take it.
WILLOWS:
But...
Uh, what about your cake?
Um...
Save me a piece.
Thanks.
(siren wails)
(indistinct chattering)
So the victim is a 16-year-old
girl who lives on the premises.
She's the daughter of
Mark and Nicole Jones,
who run the motel.
You remember them?
So...
NICOLE:
All I can tell
you is that...
that our daughter
was there...
I knew her.
Yeah, well,
I'm going to, uh...
I'm going to go
knock on some doors.
GIRL:
So, what happened?
(birds chirping)
(insects chirping)
(indistinct chattering)
What's your name?
Haley.
What's yours?
Nick.
"Nick."
So, what happened?
Well, Haley,
that's what I have
to figure out.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
(coughing)
Whoo!
How far into decomp is he?
He isn't.
Look, it's
a fresh wound
to the back of the head.
The body's still warm.
It's the immaculate
decomposition.
VARTANN:
The manager heard a gunshot.
Called it in.
Vic's ID says
"Harry Steadwell."
STOKES: One round fired
from Dirty Harry's revolver.
(chamber clicks)
Well, he wasn't shot.
(groans)
(coughs)
Ooh...
Is he the registered guest?
I found a room key
in his pocket,
but no luggage
or belongings in the room.
But he brought his own
garage door opener?
Is this his?
Yeah.
All right, I'll go
talk to the manager.
I don't mind stepping out.
Looks like the dresser
gave him the hair cut.
You know, if he fell back
from sitting in the chair,
he wouldn't have had enough
momentum to whack
his head this hard.
Unless he was...
...standing on it.
That could be a bullet hole.
(gunshot)
(groans)
Hey, Dave?
You might want to...
Oh!
Oh-ho.
God!
Oh...
No. No, that didn't happen.
Sorry, brother.
Oh, my God!
Ah! Whoa!
Eww.
(indistinct radio transmission)
MAN:
Hey, friend?
Got five bucks for
a cup of coffee?
Five bucks?
Venti half-caf latte,
couple biscotti.
You know, it's a fair price.
Oh, sorry, bud.
You'll be back.
Cops are always here.
Every nigh, manager would
be banging on that door.
"Cops are here!
Cops are here!"
Last manager took off
a week ago without notice.
The new guy started today,
so the office
is a mess.
(door opens)
Here he is.
Here you go.
VARTANN:
What do you got for me?
"Harry Steadwell."
Checked into room seven last
Thursday; paid for one night.
There's no record of him
checking out.
All right, I need to get
into the crawl space
above room seven.
Does every room have
an access panel?
Beats me. I just got here.
Look, uh,
you're welcome to check.
(clears throat)
Thank you.
VARTANN: Thanks.
Sure.
Let me know what
I can do.
Okay.
(cell phone chimes)
(siren wailing)
GRISSOM (on message):
I just spent two hours
testifying about decapitation
by blown tire
and I realized something.
Happy Birthday, pal.
(laughs)
HALEY:
You figure it out yet?
No.
No, not yet, Haley.
You can tell me.
I'm not scared of that stuff.
I can see that.
NICOLE: Haley, leave
the man alone!
If it were up to her,
I'd be locked in my room
all day.
But I told her,
forensics is just science,
you know?
It's what you go
to school for and...
But you don't look like
my Chem teacher.
Thanks.
I think.
You, uh, do know the crime
scene's in the next room?
I always look
for the yellow tape.
There's something
dead up there, Greg.
And it's big, heavy
and smells awful.
One of us has got
to go up there and get it.
You know what?
It's your birthday.
(Sanders grunts)
I'm keeping that gift card.
What?
Whoo!
(coughing)
I think I found
your Big Drip.
Looks like he,
uh, crawled in
the same way I did.
Always die downstairs.
(moans)
(coughing)
STOKES:
"Dale Durney."
Same address as the motel.
I think we just found
that missing manager.
Whoa!
That is a lot of green.
And a little grey.
It's got to be insulation.
Found the same stuff
in the crawl space.
In a No-Tell like
Park Pines,
ceiling's a favorite spot
to stash your goodies.
(beeping)
(whirring)
Hey.
Hey, the, uh,
prints on the remote
were all Dale Durney,
the dead manager.
Mm-hmm.
FYI, the batteries are dead.
And the prints
on the money's rubber band
are Dale Durney
and Harry Steadwell.
Well, we know Dale pocketed it.
Harry probably stashed it.
Why would he
leave it there
for a week?
Oh. It wasn't by choice.
Harry got arrested
the same day he checked
into the motel
for violating an ex's
restraining order.
Got released from County
this morning.
So he goes back to the motel.
Yeah, to retrieve
his money.
And then... what?
He shoots the man
who swiped his cash?
Even though the dude's
been dead for...?
ROBBINS:
About a week.
Judging by the presence of first
and second instar maggots.
Decomp appears to have
been accelerated by
extreme heat and the lack
of airflow in the crawl space.
Recovered a bullet
from the right iliopsoas muscle.
No evidence of hemorrhage
in the abdominal cavity.
No bleeding in the muscle
or intestinal walls.
So wound occurred
after he was dead.
What about COD?
Well, it turns
out his fortune
can be read from his palms.
Silvery wounds.
I excised samples
of flesh for histology.
Under magnification,
the samples showed
streaming of nuclei
consistent
with electrical burns.
COD is cardiac arrest.
Electrocution.
He was in the
crawl space,
so maybe he came
in contact
with exposed wiring.
I found the receiver to that
remote control.
Can you tell what it's for?
Yeah, it's wired
to the access panel above you.
I killed the circuit.
Hey, there's a layer of metal
sandwiched in the middle here.
It's like my eighth grade
science fair project.
A homemade electromagnet.
Wire wraps
around an iron rod.
Current runs through it,
creating a magnetic field.
Genius.
Guy who lives here
said that the manager, Dale,
was beating on room seven's
door every night,
saying the cops
were coming.
Don't remember many call outs.
Me, either.
I think it was a setup.
A week ago, Harry Steadwell
checks into room seven
with $10K, dirty money.
(tapping on window): Cops!
Cops in the lot!
Cops!
What Harry doesn't know
is that Manager Dale's
got a plan to profit
off guys like Harry.
He turns on his
electromagnetic lock.
Harry can't get his money.
Oh, come on!
Come on, man!
Gives up and leaves.
So, Dale goes to see what
goodies had Harry all fired up.
But he can't
get the panel open.
The batteries
in his remote are dead.
SANDERS:
So he hustles up and over
to reap his harvest,
notices the panel's a little
off, thinks it's a casualty
of Harry's pounding.
The real casualty
is the frayed wire
inside the panel.
And the crawl space is hot.
(electricity crackling)
Dale's got sweaty palms,
and sweat is a great
electrolyte.
A week later, Harry gets
sprung from the clink,
comes back
to get his money.
But why did he shoot
the dead guy?
I don't think he knew
Dale was up there, man.
The panel was
still magnetized.
Maybe he was using his gun
to bang it open.
It got magnetized,
and shot by accident.
(gunshot)
(groans)
Mr. Jones.
Oh, hey.
Got a few numbers of the
crime scene cleanup people.
Decomp can be
a little bit
harder to get out
of the carpet than you think.
Thanks.
(girls laughing)
Boy, she makes
friends fast.
Nah, Bree and
her have been
friends for a while.
She didn't have to switch
schools when we moved.
Well, that's good.
Take care now.
Yeah.
Hey, thanks for
those numbers.
Yeah, you got it, man.
(rattling)
Hey, buddy--
you still want
that cup of coffee?
Hell, yeah.
There you go.
Happy Birthday.
It's not my birthday.
Thanks, man.
(girls laughing)
(siren wails)
(indistinct radio transmission)
BREE:
I don't know
what they did to me.
BRASS:
"They"?
That whole family--
they're weird.
Like obsessed.
Aren't you friends with Haley?
Was.
I-I guess.
But then she and
her mom started
giving me the creeps.
Mrs. Jones would
just stare at me.
And when Haley showed up
in homeroom with her hair
exactly like me
a few weeks ago,
that was it,
I was done.
BRASS:
So, Bree, what happened?
I turned 16 tonight.
Everyone threw this bonfire
for me.
It was tons of fun.
And then the world
went all weird.
(voices and music distorted)
I don't remember anything
until I woke up here--
in Haley's living room.
My pants off.
Where was
Haley's father?
Standing over me.
(gasps)
Get off me!
(screams)
NICOLE:
We were here.
We were asleep.
Mark heard something.
Bree was in the living
room and just ran out.
I have no idea
what she was even doing here.
Haley doesn't know either.
Mr. Jones,
I'm, uh, going to need
to collect your underwear.
No, no.
You can, uh,
leave that door open,
if you don't mind.
(mouthing)
(indistinct radio transmissions)
MARK:
I swear to you,
I was sleeping.
I heard something.
I... came here and I...
saw Bree and she just...
just took off.
What was she doing here?
She has a key.
My wife gave it to her.
Told her she could hang here
anytime she wants.
Her parents, they...
they work.
They're not around
a lot, so...
She's my daughter's best friend.
All right.
Why don't you put on
some clothes.
You're going to need
to come with us--
give your statement.
(indistinct radio transmission)
BRASS:
I just need a little more
information.
Hey, Jim.
Yeah.
This SUV over here's
got mud all over
the tires.
You might want to
find out whose it is.
It's the Jones'.
Okay, so tell me again--
where were you all tonight?
Uh, we were here.
We stayed in all night.
So the car just drove
itself to the bonfire?
Is that what happened?
Huh?
It was me, I went.
What?!
I knew what was going to
be going on there tonight.
And that's why I
didn't want you to go.
So I went there and I
took some pictures,
so that you could see
what I'm talking about...
Did people see you?!
Haley, it...
Unbelievable!
I hate you!
Okay, Officer Mitchell,
Officer Mitchell,
why don't you take Haley
and buy her a soda
on us, okay?
You got it.
Miss,
let's take a walk.
BRASS:
So what, you grabbed
your camera,
said you were taking pictures
for the yearbook?
I'm going to need
to see that camera.
WILLOWS:
Can you tell me who's in
this photo from last night?
BREE:
These guys are all
baseball players.
Bryan Rupert and Cole Maliska
were my boyfriends.
Dave Henkel is.
And Trey Gallo wants to be.
Though some people
have been saying
he already is.
And what about this one?
BREE:
Whoa. He was there?
No, this creep
should not have been anywhere
near my party's galaxy.
Zack Fenish.
At school, even when I
don't see him following me,
I can smell the Sharpie
on his fingernails.
I reported him for stalking
last semester.
There's paperwork
and everything.
So if you weren't invited
to Bree's birthday party,
why'd you go?
I was looking
for someone.
That would be Bree, right?
Epic fail, sir.
No, I can't stand Bree Lindale,
her Neanderthal harem,
or the ozone of suck
that lingers around them all.
Well, according
your school disciplinary report
you were stalking her.
I was not stalking Bree Lindale.
I was stalking Haley Jones.
Zack.
ZACK:
Who always follows Bree around.
Haley's the one that I went
to go see at the party.
Zack...
Dad, she's the hottest
girl at school.
'Cause I can tell
there's a vicious
bad girl inside
just waiting to claw
its way out.
And as soon as it does,
I'm gonna be there
to rope it up and take it
to homecoming.
Anyway, she wasn't even there,
so I just left.
Okay, that's all
he's got to say.
That's it.
Come on.
Sure. We're gonna need
a DNA sample.
Absolutely not.
My son-client
will not be offering any...
All right, all right,
look, look,
I heard what
happened to Bree,
and until Pops here gets
me my birthday Beemer,
I'm rolling ten-speed.
I don't think I took her
anywhere on my bike.
I got your message.
What's going on?
Well, um...
You know the snapshots of the
bonfire Nicole Jones took?
Yeah.
Well, I checked the camera's
memory drive.
Discovered some
recently-deleted photos.
They're all of Bree Lindale.
But not one of
her own daughter.
STOKES:
Why don't you tell us
about these photos
from your camera?
I had a daughter.
You mean
another daughter?
Melissa.
She died when
she was an infant.
It was before
Haley was born.
When Haley became friends
with Bree,
I couldn't help seeing that...
Bree looked
just like Melissa.
But I thought you just said
she died when she was a baby.
I can see it
in her eyes.
It's what Melissa would have
looked like if she had grown up.
So that's why you went
to Bree's birthday party
to take photos of her.
I let myself pretend, just...
for a moment
that Bree is Melissa.
She isn't dead.
Then why did you, uh,
delete her photos?
I was worried that
Haley would find them.
We've never told
Haley about Melissa.
Do you have any idea
what it's like
to lose a daughter?
When I was driving
away from that party,
Bree was drinking
with those boys.
Did you-- did you even
talk to the boys?
Tox from Bree Lindale.
Positive for GHB
in her blood.
Date rape drug.
Yes, but Wendy
said to tell you
the SAE came back
negative for penetration.
However, there
were epithelials
of an unknown male
in the region.
By region, do you mean
the pubic region?
Because the trace
on Bree Lindale's
"down there place"
came back as Neatsfoot oil
and hydrotreated paraffinic
petroleum distillates.
Neatsfoot oil?
Used to use that to treat
our mitts in Pony League.
Much as I'm
intrigued
by this bizarre equestrian
competition of which you speak,
the compound's actually
a consumer product sold
to condition baseball gloves.
(door opens)
What's up?
You need
to swab me again?
(chuckles)
No, no, the first swab
gave us what we needed--
a warrant to search
your vehicle
while you were at
batting practice.
Where we found...
...your GHB.
My trainer gave me that.
What about Bree Lindale?
What about her?
She's my girlfriend.
I want you to listen to me now.
I know she was with you.
Now, if you want
me to match
the muddy shoe impressions
all over your passenger side
floor mat to her, I will.
You're 18, man.
You'll go to jail.
I didn't do anything.
You didn't drug her?
Come on.
You didn't assault her?
I didn't get the chance
to do anything.
I never do with Bree.
She keeps saying
that she's saving herself.
But half the dugout's
been saying
that Trey Gallo, the pitcher,
he's been hittin' it.
They even had a motel room.
(distorted):
Are you okay? What's wrong?
Do you want
to go?
Figured no point in letting
that room go to waste.
Especially if Trey paid for it.
And that GHB--
that stuff barely worked.
What are you doing?
What are you doing?!
Get off of me!
What do you think
you're doing?!
Bree, wait.
WILLOWS:
Surveillance cameras
picked you up
walking down Fremont.
The motel's only a
couple blocks from there.
You jumped out
of Dave Henkel's truck.
Then what happened?
I was kinda freaked
and I didn't want to deal
with getting home.
So you just
crashed there?
The Joneses didn't drug you
or kidnap you?
No.
Then what did
Mr. Jones do to you?
Tell her what
he did to you, Bree.
He didn't do anything.
I just didn't
want Haley
to think
we were friends again.
Like I was there
for a slumber party
or something.
So your boyfriend drugs you,
attempts to rape you,
and you're willing
to let your friend's
family take the rap?
Haley is not my friend.
MAN:
Hey, Crime Scene,
check me out.
90 days clean,
just me and Lady Caffeine.
(chuckles)
Yeah, lookin' good.
Always, man.
Flossin'!
(Stokes laughs)
Hi, Haley.
Parents around?
Okay. Well, I brought back
your mom's camera,
couple other things here, so...
Well, sorry to, uh,
sorry to interrupt you.
You want to see something?
And the hits just keep coming.
Don't worry about that.
Blow it off.
You don't get it, do you?!
My life is over!
(door slams)
(gentle melody begins playing)
(thunder rumbles)
(gentle melody continues)
♪ Come see ♪
♪ The rumble and pleads ♪
♪ Late show ♪
♪ When I ♪
♪ Can put this behind ♪
♪ I don't know ♪
♪ Come see ♪
♪ The lovely machine ♪
♪ Break down ♪
♪ Crisscross ♪
♪ I won't be around ♪
♪ When she goes down... ♪
ADAMS:
The manager's daughter
found the body
when she came in
to clean the room.
Check-in records have
her listed as Tanya Carrow,
Arizona driver's
license number.
Manager's wife
confirmed she checked in
last night.
(computer chirping)
Man, she's only 32.
Long years, though.
Just got released
from Arizona state pen.
Nine years on a narco rap.
Lot of priors before that,
mostly drugs.
Foam around the mouth.
Clothes are damp
from sweat.
Both indicate overdose.
Where's all her stuff?
There isn't any.
She could have just checked in
to use.
Then where's the paraphernalia?
Flushed the evidence
before the high killed her?
Hey, Nick,
I hear you're putting together
a college fund
for Warrick's son?
Well...
Thank you, David.
Appreciate it.
So what's with
the shattered lamp?
PHILLIPS:
She could have knocked it over
during her OD seizure.
Or there was someone else
in here with her.
They could have used together,
had a fight.
Could have grabbed
Tanya's stuff and bailed.
(rhythmic thudding,
man and woman moaning)
WOMAN:
Oh, God!
Maybe they heard something.
I'm on it.
MAN:
Oh!
Uh, hi.
From the Lime Crab.
The Crab Lime.
No, I am from the Crime Lab.
Were you here last night, sir?
Hmm. Hey, sweetheart,
firecracker wants to know
if we were here
last night.
Oh, yeah, we were
here, all right.
We were here,
over there and
back there
and everywhere till my lumbar
went out.
That's lumbar,
mind you,
not lumber.
Okay, that's...
Thank you.
Sir, were you taping last night?
Oh, yeah, live at 11:00,
12:00 and 1:00.
(woman and man moaning)
All right, so I'll work on
amplifying and isolating
the background noises from
the neighboring room.
And I'll try to scrub my
mental tape deck of the rest.
Mm-hmm.
The frequency range
for a live human voice
is much broader
than what comes out
of a crappy motel
TV-set speaker.
(indistinct voices)
How many voices?
Two, from what
I can tell.
And judging from the pitch,
they're both female.
Well, can you tell
if they're arguing or what?
They're pretty loud.
They'd have to be to get through
the walls, even thin ones.
I'm afraid we don't know
much at all.
We know the cause of death
was multiple organ failure
due to oral ingestion
of methamphetamine.
A lot more than a
recreational dose.
My colleagues tell me there
was someone else in the room.
Possibly a fight.
But as far as what else
happened to your daughter,
we really don't know.
I'm sorry, Mr. Carrow.
I know you deserve
more answers.
No, I don't.
You know, you think
it's gonna be easy.
Even with her mom dead
and you busting your ass
working every day,
small town like Eagar, Arizona,
you figure, you know,
what do you got to do
to keep her out of trouble?
By 16, she was
already gone:
drugs and juvie.
It's lost.
It's a long ride up here,
and I realized
that was probably
about the most time
I'd ever spent on her.
Hadn't really talked
for ten years.
So, no, I...
I don't know what she
and the world owed each other,
but, uh...
I don't deserve any answers.
(upbeat melody playing)
♪ All this time I was wasting ♪
♪ Hoping you would come around ♪
♪ I've been giving out chances
every time ♪
♪ And all you do
is let me down ♪
♪ And it's taken me
this long, baby ♪
♪ But I figured you out ♪
♪ And you're thinking
we'll be fine again ♪
♪ But not this time around ♪
♪ You don't have
to call anymore ♪
♪ I won't pick up the phone ♪
♪ This is the last straw ♪
♪ Don't want to hurt anymore ♪
♪ And you can tell me
that you're sorry ♪
♪ But I don't believe you, baby,
like I did before ♪
♪ You're not sorry ♪
♪ No, no, no ♪
♪ No. ♪
(helicopter flying overhead)
BRASS:
Okay, here's what we got.
The victim
is a 16-year-old girl
who lives here
on the premises.
She's the daughter
of Mark and Nicole Jones
who run the motel.
You remember them,
don't you?
I knew her.
PHILLIPS:
She was stabbed in the chest.
Nick?
Nick, looks like
a single wound.
Yeah, close kill
like this,
the killer's probably
covered with blood.
(camera shutter clicking)
So, the girl's parents
were inside the apartment
when this happened.
The didn't hear anything.
They came out and found her like
this, but we have a suspect.
The victim broke up with
her boyfriend yesterday.
Things got ugly,
officers responded,
so we're bringing
him in now. Good luck.
I heard this one was
personal for you.
Hey, Nick,
I found this in her pocket.
Same hairstyle,
not the same girl, though.
I'll spiral out,
see if I can find the weapon.
Okay.
ZACK:
A few months ago, she came
to me and she said
that she had a vision.
That's what she called it.
A miraculous vision
of her destiny.
And she said that
she was going to
embrace that destiny today.
She just told me
about it yesterday.
So she dumped you for St. Peter.
I'm gonna ask you again.
Where were you tonight?
I don't, I don't...
(whispers):
I was slinging crystal.
We're going to need a, uh,
a promise of immunity
before my client
reveals his alibi to you.
I'll mention it to the DA.
He is not saying anything
until we've been legally assured
against prosecution.
I was in Reno.
Zack, please!
I was in Reno and I was...
I was there slinging crystal.
I was dealing drugs.
That's what I do.
And Haley, she helped me.
But if that's why she didn't
want to be with me anymore,
why I wasn't
"fit for her destiny..."
I would have changed.
She didn't use drugs.
I didn't have to.
I would have done
whatever she wanted.
Now, the photo you found
in the victim's pocket...
I asked Archie
to blow it up.
Well, at first we thought
this girl and her
baby were in a park.
You see
the barbed wire?
Mm-hmm.
It's not a park.
It's a prison.
White Sands Youth Detention
Center, Arizona.
You see the logo
on the guy's jacket?
Any idea when
this was taken?
Yes.
Archie dated the Polaroid
stock by batch number,
narrowed it down to 1993.
Now, the foliage here
suggests summer,
so we checked
the facility's records.
Three Caucasian inmates
gave birth that summer.
One of those babies had the
same birth date as Haley Jones.
So Haley was adopted.
Mm-hmm.
What's her name,
the birth mother?
Tanya Carrow.
Overdosed
at the Park Pines
back in November.
Tanya Carrow.
She went
and found her daughter.
Mark and Nicole Jones
denied knowing her.
They might be telling the truth
if it was a blind adoption.
Pull my other leg
and it plays "Jingle Bells."
(tapping on glass)
Hi, uh, my name is Tanya.
Tanya Carrow.
Remember me?
Um, I'm not here
to make trouble.
I was just wondering if
I could see my daughter.
BRASS:
We had Tanya's
juvie record unsealed.
She was 16 years old. She
was babysitting your daughter.
We would never have
left Melissa with her
if we had known
that she was...
Getting high?
We... We were just
going to the movies,
and we had asked Tanya
if she would
give Melissa a bath
before she put her down.
She left her in the tub.
She drowned.
Okay, so Tanya's in juvie.
She finds out she's pregnant.
And that's when we get
this call that, um...
she wants to make amends.
A life for a life.
Haley for Melissa?
So, 16 years later,
she shows up,
wants to see Haley,
who doesn't even know
she's adopted.
What do you do?
I gave her a room.
She never checked out,
so what happened?
Nicole went to see her
that night.
She went to her room
and, um...
she told Tanya
that she would never,
ever see Haley.
They fought.
Tanya agreed that, um...
she'd leave.
I kinda figured
the disappointment...
I guess that's
what made Tanya
kill herself.
Are you sure
she killed herself?
(tapping on glass)
No coffee breaks right now,
my man.
(sighing)
Yeah?
I'm moving, into a dorm.
Got a student loan.
W.L.V.U.
Hospitality Studies.
Oh, a few months ago,
I saw something.
Mrs. Jones came out
of room eight
with two coffee cups.
I thought
it was strange she went
all the way over there
to toss them.
I could smell the meth.
The next morning you were here
and that woman in room eight...
She was dead.
I didn't tell you
about it at the time
because I figured you wouldn't
believe somebody like me.
The old me.
LANGSTON:
Nick?
I found this under
the mattress.
It was an accident.
I was in the office.
Haley came in.
With that hair.
I told her it looked disgusting
and that she would
have to dye it back,
or I'd cut it off.
So she stormed out.
I grabbed the scissors.
You were just trying
to give her a haircut?
I was just trying to scare
her a little, to finally
get her to do something
that I wanted for once.
You dye it back
or I swear to God,
I will cut it myself.
Leave me alone!
You little bitch!
I hate you!
I've always hated...
(stabbing and gasping)
STOKES:
Why didn't you call 911?
I don't know.
She was dead
when she hit the ground. I...
I panicked.
Her hair, huh?
It wasn't just the hair.
It was everything.
It was the mouth,
the attitude, her boyfriend...
She was just always
trying to get to me.
The hair... the hairstyle,
it was just one more thing.
Something that I would hate.
Yeah, because
it made her look
exactly like Tanya.
That is her
real mother, right?
The one that
killed your daughter.
And who you killed
four months ago.
She was an addict.
She killed herself.
We talked to
Haley's boyfriend.
He told us about the stash of
meth Haley was holding for him.
It was hidden in her room.
And when it went missing,
they figured, you found it,
flushed it.
But you didn't flush it,
did you, Mrs. Jones?
Zack volunteered
a sample of the meth,
and we matched it
to the drugs that were found
in Tanya's stomach
the night she died.
And I have an eyewitness
that saw you
toss two coffee cups
into the Dumpster that night.
One of which
was laced with meth.
How did you get her
to drink it, Nicole?
Hmm?
Was it a peace offering?
She had no right
to just show up.
So you killed her.
No.
Yeah.
And when you saw that Haley
looked exactly like Tanya at 16,
you killed her again.
I never wanted her.
Mark brought her
into our home.
I had a daughter.
She was murdered.
So I'm supposed to let the ghost
of that murderer live with me?
Sleep in the next room?
You all right?
She didn't have to die, Ray.
You're right.
She didn't have to die.
You aren't beating yourself
up about this, are you?
(sighs)
If I could have figured out
what was going on
in Tanya Carrow's murder sooner,
then Nicole Jones
would've been locked up.
Haley would still be alive.
I knew you were
a fellow masochist.
(chuckling)
Tell me what your favorite form
of self-flagellation is.
Tell you
what I like to do.
Get on the Internet.
Go to a Web site,
movie site.
Find my favorite movie
of the moment.
And then I like to read
all the comments telling me
why I'm wrong and
have such terrible taste.
And when I really can't sleep,
I like to sculpt orchids
because it's
the only thing that will
silence the voices in my head.
But tonight,
there's only one voice.
And she keeps asking me
what happened.
What happened?
What happened is a young girl
died because of events
that were set in motion
long before she was ever born.
It doesn't make it feel
any better, does it?
(sobbing)
You know, Nick?
Everyone keeps telling me
what this job isn't.
How you feel right now
tells me what it is.
I'm so sorry, Nick.