(woman moaning and sobbing)
See, just like
I told you, right?
It really brings back
the good old days, huh?
So, what do you think
it's worth?
(thumping, grunting)
♪ ♪
Riley...
425, suspicious remains
at the city dump.
Awesome.
Trash run for the low man
on the totem pole.
I promise not to abuse
my power over you.
Watch your back, Riley.
GRISSOM:
And for our new
CSI level three,
411A, recovered
stolen vehicle at McCarran.
Nick, 402,
possible arson
at the Burger Giant.
Well, there goes the night.
Why don't we all
meet up
at the coffee shop
after work?
Level three over here
is gonna buy.
(chuckles)
I'll take care of breakfast.
And the 419 in Green Valley.
Looks like
the king gets
to sit on the bench
for now.
That it?
No.
I know this has been
a tough year for all of us,
and I've been thinking...
I mean, more than usual.
I made a decision.
I'm gonna leave CSI.
Catherine will become
the new supervisor,
so you'll be in good hands.
While I'm clearing my caseload,
Ecklie's preparing a list
of candidates
for a new level one hire,
so...
you won't be shorthanded.
(phone ringing)
And I guess I just
came off the bench.
419 at Mount Charleston.
Okay?
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
Sir?
You okay?
Yeah.
I was just wondering what it
would be like to go fly fishing.
(chuckles)
Uh, a couple of hikers came
across the body this morning.
According to them,
it's not a popular trail.
How long do you think
that's been here?
I don't know.
Sealed bag,
cool, moist environment.
Could be weeks, could be years.
But it's definitely human.
Call the coroner.
Tell him he's got soup to go.
This is Henry-5.
We need a coroner...
(slushing)
All right, so let me
get this straight.
Grissom didn't say that he
was leaving permanently,
so he could be taking
a leave of absence.
That's a form
of leaving, right?
I think this
is leaving, leaving.
What's he gonna do?
Teach?
Write a book, go off
and study bugs somewhere?
You know as much as I do, Nicky.
Star of David.
Looks like some kind
of pendant.
Victim must
have been Jewish.
These clothes
are pretty generic.
Jeans, T-shirt, sneakers.
It's not gonna
help with TOD
or sex.
There's hair in our soup.
Most of them are brown,
but some of them are blonde.
So, maybe the vic got a piece
of the attacker.
Or maybe the victim
just had a streak
of dyed hair.
Hodges...
Hodges.
Hmm?
Collect and separate
both sets
of hairs.
Get them over to Wendy.
Run exemplars for
mitochondrial DNA.
It's best to stay busy.
ROBBINS:
Based on skull morphology
and femoral bone dimensions,
I'd say we're looking
at a Caucasian male,
around five feet, nine inches.
Partial fusion
of the coronal-cranial suture
says that he was at
least 25 years old.
Any idea of COD?
Very good idea.
Broken hyoid.
Strangulation.
Yep.
Are you really leaving?
Think of it
this way, Doc.
You'll have somebody new you
can tell all your old jokes to.
I like the old guy just fine.
Are you, uh, running
away from something?
Or running to something?
Someone?
I'm running to my office.
I think you're nuts.
(door closing)
I am never going to retire.
(sighs)
GRISSOM:
The Dick and Jane Killer's name
is Nathan Haskell.
Suspected of killing
at least 14 people
in Nevada, California
and Arizona in the mid-90s.
He was picked up at a sobriety
checkpoint near Reno.
It was a lucky break.
The blood on his car
matched a male DB
dumped in the desert
several weeks earlier.
(camera clicking)
And he had blood
under his nails
which matched another male DB
who had just been found.
A witness placed him
with one of the vics.
There was a potential
murder weapon.
Case went to trial.
In the middle,
Haskell changed his plea.
He got life without parole,
and he's serving it at Ely.
I remember this guy.
He was called
the Dick and Jane Killer
because he targeted couples.
It says here not any
of the female vics
were ever found.
He refused
to discuss the females,
but seven
male bodies
were found in various
remote locations,
each with postmortem
stab wounds.
The first body they found
had two stab wounds.
The second body
had three stab wounds.
The third had four,
then five, six,
seven and eight,
so the theory was
that the first couple
was never found.
STOKES:
And Joel Steiner
and his fiancée
were considered possible victims
since they lived near DJK
and they were reported missing
in 1997.
That's before any
of the other confirmed victims.
Guess all we need
is a positive ID on Joel.
I had this
made for Joel
for his bar
mitzvah.
He had a matching
one made
for his fiancée when
they got engaged.
Oh, Mrs. Steiner,
I'm sorry.
You can't take it with you.
It's, uh... it's evidence
in an active case.
I promise to get it
back to you
right after
we confirm the I.D.
of your son's remains.
I will.
I'll get it back to you.
But you can't keep it right now.
Sorry.
It's all right.
Thank you.
Thanks.
I'm also going to need DNA
samples from each of you.
But you already have Joel's DNA.
We gave it to the police
in Reno, 11 years ago.
I gave them his toothbrush.
They sent the sample out
to a private lab
for DNA analysis,
and that lab, um,
misplaced it
or lost it.
It happens.
David, I've been meaning
to talk to you.
It's a little too late
for that, huh?
Hey, you gotta do
what you gotta do.
Have a nice life.
♪ ♪
Well, when I heard
that those hairs might
actually be connected
to the Dick and
Jane killer,
I just put the screws to this
guy I know at Accuregen.
And he ran our mito
samples immediately.
(chuckles)
What do you got on him?
He's my uncle.
I really didn't want to wait
around for three weeks
and then get the results
after you were gone.
And it turns out
that the blonde hairs are
definitely a mito DNA match
to Nathan Haskell.
Well, as far as we know,
he was an only child.
So, it's got
to be him.
Grissom.
I just want to thank you
for everything.
For the support
and the encouragement
that you've given me.
You earned it.
Wendy.
Wasn't the
"body soup" vic
I.D.'d as the DJK's
first victim?
Yes. Brass said
that Joel Steiner's
parents confirmed that the Star
of David pendant was his.
And we're getting their DNA
to positively establish I.D.
Okay, I don't believe that
it was Joel Steiner.
The sneakers that Soup Man was
wearing were made two years ago.
And the Dick and Jane Killer's
been in jail for at least ten.
Well, how did he end up
with DJK's hair on his body?
And who is he?
Lindsey was once given
a gift certificate
for a pair
of customized jeans.
So we go to the store,
we spend two hours
picking out the wash,
the rivets,
you name it.
And-and she has
her boyfriend's name
embroidered on her butt pocket.
Well, guess what?
She breaks up with the guy
a week later.
She doesn't wear 'em once.
Still beats a tattoo, right?
Oh, don't go there.
(sighs):
In any case,
the sneakers were
definitely a custom job.
We got a warrant
for the customer records.
Catherine, I, uh,
I know I surprised you today
with the...
I knew.
I knew before you knew.
Well,
looks like the sneakers
were "designed"
by a Gerald Tolliver.
See if he's in missing persons.
Well, he's not only missing,
he's got a record.
Petty larceny,
grand larceny.
Several drug busts.
Reno P.D. registered him
as a criminal informant just
before he disappeared,
six months ago.
You know what that means?
WILLOWS:
Road trip.
Kenny Martz,
Reno P.D.
Nick Stokes.
Greg Sanders.
So, did you work this case?
No, but I brought
the related file.
Anything having
to do with DJK
is near and dear
to my heart.
Busted him back when
I was in uniform.
Practically made
my career.
So you guys held this scene
for six months?
Not intentionally.
The house is still in probate.
MARTZ:
Our CSIs found some blood drops
on this wall.
They sampled it
for DNA, and matched it
to Gerald Tolliver.
We'd gotten him to roll
on some local junkies.
We were just starting to move
him up the food chain.
We figured he pissed
somebody off,
got into a fight,
skipped town.
Is there blood on the floor
as well?
MARTZ:
Yeah.
They luminoled this area.
There wasn't
much blood,
not enough to
suggest murder.
They found what appears to be
a partial shoe tread
in this blood.
Look, Gerald
Tolliver was 17
when DJK was doing his business.
He never turned up
in the investigation.
So what's the connection?
We don't know.
That's why we're here.
Looks like Gerald was
a collector of sorts.
Maybe he was one of those
"murderabilia" freaks, you know?
All it takes is one shady
prison barber,
and suddenly people are bidding
for a lock of DJK's hair
on eBay.
But Joel Steiner's
body was never found.
How'd this guy end up
with his Star of David?
I don't know.
But I'm betting a guy like this
has other little "treasures"
stashed around here somewhere.
♪ ♪
(camera shutter clicking)
According to court transcripts,
Haskell's attorneys were
attempting to argue
that the murders were the work
of more than one killer.
That's when Haskell
changed his plea.
What was the theory?
That it would've
been impossible
for Haskell to have
strangled the males
while simultaneously
controlling the females.
They could've been sedated.
Tox on the male vics was clean.
Except for traces
of THC.
Well, these guys are
all narcissists.
Maybe Haskell just didn't want
to share the spotlight.
Or maybe Gerald was more than
just a murderabilia collector.
Maybe he was an accomplice.
Hey.
Greg.
You guys aren't
going to believe this.
Remember that apparent
S &amp;amp;amp;amp; M double murder
from five
weeks ago?
Well, whoever killed
Gerald Tolliver
was also involved in the murders
of Ian Wallace
and Justine Stefani...
His shoe print was
at both crime scenes.
And Ian had nine
postmortem stab wounds.
Didn't mean much at the time,
but it's consistent
with the DJK's MO.
I think we're dealing
with a copycat
who was trying to make Ian
and Justine the ninth couple.
STOKES:
A DJK copycat
who just so happened
to kill a DJK accomplice
that nobody knew existed
till just now?
I've clearly missed something.
I'll catch you up.
So let's just go up to Ely
and question him.
This guy pled guilty
to avoid even the suggestion
that he wasn't responsible.
He's not going to talk to us.
All roads lead to Rome.
BRASS:
So Ely State Prison
sent over all the
correspondence,
video logs, phone records
of the Dick and Jane Killer.
So I told the detectives
to be on the lookout
for any names
that are associated
with both the DJK
and Gerald Tolliver.
I think that might
be our best bet.
That's a lot of material.
Yeah, well, the guy
likes to give interviews.
Dateline, 20/20
Time magazine.
The guy likes to talk.
I think he likes
to have people
listen to him.
So I hear you're moving on.
I am.
That's too bad.
We'll stay in touch.
Sure. You know, the barbecue,
Labor Day, Fourth of July.
Go out on the boat.
You got a boat?
No.
VARTANN:
Captain, something
interesting.
It's not a connection between
DJK and Gerald Tolliver,
but there is a lot
of back and forth
between the warden
and a professor
at WLVU.
Apparently DJK's
participating in some kind
of criminology seminar.
They're setting up
a video conference
for a Q &amp;amp;amp;amp; A with the students,
the whole bit.
Wow. I'd take that class.
That's a good idea.
You should do that.
These letters say the seminar
is open to faculty.
You could go in
as a visiting professor.
GRISSOM:
So what's the real professor
going to say?
BRASS:
We won't tell him.
We'd be risking too much
if he's not willing
to play ball, anyway.
I'll clear it with the
university administration.
Hello. I'm Dr. Raymond Langston.
I'd like to welcome
all those faculty members
who have bravely come out
of the closet
and revealed themselves
to be murder freaks.
(laughter)
Now, one of things
I am most often asked is,
"What does a serial killer
look like?"
It's not a bad question.
Statistically speaking,
nine out of ten
are Caucasian males
under the age
of 30, but you
never know.
There was the case
of a mother and daughter.
In a three-year spree,
they killed over and over again,
systematically murdering
ten infants,
and they ate the remains.
(class laughing)
That's Passion
and Pom.
Jane Goodall observed their
rampage in Gombe in the 70s.
Now, remember, we human beings
share 99.5% of our DNA
with chimps.
The urge to kill...
maybe it is just
a big-brain mammal thing,
but it is in all of us.
LANGSTON:
I want to reemphasize
the ground rules here.
Orderly conduct is to be
maintained at all times.
Don't reveal
any personal information.
No names.
And the warden
has requested that the
ladies please refrain
from wearing
any revealing clothing.
My dear, you might want
to put on
a sweater.
Now, last semester,
some of you came to me
and said you wanted to know
what the face of evil
looked like.
Well, here it is.
Hello, class.
Everybody ready to learn?
What can you tell us
about your father?
Apart from the fact
that he was a mean,
miserable son of a bitch
who beat me at every occasion...
nothing.
What about your mother?
Was that who that lady was
who lived with us?
I always wondered.
Mr. Haskell.
I...
killed my first small animal
when I was nine.
It was a cat.
It's usually a cat.
Mr. Haskell.
No one knows why that is.
I mean, I know
it's a terrible thing...
If you're going
to waste our time
on playing games
and phony remorse,
I'll pull the plug right now.
Okay.
Honesty it is, then.
I didn't like your book.
It's too technical
and too depressing.
Then, let's talk
about something you enjoyed...
your first kill.
Oh, you never forget
your first time,
but I think that discussion's
a little too intimate
for this stage
of our relationship.
Maybe when know each other
a little better.
That's why we're here.
Class, question and answer.
Serial killers usually
have some sort
of selection process.
What was yours? How'd you
choose your victims?
Did you ever buy a car?
You go down to the showroom.
You're pretty sure
you're gonna get one,
but why the red one?
Why not the blue one?
Nobody knows, but...
just one of them speaks to you
and that's the one
you got to have.
How much premeditation
was involved?
Did you fantasize about
what you were going to do?
Of course, I did.
All the time.
You remind me of my first lay.
She was a hooker.
I mean that as a compliment.
GRISSOM:
Did, uh...
you ever share any
of your experiences with anyone?
Like, with a buddy?
I didn't have any buddies.
Well, you must
have had some friends.
You seem like you
could be friendly.
These days, I mostly have fans.
I get at least two or three
marriage proposals every month,
but...
they don't allow
conjugal visits,
so why carry the baggage
when you can't have the fun?
You're not a student.
What do you teach?
Sociology.
Tell us your definition of fun.
Fun is taking something away
from somebody.
Like...
a nice Jewish girl,
for example.
Taking her off
on a little vacation.
Just three days and three nights
of Heaven on Earth.
And then... just Heaven.
L'chaim.
The night before Ian Wallace
and Justine Stefani were killed,
they went to a Paramore concert,
and according
to his credit card records,
he bought tickets
for all three nights:
Thursday, Friday and Saturday.
And we also found these
old Pearl Jam ticket stubs
in Gerald Tolliver's
mattress.
According to the DJK file,
Joel Steiner
and his fiancée went missing
after attending that concert
back in '97.
So, maybe the killer
finds his victims at concerts.
STOKES:
Exactly,
so we checked
with the online
ticketing service.
Hard tickets were mailed
to Ian--
they all get scanned
at the venue--
but on the night
of Ian and Justine's murder,
they were never used.
But the ones
from Saturday night were.
You waste a couple...
why waste the tickets?
MALE STUDENT:
You never revealed the location
of any of your
female victims. Why?
Because nobody ever asked me
that question ever before.
I always thought it was strange.
Well, then, tell us now.
Why not?
You're serving two consecutive
life sentences.
You have nothing to lose.
Of course I do, Professor,
because when I took
those women,
they stopped being somebody's...
girlfriend or...
sister or...
daughter...
or fiancée.
They became
what I wanted them to be.
They're mine.
Did any of them resist?
No one tried to escape
or fight back?
Tiffany and Cynthia
fought a little... at first.
(Langston clears throat)
Um...
How did you control them?
Not with force.
I'm gonna return to
the Jewish theme here, Doctor,
although I want you to know
that I have also killed
Catholics and Protestants
and one atheist.
By the way,
they all prayed eventually.
Anyway, during the Holocaust,
when the first arrivals
at the death camps
realized they were going
to be killed,
they flew into a panic,
so the guards-- the Nazis--
started telling them that they
were going to be put to work,
that their skills
were going to be used,
and they all calmed down.
And they all marched obediently
into the showers.
You have to give them hope.
If you bring a human being
to the brink of death,
and then you offer a chance--
no matter how small a chance--
to survive,
they'll grab it.
And they'll thank you for it.
And then...
you can do whatever you want.
And believe me...
I did.
(phone ringing)
Langston.
Hello, warden,
thank you for calling.
Am I making you proud of me?
Thank you.
Okay, that's it for today.
See you tomorrow.
Be careful out there.
(quiet murmuring)
Could I buy you a drink?
Definitely.
(rock music playing,
crowd cheering)
SANDERS:
So, all these videos are
from the Paramore show
the night after Justine
and Ian were killed?
Got to love
the Internet.
The vics' tickets
were in section 203...
seats M26 and 28.
And this video...
has the best view
of those seats.
Looks like they have
the same logos
on their ball caps.
I'll enhance that.
Reliant Wash and Wax.
MAN:
Uh, yeah, I recognize them.
That's Richie and Donny--
they're in the tunnel.
Yeah, okay.
Yeah.
All right,
shut the machine down.
Okay.
Go in the west entrance.
Buckle up these two guys.
Las Vegas Police!
Las Vegas Police.
Put your hands on the hood.
Put your hands on the hood
where I can see them.
(grunting)
BRASS:
Okay, here's
a simple quiz.
The Paramore concert
five weeks ago.
Where'd you get the tickets?
I told you not to do it,
you idiot.
I got them off a scalper.
That's not illegal--
it's the scalping them
that's illegal.
Shut up.
I don't know what this
guy's talking...
coming in here...
What the scalper look like?
I don't know, it was dark.
It was in a
parking lot.
Some skinny white dude, man.
Well, that's a big help.
Any chance either of you
have the ticket stub?
Yeah, I do.
It's in my wallet.
What is this,
a phone book?
Yeah, I keep
everything.
♪ ♪
Somebody's home.
Come on, let's go.
Let's go,
go, go, go.
(knocking)
Curtis Keesey-- LVPD! Open up!
The lights are
on a timer.
(Nick coughing)
Late instar,
synthesiomyia nudiseta.
So, I hear you've been
going back to school.
Sort of.
I loved college.
Me, too.
Green Bottle Blow Fly.
These typically pupate
in about two weeks
and emerge as
adults in four.
The AC on in the trailer
slows down the timeline a bit.
He's been dead at least a month.
You're going to miss this,
you are.
There's bugs everywhere, David.
I will miss you, though.
Hey, Nicky, he's got
Pirellis in the front
and Michelins in the rear.
Consistent
with the tire treads found
at the Justine Stefani
murder scene.
That's great but unfortunately,
his shoes were not.
None of these
treads match.
So, Curtis must've
been the wheel man.
At least we got half the team
that killed Ian and Justine.
Yeah, it's the half
that's out there
walking around
that I'm worried about.
GREG:
So, six
months ago,
Shoe Print Man
kills Gerald Tolliver,
an accomplice of
the Dick and Jane Killer.
CATHERINE:
And then,
five weeks ago,
Shoe Print, along
with Curtis Keesey,
abducts and kills
a couple in what appears
to be a botched
DJK-style murder.
Can we connect Shoe Print
with the murder
of Curtis Keesey?
There's no physical evidence.
But we do know
that Curtis scalped
his vics' concert tickets,
which isn't too bright.
Reason enough for one crook
to kill another.
So, let's assume that Shoe Print
was involved in
all four murders.
It's possible he
knew Gerald, right?
Is it also possible that he
was an accomplice of DJK?
GREG:
That would explain
the nine post-mortem
stab wounds in Ian Wallace.
It's a continuation
of the master's work.
But if he was DJK's
helper back in the day,
why go quiet
for ten years and then
suddenly start killing again?
Maybe he was doing time.
And when he realized
that his old partner
turned informant, he got
scared and killed him.
Maybe that's what brought
the old thrill back.
Once these guys get a taste,
it never seems to go away.
So, we've been talking a lot
about how you did what you did.
Let's shift gears from
what you did right,
to what you did wrong.
Do you mean in a Ten
Commandments sense?
I mean in how you got caught.
That's the least
exciting part of the story.
Yeah, but didn't you want it?
Didn't you want
to get caught?
Why would I want that?
You were caught
because a rookie patrolman
spotted blood
on your car, correct?
For a careful man,
that seems a
little careless.
Everybody makes mistakes.
Not someone like you.
Not a mistake like that.
I'm flattered you
think so highly of me.
Any other questions?
Anybody else?
Mr. Haskell, you're of
average height and weight.
And not overly muscular.
I try to watch what I eat.
In jail, that takes more
strength than you would know.
A few of your male victims
were pretty big.
One even played
college football.
How were you able to
overpower a man like that,
while still keeping
control of the woman?
Why don't you tell me,
Professor?
You obviously have a theory.
Well, I think you
must've had help.
The works of great men
can be hard to comprehend
for those less great.
You said you were going
to be honest with us.
Now, answer the question.
Did you have help or not?
Well, let me think.
With Melanie, it was just
me and the baseball bat.
With Kristin, when I
cut off her right breast,
that was just me.
When I crushed Joel's neck
and felt his veins burst under
my fingers like rotten grapes,
and watched his throat
fill up with blood,
I didn't have
any help there, either.
MRS. STEINER:
Where is he, you monster!
Where is my Joel?
Where is he?!
Oh, I think I hit a nerve.
You tell me where he is!
Can I think about that
and get back to you?
Okay, I thought about it,
I'm not going to tell you.
(whimpering):
Oh, please tell me...
Don't give him the satisfaction.
HASKELL:
Joel was the first.
Joel is in the perfect place,
the place where it all began.
And if I could get
out of here, believe me,
I would bring him some company.
GRISSOM:
Mr. Haskell, we know
that you had accomplices.
If you were to reveal
who they were,
it might get you
out of keep-away.
Oh, how nice
that we have a member
of the law enforcement
community with us today.
For you real students
who don't know, "keep-away"
is what they call the kind
of solitary confinement I'm in.
Kill the feed.
It's kind of funny, don't you--
You hijacked my class
without my consent
for your investigation?!
We're working
a multiple homicide.
We didn't want to talk about it
outside the department.
You talked to the Dean.
Well, it was on a
need-to-know basis
and he had a
need to know.
Look, I don't teach this course
because I get off
on the subject matter.
If there's another DJK out
there, I want him just as bad
as you do.
I would've helped.
I would've been
happy to help you.
I'm sure that's true.
You believe DJK
had an accomplice?
I do.
Do you have a name?
Not yet.
Okay, now we're all up to speed.
Doctor...
I will keep you informed.
To the extent that we can.
Thanks. I know a kiss-off
when I hear one.
(sighs): A little cranky
for an academic, isn't he?
Actually, he's an M.D.
from back East.
A colleague at his hospital
turned out to be
an Angel of Death.
Killed 27 patients
before he was caught.
Langston was the staff
research pathologist.
All the morbidity evidence
came across his desk,
but he was unable
to connect the dots.
He wrote a book
about it.
Any good?
I liked it.
(phone ringing)
This is Langston.
Working late? I kind of thought
you might be.
Haskell.
Uh-huh. This must
be my lucky night.
Maybe it's yours, too.
What do you want?
I want you to look
out the window.
Why?
Because I'm in the parking lot.
(Haskell chuckling)
I made you look.
Is that why you called?
No, I wanted to talk to you
about what happened in class
today-- with Mrs. Steiner.
Sure, just, uh,
hold on a second.
Let me close the door.
(phone ringing)
Grissom.
Ray Langston. I have
Nate Haskell on the phone.
He wants to talk about what
happened with Mrs. Steiner.
I'd like to put you
on the other line.
Go ahead.
Haskell, are you there?
I'm sure we're all here now.
What I learned in class today,
as I was looking out at all
those scared little faces
who couldn't take
their eyes off of me,
was how much I miss
being out in the world.
And when Mrs. Steiner
had her "moment,"
it got me thinking
about... closure.
Which is what you'll find
at the corner of Boulder
Highway and Hasbrook.
It's just another empty
stretch of desert out there.
At least it was ten years ago.
The way this city's changed,
it's maybe all different now.
Although, maybe not.
It's kind of an ugly place.
Anyway, it's just the
same in my imagination.
There's a concrete bridge
built in 1938.
You can tell because the
year is stamped in the front.
25 feet from that, look west.
You'll see one dark stone
that just doesn't
quit fit with the rest.
Under there...
that's where you'll find Joel.
And if we're lucky,
maybe something else.
Grissom, we got
something here!
Because that's the problem
with closure.
Sometimes when
something closes,
something else opens up.
Guess you won't be
leaving just yet.