♪ Those who are dead
are not dead ♪
♪ They're just living
in my head ♪
♪ And since I fell
for that spell ♪
♪ I am living there as well ♪
(TV news playing quietly
in background)
♪ Oh... ♪
♪ Time is so short
and I'm sure ♪
♪ There must be something more ♪
(phone ringing)
♪ Those who are dead
are not dead ♪
Hello?
♪ They're just living
in my head ♪
♪ Oh... oh... ♪
♪ And since I fell
for that spell ♪
♪ I am living there as well ♪
♪ Oh... oh... ♪
♪ Time is so short
and I'm sure ♪
♪ There must be something more ♪
♪ Oh... ♪
(fading out):
♪ Oh, oh, oh... ♪
(loud boom, panicked screaming)
No!
(car alarms blaring)
(siren chirps)
(camera shutter clicking)
STOKES:
What's with the bikini?
Maybe she wanted to leave
a good-looking corpse.
Guys, you might want to
take a few steps back.
This could get messy.
(squishing sound)
Soup sandwich.
Should have taken
the elevator down.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
(phone ringing)
It's the lab again.
(ringing continues)
Do you want to get it?
No.
Maybe we should
go away for a while.
I can't.
We're so short.
Why don't you stay?
I can't stay here.
It would be nice
to take a trip.
I don't know.
Get on the Sea Shepherd.
Go to the Galápagos.
We can literally walk
in the footsteps of Darwin.
(police siren chirping)
(mechanical whirring)
The fall is like flying.
It's the sudden stop
that gets you.
Momentum's a bitch.
OFFICER:
Catherine.
The doorman I.D.'d her
as Sprig Greniger.
Apartment 2204.
Lives with her boyfriend.
We're putting out
a broadcast.
Well, let's find out
why Sprig was sprung.
(wind rushing)
(whooshing)
Whoa.
No sign of forced entry.
No struggle.
Nice place.
Mm-hmm.
Something smells
really good.
(traffic passes below,
horn honks)
(whooshing)
(wind rushing)
(sniffing)
Mmm.
(closes oven)
Cook ten hours at 200 degrees.
Hey.
She was getting married
in less than two weeks.
What?
Yeah, she was having dinner
with the in-laws tonight.
"Pot roast. Make and reheat."
Less than an hour left
on the pot roast.
Turn on the news,
make a pot roast,
slip into a bikini,
and commit suicide?
Yeah, it doesn't make
a whole lot of sense.
Mnh-mnh.
She got a call
just before midnight.
Maybe she and the boyfriend
had a fight.
(phone beeps on)
Oh, God.
What?
Nothing.
(speed-dialing tone)
Archie, it's Catherine.
Can you run a number for me?
(siren wailing in distance)
Sir.
Williams. Doc.
What took so long
for the lab to get here?
We're a little shorthanded,
Detective.
Sorry. Forgot.
Delivery guy found her here
a couple of hours ago.
Rough neighborhood.
(siren wails, then stops)
ROBBINS:
Looks like someone was having
a five-finger discussion
with her.
The language of the streets.
And there's your money shot.
Blunt-force trauma
to the back
of the skull.
(distorted grunting)
I think I found ground zero.
And I found a room key
in her back pocket.
Tangiers.
I'll check it out.
I don't see a purse.
Maybe she was a tourist
trying to score something
a little stronger than alcohol.
(gasping, grunting)
Detective, give me
a hand here, would you?
Yeah.
The globes of her eyeballs
are ruptured.
Looks like someone
thumbed them back
into the orbital socket.
You know, they, uh,
they squish like grapes.
This was rage.
Pure rage.
(heart monitor beeping
rhythmically)
(respirators hissing quietly)
Hi. Sorry to hear
about Brown.
Gonna miss him.
Yeah. Me, too.
Your victim was
a 34-year-old
black female.
Been in a coma
for eight years.
Result of a rape assault.
I worked the case,
along with Sidle.
Looks like the husband
disconnected the
breathing tube.
I can't get him
away from her.
The uniforms are gonna
go in and drag him out.
I'm just waiting for you.
Why don't you, uh,
hold off on that.
I'd just like
to make a call first.
♪ ♪
(beep)
I wonder how many guys go
on diets before their weddings.
She was filing
for unemployment.
Bank teller.
Maybe losing her job
sent her over the edge.
(phone ringing)
This is Catherine.
Oh, hey, Archie.
Oh.
Okay, thanks.
So, the last call
to Sprig's cell
was from a pay phone
on Paradise and Moesser Avenue.
That's right across the street.
Yeah.
STOKES:
Whoever called Sprig
had a front-row seat.
I'll print the phone,
see what I can get.
(phone beeps off)
(door opens)
(door closes)
Catherine...
this is Brett Davidson;
he's the victim's fiancée.
Mr. Davidson,
I'm sorry for your loss.
How often do you
have to say that?
Often.
You live here.
Right?
Yeah.
I'm sorry, I'm gonna
have to print you.
Where were you,
Mr. Davidson?
I had a business
trip in Phoenix.
I was just
gone for a day.
Was your fiancée depressed?
No, she invented
the silver lining.
We were getting married.
We were having my parents
over for dinner.
She'd been planning
it for weeks.
Were the two of you
having problems?
No.
I mean...
weddings don't always
bring out the best in women.
What do you mean?
She didn't want
"fat" wedding pictures,
so she stopped eating.
Obsessively counting calories,
and all that diet stuff.
(sighs)
And there's
the cost of the wedding,
the honeymoon.
Plus the, uh, mortgage
on this place.
I told her not to
worry about money,
that I could pay
for everything.
I told her that all the time.
Did she quit her job?
It was a misunderstanding.
Her drawer came in short.
After five years
of loyal service,
the bank accused her
of stealing ten grand.
She didn't do it.
It's just not who she is.
I held the scene
for you.
Thanks.
Tom?
Sarah.
What are you
doing here?
I thought
you'd been away.
I am so sorry.
I know how much
you loved her.
I promised to protect her.
I failed her once.
I wasn't gonna
fail her again.
What do you mean?
He started calling me.
Harassing me.
THOMAS:
And he was here
in her room.
Who was here, Mr. Adler?
The guy
who put her here...
Tony Thorpe.
He left me a newspaper clipping
from eight years ago,
with a note.
Said he violated her again.
That she liked it more
the second time.
It's the only way
I knew to save her.
You still have the newspaper?
We could run it
for prints.
It made me sick
to my stomach.
I burned it.
Mr. Adler,
you need to
come with me.
We need to
go downtown
so you can give
a statement.
Tom, look. Um...
I-I am no longer
a CSI, but...
I'll go with you. Okay?
I won't leave you.
Here's what got
our jumper fired.
He's making change.
(taps keys)
WILLOWS:
Oh.
He gave her two 50s.
She gave him
a hundred hundreds.
Ten grand.
Mm.
Bank manager said
when he questioned her,
she couldn't remember
the customer or the transaction.
WILLOWS:
But there's no
gun, no note.
She doesn't appear
to be under duress.
Which is exactly
why the bank figured it was
a scam-- she was in on it.
Now, this is a
day-shift case
from a couple of weeks ago.
Different bank,
same guy, same gag.
The guy hands
her two $50s.
She counts out a hundred
hundred-dollar bills
According to the case file,
she can't remember
anything either.
WOMAN:
I've been working
at First Federation
nine years.
Perfect record.
Miss Powell,
do you recognize this man?
If I knew who he was,
I'd hunt him down myself.
You know, memory
is a funny thing.
Even when they
showed me the video,
I couldn't remember this guy.
Now my mind starts thinking
I do know him.
But I'm just recognizing him
from all the times
you cops keep showing me
his damn, ugly picture.
And you don't have
any memory of what happened
the day he came in.
You always remember
the day you got fired.
What I can't remember,
is "Light Fingers" Louie there.
Miss Powell,
have you been doing anything
to lose weight recently?
Now you saying
I look fat? Because I only
gained three pounds
since I quit smoking.
Oh.
And how did you quit?
Went to the stop-smoking lady.
You trying to quit, too?
'Cause, uh...
I got her number.
(performers clucking
like chickens)
(audience laughing)
(performers clucking,
audience laughing)
My, that's a big, big egg
you're trying to lay.
(laughter)
All right, back
to your roosts.
Back to your roosts.
Back, back,
back to your roost.
(clucking continues)
Now, on my count of three,
you will go into a deep
state of relaxation.
Your eyes will become heavy.
One... two... three.
(snapping fingers)
Relax.
(audience laughs)
Deeper and deeper
into a state of relaxation.
Deeper...
and deeper.
You are feeling...
very comfortable.
Now, sweetheart,
I'm handing you
a delicious, crunchy apple.
MAN:
Oh, no.
When I tell you to open
your eyes, you will bite
into this delicious,
crunchy apple.
One, two, three--
(snapping fingers)
open your eyes.
AUDIENCE:
Ohh...
(laughing)
(applause)
MADAME MARVELOUS:
Well, the show just
pays the bills,
but most of my work
is private client therapy.
Was a young lady named Sprig
Greniger a client of yours?
She wanted to lose weight
for her honeymoon,
and she lost 12 pounds.
Well,
what did you do?
Well, I didn't
do anything.
All hypnosis is self-hypnosis.
Look, people clucking like
chickens and humping chairs,
that's all...
that's all schtick.
But...
when they come to
me for therapy,
they have a goal.
They want to lose weight
or stop smoking,
and I do visualizations
to help them get there.
"See your lungs healthy."
"See yourself
in a bathing suit."
What kind
of visualizations
did you give Sprig?
I told her to, uh,
picture herself in a...
in a teeny bikini,
on a beach in Hawaii,
taking off her towel,
then running across the sand
and jumping
into the water,
feeling fit and confident.
Sounds pretty simple.
It is and it isn't.
Hypnosis just helps you go
into different states
of consciousness.
I mean, beta is your
most conscious state.
That's what
we're all in right now.
And then
there's alpha.
That's your
meditative state.
And then theta.
That's your dream state.
And finally, there's delta.
That's that super deep sleep
you go into
after feeling really exhausted.
I mean, have either one of you
ever gotten to work and then
forgotten how
you got there?
Forgotten
the entire ride?
Well, then
essentially, you've been
in a hypnotic state.
I mean, being in love,
all you see is good.
Being in grief,
all you see is bad.
It's all altered states,
and we float between them.
What state of mind
was the onion-eater in?
Well, he was somewhere
between alpha and theta.
And what will he remember?
Eating an onion?
Or eating an apple?
As far as he knows,
he ate an apple.
Because you told him
it was an apple.
Well, because he wanted
to eat an apple.
So, could you convince
people to do anything?
Like...
rob a bank?
(laughs)
Hypnosis is not magic;
I cannot make people
do things that they
wouldn't otherwise do,
unless...
unless it was already
in their nature.
WILLIAMS:
The prints came back.
Paula Bonfilio,
high school guidance
counselor from Henderson.
How about the Tangiers
room key in her pocket?
The room was registered
to a pit boss there.
Says he uses it
to entertain high rollers.
She didn't sound like
a high roller to me.
Pit boss says he can
tell like clockwork
when she gets her paycheck.
Last night she was
in pretty deep.
He helped her get
out of the hole.
Oh, I get it.
You get a DNA sample?
It matched the semen Grissom
found in her vaginal vault.
Well, I'm glad
she's guiding our youth.
Look, I'm hung up
at the sheriff's office
helping them look
for a new undersheriff.
You're gonna find out what she
was doing in Alphabet City?
Yes, sir. I'm on my way
to talk to the family right now.
Okay, stay safe.
Okay.
(knocking on door)
MAN:
Can I help you?
WILLIAMS:
And you are?
I'm, I'm
Scott Bonfilio.
So, Scott, is
your dad around?
I don't have a dad.
I mean, I... I don't
know who he is.
I'm Detective Williams,
LVPD. This is Gil Grissom,
from the Crime Lab.
Is this about my mom?
Is she in trouble?
I'm sorry to have to
tell you this, but...
your mom has died.
It appears she
was murdered.
But I, I talked
to her last night.
She was fine.
What time?
Um...
Like around 10:00 or so.
She was with Lexi.
Who's that?
She's my baby sister.
We interrupt our program with
this important Amber Alert.
Please help police
find this little girl...
She's just two years old
and named Lexi Bonfilio.
Lexi's mother
was last seen alive
up at Tangiers Casino Hotel...
Wow, that's was really fast.
We take missing children
very seriously.
Did you find me anything
with DNA on it?
Yes.
I-I haven't washed it.
Will that work?
It's perfect.
Scott, when was the last time
you saw your mother?
Yesterday at school.
She said she and Lexi
were going shopping
I had to work, so I didn't
get home till around 7:00.
And she called
around 10:00?
Yeah.
She said she... would be gone
for the night.
Is that normal?
Gone for the night?
Yes.
With Lexi...
only if I have to work.
Did she say where she was or...?
No.
And I stopped asking.
I know this sounds terrible,
but I'm....
I'm a straight-A senior.
Going to community college
next year
because my mom gambled away
my college money.
I started hiding my paychecks
but my mom would
find them anyway.
And then she'd go to the tables
and lose it all.
This isn't your typical
mother-son relationship.
Is it possible that your
sister's with her father?
No.
My mom's always
been kind of a...
kind of a party girl.
But she never
brought guys home.
When she got pregnant
with Lexi...
she said she was a gift
from God.
I got a pretty good timeline
on Paul Bonfilio.
At 4:15 p.m.,
a hold was placed
on Paul's credit card
by the Tangiers
Casino Day Care.
Casino day care;
there's the fifth
sign of the Apocalypse.
She loses big for
a couple of hours.
Leaves the table
around 6:00 p.m.
Picked her up
on another camera
heading away with some
cheesy-looking dude.
Brass ID'd him
as a pit boss.
Entertainer to the desperate.
She goes back to the
tables around 7:00
but didn't play
for very long.
She got a call
from a disposable
cell phone.
I'm thinking it was from...
this guy.
He grabs her.
She grabs her
last 500-dollar chip,
and they split.
He got her out of there
before she lost it all.
You know,
higher denomination chips
sometimes carry
a radio frequency device.
I'll call the casino.
They'll flag it.
Someone tries to cash it,
they'll tell us.
At 8:15 p.m.,
she and Mr. Grabby
pick up the baby.
So now she's got
the baby.
The next time I have her
is at
Pete's Pawnshop
downtown,
B Street.
Right where you
found the body.
Her ATM card
was rejected there
just after 9:00 p.m.
The account was overdrawn.
And then we have a cell phone
call to home around 10:00 p.m.
That's it
for the timeline.
Last seen with a man
wearing glasses
inside Pete's Pawnshop.
I found broken optical glass
in the alley out back.
Maybe we're looking
at her killer.
Is this justice?
He's a victim in this.
He had admitted
killing his wife.
Active euthanasia
is felony murder.
I feel for the guy,
but it's out of my hands.
He said that Thorpe
went to Pam's room,
did God only knows what,
called his house,
bragged about it...
We're checking
into that.
It would have helped
if he saved the note.
Would you
if it was your wife?
Sara,
the fact is,
he unplugged her tube,
and he watched her die.
This is why I can't
do this anymore.
None of the calls
to Tom Adler's home phone
could be traced back
to Tony Thorpe.
Well, he could use
the pay phone
or a disposable phone.
There's no evidence
Thorpe was ever
in Pam Adler's room.
No trace of him
on her or in her.
And Doc Robbins found no sign
of sexual assault.
Yeah, but we don't know
when that happened.
And we both know
that semen deteriorates
within 12 to 24 hours.
Sara, you have to consider
the possibility
that the husband
made up the story
to justify his actions.
No, absolutely not.
I'm not saying
he didn't love her.
He loved her so much
that he kept her alive
for eight years.
You're still
a scientist.
You know that after
that many years
of atrophy,
she wasn't coming
back to him.
I mean, sooner or later,
a relationship in stasis
withers.
You get angry.
You need more than the safety
of knowing
that you're not alone.
Then he should have
just walked away.
Well, maybe he couldn't.
Maybe he needed her
to leave him.
Who are we talking about
right now?
MAN:
I'm going to count backwards
from ten to one.
When I get to one,
you'll be at work
the day of the robbery.
Ten... nine...
eight... breathing...
seven... six...
getting closer...
five, four...
breathing...
three, two,
one.
Now, Grace,
there's a man at your window.
He has a beard
and baseball cap.
Do you see him?
What is he saying to you?
He wants change
for two 50s.
And what do you do?
I give him a hundred singles.
Surveillance showed
hundreds on the right,
singles on the left.
She definitely gave him
hundreds.
Does he say anything else
to you?
I can't remember.
Usually, the witnesses
I hypnotize for the department
remember even tiny details.
In my opinion, whoever
hypnotized her put a block in.
What do you mean by a block?
A command to keep her from
remembering what happened.
So, you're saying this guy
can just roll
into a crowded bank,
walk up to a teller
and in 30 seconds,
look her in the eye
tell her she's
getting sleepy
and sloppy with her hundreds?
You couldn't do it
in 30 seconds.
But if there's a block,
it wasn't the first time
he hypnotized her.
During a prior session,
he must have implanted a
post-hypnotic suggestion
with a word
or a phrase as a trigger.
Could this post-hypnotic
suggestion
get people
to do anything
even if it's against
their moral code?
It's all in the phrasing.
You don't say
"Rob the bank."
You say,
"Liberate the money."
So, anybody says,
"Liberate the money"
and she sees hundreds as ones?
No, it has to be
the same voice
that planted the suggestion.
She had a female hypnotist.
We gotta get a better
description on this guy.
The man with the baseball cap
is standing in front of you.
What else do you
notice about him?
Small hands.
Little sissy hands.
Jacked-up fingernails.
ARCHIE:
Maybe it's a fungus.
I don't think
it's a fungus.
I think it's a nail glue.
That's how your nails look
after you take off
the acrylic tips.
When someone comes to me
for therapy,
they have a goal.
Archie, pull up the DMV photo
of Viviana Conway.
(typing)
And now do
a biometrics
comparison
with the guy with
the funky nails.
I figured out why Thorpe
was harassing the Adlers.
Eight years ago,
the law was if
a victim dies,
within a year
and a day from
an assault,
the suspect can
still be charged
with the murder.
Right.
We're working this case
as a murder.
At least for the next year
and a day.
And even then,
I'm still a juvie.
According to D.A. Klein,
the law's changed.
Nowadays,
if Pam Adler died,
and her death
could be attributed
to the rape assault,
Thorpe could be charged
with her murder at any time.
So if Thorpe knew that,
he would have had motive
to terrorize Tom
by making Tom believe
that he was raping Pam.
Because if the husband
goes down for it,
Thorpe's free and clear.
It's murder by proxy.
Thank you.
Grissom, ALPR's got a hit
on Paul Bonfilio's car.
We're sitting on it now.
I'll let you know.
(keyless entry remote chirps)
Excuse me, miss.
Is that your car?
I'm driving it.
Then you're under arrest
for receiving stolen property...
Hey, hey,
watch the nails!
I didn't kidnap nobody.
Where'd you get the car?
Some dude.
Hey, baby, want to taste
a little sugar?
I don't do looky-loos.
I'll give you
this car if you
drop her off for me.
Some white boy with
real hair gives you a car,
you don't say no.
Well, then it's your lucky day.
Where'd you drop her off?
At Palermo.
They got the best buffet.
WILLIAMS:
I need to pick up the child
this woman dropped off.
Name?
Trixie, Jr.
DAY CARE WORKER:
You're over the four-hour limit.
She made a couple
of stops.
You're not supposed
to leave the casino.
Bitch, can you not read
a situation?
It ain't my real baby, stupid!
(crying)
There you go.
Hey, hey...
that's okay,
I got him.
Come here.
Here's your
big brother.
Who's my good girl?
Who's a good girl?
I was so scared.
I missed you so much.
Can I keep her?
I'm 18.
I've basically been taking care
of her since she was born.
That's up to C.P.S.
But I'll have my captain
put in a good word.
MAN:
Now stage left.
Yeah.
Yeah, that's it.
It could have just looked
like teller error...
twice.
I know you're quite
the performer, but...
in our business,
wearing a disguise
is called consciousness
of guilt.
I believe that's
beta level consciousness.
STOKES:
These people trusted you.
And you got them fired
from their jobs.
Why would you do
something like that?
Because I could.
I can't sing.
I'm not a surgeon.
But I have this gift.
I have this energy
and this voice
that makes people
feel very calm.
Calm enough to get
inside their heads.
You give me 20 minutes
with anyone,
and I can put them under.
Cops, soldiers, bank tellers.
I mean, come on,
I had not one,
but two clients
who were bank tellers.
I had to try.
Sprig Greniger is dead.
We don't think
it was a suicide.
Sprig wrote five
checks to you.
According to her datebook,
she had six sessions.
The last one was
the day she died.
Explain that
to me.
I gave her a free session.
I mean, it was the least
I could do.
Like you said, you know,
she'd just lost her job.
Maybe she hadn't lost
her memory,
and she was on to you.
Hey, I've never even been
to Sprig's apartment.
No, but you used the pay
phone across the street.
Your prints are on it.
WILLOWS:
All she needed to hear
was the sound of your voice.
(phone ringing)
Hello.
CONWAY:
It's time for your honeymoon.
WILLOWS:
She put on a bikini.
She grabbed a towel.
She went out onto the balcony.
You told her to picture herself
on a beach in Hawaii
running across the sand,
feeling fit and confident.
You told her to jump
into the water.
(crashing, glass shattering)
(people yelling and screaming)
You guys might have me
for bank robbery...
but there is no way
that you can prove
I had anything to do
with her death.
It's like I told you--
I cannot make people do anything
that they don't want to do.
I can.
Get in jail.
Sara, they're
bringing Thorpe in now.
Now look, I know you have
personal interest in this.
But you're not
on the job anymore.
I know.
Tony.
VEGA:
Remember me?
Detective Vega.
Well, screw you.
I want a lawyer.
I'm not charging you
with anything.
I just want to talk.
How'd you end up
with the wheels?
Pepper Street doing
some bad shots.
I'm too tough to die.
How long ago?
Last Christmas.
WILLIAMS:
So this is what we got.
We found your prints
all over Paula Bonfilio's car.
So tell me, Leon,
how'd you bust up
your hands?
Can't remember.
Picking blueberries, I think.
Oh.
How much did Paula owe you?
Lending money to those who
need it isn't against the law.
But killing them
if they can't pay up is.
All you got left
is the baby
and the car!
Pay me right now
or I take them!
(both grunting)
Yeah, I roughed her up.
And yeah, I unburdened her
of her car and her baby.
But when I left her in that
alley, she was completely alive.
Then why not unburden her
of that 500-dollar chip
she had in her purse?
Lady owed me 12,000 bucks.
$500 barely covers the interest.
You got to tough-love
these junkie twits
or they never pay up.
I swear
on my professional oath,
I was going to give her
the car and the baby back.
Then why give them
to the hooker?
That was just after I saw
that crap on the news.
Kid's cool, right?
I didn't kill her.
We, uh...
found Thorpe.
Why did you lie to me, Tom?
I can't win for losing.
People told me I was selfish
keeping her alive for so long.
And now look at me.
Mostly I was pissed
that he's out walking around.
And whenever I wasn't working
or paying for her care,
I was just sitting
by that bed.
After a while,
I realized the only one who was
feeling any suffering... was me.
I just
wasn't living.
I just couldn't move on
and leave her there like that.
You could have asked
the doctors to help you.
By telling them what?
That I was tired?
I wanted them
to kill my wife
so that I could have
a weekend to myself?
At least that would
have been honest.
(phone ringing)
Archie Johnson.
Someone tried to cash that chip?
Yeah, send it over. Thanks.
Grissom.
(Lexi crying)
This looks like
the same gold link strap
I found
at the scene.
And there's blood on it.
Honey...
GRISSOM:
Paula called Scott
around 10:00.
Maybe she needed his help.
I screwed up... big time.
(tires squealing)
Where's Lexi?
Don't be upset.
I can fix this.
No! Are you out of your mind?!
Just tell me where Lexi is.
He won't give her back
until we give him the money!
How could you do this?!
This might
explain the rage.
GRISSOM:
He was Oedipus.
SIMMS:
I was just running
the DNA profiles,
and Paula and Scott Bonfilio
don't have
any markers in common.
I mean, these two are
definitely not mother and son.
And I checked for
adoption records
and foster records for Scott,
and there's nothing.
Now, Lexi, on the other hand,
shares markers at every
locus with both of them.
So she's their kid?
Yeah.
Now, according to Paula's
employment record,
they've only been living
in Vegas for a little
over two years.
So the child was conceived
before they got here.
Which means that Scott
was 15 years old.
This also says that
her previous place
of employment
was Archfield High School
in Akron, Ohio.
Scott was her student.
And his fingerprints are in
the missing children's database.
(sighs)
She didn't kidnap me,
but I became her hostage.
Why didn't you
call your parents?
That's like switching
arsenic for cyanide.
They'd never
let me keep Lexi.
Someone cared enough about you
to put you in
the missing kids' database.
My alkie dad was missing
his cigarette runner.
That's hardly love.
But you and Paula...
She was my guidance counselor.
She listened to all my problems.
It was the first time
I felt heard.
Then it all
went to hell.
I got too old for her.
(sniffles)
She only liked me
when I was risky.
As soon as the naughty
faded away...
she started seeking risk
anywhere else she could.
I was just trying
to start a... a better life.
To make a family.
And then she gave away our baby
for a gambling debt.
(screaming)
(grunting)
(squishing)
Have you ever loved
someone so much
that you would kill for them?
I do.
And even if Lexi
can't be with me,
she's better off without her.
and then she took it all away.