NATE HASKELL:
There's a concrete bridge
built in 1938.
25 feet from there...
look west.
That's where you'll find Joel.
BRASS:
His directions to the crime
scene were very precise.
We found the bones
of a male body
buried in three feet of dirt.
ECKLIE:
The hyoid bone was broken,
which indicates death
by strangulation, so...
pending DNA, we're tentatively
ID'ing him as Joel Steiner,
the first victim
of Nate Haskell,
the Dick and Jane killer.
BRASS:
We found another male D.B.
in close proximity.
ECKLIE:
We estimate he's been dead
no longer than 24 hours.
BRASS:
His name is Jeffrey Masters.
He was strangled
like the others.
He has a wife-- Maureen.
She's not at home,
she's not answering her cell.
According to friends,
the two of them were
out clubbing last night.
We have a broadcast out.
But you're not 100% certain
she's actually missing.
How are you so sure
they're victims
of this Dick and Jane killer?
Well, Sheriff,
we believe
the killer is actually
one of his accomplices.
DJK's signature is
postmortem stab
wounds to the male.
They're his version
of notches on a gun.
ECKLIE:
Jeffrey Masters
was stabbed ten times.
He and his wife would be the
tenth couple taken overall.
BRASS:
The M.O. of the killer is,
he usually targets a couple--
a male and female.
ECKLIE:
He strangles the male,
then dumps the body;
BRASS:
Takes the female,
holds her hostage,
tortures her; eventually,
he kills her, too.
How much time do we have?
ECKLIE:
It's hard to say.
We placed CSI Grissom
undercover in a college seminar
in which Haskell
was being interviewed.
Haskell implied that he kept
one of his female vics
alive for three days.
The general rule of thumb is,
we probably have
less than 48 hours.
This is quite the PR
crapper you've dumped me in.
LVPD and the Crime Lab run
some kind of a sting operation
in a class
about serial killers,
and the serial killer uses it
to reach out from behind bars
and kill again?
Want to know how you
can make it up to me?
Find the girl.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
A new body at the site
of his first kill
can't be a coincidence.
I think that Nathan Haskell
somehow got a message
to someone.
No, I agree-- I spoke
to the warden at Ely.
The only communication
Haskell's had
with the outside world
in the last 48 hours
was the phone call
to Langston,
and that seminar
you were in.
Also, Sheriff Burdick wants to
start a task force about this,
and he's asked me to
ask you to stay on--
so I'm asking.
Okay, I have an answer.
I'll keep you informed.
LANGSTON:
Tell us your definition of fun.
Fun is taking something
away from somebody.
Oh, you never forget your first.
(woman groans quietly)
(groans louder)
(TV playing in distance)
(exhales gently)
GAME SHOW HOST: Welcome back
to Question the Answer!
Dana's our current leader
and has control.
(door squeaks open)
Okay, it looks like
you've been the jumper today,
jumping all over the board.
What's your category, Dana?
DANA:
How about "Happiness" for $800.
HOST:
And "Happiness" for $800 it is.
Okay, Dana:
"In the central nervous system,
"this plays an important role
in modulation of happiness."
Can you...
Question the Answer?
DANA:
What is the thalamus?
THE KILLER (with TV host):
I'm sorry, that's wrong.
Serotonin is a chemical
that produces
happiness in a person.
HOST:
When serotonin is released,
happiness is the result.
Yes, it is.
(grunting, gasping)
ECKLIE:
Yes, sir.
Absolutely.
Okay. (chuckles)
I will.
Okay.
Come in.
I need a favor.
It's something
you're going to
have to clear with the sheriff.
What, do you have bugs
in my office?
No.
I have bugs in my office.
What?
What are we talking about?
Sheriff Burdick is
reorganizing the department.
From now on, the crime lab
will report
directly to him.
He just made me
the new undersheriff.
Congratulations, Conrad.
And I have a great idea for
your first official act.
Dr. Langston, I was just
going to call you.
Oh.
I'll, uh, save you
the trouble.
Come on in.
Huh.
What's on your mind?
When I was doing my background
research on Haskell,
I found something
very interesting.
Now, as you pointed
out in class,
he's five-ten, 160 pounds.
Most of his male victims
were over 200 pounds.
One was a football player,
uh, one was a Black Belt,
but none of them
had defensive wounds
and none of them were bound.
Now, most people respond
to being strangled
by fighting back.
Unless they're
already unconscious.
Exactly.
My feeling is that DJK
subdued them first,
and I doubt it was using
some kind of stranglehold,
that would've left bruises.
Well, all the male vics
had THC in their system.
But even the most potent
cannabis would not
completely incapacitate
an able-bodied man.
So, maybe DJK was
using something stronger.
Something mixed in
with the dope.
GHB, diphenhydramine,
salvinorin A, fentanyl...?
Any of these in
the proper dosage
would render a subject
incapable of fighting back.
I thought if you could ID
it, it might be helpful.
I realize that this might
be a long shot, but I...
No, no, no.
We'll try.
I'll take this to Tox.
Okay.
Dr. Grissom...
I don't like feeling like
an accomplice to murder.
You told me you'd keep me
in the loop on this.
I intend to hold
you to that.
You don't have to.
I've arranged with the lab
to retain your services
as a special consultant.
I mean, we need all the
good brains we can find.
What do you think?
Oh, I'm in.
I have a theory of my own.
Tell me.
I think that
Haskell's accomplice
was someone
from your class.
Whose idea was it
to talk to Haskell?
Uh, one of my students
from last semester...
Dan Forester.
BRASS: Okay, so how
does a clean-cut,
good-natured PhD student
like yourself
end up writing letters
to a serial killer in jail?
Well, maximum security felons
aren't allowed
unsolicited phone calls.
You look like a smart kid.
Don't be a smart-ass.
Well, I was tired of
secondary sources.
I mean, there's only
so much you can learn
about the emotional
dynamics of psychopaths
from books
and psychologists,
retired police officers
reliving their past glories.
I wanted first-hand
material,
(over speaker): and that's what
I told Professor Langston.
He thought it was
an outstanding idea.
Is that true?
Unfortunately, yes.
BRASS:
Why did you pick Haskell?
Well, he was the only
one with a response.
We sent letters to
about half a dozen.
Hmm.
You recognize these people?
FORESTER:
Uh, no.
How about these people?
No.
No?
Okay, how about now?
Uh...
Nate Haskell somehow
managed to kill
at least three people
from inside his cell.
That means he has
an accomplice on the outside.
Me?
You can't
possibly believe
that I had anything
to do with this.
I'm not a suspect, am I?
BRASS:
Well, it was your
"outstanding idea."
Well, I may have
misrepresented that slightly.
Now, I don't know
whose idea
it was first,
but we were all having coffee
after class last term,
and several of us
drafted that letter.
I suppose, yeah,
I may have been the one
that personally took it
to Professor Langston,
but he redrafted it
and sent it to Haskell.
Who were the other students?
I need their names.
I don't know.
You don't know.
Sincerely,
I don't remember.
I...
Are these people really dead?
Courtesy of your pen pal.
So, what do we do next?
Do we interview everyone
that was in the class?
Well, even if we
can find them all,
there must be 50 students.
I don't think Maureen Masters
has that kind of time.
GRISSOM:
We have to figure out
who Haskell
was communicating with.
Maybe we can see
for ourselves.
GRISSOM:
Ever had the feeling
you were being watched?
Even in a crowded room, someone
making eye contact with you,
just for a second,
triggers a powerful response.
It's the brain filtering through
a mass of visual information,
telling you what's important.
WILLOWS:
Yeah...
like which predator
wants to eat you.
If Haskell was communicating
with someone in this class,
I'm betting that they made
eye contact
with each other.
More than once.
Are we going to try to match
eye lines with the students?
LANGSTON:
The University wouldn't allow
the students' side
to be recorded
for liability
and security reasons.
Okay-- there.
We thought he said
this to Mrs. Steiner.
He's clearly talking
to his accomplice.
Joel was the first.
Joel lives in the perfect place,
the place where it all began.
If I could get
out of here, believe me,
I would bring him some company.
Pretty clear now what
Haskell meant by that.
I'll loop it.
Joel was the first.
Joel lives in the perfect place,
the place where it all began.
And if I could get out of here,
believe me,
I would bring him some company.
If I could get out of here,
believe me,
I would bring him
some company.
GRISSOM:
Mrs. Steiner was
standing right there.
It's hard to tell
who he's really talking to.
SANDERS:
Anything else he say stand out?
Yes, um...
Try two-and-half minutes in.
Someone asked
how he selected his victims.
Did you ever buy a car?
You go down to the showroom,
you're pretty sure
you're going to get one,
but why the red one,
why not the blue one?
Nobody knows, but just one
of them speaks to you,
and... that's the one
you gotta have.
Nobody knows, but just one
of them speaks to you,
and.... that's the one
you gotta have.
He's looking right here.
Dan Forester.
Brass already interviewed him.
We don't think
he's our guy.
You know, if you're already
a serial killer's accomplice,
why take a class
about serial killing?
SANDERS:
Maybe because he screwed up
with Ian and Justine.
Big time.
SANDERS:
Did anyone ask Haskell
for any pointers?
Um...
Try four hours, 23 minutes in.
Someone asked him
how he was able to manage
to control his victims.
You have to give them hope.
If you bring a human being
to the brink of death,
and then you offer a chance--
no matter how small a chance--
to survive...
they'll grab it.
And they'll thank you for it.
And then you can do
whatever you want.
And believe me...
I did.
Thomas Donover.
Let's see if we can find Thomas.
(knocking loudly)
Hallie Donover?
Yes.
Where's your husband?
He ain't in there.
He-He... He's gone...
He's gone camping.
Where?
Um, Mount Charleston.
He goes to Red Rock Canyon,
different places, I don't know.
OFFICER:
All clear.
What's going on?
BRASS:
Where's your husband work?
Right now, kind
of nowhere.
Hm.
No, sir, but he's
in construction.
You know, these day's
the city's pretty dead.
But he's going back to school.
Yeah, we know that.
So you have absolutely no idea
where your husband is?
No, sir. No.
Tom goes camping a lot,
and he doesn't always tell me
where he's going.
I don't ask, so...
You always keep tabs
on your wife?
Yeah.
That's why I'm divorced.
Everybody take a room.
We're looking for anything
that tells us
where Tom Donover could be.
(camera shutter clicking)
Shoe tread's a match
to Tolliver's house
and Justine in the desert.
This is definitely our guy.
His browser history is clean.
The laptop is filled
with encrypted files.
I'm going to get it
back to the lab.
But this guy knows
how to cover his tracks.
BRASS:
Do you have
your cell phone on you?
Why?
Let's get it on;
let's call your husband up.
We need to
talk to him.
Yeah, you're welcome
to try it, if you like.
Tom turns his cell phone off
when he's camping.
He likes his alone time, so...
HASKELL:
You have to give them hope.
If you bring a human being
to the brink of death,
and then you offer a chance--
no matter how small a chance--
to survive, they'll grab it.
And they'll thank you for it.
And then you can do
whatever you want.
Please.
Just don't kill me.
I'm going to give you
a little rest.
No, don't!
You can relax.
You act like I'm going
to turn you into
the Joker or something.
(blades scraping)
No! No!
The only way
through that door
is to break it down.
I've locked us both
in here on purpose.
There are a few
windows around.
You could probably try those,
but that would be dangerous,
because I would shoot you
in the back of the head.
Um... uh...
I'm sorry.
It won't happen again.
The only way out
of here alone is dead.
The only way out of
here alive is with me.
Now, if you behave,
you do what I say,
and you make me happy...
you'll get out
of here just fine.
I'll make you happy.
I'll do whatever it takes.
Good.
Now, when we do leave,
I can't be seen with
you looking like this.
You need to make
yourself presentable.
Well, this sure
feels familiar.
You, me, a serial killer...
Who's he?
Dr. Ray Langston.
He's an expert
on the Dick and Jane killer
and he's a consultant
on the case.
We usually don't need
a consultant.
When the team gets
a case like this,
we go into hyperdrive.
It's why we get up
in the morning.
I can't imagine
my life without it.
And you are?
David Hodges. Trace.
Pleasure
to meet you.
Likewise.
So the red flags
are the original DJK
body dumps?
LANGSTON:
Correct.
The green ones
are Tom Donover's?
That's correct.
What are the white flags?
The last places the victims
were seen alive.
They were all abducted
in Arizona, Nevada
and California.
But the male bodies
were all found
here in Nevada.
You know, Joel Steiner
was last seen
at the Desert Rose Arena.
His body was found
40 miles away
just off the 215.
Couple number two
was last seen
in Bullhead, Arizona.
And the male body
was found
just off the 93.
He dumped the
male bodies
like... like they were trash,
like he wasn't really
interested in them.
GRISSOM:
Maybe he dumped them
where it was convenient--
on the road to somewhere else.
LANGSTON:
Lake Mead?
The only problem is Lake Mead
has 550 miles of shoreline.
I can cut that in half.
Greg found Didymodon nevadensis
on the bottom
of Tom Donover's sneaker.
That moss only grows
on the north side of Lake Mead.
This is what we live for.
♪ ♪
Hey, I was
checking the attic.
A lot of dust-- but a box
was recently disturbed
with a bunch of
VHS tapes in it.
DVD player,
stacks of DVDs.
No VCR.
I'm listening.
Well, Gerald Tolliver had a VCR
at his house, but no tapes.
And we know he took souvenirs.
I found concert ticket stubs
from the summer of '97.
This tape was made
about the same time.
I want to get this
back to the lab.
You look exhausted-- why don't
you let me take care of that.
No, no, no.
I'm fine.
I'll push through it.
It's just...
It feels like Grissom's
last big game, you know.
I want to win it for him.
BRASS:
Recognize this guy?
How about him?
That's uh...
that's Gerry Tolliver.
He's an old friend of
Tom's from Reno, I think.
Right.
Kind of friend always
putting the arm on you for money
when you're doing okay,
you know?
Uh-huh.
He's a sleazy guy.
No, what he is,
is he's dead.
He's dead;
so's that guy--
they're both dead.
So's this guy
and this guy...
and all these guys here.
They're all dead.
See, your husband's a murderer.
Where is he?
Do yourself a favor,
tell me--
where is he?!
But he made me promise
not to tell.
(phone ringing)
Tox.
Hey, Henry, it's Catherine.
Grissom said that you were
testing tissue samples
from the DJK victims
for the presence
of some incapacitating agent?
Yes. Actually I just finished.
Dr. Langston was right.
They all showed
high levels of...
Salvinia divinorum?
Usually Grissom does that.
Are you bucking
for a promotion?
Yes or no, Henry.
Sorry.
It's an intense hallucinogenic.
It'll knock you on your ass
for 15 to 30 minutes.
Mandy, it's Catherine.
The print I just sent through,
it's priority one.
We're looking for anyone who
might lead us to Tom Donover.
If you get a hit,
get it to Brass ASAP.
OFFICER:
2-0-3-Charlie,
this is 3-David-34
coming up on a pedestrian
fitting your description.
3-David-34,
that's him on the left.
Let's grab him.
(siren whoops,
tires screech)
Control, this is 3-David-34
in foot pursuit of one male
Caucasian, east on Fremont.
Requesting backup.
(siren whoops)
(siren whoops
intermittently)
(heavy sigh)
Oh, man.
ANDREWS:
It appears that the drug dealer
was pretty heavy
into his own inventory.
His tox was positive for THC
and opiates.
Fresh red
around the needle marks,
and they were oozing
when he was brought in.
This guy shot up
less than 24 hours ago.
Did you check
his urine?
Yes. Urine-heroin levels were
3,000 nanograms
per milliliter.
The half-life of heroin
in the system is 24 hours.
So, when Jeffrey
Masters was murdered,
and Maureen was
kidnapped, he had to have
at least twice
that amount in him.
He wouldn't have been able
to stand up,
let alone help.
Which makes him
another dead end.
Guys.
You gotta see this.
Oh, my God! That was awesome!
I cannot believe you got
those tickets, baby!
MAN: Of course I got them.
Thank you, thank you,
for our almost-getting-
married present.
STOKES: Got this video
from Tom Donover's attic.
That's Joel Steiner
and his fiancée Tiffany Cohen.
DJK's first victims.
11 years ago.
The night they disappeared.
STOKES:
Right.
WILLOWS:
That's Tom Donover...
and Gerald Tolliver.
(talking indistinctly
and laughing)
I think I got something that'll
keep the party going over here.
And the "something" is probably
a joint laced with Salvia.
Yeah. Gerald likes souvenirs.
I'm guessing that Tom
probably grabbed this videotape
after he killed him.
Could be why
he killed him.
Keep watching.
(woman shuddering
in fear)
(clattering)
(woman screaming)
I'll do whatever you say.
I know you will.
WILLOWS:
That's Nate Haskell.
(woman screams)
STOKES:
That's all there is.
We got a better view
of the house?
We know that Tom
was continuing in DJK's work.
It would make sense
that he would
carry it out
in the same place.
Certain places hold
a special power
for some people--
Stonehenge, the pyramids.
That house could have the same
kind of power for Tom.
Could be his sacred ground.
His wife said that
he went camping a lot.
Bet that's
his favorite spot.
Mm.
STOKES:
That's as good as it gets.
We checked
Nate Haskell
and Tom Donover
for property titles.
Neither one of them owns
anything in Lake Mead.
Maybe the house belonged
to one of their relatives.
Well, that could take you
forever to run that down.
Have Archie pull
stills of the house.
Get them to every local
unit in the area;
have them check
with real
estate offices;
see if anybody
can recognize it.
Recognize what?
A house with a window in it?
Maureen Masters is
running out of time,
and the only person
who can get us
to where she is
is Nate Haskell.
This is the most fun
Haskell's had in a decade.
He's not going to help us.
It's a waste of time.
What we're doing now
is a waste of time.
...'cause when
I took those women,
they stopped being
somebody's sister
or daughter or fiancée.
They became what
I wanted them to be.
(blade scrapes)
I don't want to die.
It could just be
our little secret, and I won't
say anything, I promise.
Don't do this!
Oh, God... no!
(gasping, screaming)
It's a shame to hide that face
behind this hair.
I don't like it.
Uh... um...
What is that?
What are you doing?
I'm going
to finish your haircut.
Marco...
You're supposed to say "Polo."
Strange time to be stargazing,
don't you think?
Ansel Adams
often forgot
when he took
his photographs,
so a bunch of
astronomers tried
to figure it out
using the image itself.
By referencing
the moon's position
in relationship to known
landmarks and lunar
azimuth tables,
they were able to determine
the date and time
the photo was taken.
I thought we could
reverse the science.
We know
when this was made.
Maybe the moon
can tell us where.
Forensic astronomy?
I will never forget
the things you've taught me.
You're the best student
I ever had, Nick.
Let's see
if we can figure this out.
(wand beeps)
(lock buzzes)
(metallic clanging)
(lock buzzes in distance)
(chains rattling,
footsteps approaching)
Professor Langston,
how good to see you.
What brings you here?
I came...
to gloat.
Please.
Come in, Nate.
We got these from a videotape
of one of your kills.
It's hard to
believe, isn't it?
Now, in all fairness,
you did say that
only dummies take souvenirs,
and Gerald Tolliver
was a pretty dumb guy.
Maybe that's why
Tom Donover killed him.
I've been thinking that
maybe that's the reason
Tom Donover decided to follow
in your footsteps,
and carry on with the work.
Anyway, none of that
really matters now,
because, as you can see,
we found your house
in Lake Mead,
and...
we have Tom.
and the girl.
She's alive.
Then what do you
need me for?
Closure.
You once told me that you'd been
thinking about it a lot.
Well, I've been
thinking about it, too.
I need you to tell us
where the girls' bodies
are buried, Nate.
Us?
So you're working
with that cop now?
We're gonna find
them eventually.
You know that.
We'll dig, we'll
dredge the lake,
we'll tear that
house of yours down
to the studs,
if we have to.
Now why don't you
save us the trouble?
Tell me what I need to know.
Look, maybe I can get something
out of it for you.
Like what, you're gonna reduce
two consecutive life terms
down to one?
Like, maybe I can
guarantee that this
isn't the last
conversation you'll have
with someone who isn't
shoving your food
through a hole in the door.
I promise you, Nate,
you don't tell me what
I need to know...
...the only person
who will hear the sound
of your voice ever again...
is going to be you.
You follow the fence
in the backyard.
To where?
To where, what?
There is no fence
in the backyard.
You thought
you could make me slip up
and give you something you want.
You thought you could
get inside my head.
Get him out of here.
A person has to do
what I've done to understand me.
You have no idea
what I've started.
I'm a teacher, too,
and my students are everywhere.
They're out there,
and I've cut
them free.
Get him out of here.
They're spreading the word.
By the time you find them,
it'll be too late,
because it'll be just more blood
on your hands.
She's already dead.
Get him out of here!
(taunting):
She's already dead.
(clattering)
GRISSOM:
That's it.
All right,
I can sharpen that up.
Gris, I just, uh,
want you to know how much
I appreciate you putting me
out in the field.
I'm sure there were
times you wish
I probably didn't.
Well... you changed my life.
STOKES:
Hey.
Got the moonrise tables
for Lake Mead.
It's not gonna get
much better than this.
So the moon is waning gibbous.
On June 15, 1997,
the moon rose at 7:46 p.m.
This video was recorded
at 10:41 p.m.
That's two hours and 55 minutes
after moonrise.
That puts it about 45 degrees
above the eastern horizon.
So that view
is west to east.
You know, those peaks
look like they're
roughly the same height.
I've got the topo map.
Look for two peaks
that are approximately
the same elevation
with that geographic
relationship.
(typing)
Arch Mountain,
3,335 feet,
and Hamblin Mountain, 3,310.
Fits the bill.
The moss on Tom Donover's shoes
can only be found
on the north side of the lake.
So...
draw a vector from the
center of those two peaks
to the north shore.
(typing)
Black Mesa.
(crying, whimpering)
(alarm blaring)
MAUREEN:
If you let me go
right now, I won't tell
anybody what happened.
You can't!
I did everything that you asked!
Sorry, I lied.
(screams)
OFFICER:
Move! Move! Move!
Guns down!
(whimpering)
Okay. You're okay.
You're all right,
Maureen. You okay?
OFFICER:
Clear!
There we go.
It's okay, it's okay.
(crying)
It's okay, Maureen.
Okay, look at me.
(over radio):
This is Sniper One.
I saw pink mist.
Do you copy?
This is Brass.
Suspect is down.
Code four.
(distant sirens wailing)
Copy that. We're coming in.
All right.
(quietly):
It's all right.
(slow, mournful theme plays)
(insects chirping)
(indistinct radio transmissions)
(camera shutter clicks)
(shutter clicks)
(shutters clicking)
(door opens)
(door closes)
A penny
for your thoughts?
He was sitting right there.
He was looking at me;
I was looking at him.
All I saw was...
another student.
That's all I saw.
I guess I'm tired
of getting fooled.
People lie, Professor.
The only thing we can count on
is the evidence.
Thank you for letting me help.
It was something I...
Well, it was something
I really needed to do.
Hey.
(sighs)
I don't know if you'd
have any interest...
but we have a job position
open at our lab.
You're serious?
(chuckles): I can't
imagine myself as a cop.
We're not cops.
We come from a wide
variety of backgrounds.
You're a medical doctor;
you're totally qualified.
It's an entry-level position.
The hours are terrible,
the pay's bad...
But money's not exactly
the object, is it?
I think you'd be a great help
to CSI.
And you might really enjoy it.
I'll think on it.
Okay.
So this is really real.
Fine.
Then, as your friend
and colleague,
I feel it is my obligation
to inform you what
a colossal mistake
you're making.
Hodges...
Guys like us don't
just get to hang it up.
This job is who we are.
We are the thin blue line
between order and chaos.
You take yourself
out of the equation,
who knows what's gonna happen?
That's
the Butterfly Effect.
You taught me that.
The bad guys will win more
if we don't have you.
Who is Watson
without Sherlock Holmes?
Watson was a genius
in his own right.
It's the right time
for me to go.
Okay.
(gentle, melancholy theme
playing)
♪ ♪
(insects chirping)
(chirping)
(shutter clicks)