Previously on CSI:
BROWN:
I don't remem
GRISSOM:
You were framed.
Gedda has a mole
in the department.
BROWN:
A cop.
GRISSOM:
Daniel Pritchard.
BROWN:
There's got to be somebody
higher up than that.
I just need to know that
you're through
running the streets
on your own looking
for bad guys.
BROWN:
There's one son of a bitch
still out there.
And I promise you
we're gonna get him.
That's what makes you
a great CSI.
WOMAN (over radio):
Central Dispatch. Go ahead.
McKEEN:
Control, this is One-David-Two.
I have a 444.
Officer down in the alley
north of the 800 block
of Rayson Street.
Requesting three backup units
and paramedics.
I am in pursuit of the suspect.
Suspect is a white male,
possibly armed,
wearing dark clothing,
traveling southbound
toward Malpassat Road.
WOMAN (over radio):
Officer down. Repeat.
Officer down.
Alley north of 800 block
of Rayson Street.
Units four-five-one,
four-five-six
and four-five-seven,
respond code three.
Officer down in the alley
north of Rayson Street.
All officers respond.
Warrick...
Oh, God!
Stay with me! Warrick...
It's Grissom.
I was first
on the scene.
Heard the shots.
I was in pursuit...
...of the suspect.
(gasps)
What?
No, Warrick, come on.
(gurgling)
Come on, Warrick!
Where are the paramedics?!
(gurgling)
Please.
Come on,
Warrick.
You got to fight.
I need you to fight now.
Fight for me, okay?
Give me an ETA
on the paramedics.
We need them here now.
(distant siren wailing)
No... No, come on.
(siren wailing)
No.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
♪ ♪
(sobbing)
McKEEN:
I was on my way to the diner.
I was going to tell
Warrick in person that
he could keep his job.
I parked my car
over there
just before 4:30.
I started to walk west
towards the diner.
I was in this area here
when I heard the shots.
(gunshots)
I saw a white adult male
running north down the alley
away from the vehicle.
I checked the vehicle--
observed CSI Brown bleeding
from a gunshot wound.
It appeared to me
he was dead.
So I went in pursuit
of the suspect
and called it in.
(engine starting)
(tires squealing)
He got into a dark
four-door sedan.
Late model.
Headed east on Malpassat Road.
I got a partial on the plate,
George-Robert-Victor.
George-Robert-Victor...
George-Robert-Victor-
Zebra-9-0-3?
That's Officer
Pritchard's car.
Was it a black
Chrysler 300?
Uh...
Was it Pritchard
you saw?
I only saw him for a second.
It was dark, but...
but who else could it be?
Okay.
Have you photoed
the body yet?
I haven't done anything.
Gil, how do you want
to handle this?
I want us to do this, Conrad.
I want Nick and
Catherine on the car.
Okay.
I feel sorry
for whoever did this.
(sighs)
Greg's coming back
from the airport.
I told him to go
straight to the lab.
We're going to have to take
your clothes to get processed.
I'll drive you.
I'm going to go
with Warrick.
Are you going to do the post?
No. I've asked the day shift ME
to handle this one.
I, uh...
need to do something.
You could, uh...
pick up Warrick's clothes
from the coroner.
Okay.
♪ ♪
(camera shutter clicks)
I got a bullet.
Looks like a .25.
.25 auto pistol on the floor.
And a .25 shell casing
right next to it.
Warrick's service weapon's
still in evidence.
He didn't carry a backup.
It's got to be
the murder weapon.
Leave the gun,
take the cannoli.
This was a hit.
Looks like Pritchard's been
taking lessons from Gedda.
There were at least
two shots fired.
One of which came
from inside the car.
Window was down.
I don't think the killer
was sitting there.
I think he was
standing out here.
He stuck the gun
through the open
window and fired.
If you're right, there should be
GSR on that headliner.
It's positive for lead.
Why was the window down?
I don't know.
It was a warm night.
If he wanted to get
some air, why not...
roll down his own window?
It's all hands on deck.
Right now, I'm pulling
everybody off
whatever it is they're doing.
Warrick Brown
is our only case, okay?
Officer Daniel Pritchard
is our suspect.
The assignments are
going to break down
generally like this--
some of you go to the
airport with photos.
If Pritchard tries
to get on a plane,
we grab him.
Now, Vegas highway patrol is
already setting up roadblocks
on all the roads leading
out of the city.
Now, we have the addresses
of his ex-wife, his family,
his friends,
all his known associates.
Most of you will be
following those leads.
Now look under
every rock.
If he's within
spitting distance,
I want him in custody
immediately.
(sniffles)
I caught the
first flight out.
He didn't want to go, Sara.
Tell me.
I was holding him.
God, I could feel his life.
I guess I felt
if I could...
hold him tight enough,
he'd be okay.
You know there is nowhere
in the world
that he would've rather been
at the end.
He loved you.
Yeah. I loved him.
Oh.
I'm so sorry.
It's so good we can all
be together.
I'm glad you're here.
(Stokes sniffles,
clears throat)
Look, maybe I can pick
up some of the slack.
I-I know I can't work the case,
but maybe I can make
some of the, uh... arrangements?
That'd be great.
I'll help you.
I'd appreciate that.
Since his grandmother passed,
we were
the only family he had.
He once told me he'd like
to be buried next to her.
I went to her funeral
with Warrick.
She's, uh, buried
at the Baptist cemetery
on Eastern.
We're going to need a... a key,
I guess, to his place.
WILLOWS:
I've got one.
I went over to his place
to get him some fresh clothes
when he was in custody.
STOKES:
Warrick was right about Gedda.
And he was right
about the department.
Let's finish this for him.
Hey, Jim.
Hey.
Look, uh, there's something
I need to get off my chest.
Okay.
I know that you and
Warrick were close.
And I don't want you to think
that I had it in for the guy.
Why would I think that, Jeff?
(chuckling):
I don't know.
Maybe I'm feeling guilty.
I thought Brown
was a bad apple.
I was certain that
he killed Gedda.
And I was wrong.
I know it's a little late
for apologies,
but I-I... I just wanted
to tell you.
Hey, we all have regrets.
I thought he killed Gedda, too.
You know what the last thing
I told him was?
No.
"I hope you remember
how lucky you are."
Some luck, huh?
(softly):
Yeah.
Thanks.
(sighs)
(gunshot)
(whirring)
(hissing)
♪ ♪
(neo-soul song playing on radio)
(door alarm dinging softly)
♪ ♪
Looks like he
never settled in.
Yeah.
SIDLE:
You know, after being
in so many victims' houses,
I never left my house
without making the bed
and taking out the trash, just
in case I didn't come home.
What about now?
Since I left Vegas,
I don't do that anymore.
See if you
can find a tie.
Yeah, I'm on it.
Sara?
Warrick has a son.
Did you know?
He never mentioned it.
At least not to me.
This is from his attorney.
"I have enclosed the DNA results
which were filed with the court,
"along with a copy
of your psych evaluation
"as ordered by the judge
in connection with our battle
to win custody of your son."
WILLOW:
Gun's a dead end.
No prints,
shooter wiped it down.
No recoverable DNA.
The serial number
was filed down,
but I got one on the grip.
Traced it back
to an armed robbery.
Pritchard was
the arresting officer.
The case was adjudicated,
and according to the log,
the gun was destroyed
last July.
Or not.
Pritchard stole it
from Central Property.
He had to have somebody on
the inside to fudge the records.
Maybe Gedda's got another
cop on the take.
But why would Pritchard
kill Warrick with a gun
that could be
traced back to him?
'Cause he didn't care.
He's in the wind.
I got something.
When I rolled up the
passenger side window,
I found a cluster of
impressions on the glass.
No ridge structure, so
they're not fingerprints.
They're... knuckle prints.
The stereo was turned down low.
The only fingerprints on the
volume knob are Warrick's.
And... if you've ever ridden
with him, you know he'd...
he'd make your eardrums bleed.
So...
volume turned down,
knuckle prints on the glass.
I think the killer
knocked on his window.
Well, Warrick would have never
rolled down his window
for Pritchard.
No. No, not after he'd just
killed Gedda
and he was trying
to frame Warrick for the murder.
Are we saying
it's not Pritchard?
I think we are.
McKeen.
He's the only eyewitness.
He's the one that placed
somebody that looked like
Pritchard in the alley.
He's the one that said the
suspect got into a vehicle
with a partial plate
that was a match to Pritchard's.
There's something
you need to see.
Has to wait.
We're going back to the alley.
It can't wait.
WOMAN:
So what makes you think
you'd be a good father?
You were raised
by your grandmother.
You never even knew
your biological father.
Which is exactly
why Eli needs to know his.
Look, the most important thing
you need to know
to raise a child
is how to give a child love.
And I've been loved.
Listen, I've always tried
to be a good man.
I've screwed up.
And when I have, there's always
been one man in my life
that set me straight.
I've learned a lot from him.
How to be fair.
How to forgive.
How to be inspired.
How to inspire others.
WOMAN:
That sounds
like a special person.
He is.
If I could've picked
my own father,
I'd have picked him.
We're ready
on this end.
GRISSOM:
McKeen said he was
about 20 feet west of the alley
when he heard the shots.
I'm there.
Let's do this.
Firing two.
(gunshot in distance)
(techno-pop plays)
(music stops)
Gil, what is it?
I just realized something--
there was music,
loud music coming from here.
We need to do this again.
Okay.
Come on back.
(loud techno-pop playing)
This is the volume level
from around
4:00 a.m. last night.
(loud music continues)
(shouts):
Go ahead, Nicky!
(music continues)
(gunshot)
(loud music continues)
Where are you?
I didn't hear any shots.
GRISSOM:
There's no way that McKeen
heard those shots.
So why did he say he did?
He also implied
that he saw Pritchard running
away from Warrick's car.
But he never said
it was Pritchard.
He led us to believe
that though.
(sighs)
You know, when I first came
to Vegas, over 20 years ago--
I haven't thought
about this in a while--
Jeff McKeen was
a detective then,
he invited us all up
to Mount Charleston to
his cabin, you know,
all the new guys.
Have a barbecue,
we'll cook some steaks,
have a few drinks, get
to know each other, you know?
And it was a nice place,
you know, but not too
nice for detective pay.
I mean, my radar's
already out
because I came from
Jersey, you know?
Guys...
took more than they gave.
And they made an art form,
how not to push it,
how not to make it showy,
you know.
Anyway, Jeff is sizing me
up, he's sniffing around,
he's telling me
great Vegas is,
how great it'd be
for my career.
But I let him know,
without busting his balls,
that I wasn't in the game,
I wasn't for sale.
And it's a good thing
I took a look around
up there at Mount Charleston,
because I never
got invited again.
No more
barbecues for me.
Hmm.
First witness at the scene
is the first suspect, right?
Right.
When I told Warrick
that Pritchard had framed him,
he said that Gedda's mole
had to be higher up
on the food chain.
If I were McKeen,
I would worry that Warrick
would never let it go.
It'd take more
than a beat cop to...
get over on that fat bastard.
I'd think it's got to be
somebody much higher up.
Let's say that McKeen saw
the interview video.
From the time that
Warrick left the PD
to the time that
Warrick got killed
was, like, an hour,
an hour and a half.
Is that enough time
to frame Pritchard?
For all we know,
Pritchard's not
even in Vegas.
Yeah, but if Pritchard
gets picked up somewhere else,
that gives him an alibi,
and McKeen is screwed.
Unless he knows
exactly where Pritchard is.
(lock beeps)
(baseball game
playing quietly on TV)
SPORTS ANNOUNCER:
But right now,
Los Angeles doesn't appear
to be in a helping mood.
Two-one count.
Jason delivers.
And there's a flare
to right field!
I can't believe Bobby Cox
is still managing.
What took you
so long?
I'm starving here.
I thought
I was clear with you.
About what?
Where's my food?
I told you
not to leave the room.
I didn't.
Scout's honor.
Why would I
leave the room?
I'm trying to leave the country.
You killed Brown
on the way out.
I get it.
But now you made a mess,
and I got to clean it up.
You think I killed Brown?
Come on, who else?
I just framed the guy--
why would I want him dead;
I wanted him in jail.
If I wanted him dead,
I would've shot him in Pigalle
instead of going through
all this freakin' crap.
The murder weapon was traced
back to one of your cases.
What case?
What are you talking about?
An armed robbery, I believe.
A .25.
Judge ordered it destroyed.
Oh.
That gun.
Look,
you can blame everything on me
when I'm in Mexico,
but I'm not in Mexico yet.
Killing you might
just be easier.
Then do it.
You shoot me here...
you're gonna have
a lot of explaining to do.
We going to Mexico, or what?
Gil, you take this
to the wrong judge,
and McKeen finds out
he's being investigated,
he'll stick a fork
in all of us.
I think that's a risk
we're all willing to take.
Well, all I'm saying is,
let's be smart about it.
Get more evidence.
We got what we got.
Knuckle prints on glass.
SANDERS:
Yeah, but knuckle prints
can't be individualized.
Even if we had exemplars,
we couldn't exclude Pritchard
or include McKeen.
All right, wh-what
about the murder weapon?
We printed it,
swabbed it for DNA.
It was wiped clean.
SIDLE:
The gun was evidence
in an armed robbery
case, right?
Was there any
ammo with it?
No.
So if McKeen lifted
the gun from Evidence,
he still had to load it.
WILLOWS:
No prints on the magazine.
What about the bullets?
ECKLIE:
A .25?
We've never gotten prints
off a cartridge that small.
♪ ♪
(sighs)
That is one tiny partial.
This may be f-four millimeters.
So we got one shot.
Yeah.
So don't screw it up, right?
Just enough for a comparison.
Here, compare it to
Pritchard's ten card.
It's not Pritchard's print.
Thank you, Mandy.
I need you to step out.
You're kidding, right?
No, I'm not.
(beeping)
BRASS:
No, Your Honor,
we all understand
the gravity of this situation.
But we're under
a lot of pressure,
and we have to move fast.
No, I didn't call the mayor--
I wanted to call you first.
He's not at home,
he's not at work,
and if we tip him off,
he'll run.
Judge... Judge...
I wouldn't call you
for a warrant if I wasn't sure.
STOKES:
I need you to pull
McKeen's phone records.
The undersheriff?
The last 24 hours,
all incoming calls.
(keyboard clacking)
STOKES:
Eliminate any
that are work-related,
from a PD number.
Three calls
from the same number.
Do a reverse look-up.
Whiskey Bend.
That's a place you
go to get lost.
He recognized McKeen.
Said he paid cash.
Wasn't staying here--
it was for his buddy.
"Do not disturb,"
give me a break.
Okay, go ahead.
Okay, come on.
It's clear, Captain.
Ice in the glass.
Wet towel.
We just missed him.
(country music plays
as radio stations change)
Pick a station and go with it.
You're driving me crazy.
It's all country.
I don't like country.
Yeah, well, at least
they're all in English.
(turns radio off)
Bienvenidos a Mexico,
my friend.
(long beep)
ID's confirmed.
Pritchard was in the room.
McKeen's had this room
for four days.
Pritchard's probably been
holed up here
ever since he killed Gedda.
Pritchard's his problem solver.
McKeen is protecting him.
STOKES:
Not anymore.
He killed Warrick.
Now he needs a fall guy.
Which makes Pritchard
a dead man.
Hey, Jeff, it's Jim Brass.
Well, looks like
Pritchard is our guy.
(phone rings)
All the evidence points
that way.
No, we're still looking.
I'll put an APB out on him
right away.
Keep you posted.
Yeah, Brass is talking
to him now.
Archie's working on
triangulating his cell.
BRASS:
Jeff, you're breaking up.
Are you in your car?
Yeah, sure, get some rest.
The press is gonna want
a statement from you
when we bring Pritchard
into custody.
STOKES:
McKeen's with Pritchard.
You have his 20?
Not yet.
(computer trills)
Got him.
He just moved from tower
eight to tower nine.
He's heading east
on Boulder Highway
about a mile west
of Highway 166.
Let me know
when you got him, Jim.
Got who?
Relax.
What happens when we get
to the state line?
Every cop in Nevada's
got a picture of my mug.
Don't worry about it.
I got a radio on.
Anything happens,
I'll hear about it.
I'm the undersheriff,
remember?
Nobody's gonna search my car.
In 12 hours,
you'll be sitting
on a beach in Mexico
sipping margaritas.
What's so freakin' funny?
What, are you gonna shoot me
going 80 miles an hour?
You think I'd let you get in
this car with a loaded gun?
(laughs)
Just sit back
and enjoy the ride.
Air One, this is Captain Brass.
Air One here.
Do you have a visual?
Affirmative. We're about
three miles behind him.
Stay on radio frequency
tac three.
In case he has his radio on,
we don't want to tip him off.
Copy that.
The green is Nick?
Yeah. He and Brass
are on his tail.
Air One at your six.
All ground units be advised
your next is in 90.
Hairpin right. Easy speed.
What's happening?
Nick, McKeen's vehicle
has stopped.
Where is he?
You should be right
on top of him.
Either McKeen threw
his phone out
or he pulled over.
He's just ahead of us.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
(tires screech)
(indistinct radio transmission)
Nick... cover him.
Control, this is Brass.
One-David-Two's vehicle
has broke through a guardrail
and gone into a gully
near mile marker 114.
Send additional backup
and paramedics.
Copy that. We'll notify backup
and EMS.
Got a .357 magnum.
McKeen carries a nine.
Looks like Pritchard's
got a broken neck.
No holes in him.
(helicopter blades whirring)
(grunting)
Control, this is Brass.
Pritchard is dead
and David-Two is on the run,
armed and dangerous,
possibly injured.
We're in pursuit.
Copy that, Captain Brass.
Will advise.
D2 is on the run.
Nick. Nick, this is Brass.
Come in.
Go to channel three.
Nick?
(lowers volume):
We're on channel three.
You copy?
(turns off radio)
(coughing)
(inhales sharply)
Stokes, thank God you're here.
I was trying
to bring Pritchard in.
Shut up.
He got
the drop on me.
He grabbed my gun.
I lost control.
I said shut up!
Air One, Air One, come in.
This is Brass.
Air One, Air One, do you copy?
Air one here.
There are four of us.
We spread out.
We're all heading due west.
CSI Stokes is in the lead.
We're looking for a visual
on McKeen.
Can you verify?
Stand by.
Air One confirm visual.
CSI Stokes has located
the suspect
and has him at gunpoint 300
yards due west of your position.
Copy that.
Okay, you want to know
why I did it?
Warrick had a big mouth,
and I had to shut it.
I tried to warn him,
but he was just too stupid
to listen.
(coughing)
You know, when I shot him,
he had a big...
smile on his face.
I told him
he could keep his job.
I didn't have
the heart to fire him.
Shut up.
(cries out in pain)
He was your friend.
What kind of friend are you?!
Shoot me, you son of a bitch!
(gunshot)
(helicopter blades whirring)
Nick?
McKeen has a gunshot wound
to the stomach.
(coughs)
He's lost a lot of blood.
We should get the medevac
chopper here ASAP.
What was that shot?
A miss.
Jeffrey McKeen,
you're under arrest
for the murder of Warrick Brown.
Yea, though I walk through the
valley of the shadow of death,
I will fear no evil
for thou art with me.
Thy rod and thy staff,
they comfort me.
Thou preparest a table
before me
in the presence of mine enemies.
Thou anointest my head with oil.
My cup runneth over.
Surely goodness and mercy
shall follow me
all the days of my life,
and I will dwell in the house
of the Lord forever.
Amen.
ALL:
As crime scene investigators,
we meet people on the worst day
of their lives.
They've just lost
a family member,
somebody they loved,
often in a horrible way.
A piece of their heart is gone
and will never be replaced.
The phrase we're trained
to offer them,
"I'm sorry for your loss,"
as we know now,
doesn't offer much.
Warrick Brown was a young boy
when his parents passed away.
Much too young to learn
that life can be
so tragically short.
But I think that it taught him
how precious life is,
and so he lived his life
to the fullest each day
as if it was his last day.
I was with Warrick
on his last day.
All the qualities that defined
him-- his tenaciousness,
his deep sense of loyalty,
his courage...
to risk his life
for what he knew was right--
all those traits were with him
on that last day.
Just before he died...
we were all having breakfast
together--
our team...
...his friends...
...his family.
And Warrick was...
he was...
I'm gonna miss him so much.