(woman singing upbeat
pop song in Korean)
♪ ♪
Hi!
(song continues over
lively conversation in Korean)
(meat sizzling)
♪ ♪
(gunshot, girl gasps)
(people screaming,
shouting)
(gunshot)
(people screaming)
(clinking)
(gunshot)
(speaking Korean)
(two gunshots,
panicked screams)
(screaming, shrieking)
Did you see
anything?
(speaking Korean)
Okay, hold on;
hold on.
Look at me.
I don't know.
Did you see this?
Did you hear anything?
You just ran over there?
(speaking Korean)
No.
Did you see it?
(scoffs)
PHILLIPS:
Three holes in the male,
two holes in the female.
(camera clicks)
Five holes, one casing.
But with all this foot traffic,
the other shells
could be anywhere.
There's no I.D. or anything
on the female.
But... we do have a big bulge
right here.
Got a license.
Vic's name is Sung Bang.
Apparently, his day started
a lot better than it ended.
Prison release forms.
Spent six months in Jean
for repeat DUIs.
Walked out today.
It's weird--
the female vic
doesn't even
have a lint in her pocket.
This guy, it's an I.D. orgasm.
Overload.
I meant I.D. overload.
Must have been at least
a dozen people
within ten feet of the victims.
Yeah, well, I don't think
we're gonna learn much
from this crowd.
Tells me
we're probably
looking for a Korean.
If the killer
had been black,
white or brown, we'd
already have height, weight
hair and tattoos.
Smells like a gang hit.
I found a pair
of kid's sunglasses
with blood spatter
all over them.
Prints and smudges.
He must have been standing
right here.
He would have seen everything.
If it was me,
I would've run.
The killer could've taken him.
Either way, he's missing,
and we have to find this child
before something happens to him.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
The incident shattered
the calm in Koreatown,
where partiers were celebrating
until the violence broke out.
Officers have been unable
to identify the female victim,
and that's holding things up.
The investigators
say they're hampered
by a language barrier,
and their job is also
complicated by the fact
that many
of the partygoers distrust
or even fear the police.
(man speaking Korean)
(indistinct, overlapping
crowd chatter)
WOMAN:
I don't know, I don't know.
MAN:
That is all I know.
All right, thanks.
You're free to go.
Next.
(man speaking Korean)
How's it going?
Sir, how close were
you standing to the victims?
If you speak English, now would
be a good time to start.
If it's gonna get me out
of here quicker,
I'll be William freakin'
Shakespeare.
From what I understand,
the Korean culture's
very big on respect.
(weary sigh):
Yeah.
So how about giving
maximum respect
to the two people
who were murdered
and tell me what you saw?
(wry laugh)
You know, I like
your style.
Yeah, I give you all
the forensics you want--
a Q-Tip in the mouth;
you can have my ass
prints if you want,
but don't ask me
what happened.
It's not my business,
so I shouldn't be
flapping about it.
So you think
that's real, too,
letting murderers
run free?
We know it's
a gang thing.
You don't need me
then, do you?
ROBBINS:
Male C.O.D. is exsanguinations
due to multiple GSWs.
Same with the female.
Exsanguinations due
to multiple GSWs.
The bullets in the male
were cannelured.
He was shot with a revolver.
Female was shot twice
with a semiautomatic.
Two guns, two killers?
Or one killer, two guns,
gangsta style.
Well, his shots seem
fairly straight and level,
but it looks like
the bullets entered her
at a much steeper trajectory.
Yeah, approximately
20 degrees up,
front to back.
So, what,
He gets gunned down,
she's terrified,
tries to flee
and then falls down
as she's shot,
exaggerating the trajectory?
Could be a drug thing.
She's got the needle marks
to prove it.
I sent blood and tissue samples
to Tox.
GRISSOM:
This is an odd-looking scar...
on both eyelids.
Could be cosmetic
surgery.
She's a little young
for a facelift,
don't you think?
GRISSOM:
Attractive girl on drugs,
on the street with an ex-con
and no I.D.
Sounds like a street hooker.
Yeah, but not someone
who pays for plastic surgery.
ROBBINS: Well, maybe it's
a business investment,
courtesy of her pimp.
ADAMS: So he's unmarried
with no children
and apart from the DUIs,
clean record.
No known gang affiliation.
He was at Dempsey's
Department Store
a half an hour
before he was shot
and was released from Jean
an hour before that.
Jean is a 45-minute bus ride
to Vegas.
So this guy gets
out of jail
and in under the running time
of The Godfather, he's dead.
Well, a lot of people die
at the end of Godfather.
Riley ran all the bullets
and casings from the scene.
Gun is clean.
Any I.D.
on the female?
No, but she had
a blepharoplasty.
Asian eyelid procedure
fairly common in Korea
and apparently catching
on here, too.
Brass passed the vic's photo
around Makeover Town.
Makeover Town? L.A.?
No, it's a block
of plastic surgeons
in our Koreatown.
Our Koreatown
is a block.
Maybe that's why
he was able to
find a doctor.
MAN:
I didn't know her name.
BRASS:
You put a woman
under anesthesia,
you cut her open,
and you don't know her name?
Sir, she was not
an ordinary client.
So they forced you
at gunpoint
to perform eye surgery on women
in a procedure that Westernizes
their appearance,
resulting in an effect
called "round eyes"?
Ever since Jackie Chan
got his eyes done,
the surgery's
been very popular.
And then they just left?
Yes, after they forced me
to agree to give them
15% of my profits.
I'm gonna need names, Doctor.
They didn't leave
any business cards.
I think they belong
to a group called The KD.
The Kkangpae Dragons.
I never heard of.
And there isn't much in Vegas
I haven't heard of.
A new outfit.
They don't have any tattoos
or drive lowriders
or spray graffiti.
They don't even sell drugs.
So what do they do,
just force plastic surgeons
to operate on their prostitutes?
Extortion is their trade.
They just take.
Right.
And they take from their own
because they know their own.
They know that their own
won't turn them in.
Well, you're very courageous
to come in and report this.
Why won't others come forward?
You want a bunch of immigrants
to come to the police?
Why don't you protect them
the way you protect the tourists
on the Strip and the big shots
in Anthem and Seven Hills?
Save the stump speech
for when you run for mayor.
I'll vote for you.
Are you still paying extortion?
No, not anymore.
Six months ago,
I joined an HMO.
And they installed
several security cameras
around my building.
The Dragons don't like
to be seen.
They prefer to be invisible.
CAVALIERE:
Excuse me, Captain.
We got a surveillance hit.
CSI said there were
no surveillance cameras
at the crime scene.
Hit didn't come from CSI.
One of my video analysts
caught news of your double
in Koreatown
and recognized the male vic
while scanning
one of our video feeds.
from a unrelated
shoplifting investigation.
Wow.
Video analyst?
Yeah, why?
What do you call them?
(keypad beeping)
"Forensic Services."
(Willows chuckles)
Must have a hell of
a shoplifting problem.
We're in a
high crime area,
and this facility represents
a corporate mission
to prevent theft, fraud and
personal injury in our stores.
BRASS:
You're not outsourcing that
to China, too, are you?
All right, Artie, bring it up.
You know, what's your solve rate
on property crime these days?
One in ten? One in 20?
Hey, you didn't tell me
we were going to have a quiz.
You know, we nail 93%.
Nationwide, Dempsey's
Forensic Services
has put three fugitives
behind bars; we're going to be
in 300 locations by next summer.
BRASS:
Hey, look, you know,
if it, uh, if it's legal
and makes my job easier,
I'm all for it.
There's our guy.
Sung Bang.
Archie...
Artie... could you enhance
the image of the boy?
(typing,
then computer trills)
WILLOWS:
Wow.
You've got some
really great cameras.
Good as any on the Strip.
In fact, our crime lab
is better equipped
than most in the country.
Now, that's a crime.
WILLOWS: We're going
to need that toy.
Mindy?
The toy
and the lift.
We didn't bother running it
through AFIS.
He's obviously
under 14 years old,
so he wouldn't be
in the database.
We, uh, licensed it
from the Feds.
Loupe, please.
Thank you.
This is the same boy.
Is that the vic's kid?
BRASS: From
everything we know,
Sung Bang
had no children.
He sure looks like
the happy dad to me.
BRASS:
This is the last footage
of Sung Bang leaving
Dempsey's Department Store.
Who's the kid?
The boy's name
is Park Bang.
Sung is his uncle.
You positive?
I've been Park's
CPS investigator
for over two years.
I know what
he looks like.
Okay. Who's this?
Uh...
Here. Come over
in the light.
(switch clicks)
Her name's Kora Sil.
Park's mother.
Poor boy has lost everyone.
What about his father?
Dead.
He was supposedly some big
gangster here and in Korea.
The Kkangpae Dragons?
I don't know.
I never actually met him.
He died of AIDS a few years ago.
That's when Sung took
over the father role.
In fact, it was Sung
who notified us
about Kora's drug use.
He loved that boy.
You know, CSI did
a tox panel on the mother.
Came back positive
for HIV.
What's the boy's status?
Do you know?
He's also
HIV positive.
Park's on a very strict
drug regimen,
so we need
to find him immediately.
Well, I mean, the drug regimen
may be the least
of his problems.
I think the gang
killed his uncle
and his mother, he saw it;
he may already be dead.
(sighs heavily)
WILLOWS:
Our girl has done time.
Three months for prostitution.
Three months?
That's pretty
harsh for Vegas.
Prostitution with HIV.
That's like pointing a gun
and pulling the trigger.
Any last-knowns?
Over a dozen.
She's moved around a lot.
PD's running them down.
Kora Sil's Friend Agenda page.
Single... Born in Seoul...
Likes rap music...
doesn't drink or smoke...
But likes to shoot drugs
and turn tricks with HIV.
Well, it's always
something, isn't it?
Let's check the IP address
of the last comment
she posted.
Yeah.
JOHNSON:
Well, looks like she's using
this page to score drugs.
Welcome to the dark side
of social networking.
JOHNSON:
Okay. The IP address... is...
What a surprise.
Koreatown.
MAN:
Of course I know Kora.
But why do you ask?
We're looking for her son.
Why would Park be here?
We're going
to take a look around.
That's a field I.D.
We photograph every person
of interest in a case.
It's standard procedure.
I have no reason
to lie to you.
I know Park and Kora.
They come over
to use my computer.
Mr. Pan, you don't strike me
as the kind of guy
who would have nefarious
individuals
in your home.
Captain Brass,
may we talk outside?
No.
(speaking Korean)
I've known Park's father
his entire life.
We came over
from Korea together,
but we went
in different directions.
But I still treat his family
as my own, and
if they want to use my computer,
I let them.
There's nothing
wrong with that.
No, I'll tell you
what's wrong.
The young woman
Kora is dead,
and her son Park
is missing.
Now, this
crime happened
about a block
from where you live.
I can't believe you
haven't heard about this.
I had no idea.
I was in Phoenix on business.
Oh. Phoenix, huh?
House is clear, sir.
Thanks, Kwan.
Do you have any idea
where Park might be?
No. No. I don't know.
I... I'm truly sorry.
Okay, look.
Here's my card.
Call me if you hear
or see anything
that may be
useful to me.
Thanks for your cooperation.
Sorry for the inconvenience.
Park Bang left
Dempsey's Department Store
at around 4:00 p.m. with
a shopping bag full of stuff
his uncle just bought him.
The shooting occurred here
about a half
an hour later,
and that's
only a couple
blocks away;
the uncle doesn't have
a car, so...
they probably walked,
using one of these routes.
What's on that receipt again?
Uh... T-shirt,
novelty sunglasses, Crunchies,
Double Fudge, Fruit Funzies
and Nutty Cups.
Nothing says
"I love you"
like processed sugar.
The only thing we found at
the scene were the sunglasses.
Where's the rest of it?
STOKES:
Okay, we're digging
through trash.
More specifically, anything
from Dempsey's Department Store.
Clothing tags,
assorted candy items.
Okay? Check the cans,
the Dumpsters,
sewage drains,
Port-a-Potties.
Okay, be thorough.
Yeah, let's do it.
Remember to check
along the fences, under cars.
These are places
where evidence can hide.
Use your imagination.
STOKES:
I know this seems
like a simple trash hunt,
but it could make
or break the case.
The sooner
we find the stuff,
the sooner we're
going to find this kid,
so don't be afraid
to get your hands dirty.
Hodges.
Come on, man.
I know you're not nuts
about the field,
but I didn't bring you
all the way out here
to just stand around.
You know what I mean?
Can I see you for a second?
What?
You can work hard
or you can work smart.
Can I go now?
(knocking on door)
LVPD! Open up!
(door bursts open)
(people chattering in Korean
on TV)
(yelling in Korean)
Sorry to barge in on you, ma'am.
We're just looking
for a missing little boy.
ADAMS:
Gun!
She's got a gun!
Nick, she's
got a gun.
What are you doing?
Put that thing down.
(yelling in Korean)
Lady, put that
gun down right now.
Put the gun down
or we'll shoot.
No, we won't. Relax.
Ma'am, we're looking
for a little boy
who's in really
big trouble.
His name
is Park Bang.
(yelling in Korean)
She doesn't understand.
Where the hell
is the translator?!
She understands just fine.
Don't you?
Park Bang.
We just want to help him.
She doesn't understand.
(yelling in Korean)
Drop the gun! Nick!
(speaking Korean)
(boy speaking Korean)
Riley. What's the deal?
(sighs)
Kid's pretty weak.
I asked him if he remembered
anything about the shootings,
but he wouldn't
even open his mouth.
Where is his
CPS investigator?
En route.
You interviewed a minor
without an advocate present?
Not officially.
Those regulations are there
to protect the welfare
of the child.
Don't ever do that again.
Look, I didn't
do anything wrong.
I was just trying
to help our case.
Maybe you should
go back to the lab.
Happy to.
Okay, let's get
that shirt off.
Sit up
a little bit. Okay.
Good job.
GRISSOM:
Excuse me, Doctor.
I'm with the Las Vegas
Police Department.
Why does this boy
have a gastric tube?
Might be an issue
with feeding.
Trouble swallowing,
that sort of thing.
We'll do a chest X-ray
to be sure.
What about this
skin condition?
Yeah, probably a side effect
of his HIV meds.
CPS sent
his records over.
He's on a pretty
severe regimen.
Why is there dried blood
around the feeding tube?
He could have caught it
on something--
tried to pull it out.
Hey, kiddo,
I'm going to take
good care of you,
don't worry.
(raspy breathing)
(three gunshots)
(woman speaking Korean)
OFFICER KWAN:
She says that she was just
watering her garden
when she heard gunshots
and people started running.
(crowd screaming,
shrieking)
(speaking Korean)
She took the boy in
and fed him and let him
play with some old toys.
(speaking Korean)
And then the boy
went to sleep
like little boys should.
(speaking Korean)
She says she was just trying
to protect the boy.
Why'd you pull a gun
on the police?
(translating in Korean)
(replies in Korean)
She says that where
she comes from,
people would take care
of their neighbors.
You should've turned him
over to us right away.
(Kwan translating)
(replies in Korean)
She asks why?
So you can cut another
hole in his stomach?
BRASS:
Okay, then,
how about these guys?
Any of these guys
look familiar, huh?
Come on, Park,
you can talk to me.
(Chin speaking Korean)
These people are here
to help you.
If you see one
that hurt your mommy or uncle,
all you have to do is point,
okay, pal?
Huh?
Don't want to do it now?
Okay, I'll tell you what,
we'll do it another time.
Take care, buddy.
I'm going to put some
police officers at the door.
I don't think the KD
will try anything here,
but you never know.
Are you finished?
I still got to
collect biologicals.
I'll see you later.
He understands
English, right?
Mm-hmm.
Hi, Park.
My name is Gil.
I'm not a doctor,
I'm not a policeman.
I'm kind of a...
What am I? I don't know.
I mostly do a lot of thinking.
But I do need to look
under your fingernails.
I'm not going to grab your hand.
I'll just wait here
until you want to
give it to me, okay?
But I promise you
it won't hurt.
Thank you.
Hello, Mrs. Chin.
I got here as fast
as I could.
Dr. Eisling, this is Mr. Grissom
from the crime lab.
How do you do?
Hey, Park.
We're, uh... we're going
to have to give him
his medication here.
(whines in protest)
He doesn't seem to want it.
Well, that's why we gave him
a gastric tube.
Okay, now come on...
No! (yelling in Korean)
Okay, come on...
Can you hold him, please?
I know, I know...
Okay, I know, I know.
(yelling in Korean)
Come hold him.
Just take his arm.
I know. I know.
(screaming)
Stay still,
Stay still.
(Park screaming)
EISLING:
Okay. All right.
So Park was wearing the white
T-shirt during the shooting.
He changed into the blue one
at the old woman's house.
Threw the white one away.
Makes sense. Had his mother
and his uncle's blood
all over him.
(two gunshots,
blood splattering)
Park Bang's
tox report.
Most adult cancer patients
don't have this many drugs
in their systems.
But an eight-year-old...?
Never seen
anything like it.
Most of the drugs
on that list
are meant to stop cell
development, stop bone marrow
from producing blood,
stop proteins from assembling.
If he continues
on this regimen,
by the time he's 15,
he won't even have
the physical development
of a ten-year-old.
Does he actually have AIDS?
No, not yet.
He's HIV-positive.
If you ask me, he's being
badly overmedicated.
Zendrek has
an FDA black box label.
That's the strongest
warning there is.
Life-threatening side effects.
Some of the other drugs
aren't even on the market.
They're only being used
in clinical trials.
Maybe he's in one.
GRISSOM:
How does
a little kid
with a junkie mother
and gangster father
get on a clinical trial?
♪ ♪
ADAMS: Well, so much for
the upstanding businessman.
This guy's real name
is Jin Ming
and his mug shot was taken
when he was 18 years old
when he was caught stealing cars
with a street racing gang.
Now he's 30 and he hasn't
been busted since.
And Park had this guy's skin
under his fingernails?
Yeah.
So they must been fighting?
Possibly.
The thing is, that skin that was
under Park's nails--
it was gluteus maximus.
It's very similar
to the epidermal tissue
on the rest of the body,
but it's got far fewer
hair follicles.
So, in addition
to everything else,
this kid's been molested?
Well, maybe not.
Here.
Take a look at Jin's neck.
No tattoos.
He had a major makeover.
Yeah.
I went out a couple times
with a casino executive
who had some really
unusual scars.
And, long story short,
he told me that
he was very embarrassed
by some old tattoos that he had.
So he had them covered
with replicated skin.
From his butt?
I didn't ask.
But, you know,
if you're a street racer,
then it might be kind of cool
to flash a lot of ink.
But if you're
a Kkangpae Dragon...
It pays to be invisible.
(banging,
wood cracking)
I got left.
This basement's the only room
with anything in it.
The uni's were looking
for the kid, first time through.
It's probably why
they missed it.
This must be where
Park and his mother lived.
Why would this guy Jin
kill somebody
he let live in his house?
He's in a gang.
She's a druggie.
The possibilities
are endless.
CAVALIERE:
Yeah.
Look at this.
Scumbag's in the picture
with them.
(ticking)
(beeping)
Down!
(explosion)
(glass shattering,
debris clattering)
Officer down!
Clear the house
and call the paramedics!
SANDERS:
Detective Cavaliere's
going to be all right.
Minor injuries.
Bomb squad said the
explosive was a trip
wire booby trap.
Yeah, if Jin and the K D.
really wanted to hurt somebody,
they would've sent
a more powerful message.
So, I found an
ambulance chaser's card
on Kora Sil's desk.
I just got off the
phone with him.
He claims that Kora was
suing Park's doctor.
For what?
Money.
According to the lawyer,
the doctor paid Kora to put
Park on the clinical trial.
She wanted more.
How much was she getting?
25 a week.
She wanted 50.
♪ ♪
Hello, Doctor.
What are you doing here?
I'm here to give Park
his medication.
Oh, yeah. He needs to get it
every day, doesn't he?
Yes.
Or else the data's useless.
I suppose so.
GRISSOM:
Well, then what good
would it do
to continue to dose him
after he went missing
for two days?
These drugs are saving his life.
No, they're not.
I don't need to be
a medical doctor to see that.
No, what you're seeing
are side effects.
And there are side
effects to every drug.
Look, this is a legitimate
clinical trial, Mr. Grissom,
approved by a
formal committee...
Consisting of doctors
who are shareholders
in the pharmaceutical companies
that make the drugs.
Without these trials,
these kids get nothing.
And what do you get?
Kickbacks?
Your medical opinion
is irrelevant.
What I'm doing
is perfectly legal.
So, we're done here.
Excuse me.
You touch that kid,
and I will charge you
with reckless endangerment.
Child Services will back him up
on that.
So I think
you're done here.
We'll see about that.
(button clicks)
Park...
I need to ask you
a few questions.
You don't have to answer them,
if you don't want to, okay?
Do you know this man?
That's Jin.
Did you and your mother
live at his house?
Is that where
Uncle Sung found you?
Yeah.
(Park squeals happily)
(speaking Korean)
(groans)
(sighs)
(speaking Korean)
(breathes weakly)
Uncle Sung didn't like my tube.
(shouting in Korean)
PARK:
He fought with Mama.
(screams)
Then Jin came down.
(Park crying, Jin shouting)
Uncle Sung
saved me.
What happened after that?
I'm not gonna let Jin
or Dr. Eisling hurt you.
But that's why I need
to know what happened.
Jin and Mama found us.
(gunshot)
(shouting in Korean)
(two gunshots)
(shell casing clinks on ground)
Why would he want
to hurt your mother?
I guess he was just sick
of having us around.
(coughs)
(coughing)
I finally got a statement
from the kid.
He says that Jin
shot both his mother
and his Uncle
with two different guns.
BRASS:
Well, that's great.
Uh, that should be enough
to charge Jin when we find him.
I-I just got faxed
Sun Bang's prison record.
And there's something weird
on his personal release form.
Listen to this:
the guy left prison
with a nine millimeter.
They let him out of jail
with a gun?
Well, it's only a misdemeanor,
you know.
It's like a hotel; you get back
what you checked in.
So you can go out
and commit a felony.
Apparently.
Now, is there any chance
that Sung fired back?
No, we would have found extra
bullets or shells at the scene.
Well, maybe there's a bullet
lodged in Jin's body.
No sign of a third bleeder.
And if I understand the kid,
Sung never got a chance
to shoot back.
Okay, thanks. I'll work on this.
Yep.
He carried his gun
in his waistband.
Still doesn't
mean he used it.
And doesn't really
change Park's story.
How do we know Kora
wasn't packing?
The father of her
son was a gangster.
She was living
with a gangster.
I wouldn't put
it past her.
Well, let's see.
Most women's
clothes
don't have a place
to hide a gun.
That's, uh...
That's what
purses are for.
Maybe Kora didn't need
Jin to get her son back.
Maybe she took care
of it herself.
(panting)
(shouting in Korean)
(gunshot,
people screaming)
(grunts)
(gunshot)
You think they shot each other.
Why not?
There's motive,
the evidence suggests it.
Where are their guns?
Dead man with a gun
in the hood.
Gone in 60 seconds.
Jin skips town because
this family dispute uncovers
his once invisible gang.
He leaves the booby trap
because he's angry about it.
It's possible.
It's also possible
that Jin shot both vics.
Which is what the kid said.
And he was
the closest witness.
If your uncle and your mother
shot each other,
you would probably
blame the gangbanger, too.
Okay, pilgrim...
we'll settle this on the street.
If you need any water or
anything, you just let me know.
Okay.
Okay, Park, I know
you already told me
what-what happened,
but now I need you
to show me
what happened, okay?
Now, we're gonna pretend
that this is your mother,
this is your uncle,
and that's Jin.
Would you show me
where your uncle was standing
when the shooting began?
Where was your mother standing
Would you show me
where Jin was standing?
And where were you
standing?
Did your uncle have a gun?
Did your mother have a gun?
Did your mother fall down
before Jin shot her?
Did Jin fall down
before he shot your mother?
He's lying.
Well, the ferrotrace
doesn't confirm
that either of them had guns
at the time of the shooting.
But the trajectory...
Neither Kora nor Jin fell.
How do you explain
Kora's 20-degree entry?
Park,
could you show me
how Jin shot your mother?
It was like this:
Bang, bang!
Park, would you do that again?
But this time,
keep your arm out.
Bang, bang!
(shouting in Korean)
(shouting)
(grunts)
(speaking Korean)
(gunshot, blood splattering)
(another gunshot)
(shell casing clinks on ground)
(crowd screaming)
The kid shot his mother
for shooting his uncle.
So you think Jin
had nothing to do with it?
Not the shooting.
Well, it makes sense.
I mean, his uncle was trying
to protect him,
and his mother
was torturing him.
GRISSOM:
Park never controlled
anything in his life
till he fired that gun.
BRASS:
An HIV-positive eight-year-old.
No wonder
no one wanted to talk.
Juvi may be
the best thing for him.
He'll get the care
he needs there.
Yeah.
I'm sorry we solved this.
I really am.