It doesn't have to be this way.
Just listen to reason.
I have no use for reason...
puny human!
The Selbachian ship
is almost within range.
And this vessel shall be
the instrument of my revenge.
Turn your weapon systems
over to me now,
or I will kill one of your crew
every 2.5 Earth minutes,
beginning with the female.
Commander?
It's going to be all right.
(beeping, whirring)
(alarms blare)
(grunting)
(alarms cease)
COMPUTER: All stations secure
from general quarters.
A pleasure working
with you, Yeoman.
As always.
MAN: We're talking about a piece
of television history.
The actual Spaceforce microprobe
Commander Artemis Bishop used
to subdue the alien Gorth
in the season 2 finale
of Astro Quest.
And it can all be yours
for just $750.
750?
Do I look like an idiot to you?
(beeping)
(whirring)
(speaking alien language)
That's nice!
MAN (over P.A.):
Welcome, Whatifitconners.
A special encore presentation
of Astro Quest: Redux
will begin in Room 21-B
in just a few minutes.
(microprobe beeping)
Nice uniform.
Wendy?
You're Yeoman Malloy.
You have a microprobe.
(chuckles)
I can't believe this.
You're a Questor?
I think Astro Quest
is the greatest science
fiction show of all time.
I'm a Commander Bishop
fan myself.
Who isn't?
Why Malloy?
I loved her.
I mean, I know that she was
completely underwritten,
but she was the only
female biochemist on TV
and I liked her spunk.
Do you think that, um,
I got the collar right?
'Cause I think on the show
that it might've been
a little more, um, swoopy.
You... It looks perfect.
Thanks.
(indistinct announcement
over P.A.)
Can I see that?
(whirring)
Wow...
(giggling):
That's great.
Jihw-CHOK chom-CHEM
jag-eej BRYCE cichoki.
I don't speak Vellikon.
What did you say?
(woman screams)
(over P.A.): Security to Room
21-B immediately.
Oh, my God, Jon?
Security, 21-B
immediately...
Jon?!
We need medical personnel
in 21-B.
Jon?!
Medical personnel
in 21-B.
Jon? Jon? Wake up!
What is the matter with you?
Oh, my God. Speak to me!
Jon?
Excuse me. Excuse me.
Excuse me.
Wake up! Wake up!
Please, everyone stay calm
and stay back.
We're with the Crime Lab.
Ma'am, don't touch anything.
Don't...
Jon!
Please, come with me.
Jon.
Come with me.
(speed-dials)
Brass.
Yeah, it's Hodges.
Who?
From Trace.
We have a situation
at the Whatifitcon.
The Whatifit-what?
How'd you get this number?
I cloned Grissom's cell phone
on a work-related matter.
That's not important now.
We have a situation.
It's one of the exhibitors.
Could you be more specific?
He's dead, Jim.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you. ♪
(clamoring)
Jonathan Danson, 36,
from Chowchilla, California.
STOKES: 42 bucks and
a couple of credit cards.
So it probably
wasn't a robbery.
Bloody nose,
scratches on the face.
This guy's been
in a fight or something.
You know, if there
was a struggle
it'd be really hard to
tell on a set like this.
Liver temp was
89.7 degrees.
He probably died between
midnight and 3:00 a.m.
So, between then and now
there's probably been
a few thousand people
with access to this booth.
You're going to need
a lot of tape lifts.
And swabs.
(sighing):
Or...
I could run a vacuum cleaner
over the whole scene,
get exemplars
from all these folks
and keep you two knuckleheads
busy for the next few months.
How'd that be? Hmm?
Do me a favor:
beam yourselves back to the lab
and let us do our job, please.
Okay.
Thank you.
Nice outfit.
WOMAN:
I just can't believe it.
I mean, this-this project
was Jonathan's dream.
We were so close.
So close to what?
He spent five years
on this pilot.
It's a remake of the
original Astro Quest.
An executive from Paramount
approached us about it--
turning it into
a full-on series for the CW.
Oh, yeah, really?
No kidding.
"Produced by Jonathan Danson
and Melinda Carver."
So, do you have a financial
interest in the project?
Well, yeah, I financed it.
So, what happens to the rights
with Jonathan
out of the picture?
They revert to me, I guess.
What are you getting at?
Exactly what you think I am.
HODGES:
A guy in a red shirt
dies at the beginning
of most Astro Quest episodes.
I remember.
Come on in.
Thanks.
Take a look.
Perimortem bruise
on the neck.
And a...
right-angled laceration
at the base of the nostrils.
The skin appears
to be split, not cut.
There's metallic trace
in the wound.
You and Wendy always go
to Whatifitcon together?
Actually, it was our first.
(humming)
Pleasure working
with you, Yeoman.
As always.
Tell me something,
Commander.
Were you scared?
I wasn't before.
But I am now.
But you're my
commanding officer.
(shudders)
I'm also a man.
With a man's needs.
If you only knew how
many nights I lay awake
dreaming of a moment like this.
Oh... I can guess.
Hodges, you forgot this.
GCMS, chop-chop.
(dramatic music plays)
My name is Jonathan Danson,
and I'm here to set you free.
Free from a vision
of an antiseptic future
filled with...
with heroes and heroines
who are always steadfast
and well-adjusted
and altruistic.
When was this taken?
Last night,
special preview event.
Anything interesting happens
at a sci-fi convention,
it's online somewhere
about five seconds later.
DANSON:
Like most of you,
I grew up with Astro Quest.
Every Thursday night
my dad would gather the family
around our TV
to watch the latest episode.
(laughing):
I loved it.
But the older I got,
the more the mythology
began to eat away at my soul.
I couldn't measure up to the
brave crew of that perfect ship.
I wasn't handsome,
courageous, strong.
I was weak, petty,
self-destructive.
And I hated myself for it.
But then...
One night...
it hit me like a...
like a bolt of lightning.
I looked around the bar
at the other
frightened, sad people and I...
and I said to myself, "Do you
see an Artemis Bishop here?"
"Do you see one at work?"
What's this?
He's showing the Redux.
Uh, in your apartment building
or on the street?
People, look around you.
Do you see an Artemis Bishop
anywhere?
Of course not.
Because he's
a fictional construct.
A phantom who whispers,
"You are not enough."
Well, I am here to show you
who we really are.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I give you...
Astro Quest: Redux.
(dramatic music plays)
(static buzzes)
I swear to God
I'm gonna do her!
Garth, you know me.
Just stand down.
I don't know
anything anymore!
I'm gonna do her.
I swear I'm
gonna do her!
Commander...
Okay, Sally, everything's
gonna be all right.
(three gunshots)
Nothing's ever gonna
be all right again!
Do you see that?!
Now you're gonna
do what I want.
(sobbing)
(murmuring)
You suck.
You don't have the...
(crowd clamoring, booing)
Do you get it?
MAN: We're not gonna watch
that crap! Get outta here!
So let me get this straight.
Some nerd
takes a cheesy, '60s sci-fi show
and turns it into something
a little bit more realistic--
minus the spaceship, of course--
and the other
nerds get
pissed off enough that they beat
him up and kill him over it?
Well... people don't like it
when you mess with their heroes.
You got something, Riley?
Hmm...
No sign of blood.
I doubt it's
the murder weapon.
(sighs)
Are we going to have
to figure out how many Dumpsters
3,000 people can fill
in three days?
Boy, I hope not.
Whoa.
I got a...
whole lot of geek love
on the command chair.
Isn't that nice for them?
I just found A/V central.
DVD player,
sound gear.
And the vic's laptop.
There's a DVD in the player.
MAN: According to Article 13 of
the Planetary Alliance Charter,
we find Jonathan Danson guilty
of high treason.
STOKES: This wasn't part
of the presentation.
And the penalty is...
Please!
No!
(sobbing):
I'm sorry!
I won't ever do it again!
Don't kill me, please!
I got to start
watching this show.
MAN:
Sic Semper Tradi torae.
Death to traitors.
(knocking)
Yeah?
Uh, Catherine, um,
hypothetically,
if I knew of someone in the lab
having a relationship...
What kind of a relationship?
Um... personal.
Affectionate.
Romantic?
Okay.
Um, hypothetically,
if I knew of someone in the lab
having a romantic
relationship...
...would I be obligated
to report them?
Yes.
To Ecklie.
And, hypothetically,
would they suffer consequences?
Are they hypothetically
on the same shift?
Yes.
Supervisor-subordinate?
No.
Then one of them will
have to change shifts.
But other than that,
they should be fine.
Just tell them
to report it to Ecklie
and to go for it.
Life's too short, right?
(mouthing)
SANDERS:
So what's a college professor
doing taping the debut
of Astro Quest: Redux
at a science fiction
convention?
I was there
with my crew.
I'm making a documentary
on the gestalt constructs
of sci-fi mytho-cultures.
Really?
Have a seat.
Thank you.
I wanted to talk to you
about your video.
The crowd didn't seem
to like Danson's new take
on their old mythology.
Danson was a provocateur.
I actually loved his boldness.
But he was playing with fire.
You believe
one of these people
killed him?
Would you believe it?
(crowd clamoring)
To its fans,
Astro Quest is more
than just a television show.
It's a religion.
When he screened
his Redux,
that was the sci-fi equivalent
of Martin Luther nailing
his "95 Theses"
to the door of the Castle Church
in Wittenberg.
That's keeping it
in perspective.
People kill each other
all the time
over belief systems,
Mr. Sanders.
Or perhaps you're not familiar
with the Middle East.
ROBBINS:
C.O.D. was cerebral hemorrhage
due to blunt-force trauma.
Sharp blow to the nasal bone
snapped the nasofrontal
suture,
driving it
into the frontal sinus,
where a secondary fracture
penetrated the frontal lobe.
Instant unconsciousness.
He was dead
within minutes.
Any idea what hit him?
Something angular,
silver-colored.
We haven't found
the murder weapon yet.
Uh, David, would you finish
stitching him up, please?
PHILLIPS:
I'm not a seamstress.
I'm a coroner's
investigator, damn it.
(sighs)
He's been doing that all day.
He's riffing
Corpsman Scully's one-liners
from Astro Quest.
Didn't watch it much.
PHILLIPS: Because you're
not a couch potato.
You're a medical
examiner, damn it.
Well, he was obviously
in some kind of struggle.
What do you make
of this contusion here?
ROBBINS:
It's on a pressure point.
Maybe someone attempted
a sleeper hold.
You mean like a Sethlan
submission claw?
That's real?
ROBBINS:
Well, you tell me.
(grunting)
Aah! Okay!
Ow! Ow!
Ow!
(grunts)
There was something odd
in the stomach contents.
Take a whiff.
Alcohol.
Curaçao, maybe.
What are these, um,
vermiform chunks of meat?
Those are Vellikon skullworms,
which would of course explain
the Tijillian ale.
It's Astro Quest food.
Some of the bars
and restaurants
around the convention
do that sort of stuff
for the conventioneers.
That hurt.
Good.
STOKES:
His name is Jonathan Danson.
You recognize him?
Yeah.
Yeah, he was in here
that night.
And he wasn't
a happy camper.
He'd been alone at the bar
knocking back drinks
when this Astro Quest girl
comes up.
Yeah, another
Vapor, please.
He started jocking her
pretty hard.
No, thank you.
No?
Could you please
let go of me now?
Please.
Her friends didn't like that.
Sir, you just need to
let go of my commander.
Everything will be okay.
Sir, please.
WOMAN:
Let go!
Just let go!
Hey, stop that!
You have no respect!
(shouting)
Get him!
First off, we abhor violence.
That's the first thing wrong
with your entire show!
Yeah, now--
see how it feels?
I'm not down with violence.
So I put an end to it.
Any of those people
in these photos?
Yeah, these three right here.
You didn't happen
to get any names, did you?
No. Sorry.
After the fight they all split.
Well, there's nothing
worse than a bunch of
drunk conventioneers.
Must be hard enough
to sling drinks
without making you play
dress-up.
How do you like this makeup?
Got it on my second tour
of Afghanistan.
These Astro Questors,
they believe in a future
where human beings, they
transcend their differences.
I wouldn't mind living
in a world like that.
Yeah, me either.
(whirring)
You better be careful.
That thing gave me
a nasty little shock.
Well, of course it did.
This is the...
Compliance yoke from
"The Slavers of Sirenodon."
It's a classic.
I know, right?
So, the commander and his
crew are basically forced
into hard labor, right?
By the planet's...
disembodied rulers.
Disembodied, yeah.
And they make everybody
wear one of these things
around their necks.
Yeah, and if they don't
follow orders,
then they get zapped
with this paralyzing pain.
Hey! Hodges!
You don't have gloves on.
It hasn't been processed.
Sorry.
Don't make me use this.
(machine powering down)
What, if anything else,
did you do growing up?
Sneer if you wish,
but science fiction
has been the inspiration
for many great technological
breakthroughs.
I'm not knocking it.
I love sci-fi.
You know, especially
that talking horse show.
That was one of my favorites.
Mr. Ed?
Yeah.
That's not science fiction.
Sure, it is.
It postulates
an alternate universe
in which horses
evolve a larynx.
No.
See, that's fantasy.
No, fantasy is anything
that travels
faster than the speed
of light, Hodges.
Which is why if Albert Einstein
were alive today,
he'd slap your face.
(whirring)
HODGES:
I wasn't born to be a slave.
(dramatic music plays)
Is this what
we're supposed to do
for the rest
of our lives?
Yes.
The supervisors assign us
the tasks we are to perform.
Yours is to collect
carbonite rocks.
Mine is to ensure that you
collect carbonite rocks.
I'm sick
of picking up rocks!
Rest if you wish.
What I wish...
is to be free.
On my planet,
we choose where we go,
what to do, who to love.
What is...
love?
On my planet,
love is the single most
important thing
that can happen
between sentient beings.
Oh, you mean mating.
When the time comes
to increase the staff,
my supervisor will
approve a mate for me.
Wouldn't you like to
choose your own mate?
Wouldn't you like that?
Such talk is not permitted
in the workplace.
Wouldn't you like...
just once...
to choose for yourself?
(electronic tone warbling,
buzzing)
(groaning)
No! No!
Catherine said
it would be all right.
That Ecklie wouldn't have
any problem with it.
WEBSTER:
Hey, Hodges.
No!
Hodges!
Yes?
I got work hits
off both sets
of those prints
from that DVD,
and they are locals.
Well, sort of.
They're from Pahrump.
(knocking)
BRASS:
How do you
do, ma'am?
I'm Detective Jim Brass,
Las Vegas Police.
We're looking for Lionel Rose
and Steuben Lorenz.
They're upstairs.
Where else?
ELECTRONIC VOICE:
Identification.
(beep, whirr)
Mom, not now.
I told you
we're debriefing.
Red alert.
Yeah, we made it.
It was a joke.
Of course, humor is subjective.
So, when
Jonathan Danson
found you sabotaging
his life's work,
did he subjectively
kick your ass?
DANSON:
Hey!
What the hell
are you guys doing here?
What...
(yelps)
Don't touch that!
No, no, that's not true.
(sighs)
He kicked our asses before,
at the bar.
You see, I adopted
a Gandhi-esque strategy
of passive resistance
to force the aggressor
to recognize the immorality
of his actions,
while Lionel attempted
to avoid confrontation
like an inferior male baboon
who presents his rump
for the dominant male to mount.
Unfortunately...
Danson proved ignorant
of baboon body language.
We-we didn't even go to
the convention hall that night.
We sent her: Risa.
Risa Parvess.
P-A-R-V-E-S-S.
Uh, I didn't think
it was a good idea.
I mean,
she's always been
really unstable.
STEUBEN:
Did you deliver
the payload?
Yeah, I guess,
but there were...
complications.
Complications, like what?
Did someone see you?
If you did anything
to compromise
the safety of
this crew...
There is no crew!
This isn't
a spaceship!
I'm done playing
your stupid games.
Where do we find her?
STEUBEN:
I have no idea.
She's always been
quite unstable.
(snickering)
SIMMS:
Hey.
I just got the results back
from the command chair,
and it's the victim,
plus an unknown female,
so we're closing in.
Great.
Hey, also, I was thinking
that maybe after shift,
it would be kind of fun
to have a little
Astro Quest mini-marathon.
Ooh.
Like maybe
"Yesterday's Tomorrow,"
parts 1, 2, and 3?
You mean the time travel
trilogy from season 4?
Oh, yes.
It's great.
Yeah, count me in.
Good.
Yeah.
Hey, uh, I'll even
spring for pizza,
if it's not too much
of a crowd.
Well, two is not much
of a crowd, really, so...
You mean just you and me?
Yeah.
You, me, the
Blu-Ray DVD box set
and a brand-new
plasma TV.
Over at your place?
Yeah.
That's where I keep my TV.
Okay, sounds good.
Yeah, it will be.
Have you ever
actually seen one?
I mean, have you ever
actually seen one...
in the flesh?
A Tijillian concubine.
JOHNSON:
Feral...
carnal...
voracious.
JOHNSON:
I'd say she's worth
a change in shift.
Wouldn't you?
(whispering):
You're on fire.
Hodges, you're on fire.
(fire crackling)
What happened?
I was checking the unknown's
solubility in acetone,
when I guess it caught on fire.
My mind wandered.
That's been happening
a lot lately, Hodges.
What's going on with you?
There's nothing going on.
This is a crime lab,
not some Tijillian casbah.
Excuse me?
You, me,
a DVD...
I don't think it's going
to help us catch a killer.
Are you actually trying
to blame all this on me?
Not in so many words.
Okay, you know what?
I asked you
to come over
and watch a DVD--
that's it--
so if you're having
some fantasies about me
dressed up
in a tinfoil bikini,
dancing around in a casbah
on a strange alien planet,
then... good.
Good?
Yes, good, 'cause it means
you're not as oblivious
as everyone around here
seems to think you are.
But the fact is,
if you can't handle
the way...
if you can't handle the way that
those fantasies makes you feel,
don't turn all that around
and blame me
when you screw up.
Don't worry
about it.
It's not gonna happen again.
Well, that's
not the only thing
that's not gonna happen.
Fine.
Yeah, she, uh, wandered
into the bar a couple hours ago.
Totally strung out.
Okay.
Put a little caffeine in her,
a little conversation,
and she was willing to come in
and do the right thing.
Okay... thanks.
No problem.
Hey, you know, um...
they were giving these away
at the convention.
You should check it out.
You might like it.
Thanks.
Miss Parvess?
My name is Nick Stokes.
I'm with the crime lab.
I really appreciate you...
coming down here
to talk with me.
Okay, I'm going to make this
real easy for you.
I know that Jonathan Danson
harassed you in the bar.
And I know you were
in the booth that night
planting
your pals' DVD.
I also found evidence
of sexual activity
on the command chair.
Now, listen...
if he assaulted you
in any way and you fought back,
that's self-defense.
You know that, right?
It wasn't self-defense.
I liked his show.
I think he must have
been able to sense that
when he saw me at the bar.
I used to be
just like you.
Tormented by impulses
I thought were dirty.
Desires that
have no place
in a squeaky-clean
universe.
Let go of me.
Let go of yourself.
Stop trying to be
something you're not,
and the guilt
that's eating you alive
will fall away.
Let me set you free.
(collar buzzing)
RISA:
He took me...
to an incredible place.
No preconceptions or judgments.
Just...
pure impulse
and...
raw instincts.
He showed me who I really was.
He even gave me
his cell phone number.
He said he was going
to take me to Cabo.
WILLOWS:
Well, I'd say that confirms
at least part of her story.
Where did you
get this?
Found it on the
vic's laptop.
He has quite
a collection.
And that's
Melinda Carver,
his producer.
It's about seven
hours before Risa,
just before the
VIP premiere of his show.
It's good to be
the commander.
So, what's the point?
The point is
that you didn't tell me
that you were banging
the dead guy.
That had nothing
to do with this.
And you didn't tell me
you emptied out your 401(k)
and gave all the money
to Danson.
We checked his bank records.
He needed it
to complete the project.
Right. He's been completing
a lot of projects lately.
And according
to the GPS tags
on those photographs,
he's been working his mojo
at most major sci-fi
conventions in America.
He's a busy guy.
I knew about the other women,
because Jon told
me about them.
We had an, uh, an
open relationship.
Look... Jon was an extremely...
complicated human being.
(sighs)
He was trying
to expose
the hypocrisy of a sick society.
He was a
real artist,
and that's all
that mattered to me,
not who he was poking
in that chair.
That's a nice speech.
I'm done
talking to you.
And that's a nice purse.
I'm gonna have
to hang on to that.
Check it for blood.
Be my guest.
ADAMS:
The weird thing
about these photos
is the camera angle
and the background never change.
Which means there must
be a hidden camera
on the set somewhere?
May I?
Yeah.
Every shot, the victim's hand
is on that button.
It must be
some kind of trigger.
Mm-hmm.
You didn't notice a camera?
No, I didn't,
but, I mean,
they make them
pretty small these days.
Some of them even have
built-in memory.
In other words,
if we find it,
we may have a photo
of our killer.
The background in the photo
is this point here.
The beam needs
to line up with the left arm
of the chair.
Bring it
up a bit.
A little
bit more.
Perfect.
The camera should be
somewhere along this beam.
I don't see
any camera here.
Maybe Danson had a voyeur
buddy take the sex pics.
Mm. From the same
exact angle every time?
Wendy?
I think I've got it.
Got what?
The metallic trace
from the victim's wound.
Give me a second.
Does this remind you
of anything?
Yes.
Right?
(keypad beeping)
(phone rings)
Langston.
HODGES:
It's Hodges and Wendy.
What do you got?
Yeah, uh, we know
what killed Danson.
It's in the helm.
Okay, I'm going
to put you
on speaker.
Now, it's, it's
in the what?
I-It's the console
that's directly opposite
the command chair.
There's a retractable viewer
inside.
HODGES:
It's from the show.
Looks like some kind
of piston system.
Yeah, th-there should be
a control
for it someplace.
It's called a
targeting scanner.
I think we have it.
We also have a
digital sex camera.
And blood, 90-degree angle.
Silver metal paint
and a bloody fingerprint.
Nice work, people.
See you back at the lab.
(closes phone)
(chuckles)
Nice work, Hodges.
You, too, Simms.
Is she mad at you again?
Why don't
you two just
get it over with?
You've been dancing
around it for years.
Just tell her how you feel.
Tell her what, Mr. Andrews?
That I'd never be able to
give myself to her fully?
Because I've made a
commitment... to this lab.
The pursuit of justice.
Do you think it's easy?
In the dead of night,
I can't help but wonder
what it'd be like to savor
the pleasures of ordinary men.
Moonlit dinners.
Murmured endearments.
The caress
of a woman's soft skin.
Long, languid walks
on the beach.
But you hate the beach.
It's understandable,
I guess,
considering your complexion.
What?
BRASS:
It's good
that you're politically active
because if you weren't,
you wouldn't have been arrested
at that sit-in
at Global Media six years ago.
Caught in the web
of the combine.
Hm.
That's a reference
to One Fl...
Yeah, One Flew Over
the Cuckoo's Nest.
I know.
And I also know
that you didn't mean
to kill
Jonathan Danson.
I know that.
It happened.
But this is your one chance
to get out in front of it,
so tell me
what happened.
Just tell me
the truth,
and I promise I'll do
everything I can to help you.
I will.
Jonathan Danson took
my media semiotics course.
He was a good student.
Mm-hmm.
I heard about his project
and thought it would be
perfect material
for my documentary.
Ah.
But then I saw Redux.
I'm gonna do her!
I swear I'm gonna do her!
I gave a lecture once,
deconstructing Astro Quest
as an example.
(gunshot)
(body thuds)
Jonathan had integrated
all of my conceits
into his fictional construct.
He stole your idea.
He didn't ask for permission.
He... He didn't even
acknowledge me in the credits.
You want credit?
Now, why would
I give you that?
Because they're
my ideas.
Whatever happened
to "Nobody can own an idea"?
Let me tell you
something.
Ideas are a dime a dozen.
If you want to make them
into art,
it takes drive,
vision, creativity.
Hey, I have created...
What?
Hyperintellectual diarrhea?
Go back to writing theory papers
for the six other people in
your department who read them.
I've got a TV show to make.
You! You!
Let me go!
Not till you
cool down.
Are you gonna be cool?
(quietly):
Yes.
20 years devoted
to media theory.
Talk about a wasted life.
(screams)
(grunts)
(gasping)
You see the irony, don't you?
Jon attempted to deconstruct
Astro Quest's iconography,
and he was killed
by one of the signifiers
he sought to subvert.
Derrida, Derrida
would have called that...
An epistemological
dichotomy?
I just call it
second-degree murder.
Anybody up
for a little Astro Quest?
Oh, no, not tonight.
Thanks, though.
All right.
Break room in five.
Let's go.
Uh, no, thanks.
Enjoy.
STOKES:
"A Dollop of Apocalypse."
LANGSTON:
Oh, that's the one
where they find
this planet
where, um, amphibians
are the dominant species,
and they worship Peyton Place
as a sacred text.
It's classic.
ADAMS:
W-Wait, the amphibians can
read and they choose that?
LANGSTON:
There's a reason
for it. You'll see.
(typing)
HODGES:
Jihw-CHOK
chom-CHEM
jag-eej BRYCE cichoki.
SIMMS:
I don't speak Vellikon.
What'd you say?
Anytime you're ready, Ecklie.
You will leave
me... now?
The lab needs me.
You have needs of
your own, as do I.
Maybe, someday,
our needs will coincide.
I hope so.
Till then...
(electronic whirring)
Someday.