(distant sirens wailing)
(metallic creaking)
Drop your weapon.
(clattering)
(metallic creaking)
(loud clattering)
Drop your gun!
Drop your gun now.
(gun clatters on ground)
You can't win; it's four on one.
Then I guess it's just about
how many of you I take with me.
It's okay, Riley.
We got you covered.
(two gunshots)
WILLOWS:
You're dead.
Nice shot, Willows.
(blows)
WILLOWS:
Thanks.
And, Adams, you get points
for calling Sanders
by your name
to communicate your intentions.
That's a good job.
Hey, how many points
does she lose for missing?
ADAMS:
I don't want
to be defensive or anything,
but the only reason
I missed was because
Greg couldn't get
out of the hold.
(chuckles):
Oh, please.
Lee knows the signals
better than we do.
And besides,
you could've been more subtle.
Play nice, kiddies.
LANGSTON:
I need sidearm clearance
and I've got to take a look
at the tactical manual again.
These codes are very,
very confusing.
Uh, the most important
signal is Code Four.
Situation's secure--
Code Four.
SANDERS:
Second most important:
four eighty-two.
I know this.
482 is...
What is it?
Lunch.
Okay.
And Riley's buying.
(cell phone ringing)
Nice.
ADAMS: I'm buying?
Yeah.
ADAMS:
Well, then I hope you
all like value meals.
This is Catherine.
Oh.
Uh, uh,
ten minutes out.
Copy that.
(snaps phone shut)
Multiple 419s
at Green Valley and Elm.
All hands on deck.
(sirens wailing)
(helicopter flying overhead)
LANGSTON:
I looked at a house around
the corner from here
when I first moved to town.
I thought this was
a nice neighborhood.
It is.
MAN:
I heard this big crash,
so I ran outside,
and I saw three, maybe four guys
fighting with Reggie Hatcher.
Bill came out running
with his gun.
He tried to stop the fight,
and they shot him.
It was like Halo 3;
everybody started shooting.
Next thing you
know, I go down.
Okay, here's what we got.
A call came into 911
at 11:00 p.m.--
shots fired.
Neighborhood Watch captain
was shot dead in the street.
A seven-year-old boy was shot
and killed by a stray bullet
when he came out
to see what was going on.
All this happened in front
of the Hatcher house.
Any suspect info?
Well, it's early,
but what we know so far is
it could be between two,
three or four suspects,
black, Hispanic or white.
They were driving an SUV
that's either black,
navy blue or dark green.
Okay?
I know that doesn't give us
much to work with.
There's plenty
for us to work with here.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
According to witnesses, the
suspects' car was parked here
in front of this house,
facing the wrong way.
The suspects then proceeded
on foot to the Hatcher house.
The owner, Priscilla Hatcher--
she was transported to the
hospital with a head injury,
so the interview was limited--
but she told me
that a group of men--
uh, she wasn't specific
about how many--
broke in, they roughed her up,
they roughed up her son Reggie
and her nephew Frankie.
So what do the son
and the nephew have to say?
Well, they're in the wind.
We're looking for them.
So they could've been abducted.
Something bigger than a bullet
came through this window.
You've got bloody glass,
blood drops.
Fight looks like
it came out this way.
Well, that confirms
what Priscilla Hatcher said.
She said that
her son Reggie
got into a scuffle
with one of the intruders,
and they came
through the window.
The Hatchers were the targets,
yet suspects didn't
park out front.
Maybe the suspects didn't want
the vehicle to be seen.
Or didn't know which house
they were going to hit.
Why don't you guys
take the house.
All right.
BRASS: The Neighborhood
Watch captain.
His name is
Bill French.
He's a veteran.
Survived a tour in
Iraq only to get
gunned down in front
of his own house.
It's a shame, really.
ADAMS:
We have a gun here.
He got off two rounds.
.38 caliber.
WILLOWS:
Nine millimeter.
Shells all over the place.
Most of the recent
gang shootings were with nines.
A blood pool and a blood trail
away from the body.
Got to be from
a second source.
Maybe the Watch commander
shot one of the bad guys.
You got this, Riley?
Yeah.
PHILLIPS:
Sir, I know this is hard.
I am just doing my job.
MAN:
No. Just leave us alone.
Sir, please...
Listen, you can't take him.
I'll drive him
to the hospital, okay?
I'll drive him.
PHILLIPS:
Sir, please.
I need to take him.
You don't even know his name.
Okay, but...
Excuse me.
I'm Greg Sanders.
I'm with the crime lab.
What is your son's name?
Jason Morley.
All right,
Mr. Morley.
Jason's no longer with us.
He's in a better place.
There's nothing any of us
can do to change that.
But you have to let us take him,
so we can figure out
who did this.
(sobbing)
David here will take
very good care
of your son.
I promise.
Sir, please.
(sniffles)
(sobbing softly)
Okay. Okay.
Okay.
(sobbing)
Fresh collision damage.
Broken car lights.
Paint transfer.
Got to be from our
suspects' vehicle.
That's what I'm thinking.
Suspects' car
is parked
on the west side of the
cul-de-sac, facing north.
Right.
If that blood
does belong
to one of
the suspects...
Mm-hmm?
...I'd say he got
into his car, peels out,
leaving behind
these yaw marks...
(tires screech)
Go, go!
...sideswipes
the two parked cars?
Yeah, that's
about it.
Riley.
Make sure that
you process
the collision damage
on the two cars.
You got it, boss.
Thank you.
(camera shutter clicking)
(men grunting)
(glass shatters)
(camera shutter clicking)
This must be Reggie
and his cousin Frankie.
Reggie was valedictorian
of his high school class.
Smart kid.
Hope he has
some street smarts, too.
I'll go take a look around
the rest of the house.
Okay.
What do we have?
I got a
pretty good
handprint off the TV here.
We have two bedrooms--
Mom's and Frankie's.
Found a rolled up sleeping bag
and Reggie's backpack
on the floor in Frankie's room.
He's a student at WLVU.
I don't think
he lives here though.
Maybe he comes home
to do his laundry.
According to this...
...he lives right down
the street.
(cell phone ringing)
It's all clear.
Nobody home.
This is the house the SUV
was parked in front of.
Yeah. Brass.
Okay, I'm going to
want to talk to him.
I'll be right there.
So a shooting victim
just rolled in
to Desert Palm Hospital.
Could be one
of our suspects.
I'm gonna go.
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
When can we
talk to him?
Well, he's
in rough shape.
The docs are
working on him.
The bullet hit an artery.
He's lost a lot of blood.
I don't know... Hey, Doc.
He's dead, I'm afraid.
We found a
gun on him.
It's in there
with his clothes
and a bullet that I pulled
out of his leg.
Thank you.
Sure.
Nine millimeter.
BRASS:
Cuts on his face--
maybe he went through
the window with Reggie.
Snakeback tattoos.
Guy's a gangbanger.
(beeping)
WILLOWS:
Marcus Garfield.
Five arrests for drugs
and various armed assaults.
Well, the
Snakeback gang's
primary source of revenue
is drugs.
But that street--
it's not in their territory.
WILLOWS:
Well, Reggie Hatcher
was a student at WLVU,
which is in their territory.
Maybe Reggie knew them.
That would make Reggie
the target, not the house.
Then Reggie and Frankie
are probably dead.
(computer beeps)
WILLOWS:
Let me drive.
Just give me a second here.
I'm trying to do Archie a favor,
not get him fired.
He's at the Academy meeting.
In Denver.
Which means he's
snowboarding.
There is more
to life than work.
That's a lesson I learned
from your predecessor.
(keyboard clacking)
Where did it go?
Hmm.
Camera angle's too high.
I can't isolate
the driver's face.
Good. I thought
I missed something.
With these tinted windows,
you can't tell
if anyone else
is in the back.
But I did get you
the license number.
And, uh, just
for the record,
Archie may be riding
a half-pipe,
but it's only
in between lectures.
Such as, uh, "Breath Analysis
as a Forensics Tool."
That one's for me.
It's a part of our deal.
He got funded and I didn't.
R.O. is Marcus Garfield.
So I got you the driver.
No. He may have driven
to the crime scene,
but he didn't drive
to the hospital.
He's the one
that got rolled out.
Hey, ran the bullets
and the shell casings.
All nine mill.
14 from the dead suspect's gun,
13 from some other nine.
27 in total.
So they were packing
high-capacity semiautos.
Nick and Langston didn't
recover any ammo evidence
from the Hatcher house.
If they went there
to kill Reggie,
they would have
shot him inside.
If they didn't want to kill him,
what did they want?
(phone ringing)
Jim, what's up?
Copy that.
On my way.
(snaps phone shut)
Brass may have just found
both Reggie and Frankie.
Jim.
Oh, decomp.
BRASS:
The mall security
smelled it, too.
When she was writing up
the third parking violation.
The car's registered
to Aaron Sweets.
He ran with the Snakebacks.
And according to his record,
he knew Marcus Garfield.
James, come on in
and open this up.
We're only about six
or eight blocks
from the crime scene.
Well, that's not Reggie
or Frankie.
Who's buried in Grant's tomb?
Sweets.
You see the candy cane?
Aaron Sweets.
Well, first ticket was written
day before yesterday.
BRASS:
Well, that means Aaron Sweets
is not our missing suspect.
♪ ♪
That makes four.
All .22s.
None of the players
in our mess had .22s.
TOD?
Mr. Sweets here
had assumed room temperature.
Been dead 24 to 48 hours.
So he was dead
before the shoot-out?
Mm-hmm.
I get gangbangers in here
all the time.
Might be unrelated.
Scenes were six blocks apart
in a nice neighborhood.
This isn't just
a coincidence.
Marcus Garfield and
an unknown suspect
gained access to the
Hatcher house there.
STOKES:
He's not unknown anymore.
I ID'd the handprint
on the TV--
Robert Danward,
aka Little Bobby.
Another member
of the Snakebacks.
All right. We compared
the blood on the glass
to the DNA on the toothbrush
found in Reggie's backpack.
Confirmed that
Marcus Garfield and Reggie
crashed through the
window together.
The fight continued
into the street.
According
to the witnesses,
the Neighborhood Watch captain
confronted the suspects.
The bullet
pulled from Garfield's leg
matches
the Watch captain's .38.
The bullets they pulled
from the Watch captain
came from Garfield's nine.
(both groan)
(groaning)
One of Garfield's stray bullets
hit Jason Morley
who lived here.
He was the seven-year-old boy.
Aaron Sweets, another Snakeback,
was shot four times with a .22.
His body was found in the trunk
of his car in a parking garage
six blocks from the crime scene.
There was no .22 ammo
at the scene.
SANDERS:
Can we find any connection
between Sweets and Reggie?
Brass checked
with WLVU. Um,
Reggie's a straight-A student.
He was accepted early admissions
for graduate school next fall.
And I checked Reggie's cell
phone and land line records.
No calls to or from
our suspects.
What about Sweets?
Didn't have his number.
Try 555-0121.
Sweets called Reggie's land line
six times
in the last four days.
Well, that's our connection.
Has anyone checked
Reggie's house?
The uniforms cleared it,
but they were only looking
for bodies.
I tore the kitchen apart.
No drugs, no weapons.
This doesn't really look
like a college kid's place.
Reggie inherited this house
from his grandmother.
Lots of sculpture, paintings.
Lots of phone jacks in Grandma's
house, but no phones.
Did you see a phone
in the kitchen?
No, and none in the master
or guest bedroom either.
Let's try Reggie's
home phone number.
Yeah.
(dialing tones)
(muffled ringing)
(ringing continues)
Who puts a phone
in the closet?
(creaking)
(ringing continues)
Wait, wait, wait.
Let me go first.
When you start
carrying a gun,
you can lead next time.
(ringing continues)
(ringing stops)
(keypad beeps)
Odd place for a phone.
Yeah.
Piperidine, ether, cyanide.
Hydrochloric acid,
magnesium turnings.
This is a PCP lab.
This is all highly explosive.
We should get out of here.
Yeah.
Word on the street is
a college kid
with talent as a mixer
is pushing sherms
in the Snakeback turf
without paying them tribute.
Okay, so Reggie's got
a target on his back
because he's operating under
a different business model?
You can get a degree,
but it doesn't make you smart.
Any word on
Little Bobby?
I heard he's taking
some vacation time.
What do you want?
Hey, I just wanted
to let you know
we got the the guy
who shot Jason.
He's a known gang member.
I'd like to rip
his heart out.
I'd like to let you...
but he's already dead.
I know it probably doesn't help.
You have to do this very often?
It's not part of my job.
Thank you.
I lost my wife last year.
Jason...
just started sleeping
in his own bed again.
Cops like coffee, right?
You want a cup?
Sure.
Send these up to Catherine.
She says Hazmat wants to know
exactly what's down here.
Pure white powder.
Clear crystal
finished product.
Usually this stuff
looks like yellow sludge.
Reggie had it going on.
It's high grade.
(whispers):
Riley.
Blood. Still wet.
Stop right there!
Don't move!
(groaning)
Hey, I'm just gonna go check
on my guys.
If you need anything,
let me know.
All right.
Drop your guns!
ADAMS:
We're not cops.
We're lab techs.
We don't carry guns.
Over there! Sit down!
Just put the gun down, okay?
We'll do whatever you want.
There's a lot of chemicals
in here.
If you shoot,
you're gonna blow us all up.
Sit down!
Shut up!
Go!
And shut up!
What happened
to your friend?
I said shut up!
SANDERS:
Knock, knock?
Anybody home?
Who the hell is that? A cop?
No. He works with us.
I'm gonna get rid
of him, okay?
You don't need
any more problems.
SANDERS:
Hello?
Hey, guys.
Get over here.
Hey, you down there?
I was in the neighborhood,
thought I'd stop by,
see if you need any...
It's okay.
Riley...
we don't need any help.
Okay, Sanders.
See you back at the lab.
Here, sit, sit!
We have a situation
downstairs.
Suspects on
the premises.
There's a surveillance camera
over the front door.
I'm going to go
call it in.
BRASS:
Hey, Greg.
Langston and Riley
have been taken hostage
at the PCP lab.
I don't know who or how many.
I'll call SWAT,
notify Catherine.
LANGSTON:
You're Reggie, right?
Hey, man, you listen, okay?
I'm not gonna tell you
again, okay?
Just sit there
and shut up.
All right, Frankie,
try to calm down.
How do you know who I am?
Reggie, your mother's
in the hospital.
She's worried about you.
She's worried about
the both of you.
Reggie looks like he's hurt
pretty bad, Frankie.
I can help him.
I'm a doctor.
(gasping)
I can help him.
All I need to do is look at him.
Go.
No, no, no,
you sit.
I need more light
to examine him properly.
Can we bring him into the lab?
Yeah, okay, okay, okay.
But this better not be a trick!
We'll lay you down
on three.
One, two... three.
(gasps)
You hanging in there?
Is my mom okay?
I think she's going
to be fine.
I didn't mean
for any of this to happen.
Well,
no one ever does.
Am I... am I gonna die?
If you tried to take
this glass out yourself,
you probably would have.
You know, I was...
I was a big fan of Steve Irwin.
Me, too.
Hey, come on, man, there's
nothing wrong with his head.
Get your finger off of there.
I need to check his vitals;
his heart rate.
I want to make sure
that he doesn't go into shock.
Look at me, Reggie.
Open your eyes, look at me.
(gasping)
Good.
Okay.
(Reggie gasps)
Frankie, Reggie's
having a reaction
to the chemicals
in this room.
He's been in here too long
and so have you.
We've to get the both of you
out of here.
No, no, no, no.
What do you think
I am, stupid?
I think you care
about what happens to Reggie.
Frankie, let him help me.
Oh, come on, Reg.
Don't be on their side. What,
are you stuck on stupid, too?
Can't you see
they're playing you?!
You know, that's
your problem.
You always let
people sucker you.
My problem was
I tried to help you.
I should've just let you die
in the streets, man.
(gunshots)
FRANKIE:
Mr. Book Smart.
Man, you ain't that smart.
You don't know nothing about
the real grind
like I do.
The real grind, Frankie?
Yeah.
The real grind?
The only thing you know
is a gun.
Without that gun,
you're nothing!
I'm nothing?!
Man, without me,
you wouldn't even have
a dime for grad school!
I'm the one who turned
your little chemistry projects
into paper!
And then you want to go pay
off Sweets like a chump.
Man, you didn't need to pay
for protection!
Talking about, you need
protection, this and that!
You didn't need protection!
You had me!
I'm the one who
killed Sweets!
I'm the one who protected
your ass when you needed it!
That was me! Me!
Look at me, Frankie!
What?!
He's bleeding.
Sit back, Reggie,
sit back, sit back.
(groaning)
All right, Frankie,
he's gonna die
if I don't help him.
You've got the gun--
that means you're in charge,
so you better make a decision.
Okay.
Do something,
whatever.
I need, um, a towel,
some kind of cloth
to clean up this wound.
I have to irrigate
the wound.
I need alcohol or water.
Do you have any of
that here in the lab?
We also have to seal up
all those chemicals.
Yeah, okay.
Go.
Um...
Here...
Here are paper towels.
Uh... fresh water
over there.
(closes door)
We don't have any lids here.
But I have some tape
in my kit that will work, okay?
(quietly):
Okay. Go.
(Reggie groaning)
(radio squawks)
What the hell are you doing?!
Frankie!
You calling the cops, huh?!
Hey...
Is that what you doing,
Miss Smart-Aleck, huh?!
Leave it! Drop it!
Listen to me.
If I don't pick up that radio...
it's going to send out
a "horizontal alert."
Now, that means the
police will know
that we're in trouble
within 30 seconds.
(gasping)
So just let me pick it up, okay?
(mutters):
Turn it off.
Turn it off!
T-Turn it off!
WILLOWS:
Ray e-mailed me photos
from the PCP lab,
one of which includes
a surveillance monitor.
The suspects have a clear view
of the front of the house.
We got a three-man
entry team right here.
We'll find an
alternate way in.
FRANKIE (on radio):
I'm running the show here, okay?
Hey, we got an open mic.
LANGSTON:
Look, tell me who's going
to help me here with Reggie.
I need another pair of hands.
Reggie and Frankie
are both in there.
Are you going to help me?
Sounds like Reggie's injured.
Which means there's probably
only one gun in there--
Frankie's.
FRANKIE:
Get your... get your little
nurse lady to help you.
That's right, go over there.
Go help my cousin.
Frankie, listen to me.
You haven't hurt anyone yet.
But if you... if you pull
that trigger, that .22
is going to change everything.
Frankie's got the .22.
Sweets was killed with a .22.
I haven't hurt anyone yet?
Is that what you just said?
I wasted a guy, okay?
I killed a gangbanger.
(gunshot)
It's not like the court's
going to execute me.
I'm only 14!
So, go ahead!
Just do something!
Just fix my cousin!
(helicopter blades whirring)
What the hell
are they doing here?
It's a damn news chopper.
This is restricted
air space.
We'll get them
out of here.
(helicopter blades whirring)
Cops?
It was the radio!
You tricked me,
you bitch!
(shouting)
(screaming)
Frankie, that's enough.
You!
(phone ringing)
(ringing continues)
(cocks gun)
If he dies...
then we all die.
Frankie, just let me
answer the phone
and tell them that we're okay.
(phone ringing)
No. No, no,
they don't need to know squat.
Look, Reggie has got
to get to a hospital.
But you said you could fix him.
I don't have
the proper equipment.
He needs a surgeon.
I'm not a surgeon.
But you're a doctor, right?
Yes.
Yeah, so, so, so figure out
something.
(phone ringing)
Doc...
(weakly):
I don't feel good.
Everything is spinning.
Um, all right, I have, uh...
Well, I can use the ether
to put you under.
I've got a scalpel in my
kit to make the incision.
And hemostats
to clamp off the veins
before I remove the glass.
Um, I still need
other things.
I-I-I need, uh, gauze,
sterile gauze,
a needle and thread, antiseptic.
We don't have any of that stuff.
Okay, I have all of that.
It's up in the first aid kit.
But it's in the truck, upstairs.
(phone ringing)
No...!
No. No one's
going anywhere.
I can help Reggie,
but I need the kit.
I have to have it.
Let me tell them
I'm coming up there.
(phone ringing)
This is another... another one
of your tricks, isn't it?
This isn't a trick, Frankie.
I want us all to walk
away from this, okay?
This is Adams.
Are you and
Langston okay?
Yeah, yeah. We're all okay.
Without alerting the suspects,
can you describe
the situation in detail?
We have a kid down here
who is injured.
He needs medical attention.
I'm going to come up and get the
first aid kit from the truck.
Langston is going
to stay here.
I have to be able
to come back down.
Okay.
She's got to go back in,
or Langston's dead.
Jack, give me a walkie.
I want to talk to her.
The front entrance
and the street are covered
by surveillance.
They'll be waiting for us
to make our move.
Okay, I got it.
We got to try.
I can't just sit here
and do nothing.
The tree behind the Denali
is the edge of frame.
Stay behind that.
BRASS:
Right. Yeah, I got that.
Why is she going to the back
of the truck?
We keep the first aid kit in
the back of the truck, Frankie.
You have to trust us.
She better not run.
How you holding up?
How many guns?
You armed?
Then you know
what you got to do.
LANGSTON:
Frankie, bring me
that bottle of ether, please.
Yes, that's it.
Put it down there.
Thank you.
(wood creaking)
I came right back.
Frankie, I'm going
to open this up
so you can see
for yourself no tricks.
(Reggie groans)
Please, please, don't...
don't touch any of that.
You'll contaminate it,
and Reggie could get infected.
Look, I'm going to need
another pair of hands.
Which one of you is
going to help me?
Ain't gonna be me.
REGGIE:
Relax, Frankie.
You just worry about how you're
going to get us out of here.
Be strong.
Riley, I want you to
apply pressure here.
That's good. With your
fingertips, just like that.
Very good.
Reggie, I want
you to understand
exactly what I'm going to do.
First, I'm going
to put you under.
Once you're under,
I'm going to stop the bleeding,
and once that's done,
I'm going to try and remove
the glass. All right?
Listen, tell my mom I love her.
You tell her that yourself.
You know, I only wanted
to become a real scientist.
Maybe do some good.
I guess I thought
I could handle everything.
Things got away from me.
Try and relax.
I shouldn't have run.
Don't fight it.
Just relax.
Take a couple of
deep breaths.
(Reggie breathing deeply)
I have to cut
him, Frankie.
It's very difficult
to concentrate with you
pointing that gun at me.
We can pump in CS gas.
On the west end of the house,
there's a vent
that leads directly
into the lab.
Except we're talking about a
14-year-old kid with a gun
that he's not
afraid to use.
The gas could
cause him to panic.
Yeah, one wild shot
and he blows up the whole block.
STOKES:
Riley's armed.
She's trained for this.
If she gets the opportunity,
she will take it.
One thing we got going for us,
time is on our side.
I say we trust them.
So do I.
We need more towels.
Hand me another hemostat.
Okay.
All right. Ready?
Yeah.
And... here we go.
Okay.
Oh, my God!
What did you do to him?
I need help.
He's not going to die, is he?
I need someone
to put pressure on the artery.
Give me the gun.
I need someone to
apply pressure
to the artery while I make
a pressure bandage, Frankie.
I need your hands.
ADAMS:
Reggie needs your help.
Give me the gun.
Come on, do some good
for a change.
Frankie, I need you
over here now.
LANGSTON:
You see where my hand is?
Put your hand there.
You feel it?
You got it?
That's it, right there.
Keep the pressure tight.
Good.
Code Four, suspect's disarmed.
We need an ambulance,
Code Three.
Have your people treat
him fairly, Captain.
He doesn't have to
be a lost cause.
Somehow, I knew
you were going to say that.
(indistinct radio transmissions)