So, uh... you are
dating that nurse.
Uh-huh. Kind of.
MAN:
I have to work with you?!
Uh-huh. And what happened
to Doc Robbins' niece?
Oh, nothing.
I'm just keeping
my options open.
I called her, genius.
She's not answering
her cell phone.
Why do you think
I called you people?
You know what?
I want to talk to your boss.
I want to talk to him now.
She's busy.
"She."
All right,
what's going on, Mitch?
Meet Dwayne Hicks.
He reported his wife missing.
He's all yours.
Mr. Hicks, I'm Nick Stokes.
This is Sara Sidle.
We're with the
crime scene unit.
When's the last time
you saw your wife?
Last night.
Debbie and I had an early dinner
and then I went to work.
And where do you work?
What the hell does that have
to do with you finding my wife?
Are you refusing to
answer the question?
Okay, look...
Mr. Hicks...
we're just trying to
help you out, man.
All right.
I work as a night manager
at the Swift Deal, okay?
All right. And, uh...
where was the last place
that you saw Debbie?
Deb... yeah, Debbie.
At home.
You want to know
what we ate, too?
Um...
which house is yours?
Five twenty-eight.
The vacant lot.
Yeah, it's a vacant lot because
someone stole my house.
So you're saying when you
went to work last night,
the house was there,
and your wife was inside?
Yes.
And now they're
both missing.
Ye... that is what I'm
trying to tell you people!
Come on!
So you think somebody was after
the house, or the wife?
Oh, that's great!
DWAYNE:
Yeah!
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
Okay.
Is your name Julie Finlay?
Yes.
And were you
born in Philadelphia?
Yes.
Have you used any illegal drugs,
including marijuana,
in the last ten years?
No.
Hm.
Do you...
...resent having my honesty
gauged by debunked
pseudo-technology?
Don't do that...
Yeah. A little bit.
Please keep your answers
to a "yes" or "no."
Yes.
Do you have any
criminal history?
I was married twice.
Did my time.
Have you ever had sex
with an animal?
(laughs):
Oh, my... really?
Oh, God.
SPECIALIST:
Yes, or no?
Well, my first ex-husband
was a bit of a dog.
And my second, a pig.
Does that count?
I don't know why you bother.
Those people never have
a sense of humor, you know that.
I know. I couldn't help myself.
Well, I did pass, didn't I?
Welcome to Las Vegas.
Ugh.
Well, at least it's a better
picture than I took in Seattle.
Things are looking up.
Yeah. Um, hey, guys?
Do me a favor,
come in here for a second?
I want you to meet someone.
Sara Sidle, Morgan Brody,
this is Julie Finlay.
Uh... Finn,
with two N's.
So nice to meet you.
Finn's coming on board.
Oh. I heard about your, uh,
amazing blood reconstruction
from Greg.
Oh...
Why don't you guys
give her the official tour?
I'd love to, but I'm due back
at my crime scene.
We have a house to find.
But, uh, it's nice
to meet you, Finn.
Nice to meet you.
I'll do it.
I'll even give you
the unofficial tour.
Nice.
I like her already.
This damage is recent.
BRASS:
Yeah. Ran the plates.
Car belongs to the missing wife,
Debbie Hicks.
Supports the husband's story
that the wife was inside the
house when the house was stolen.
I mean, if you want
to kidnap someone,
why take the whole house?
Captain, I talked
to the neighbors.
A couple of them saw the house
driving off last night.
Thought the family was moving
to another neighborhood.
(rap music blaring)
What the hell?
What'd you do with the house?
What do you mean, me?
You stole the house!
I didn't do nothing, okay?
You stashed it away somewhere!
DWAYNE: Really? Why would I
steal my own house?
JIMMY: Because it's not
your house, Dwayne.
STOKES:
Hey, calm down, now.
Oh, my God!
Just 'cause you live in the
house doesn't make it yours.
Possession is 9/10 of the law.
What are you,
a lawyer now?
I don't need to
go to law school...
What happened to our house?
Hey, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
And you are...?
I'm Marla Hicks.
I'm Dwayne and Jimmy's sister.
Dwayne and Debbie
jacked our house, Marla.
Debbie is missing, dumb-ass.
What?
That is a load of crap.
Oh, is it?
Okay, he has always been
trying to steal from me.
Oh, really?
Ever since we were kids.
Are we going to do this out
in front of all these people?
MARLA: Not right now!
Jimmy, not right now!
...my Hot Wheels,
my pot, my Jarts.
I loved those Jarts.
The Jarts were for both of us.
(honks horn)
It's a two-man game!
A woman is missing,
and this fighting
is not helping us find her.
You know, that's
an excellent point.
So let's take this
family feud downtown.
Nice. Talk about pot more
in front of cops.
Why don't you try and
steal the police station?
MARLA:
Why don't you both shut up?
JIMMY &amp; DWAYNE:
Shut up, Marla.
MARLA:
Oh, funny.
A family like that kind of
makes me glad I'm an only child.
Huh.
STOKES: Well, maybe if we figure
out what happened to the house,
we'll figure out
what happened to the wife.
No prints.
They didn't even bother
to turn the water off.
They just sliced
right through the pipe.
Well, there's four different
sets of shoe prints
around the house.
Is it even possible to
move a whole house overnight?
Yeah. Yeah, actually, it is.
And it's not really
that hard to do.
Just slide two support beams
under the joists,
jack it up,
lower it onto a flatbed...
and off you go.
With the wife inside?
Yeah, she had to have
been unconscious,
or she would've heard something,
or felt the house moving,
don't you think?
Unless she was dead.
Could be the perfect crime.
No body, no crime scene.
JIMMY:
Debbie is a total bitch.
I'm surprised Dwayne's been
with her for this long.
BRASS:
They're having marital problems?
Hell, yeah.
At each other's throats
night and day.
About anything in particular?
Money, mostly.
You know, Debbie
loves her slots.
She gambled away their savings.
Wow. That must have
really pissed Dwayne off.
Yeah, I was mad.
We lost our condo.
We had to move
back in with my mother.
So the house
belongs to your mother.
Where is she?
She's dead.
Oh. Sorry for your loss.
So your mom left you the house?
She would've.
If she had a will.
Look, I don't know what
my idiot brother told you--
and he is an idiot--
but Debbie swore off
gambling, all right?
So we... we are in
a good place right now.
Okay?
Oh, really?
Yeah.
Because there was
a disturbance call
at the Tasty Time last week,
involving you and your wife.
All right.
Debbie got a little
flirty with the fry guy.
And she knows
how much I hate that.
It seems you hate a lot
of things about your wife.
Maybe enough to want her dead?
Look, if I killed my wife,
why would I be the one
to report her missing?
Maybe to throw
suspicion off yourself
and onto your "idiot brother".
Well, why don't you find out
what he was doing last night?
Getting the old rifle cleaned,
if you know what I mean.
Lucky you. Where?
Black Stag.
Why make that face?
Where'd you go after?
Home.
Alone?
Yeah, alone. Why do you think
I had to pay for it?
It says here you
work in construction?
Off and on.
I don't know if you've noticed,
but not a lot of building
going on in Vegas these days.
But you have the skills and
connections to move a house.
And you said, I quote,
"Debbie's a total bitch."
Look, I did not
steal that house.
And I did not hurt Debbie.
I love that you're
all up in my business.
Have you even talked to Fred?
Who's Fred?
Fred Blanchard.
He and my dad had a dry-cleaning
business together.
Until my dad stole all
their money and took off.
When was that?
Ten years ago.
I haven't seen or
heard from him since.
Tough growing up without a dad.
You didn't know my father.
Him leaving was the best thing
that ever happened
to our family.
He was a real son of a bitch.
Your brothers think that
Fred stole the house.
Fred? No.
Fred would never do that.
He was there for us the
second my dad left, and...
actually, a few years ago,
he and my mom got really close
and he moved in.
So Fred was living
in the house too.
Yeah.
Until my mom died.
And then Dwayne kicked him out.
I'm sure it was Debbie's idea.
What about you?
I mean, no will.
The house is just as much
yours as it is theirs.
I... I don't want any part
of that damn house.
I'm glad it's gone.
You glad Debbie's gone, too?
I didn't like her, but...
I never wanted anything
bad to happen to her.
SANDERS: I heard you and Finn
worked together in Seattle.
Yeah, yeah. Heard right.
Rumor has it you fired her.
Right again.
So that means there's a good
story in there somewhere.
David! What the hell
you got here, buddy?
Road kill.
Lost an arm and a leg.
I.D.?
No I.D., but...
check out these tread marks.
About 22 inches, give or take.
This is only sixteen.
So our guy was run over
by at least one big-rig
and maybe
a car or two.
90 degrees. He's been dead
around eight hours.
SANDERS:
Died last night.
Not a lot of streetlights.
Would've been hard to
see in the dark.
Hey, there's a bar back there.
Maybe he, uh,
hit the hooch
and hit the road.
You know, for someone who got
run over a couple times,
I'm not seeing a lot of blood.
Hey...
Check this out.
Blanched skin.
His injuries
have an orange tone.
So the blood wasn't circulating.
He was dead before
he was run over.
Yeah, this isn't a hit-and-run.
This is a dump-and-run.
(typing)
HODGES:
528.
That's the right address.
As opposed to the other houses
that were stolen last night?
Any of these guys
the Hicks brothers
or Fred Blanchard?
No, but any of them could've
hired these guys.
Or it was just a random
house-stealing.
Or maybe Debbie Hicks
was still gambling,
and she owed
somebody some money,
and they took her
and the house as payment.
Let's get a closer look
at that guy.
(mouse clicks)
Where was this taken?
Corner of Sunset and Barlow.
But there's no other
traffic-cam footage after that.
Doesn't mean we can't track it.
You must be Finn.
You must be Stokes.
Yes, ma'am.
Hi. David Hodges.
Anything you need to
know about Sin City,
I'm your man.
Russell tells me
you're quite the insider.
Well...
Yeah, how did you you duck
the "sex with animals"
question on
your polygraph?
Given your tentacle porn fetish.
Yeah.
Russell told you about that.
Mm-hmm.
What do you have for us?
Well, it looks like our house
thieves were pretty sloppy.
I accessed all the
911 calls from last night.
Several reports
of downed power lines,
as well as a dozens of reports
of sideswiped cars
and other property damage.
Looks like "Housezilla" left
quite a path of destruction.
Follow the destruction,
find the house.
Yeah, and maybe Debbie.
Hmm...
FINLAY:
House is heading east.
What's over there?
STOKES:
About a hundred miles of desert.
That's a lot of ground to cover.
Not if you have
eyes in the sky.
I like the way
you think.
Jim. Stokes.
We need a chopper.
(Russell, Finlay laugh)
Will you look at this!
You, uh, want to wrap it up,
take it back to the lab?
RUSSELL:
Yeah! (laughs)
You're still doing that?
If it ain't broke.
Hook up the satellite,
I want to live here.
FINLAY:
It's nice and quiet.
No annoying neighbors.
Well, maybe one,
but he's quiet.
Those are guys' legs.
It's definitely
not Debbie Hicks.
Ruby red shoes.
I have a feeling
we're not in Kansas anymore.
(wood creaking)
Do you need a hand?
Oh, no, I've got it.
Thanks.
I'm Finn.
David. Welcome aboard.
Thank you.
PHILLIPS:
Oh...
Chest is completely concave.
Obvious death;
crushing injuries.
Uh-huh.
Hmm.
These shoes
match the impressions
I found at the Hicks property.
He's definitely one
of the house stealers.
Has he got
an I.D. on him?
"Dennis Hutchings."
I recognize him from
the surveillance video.
RUSSELL:
Finn, do me a favor,
and get a picture
of that jack under there.
Okay.
RUSSELL: Actually,
you know what?
I think I got something
in the truck
we can use
to get that out of there.
I got it.
What are you doing?
Aw, come on, Jules!
Don't call me that!
Well, get out from
under there, will ya?
Unbelievable.
Here you go.
You know, I bet I know
what happened.
I bet you they were trying
to lower the house,
this one got jammed,
Mr. Hutchings here tried
to fix it.
(wood creaking)
Cause of death:
terminal stupidity.
Cause of death: karma.
Guy steals house,
house kills guy.
Hey, fellas,
lower it back down, will you?
MAN:
Yes, sir!
We should probably get in there.
It's time to figure out
what happened to Debbie Hicks.
It's hard to tell if this mess
was from a struggle or what.
Well, I can tell you
that this was...
Does not bode well for Debbie.
Blood pool's over a liter.
Nobody can survive
that volume of blood loss.
Injuries and death
occurred here.
Drag marks leading
to the kitchen door here.
So whoever killed her
dumped her body before
they dumped the house.
High-velocity spatter.
If that's from a gunshot,
it must have been a revolver.
I don't see
any casings laying around.
Killer could've picked them up,
though, right?
STOKES:
Yeah.
Yeah, one single air bubble.
Spatter's not from a shooting.
It's expirated blood.
RUSSELL:
So, Debbie coughed up blood
during the attack.
Can you tell what kind
of weapon he used?
Well, we have a castoff pattern,
relatively short arc--
one, two, three--
could be from a beating.
Maybe Debbie put up a fight
when Hutchings came
to steal the house.
He could've brought tools,
right?
Maybe a hammer, a crowbar.
Short castoff arcs with no
associated medium-force spatter.
Indicative of
sharp-force trauma.
So you're thinking stabbing.
(screams)
(coughing)
Three castoff events.
First stab's always for free.
So, that means she
was stabbed at least four times,
left here to bleed out.
Okay, let's back up a second.
So, just because Dennis
Hutchings stole this house,
doesn't mean he's our killer,
though, right?
No, we got a lot
of suspects here, boss.
Husband, brother-in-law,
sister-in-law, Fred.
A whole lot of house to process.
♪ ♪
Where you planning on
sticking that thing?
In your mouth. Open up.
I don't understand.
Why you need my DNA?
To prove that
you killed my wife.
Mr. Hicks, please step back.
I'll be with you in a minute.
You honestly think
I killed Debbie?
I want to see you get
his DNA good.
SIDLE: I'm gonna need
to take yours, too.
JIMMY:
Ha!
Why?
Well, we need
to eliminate everyone
who has legitimate access
to your house.
It's not his house.
It is my house.
Thanks for saying it.
Will you shut up about
the house?! Debbie is dead.
JIMMY:
It's not your house.
It is my house.
Where's the deed?
You can't even read
the deed, so...
Hey, wait.
Hang on a second.
Don't you need a warrant
or something?
Only if you refuse
to give it voluntarily.
What, are you scared they
might find out
that you did it?
If you didn't do it,
you don't have
anything to worry about.
Look at his face.
His wife is dead.
Guys...
He can't even fake
a few tears.
You totally did it.
Get out of my face.
Get out of my face!
Stop it!
Guys, stop it!
Guys! Do you want to spend
a night in jail?
Be good for you, bro.
Get used to it.
I want a lawyer.
Dwayne?
Debbie?!
I knew it was too good
to be true.
You're alive?!
What happened
to our house?!
Wait a second.
Where the hell have you been?!
I was out gambling
with my friend.
All night?
Well, you lose track of
time in the casinos.
We may have had
a few mojitos.
Okay, five.
All right, well, I'm gonna need
the name of your friend,
verify your alibi.
Alibi for what?
House stealing and murder.
Murder?
Well, when
we found the house,
we also found
a bloody crime scene.
Do you know anything about that?
No. No.
Last night, I waited
for Dwayne to go to work,
and then I hit the Strip.
The house was spotless.
Do you know a guy
named Dennis Hutchings?
I never heard of him.
I didn't kill anybody.
Look, when do
I get my house back?
Mrs. Hicks, like I said,
your house is a crime scene.
Then you should be talking
to Dwayne's idiot brother.
If somebody was killed
in that house,
I bet you 100 bucks
he had something to do with it.
Well, you know, we thought
the blood was yours.
So who does it belong to?
BRODY: Amazing how much damage
a big rig can do.
Good way to dispose of a body.
Hopefully, he got a piece
of his killer.
Well, he definitely got a piece
of the murder weapon.
BRODY:
Tip of the knife.
Non-serrated,
single-edged.
So he was stabbed.
ROBBINS:
Yeah.
Based on my analysis,
I found...
...four penetrating
sharp-force injuries.
And you know that how?
Uh, Doc Robbins,
this is Julie Finlay. Finn.
And this here is
Fred Blanchard.
You I.D.'d my victim?
Well, technically,
he's actually my victim now.
DNA matched Fred here
to the large blood pool
found at the Hicks' house.
The stolen house
in the desert?
Mm-hmm.
This guy was stabbed there?
It doesn't make sense.
We found him
in the middle of a truck route.
Yeah, I heard.
Can I see your report?
Fred Blanchard's body
was found right here.
And this is the route
that the house took.
I don't think the drag marks in
the kitchen were drag marks.
What do you mean?
This is hard to see
in the dark wood,
but if you look at the bottom
of the door, that's blood.
That would not be there
if somebody had dragged
the body out
because the killer
would have opened the door.
So they're slide marks.
All right, so if Fred's body's
in the house while it's moving,
he could've slid out
the back door
when the house made this
right turn, right here.
♪ ♪
We know that
Fred Blanchard's our victim.
Who's our killer?
Well, we have Dennis Hutchings,
the dead, not so bright
house thief.
Right.
So Fred comes home,
catches Dennis in the act.
Dennis kills Fred.
Maybe.
Maybe. Okay.
Yeah, the
Hicks siblings
still have the
best motive.
All right,
Fred is living
with the mom. Mom dies.
Kids are worried that Fred's
gonna take the house from them.
Yeah.
Debbie and Dwayne kick him out.
But that's not a permanent
enough solution.
Dwayne's alibi's a little shaky.
He said he clocked in
to work at 7:00,
but nobody could verify that
he spent the whole night there.
Debbie's alibi's even shakier.
She said that she was drinking
and gambling all night
but can't remember
all the casinos
she went to
after mojito number three.
(chuckles):
What?
(cell phone chimes)
Nothing.
Brass just got a lead off
Dennis Hutchings' phone records.
So, Marla, how do you
know Dennis Hutchings?
I don't, really.
He was just doing
a construction job at my school.
I'm studying to be a nurse.
But you hired him
to steal the house.
(quiet laugh)
He was after me for months
to go out with him.
So, finally,
I said that I would,
if he would do me a favor.
Stealing a house;
that's a pretty big favor.
I didn't mean for anybody
to get hurt, really.
I didn't know
that Fred was gonna be there.
I told Dennis to make sure
that the house was empty.
And he wasn't gonna
let anything or anyone
get in the way
of his date.
Fred was like a father to me.
I hated the way
my family treated him.
All because
of that stupid house.
Okay, well, i-it
still doesn't explain
why you wanted
to steal the house.
I didn't think it through.
I just wanted
the fighting to stop.
I mean, my mom's
body wasn't even cold
before my brothers were
arguing over who gets the house.
And how could they even want it
after it killed her?
The house killed your mother?
She was... hanging a flower pot
on the back porch
and it... just collapsed
on top of her.
Termites.
Okay.
First your mother,
then Fred, then Dennis.
That's one killer house.
Hey.
You my reinforcements?
Yep.
New marching orders.
Doc Robbins found
the tip of a knife
in Fred Blanchard's rib cage.
So Finn was right--
this was a stabbing.
Now all we gotta do
is find
a knife with a missing tip.
♪ ♪
Morgan.
Found something.
Murder weapon?
No, not exactly.
(gasps)
Oh.
(anxious laugh)
Whew! Most families
keep their skeletons
in the closet.
Got it?
Yeah.
(sighs)
This house has killed
four people now.
The mom,
Dennis the home stealer,
Fred Blanchard and
now this guy.
That makes it a serial killer.
ROBBINS:
Based on the height,
shoulder width
and clothing,
looks like an adult male.
Fractured skull;
possible blunt-force trauma.
Calliphoridae.
Blowflies.
They arrive within
minutes of death,
which means this guy
decomposed in the wall.
What are the odds
the family didn't know
there was a rotting
corpse in their wall?
Well, given the dehydration
and the condition of the body,
this guy's been dead
at least ten years.
Hicks brothers
would've been teenagers.
Old enough to commit murder.
According to Marla Hicks,
the dad, Walter,
walked out on the family
ten years ago.
You think this
is Walter Hicks?
Look, everybody says he was
a mean son of a bitch.
His wife, his kids,
his ex-business partner, Fred,
they all hated him.
They all had motive.
(wry laugh)
Maybe he never left.
(grunts)
(crackling)
(crackling, flies buzzing)
There's some papers in here.
Well, they've
been exposed
to adipocere during decomp.
They were holed up
in the wall with the body.
Could be significant.
Yeah. Maybe QD can
help restore them.
First things first-- let's get
our mummy back to the morgue.
♪ ♪
(electric saw whirring)
(camera shutter clicking)
Okay. Let's run it.
Well, based on the tool
marks on the mummy's skull,
the killer's weapon of
choice was a hammer.
SIDLE:
We did find traces
on the mummy's clothing,
of sarsaponin.
It's from the yucca plant.
It's sold commercially to
eliminate strong odors.
The main distributor is
a company called
Stink Away.
So the killer must have
doused him with it,
tried to cover up
the stench of decomp.
So it is possible
that the family
didn't notice
the rotting corpse
in the wall.
DNA results.
Our mummy is a daddy.
FINLAY:
Really?
So it's Walter Hicks?
Uh, maybe, maybe not.
Here's where it gets
really interesting.
I compared his DNA to all three
of the Hicks siblings.
It turns out our mummy is
the biological daddy of Marla
but not Dwayne and Jimmy.
Uh-oh. Well...
looks like Lois Hicks
stepped out on her husband.
FINLAY:
Okay. We still don't know
who the mummy is
or who killed him.
And we still don't know
who killed Fred.
Actually, I may
have a lead on that.
Epthelials under
Fred's nails
belonged to one
of the Hicks brothers.
DWAYNE:
Fred attacked me.
Look, that's how I got these.
BRASS:
That's why you're reluctant
to give us your DNA.
You were afraid we were
gonna connect you to Fred.
Like I told you,
he attacked me.
I'd like to believe you, Dwayne.
I really would.
But Fred is dead.
And more than likely
you got those scratches
because he was struggling
for his life.
I didn't kill Fred.
Come on, Dwayne, you kicked
him out of his own house.
Hey, that is not his house!
When Mom died,
he should've left on his own.
So... so what?
I gave him a little push.
FRED: Dwayne, stop it!
You can't do this.
Yeah, I can. Here, Fred,
take your stuff and get out.
If your mother were here,
she'd be so ashamed of you all.
Yeah, well, she's not here--
she's dead. Time for you to go.
You cannot just
kick Fred out!
This is his house too.
BOTH:
Shut up, Marla!
This is our family home,
and he is
not part of our family!
(all shouting at once)
Oh, man.
You kicked him out
of the house in the morning.
He came back at night, right?
Maybe to get his things?
And that's when you killed him.
Hey, that's a great story.
That's your story;
I'm sticking with my story.
And if you don't believe me,
you can ask Debbie,
you can ask Marla,
ask them both.
BRODY:
No prints in the house
belonging to anyone
outside of the family,
and no sign of
the murder weapon.
Nick and I searched every
inch of that house.
Okay, so blood spatter
tells us
that Fred was killed
in the kitchen.
Tip of the knife
broke off in his chest.
Maybe the killer...
took the knife with him.
Oh, wait a minute...
maybe the knife
was still in his chest
when he slid out of the house.
And broke off
when he got run over.
Which means the knife
would still be out on that road.
Okay, expand the search area.
And you can take
boyfriend Greg with you.
Part of the blade.
Blood on it.
If we can find
the other piece
of the handle,
maybe we can get
some DNA, prints.
Well, I found one piece.
This is gonna
take a while.
♪ ♪
BRODY:
Ridge detail.
You any good at
jigsaw puzzles?
My dad gave me one
for my eighth birthday.
Empire State Building,
thousand pieces.
Did it in six hours.
By myself.
Let's see if we can
break your record.
Got a partial.
SANDERS: We've gotten
AFIS hits off of less.
I hear you're gonna
blow my mind.
Blood on the knife
is a match to our vic,
Fred Blanchard.
Which means it's definitely
the murder weapon.
Not exactly blowing my mind.
Oh, we're getting there.
We recovered a partial print
off of the handle of the knife.
It didn't match Dwayne Hicks.
So, we have three
other Hicks, right?
Debbie, Jimmy, and Marla.
None of the above.
Really?
BRODY:
But we did get a hit in AFIS.
Prints came back
to a long-lost member
of the Hicks family.
Walter.
Whoa.
Dear old not-so-dead Dad.
My mind is blown.
He was in the system
for assaulting a guy
in a bar fight 15 years ago.
So now we know the mummy
in the wall isn't Walter.
So who is he?
Walter Hicks is alive and well.
Came back to town...
killed Fred.
Did he kill the mummy, too?
We still have no idea
who that is.
Well, at least we know that the
mummy is Marla Hicks' father.
If Walter found out about it,
that is motive.
Yeah. Yeah, and-and
I sent the papers
walled up with the mummy to QD.
If I can restore them,
I bet they'll help us
figure out who the guy is.
♪ ♪
So you're saying that
Walter isn't my real dad?
That's what I'm saying, yeah.
Your biological father's name
was Tony Perrella.
He was a-a handyman.
Did some work around your house.
My mother had sex
with some handyman?
I think it was
a lot more than that.
I think she and Tony
were the real deal.
I found some letters
that he wrote to her.
You, uh, you want to
take a look?
Thank you.
"I never believed in soul mates
until I met you."
"When you told me you loved me,
"I felt like the luckiest
man in the world.
I can't wait to start
our life together."
Sounds to me like
she really loved him.
I think she was even going
to leave Walter for him.
FINLAY: Yeah, and the little
we know of Walter,
that was a very good decision.
Tony was reported missing
on March 20, 1991.
I was born in November.
So my mother probably didn't
even know that she was pregnant
when he was murdered.
She probably thought
Tony left her
because he was tired of
waiting on her to leave Walter,
you know what I mean?
Yeah, it must have
been hard on her.
Losing somebody that
she loved that much.
My mother always had
this sadness about her.
Now I know why.
(door opens)
BRASS:
You know, it's funny.
When we were looking for you,
we couldn't find any record
of a Walter Hicks since 2002.
But then we ran your full name,
Walter Douglas Hicks,
and wouldn't you know it,
there's a Walter Douglas
living in New Mexico.
RUSSELL:
Who just happened to use
his credit card here in Vegas
two days ago.
BRASS:
So it's been ten years, Walter.
What brings you
back to the city?
Gambling? Nightlife?
Or... maybe this.
BRASS: CSI found it
in your old house.
I haven't lived there
in ten years.
Tony Perrella's been
dead for 20.
Who?
Your handyman.
We have some invoices here
that said Tony spent a lot
of time at your house.
Doing repairs.
Your wife.
RUSSELL:
We also found love letters
that Tony wrote to your wife.
I'm pretty sure you
found them too, right?
And that's why you killed him.
Love letters?
That's all you got?
No, actually,
we have a lot more.
We have some, uh, some receipts.
For some, uh, 2x4s,
spackling, drywall,
from a local hardware store.
Right around the time that
Tony was reported missing.
RUSSELL: Yeah, don't forget
that large bottle
of Stink Away.
Stink Away. Right here.
BRASS: Ravenson Hardware
keeps impeccable records.
You remember Tony now?
Lois took the boys to
her mother for the week.
I... got Tony to
come to the house.
You think you can screw my wife?
Huh?
I love Lois.
You don't give
a damn about her.
You stay the hell away from her.
WALTER:
He said he wanted to
fight for her.
He lost.
You got away with murder.
Too bad Lois died, right?
Probably got a little worried,
maybe someone'd buy the house
and find the body.
So you came back
to move it.
And guess who shows up.
BRASS:
Your old business
partner, Fred.
What the hell
are you doing here?
Heard about Lois.
What? And you came
to pay your respects?
You never cared about her
when she was alive.
Why start now?
We know what happens
when you lose your temper.
Somebody ends up dead.
Fred threatened
to call the cops
about a financial dispute
we had ten years ago.
Financial dispute?
Oh, you mean that's when you
stole all the money
out of your business account
and left Fred
with nothing?
I didn't want to go to jail.
Take your hands off of me.
You come back to move the mummy
out of the wall,
but you leave a fresh body
in the kitchen?
I heard this big truck
pull up outside.
And I had to get
out of there in a hurry.
Yeah, that would be
the house stealers.
It's... long story.
You know, you're a very mean,
angry man, Mr. Hicks.
And anger's like a toxin.
It poisons everything
it touches,
especially your family
and also that house of yours.
Prison is full of mean
and angry people, Walter.
So you'll fit right in.
You are not seriously
doing this!
I'm going after him.
Hey! Hey!
Yeah, that's gonna help.
Do not do this.
Stuff is in there.
What? You're gonna
lock our stuff in there?
Oh, great, look at this.
Jimmy? Seriously?
Look at this.
You're so dumb.
...coming back.
DEBBIE:
No...!
Thank you for coming.
I didn't know who else to call.
DWAYNE: You cannot change
the locks on this house!
It's not your house,
dumb-ass!
JIMMY:
Like you said, bro,
possessing is nine-tenths
of the law.
It's possession, you idiot.
DWAYNE: Thank you.
Hey, arrest him, he's squatting.
Hell, shoot him.
Yeah.
No, no, no...
No one is shooting anyone.
MARLA:
It is just a house.
It's not worth
killing each other.
Shut up, Marla.
You're not even
our real sister anymore.
Yeah, you're barely
family, okay?
We have the same mother,
you idiots.
DEBBIE: Hey, are you guys
gonna do anything?
Do something.
What are you doing?
We're gonna do something.
DWAYNE: Good.
You are so dumb.
Why are you still
doing that?
Get off my lawn.
DWAYNE:
This is not your lawn.
It's the desert.
JIMMY:
Get off my desert.
SIDLE: Finn?
Finn, um...
(chainsaw buzzes)
(all the Hicks
shouting, "Whoa!")
You each want a piece
of the house?
Great. Let's divvy it up.
What do you want?
You want the living room
and the dining room?
Yeah?
No!
Would you like the bedroom
and the bathroom maybe?
Hey, hey, hey!
I'm just gonna chop it
right in half.
You can't chop up our house.
Okay. Is that good?
(all the Hicks shouting "No!")
Or, you know, there's
another way to settle this.
This house caused
a lot of damage
on the way up here.
Over $100,000.
Whoever owns the house
gets the bill.
Wait... the house isn't
even worth that much.
She stole it.
Yeah, give her the bill.
What?!
I never even wanted this house.
FINLAY:
And then we told Marla
that she could donate the house
to a charity or the city,
so she doesn't have
to pay the bill.
Smart.
It was actually Sara's idea.
Probably didn't hurt
to have some crazy lady
running around with a chainsaw.
You heard?
Yeah, I heard.
A little too familiar.
I don't get it.
What's that?
Well, I've been walking
around this place
the last couple days,
trying to find the problem.
This place is like a family.
You've got the best of the best.
That's true.
So why... why'd you
bring me here?
Best of the best
can always get better.
Right?
You know that's
only half an answer.
Jules, let's not do this.
I just don't want history
to repeat itself.
Well, that makes two of us.