You ever seen anything
like that?
I don't even know
what I'm looking at.
That's just wrong.
Lucky for you,
I come prepared
for this type of crisis.
"Habanero Massacre"?
Mmm!
It's a mercy killing
on a burrito this bad.
(car horn blaring)
Whoa, whoa, whoa, girl.
You sure about that?
(tires squealing, horn blowing)
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Control, this is CSI Brody.
We've got a single-car
collision, Tropicana,
block east of Nash,
injuries.
Paramedics are
on their way.
He's got a pulse,
but he's lost a lot
of blood.
He's got a really
nasty head wound here.
We've gotta move.
Engine's going up.
All right, I'm gonna try
to get him out of here.
Come on, boy, I got you.
I'll get his legs.
Come on. Come on.
Come on.
Okay...
Get him far enough back now.
I'm trying.
Ah, that's good,
that's good.
Wes Clyborn.
Seven Hills address.
Wes, Wes, my name's Nick.
You hang in there now.
Help's on the way.
Damn.
What?
He didn't hit his head.
This is a gunshot wound.
I didn't hear a shot
before the crash.
I definitely didn't hear two.
I think that's
a second GSW to the abdomen.
Looks like the same caliber.
They're-they're-they're
bleeding.
What are you
trying to say, Wes?
They're dying.
STOKES:
Who's dying, Wes?
Wes, talk to me.
Who's dying?
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
Grab those doors for us?
Hang in there, Wes.
You're in good hands now, bud.
They're gonna
take care of you.
EMT: We've got a GSW
to head and abdomen.
Okay. Get him on the monitor.
Full set
of stat labs.
Type and cross for packed
red cells for transfusion.
(nurses conversing
indistinctly)
We have O-neg
standing by.
16 or 18 gauge.
Excuse me, Nurse,
I'm with the Crime Lab.
I'm gonna need to take the
clothes he's wearing
with me, okay?
I'll see what I can do.
Prep him for a central line.
(alarm beeping)
Code blue.
He's in V-Tach.
DOCTOR:
Okay. Clear the room.
That includes you, Crime Lab.
Yes, sir.
Thank you.
Charge to 200.
100 milligrams.
Hey.
Oh, hey.
Morgan called.
Told me you'd followed
the victim here.
Wow, look at you.
You all right?
Uh, yeah.
I'm fine.
But, man, this guy's
in really bad shape.
And here's the thing.
He said that
there are others,
and that they're
dying or dead.
I'm not really sure
what to make of it.
So you think there's another
crime scene out there?
Maybe more victims, too,
you know what I mean?
Okay.
Why don't you clean yourself up.
I took the liberty of bringing
you a shirt from your locker.
Thanks.
You hang here, if our guy
pulls through, maybe
he'll tell you something.
More than just "thank you."
Hey, Nick...
way to go.
That took a lot of guts.
Thanks.
Registration belongs
to Elena Perez, 35.
Vartann's checking out
her address.
No known employer.
Looks like she's been
living here.
Blood on the headrest
is from transfer--
Wes Clyborn's
head wound.
No high-velocity
blood spatter.
No gunshot.
No HV on my side, either.
Significant blood pool
on the driver's seat.
Probably from the shot
to the abdomen.
That's a lot of blood.
So...
not shot in the car.
Shot before he got in the car.
Losing blood,
losing consciousness,
he runs
into the billboard truck.
You know,
considering his condition,
he couldn't have
gotten more than a mile or two.
Couple of square miles...
and still a lot
of ground to cover.
Our primary could be anywhere.
Crime Lab.
Hey. Well, I'm Nick. Stokes.
What's your name?
I'm Lauren.
Lauren, nice
to meet you.
Nice to meet you, too.
Yeah, thanks
for your help.
Sure.
I have the patient's
clothing for you.
Okay. Good.
Sorry.
Got a little scissory.
Oh, that's okay.
So... how's he doing?
He's good. Out of surgery.
Stable. Oh...
The doctor removed this
from Mr. Clyborn's abdomen.
Fortunately, internal
damage was minimal.
Only one bullet?
The one that penetrated
his brain's
gonna require
more attention.
A neurosurgeon's
flying in from L.A.
You've done this before.
Yeah, more times than any
one person should have to.
The owner of the Grand Am,
Elena Perez,
was evicted from her place
a month ago.
And no one has
reported her missing.
So I'm working on a warrant
for her cell phone records.
That might be the only
way to track her down.
What about the cell phone that
Nick recovered from the victim?
Yeah, Wes Clyborn.
He's a popular guy.
I traced most of the calls
to his friends.
And no one has ever heard
of Elena Perez,
and nobody knew
where he was last night.
One thing, though--
the last few calls,
they were all made
to the same number.
Do we know who?
There's no way to know.
It was a
"pay-as-you-go" cell.
Oh, great.
So totally untraceable.
Bullet entered the left
middle temporal lobe.
Houses the hippocampus
and related structures.
STOKES: Those are areas related
to his memory, right?
DOCTOR:
Right.
Generally, retrograde amnesia
exhibits a temporal gradient.
Last in, first out.
So things he learned in school,
his mother's name,
sense memories, there's a good
chance they remain
But the memory of
who shot him last night...
May or may not be there.
Okay.
So is he conscious?
Fully.
Soon as the neurosurgeon
arrives,
we prep him for surgery,
take him in.
What are his chances?
I don't think we'll know
till we get in there.
So if you're going
to talk to him, do it now.
Appreciate it.
Yeah.
(laughing):
Hey.
Look at that.
He's conscious.
How you doing, man?
You look good.
Thank you.
Yeah.
No.
Thank you.
The nurse said you saved me.
Yeah.
You don't remember
any of that, huh?
(sighs)
No. I'm sorry.
Wait, you don't have to
apologize to me, man.
You got a massive
head wound.
It's gonna take
some time.
So it's bad if the
beeps stop, right?
It's not good, no.
But don't worry
about that.
That's not
gonna happen.
Do me a favor, Wes.
Let me see your hands.
If you were in a struggle
with somebody, we might be able
to find something
that can help us out here.
Yeah, sure.
Whatever you need.
Ooh, looks like you put up
a hell of a fight.
WOMAN:
Why would anyone
want to hurt our son?
Did someone
try and rob him?
We don't know that, sir.
That's what we're
trying to find out.
You guys have any idea
where he was last night?
No.
Well, do you know who
he might've been with?
Wes has a lot of friends.
STOKES:
Okay.
But he still lives
at home with you, right?
Yeah, since he
graduated in May.
From 'SC.
He's still exploring
his options.
We give Wes his space.
He comes and he goes.
Not much more
we could tell you.
Except that
he's a good boy.
Do you recognize this woman?
No.
Why?
Name's Elena Perez.
She's the owner
of the car that Wes was driving.
I've never seen her before.
You're sure she's not
a friend of his?
I've seen enough of Wes's
friends to know this woman
would definitely not fit in
with any of them.
Now, if you'll
excuse us...
we'd like to see our son.
Dad's not exactly
Mr. Warmth, is he?
♪ ♪
♪ Wrapped me up in fur ♪
♪ Tied me to the bed ♪
♪ ♪
♪ She's more than a tease ♪
♪ She really means to please ♪
♪ She's not to be ignored ♪
♪ ♪
♪ She wants to be adored ♪
I think I found
our other victims...
the ones the guy in the hospital
was talking about.
What do you mean
found them? Where?
Here.
They're all over his shirt.
No surprise I found
the victim's blood.
But I found three
other contributors.
Three other people.
ANDREWS:
I know.
Is Elena Perez one of them?
Based on exemplars
from her car, yes.
What about the other two?
One is male.
Familial match to Elena.
I ran it through CODIS
and got a hit on her
brother, Juan Perez.
Convictions for assault,
armed robbery...
and, oh, yeah, carjacking.
Paroled six months ago.
What about the last contributor?
Unknown female.
Wow.
Look at all that carnage.
Wonder what the hell happened
right before Wes
Clyborn got in that car?
I don't know.
I can't get you any
closer to the primary.
I don't have any answers about
what might have happened or how.
Or why.
All I have is blood.
Sometimes blood is all you need.
Oh, boy.
Wish me luck.
Where are you going?
We need a blood whisperer.
No signs of forced entry.
Victim probably
knew her assailant.
Could have been a hotel
employee who had a key...
who had access.
M.E. estimates time of death
around midnight.
C.O.D. is
blunt force trauma,
consistent with the claw hammer.
Yeah.
Oh! You're killing me.
Tell me something I don't know.
Guys, your bosses
are paying me a lot of money
for this seminar.
Come on!
Okay, I'll give you a hint.
Look at my body.
The position
of my body.
Right, sorry, got it, um...
(clears throat)
Your hand appears to
be extending outward.
Good, good.
Why is that significant?
Look at the
blood smear.
I've made a blood angel here.
Why?
RUSSELL:
Well, at first blush, it
looks like you're trying
to reach your cell phone
that fell under
the lamp there,
but the blood angel shows
that your arm stopped,
so you didn't get
the phone.
You didn't call 911.
You got any ideas?
The assailant's
still in the room.
She's afraid to call.
Jules,
what do you say?
I say he's close, and there's
only one person in the world
who would dare to call me Jules.
(sighs)
(chuckles)
Okay, guys,
that's a 482.
We'll pick up after lunch.
I know what
you're thinking.
Of all the mock crime
scenes in all the world...
No, that is not
what I'm thinking.
It's good to see you.
I like
your scene.
Are you
on the registration list?
Uh, no.
Because I know
you don't like
to make social calls
unless, of course,
you want to make
your wife happy,
and I don't
see her around.
So what do you want,
Mr. Russell?
Straight to the
point, as usual.
Okay, uh... I need
a little help.
Open case--
blood's all we got, but,
oh, it's a good one.
We know how it ended
last time.
Yes, yes,
that's true, uh, but
this is just one case.
I'm already working
a crime scene.
You sure?
Yeah.
Okay.
Well, worth a shot.
Oh, yeah, uh, before
I go, I almost forgot.
The assailant was
still in the room,
uh, but your arm was
reaching out but not
to grab your cell
phone but to motion
to your daughter,
tell her to stay hidden.
I know you... you think
you hate me,
but the whole, uh,
lying on the floor,
playing the victim thing
kind of says you miss me.
Or not.
(claps hands)
Okay.
(grunts)
Lauren.
Hey.
Got your message.
What's going on?
It's Wes Clyborn.
Is he all right?
He's a little worked up.
What do you mean?
Why?
I don't know,
he won't talk to me.
Keeps asking for you.
All right, cool,
I'll talk to him.
Okay.
Thanks.
Hey, it's good
to see your appetite.
But you didn't eat
the Jell-O.
I remember something.
Okay.
Remember something
from last night?
I was in a room.
A room.
What kind of room?
Do you recognize it?
No, I'd never been
there before,
but th-there was a man.
And he had a gun.
Do you recognize him,
know his name?
No.
Was it that dude?
I tried to fight this guy off.
Don't worry about it.
He had a gun.
Next thing I remember,
I was running.
I had car keys, but
they weren't mine.
I-I took her car.
Her?
Do you mean Elena?
Elena Perez?
(sighs)
I don't know.
It's all right.
Is that her?
Yeah, yeah, sh-she
was there, but...
th-th-there was somebody
else, another girl.
Who?
I can see her, she...
She was beautiful.
You, uh, you had this pendant
in your pocket.
You were carrying
it around.
It must be important.
Think it was hers?
(sighs)
Vicky.
Vicky?
Her name's Vicky?
Yeah.
(chuckling):
All right, all right,
that's good.
That's going
to help us out.
Listen, Wes...
you and I are going
to figure this out together.
We're gonna find Vicky
and we're gonna find out
who did this to you.
I promise.
♪ ♪
Hey, ran ballistics
on the bullet
that was pulled out of
Wes Clyborn's stomach.
It matches a
round fired
at a liquor store
robbery four weeks ago.
Perp's still out there
along with the gun.
Huh. Liquor store robbery
would match Juan Perez's M.O.
And grabbing up
two rich kids at gunpoint fits
with what Nick has gotten
from Wes Clyborn
up to this point.
So does Henry's
DNA report.
The bullet had
Wes Clyborn's DNA.
Well, that makes sense.
It also had
tissue that belongs
to our unknown female.
Well, that means...
...the bullet traveled
through our unknown female...
...before landing
in Wes Clyborn.
Clyborn says he remembers
a girl named Vicky.
She was with him
when he was shot.
Girlfriend maybe.
Through-and-through.
The tissue on the bullet
says it wasn't a head shot.
She could still be alive.
She hasn't called for help.
Well, maybe she can't.
Maybe she's still being held.
Bleeding out
on a floor somewhere.
(sighs)
Wes might have been
the lucky one.
Think you're getting
kind of forgetful.
Must be all of that Zen master
living-in-the-moment stuff.
Yeah.
At least
you remembered
to put on socks.
Did you take a look at it?
Yes, I did.
It is a good one.
Yeah.
So?
I want to have
some ground rules.
Okay.
All right, number one,
you are not to call me Jules
in front of other people.
It is Finn.
Finn.
Number two,
we are never going
to talk about the past.
Sounds to me like you want
to live in the moment.
And when that Zen crap starts,
we need to have a safe word.
Pick one.
Um...
"Stop."
Would that work?
You got it.
All right.
And what about you--
do you have any rules?
I'm gonna have to hire
you on a temporary basis,
uh, as a consultant.
I've already run
that by HR.
Of course you have.
And...
legally, we need to pay
you a consulting fee.
Figured the case
was so fascinating, you'd
want to do it for nothing.
You know me so well.
And you know blood better
than anybody I know.
All right, I want
your best DNA person.
I don't want
your best tech.
I want your best mind.
You got it.
You got me.
FINN:
Wow.
The case file
did not do this justice.
Sanders, right?
Uh, Greg.
Finn.
You know, I get the whole E.R.
urgency over evidence thing,
but did you
cut out all these samples?
No.
But if I were still
working DNA, I would have.
No, no, no,
it's not you.
I get it, DNA is king
these days,
but people don't understand
that blood spatter
can often tell you more
than any test tube.
Russell says
you're the man.
Oh, did he?
Mm-hmm.
Hmm, I try
my best.
God, I hope somebody got some
pictures before the DNA moths
got to this.
(sighs)
Great.
We're not totally screwed.
Yeah, we're
pretty good
about using cameras around here.
Okay, we're going
to reconstruct
all the blood events
on these clothes
and we're gonna map every inch
by DNA contributor.
I have the DNA
reports right here.
Oh, good.
Oh, do you have a dummy?
♪ ♪
(woman singing indistinctly)
Wow, you truly are
the Blood Whisperer.
Stop.
Okay, so we've got
five blood events.
My logic suggests
a certain order.
Okay, let it bleed.
All right, so your victim
remembers a struggle
with Juan Perez.
Here is Juan's blood
on Wes's shirt.
Pattern indicates blunt force
trauma, close quarters combat.
But I don't think that Juan
was the only one
in there fighting.
RUSSELL:
Elena Perez.
So... brother and sister were
both mixing it up with Wes.
Both getting their blood on him,
and then, according to Wes,
Juan goes ballistic--
literally--
firing a bullet...
through our unknown female
and into Wes.
Okay, so that could be
girlfriend Vicky.
Could be.
Here's her HV spatter
from the through-and-through.
Of course, nothing
says "fight over"
like a good shot to the head.
And so do the gravitational
drops from Wes's head shot,
leaving the final
blood-soaked area
from the abdominal
gunshot wound.
Nice job.
Thank you.
So...
our kid wrestles
with two assailants,
gets shot twice.
But how the hell
did he get out of there?
Maybe he was left for dead.
Well, that does not
bode well for Vicky.
Hey, hey.
Hey.
I talked
to Juan Perez's PO.
He hasn't heard
from Juan in a week.
No current address
and no job on file.
(growls)
On the bright side,
I think I found Vicky.
Really?
How'd you do that so fast?
I just did a web search, man.
I punched in Vickys with
a connection to Wes Clyborn.
Of course.
I think I got a lot more
than I bargained for.
A newsletter from
Jonah Clyborn's financial firm?
Take a look
at the Christmas candids.
Vicky Sheldon?
Former assistant
to Jonah Clyborn,
filed for unemployment
two months ago.
It looks like she's holding
onto the boss pretty tight
before he let her go.
Yeah, maybe because she found
another Clyborn to hang onto.
What do you mean?
I went by Vicky Sheldon's place;
she wasn't there.
Landlord said that he hasn't
seen her the past 24 hours,
but he has seen plenty
of Wes Clyborn
the last few months.
Well, maybe this Juan
Perez dude graduated
from carjacking to hit man.
And maybe my next search
turns up a connection
between him and the dad.
You really think the old man
would put out a hit
on his own son?
Hey,
over a woman?
Anything's possible,
I guess.
Look,
you said it yourself, right?
This guy isn't exactly
Mr. Warmth.
No.
No, he's not.
Mr. Clyborn?
Thank you
for coming down.
I know you've already spoken to
my colleagues at the hospital,
but I just
have a few more questions
for you.
What about?
Vicky Sheldon.
She worked for you
as your personal assistant
for over a year.
That is, right up until...
two weeks ago,
when she was fired.
Vicky was one of several
personal assistants.
Yeah, but probably the only one
who's dating your son.
Am I right?
News to me.
So,
that wasn't the reason
why she got her pink slip?
SIDLE:
And...
how long have you known
about the relationship?
Wes told me about it
a month ago.
Do you approve?
Wes is an adult.
He makes his own decisions.
That wasn't a yes.
Honestly, I think
she was using my son.
How's that?
While Vicky was employed
by my husband, I learned that
Wes was supplementing her wages
with checks drawn
from Jonah's business account.
I told Jonah to fire her.
Mrs. Clyborn, are you
sure that Wes was the one
that was paying her bills?
What exactly are you suggesting?
RUSSELL:
Okay, let's see.
Three days ago,
a car crashed into the wall
outside of Vicky Sheldon's home.
Just barely missed going
through her picture window.
So?
So...
by the time the police arrived,
both the car
and the driver were gone.
And Vicky didn't want
to talk about it,
and nobody saw anything
but the car.
Not many fender-busted Bentleys
get sold for scrap around here.
Oh, yeah, and, um,
car's registered in your name.
I wasn't driving it.
Wes told me he hit
a fire hydrant.
Well, that's got to be
a little infuriating.
More engine than
he could handle.
No, I mean,
kid lives at home,
spends your money,
wrecks your car.
Late at night,
outside the home
of your ex... assistant.
That's got to grind at you.
I know you aren't
accusing me of something.
If Wes wanted to go
slumming with the help,
that was his prerogative.
Kid didn't deserve
to get killed over it.
But that's on him.
Not me.
(clears throat)
Ah.
New lab coats.
Although,
I ordered periwinkle,
not royal blue.
They're not for you.
This work smock is from the
trunk of Elena Perez's car.
And this one, I just found
searching Vicky
Sheldon's apartment.
Vicky and Elena worked together?
Identical smocks.
And they definitely
know each other.
I found Elena's number written
on a note in Vicky's place.
Working with a lady
who's living in her car.
That's a doozy of a drop
from Vicky's previous job.
So maybe Vicky wanted
to cushion the fall
with some Clyborn money.
Got Juan and Elena
to help her rob Wes,
the rip-off went bad,
and Wes escaped?
Laverne and Shirley
go femme fatale.
Love it.
And I would love
to know where those
smocks were employed.
Can you please
check them for trace?
Any answer could help
us find our primary.
Hey.
Finally got
cell phone records
for Wes, Juan and
Elena last night.
Last calls were made
at the same time
in the same vicinity.
Got the cell phone towers.
Let's see where
the coverage overlaps.
Overlap places all
three callers...
(beeping)
Here.
STOKES:
Arroyo Horizons Business Park.
Why would they all be there
on a Saturday night?
LVPD.
Site manager said
this was the only facility
that wasn't locked down.
Got blood.
Shoe impression.
Yep.
Looks like it's coming
from back there.
STOKES:
Vicky Sheldon.
Body's cold.
She's been here
for a while.
Same story here.
Elena Perez?
It's hard to tell
from what's left of her face.
What the hell happened in here?
Well, it's not like
Wes Clyborn
can really help us out
right now.
No, but I know who can.
Yeah, the only guy we know
who walked out of here.
Juan Perez.
He's got a lot to answer for.
(shutters clicking)
Fabulous Las Vegas.
Not so fabulous for her.
SIDLE:
Elena Perez's car
said she was down on her luck.
Looks like her luck ran out.
Still in full rigor.
T.O.D. is approximately
18 to 24 hours ago.
Same time frame
as this poor girl.
Vicky Sheldon, GSW
through and through.
There's quite a
blood pool here.
ROBBINS:
Bullet probably severed
her left hepatic artery.
Well, if that's the case,
she lost consciousness and
then bled out rather quickly.
PHILLIPS: Got off easy
compared to her friend.
SIDLE:
Massive blunt force trauma.
Nearly every bone
in her face is smashed.
SIDLE:
Overkill.
Rage.
The wounds
show a distinctive pattern.
Could be brass
knuckles maybe.
Maybe.
But how do you explain
the punctures?
I might be able
to answer that question.
Brass knuckles included.
Could have a partial
palm print here.
Looks like what happened
in Las Vegas
kind of stayed on Las Vegas.
Well, I see your palm print,
and I raise you
a knee impression
and a footprint.
What kind of shoes
was Wes Clyborn wearing?
Uh, dress shoes.
Why?
These aren't dress shoes.
They're work boots.
And they look like they are
hauling ass out of here.
Right out the back door.
Work boots weren't
the only thing hauling ass.
Mm-hmm.
Tire treads
and boot prints.
Got some paint.
Could be transfer.
It looks like we've got
some trace here.
White and crusty.
Not much different
than what's in your fridge.
Sodium bicarbonate.
Trace from the boot print
is baking soda?
HODGES:
Specifically, the chemical
formulation used
in industrial cleaning supplies.
Still pretty generic.
Doesn't get us any closer
to tracking Juan.
Well, if you want unique,
I've got just your color.
Royal crimson metallic.
Auto paint transfer
from the loading bay
at the crime scene.
Used exclusively
on one vehicle model,
Austin Healy B-100.
From 1955 to 1957.
That's a hell of a nice car.
I don't see Juan
Perez owning it.
Maybe he was working on it.
Soda blasting.
Sodium bicarbonate
applied through
compressed air.
Used by auto-detailing places
to prep a car
that's about
to be repainted.
Perhaps with royal
crimson metallic.
Maybe Juan borrowed the car.
If you owned a classic ride
like a '56 Austin Healy,
I doubt you'd take it
to the corner body shop.
No.
I'd go to the best
to pimp my ride.
(man rapping indistinctly)
♪ ♪
That guy there.
Juan Perez?
LVPD.
Your parole officer's
been looking for you.
So have we.
I guess you found me.
Hmm?
(grunts, hissing)
(grunts)
(tires screech)
VARTANN:
Oh.
Ooh. That had to hurt.
(grunts in pain)
Maybe you can fix that dent
before we take you downtown.
(scoffs, panting)
♪ ♪
♪ When I was nine years old ♪
♪ My daddy made me see ♪
♪ The story of the railroad ♪
♪ And how it came to be ♪
♪ He said the men
who laid it down ♪
♪ Had left their own hometowns ♪
♪ And broke their backs
to give us traction ♪
♪ And that's what he did
for me ♪
♪ Ne'er do wells ♪
♪ And woebegones ♪
♪ Show your face ♪
♪ For we were wrong ♪
♪ Ne'er do wells ♪
♪ And woebegones ♪
♪ Feel no shame ♪
♪ It won't be long ♪
♪ ♪
♪ Ha ♪
♪ Come on ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ ♪
♪ Ha ♪
♪ Mm-mm-hmm ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ ♪
♪ Ha ♪
What took you so long?
I've been busy today.
We recovered
Juan Perez's gun.
We're running it.
Well, I can tell you right now
that Juan fired that gun.
All right.
Blood pools from Wes Clyborn's
two gunshot wounds.
He was shot standing, falls.
Bleeds from the head
and the gut.
And over here, HV spatter,
another blood pool.
RUSSELL: Which comes
from Vicky Sheldon's GSW,
the through-and-through,
which ends up in Wes.
Okay, so, bang, bang.
Two gunshot victims.
Efficient, expedient.
Nothing in common...
with this.
The beating
of Elena Perez.
Yeah.
Look at all of that blood.
Not efficient.
Not expedient.
No. I calculated
roughly ten to 12 blows
to the head
with the murder weapon.
And then this knee impression.
At first,
I thought
that it was the killer.
But the void from the castoff
and spatter
is actually
on the other side of her.
So, the killer was on
this side, which means
that the knee impression
was not from the killer.
It was from somebody who came
after the beating.
Maybe somebody
who wanted to help.
Somebody like a brother.
Where are you going with this?
Juan may have pulled
the trigger,
but I don't think
he was the trigger.
It's a little Zen.
Okay, so,
our current assumption
is that Juan Perez
held Wes Clyborn here
at gunpoint, right?
Right.
All right.
So, let me ask
you a question.
You're an ex-con with a gun
at my back.
Okay.
And you are
ready to use it.
Oh! (chuckles)
Where's my safe word?
You don't need one.
You have a gun...
and I don't.
And all of this blood says
that I managed
to punch you in the face,
not once,
but over half a dozen times.
A rich kid takes down
an ex-con with a gun?
How does that happen?
It doesn't.
You make a good case.
Juan Perez's blood
makes the case.
He may have walked out
with that gun,
but I don't think
he brought it.
Doesn't look good, Juan.
Career criminal
running from the cops,
gun with your prints
found in your work locker.
So why all
the talk?
I mean, you got me,
and you got the gun.
And ballistics confirms
that you used it
against Wes Clyborn
and Vicky Sheldon.
If you don't mind,
I have one question.
Am I going to give it up,
right?
Why else you think
I'm sitting here
without some half-asleep,
court-appointed,
public pretender
sitting next to me?
That wasn't my question.
We have your sister Elena's
cell phone records
that shows that
she called you
the night of the murders.
My question is, why?
Why do you think?
I think she needed you
because she was scared
for herself
and her friend Vicky,
whose ex had been calling her
all night long.
He tried to ram his car
through her apartment
a couple of days
before that,
but now he had a bigger head
of steam going.
He wanted what was his...
and he came for it.
Vicky...
It's over!
You got that part right.
Hey!
What's going on?
RUSSELL:
How am I doing so far?
You were just trying
to protect your sister.
You just didn't count
on the rich boy
having brought a street gun
to the party.
(grunting)
(yelping)
(screaming)
RUSSELL:
You came to,
you saw Wes
beating your sister,
and you had to stop him.
You had to protect the family.
Get off her!
Juan, put the gun down, please!
(gunshot)
You had no other choice.
(whimpering)
RUSSELL:
Your sister was already dead.
You knew how things would look,
so you ran.
This is your lucky day.
There's the pen,
and there's the paper.
Write it down.
(sniffles)
Yeah, I was always
the troublemaker.
Life wasn't fair,
so I made it fair.
But Elena never complained.
Elena worked hard.
Elena had faith.
(voice breaking):
And the one time
that she needed me--
someone like me...
...I failed her.
(sniffles)
How the hell do you know
what went on in that room?
I have
a very smart friend.
She's your friend, too.
(sniffles)
Give us a minute, will you?
Tried to take my hallway walk.
Cops wouldn't let me leave.
I'm not going home...
am I?
No.
Did I hurt Vicky?
You hurt 'em all, Wes.
Two people are dead
because of you.
I remembered something
this morning.
I loved her.
(sighs)
I know I did.
The person you say did this...
...I don't even know him.
Neither do I, man.
That was very nicely done.
You did all the work.
I did, didn't I?
And here's your...
dollar back.
Like you said,
I'm not really in it
for the money.
Don't you ever miss it?
I mean, you've been out
of the game now,
how long?
You know how long.
You want back in?
You asking?
Oh, come on.
Don't make me beg.
I like it when you beg.
I have my own envelope.
My expenses.
Party table rental,
two smocks, some paints.
It's all in there.
Come on. What do you think?
(sighs)
I don't know.
I really don't know.
Okay.
I will think about it.
I may call you.
I may answer.
Wait. Whoa.
Whoa-ho!
Nobody calls me Diebenkorn
around here.
It's D.B.