WOMAN:
911. What is your emergency?
No, I can't give you directions
to the Luxor.
Look for the searchlight
pointing straight up.
You can't miss it.
MAN: Sir, this line
is for emergencies only.
911. What is
your emergency?
911. What is your emergency?
WOMAN: No, ma'am,
the fire department won't fish
a rat out of your pool.
Even if it's the size of a dog.
911.
What is your emergency?
WOMAN:
There's a dead man in my bed.
And how do you know he's dead?
I performed CPR,
but he's not...
he's not breathing.
There's no heartbeat.
Okay, ma'am, I have you
at 5415 Deertrail in Henderson.
That's right.
I'll send officers out
right away,
and I'll notify the coroner.
Don't worry about the coroner.
I'll call him.
(siren whooping)
♪ ♪
We need to keep Doc
out of here.
This will tear his heart out.
Yeah, been there before.
Well, then again,
maybe it's not
what it looks like.
Well...
a cheating wife and
her dead lover?
You see something I don't see?
Yeah.
A crime scene that has yet
to be processed.
♪ Who are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
(cell phone ringing)
Hey, Doc.
Hey, D.B.
We've got a
crime scene.
And you're delivering
a personal invitation?
Your wife's fine.
What are you talking about?
The crime scene is
at your house, Doc.
(siren wails, stops)
So you and, uh,
Dan Traxler--right--
were doing research.
Yes, that's--
that's right.
So what'd you do,
um, take off
all your clothes and jump
into bed for research?
I don't appreciate where
you're going with this, Jim.
Judy, explain how a naked man
ended up dead in your bed.
I can't.
We were talking
in the living room.
I got a phone call.
Hey, hon.
Our grandson has colic,
and it's driving
our daughter crazy.
We must have talked
for almost 20 minutes.
Where was Traxler
at this time?
In the living room, but when I
walked back inside, he was gone.
I'm sorry. I just...
JUDY:
Dan's not the kind of person
who just up and leaves,
so I called his cell phone.
(cell phone ringing)
(gasps)
I don't know.
I thought maybe
he got the wrong idea about us.
You know,
because of the wine,
or I-I don't know,
I might have hugged him.
Judy, if you were having
an affair, just cop to it.
It can't get any worse
than this.
♪ ♪
(music stops)
(camera shutter clicking)
This is just so terrible. I...
Dave, just try and stay focused.
Okay.
Is it okay if I...
swab his face?
Yeah, go ahead.
PHILLIPS: You know they
celebrated their 25th
wedding anniversary in October?
Want to talk about how he died?
Yeah.
There's no
obvious injuries.
Dan Traxler, 45 years old.
He's not her type.
Yeah, what type is that?
Doc.
Doc Robbins is her type.
(device beeping)
95 degrees.
He hasn't been
dead long.
Maybe a couple hours.
There's blood
in the mouth.
Maybe he bit his lip.
Yeah, but you usually
don't find blood
with a heart attack.
JUDY:
Al. God.
I'm so glad you're here.
No, no, no. No, wait here.
Wait here.
I'm sorry, Al.
You got to back off
and let us do our job.
Jim, I need to speak
to my wife.
I can't let you do that.
Please.
Sorry.
Let me talk to him.
I'll fill you in, okay?
BRASS: Okay, no sign
of forced entry.
The neighbors didn't see
or hear anything.
The victim's car was
parked a block away
and had been
ticketed before.
What are you thinking--
an affair?
Well, yeah, yeah.
I mean, I think the guy
crapped out in bed, right?
And she's not coming clean
because she knows all of us.
Greg, you got anything to add?
Yeah. There's, uh, blood
in the guy's mouth.
Hadn't gone there.
All right.
Well, we need backup.
We got to play this smart,
treat it as a homicide.
I need to take
Judy downtown.
Okay. Let me
process her first.
Okay, here's a
helpful hint:
She said she
was on her cell phone
when whatever
happened happened.
You might want to
check that out.
Mrs. Robbins.
Yes.
D.B. Russell.
I-I am so sorry
that we have to meet under
these circumstances.
Yeah.
I'm going to need
to see your cell phone.
Yes.
And who... who's Pam?
Pam is our daughter.
That was a long phone call.
Yeah.
Where'd you take it?
Um...
I was in the back,
on the lanai.
Okay. Well, you relax.
We're gonna sort this out.
Thank you.
Hey, doll.
No, no, I'm... I'm at a scene.
No, it's okay. I-I can talk.
As a matter of fact,
I can talk for about 20 minutes.
Gee, I wish you could see this.
Their geraniums are doing
so much better than ours.
Hold on a sec.
I called, uh,
Sylvia Sloane from days
to do the post.
Okay.
Um, I'll stay
with the body.
Good.
Don't want any questions
about how we handled this.
Right.
Doc...
Mrs. Robbins?
I'm CSI Brody.
I'm here to process you.
Doc.
Uh, you can't
come in here.
Morgan's processing Judy.
Could you grab her something
to wear out of that top drawer?
Uh, yeah.
I'll make sure
she gets something.
Greg, do me a favor.
Run this scene for me--
Doc Robbins, coroner--
not Al Robbins, husband.
It... it's still early.
All right.
Our victim is a white male, 45.
Name's Dan Traxler.
He was found naked in bed,
here, supine.
No traumatic
injuries.
Blood on his
teeth, gums.
ALS indicates semen.
That's her side of the bed.
What?
That's Judy's side
of the bed.
25 years of marriage,
and we never changed sides ever.
Ever.
Doc, you really got to go.
So I'm, uh, guessing
by the increased personnel,
Dan didn't die
of a heart attack, huh?
(sighs)
May I see your
hands, please?
Hey. Hey.
Hey.
Good thing about evidence--
it works both ways.
It can prove guilt,
and it can prove innocence.
You know, Jim Brass
didn't believe a thing I said.
If I was going
to have an affair,
I wouldn't be having it
in my house, in my bed.
You know, every marriage
has its problems,
but that bed's sacred.
You cross that line,
and there's no going back.
Her fingers are green, right?
How did you know that?
You deadhead, don't you?
That's what you were doing
on the phone with your daughter?
Yes.
That's just sleep deprivation.
Strap him into the car.
Take him for a drive.
I'm sure that will put him
to sleep.
Well, did he nap today?
RUSSELL:
Stems were still moist.
Just been pruned.
There was a pile
of brown leaves
on the table--about 20 minutes
worth, as a matter of fact.
Best way to keep
geraniums in bloom.
Ah. I knew there was a secret.
You know what to do, right?
Test for chlorophyll.
BRASS: How are things
between you and Judy?
Solid.
Did you know the victim,
Dan Traxler?
No.
Your wife knew him.
Judy's friends
with a lot of people.
We found an ATM
receipt last night
with a large
cash withdrawal.
Judy has girls' night out
on Tuesdays.
Except, last night,
she stayed in.
Are you investigating
this incident, Jim, or my wife?
Look, Al, you know,
you're not the only guy
to get blindsided.
My ex-wife screwed around
on me for a year.
Me. Go figure.
That's your marriage, not mine.
Oh, okay.
Well, consider this.
They're drinking wine.
They went from the living
room to the bedroom.
I don't believe
it was like that.
All right, look, this is more
information than I'm prepared
to give you anyway, okay,
but I see a pattern here.
Judy's night out was
Traxler's night in.
Th-There's got to be
more than that.
Look, as my friend,
I am asking you to broaden
the scope of your
investigation.
You gotta prepare
yourself, Al.
because this is only
gonna get worse.
No, you gotta prepare
yourself to be wrong.
Your past is clouding
your judgment,
and I expect more
than that from you.
You okay?
Want to take a minute?
Dr. Sloane...
what do we know?
Daniel Traxler is an otherwise
healthy adult male.
No traumatic injuries.
No lacerations.
No broken bones.
Heart tissue
shows no signs
of ischemia
or infarction.
So, no heart attack?
SLOANE:
I sent blood samples
to Tox, tissue sections
to Histo-Path.
And the penile swab?
Sent it to DNA.
Did anything present?
(heavy sigh)
Just this.
ROBBINS:
Frenulum is torn.
That explains the
blood in his mouth.
RUSSELL:
He was smothered.
I'm sorry, Al.
This looks like a homicide.
Smothering is passive.
It's got female
written all over it.
Can you just process
the bathroom?
(shutter clicking)
You know, if it was
anybody else,
I'd buy the whole
cheating wife thing, but...
it's Doc.
He's amazing.
Nothing ever slows him down.
He's got this great
outlook on life.
And every day he comes home
and takes off his legs.
HODGES:
Sildenafil. Wow.
At least he's keeping up
his end of the bargain.
Why would Judy
do this to him?
SANDERS:
Don't the Robbins
have a cat--a gray tabby?
(shutter clicks)
Yeah. Her name's Cinder.
The reason I know that
is because that's the name of
my first cat, who,
ironically, died in a fire
of mysterious origins.
My stepfather was
allergic to cats.
I found a box of condoms
under the sink where Doc
couldn't see them.
At least Judy cared enough
about him not
to give him a disease
while she was
screwing around.
Hodges, you need to
shift it into neutral.
I'm gonna go look
for that litter box.
♪ ♪
(rattling)
Cinder?
Hey,
have you seen that cat?
I think I spooked it.
Yeah.
He, uh, ran in that room.
What have you got?
Carpet impressions, but...
they're not the
same shape or size
as anything else in the room.
Maybe it's a table or a lamp.
Then it would've
blocked the pathway
to the sofa.
SANDERS:
Well, whatever it was,
it's not here now.
BRASS:
So, Judy...
Tell me more
about Dan Traxler.
Uh, he was a-a genealogist.
I found him online when I
was looking for somebody
to do Al's family tree.
And when did
the affair start?
There was no affair.
Come on.
The lingerie, candles,
romantic music...
Al and I like to keep
things interesting.
Judy, you're not here
because, you know,
you're having an affair.
I really don't care.
You're here because
it's a homicide.
I did not cheat
on my husband
and I did not kill Dan.
Am I free to go?
Nope.
These marks were left
on your living room rug.
Do you know what
made them?
No.
BRASS: Judy, whoever
you're protecting,
it's not gonna matter
in the end.
Albert, I can't
let you see her
until I've confirmed
your alibi.
Captain, I-I'd like to ask
Mrs. Robbins a question,
if that's cool with you.
As long as you don't pass notes
from your new best friend.
BRODY: Did Mr. Traxler
bring anything
to the house with him?
Uh, yes. He, uh...
brought a-a-a briefcase.
We didn't find
a briefcase.
He definitely brought
it into the house.
Was there anyone
else in the house
besides you and Mr. Traxler?
Yes.
Whoever killed him.
Hey.
You were married.
Do you think it's odd
that our dead genealogist
was on Judy's
side of the bed?
Well...
you choose a side
early on in a relationship,
and you pretty much
stay there,
unless you're...
mixing it up with
some extracurricular.
Did you find semen?
Yeah.
Henry's testing it now.
We think that Traxler
might have had a briefcase.
Only, Morgan and I
weren't able to find
one at the scene.
Judy have time to ditch it?
I don't see how she could.
She was on the phone for 20
minutes with her daughter.
Two minutes later
she called Traxler's cell,
and a minute after that,
911.
And they kept her on the phone
until a patrol showed up.
Besides, why would she
ditch his briefcase,
but not blow out the
candles in the bedroom,
or turn off the
Marvin Gaye?
(sighs)
Wow.
Marvin Gaye?
"Sexual Healing"?
Why else would you
play Marvin Gaye?
Well, if that
briefcase is missing,
it had to be
important to someone.
You need to find out more
about your dead genealogist.
And always get permission
from the church
or the cemetery administrator
before you start
any grave rubbing.
WOMAN: Doesn't friction
damage the stone?
Yes, it can.
That's why I use
synthetic rice paper
and light, even strokes.
There, okay?
All right, you guys
go out and do it.
Have fun.
Okay, thank you.
You bet.
Donna Hoppe?
Yeah?
Your secretary told me
you would be here.
My name is Greg Sanders; I'm
with the Las Vegas Crime Lab.
Sanders? that's
Americanized, right?
Yeah.
Shortened from Sanderson.
My father's side was
from Harstad, Norway.
And your mother's?
Hojems.
From Oslo.
How many were named Olaf?
My grandfather was
Olaf Hojem the eighth.
(laughs)
You should hyphenate.
Hojem is an infinitely
more interesting name
than Sanders.
But if you wanted
a genealogy lesson,
you should have shown up
earlier, for my seminar.
Actually, I'm here
on other business.
Mrs. Hoppe, I'm very sorry
to tell you this,
but your business partner,
Dan Traxler,
was killed last night.
Oh, my God.
How?
What happened?
Well, we're investigating
it as a homicide.
(gasps)
Oh, my...
Do you know if he
had any enemies?
Anyone threaten him
or your business?
No.
Dan was a prince.
Everybody loved him.
Genealogy was his life.
If he had any faults,
it was that he got too
close to his clients.
What about his
personal life?
No, he wasn't seeing anyone.
Did he usually
carry a briefcase?
Yes. It was
his second office.
What was in it?
Um, his work,
his research.
Did he have a client list?
Um...
Client names, phone numbers.
Oh, great, thanks.
Mrs. Hoppe,
was it normal
for your partner
to meet with his
clients at night?
Yes, we try to accommodate
their schedules.
If they're working, then
we visit them after work.
There's a Judy Robbins
on this list.
Do you know her?
No, I think he
finished that project.
I'm sorry.
Will you excuse me, please?
Thank you for not
asking how I'm doing.
David's been asking me
every five minutes.
Well, he's concerned.
As we all are.
I know what you're thinking.
Well, uh...
it's just hard enough
when someone you
love's in trouble.
It's harder still when
you're dealing with betrayal.
You don't think about that
when you have an affair.
Judy had an affair before?
Not her. Me.
Everyone assumes
that I can't...
a-and I wanted to
see if I could.
Almost destroyed Judy
and our marriage.
When I was married to Eddie,
he would hurt me,
and then...
I would hurt him back,
and it was just...
years of back and forth.
That what you think
happened here?
(phone ringing)
Cath, I have to take this,
I'm sorry.
Yeah. Oh, of course.
Yeah, thanks for getting back
to me so quickly.
I got your name
from a colleague.
My wife needs a criminal
defense attorney.
It's a murder.
Hey, Russell wants an update.
You know, for a guy
who seems so laid back,
Russell can be terrifying.
Terrifying? No.
I mean, maybe a bit
odd or demanding.
But, hey, as long as
you get the job done
as fast as humanly
possible--
Does he ever yell
out your name?
I like to think of it
as a respectful shout.
Hm.
DNA results?
There.
Help yourself.
All right,
semen stains on the bed sheets
are an admixture of DNA
from Doc and Judy.
I didn't find semen
from Traxler anywhere,
but I found his saliva.
On a pillow?
Likely the murder weapon.
Found touch DNA, too.
SANDERS: So the killer
didn't wear gloves.
And the DNA's male,
and... not Doc Robbins'.
I'm running it through
CODIS right now.
And our guy's not in CODIS.
I'll give you anything
if you tell Russell.
So, the DNA's
a dead end?
Um... well, not necessarily.
We could expand our search
from an individual
to a family.
If it gets
a hit in CODIS,
that family could
lead us to the killer,
like a DNA family tree.
If the killer
has family in CODIS,
we'll get a partial match.
Just--just one problem.
Uh, can't exactly push
a button to do this search.
You need
the sheriff's approval.
Okay, I will...
mention that when
I talk to the sheriff.
Was there something else?
No.
Okay.
I can't believe somebody
hurt that nice man.
Ms. Smith, you were on Dan
Traxler's client list.
You hired him?
Yes.
See, I'm getting married.
And my dad's dead;
his folks, too.
My mom's not close to
our family, but I thought
if I found her father--
my grandfather--
maybe he could walk me
down the aisle.
So you wanted Mr. Traxler
to find him?
Yeah. He said
if my grandfather was alive,
he could track him down.
Did he?
I don't know.
We were supposed
to meet again today.
He was excited
to show me new documents
and records he found.
He was like a paper detective.
Mr. Traxler ever...
behave inappropriately
towards you?
(laughs):
God, no.
The guy was a monk.
He lived in the past.
"Feasted on history."
His words.
Ask his other clients--
they'll tell you the same thing.
I spoke with a couple
of them before I hired him.
Oh, did you speak
to Judy Robbins?
Yeah. She couldn't say
enough nice things about him.
I was really counting on having
my grandfather at my wedding.
What is your
grandfather's name?
Samuel Francis Duggan.
Isn't that a nice name?
♪ And here's to you,
Mrs. Ro-hah-bins... ♪
That's not funny, and I'm busy.
So if you have any results
for me, cough 'em up.
(clears throat)
Lipstick on the victim's face
was a match to Judy's brand.
Well, she said
she gave him CPR.
I'll bet that's not
all she gave him.
I'm just saying
that when I play
"Sexual Healing,"
it's foreplay.
Yeah, well, playing it
for yourself doesn't count.
(wry laugh)
What about
the cat litter?
Not a match
to the Robbins' cat.
It contained urine
with alprazolam.
Why would a cat need
antidepressants?
Antidepressants are commonly
prescribed for felines
undergoing prolonged
medical treatment.
And... check this out.
One sweep of my radiation
isotope identifier...
(beeping)
Rings like a Super Jackpot.
So the cat urine
is radioactive?
Iodine 131.
It's used to treat
thyroid cancer, and it has
a half-life of eight days.
Now, I'm thinking
that the sick cat belonged
to the illicit lover.
No.
No way. I checked Traxler's
shoes, office, house--
no kitty litter
and no kitty.
There's always the
"unknown accomplice" theory.
Or Judy's telling the truth
and someone else
was in that house.
Either way, you're looking
for a sick cat.
Chemotherapy's expensive, done
only by veterinary specialists.
Okay, so then get me a
list of those specialists
and every cat they've treated
in the last eight days.
Get me a warrant.
There's a pet-vet privilege.
Seriously?
No can get you
a list of furless
felines without it.
(groans)
RUSSELL:
Henry,
what do you got?
Ah, the CODIS
familial search
found our killer's
first order relative.
A Jimmy Duggan.
"First order"
meaning father, brother,
son of our killer, right?
Here's what I've got.
Traxler's client,
Carla Duggan Smith,
was looking for
her grandfather--
Samuel Francis Duggan.
Maybe Traxler found Sam,
and then Sam found Traxler?
So now we need to find Sam.
Hey, maybe Jimmy knows
where he is.
I actually did
some extra credit.
I could tell you
where Jimmy is.
Same place he's been
the last 13 years.
That's almost too easy.
Whatever you want,
I didn't do it.
(chuckles)
It says here that
you're serving
a life sentence
for armed robbery
That third strike,
that--that's a bitch.
I'll bet.
I want to ask some questions
about your family, specifically
Samuel Duggan.
My old man left when I was 13.
He divorced my crazy
bitch of a mother.
I mean, she was always
high on something.
Used to beat the crap out of me.
That must've been rough.
Yeah, well,
you won't see me crying.
When the old man left,
I did, too, you know?
On my own at 13.
No wonder I ended up
in the big house, right?
Do you have any
brothers, Jimmy?
No.
I got one sister--Jasmine.
She likes to pretend I'm dead.
And, of course, the old man, he
could have more, I don't know.
No, I'm looking for full
male relatives, no steps.
You have any sons?
Nope.
What did that bastard do?
Maybe nothing, maybe murder.
Well, hot damn!
We'd be cell mates.
(both chuckling)
Hey, do you think your mom
might know where Sam is?
Nah, doubt that.
If she's sober,
you can ask her yourself.
She lives in Primm.
I searched all
our databases--
all I got was Samuel
Duggan's date of birth.
Oh, archival databases are
notoriously incomplete.
He could live in another state;
he could be dead.
But Dan would have
discovered that weeks ago
and informed his client.
So...
let's find Jimmy's
father Sam by doing
the Smith-Duggan
family tree.
Okay, tell me
what you know.
All right, uh, my boss
talked with Jimmy Duggan.
His dad, Sam,
married Eunice Carter
in 1956 or '57,
right out
of high school.
Mm-hmm.
They had Jimmy in 1958
and his sister Jasmine
in '67.
Now, Jasmine
Duggan married
Gary Smith in '88,
and they had Carla
in 1990.
Oh, she's the client
who wanted to be
walked down the aisle
by a male relative, right?
Right. According to Jimmy,
there are no other
male relatives.
(sighs):
Okay, Hojem-Sanders...
the last document signed
by Samuel Duggan
was the divorce decree--
as far as we know--
in 1971.
All we have to
do is find it.
(pats Sanders' thigh)
BRAD LEWIS: She's done
answering questions.
Judy, let's go.
(sobbing sighs)
Oh... Al.
(crying)
I just want to go home.
Listen, Mr. Lewis
will drive you home.
Al... we need to talk.
I want to explain everything.
It's just...
Judy, Judy...
I need to believe in you--
in us--
and if we talk
and I'm not convinced...
it'll all be gone, and
I'm not prepared for that.
(whispers):
Okay.
Well, when you're
ready to talk...
I'll be at home.
Sit down, Hojem-Sanders.
Have I got a story for you.
Sam and Eunice's
divorce decree.
And here's the
interesting part.
In the state of Nevada,
a divorce is normally given
six months after
the filing.
Check the dates.
Well, this one took
nine months.
Why is that?
Eunice was pregnant.
Judges won't grant
a divorce if the
woman is with child.
They want to wait
till after the birth
to resolve any
custody issues.
So Jimmy Duggan
could have a sibling
that he doesn't even know about.
Oh, it gets better--
there is
no mention of a baby
in this decree.
And there's no record of a
birth certificate in 1971
for a Duggan.
And I even checked
under Eunice's
maiden name Carter.
Nothing.
So where does that leave us?
"A baby was left on the steps of
Desert Palm Hospital yesterday.
"In honor of St. Patrick's Day,
"the nurses named him
Baby Patrick.
"He will be sent
to St. Martine's Orphanage
later this week."
March 17, 1971.
Date fits.
It's not very scientific.
Well, this isn't science,
this is genealogy.
Trust your gut.
SANDERS:
Well, my gut says:
How do we find
St. Patrick?
Have faith, my son.
Have faith.
SANDERS: I'm really digging
this genealogy stuff.
When Denmark ceded Norway
to Sweden, back in 1814,
with the Treaty of Kiel,
my great-great grandfather,
Olaf Hojem, was one of
the leaders of the uprising
against Swedish rule.
He helped convene the
first Norwegian assembly
and write the
national constitution.
That sounds great, but
tell me about Baby Patrick.
Well, St. Martine's
Orphanage is long-gone,
but Donna was able to
track down one of the nuns.
According to
Sister Mary Agnes,
Patrick's legal name
is Patrick O'Toole,
which was the nun's
family name.
Apparently, there's a lot of
O'Tooles running around Vegas.
What do we know about
Patrick O'Toole?
Uh, he's still local.
I checked out his work--
Hodges is at his apartment now.
Hey.
Wait until I tell you
about Eunice Duggan.
I always try
to remain impartial,
but a woman like
Eunice Duggan
should not be
allowed to procreate.
That woman didn't stop
yelling at me the entire
time I was at her house.
So Eunice was
ex-wife of Samuel
and mother of Jimmy.
And possibly
the birth mother
of Patrick O'Toole,
who dumped him
at Desert Palm Hospital.
Eunice gave up DNA, but denies
having a kid in 1971.
Anyway, Henry's running her swab
against the other samples.
HODGES:
Okay, so,
uh, the landlord
would not let me
into Patrick O'Toole's
apartment, but he did give me
one very interesting piece
of information.
O'Toole has a cat.
A sick cat.
And there's only
one vet in Vegas
that does cat
thyroid chemo.
(cat mewing)
What--What about my cat?
You pretended
to be my vet,
you told me Barclay
needs emergency surgery?
That's entrapment
or something.
If I were you,
I'd be more worried
about the DNA sample
we just sent to the lab.
Barclay needs his meds.
Well, the vet is
right outside.
He's gonna make sure
Barclay gets what he needs.
All right?
Now that we got
the cat out of the way,
let's talk about murder.
You ever hear
of Dan Traxler?
Nope.
Let me see the bottom
of your shoes.
What, you need help?
Looks like someone
stepped in it.
(electronic crackling,
blipping)
Radioactive cat litter.
So, you were in
Judy Robbins's house.
Who the hell's she?
Dan Traxler was visiting her
when you killed him.
Look, the evidence
is going to tell us.
I just want to hear it from you.
What the hell's
wrong with you?
I think I screwed up
the DNA.
Well, if you screw up the DNA,
you can kiss your
career good-bye.
I know! Just... look.
Well, the sample
runs look fine.
Look at the references.
Oh.
(sighs)
I'm not so sure
you did anything wrong,
but somebody might've.
We have to do a kin test to try
and make some sense out of this.
Well, I'm not gonna
do this by myself.
Get the reagent.
♪ ♪
Not a lot of diversity, so,
Eunice, Jimmy and
Patrick are related.
Just not how we
thought they were.
We need to confirm this
with Y-STR.
Y-chromosome-linked DNA.
That's the only
way to be certain.
Missing briefcase?
Yup.
Recovered it
from Patrick's car.
All right, great. So that proves
that he was in Doc's house.
What was in it?
Documents from a bunch
of clients, including
Carla Duggan Smith.
Traxler kept
very detailed records
of everything--every
meeting, every phone call.
And according to his log,
he did meet with Patrick
several times, including
the day he was murdered.
Maybe Traxler stumbled
across Patrick
when he was looking for
Carla's grandfather.
You know, maybe he thought
he'd found another relative
for Carla to invite
to her wedding.
I'm still not sure
how this leads to murder.
Yeah, me, neither.
Greg's working that angle.
Oh, good. Greg!
Good job.
You know we have
an intercom system.
I got our motive.
I know why Patrick
killed Traxler.
And it's twisted.
Cue the banjo music.
This report says
that your DNA was found
on the pillow used to
smother Dan Traxler.
Without saying one word,
that's 25 to life.
It also says that the Duggans
have one hell
of a family secret.
Screw you.
You were orphaned, abandoned,
on your own since you were born.
Must have developed
a thick skin.
Probably tried to forget
you even had a family.
Hard to miss
what you've never had.
Until that genealogist
showed up asking questions
about your family,
especially your father.
And your curiosity
got the best of you.
BRASS:
So you followed him,
and I'm betting
that the old lady,
Mama Eunice, wasn't
too happy to see you.
And she told you
who your father was.
You are the devil's spawn.
I didn't want you then,
and I sure as hell
don't want you now.
My mother had sex
with her own son.
BRASS:
When Jimmy was 13.
Now, that's rape in 50 states,
without a statute
of limitations.
She's going down,
and you're the walking,
talking proof of her crime.
Why take your anger out
on Traxler?
This guy shows up
all excited,
talking about family reunions
and happy endings.
And for the first
time in your life,
you thought,
you're not alone.
Yeah.
And thanks to him, I know just
how screwed up my family is.
What were you doing
at Judy Robbins's house?
After I left that
crazy bitch,
I went to Traxler's office
to get in his face.
Saw him leave,
so I followed him.
Patrick.
Get up. Now!
Come with me.
And the briefcase.
You banging this broad?
Absolutely not.
She's just a client.
Take your clothes off.
Do it, or I'll kill her.
Now get in the bed.
Okay, okay...
(muffled screaming)
PATRICK: Everybody screws
everybody in this world.
I knew you cops would think
it was a sex thing.
My mother's a drunken whore,
and my brother's my father.
I didn't need
to know that.
He ruined my life.
SANDERS:
Well, for what it's worth,
I don't think
Traxler knew about the incest.
I don't care!
Rodriguez,
wrap him up.
That's it?
He should've just
left it alone.
SANDERS:
Donna.
What brings you here?
I found Grandpa
Sam in Provo.
He goes by Grafs now.
And he's agreed to meet Carla.
Oh. Well, after all that,
I hope
he walks her down the aisle.
Hojem-Sanders,
you are a true romantic.
It's very appealing.
We arrested the man
who killed Dan.
I heard.
Thank you for that.
It's easy to get too
close to a client.
But Dan always had their
interests at heart.
(sighs)
In the 1900s,
Alrik Magnar Hojem
was one of the richest
men in Edina, Minnesota.
And legend has it,
that because of his vast wealth
and enormous ego,
he earned the
nickname "cake-eaters,"
a derogatory term used to
describe all Edina residents
by their less
affluent neighbors.
Alrik was my great uncle.
His ego was legendary.
In fact, that's how my family
ended up in California.
Ah.
If I wanted to learn more
about my family history,
is it okay to call you?
Of course.
But let's concentrate
on the Hojems.
And remember, hyphenate.
Hey.
I'm glad I caught you.
Al, everything
Judy said checked out.
I just couldn't get past
that first impression.
Hard for me to
get past it, too.
Yeah, I guess
I was punishing her for
what my ex-wife did to me,
but that was my marriage,
not yours.
You were right.
My past clouded my judgment.
I'm sorry.
I appreciate that, Jim.
Yeah...
Oh, uh... oh,
this is... (laughs)
This was in
Traxler's briefcase.
It has your name on it.
I'll let Judy tell you
what's inside.
Go home to your wife, buddy.
♪ ♪
Hi.
Hi. (laughs)
I was beginning to think
you were going to
sleep at the office.
I'm sorry for doubting you.
And... I'm sorry for...
for keeping secrets. I...
I wanted it to be a surprise.
You did that.
Al, I love you.
Don't ever doubt that.
I won't.
(sighs)
Mm!
All right, go ahead,
open it.
Whoa!
Yeah.
And look at this.
Look.
I'm related
to Buffalo Bill Cody.
That is so cool.