(music playing, cheering)
Yo, Gossip Girl!
Slow down!
Who'd you piss off now?
Not now, Jake.
Well, if you're looking for
our girlfriend, okay,
you just missed her.
(cheering, whooping)
Aren't you Brooke Cassidy?
That's me.
So, you really a virgin?
You forgot your number.
I could be your first time!
♪ ♪
Yeah! Whoo! Yeah!
(yells)
Drink, drink, drink,
drink, drink!
How did I let you
get me into this?
Come on!
Drink, drink!
Ladies, got a room upstairs.
Get off of me!
Babe.
Uh, you find your
little, uh, BFF?
Oh, let it go.
I'm sorry, I meant GBF.
Gay Best Friend.
(chuckles)
Stop!
(grunts)
I'm sorry, I left my
purity ring in my room.
You want to come help
me look for it?
Bye.
We're trending!
(cheering)
BRASS:
So,
a series of 911 calls came in
just after 4:00 a.m.
Dead body.
An anonymous tip
gave us the location.
Who invited the campus?
I know, they keep coming.
It's like moths to a flame.
Anyway, this place is notorious.
It's called
Finals Bridge.
32 feet down
to a broken neck.
So a big suicide spot?
Well, used to be
till the university closed it
down five years ago. Anyway,
I got to get back
to take statements
from the first
responders.
Hey, what do you got?
Well, I got a beer bottle.
Well, that's something.
Mm-hmm.
RUSSELL:
Still wet, so it's recent.
Yeah, and I got some
sediment disturbances
here on the ground.
And then up here...
base of the lamppost.
Two different sets
of shoe prints here.
They're not distinct,
but it looks to me
like there might
have been a struggle?
Yeah.
Well, there's more...
here... on the ledge.
Doesn't look
like he jumped.
Maybe someone pushed
this kid over the edge.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
All right.
Ow.
You okay?
Yeah.
Nothing that a chiropractor
can't fix.
Five call-outs today.
Not one died some place where
I'm not risking my life.
Yeah, well it sounds like
it's been a rough night
for everybody,
especially this guy.
And you can smell it.
He's had more
than just a
couple of beers.
Long night of partying.
Things got out of hand.
Student looky-loos
say they last saw him
at the Theta Delta party.
STOKES: Student I.D. says
Pete Moyer, sophomore.
Has he got a cell phone
on him, Super Dave?
No, not on him.
College kid without a cell
phone, that doesn't happen.
Antemortem bruising
on the face.
Yeah, from a fight maybe.
Skull's crushed.
It's consistent
with the fall.
BRODY: Yeah, he didn't
drop straight down.
Trajectory says,
he had some momentum
when he came off the bridge.
(yelling)
Suggests a push.
Maybe it was from the same
person that messed up his face.
What are you doing,
taking candids of our crowd?
You never know if the suspect
might return to the scene.
Out of feelings of guilt?
Maybe they want
to enjoy the show.
Ah, person of interest.
Oh, yeah.
(chuckles)
Charlie.
Giving the girls trouble?
Between school
and basketball,
I don't really
have much time.
It's good to
see you, Finn.
It's really good to see you.
And Dad said you two were
working together again.
Yes, we are.
So when are we going
to play tennis?
Think you can
finally beat me?
Ah, yeah, good luck
with that, buddy.
How come you're not
in class?
Dad, it's 7:00 a.m.
Besides, everybody's
talking about this.
Yeah. I noticed that.
How'd they get here
so quickly?
Um, it's trending.
What?
Can I see that?
Posted at 3:57 a.m.
User name Voyeur4U.
3:57.
Brass said the 911 started
coming in after 4:00.
That means this Voyuer4U guy
knew about the body
before the cops or anybody else.
So this guy could
be our killer.
The dude wanted
to post and boast.
Just saying.
That is a good theory.
Must run in the blood.
What can you tell me, Doc?
Well, our young man's
skull fracture
was accompanied by a fracture
to the C1 vertebra.
Severed the spinal cord.
Injuries were debilitating
and fatal.
What about
the antemortem injuries?
Well, besides
the split lip
and contusions,
he suffered a fracture
to the zygomatic arch.
Also the nasal cartilage.
And there was blood
in the nares, the nostrils.
He really took a beating.
Contusions take around
six hours to set.
He was killed around 4:00 a.m.,
means he was assaulted
around 10:00 p.m.
And there were no
defensive wounds.
The fight was one-sided.
Somebody really had it in
for this kid.
All right, so, the autopsy says
that Pete Moyer got himself
beaten up at about 10:00 p.m.
We didn't find any blood on
his clothes from a fight but,
Nick and Greg did find bloody
clothes in his dorm room.
And apart from the clothes,
the room was
completely empty.
What do you mean?
Apparently, a bunch of
students went in there and
helped themselves
to his stuff.
You're kidding me.
Yeah.
Isn't that disgusting?
So, Pete, last night,
gets into a fight,
goes back to his dorm room,
changes his clothes and then
he goes the Theta Delta party.
Yeah, where, maybe,
he runs into the guy
that he had the fight with,
and then the fight continues,
and ends on the bridge.
Okay, so...
sounds like we need to know
more about this party.
Oh, yeah, what about
this Voyuer4U guy
who posted the photo?
Yeah, Archie's working on it
right now.
Yeah, please, make
yourself a home.
Thank you.
I can't believe...
Hey, Archie.
What do you got?
Running an
ISP trace on Voyeur4U.
Still waiting.
Are these from the Theta party?
Yeah. Going through
all the posted photos
looking for Pete.
No luck yet, but, uh,
still got another
1,367 photos to go.
Oh, great.
What do you have?
Pete Moyer's
FriendAgenda page.
This guy lived out loud
in more ways than one--
openly gay,
and he didn't pull any punches
when it came
to his feelings about others.
What do you mean?
He kept a VLOG.
Video blog.
Kind of like a campus version
of Perez Hilton.
Pete posted juicy gossip
about everybody on campus.
Everything from
who's sleeping with whom,
to whose spring break was
more like spring rehab.
Okay, so sounds like this guy
made a lot of
enemies, right?
Oh, yeah,
one in particular--
username Jonesin4.
Comments are full
of homophobic slurs.
Some of 'em are kind of violent.
Like this one,
posted last night.
"Hey, Queer.
"Stop gossiping and meet up
with me, if you're man enough.
Or I'll find you."
Maybe this is a hate crime.
Hey, guys.
We got a hit on Voyeur4U.
Who is it?
Pete Moyer's account.
His death shot was posted
from his own phone.
We didn't find
his cell phone at the scene.
Maybe the killer
picked it up, you know.
He might still have it.
Track the cell's GPS.
Already on it.
JOHNSON:
WLVU campus, Vincer Hall.
That dorm has five floors.
And I can track the current
altitude of that cell phone.
You're kidding me.
2,061 feet above sea level.
So, in Vegas, that's
about 27 feet above ground.
I'd say that's the third floor.
Hey, Nick.
Are you and Greg
still on campus?
STOKES: Yes, sir.
Yeah, we have a location
on Pete Moyer's phone.
Room's clear.
Next one.
LVPD!
Open up!
(window opening)
Get in there, Vaughn.
Don't leave out that window!
Get your hands off me!
Why you running, dude?
Resisting arrest--
not cool.
That must be Jonesin4.
(chuckles)
I think I know for what.
Whatever you're jonesing
for, this guy's got it.
Hey, try the number.
(line ringing)
(phone chiming)
(sighs)
Pete's phone.
So you think this guy's
Pete's killer?
I think we have
a strong connection.
You guys got this so wrong.
"Hey, Queer. Stop gossiping
and meet up with me
if you're man enough.
Or I'll find you."
Now, it sounds to me
like we've got it right.
You had it in
for Pete.
So is that your thing--
you like to gay-bash?
The last person who'd bash Pete
for being gay is me.
Really?
Why is that?
Because I'm gay.
"Hey, Queer" and
all that--
it's just the way
we talk to each other.
It's kind of an "us" versus
"you" thing.
Well, we have
evidence that suggests
a "you" versus "Pete" thing
on the bridge last night.
We found a beer bottle
with your DNA on it
in the exact spot where somebody
pushed Pete to his death.
Look, I didn't kill Pete.
Okay, you were on the bridge--
at least give me that much.
Yes, I admit that,
I was on the bridge.
But only because
he texted me.
He said he needed help.
Someone had done a number
on him.
(phone ringing)
Figured he was in trouble.
By the time I got there,
he was dead.
Whatever happened on that
bridge, I was too late.
(camera clicks)
Yeah, well, you're a really
good friend, man.
You find him dead,
you take his phone, you take
his picture, and you post it
to the Internet?
Yeah, what, did you forget
to call 911?
I called.
When I got back to my room.
I told you
where to find his body.
Posting that photo
is what Pete would've wanted.
What's that supposed to mean?
Trend To The End.
All right,
well, let's say
that you were just
the photographer,
who do you suppose
had it in for Pete?
Don't know who.
Might know why.
It's all about the "scan-dahl."
What scandal?
Pete wouldn't tell me.
But he had some campus dirt
that he was going to dish.
Total TMZ.
Love me, hate me.
But you know
that I live by one rule:
privacy is history.
The eye in the sky sees all,
shares all.
Now, if you can't own it,
don't do it.
Now, sometimes this means
making hard calls,
hurting people close to you,
but I'd be a hypocrite
if I didn't tell all.
And this bomb
that I'm about to drop...
it's gonna blow you away.
(mimics explosion)
BRODY:
Got this off Pete's phone.
Thinking it was going to be
his latest VLOG entry.
Or whatever his tell-all was.
I think I know
what it could
have been about.
I found these pictures
of Pete talking
to Brooke Cassidy,
the actress.
Oh, more than
an actress.
Brooke Cassidy
is an industry.
Kids love her;
parents love her even more.
Yeah.
No sex, no drugs.
America's
favorite virgin.
Tough act to keep up in college.
Yes, and maybe she didn't,
and maybe Pete found out.
And here he is,
giving her the heads-up.
Before he drops the bomb.
Excuse me, Ms. Cassidy.
We're from the Crime Lab.
This is CSI Brody.
I'm CSI Finlay.
We're investigating
Pete Moyer's death.
It's an awful thing.
Yeah. Yeah, it is.
And according
to Pete's VLOG,
you guys were
pretty good friends.
Yeah, that's right.
According to photos posted
from the Theta party,
you were one of
the last people to see him.
I guess so.
What exactly can you tell us
about his state of mind?
I don't know.
Pete was Pete.
What does that mean?
A hot mess.
Opinionated.
He could be cruel sometimes.
Was he ever cruel to you?
It seems like everybody wants
to get ahead, so they'll say
whatever they want about me,
even if it's a total lie.
I came here
to be a student,
and I thought
that Pete respected that.
And that would be
important to a woman
who had made a very public
pledge of purity until marriage.
What are you implying?
We would just like to know
what the two of you
were talking about
before someone pushed Pete
off the bridge.
Whatever it was,
you don't look happy.
Okay, I don't like
where this is going.
I don't either.
And you are?
Jake Pychan,
Theta Delta Zeta president.
Are these people
giving you a hard time?
No. They're just asking
questions about Pete.
Oh, I can tell you
all you need to know.
Oh, great.
Pete Moyer was a leech.
A nobody who tried to be
a somebody by posting lies.
I warned Brooke
about him.
I can see you're very
protective, Mr. President.
And busy.
I got a class to get to.
So does Brooke.
Is that everything
from Pete's room?
Almost.
Still haven't got
his computer yet.
Oh, look at that.
Nice to see some
things never change.
Instant ramen!
And a Crock-Pot.
Good times.
The kid had all kinds
of electronica.
Cameras and microphones...
listening devices.
Took this whole paparazzi
thing pretty seriously.
Yeah.
Like, A-plus seriously.
Pete wrote a term paper
here called
"Phone Hacking for Hacks."
It's like a how-to guide.
Phone hacking for credit?
What kind of class teaches that?
Anthropology of Fame.
Taught by Professor Tom Laudner.
Tom Laudner?
I know that guy.
He has a tabloid TV show
called Celebrities Indisposed.
He earns his living
harassing celebrities.
And now he's
teaching our kids, right?
Hester...
Prynne.
The Scarlet Letter.
I like to think of Hester
as the first bad girl
gone viral.
But that was then.
This... is now.
Today, the scarlet letter--
it gets you a book deal,
it gets you a product line,
it gets you a reality show.
Fame is good.
But...
without the judgment
of the church
or the community,
what's left to keep us in line?
Hmm?
Gossip,
fear, ridicule, shame.
Gossip is good.
Gossip works...
for society.
Wow. That was a great lecture.
Professor Laudner, right?
Mmm, yes. Well,
I'm glad you could make it.
Uh, the police, right?
Uh... CSI.
D.B. Russell.
Oh, nice to meet you.
Yeah. You too.
Yeah. I presume
this is about Pete Moyer, yeah?
Yeah, yeah. He was
one of your students, right?
He was my best student.
Yeah, I could tell that.
You know,
I saw some of his course work.
Especially that paper
on phone hacking.
That was a good one.
Well, maybe not so
good for Pete.
See, I think he may have
tried to hack the wrong phone.
Well, I mean,
I couldn't tell you
anything about that.
No. Well...
I mean this is a classroom
and, you know, we just try
to create a safe environment
for students to pursue
their intellectual muse.
Oh, I'm confused.
I thought you taught
a class on gossip.
Oh, no, no, no, no--
I teach a course
on the sociology of celebrity;
the culture of idolatry.
I mean, college
is to prepare students
for the real world, right?
The campus
is a microcosm for society--
you got the haves,
you got the have-nots,
you've got the beautiful people,
and the, uh...
you know,
not-so-beautiful people.
And you got a real world actress
playing student too, right?
Yeah.
Brooke Cassidy? Fabulous girl.
Yeah, she was kind enough
to serve as an object lesson
in one of my lectures.
That was kind of her.
'Cause the way I hear it,
she's, like,
this scandal waiting to happen.
Yeah.
Teen Dream deflowered.
It'd obviously
make a good story.
Hey, did you have Pete
try to hack into some of that?
Pete? No, no, no, no.
He's one of my students,
he's not one of my employees.
(laughs)
Right. Right, right, right.
Listen, what I can tell you
about Pete...
as "out" as he was,
he kept a few things
in the closet.
That's as close as you'll get
to an exclusive from me.
Okay.
I hope you return the favor.
Oh, hey, thank you so much.
That was very helpful.
No, no, no, thank you.
Nice to meet you, sir.
Take care.
Yeah, you, too.
Good luck.
Thanks.
What are we looking for exactly?
Oh, you know,
something besides
a computer
or a hard drive
where Pete could've stored
whatever dirt he dug up
on Brooke Cassidy.
You sure the professor's
not just messing with you?
He was pretty clear
about the quid pro quo.
I think I...
may have just found the quid.
I got to get me one of those.
Flash drive.
Let's check it out.
Okay.
Let's see what's in
Brooke's folder.
Wow. Okay, so Pete
wasn't just hacking messages.
He was hacking into
e-mails and photos.
Mm-hmm.
America's favorite virgin's
looking pretty virginal.
There's nothing really
controversial here.
Let's check Jake's file.
Okay, wait a minute now.
I've seen that
tatt before.
Where?
Climbing out a window at WLVU.
That's Sebastian Jones.
One of Pete Moyer's buddies.
Hmm.
Whoa.
Looks like
he's got another buddy.
That's Brooke's boyfriend,
Jake Pychan.
Looks like boyfriend's
got a beard.
Where did you get these?
Not off the computer
you stole from
Pete Moyer's dorm room,
if that's what you mean.
We found his computer
under your bed.
RUSSELL:
Those photos were on a
flash drive that Pete hid
in some dirty clothes.
But you didn't
think to look there.
And they came from your phone.
Which Pete hacked into.
Son of a bitch.
I guess you
didn't take that
same purity pledge
as your girlfriend.
That isn't sex.
Oh, I don't think your
girlfriend would agree.
Does she know you're gay?
I'm not gay.
RUSSELL:
Gay, straight,
your business,
or at least
it was your business right up
until Pete
decided to make it everyone
else's.
BRASS:
And then you threw
him off the bridge.
I didn't touch him.
When I saw him last night
at the Theta house,
somebody already worked him
over pretty good.
Well, then, you won't mind
giving us your prints
and some DNA?
I have rights.
Yeah, you got rights, but you're
a suspect in a murder case.
And we don't have a lot of time,
so tell us what happened.
Sebastian texted me
after Pete was dead.
He said...
Pete might have
some photos of us.
Sebastian already
had his phone,
so I went for his computer.
I just didn't want them
getting online.
People wouldn't understand.
RUSSELL:
Well, then,
give us what we need,
you know, help us
rule you out as a
suspect, and if you do,
I promise that these photos
will get buried
in the evidence vault.
We can do that, can't we?
Yeah, sure.
Okay.
Ah. Yeah, there you go.
Thank you.
JOHNSON:
Why does a gossip hound need
military-grade encryption
for his computer files?
Well, certainly not 'cause
he respected anyone's privacy.
Probably just didn't want
to get scooped himself.
So, how long till you
can unscramble it?
This is complicated.
I'm gonna need some time.
When I said Pete was taking
his paparazzi work seriously,
I didn't realize
he went full-tilt P.I.
Must have dropped a mint
at some spy store.
What is that?
A remote digital receiver.
JOHNSON:
Oh, that's top of the line.
(beeps)
Ah.
Still receiving a signal.
(keyboarding)
That's a live feed
from a camera...
...mounted
somewhere.
SANDERS:
Maybe an office?
This picture's fuzzy 'cause
we're at the edge
of the camera's broadcast range.
Pete Moyer's entire
world is WLVU.
I guarantee you this room
is somewhere on campus.
Can you get me a better picture
at all?
No. You guys should just start
walking this thing
back towards campus.
Or I could try and do my job,
amplify the reception range
and get a cleaner image.
That's a good idea.
Second.
Yeah.
Hey.
Mom insisted. She's worried
you're not taking care
of yourself.
Come on in.
Case must be
going well.
Hear you have a suspect
in custody.
You're trending.
I'll be darned.
So, it's like the court
of public opinion
in the digital age, right?
Yeah.
Oh. What... What do you...
what you got there?
Are those salt and
vinegar chips?
Mm-hmm.
(chuckles)
Oh, yeah.
It's nice to see Finn.
Yeah.
How's that working for you?
It's fine.
Why do you ask?
Just kind of a drag last time.
Well, second time's a charm.
Yeah, hope so.
Mom's not the only one
who worries.
(quietly):
Ugh...
BRODY:
Finn?
Morgan, did you bring lunch?
We have company.
Hi.
Oh, hi.
Um, have a seat.
Thank you.
I didn't want to
be seen walking
into the police department,
so, I thought
I could talk
to you guys instead?
Sure.
Of course you can.
I know Jake's been arrested,
but he had nothing to do
with Pete's death.
Really? And why
are you so sure about that?
Because I was with him...
all night.
All night?
Yeah, at the party
and at the bridge
with everyone else,
after you guys found Pete.
You don't have to have sex
to spend the night with someone.
No. No, you don't,
and I'm sure
it's easier to keep
your pledge of purity
when your boyfriend's
not that into you.
Look, I'm not naive.
When I met Jake,
I really liked him.
You know, he was
the perfect boyfriend for me.
Sexually confused enough
that he would never
pressure me to break my vow,
which, believe it or not,
is very important to me.
Uh, Brooke,
we have evidence that
Pete knew about Jake's
sexual confusion,
and may have been
planning to out him.
BRODY:
Is that why
you and Pete were fighting
at the party?
We weren't fighting
at the party.
No, it had nothing
to do with Jake.
Pete was venting
about Professor Laudner.
BRODY:
Professor Laudner?
Why?
Because Laudner's
a douche.
And Pete idolized him,
wanted to be just like him.
I don't know what went
down between those two, but
Pete told me
I was right all along.
Did he mention
a physical altercation
that took place
with Professor Laudner?
I asked him
why his face was all messed up,
and he told me
to check his next VLOG.
That the truth
would be revealed.
Hey, Greg.
I tried boosting
the reception
from Pete's camera, but, uh, the
image didn't get much better.
So, I enhanced this
one area here.
Looks like a poster.
Yeah, for
Celebrities Indisposed.
Pete's camera is
in Tom Laudner's office.
(sighs)
There's the poster.
Camera's got to
be somewhere
over there.
Yeah.
Bookcase is a good place
to hide a camera.
Think I got something
on the top shelf.
Here it is.
And that's what
it's looking at.
Yeah, well,
there's only one reason
why Pete Moyer would want
a bird's-eye view of
Professor Laudner's couch.
Ah, Professor.
Thanks for coming down.
Didn't seem like I had a choice.
You didn't.
Sit down, please.
I have something that
I want to show you.
Really?
That's my office.
Do you have a warrant?
Actually,
that's university property.
And yeah, they've been served.
But you don't have
probable cause
for any wiretapping
or surveillance.
That's true, that's
true, we don't.
You see, Pete Moyer put
that camera in your office.
He's the one who's
been watching you.
Got a blood drop.
Yep.
Somebody cleaned up this rug.
If that's
Pete Moyer's blood,
then he was beaten
in this room.
RUSSELL:
So,
Pete was in your office
last night,
and the two of you got
into a fight.
Yeah. That's none
of your business.
You're pulling
the privacy card. Wow.
After you made a career
out of exposing
everyone else's business.
That's a little hypocritical,
don't you think?
Guilty.
Do you have anything else?
Yeah, actually I do. Thank you.
I have blood...
on your rug.
See, you tried to clean it up,
which makes it my business.
Oh, this thing had
quite a workout.
Yeah. Maybe
one of Laudner's students was
riding the extra credit couch.
Your office hours must
be very stimulating.
I'm sorry.
Did I miss the question?
How many women are enrolled in
your Anthropology of Fame class?
Thirty-eight.
And how many
have you had sex with?
Okay, here's what I
think happened. I think
Pete Moyer found out,
confirmed it with his camera,
and then threatened
to expose you.
Mr. Russell,
even gossip is woven
with a thread of truth.
Then I think that you tried
to rough him up a little bit,
but when that
didn't work, I think
you lured him out
to Finals Bridge.
What, and pushed him off?
You thought it would
look like a suicide.
Your protégé caught you
with your pants down, Professor.
You panicked, you thought
that the scandal would ruin you.
Are you serious?
Teacher sleeps with students,
none of them underage,
not the same sex,
and all of them consensual.
What scandal?
Hey, Nick?
Come here for a second,
will you?
Yeah.
I hate it when a suspect blows a
hole in a perfectly good theory.
Professor Laudner.
Okay, okay,
now, so what
if Pete Moyer recorded
the professor having sex--
consensual sex-- with a student?
Seven different students.
Whoa.
According to
the vaginal contributions
on the couch,
he was a busy man.
But that just
makes him the guy who can.
It doesn't make him a killer.
And like he said in
his dumb lectures,
sex scandal nowadays just means
that you got yourself
a book tour, a reality show,
and a movie deal,
for crying out loud.
You're not really letting
this guy get to you, are you?
That's beside
the point.
What I don't see is
a motive for killing Pete.
We know he punched him.
We confirmed it was Pete's blood
in Laudner's office.
Okay, but if...
if the fight wasn't
about a sex scandal,
then what was it?
You never know what you're gonna
see when you turn a camera on.
Or what people
are gonna do.
Maybe Pete saw
something more than sex.
something Laudner
didn't want him to.
I wouldn't put it past Laudner
to take advantage
of his students, would you?
And maybe not take no
for an answer.
Maybe.
I like that.
Okay, we need to identify
these seven women.
(quiet, indistinct chatter)
You see the cops
take him away?
Yeah.
So it's got to
be true, right?
Professor Laudner's
been arrested?
Good afternoon, class.
My name is
Julie Finlay,
and this is Morgan Brody.
We work with the Crime Lab.
We are here investigating
the death of Pete Moyer.
We are going to share
details with you
regarding our
homicide investigation.
Now, this information has been
withheld from the public.
FINLAY:
We discovered
epithelials,
skin cell DNA, under
the victim's fingernails,
which tells us that
he struggled with his killer
in the moments before his death.
(murmuring)
BRODY:
The way this works,
we start by trying
to exclude Pete's
classmates and friends,
in order to zero in
on our killer.
Now, in order to do that,
we need to collect DNA samples
from all of you.
What if we refuse?
FINLAY:
Well, you do have
that legal right--
this is strictly voluntary--
but I would like
to ask you all to refrain
from spreading false rumors
about any classmates
who refuse to cooperate.
So no sharing,
no posting, no kidding.
First volunteers
get the clean swabs.
I can't believe
that just worked.
Mm-hmm.
ANDREWS:
Hey, Nick.
I identified the seven
vaginal contributors
from the couch
in Professor
Laudner's office.
All these girls
were in his class.
All right, I'll have
Brass bring them in.
WOMAN:
Well, Professor Laudner's
office hours
are open to every student
in the class, so...
are you asking me if I had sex
with Professor Laudner?
I'm asking you if
it was consensual.
I took Laudner's class
for an easy "A."
Everybody knows
that if you're a pretty girl,
wear a short skirt
and sit in the front row,
you get an "A."
Did he promise if you slept
with him he'd give you an "A"?
He never made
any promises, but...
it was understood.
FINLAY:
Ashley,
we've collected
forensic evidence,
and we're talking
to other girls.
We know that
Professor Laudner
offered sex for grades.
I am not accusing
you of anything.
I just would like
to ask if you had
consensual sex with
Professor Laudner.
Did Professor Laudner hurt you?
I don't want
to talk about it.
Ashley, I know you want to
help us find Pete's killer.
I think Pete found out
about what happened to you,
and then he tried to help you.
Pete did not
want to help me.
Pete only cared about Pete
and his damn gossip!
I didn't want to talk to Pete,
and I don't want to talk to you.
I have a right to be left alone.
Ashley,
I understand that...
but what Pete found out
cost him his life,
so I need you to help me find
out what happened to him,
and I need you
to let me help you.
You can't help me!
No one can!
I would like to try.
I killed Pete!
Okay? I was the reason
he was at that bridge!
I pushed him off!
Can you help me now?
(sobbing)
(continues sobbing)
ASHLEY:
Get off me! Please!
JOHNSON:
Finally decrypted
Pete's hard drive.
Been through
all the videos.
A lot of sex, but...
nothing like this.
(turns off video)
That is so
clearly rape.
Why wouldn't Ashley
have reported it?
A lot of shame associated
with sexual assault.
Especially if the rapist
is known to the victim.
So, Mandy matched three unknown
sets of prints from the bridge
to the ten-card that Finlay
collected from Ashley Benson.
So she was there?
Yeah.
The problem is,
there's an inconsistency
with her confession.
Mind if I get in there?
So...
all of her prints are on...
this lamppost.
The first set is
at approximately five feet.
The highest is
a little over eight.
Well, Ashley's
about my height, so...
Here's your first
set of prints.
Okay.
Add what, 18 inches
for the bench?
There's your
second set of prints.
Well, another 18 inches,
and you're at eight feet.
Looks like you might
need a little help
to get there.
Ashley was climbing.
Yep. Right onto the ledge.
Pete followed me
to the bridge...
ambushed me as I was
leaving the party.
He said he knew what
Laudner had done to me
and he'd seen it
with his own eyes.
So he...
told you about the tape?
Yeah,
he said he was gonna
post it on his Web site
and that he wanted
my exclusive.
I knew the rumors.
I knew that some of the girls
were sleeping with him.
(crying):
But I'm not like that.
(sobbing)
I should have taken the "C."
I was trying so hard to get
into business school, and...
Ashley, you did
nothing wrong; nothing.
Have you seen it?
The tape is evidence.
(sobbing): So it's
gonna be everywhere.
I need you to tell
me what happened.
(laughs): I... I
thought Pete was there
because he actually
cared about me.
PETE:
Look, forget my VLOG.
I'll go with you to the cops;
we'll talk to them together.
It doesn't matter!
He raped me!
You don't have to do this.
He said we
couldn't give up,
and that I couldn't
let Laudner win.
I want it to be over!
Come here.
Take my hand.
Hey, you have to trust me.
And then I turned around,
and he had his phone out.
He was recording us,
or-or texting,
or tweeting,
I don't know, but...
I knocked it
out of his hand.
(Pete yelling)
(sobbing): If I just hadn't
gone into Laudner's office,
Pete would still be alive!
Ashley,
from what you're telling
me, it was an accident.
It was not your fault.
Okay? None of this
is your fault.
Not Pete's death, and certainly
not what Laudner did to you.
I lived with it for 13 days.
I went to class.
I worked at my job.
I talked to my parents.
I just...
I boxed it up,
and I put it on a shelf.
Ashley, listen to me:
I am gonna have
experts testify
to your behavior, so that
when you take the stand,
the jury will know why you
went back to that class.
A jury?
I-I can't stand
in front of a jury.
There is no hope of stopping
Laudner if you don't.
That's not my problem.
I just want to be left alone.
Please.
(Finlay sighs)
BRASS:
You know I talked
to the D.A.
She's not gonna file
on just the tape.
Which means the guy walks.
Yeah, and the bastard's gonna go
do it again to another girl.
We have to take our
victims as they come.
CHARLIE:
Hey, Dad.
Oh. Hey.
You look terrible.
Oh, thanks a lot.
Were we supposed
to be doing something?
No, but Mom thought
it would be cool
if we all met up for dinner.
Oh, that sounds fun.
Something wrong?
Well,
some cases don't end up
the way you want them to.
Yeah, but this
one did, right?
No.
Really? Check it out.
It's all over
the Internet--
Professor Laudner
raped a student.
Ah. News travels fast,
doesn't it?
The university
suspended him.
What?
I mean, look at
all these posts.
It's not like he's
gonna get away with it.
Yeah.
So...
this is what you
call trending, right?
Mm-hmm.
(chuckles)
Let's go meet your mother.
Yeah?
Yeah.