♪ ♪
What if someone sees us?
Please, this place is
like a ghost town.
Well, what about God?
He sees everything.
Well, I mean, if he
has a problem with it,
he'll let us know,
right?
Uh, you're, um...
What?
There's, uh...
You're covered in...
(screams)
(siren wails)
Is it really...?
Blood?
Yeah.
(indistinct radio transmission)
Excuse me.
So, I talked
to Kid Casanova.
He tells me that God's
wrath rained down.
You know, you lose the blood
and the police tape,
my wife could
really go
for a neighborhood
like this.
Very eco-friendly.
WILLOWS:
Not so friendly tonight.
The Chambliss family.
Quadruple homicide.
You're gonna need backup.
You get many "Stigmata"
houses in Seattle?
No, no, our saints bleed coffee
up there.
BRASS: The owner was a
pharmaceutical salesman.
Laid off six months ago.
Okay, thank you.
I got it.
Well, I hope Moonbeam
brought his booties
and a strong stomach.
(sighs)
(door creaks)
(indistinct sportscast
plays on TV)
ANNOUNCER: ...retain possession,
very, very lucky.
Lining up for the next play, Al.
That'll make it second down and
a loss of five on the play.
Second down and 15...
(whirring)
Greenhouse
gray water system.
Recycles everything that goes
down the drain.
And out to
the sprinklers.
Explains why
the house was bleeding.
Look at this.
When was the last time you
bought a rainbow marshmallow?
When my daughter was eight.
Oh, God.
Do you feel that?
Change in temperature.
(door creaks)
RUSSELL:
Oh.
There's no blood on
her pajamas.
She's been redressed.
Cleaned up,
tucked in.
By somebody
who cared about her.
This was where she was shot.
What's blood doing way up there?
(indistinct radio transmission)
Wait here till
you get the Code Four.
(door creaks)
OFFICER: Got someone over here.
Show me your hands!
Get down on your knees!
Sounds like a Code Four to me.
BRASS: Let me see your hands!
Get down on the ground!
Let me see those hands!
Get him down!
Get him on the ground!
Get on the ground!
I loved her!
Do not resist!
Cuff him up.
I loved her! Oh, God!
Cuff him.
Get him out of here!
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
COMPUTER VOICE:
You are going the wrong way.
Make a U-turn at the next
intersection.
Intersection?
You are going the wrong way.
There's no road!
Recalculating.
(tires screech)
You have arrived
at your destination.
Your dad teach you how to drive?
Funny. You guys could use
a few more freeways around here.
Who's inside?
Me and Greg. You want
to take the perimeter?
I got my sunscreen.
Ah, there you go.
Oh, speak of the devil,
there's the old man there.
Enjoy yourself. (chuckles)
Hey, Conrad,
how you doing?
Nick.
Good to see ya.
(siren wailing)
Cigars?
Kills the decomp.
I always had
a few on hand.
So, uh, you settling in?
Yeah.
You make an appearance
at every crime scene?
I usually roll on
anything over a double.
And this one, press is
gonna be all over it.
I got stuff to do.
REPORTER:
Undersheriff Ecklie!
Is it true
you have a suspect in custody?
Can you tell us if you
have any leads?
Can you tell
us if you have a suspect?
Look, look, all I can say is we
have a person of interest
in custody and that we intend
to question him.
REPORTER: Is there any
additional information
you can share with the press?
ECKLIE:
As a matter of due diligence,
we're performing a thorough
search of the neighborhood,
including one of the
neighboring homes.
Uh, don't mean to interrupt
your search, but, uh,
I've torn this place
apart-- there's no gun,
no knife...
Did you notice the decor?
You in the market
for a decorator?
The kid's 27 years old.
He answers phones
at a body shop.
Yet all the furniture
in this place looks like
it belongs to his parents.
Like hand-me-downs.
The only room that
reflects his taste
is this one,
and it's laid out
exactly like...
like the dead
little girl's room.
Even has the same dollhouse.
WILLOWS:
Not exactly the same.
Ahh...
(scoffs)
Guy lived just across the way.
He's been watching
her for years.
(camera shutter clicking)
(shutter clicks)
Sanders?
I got boot prints.
Me, too.
(phone rings)
Mine have been
here a while.
I think somebody made a habit
out of hiding back here.
Yeah. Looking in.
Just got a text
from Catherine.
Our perp is a peeper.
BRASS: Can I get you
anything?
Want a soda, something?
Cherry cola would be nice.
I'm sure it would.
I know what you think.
(quietly): You're
just lucky I'm a cop.
I'm CSI Willows
here to process you.
Get up.
Step on the paper.
Strip.
Just pretend she's an
eight-year-old girl.
Pants next.
Could you close the blinds?
BRASS:
Better?
Keep going.
PHILLIPS:
Three in the van.
Still waiting on the mom.
Thanks, David.
(camera shutter clicking)
ROBBINS:
Any reason you're holding her?
I need her in context.
There's a lot of
blood spatter here.
There's a lot of blood
in this house, period.
All this had to have taken
a lot of time.
Grandmother was
stabbed a dozen times;
the father was shot
three times.
Guy has a knife and a gun.
So why does he need
the towel bar?
You really think one person
could've done all this?
Cadets are outside
beating the bushes
looking for the
knife and the gun.
They're having
the same luck that we did.
I've seen this freezer before.
My wife and I once
went away for a weekend,
and we left
our eldest in charge,
God help us,
so the kids
did all the shopping.
When we came back,
the freezer
looked just like this.
SIDLE:
Popsicles, ice cream.
It's a great way to lure a kid.
Yeah. You know, not a lure,
more like a...
a lifestyle.
Arrested development.
You think
John Lee likes little girls
because he's a little boy?
Immature, isolated.
You know, he hides,
takes pictures through windows.
I'm passive;
I'm not aggressive.
I thought you
liked to play dead,
get into the head of the victim.
You know, it depends--
you know, you walk
into a room,
the victim, suspect.
I go with whoever has
the best story to tell.
What story is
this guy telling you?
I don't know yet.
But I'm not so sure that it ends
in a quadruple homicide.
Oh, whoa,
you don't think
the man-boy did it?
He was in their house,
he... was holding
the little girl's nightgown,
he watched her
for years.
Yeah, exactly.
For years. Thank you, yeah.
And all of a sudden one night
he stops watching
and he starts killing?
Why?
(gulps, shivers)
WILLOWS:
Right hand.
Is it gonna hurt?
A lot less than
jabbing a towel bar
into a woman 20 times.
I didn't do it.
Any of it.
I went by the house.
I looked in
and I saw her.
She was already dead.
The blood.
(cap snaps on)
I loved her.
I couldn't leave her
there like that.
Other hand.
BRASS:
You know,
I ran you-- you had no
record, no complaints.
But here's what
I think happened.
I think you were hanging out
by that window peeping,
and someone saw you,
told the Chamblisses--
Dad didn't like that.
So he walked across the
street to your house,
knocked on your door,
then knocked on your head.
And you didn't
like that.
I tested your hands
for lead to determine
if you fired a gun.
And guess what
color positive is?
WILLOWS:
You shot that
little girl.
You shot her father,
sliced and diced
her grandmother,
and stabbed and beat her
mother with a towel bar.
BRASS:
And we're gonna
prove it, too.
So you got a choice-- you can
spend the rest of your life
in general pop with a bunch
of gangsters and killers
who never get to
see their kids,
they're gonna take it out
on you in a heavy way,
or you can tell us
what you did...
and maybe buy yourself a private
cell-- what's it gonna be?
I did it.
I'm the one who killed
the Chambliss family.
(reporters clamoring)
Good afternoon.
I'm Undersheriff Ecklie
of the Los Vegas
Police Department.
I'm here to announce that,
thanks to the fine efforts
of our detectives and CSI's,
we have a suspect in custody
who has confessed to the murders
of the Chambliss family.
Can you tell us his name?
Why did he do it?
How did he it?
I have no further comment
at this time.
Why can't you tell us?
One last question.
Hey, thanks.
Nice job.
Good work, sir.
(chuckles):
Yeah.
WOMAN:
I am saying there
has been a mistake.
I saw the news--
that sheriff...
OFFICER: Ma'am,
slow... down.
WOMAN: Don't
patronize me.
I have
information about
the Chambliss murders.
I need to talk
to somebody in charge.
OFFICER: That would
be Captain Brass.
You arrested
the wrong man!
WILLOWS:
Really?
And you would
know that how?
I know because I did it.
I'm the one who killed
the Chambliss family.
BRASS:
So...
Leslie, uh...
Gitig.
Leslie Gitig.
G-I-T-I-G.
People always
get it wrong.
Well,
we're gonna get
everything right today, Leslie.
How do you know
the Chambliss family?
Calvin Chambliss and I
were having an affair.
He promised he'd leave
his wife Susan
for me.
I guess that didn't work out.
He caved.
He told Susan about me.
(laughs softly)
Bitch.
And then he
stopped calling.
You can check
my phone records.
Oh, we're gonna do that.
ECKLIE:
So, where were you
last night between
9:00 and midnight?
Where I always am--
parked outside their house.
You can check the
traffic cameras.
Oh, and I stopped for gas.
So you got out
of your car?
Yes.
Then what?
I rang the doorbell.
Cal's mother, Anita,
answered the door.
I told her I was
there to see Cal.
She wouldn't let me
in, so I killed her.
And then I
killed Cal...
and Susan...
and Fiona.
ECKLIE: Yeah,
I read the paper, too.
Tell us something the whole
world doesn't know, Ms. Guy-tig.
Gitig.
You mean like Anita's
throat was slashed.
(Anita gasping)
Cal was shot
twice in the chest,
once between the eyes.
And Susan
was stabbed repeatedly.
(crying)
Oh, and little Fiona...
(Fiona screams)
...was shot in the head.
So, you said you entered the
house through the front door?
If you want to videotape this,
I can start again
from the beginning.
(door opens)
(door closes)
I heard about
the second confession.
One is good; two is bad.
Nut job or not,
she's just made things a
lot more difficult for us,
creating reasonable doubt.
(sighs):
So...
where would you
like to start?
Let's start with Mom.
Susan Chambliss.
Massive head trauma.
Exsanguination.
24 sharp-force injuries
consistent with
the jagged ends
of the towel bar.
15 accompanying
blunt-force injuries
consistent with its
rounded sides.
Beaten and stabbed to death.
39 blows.
Towel bar ripped
from the wall.
Rage.
Yeah.
Dear old Dad's
a different story.
Two gunshot wounds
to the chest,
and a coup de grâce.
David found these blue fibers
on Dad's clothing.
Could be the shooter.
Contact wound right through
the frontal bone,
execution style.
Clean and quick.
Rounds look like
nine-mill.
Same as little girl.
I'm not sure I want
to hear this, but...
sexual assault?
There was nothing.
No physical findings
of any sexual abuse.
He escalates to murder
but leaves the object
of his perversion untouched?
Then he just kills her?
Doesn't make sense.
RUSSELL:
Hey.
Good first day?
Yeah.
Finished processing
outside, and I'm
starting on the blood inside.
Great, great.
Walk with me.
Family meeting.
Everybody. Let's go.
Is he for real?
Hey, looks good, Greg.
Okay.
So, this is
how I like to run
a family meeting.
Clarify the problem
first, okay?
And we have two competing
stories in this case.
Who thinks that, uh, the
target of this attack
was the little girl?
Raise your hands.
Okay.
Never mind.
Point of entry.
The window?
All right, okay,
all right.
Here comes the birdbath. Smash!
What's the
little girl do?
I, uh, found a puddle
of urine under the bed.
She must have hid there.
All right.
Nick, you processed the dad.
Could he have
heard all of this?
Evidence tells me no.
He barely got off the sofa
before he was shot.
TV was on-- he might
have been asleep.
And Grandma wears a hearing aid,
so she probably
didn't hear anything.
SANDERS:
Flour on the kitchen floor
indicates Mom was
baking a cake.
Mixer's on.
That's pretty loud.
Okay,
so maybe nobody hears
the window break.
But that's crazy.
You know, if someone breaks in
to my daughter's bedroom,
first she yells
bloody hell, then
she wouldn't hide,
she'd run to me.
Little girl's
behavior is off.
Everybody's behavior's
off on this thing.
Oh, by the way,
Catherine called and said
John Lee did not touch
the girl sexually.
So I'm glad to see
none of you raised
your hands when I asked
if she was the source
of this whole thing.
In that case,
I'd like to retract
my hand-raise from earlier.
Girl's behavior
is more consistent
with point of entry
at the front door.
Then she ran and hid.
But there was no evidence of
forced entry at the front door.
Dad's on the sofa,
Mom's in the kitchen...
and Grandma had to let them in.
STOKES:
Grandma was first,
Dad was second, Mom was third,
stabbed and then dragged
into the bathroom.
Fiona was last.
But if John Lee
didn't assault her...
Why did he kill her?
Well, maybe he
didn't, now.
Maybe he came in
after the killings.
He breaks in, throws the
birdbath through the window,
and then, like he says,
he changes her clothes.
It would explain
why we haven't found
any bloody clothes, or a gun,
or a knife
at his house.
Somebody else
killed this family.
GITIG:
I wore gloves.
I always keep a pair in my car.
Disposable.
BRASS:
Disposable?
Where'd you dispose
of the gun,
the knife,
the clothes you wore?
I threw them away.
Where?
(clears throat)
I disposed of my Beretta
in the water hazard
off the 12th hole
at the Alsted
Country Club.
I drive by there every day
on my way to the firm.
I find it peaceful.
Ooh. Is that it?
Just like she said.
12th hole
water hazard.
Swan took a bite
out of the diver.
I'm surprised you let
someone else go in after it.
You know how those
Navy Seals are.
They make us Marines
take a back seat.
Yeah. Well, bullets
are in evidence.
When you're done, make sure
Russell gets your report?
Got it.
Best job in the world.
Get to play with guns.
Nobody's shooting back.
SANDERS:
Print of John Lee's boot.
Here you go.
Great.
Individual characteristics
line up.
Boots match.
Got him at the window.
But not in the house.
He gained two sizes coming in.
Russell was right.
Nice hand retraction...
brown nose.
♪ ♪
Fire in the hole.
(beeping)
(door opens)
Where are the other gentlemen?
(sighs)
If you're going to ask
me the questions now,
that red light isn't on.
You know what
a ballistics match is, right?
Yes.
Well, the gun
you had us fish out
at the country club
was not the murder weapon.
The caliber was the same,
but the rifling
wasn't even close.
Wow. As I understand it,
any number of things can change
a gun's rifling characteristics.
Like shoving a screwdriver
down the barrel.
Are you going back to the lake?
Obviously,
you found the wrong gun.
You...
are a...legal secretary, right?
You seem like you'd be
really good at that job.
I mean, you know
criminal procedure,
you got the lingo down.
I bet you even
have contacts at PD,
or maybe
the coroner's office,
or the crime lab.
I killed that family.
Do you want to know why
I did it?
'Cause that bitch
got in the way of me and Cal.
Which is why
I sunk that knife into her
24 times.
I'm sorry.
I completely forgot.
Um... be right back.
Don't-Don't go anywhere, though.
Oh, brother,
she's a piece of work.
And she's, what, like,
105 pounds soaking wet?
And I don't think
she owns work boots.
Not men's size 12, anyway.
It was a towel rod,
not a knife.
I ran her phone logs.
She's been making calls
to law enforcement
all over the county.
She got a look
at our evidence.
You know, she
may be crazy,
but she figured out
point-of-entry before we did.
Maybe we should keep that
to ourselves.
Yeah.
John Lee dressed yet?
I would hope so. Why?
Guy's a peeper.
And if he didn't murder
that family,
maybe he saw who did.
So, John,
we know you were
in the house that night,
in Fiona's room.
Now you said that...
that she was already dead.
Let's say we believe
your first version.
You were still there.
WILLOWS:
Did you see anything?
No.
RUSSELL:
Oh.
Well, maybe not the
night of the murders,
but come on, buddy.
You've been watching
that family for years.
You trying to trick me?
No. No, no, no, no.
John,
you loved Fiona.
Loved her.
And something horrible
happened to her.
She would want you to help us.
Have you ever
seen this woman?
Red BMW.
Three Series.
She would park down the street
and just sit there.
She's an awful woman.
How do you know?
You can just tell sometimes.
RUSSELL:
Did this
awful woman ever go inside?
Did you ever see any other
awful people go inside?
Can I have that cherry cola now?
Explain this to me.
Some perv stalks your daughter,
peeks in her window,
takes photos for years.
Mother doesn't work;
father is unemployed.
I mean, they
were around.
You can't tell me
they didn't know.
I found dozens of footprints
outside that window.
So why didn't
they call the police?
Maybe they couldn't.
Did you get a look
inside that garage?
Porsche still has dealer plates,
new Volvo wagon.
Money.
Dad was laid off.
Where'd it come from?
In L.A., at least 70% of all
murders are related to drugs.
Well, that might explain what
I recovered from the kitchen.
Finally got
a chance to process everything.
I don't think
Mom was just baking cakes.
That is a lot of baking soda.
And one seriously
accurate scale.
MORGAN:
Either mom was OCD, or
she was cutting powder.
Cocaine?
Maybe meth.
Well, we didn't find
any drugs in that house.
Because we weren't looking
for them.
I'll drive.
I know the way.
STOKES:
What are you doing?
(gasps) My hand looks
like Gorbachev's head.
I was out in the field whacking
the weeds for weaponry...
You know better than to handle
evidence without gloves.
...when I dropped my gloves.
And when I went down
to pick them up,
I put my hand in some very
un-eco-friendly battery acid.
Why'd you drop your gloves?
You know, they really
shouldn't even let you out
of the lab.
May I cite you
in my Workmen's Comp case?
How about citing your results
from the blue fibers
Super Dave found
on Mr. Chambliss, instead?
Lucky for you, I can
work through the pain.
Your blue fibers-- denim.
Of the phylum Levis.
So jeans.
Almost.
Just as you'll
never get the chance
to run Grave, these never
got the chance to be pants.
How much pain do you want
to have to work through, Hodges?
Please turn to page two.
The fibers were saturated
in borate-- fire retardant.
Jean companies will pulp
their cutting-room scraps
and sell them
for insulating materials.
Which is used
in green construction.
So how does insulation
end up on Dad?
Well, maybe he was doing
some sort of home improvement?
Or maybe
the killer works construction.
You don't have
to be mean about it.
SIDLE:
Morgan, Greg,
get in here.
This is the exact layout
of John Lee's bedroom,
except he didn't
have one of these.
Yeah, and the electrical
panel's in the garage.
Good call, Hollywood.
I love it when I'm right.
RUSSELL:
We searched the house, John.
We know about the drugs.
So these awful people
that went
into the house--
is-is that what they came for?
They let strange men sit
on her bed.
Made her sit out
in the hallway.
One time, she
forgot her doll.
Tried to come
back in and get it.
Her dad yelled at her.
She cried.
He yelled a lot.
Did he ever yell
at anybody else?
(computer trilling)
Got a hit-- multiple arrests
for drug possession.
SIDLE:
"Lonny Gallows."
John, you saw something happen
in that house.
You saw someone arguing
with Fiona's dad.
Who?
(phone chirps)
John, is this the guy?
Hey! Did you ever
see this man, John?
Yes.
In Fiona's bedroom?
Yes, a lot.
Lonny Gallows?!
(tires screech)
(grunts)
Get out of here.
Where you going,
dude?
Yo, I didn't
do nothing!
Yeah, pat him
down good, Mitch.
(Lonny sighs)
Lonny,
this looks bad.
Yeah, this looks worse.
Lonny Gallows,
you're under arrest.
Possession for sales
of a controlled substance.
Well, you're in a lot
more trouble than that, bud.
Hey, what are you doing
with my son?
Arresting him for murder.
My son didn't kill anyone.
Sir, stay out of this now.
You don't want to interfere
with a police
investigation.
Those boots are mine.
So are the gloves.
Arrest me. I did it.
I'm the one who killed
the Chambliss family.
You got to be kidding me.
You understand lying to
a police officer is a crime.
I'm not lying.
Really?
I got your file.
You know, Mr. Gallows,
you've never done
anything wrong
in your life.
You're a family man,
you own your own business,
you're doing well.
You're the only guy
in construction that I know
who's making money.
Then you massacre
a family?
I want to make a deal.
I'm not making a deal with you
because I don't believe you.
I did it.
Listen, listen, we know
your son's a drug addict.
He was high
when we busted him
and it's pretty safe
to assume he was high
a couple of nights ago when
he committed these crimes.
We found his prints all
over the cash and drugs
in the Chambliss house.
That's how we know
he was running drugs
for Cal Chambliss.
I get it--
you want to protect your kid.
I did protect my kid
by killing that family.
Lonny got clean in rehab.
I tried to keep him clean,
I put him on my crew
building
green houses--
same damn houses
in Cal Chambliss' neighborhood.
So that's
how they met.
It's my fault, my mistake.
Here's how I
correct it.
You drop the drug charges
on Lonny...
and I'll tell you everything.
BRASS:
Well, thanks to Maurice
Gallows' confession,
Leslie Gitig
just got sprung,
and our perv John Lee
just made bail.
I'm telling you, it pays
to have rich parents.
I don't see
the dad doing it.
No, no, man, he's taking
the rap for his son.
Okay, so Lonny's dealing
drugs for Chambliss,
gets hooked, starts dipping
into his boss' supply.
Cal cuts him off, and Lonny
just decides to gets even.
ECKLIE:
Great,
so our only viable suspect
is the one person
who hasn't confessed
to the crime.
Any thoughts?
Yeah.
Who killed Cock Robin?
Those shrooms in your office
aren't medicinal, are they?
"I," said the Sparrow.
"With my bow and arrow,
I killed Cock Robin."
Who saw him die?
"I," said the Fly.
"With my little eye,
I saw him die."
"I," said the Fish,
"I," said...
Oh, come on.
All right, forget
folk songs.
Uh, crime novels.
Strangers on a Train.
ECKLIE:
Yeah, I saw the movie.
What's, what's
your point?
The p...
(sighs)
Nick, when you were
hooking up Lonny,
what did his father say--
exact words?
He said,
"I did it, I'm the one who
killed the Chambliss family."
"I," said John Lee,
"I did it, I'm the one who
killed the Chambliss family."
"I," said Leslie Gitig,
"I did it,
I'm the one who killed
the Chambliss family."
Now, that's three confessions,
all identical.
Hell of a coincidence.
So it's like they got
their stories straight.
They were working together.
STOKES: Strangers
on a Train.
Total strangers get together
to commit a crime,
figuring the cops won't
make the connection.
And each one of
them had motive
to do harm to someone
in that family.
ECKLIE:
And each had
reason to confess.
By all confessing,
they muddied the water.
There is
no perfect crime,
but if you create
enough reasonable doubt,
you might just have
the perfect defense.
And that's something
a legal secretary would know.
ECKLIE:
Now,
how do we get
around reasonable doubt?
Find the train.
WILLOWS:
All right, thank you.
So I just spoke with the owner
of Benson's Auto Body.
Two weeks ago,
Leslie Gitig
paid him $4,500.
Benson's Auto Body?
That's where
John Lee works.
Could be
where they met.
Leslie's BMW was
in an accident
and she didn't want to run it
through her insurance.
She paid cash, but not just
for her repair but
for the truck that
she plowed into.
Truck, what kind of truck?
I don't know,
the driver
hasn't brought it in yet.
Maybe 'cause he needed it
for work.
I saw a couple of thousand
dollars worth of damage
to Maurice Gallows' truck.
All right,
well, sounds like
we need to take
a look at that truck,
compare the damage
to Leslie's car.
I'll take the truck.
Greg and I'll take the Beemer.
WOMAN (over radio):
Victor 2-4, Victor 2-4. Come in.
Nice job matching
the color.
Well, yeah,
to the naked eye anyway.
(beeping)
Yep, left-side damage.
I'll call for a warrant.
(gunshots)
3-David-34.
Shots fired. Request
backup at our location.
2-David-3-4, copy that.
4-34 call.
We got one down.
(gasps)
We need rescue
at 10923
Cartland Avenue.
Gunshot victim.
OFFICER:
Put the gun down!
Put the gun down! Now!
Stay with her.
OFFICER:
Drop the gun.
John...
please...
do what he says.
Put down the gun.
(sobbing)
They made me go there.
She made me.
Leslie?
She said I could have her,
but she didn't tell
me what we had to do.
And then the screaming started.
The shooting--
it was so loud and
there was blood.
There was so much blood.
John, we can talk
about this.
You've got to put the gun down.
She said Fiona had to die.
She gave me
her gun...
this gun.
(screams)
Oh, shut up!
I just couldn't do it.
Give me that.
No, no!
(gunshot)
She was so beautiful.
I didn't want to
remember her like that,
so I came back
afterward.
That awful woman.
Sh-She took my
Fiona away from me.
(distant siren blaring)
Now... I have nothing.
(gunshot)
(gasps)
RUSSELL:
We found the murder weapons
at Leslie Gitig's house.
Knife, gun-- the real one.
I killed Chambliss
and his family,
like I said.
Well,
it's a good story,
but this gun tells
a better one.
Maurice, your son did it.
BRASS:
The gun goes back to him,
so unless you make us
understand
what really happened,
Lonny's going to
get the needle.
This is crazy, you know, I...
I'd blame Leslie.
It wasn't like she hit
your truck by accident.
That's just the beginning
of the damage she did
to you and your family.
There are no
accidents, right?
A woman scorned
parks outside her ex-lover's
house night after night,
thinking about how
to destroy him?
What does she see?
A pedophile lusting
after a little girl...
Stop pushing
drugs on my son
or I swear I
will kill you.
...and a father
fighting for his son.
You and your whole family!
Three strangers
who all want
something.
They just need to meet.
I did everything I could
to get Lonny clean,
and it was working.
Then he met Cal,
and I was losing him again.
She swore
it was just going to be Cal.
Cal's expecting me.
MAURICE:
She lied.
(screaming)
What are you waiting for?
MAURICE:
Once I stepped into that house,
I had no choice.
(gunshot)
Run!
No!
(screams)
(gasps)
You bitch!
(screaming)
(Fiona screaming)
Give me that.
No, no!
(hammer cocks, gunshot)
You know what it's like
to lose a kid to drugs,
to wish the world for 'em
and see that world
come crashing down around 'em?
I do,
actually.
I do.
But it still
doesn't justify killing
a whole family.
(footsteps approaching,
knocking at door)
I'm going to head out.
You need anything?
No, I'm good, thank you.
I'll see you tomorrow.
"Cock Robin."
Really?
(chuckles)
What journal
did you get that one from?
My parents were singers,
and that was kind of a
favorite around our, our van.
Oh.
Go with what you know, right?
Yeah.
Well, it worked,
it really worked.
What's going on?
Are you all right?
(phone buzzing)
Aren't you going
to get that?
I don't want to be rude.
Oh, be rude.
Good night.
(phone continues buzzing)
Hey, doll,
how are you?
Uh, don't worry
about it.
I-I'll pick something up
for us on the way home.
Yeah, hey, hey, wait, how, how
did Charlie do in practice?