Previously, on CSI:
RUSSELL:
Extended family meeting-- now.
This is Agent McQuaid,
Special Agent in Charge Pratt.
They're with the FBI.
McQUAID:
Four weeks ago, in Pakistan,
a warehouse guard was killed
trying to stop
a raid on U.S.
military supplies.
The scene was processed by
operatives working for
Ceressus Logistics.
WILLOWS: Laura?
What are you doing here?
LAURA: My husband is helping
out on a case
with the police and the FBI.
Your husband's Mark Gabriel.
The sort of corruption you're
implying is neither encouraged
nor tolerated at Ceressus.
Get down!
WILLOWS: We know that Ceressus
is implicated.
We just want to know
how far up the ladder it goes.
WESSON: I tell you everything,
I want immunity.
Lenny Wesson died en route to
a federal holding facility.
I heard something.
By accident.
WILLOWS:
He's a good lawyer.
He's Sam's guy.
I think you might need that.
MALCOLM TURNER:
...but what's gonna happen is
that you've got to come in here,
we gotta have a face-to-face.
And that's what we're gonna do.
Other than that...
RECEPTIONIST:
Right.
TURNER:
This can't go anywhere.
RECEPTIONIST:
Yes.
What's the point?
Absolutely.
Okay. All right, I will.
That's right.
Right.
He has one more client.
All right. I'll have
him call you back.
Joey, please.
You disposed of a body,
I disposed of the case.
Aw, jeez...
(groans)
A Mrs. Hobart is waiting.
Last appointment of the day?
Let me guess:
Messy divorce?
Contested will?
I'll let you be surprised.
(chuckles)
I think we're okay on water...
Excuse me.
Excuse me, did you
hear what I said?
We don't need any water.
♪ ♪
(sobbing)
The office is closed.
(siren wails)
Who called this in?
Couple of campers,
but, uh, they moved on.
Yeah, they didn't want to
spend the rest of
their camping trip
talking to us.
Well, based on the pelvic bones,
I'd say one male, two female.
If I was going to
kill three people,
I'd want a little more privacy.
Yeah, this close to the road...
Looks like a body dump to me.
VARTANN: Well, looks like
they've been here a while.
Dermestes maculatus.
Hide beetles.
Nature's cleaning crew.
Depending on
the weather conditions,
they usually set up shop
5 to 11 days post-mortem.
So those guys should help
narrow down the time of death.
Yeah, but a cold front
and heavy rains
blew through here
a few days ago.
Don't hide beetles
hate the cold?
Yeah. They like
the rain even less.
So...these many bugs
shouldn't still be here.
STOKES: And there's
no way these bodies
should be
this badly decomposed.
Something's not right here.
Bugs don't lie.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
ROBBINS: D.B., you may want
to take a look at this.
RUSSELL:
Jane Doe Number One.
Entry wound
looks like a small caliber.
Bullet is copper-washed.
Looks like a .22.
Kill shot.
She sustained at least
five other GSWs.
Four perforating,
through-and-through,
caliber unknown.
And one penetrated.
I pulled this bullet
from the spinal column.
Well, that's definitely
not a .22.
It's too long.
Xiomara will be able to
tell us what it is.
You ever heard of anyone
named Xiomara before?
No.
There was a Xiomara in
my gross anatomy class.
And let me tell you, her anatomy
was anything but gross.
If you know what I mean.
(laughing)
Okay.
I have bodies to wash.
Indeed.
Yeah.
I found similar beveling in our
other Jane and John Doe.
As far as I can tell,
they both sustained
five gunshot wounds
to the torso.
All evenly spaced.
So Jane Doe Number One gets
a kill shot to the head,
and these other two got
stitched across the chest.
Very precisely.
Looks professional.
I'll say this, all of our
victims had excellent teeth.
Served them well in life.
May serve us in death.
I'm sending these over to
Henry to pulp and process.
DNA may give us an I.D.
♪ ♪
Henry?
We're here.
What do you got?
I got your I.D.s.
Victims were all
in Missing Persons.
Ladies first.
Amelia Gross, 52, receptionist.
And Julie Blanch, 28, paralegal.
Both worked for...
Malcolm Turner, 64, attorney.
Didn't he work for your father?
How long did you say
those bodies
were out there in the mountains?
Nick wasn't sure. He thought
maybe a week or so. Why?
Something wrong?
I hope not.
(line ringing)
Come on, Laura. Pick up.
Come on, come on,
come on, come on...
Laura, why are you here?
Is it about Mark?
(line continues ringing)
LAURA:
I'm scared.
Sometimes... I'm scared
to even say something aloud...
Voice mailbox full?
LAURA:
I took your advice.
I'm leaving Mark.
I talked to that lawyer.
He's arranging a meeting
with the FBI.
I'm going to tell them
everything I know.
...tell them everything I know.
WILLOWS:
You're doing the right thing.
Where are you? Where are you?
WILLOWS:
Do you need a place to stay?
I'm staying at our
condo in town.
I want you to have a key.
Just in case.
WILLOWS:
I went to Laura's condo.
Her things were all there,
but there was no sign of her.
And the doorman hadn't seen her
since Saturday night?
No.
You really think something's
happened to her.
I do.
I do, and I think I know
who's responsible.
Well, we're about to
find out if you're right.
BRASS: Thank you for
coming in, Mr. Gabriel.
Didn't think we'd
cross paths
so soon.
What's happened to my wife?
Why don't you tell us?
I haven't seen Laura
in two weeks,
since she moved out of
our place in Denver.
Since she talked to the
lawyer you sent her to.
BRASS:
Where'd she go?
She said she was staying at our
condo here in Vegas for a while.
Marriage not going so well?
That's between me and my wife.
Well, now that she's missing,
it's between you and LVPD.
No one is more concerned
about finding Laura than I am.
I've been trying
to reach her for days.
BRASS:
We know.
Her voice mailbox is
full of concerned messages.
You've been on the phone a lot.
Not only to your wife,
but to her lawyer, as well.
Malcolm Turner.
So? We've spoken
on the phone...
Not lately, I bet.
His office isn't taking
any calls.
I came here because you said
my wife was missing.
I came here to cooperate.
But I see this is going the same
way my last interview here went.
So, let's end it the
same way, shall we?
You can contact my attorneys.
Son of a bitch killed her.
I don't like the guy
any more than you do,
but let's just back up
for a second.
Malcolm Turner
wasn't just any lawyer,
the guy was a fixer.
He had enemies.
And as far as we know,
your friend Laura
might just have run away.
Yeah, she ran to Malcolm Turner.
I sent her there because of him.
We know that Mark Gabriel dumped
guns on the streets of Vegas.
And we can't prove it.
Because our best witness
ended up dead.
Laura had information.
About what?
About Gabriel's business?
She was afraid to say.
So we're still not sure, right?
I'm sure that it got her killed.
Did you take
their statements yet?
(chuckles)
No, they, uh...
they lawyered up.
But I'm having a little trouble
with their story anyway.
You know, I confirmed
the weather conditions
where we found the bodies.
Now, given the cold
and the rain,
we really shouldn't have found
any beetles out there at all.
And the condition
of the bodies
suggests that bugs had
been eating on them
for at least a week.
Well, forget a week.
How about 14 hours?
What?
Vartann interviewed
Malcolm Turner's widow.
She talked to
her husband's receptionist
around 8:00 last night.
Which means all our victims
had to have been in the office
around that time.
No, no-- 8:00 p.m.
last night?
That's impossible.
The bodies were picked clean
by this morning.
(rattling)
(beetles churring)
Have you eaten lunch yet?
Well, I hope
they like it extra crispy.
(chuckles) No, they're
actually a little bit
smarter than we are.
They like it healthy,
so I'll get the
skin off here...
There you go.
Bon appétit, gentlemen.
(churring)
Now-now... now,
wait a minute.
You know we can't
eat in here, dude.
Well, I won't tell Russell
if you don't.
Yeah, okay, sounds like a deal.
VARTANN:
Surveillance confirms that
Malcolm Turner and his staff
arrived for work at 7:48 a.m.
Now, the phone logs say
that they worked all day,
and that they ordered lunch in.
No sign of
them leaving?
Nope.
Their cars are still
in the garage.
So how'd they make
the big reverse commute
back to the mountains?
SIDLE: It does not look like
they were killed here.
BRODY: What?
They just vanished?
Janitorial came through
at quarter to 9:00.
They found the place
locked, nobody here,
and they saw nothing
out of the ordinary.
(Morgan laughs)
I gotta get these guys
to clean my place.
Not a single smudge or print.
You know, the only janitor
I know who's this thorough
turned out to be
a serial killer.
What do we know about
this cleaning crew?
Same guys who've been cleaning
this office every night
for the last seven years.
BRODY:
Okay.
So, if these guys
didn't give the place
the white glove treatment, who
did?
(churring)
It's amazing.
They picked it clean
in less than an hour.
Yeah. They eat
even faster than you.
(wry laugh)
Well, they eat faster than any
hide beetles I've ever seen.
Maybe that's why the decomp
was inconsistent with T.O.D.
Super beetles.
STOKES: They're
some kind of different,
I'll say that.
Question is... how?
Genetic anomaly?
Freaks of nature?
It's definitely an
entomological mystery.
Where did you come from,
you little beasts?
(scoffs)
♪ ♪
Whew.
(crying)
(screams)
(gunshot)
This office
is definitely our primary,
but only you, me, the walls
and the carpet know it.
And do you smell what I smell?
Nothing.
No bleach.
They used ethanol
to destroy the DNA.
Smart.
Any blood, fingerprints,
any trace of what happened
in here is gone.
They even walked
the bodies out of here
without anybody noticing.
Call log said the last call
came in at 8:07.
Janitorial crew got here
at quarter to 9:00.
We're talking less
than 45 minutes.
Russell said the hit
was professional.
Clean-up was professional, too.
Who are these guys?
BRODY: I checked surveillance
covering the 45 minutes
it took our bad guys
to kill and clean.
According to Skadden Springs,
there were no scheduled
deliveries last night.
Okay, so bogus delivery guy.
BRODY:
That's not the only thing
that was bogus.
We were wondering
how they got the bodies out.
I think I can answer that.
At 8:02, three men delivered
office furniture
to the building.
And at 8:47,
just as the janitors
were entering
the legal office upstairs,
the same three guys
came back out...
With the exact
same furniture.
Maybe just a little heavier.
Oh, look!
There's our water guy again.
What do you want to bet,
he was delivering ethanol?
"Jordan's Office Supply."
I ran it.
Company doesn't exist.
(laughs)
These guys are good.
Organized.
Covert. Precise.
If I didn't know any better,
I'd say
they had military training.
Yeah, just like the army,
every squad
needs a squad leader.
Four paths converged
in a service area,
and they took the path
most traveled by...
What're you getting at?
Walk these guys
back out again.
Yeah, look at this.
"Hello, boss."
"Hey, nice work."
See, they're talking
to each other.
"Ah, well done."
"Thanks, boss."
When was the last time
you saw anyone wear
a raincoat in Vegas?
I think I can answer that.
(typing)
Just after 8:00 p.m.,
guy in the raincoat
got on the elevator.
Ten minutes later, he got off.
After the murders.
All right,
so we got our cleaning
crew and our hit team.
Let's take a closer
look at these guys.
Pull their faces
out of the crowd.
(churring)
Rest in peace, little man.
Hey, Nick. What's up?
Well, that's just it.
I'm not real sure,
and I could use your help.
Okay?
Okay.
Greg and I did a
little experiment
with the beetles we found
at the dump site.
They have an appetite unlike
any other bug
I've ever seen before.
Check that out.
Now...
that explains how the bodies
were picked clean in half a day,
but it doesn't explain this.
What am I looking at?
That's the beetle's equipment.
Enhanced.
Obviously.
And completely useless.
Well, my guess is,
they were irradiated.
Where are you going with this?
I think someone's
bioengineering these bugs.
I know it sounds
crazy, but it's like
something has switched off
their "I'm full" button,
made them great eaters,
bad breeders,
so that they do their job,
and they just disappear.
Along with their dinner.
Yeah.
Pretty crazy, right?
No. No.
That's... Actually,
that's pretty consistent
with Mark Gabriel
and Ceressus.
That company is into
all kinds of covert ops,
weapons development,
you name it.
(cell phone chimes)
Ballistics came back
from our victims.
The main caliber used
was a 5.7 by 28.
5.7 by 28.
That's the same caliber
as the bullets
that killed that ballistics
expert last month, right?
That's the same caliber
as the assault rifles
that went missing in Pakistan
and ended up here in Vegas.
But I thought we got all those
off the streets.
Apparently not.
Okay, but
Mark Gabriel claimed he had
nothing to do with those guns.
Yeah, just like he had nothing
to do with his wife's
disappearance.
(dialing)
So who you calling now?
The FBI.
AGENT PRATT:
Look.
I'm sorry, a few bullets
and bugs isn't enough for us
to put the target back
on Mark Gabriel.
What about his wife and
her lawyer coming forward?
Laura Gabriel was coming to you
with information.
So the FBI is brought in
on a case,
and nobody thinks to call me?
Jim...
Yeah, actually,
no, it was my bad.
I-I called them.
I should've given you
a heads-up.
Okay.
The heads-up can start now.
Well, you remember Special
Agents Pratt and McQuaid.
You're working
the Ceressus case.
And they just agreed
to provide background
that might help us out
on our current investigation.
Isn't that right?
That's about right.
RUSSELL:
Because the truth is,
you wouldn't have responded
quickly to my phone call
if you didn't think
that Mark Gabriel
was guilty of more
than gunrunning.
Right?
We've had reason to believe
that Ceressus's been engaged
in a number of illegal
activities here in the U.S.
BRASS: What illegal
activities
exactly are you talking about?
Full disclosure.
That would be refreshing.
We've been looking at Mark
Gabriel for almost a year now.
We believe that Ceressus is
heavily involved in gunrunning,
corporate espionage, computer
hacking-- the list goes on.
Bringing their international
expertise to a domestic market.
Corporations.
Cartels.
Whoever's got the
highest bid.
How about murder for hire?
Okay. I guess
we take that as a yes.
Okay. What have you got?
A lot more than you think.
You know these people?
Yeah, we've seen them before,
but we haven't been
able to connect them
to Ceressus or
Mark Gabriel.
I mean, the guy
doesn't make mistakes.
Thank you
for the full disclosure.
As for the mistakes,
I beg to differ.
He made three.
I'm sorry
about your friend.
(sighs)
Me, too.
Hey, look, I was going
to call you, but...
It's probably better
that you didn't.
(sighs)
Maybe we could...
We've got work to do.
Yeah.
Hey. Who was that?
He's Jim McQuaid
with the FBI.
They're cooperating
on the Gabriel case.
I ran down Laura
Gabriel's financials.
She closed out her bank
account five days ago.
Withdrew $28,000.
Sounds like
she was scared.
Maybe she tried
to go on the run.
Well, I don't think
she got very far.
Activity on her cell phone
stopped the day
before the hit
at the law office.
You all right?
I will be.
When we nail Gabriel.
Mom.
What are you
doing here?
At the desk,
they said it was okay.
Well, sure, it's okay,
but why are you here?
This came in my mail,
but the card
was meant for you.
"Catherine, sorry I
couldn't make it.
I tried.
David Campbell."
David Campbell?!
I know.
Laura's father.
I-I-I...
I don't understand.
The man died
20 years ago.
Catherine, what is going on?
Did something
happen to Laura?
Has anyone else touched this?
Just me, the mailman,
and now you.
I'm going to have someone
escort you home.
Card's the same story
as the envelope.
Besides you and your mom,
just partials;
nothing usable.
I'll swab it for DNA.
Laura mailed the card
a day before the murders
at the law office
and sent it directly
from a post office
in Pahrump.
She wanted to make sure
you got it.
And make sure that Gabriel
didn't intercept it.
That's why she sent it
to my mom.
You really think Mark Gabriel
is reading your mail?
I wouldn't put anything
past him.
You and Laura close?
(laughs)
Yeah.
At one time, yeah.
When we were kids,
Laura's house
was like my second home.
Until Sam, her dad
was like the closest
thing I had to a father.
We were like sisters.
This card play music
when you got it?
Well, no, but I just
assumed it wasn't working.
Well, I think I know
why you got cheated
out of a birthday song.
This is a cell phone
memory card.
JOHNSON:
So I ran the memory card.
It's not Laura's.
It's registered
to Mark Gabriel.
And this is all that's on it?
Ah, pictures of the Gabriels
over the last year.
Why would Laura go
to all that trouble
to send me vacation photos?
If you didn't know
any better, you'd
think they had a
pretty wonderful life.
You know, there
was one picture, though,
that seemed a little
out of place.
Show me.
Yeah.
Some kind of weird
self-portrait.
En-Enlarge it, please.
Yeah.
I know that house.
I've been there
when I was a kid.
That's Laura's cousin's house.
(sirens wailing)
LVPD!
Blowflies.
Copper in the air.
(door creaking, banging)
Is it Laura?
It's Laura's cousin Helen...
and Helen's husband.
Both shot in
the head.
She took a beating.
So where's Laura?
When we were kids,
we played here.
Laura's granddad grew up
in the Depression.
Didn't trust banks.
So, when he built
this house, he made sure
that he would never need
any banks
to keep his money safe.
Laura!
RUSSELL (over phone):
Laura Gabriel's alive?
Yeah. We found her hiding in
a crawl space under the house.
Catherine's talking
to her right now.
You think it's the same crew
that hit the law office?
Oh, it doesn't look like it.
The place is a mess.
Unless they're losing
their touch.
Maybe they got interrupted.
Okay.
Uh, finish processing the scene.
I'll let the FBI guys know.
I got it.
It happened so fast.
I heard them break in.
Helen told me to hide.
They had Derek.
They were yelling at him.
Helen was screaming.
Please don't shoot him!
(gun fires)
HELEN:
No!
(sobbing)
Next thing I know,
they were shouting at her.
Hitting her.
(sobbing):
Please...
And then...
She wouldn't tell them.
They were beating her,
and she still wouldn't
tell them anything.
Could you tell
how many there were?
No.
I heard one of them.
He got a phone call.
Sounded like he had an accent.
After that, they left.
When I heard footsteps again,
I thought they'd come back.
I was sure that
they'd find me.
(sobbing):
But it was you.
Laura. Laura.
What is it
that you know
that has Mark so worried?
Remember when I told you
I overheard something?
One night, Mark was in
the study with a man.
They were talking about
cleaning the offices
of Stanley Merrill.
Why do I know that name?
Stanley Merrill
was a military contractor,
rival of Mark's.
Went missing
11 months ago.
Mark killed him. I know it.
You're here,
so I'm assuming
you got the card I sent?
Yeah, and the memory card
with the photo
that you took.
You knew that I'd
recognize the house.
There were more photos
on that memory card.
Yeah, the vacation photos.
More than that.
What do you mean?
When Mark conducted business,
he always swapped out
the memory card on his phone.
That one was in his pocket.
I took it.
I know Mark.
There has to be something more.
HODGES: There really is
nothing more tedious
than to have to sit
through a slide show
of somebody else's
vacation photos.
My mother went
to Anguilla
over Christmas
with her new boyfriend.
He's a regular
Ansel Adams.
I sat through four hours
of sand, sea and sunset.
I didn't know your mom
had a new boyfriend.
Yeah, I don't want
to talk about it.
Good. Me, neither.
What are you doing?
Catherine thinks there's
some kind of information
hidden in these images.
Steganography.
The art of embedding data
within data.
So I'm analyzing
the noise levels to see
if there are any data packets
embedded in these pixels.
Have you checked
the noise levels on this marlin?
No, not yet.
Haven't gotten there. Why?
Well, I'm no expert,
but this little
Punxsutawney Phil of the sea
isn't seeing his shadow.
You're right--
no shadow.
This fish has been Photoshopped.
These noise levels
are off the charts.
There's definitely data
embedded in this fish.
Let's gut it.
Running it through
steganalysis decryption...
now.
Numbers.
Could be a code?
Yeah.
PRATT:
So, Mr. Martens,
is there a reason why
Mark Gabriel sent his number two
instead of coming
here himself?
Mr. Gabriel had
an important conference.
He sends his regrets.
I'm sure he does.
PRATT:
So, as the CFO
of Ceressus,
you're the money guy.
And legal counsel.
What's this about?
Well, we went on a little, uh,
fishing expedition,
and we found
a bunch of numbers embedded
in this image right here.
First, we thought
that they were code,
but then we realized
that they were actually numbers
and dates of transactions.
PRATT: Recording monies
being wired
from a subsidiary
of Ceressus
to a single account
in a Swiss bank.
And where did you get
this information?
Ah, well, that's all
very cloak-and-dagger.
But here's where
it gets interesting.
The actual dates
of the transactions.
PRATT: 11 months ago,
your boss's rival,
Stanley Merrill, disappears.
And money goes to Switzerland.
I don't know anything
about that.
Four weeks ago, Lenny Wesson,
witness against Ceressus,
dies in custody.
And money goes to Switzerland.
These numbers are meaningless.
Four days ago, Malcolm Turner,
lawyer to your boss's wife,
who'd agreed to come forward
with information, is murdered.
Once again, the Swiss economy
gets a shot in the arm.
Now...
I know that your law degree
is telling you
that we don't have enough
to make a case,
but sooner or later,
someone's going to talk.
And my common sense degree
tells me
sooner would be a lot better
for you.
Look, I have no knowledge
of this subsidiary of Ceressus,
and I don't know anything
about these transactions.
All right.
You know them?
These men? No.
This man,
I'm sorry to say, I do.
Who is he?
A contractor who's done work
for Ceressus abroad.
What kind of work?
I think you know the answer.
To my knowledge,
we've never called
on his expertise
for any assignments
in this country,
nor would I ever
sanction it.
Well, sounds to me
like someone left you
holding the bag.
Or perhaps given me reason
to cooperate.
I'm going to need cover.
RUSSELL:
Okay.
Now we're getting someplace.
I've got some
good news.
You're not going to be
alone in coming forward.
What do you mean?
Someone else has agreed
to cooperate with the FBI.
Who?
Well, I can't say.
But what I can say
is that you're going
to get through this.
I hope so.
For all our sakes.
Yeah.
Sir...
MARK: Laura!
Laura!
Hey, hey, whoa, whoa, whoa.
I can't let
you in here.
I have the right
to see my wife.
McQUAID: Actually,
Mr. Gabriel, you don't.
Mr. Gabriel, I'm gonna have
to ask you to stay out here.
Get him the hell out of here.
That's my wife!
She's a witness.
And she's going
to bury you.
No, you're the one
trying to bury me.
Oh, if I was going to bury you,
I'd put you in the ground where
they'd never find you.
Really? Is that a threat?
Do you need help
finding the door?
We're not done.
(sighs)
Everything's going
to work out, you'll see.
Thank you.
She's scared.
Yeah, well...
she's got reason.
Wish I could say it'll
go away with time,
but I'd be lying.
You can never completely
outrun your past.
I'm never going
to see her again.
What about you?
Well, that's your call.
(sighs)
Transport team's here.
Don't worry...
I'll be with her the whole time.
♪ ♪
(speaking quietly)
BRODY:
Name's Paul Obrecht, 54.
German native.
Emigrated to the
U.S. when he was 16.
According to the Ceressus file
we got off Gabriel's number two,
Obrecht served in the military.
Army Special Forces.
Honorable discharge, 1989.
At which point,
he became a soldier-for-hire.
Assignments in Africa,
the Mideast,
South America.
And now, apparently, here in the
U.S., working for Mark Gabriel.
Laura said that the man
that Gabriel hired
to kill Stanley Merrill,
the man that she heard
at her cousin's house,
had an accent.
These guys are pros.
Yeah, but they're
not infallible.
And their loyalty
is only to themselves.
Right.
So, if we catch them,
maybe we can get them
to flip on Gabriel.
Right.
FBI sent over the case file
on Stanley Merrill's
disappearance.
Putting our bad guys there, too.
Same cast of characters.
Including one we overlooked
at the law firm.
And at Stanley Merrill's
office 11 months ago.
Push in on the woman's face.
I just saw her.
Where?
At the hospital.
She's on the FBI
transport detail.
How long ago
did you lose contact?
Jim, we've got
a situation.
Come on, Pratt, all your
vehicles have GPS, right?
Where? When?
No, Willows identified her.
She's on the hit team,
I'm sure of it.
Are you sure?
Well, keep me in the loop.
LVPD found them.
(siren whoops)
Sorry, guys, the
FBI's got this one.
What happened?
Evidence on the ground
suggests an ambush.
They took out the lead car.
The FBI guys
never saw it coming.
And the car with Laura Gabriel
and Agent McQuaid?
They tried to
evade the shooters.
Driver was hit first.
And then Laura and McQuaid.
And then they torched the car.
RUSSELL:
Any witnesses?
No.
But I found these.
Seen those before.
VARTANN: Hope they were
dead before the fire...
PRATT: ...probably a guy
or two down here.
Trying to figure out if the
convoy was off course or not,
or if it was driven
into this ambush...
How could you let this happen?!
CSI Willows, please.
How could you allow an assassin
to infiltrate
your protection team
and got four agents
and my friend killed?!
This is not the time.
Catherine, let's let them
do their job, okay?
Oh, it's a little late for that.
This should be our crime scene.
You should be on the phone
getting everybody
down here!
All hands on deck!
Hey, hey, hey, listen.
I know how you're feeling
right now, believe me.
I'm going to give you some
advice someone gave me once.
Walk away.
Right now.
Walk away?!
Yes, go to the office,
leave your notes on my desk,
and then go home.
Just like that?
Yeah, just like that.
Don't let her
drive herself.
(blip)
Do you want me to come in?
It's probably not a good idea.
Well, if you need anything,
call me.
Okay?
(sighs)
Thanks.
You deserve more, Lou.
(engine starts)
♪ ♪
(gunshot)
(automatic gunfire)
(groans)
(grunts)
♪ ♪
(tires screeching)
Get in!
Hurry up! Come on, come on!
Here they come!
WILLOWS:
Go! Go!
(panting)
You okay?
I'll live.
Whoa!
Aah!
(Willows grunts quietly)
Ooh...
(gasping)