BRODY: I'm not saying
I don't like Vegas.
I'm just saying L.A. clearly
owns it
in a number of key categories.
Vegas has no heart,
no history...
SANDERS: No history?
RUSSELL: No taxes ought
to quiet your complaints.
BRODY:
No ocean.
SANDERS:
All right, Morgan,
I'll give you the ocean.
And the weather,
and the Lakers.
And the ability to walk
down the street
without being handed
full-frontal business cards.
Okay, but if you think L.A.
beats Vegas at night,
you need professional help.
Oh! You offering your services?
RUSSELL:
Hey, guys, please,
we're here for a crime scene.
(helicopter rotors whirring)
What is that?
CSI Russell?
Rescue helicopter?
Yes, sir.
We just drove 70 miles.
We were promised murder.
And you had it,
till 30 minutes ago.
What, the vic came
back to life?
He didn't have a pulse when
I found him on my patrol.
Called it in-- all
of a sudden, he groans.
Document everything
before we lose him.
GSW in the shoulder.
Right, let's
get him loaded.
Looks like a bullet graze
wound on the forehead.
Two gunshot wounds,
no blood pool?
This can't be
the primary.
Get a shot of his wrist.
Those are abrasions.
That guy was bound.
(phone rings)
Yeah. And burned.
Looks like two stun gun
marks on his neck.
EMT:
Spike 80-50 push.
No wallet?
Nothing.
Yeah!
Hey, it's Nick.
I just landed
a double in Northtown.
Is there anybody around
who can give me a hand?
Catherine
and Sara are in court.
It's your lucky day.
Our Mount Stirling D.B. just
Frankensteined on me.
So I'll send someone your way.
Okay, that'd be good. Thanks.
Hey, Greg, why don't you
hop on the chopper?
Process our vic at the hospital,
then head over to Northtown.
Nick has a double
he's having trouble with.
Oh, you want me to leave this
gorgeous crime scenery?
I'll do it.
All right, you go.
We'll stay.
A chopper ride and
a double homicide?
I'm up for some excitement.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
(phone ringing)
Miss me already?
Head 50 yards
from your 3:00.
I think I just found
the rest of your scene.
I won't tell Russell
I gave you the tip.
You can look smart
and owe me one.
All right, thanks.
Hey, sweetheart, it might
get a little bumpy.
No sign of forced entry.
Mailman spotted them through
the iron barred windows.
Mailman delivers door-to-door
in this neighborhood?
Takes some serious mail-sack.
Yeah.
So was the TV
or stereo on when the officers
responded?
The whole system was blaring.
I know both of these guys.
Wes Aykin, Tony Malos.
I busted them for some
juvie stuff a while back,
but now their ink
tells me they've turned pro.
Yeah, "Mad-10"?
Madison and Tenth.
That's the gang/syndicate
that runs this hood.
Diversified portfolio--
drugs, extortion,
prostitution,
Internet porn.
STOKES: Mm-hmm, and
quite the racket with
the fake credit cards.
The killer sure did leave
behind a lot of plastic.
You know, it doesn't seem like
this was about business.
Maybe it was personal.
Metal shavings.
Coming from the back door.
Yep. Here's our
point of entry.
Plasma cutter.
Slashed right
through the metal.
Inert gas and an electrical arc
create an ultra-hot plasma
that chews right through
the metal.
Hey, here it is right here.
"Stolen from Ronston Welding."
I'll give 'em a call.
Casa de Brass could use
some discounted pipe work.
(steady electronic tone)
What can I do?
Just stand back.
I've got epi running.
He's gone back into V-fib.
I'm going to shock again.
Clear.
Actually, lift the lids.
No pupil reaction.
One more time.
Clear.
(steady beeping)
There we go.
Welcome back, buddy.
You're on your way
to the hospital.
(mutters):
Samantha...
Samantha.
Hey, boys.
Didn't hear
you come in.
What's going on?
We already flipped 'em
and sticked 'em.
Both died around midnight.
I notice some burn marks
on the neck
consistent with
a stun gun.
Those are some pretty
nasty neck wounds.
ROBBINS:
They were both garroted.
I found that wire
under this victim.
Hmm.
Okay.
This attack was
clearly planned.
The killer used a plasma cutter
to gain entry.
He must have known it was
a good time to strike.
Yo, where's the beer?
What the...?!
(stun gun crackling)
Why are you doing this to us?!
ROBBINS: There are easier
ways to end two men.
The killer was either
getting off,
or trying to get
something out of them.
RUSSELL:
You sure about this, Greg?
Sure as
I can be.
RUSSELL:
Oh, there you go.
Good hunch, buddy.
Way to call it.
Eh, just trusting my instincts.
(camera shutter clicking)
Looks like we've got two nine
mill casings over here.
So one shot goes into our
victim's shoulder,
and... Oh, yes.
One shot grazes his head.
(gunshots)
Definitely our primary.
SANDERS:
Maybe more than that.
Second blood pool.
Two more casings.
We got a second
gunshot victim?
I don't know.
Not much blood.
And it looks like the ground
took the brunt of these shots.
No blood or tissue
on these bullets.
Maybe they didn't hit anybody.
Okay, so maybe both
of our blood pools come from
our guy on the chopper, right?
Let's keep looking.
Ah, found his jacket.
And I think I found his ride.
Tire impressions.
Wide axle.
Pickup or SUV?
So they drive our victim up
here, they shoot him,
and then they
leave him for dead.
His hands and knees
were caked with dirt.
He tried to crawl to the road.
Yeah, here we go.
Got a bloody print.
I'll send a photo
to Mandy for an I.D.
BRASS:
Save your powder.
We have a suspect.
Yeah? Who is it?
Ronston the welder
told me that an assistant of his
ran off with a bunch of
equipment last night,
and didn't show up
for work today.
His name is Frank Cafferty
and he has a record.
Got out six months ago
after doing a ten-year stint
for manslaughter.
RUSSELL:
Ah, thatagirl, Mandy.
Look, she sent us
a match for our print.
So our guy in the chopper
is a Frank Cafferty.
That's a little weird.
(phone ringing)
Stokes.
Yeah, Nick, you just
entered a print
for a Frank Cafferty
into the system.
Yeah, he's my suspect
over here.
Double homicide.
Yeah, he's our victim.
You mean the exact same guy
that's...
Yeah, up in the air
with Morgan.
Hell, you're a fighter.
PILOT:
This is Medevac 103.
(phone ringing)
Estimated time of arrival
at Desert Palm 0945.
Tracing Route 160
toward Wilson Ridge.
Still in the air, boss.
Really?
The Northtown double?
Copy that.
I'll make sure he's in custody
when we land.
(phone beeps off)
He's convulsing!
Protect him!
Get the I.V.--
Hey! Get back!
Hey!
I see you touch that radio,
or punch in codes,
bitch is dead,
you hear me?
Yeah.
Unstrap me.
I said unstrap me
or the cop eats it!
I'm not a cop...
Now!
Listen up!
I want your cans off
and your cell phones!
Throw 'em back!
Now! Hurry up!
Come on!
Now!
You! Due south. Fly low.
I see a town, a cop,
or a highway,
it's the last
thing you see.
You got it?
Yeah.
Where are we going?
Mexico.
I'm not sure how much "we"
there's gonna be about it.
(panting)
RUSSELL: So Morgan's still
not at your scene?
STOKES:
No, it's been over an hour.
She should've gotten there
by now.
All right, well, I'll check
with Medevac Dispatch.
Do you still
need a hand?
STOKES:
Nah, I'm good.
Catherine and Sarah
finished in court
and they're checking out
Frank Cafferty's address.
All right, good.
Thank you.
No service on Morgan's cell.
WOMAN:
Dispatch.
Uh, yeah, this is D.B. Russell
with Crime Lab.
Do you have an ETA
on a Medevac Three,
heading from Mount Stirling
to Desert Palm Hospital?
Negative. We've been unable
to reestablish radio contact
with Medevac Three.
All right, well, check
with Air Traffic Control,
will you, please?
Yes, sir.
Maybe they're taking
the scenic route.
ROBBINS:
Looks like a match.
Stun gun burns on
Frank Cafferty's neck
and the necks
of these dead Mad-10s
are three of a kind.
Well, Sara and I
just got back
from Cafferty's apartment.
The door had
been kicked in,
there were signs
of a struggle...
So Cafferty zapped and killed
these fine gentlemen
in Northtown,
retired for the evening...
Somebody else-- probably
from their crew--
went after Frank,
busted into his place,
used a stun gun on him,
then dragged him out
and up to the mountains.
Any idea what started the feud?
Well, Frank'll be at
the hospital soon.
I'm sure he's got
all kinds of answers.
Who's Samantha?
You might've been dreaming.
You kind of muttered it
while you were under.
I wasn't dreaming.
Is she someone special?
What'd you do?
Nothing.
You moved!
You're trying to do something.
I didn't move.
You're on medication.
Your vision's compromised.
Oh, yeah? You want
to test my vision, Doc?
Frank, come on,
it's not worth it.
Please...
Put him down.
What?
Drug him! I don't
want him moving!
I said drug him.
You got five seconds:
five... four...
Midazolam-- two ccs,
front pouch, clear bottle.
Hurry! Do it!
Quit eyeballing me.
Turn around!
Hurry up!
(grunts)
That's right.
Now, sit back...
enjoy the ride.
Okay, thanks, Jim.
So Brass dug in
to Cafferty's file.
There were no
gang connections.
The guy spent the past
ten years in prison
for a bar fight gone bad.
There was no gang beef
while he was in lockup,
and prior to prison,
he was in the service--
chopper pilot.
You know, I've been
going through the stuff
from his apartment--
you know, he doesn't
strike me as a gangbanger.
WILLOWS: So what was he
doing in that house,
torturing and killing
two Mad-10s?
Did Brass say anything
about a daughter?
Actually, yes.
His Army file claimed
that he was divorced
with one dependent.
Hm.
Daughter's name is Samantha.
She sent him a letter in
prison, four years ago.
"I've got a better
man in my life now.
"He looks out for me
like you never have.
You asked me for a recent
photo-- here you go."
Well, she grew up.
Ouch.
I've seen him before.
That's one of the Mad-10s
that Frank Cafferty killed.
Now we know why.
So the daughter
is the connection.
(phone rings)
Hi, Russell.
And that's all we know?
Hey... we need to talk.
Uh-oh. Which one
was it this time?
Morgan.
Well, that didn't
take long.
How'd she screw up?
Well, she didn't, actually.
Let me talk to you
for a second.
She hitched a ride
on a medevac helicopter
that was supposed
to land an hour ago.
No sign of it yet.
Was there a distress call?
No. No radio,
no transponder signal,
no appearance on radar.
Now, look-- this is my team,
my responsibility.
Yeah-- my daughter.
I know. I know.
Then again, you're
a better supervisor
than I ever was a father.
Air Traffic Control
better have some answers.
SANDERS: When he took off
from Mount Stirling,
the pilot reported
his flight plan to Dispatch.
PILOT:
Estimated time of arrival...
SANDERS: Because of the
patient's head wound,
he wanted to avoid altitude,
so he was going
to trace Route 160
and cut across Wilson Ridge
toward the city.
Now, McCarran radar
can't pick up aircraft
blocked by the mountains,
but at the last radio update
to Dispatch, at 9:27 a.m.,
the copter was here.
Now, it should've emerged
from behind the mountains,
and onto McCarran radar
six or seven minutes later.
It never emerged.
Archie pinged the
cells of Morgan,
the pilot and paramedic--
all three were emanating
from a one-acre area
here.
Sheriff's deputies
recovered the phones,
but no sign of any wreckage.
Cafferty-- he made 'em
toss the phones.
That chopper's hijacked.
Okay...
All right,
we keep working the case.
I want to find out everything
we can about Frank Cafferty,
in case we make
contact with him.
I was supposed to be
the CSI on that flight.
We don't have time
for that right now.
Let's just stay focused,
and make sure we bring
our girl home, okay?
Why don't you check out Sara,
see what she's got.
So I think I know why Cafferty
was at that Northtown house--
he was looking for
his daughter.
Samantha used to go out
with Wes Aykin,
one of the dead Mad-10s.
So, Cafferty figures that
Wes and the rest of the gang
might know where
she was, right?
Well, it was more than a hunch.
He had seen some awful proof.
I'd found a Web address
jotted among Frank's
possessions.
The URL-- it's a
file-sharing site.
Specifically, one file.
Porn video.
She looks drugged.
Yeah.
So Cafferty sees this
and wants to
rescue his daughter.
Tries to strangle her
whereabouts out of Wes and Tony.
Right?
Mm-hmm.
So do we know where she is?
No. She renewed
her license a month ago,
but the address
she used is a weekly,
and she's no longer there.
Tire treads Greg photo'd
at the mountain scene.
They're high-end run-flats--
standard on a number
of luxury SUVs--
Lexus, BMW, Porsche...
Cafferty had a digital camera.
There were some amateur
surveillance photos on it.
He was tracking
the Mad-10s.
Probably since he
got out of prison.
Their properties,
cars, including...
a Porsche Cayenne.
So that could be the vehicle
that took Cafferty
up into the mountains.
WILLOWS:
Partial plate--
I'll run it through DMV.
I had all the techs
and interns
put out a photo file
on the copter--
e-mail, Twitter--
saying that:
If you see this, let us know.
Good idea.
She's a really good CSI.
Nick, you got anything?
Twentynine Palms
Marine Corps Base,
100 miles south
of Mount Stirling,
reported a non-transponding
radio-silent craft
in their airspace
15 minutes ago.
Guy in the tower said it
looked like Medevac Three.
By the time we
got the message,
it was off radar.
RUSSELL:
So they're heading due south.
What, Mexico?
CHP's on the lookout,
but they haven't seen it.
You know, Cafferty
may have the pilot
zigging and zagging
around up there.
Yeah, well, even if they're
straight-lining it,
they're gonna
have to refuel
before they
get to the border.
Every airstrip between here and
there's got a heads-up, so...
I got that DNA on the
two blood pools
you and Greg found
at the mountain scene.
The big pool was Cafferty.
The small pool was a second
contributor-- a female.
Cafferty's daughter?
No, a 19-year-old
named Tiffany Bamford.
She's got priors for assault;
and ties to the Mad-10s.
And I checked hospitals--
she's at Desert Palm.
They didn't want me
comin' here but...
my head just kept
hurting worse.
Who didn't want you
to come here, Tiffany?
Who did this to you?
Hmm?
Was it the Mad-10s?
They said they weren't really
going to do anything to me.
Supposed to be fake.
Just mess with this guy.
Get some cred.
They took me out there.
Want your daughter,
Frank?
Here she is.
No...
Look what you've made
us do to her!
No!
Samantha!
I'm gonna kill you!
You hear me?
No! No!
Samantha!
Tell me their names.
I'll protect you,
I promise.
Can I help you
with something?
Thought this was
my grandmother's room.
Yeah, well, it's not.
My mistake.
Yeah, it is your
mistake. Beat it.
Now, Tiffany, we can post
an officer
right outside of your room...
Get out.
Get out!
So these guys wanted Frank
to think they killed Samantha.
The fact that they had
to fake it says... what?
She was already dead but they
couldn't produce a body?
Or she's still alive; they
couldn't get their hands on her.
And what if we did?
What if we find her, and let
Frank know she's still alive?
That might just bring him
back down.
Yeah, but how are we gonna
find her? No address,
no phone number.
And in the meantime,
Frank Cafferty
thinks he watched
his own daughter's murder.
I can't help but think what that
might mean for my daughter.
She's dead.
My daughter, Samantha.
You asked.
What happened?
When she was little,
I was, um...
I was a bad person, you know?
I went away.
She ended up
getting mixed in
with the wrong crowd.
When I got out...
I tried to save her.
You wanted a second chance.
Yeah.
Ended up getting her killed.
How?
A month ago,
I sat down with my dad
for the first time
in a dozen years.
He left when you
were little, too?
When I was about 14
and he'd messed up so much
that my mom decided she wanted
to leave for California...
he didn't fight for me to stay.
If he'd only
just fought for me.
That would've been enough?
You finally forgave him?
I finally decided
it was worth a shot.
So we're starting over.
Whatever mistakes he made...
we can get past them.
People change.
He's a better man now.
He had a second chance.
(grunting and groaning)
(gunshot)
(screams)
Look what you made me do!
(groans)
Don't you move.
You hear me? Don't you move.
Okay.
Excuse me, Undersheriff?
This young woman needs
to talk to you.
Not the time, Shelley.
I saw on the news about my dad.
The, uh, helicopter.
Samantha.
I want to help.
Your father's been
up in the air
with hostages
for over two hours.
Do you have any idea
which way he's going?
I don't know.
I-I barely know him.
Letters, when he was in prison,
a handful of weekends
before that, but we have
never been close.
You don't understand.
He was trying to save you.
Samantha, your Dad knew that you
were caught up with the Mad-10s.
He was trying
to rescue you.
(sighs)
I didn't need his help.
I checked out of that
life a year ago.
I'm sober.
I'm just trying to live quiet.
So, you know what,
all of this is just...
No, you know what? My daughter
is on that helicopter.
Along with an innocent pilot
and a paramedic,
who both have families.
I know.
That's what they
said on the news.
That's why I'm here.
Not to help him.
I just don't want to see him
hurt anyone else.
So how do I talk to him?
(radio static crackles)
OFFICER:
Frank Cafferty,
Samantha is alive
and wants to talk to you.
Do you copy?
Frank Cafferty, Samantha is
alive and wants to talk to you.
He's either not hearing it,
or he's not buying it.
No, no, he's probably cruising
at a lower altitude.
You know, he'll hear it
when he rises above the crest.
I appreciate the
rationalization, I really do.
When it comes to Morgan,
I've become something of
a master at it.
"She's 14; she
doesn't understand
what her mom and I
are arguing about."
"16-year-olds are all moody,
they... she doesn't mean it."
"She'll call.
She's busy at school."
"She's busy at work.
She'll call. She'll call."
"She'll call."
And then she's here.
Chip the size of
the stratosphere
on her shoulder,
still vowing eternal vengeance
against me, but, uh...
Hey, you know what?
This could be
a second chance for you guys.
Maybe.
It just cannot end like this.
Hey, Catherine? That Porsche
Cayenne from Cafferty's
surveillance photos.
DMV had only three matches
to the partial plate,
but one of them was in
the Mad-10s' neighborhood.
It's registered to an
Alexander Zadian.
Brass says he's a shot caller
for the Mad-10s.
Priors for assault, extortion,
possession with intent,
and he's on the
street right now.
And the best suspect
for the attempted murder
of Frank Cafferty.
Uniforms are out
looking for Zadian.
I will let you know
if their luck changes.
Thank you.
PILOT:
Well, it's your call, Ace.
We're ten minutes out from
Parham Airstrip.
We touch down and refuel,
or this party's not
going much longer.
(groans)
Shut him up!
Go to hell.
We got to get him to a hospital.
Please, Frank.
I'll stay with you. Just let us
land and get him some help.
I can't.
Please!
I can't do that!
(groans)
Shut him up!
OFFICER:
Frank Cafferty, Samantha is
alive and wants to talk to you.
Do you copy?
Frank Cafferty, Samantha is
alive and wants to talk to you.
Do you copy?
(static crackles)
This is Frank Cafferty.
(whispers):
Come on.
Frank? This is D.B.
Russell, L.V.P.D.
There's someone here who would
like to talk to you.
Go ahead.
(radio beeps)
Dad?
Samantha?
Oh, my God, baby.
Sammy, I thought
you were dead.
The police told me.
That wasn't me, Dad.
I'm... I'm fine.
They also told me
you were trying to rescue me.
I tried, Samantha.
I tried as hard as I could.
You remember when I was little,
that, uh, wishing well
you told me was mine?
Of course I do, baby.
Go there.
I've sent someone to
help you get away.
I love you, Dad.
Frank?
Get her out of here!
I don't want her
talking to anyone!
Frank?
(radio whirrs)
Go north.
Hey, come on, man.
We're not gonna make it
to the next airstrip.
I got no problem
flying solo.
Don't you want to see her?
Now!
Maybe next life, you keep a
better grip on your pistol.
While Greg and I
work on figuring out
what the "wishing well"
might be,
I want the two of you
to work on
who Samantha might have sent out
to meet Frank, okay?
Now, she didn't have
a cell phone on her, so...
She might've stashed that
in her car at P.D.
We check her recents,
see if we can find
the getaway driver
she contacted,
maybe we can
intercept or follow.
Good.
Yeah, let's do it.
Why not let Frank get away?
Wouldn't it be safer for Morgan
and the others
if we just let him land?
Let him run.
I don't think so.
Why the hell not?
Because I'm not so sure
that Samantha's trying
to help him get away.
That girl hates her father
for leaving her.
Now, what's more likely,
that she wants to help him
or hurt him?
That's why.
You gonna be okay?
Yeah.
Good.
STOKES:
Samantha Cafferty arrived at
P.D. at around 11:16 a.m.
Let's see what
she was driving.
Black Cayenne.
Zoom in.
That's Zadian.
She's in with the Mad-10s.
She set her dad up.
You set them up!
You're gonna get
them killed! Bitch!
Sanders?
Frank really thinks
I tried to help him?
Where did you send them?
If they hurt her,
I swear to you...
Mad-10s are my family.
Frank killed two of us.
He has to pay for that.
Where did you send them?
It's done.
RUSSELL: Web search didn't find
any "wishing well" in Nevada.
Cafferty's not
picking up on the radio,
so we have no idea if he
got any of our warnings.
We're gonna have
to find this place,
so we can get there before
Zadian does.
Well, Frank and Samantha didn't
spend much time together.
So if this wishing well
is a shared memory,
it might be in one
of these boxes.
It's worth a try.
♪ ♪
I've got it.
All right, it's a park
someplace, right?
Yeah, I'm not sure where.
Wait a second.
Look--Look at the clothing.
I've seen that before.
There's other shots
they were wearing
that same outfit.
I've seen it.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Here we go.
What is that?
Winston's Wild West Village.
That was an
old theme park
that shut down years ago.
(alarm beeping)
Hey, we're on fumes, man!
What are you looking for?
Shut up!
There it is. Right there.
Take her down now.
Wait.
Who is that?
Cops?!
BRODY:
Not cops.
Get us out of here.
What?
Now!
(alarm wailing)
That's all she's got!
♪ ♪
(shallow breathing)
(sirens wailing)
BRASS:
This is Brass.
I want the CSIs
to keep their distance.
I got lead.
You got that, Sanders?
Copy.
Follow me.
They're coming.
We got to hide.
Dude, you've got the gun.
Come on.
(groaning)
Come on, let's go.
This way, come on.
All right, all right.
I got you.
Let's go.
Come on.
I got you.
(coughing)
These guys friends of yours?
Probably the same
guys who left me
for dead last night.
Bet you wish they'd
finished me off, huh?
Bet you wish you were
in Cabo right now.
(chuckles)
How do they know
we're here?
Samantha.
(coughs)
They're in here.
Cover the back.
(tires screeching)
(gunfire)
♪ ♪
Come on, we got to go.
I can't.
We got to go!
I can't!
I said, "I can't."
I'm sorry.
I have nothing left.
Save yourself, okay?
(floorboards creak)
(sirens wailing outside)
Everything
clear outside?
Yeah.
He's over here.
(garbled radio transmissions)
(sirens wailing)
Morgan.
(panting)
Are you hurt?
You still owe me one.
Morgan.
What can I...
I'm fine, Dad.
I just want to get out of here.
Yeah, okay.
Can we go?
Sure.
You're going to be okay.
I'm fine.
(sobbing)
You're going to be okay.