(rattling, squeaking)
(lid thuds)
(startled shout)
(woman yelling)
(grunts)
(gasping)
(anxious breathing)
(woman whimpering)
(whimpers, shudders)
(screams)
(crying)
(screaming)
(sirens wail,
indistinct radio communication)
What are you looking at?
The view.
Oh.
Never seen the city from
this perspective before.
It's beautiful.
Takes your breath away.
Yeah.
It can take more than that.
We used to call this place
the Missile Base.
The Missile Base.
Uh-huh.
Care to share why?
Why did I bring that up? Oh!
All right, I'll
tell you what.
I'll make it easy for
you-- I'll go first.
I met my wife freshman
year in college,
and she was my
first and only love.
Aw.
Seriously?
You lost your virginity
to your wife?
Yep. Yep.
Life is simple sometimes.
You meet the right person,
and you know it's forever.
And that was a boring story,
so it's your turn.
Tony Anthopoulos.
I was 16.
Too many beers,
too little romance.
Seemed like a good idea
at the time.
Ah, that's better.
Swept away
by the passion of the moment.
Something like that.
Tony was a bad boy.
First of many.
I liked being wanted...
till that got old.
Well, you're a
very smart woman.
You probably just wanted to be
appreciated for that too.
Yeah.
Hey, David.
Oh, hey.
So, what are
we looking at here?
I'm not sure yet.
Just got here myself.
WILLOWS:
The tarp's pretty clean.
Doesn't look like
it's been dragged or rolled.
Looks more like it was
carried and placed here.
WILLOWS:
We'll get it to Trace.
Concrete and caliche.
Not going to get
any foot impressions.
Oh.
RUSSELL: There's like
a dozen needles here.
But there's no blood.
(camera shutter clicks)
You got your shots?
Yeah.
There's some expertise
demonstrated here.
Those needles are thrust through
and through-- see that?
Yeah. Right under the cornified
layers of the epidermis.
Minimize the hemorrhaging,
maximize the pain.
RUSSELL:
Well, this was not about
killing her.
It was about
watching her suffer.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
(camera shutter clicking)
(door opening)
Morgan.
I heard Russell cleared you
to come back.
If you need more time...
Oh, I'm good.
I might put off
that helicopter tour
of the Grand Canyon
for a while.
Yeah, that'd probably be smart.
Well, since you're here,
I could use a hand.
Yeah, no problem.
These are 20-gauge hypos.
The kind used
in bone marrow transplants.
Killer had access
to medical supplies.
Needles are inserted
approximately
three inches apart.
Perpendicular,
in a line, wrist to wrist.
You think
the pattern is significant?
Seems ritualistic.
But it's definitely
sadistic.
Yeah.
Hold on.
This isn't a hypo.
(scoffs)
Shish kabob skewer.
It's a black residue.
Looks like candle wax.
The scarring--
it's all over her body.
Consistent with the needles
and the skewer.
You'd think
after all these years,
I wouldn't be surprised
by what people are capable of.
(light scratching in distance)
Hodges?
(gasps)
What are you doing?
Scusi.
Did Lorenzo interrupt
Michelangelo
when he was creating?
He didn't wrap bodies
in his canvas.
And I thought you said
you didn't find
any trace on this.
Not trace.
Something better.
Art.
Are you familiar
with a pentimento?
What do you think?
It's an alteration
in a painting.
When an artist makes a mistake
or they want
to change something,
they simply whitewash
over the error,
and then begin again.
I don't want to
get too excited,
but we may have a
lost treasure here.
Maybe even a Rembrandt.
Really? Uh...
scusi.
Hmm? Oh.
Prego.
Mm.
I am getting excited.
See?
What I see is more layers.
More paint, Leonardo.
Maybe what's under here will
give us a clue to our killer.
So stop your scratching.
Canvas is mine now.
Huh. (speaks Italian)
Hey, you better hope I don't
find out what that means.
I ran our Jane Doe information
through Missing Persons.
Nothing.
Run it again.
I did. I know.
It doesn't make sense.
The injuries, the
evidence all suggest
that she was
abducted weeks ago.
Somebody should have
missed her by now.
Doctor.
Hey.
So, C.O.D.?
Don't know yet.
I sent samples off
to Toxicology.
We'll see what
Henry has to say.
As you both observed,
the external scarring
indicates a prolonged
period of abuse.
However, I did find
something unusual
about the injuries.
Scar tissue in the wound tracts.
It's as if the
needles and the skewer
were inserted in the
same areas repeatedly.
You mean like body piercing?
Similar. In piercing,
a needle's inserted
through the skin,
penetrating the various layers
of the epidermis.
As scar tissue develops,
a permanent hole is created.
Difference in this case is,
we're not talking
about piercings.
RUSSELL:
No. No, we're not.
We're talking about 20-gauge
needles and a barbecue skewer
driven repeatedly
into this girl's flesh.
That's what we're
talking about.
What is this?
Is this a knee implant?
Hers, I assume.
She had unicompartmental
knee arthroplasty.
Likely due to injury,
given the attenuation
of her collateral
ligaments.
RUSSELL:
Whatever the case,
we have a lot number, which will
give us an orthopedic surgeon.
And a name for our...
our Jane Doe.
WOMAN: Renny was born
with an angular limb deformity
in both rear legs,
which means that her back legs
were growing faster
than her front legs.
A horse foal my daughter Sylvia
is nursing has
the same condition,
so, in order
to help the bones grow,
we performed
a brief surgical procedure
called a peristeal
stripping. Now...
Dr. Grier?
Yes?
I'm Catherine Willows
with the Crime Lab.
I need to speak with you.
I'm sorry.
I'm in the middle of a seminar.
It's about your sister Rachel.
So, when was the last time
that you saw your sister?
I haven't seen Rachel in years.
She called me
a few months ago.
Um, she had some medical bills,
needed money.
Fort Lauderdale.
She had knee surgery.
I just wired her the money.
I stopped asking questions
a long time ago.
What do you mean?
My little sister was
a wild child.
She ran away after high school.
She broke my mother's heart.
(voice breaking):
Rachel couldn't even be bothered
to come to her funeral.
You say that she met
with violence.
What does that mean?
What happened?
I'm sorry;
I can't discuss the specifics.
What I can tell you is
that we found her here in Vegas,
and we suspect
that she was taken
against her will, probably
several weeks ago.
That's impossible.
I had lunch with
Aunt Rachel on Monday,
and she was
totally fine.
You had lunch
with Rachel?
I didn't even know
she was in town...
WILLOWS:
Excuse me, Sylvia,
you saw your aunt
three days ago?
Yeah. I mean, she called,
and she said
that she was in town
and needed to talk.
Made me promise not
to say anything.
Why?
My mom and Aunt Rachel
don't really talk.
But Aunt Rachel
wanted things
to change;
she wanted to fix things.
She wanted to come home.
Where did you
and your Aunt Rachel
have lunch?
The Tangiers.
I don't know.
Maybe she was staying there.
SANDERS:
Hey, Catherine.
Tangiers was a bust-- Rachel
Grier was never registered,
and no one I.D.'d her photo.
Yeah, I'm on it.
Hey, Henry,
got my tox report?
Yeah, right here.
Great.
Mm, not so great.
What's the problem?
You'll find the findings are
both inconclusive and,
well, confusing.
She had lidocaine in her system?
But it didn't kill her.
"Injected at therapeutic levels
directly into the tissue
surrounding the
hypodermic needles."
And the skewer.
What kind of sadist uses
an anesthetic
before torturing their victims?
♪ ♪
STOKES:
I dug out these images,
using optical microscopy.
So what are we feeling
about this?
Depressed.
Yeah, I mean,
it's no Rembrandt.
RUSSELL:
You know, maybe it's
a Rachel Grier.
I mean, look at that.
That's gotta be more
than a coincidence.
WILLOWS:
Yeah, there's a similar pattern
to the needles in her arms.
BRODY:
And the flames--
we did find candle
wax residue.
HODGES:
Now, is it me
or does she look like
a human candelabra?
RUSSELL: All right,
let's think about this.
Maybe our victim was posed
to look like this painting.
So you're saying you think
that our killer was inspired
by this image?
Maybe.
Or maybe the killer got artistic
as he was torturing her.
Poses her, paints her,
doesn't like his work,
so he whitewashes
over it,
and then just
wraps her up in his failure.
Question is, which came first--
Rachel Grier
or Rachel Grier?
BRODY:
Hey, guys.
I just did an image search
for "human candelabra."
Check it out.
Major Willie's
Rambling Carnival
and Curious
Extravaganza.
HODGES: Which century
you get this out of?
(Brody chuckles)
This one, as in tonight,
two shows,
7:00 and 10:00.
WILLOWS:
Featuring the Human Candelabra.
RUSSELL:
"The Magnificent Femmistopheles,
Empress of Pain."
STOKES: Looks like
it's time for a road trip.
(man speaking indistinctly
over P.A.)
BARKER: You wish to try?
Only ten bucks to try.
(groans quietly)
That's the oldest
trick in the book.
About all they're
good for nowadays.
BARKER: Come up
and get your darts.
You buy the darts
for ten
of your Yankee dollars.
Now, who will be next?
Pop the cherry,
win a prize.
Come on, you have to
do better than that.
Pop the cherry,
win a prize.
This is
entertainment?
(groans)
Hard to tell
who's more entertained.
(man groans, spectators applaud)
Well done, mate.
Sorry, kitty's
not a virgin.
Zodiac will be back
in 15 minutes.
Be seeing you.
Oh... my... God.
Oh, it looks like Femmistopheles
is a no-show.
RUSSELL:
I want to look inside.
Can I help you?
We're from the Las
Vegas Crime Lab.
Sorry, no comping the
constables here, I'm afraid.
So who's in charge
of this freak show?
Me-- you've seen the game,
you know the name.
Major Willie
at your service.
Good to know.
WILLOWS:
Have you seen
this woman?
Seen her?
I've seen all of her.
Femmistopheles, Empress of Pain.
So, what'd she do
this time?
She's dead.
That's... unfortunate.
You don't seem too broken up.
Or surprised.
WILLOWS:
Maybe we know why.
WILLIE: Am I surprised
Rachel's dead?
No.
RUSSELL: And why is that?
Well, take a look
around you.
You've heard what your friend
said-- we're freaks.
You try cranking up
this whoopee machine
two shows a night,
on the road 351 days a year,
ending up in places
you wouldn't want
to be seen dead in.
Sorry, poor choice.
So what was it--
O.D., old ex?
Rachel always did have the
most appalling taste in men.
Does that include you?
I was the best thing
that ever happened to her.
I saw qualities in Rachel
she couldn't see in herself.
Lucky girl.
Willie, we need
to check out
that tent, so you
gonna step aside
or do we need to
go get a warrant?
Boss.
Joey needs his intro.
Zodiac, aidez les gendarmes.
It's all good.
I'm gonna keep my eye on Willie.
Yeah, D.B., I'm gonna
grab some equipment.
I'll be right back.
Life is full
of terrible surprises
and miserable fates.
Consider that
of a young woman,
heavy with child,
mauled by
a ferocious pachyderm--
her son born hideously deformed,
yet able to sow the seeds
of future generations,
all cursed
to the same twisted destiny.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I present to you the last heir
of the House of Merrick--
Joseph the Elephant Man!
MAN:
Aw, come on.
ANNOUNCER:
Surprised?
Disgusted?
Not what you paid to see?
I want to draw your attention
to the condition
of this poor specimen.
Note the aquiline jaw,
the sharp, muscular definition.
This animal...
is not one of us.
He is not a freak,
a freak like me.
(gasping and murmuring)
Watch as she continues to wrap
these chains around me...
I got hypos and skewers.
I got blood.
If she was tortured
in this chair,
the blood pattern's off.
There's no void.
Hey-- see these streaks?
This contraption could be
our blood source.
Where is, uh...?
Oh, yeah.
What, what do I
call you again?
Zodiac.
Can you tell us
a little bit more
about Femmistopheles' act?
Wasn't an act.
It was unlike anything
you ever seen.
(gasps)
(screams)
(crowd applauds, whoops)
(whistling, applause)
ZODIAC: She didn't just give
a performance.
She gave her own blood.
She rocked the house.
And people--
what, they'd pay
extra to see this?
What's the point
in torturing yourself
if we ain't all going
to have some fun?
Okay, and what's back there?
Femmie's
dressing room.
She lived in it.
♪ ♪
(clears throat)
Ah...
Empress of pain and pleasure.
You mind?
Thought you were a coffee snob.
Machine in my office
is broken.
I'm waiting
for parts.
(sniffs)
Mm.
A little light
reading, I see.
Satisfying
my curiosity.
So Nick and I found
a whole pharmacy
in Rachel Grier's tent,
including
lidocaine.
Henry is sourcing
the stuff for me.
Also running
an expanded tox panel.
Maybe one of the other drugs
killed her.
Here, we thought some sick
bastard tortured the girl.
Maybe she OD'd.
Nah, you know, I don't
think so, actually.
I mean, she certainly wouldn't
have wrapped up her own body
and dumped it.
No.
You know, there's something
about this Major Willie.
He reminds me of...
I told you about my parents
being singers, right?
Yeah.
Performers, really.
When I was a kid, they were
part of this traveling show.
We went around the country
in our van.
Anyway, the leader
of this group was a,
a guy who called himself
Durga Joe.
He was a real
charismatic,
kind of like
this Willie guy.
He could make people...
he could make people do pretty
much anything he wanted.
That was the problem,
at least for my parents,
so, one day they
decided they wanted
to leave and Durga Joe
did not like that at all.
What happened?
In the middle
of the night,
we got in our van
and we just took off.
And never really...
looked back.
Anyway... the point is
that this Rachel Grier,
she wanted to leave,
too, you know?
She wanted to go home.
Maybe this is about control.
Major Willie's
Rambling Carnival--
one big, happy family.
Until somebody wants to leave.
Got your new
and improved tox panel.
I know what killed
Rachel Grier
and maybe who.
STOKES: Major Willie-- aka
Steven Watt of Tampa, Florida.
You know, without
the Willy Wonka get-up,
you could pass for
just another freak.
The word is "geek,"
as in someone who
can perform freakish acts
without actually themselves
being a freak of nature.
I'll take your word for it.
And I will
take that.
Oh, look.
What's he going to do?
Yeah, and if you
think that's freaky...
(splutters)
Don't worry,
I'll regurgitate
it later.
Wow. We gotta learn
how to do that.
So, uh...
we know what killed Rachel--
propofol.
Which is used
in anesthesia,
but in high enough doses
and without a ventilator,
it paralyzes the diaphragm.
So basically...
Rachel... suffocated to death.
STOKES: You're licensed in
Florida and New York
to practice body piercings
and modifications.
That's how you were able
to obtain the pharmaceuticals
we found in Rachel's tent.
You people just don't get it.
We don't get what?
Freaks versus geeks.
A guy like Zodiac,
he has congenital
analgesia.
He was born
not feeling pain-- a freak.
Rachel and me,
we need...
needed help.
A little pharmacology.
Stuff like lidocaine,
to take the edge off the pain,
to enhance performance.
No drugs, no show,
no dough.
I won't lie-- maybe at
the end of the evening
we all like to indulge
in a little...
something something...
to ease an old carney's burden.
But straight up...
I am a businessman;
I look after
my people,
I take care of them.
And Rachel, she was an earner.
Who wanted to stop earning,
I believe.
She would never have left me.
You didn't find any propofol
in Rachel's tent, did you?
No.
Am I under arrest?
Not yet, no.
But this, uh, this is
just our opening act.
Here. One for the road.
BRODY:
Got the DNA results
from Rachel Grier's tent--
the blood Russell found
in the fridge is
a match to Rachel.
Also the torture chair.
Well, it makes sense.
Rachel was storing her
blood to use in her act.
Yeah, well, the blood also
tells us another story--
hormone levels suggest that
Rachel was pregnant.
Labels on the pack say as
recently as two weeks ago.
There was no evidence
in autopsy.
Not just that.
Nick found traces of blood
and semen in Rachel's bed.
Single donor.
No hits in CODIS.
"Profile is a male Caucasian
suffering from
neurofibromatosis
type-1 and Proteus Syndrome."
Rachel was sleeping
with the Elephant Man?
So, last heir to
the House of Merrick.
That's a good story.
I saw the movie, too--
it was... I liked it.
But truth is, there
is... no house, right?
Because the Elephant Man
didn't have any children.
So your name's not
really Merrick, is it?
No.
My name is Joshua Helm.
And, Joshua,
you don't have any children,
either, do you?
No.
Rachel Grier made
sure of that.
She got rid of the baby.
Just like she wanted
to get rid of you.
You don't know
what you're saying.
Rachel and I were in love.
Is that why she was making
plans to leave the show?
Yes.
I told her she was crazy,
that we couldn't have
a normal life
on the outside.
Wait-wait-wait a minute.
So you're saying
that the two of you were
planning on going away together?
That's what she wanted.
You could survive
on the outside,
but I can't.
You can with me.
I love you, Joshua--
that's all that matters.
Rachel had lost the child,
and she wanted to try again.
I said no.
I told her she could
leave if she wanted to,
but that I wasn't
going with her.
Rachel was always naive,
living in a fantasy land.
You do tell a good story.
Is that what you
think this is?
I've already
seen the show,
and I'm familiar
with the story.
Girl hates her life,
is searching for something,
thinks she finds it
in a man,
a man who needs her,
and then...
it all goes wrong.
You killed her because
she wanted her life back.
Look... I don't know what
happened to Rachel,
and if you're trying to
provoke me, it's not working.
You can't
imagine how the love that
we had for each other existed,
because you've never known it.
And you never will.
SANDERS:
So, we turned
Major Willie's Carnival
upside down, didn't
find any propofol.
We have any record of
him buying the stuff?
No, we have nothing to tie him
to the drugs that killed Rachel,
(phone rings)
and Brass just cut him loose.
Stokes.
Yeah.
You kidding me?
Greg'll be interested to
hear that. Thanks, Jimbo.
Well, it looks like
we're gonna have to cut
Major Willie loose again.
Well...
rigor hasn't set in.
T.O.D.'s less
than two hours ago.
STOKES:
No vital response.
He was dead before
he was hanged.
Staged.
Yeah, poorly.
Okay, cut him down,
get him to Autopsy.
Let's find out what
really killed him.
CSI Stokes?
Yeah.
We've got a suspect
in custody.
OFFICER:
You need to stay back, okay?
Which one
of the freaks is it?
There.
Suspect's name
is Sylvia Grier.
STOKES:
Rachel Grier's niece?
(blipping)
WOMAN:
This is insane.
Dr. Grier, your daughter
was detained
while fleeing the scene
of an apparent homicide.
I... I don't know what Sylvia
was doing at that freak show,
but... but I do know that
she would never hurt anyone.
Well, then neither
you nor Sylvia
has anything to
be afraid of.
What were you doing
there, Sylvia?
I went there because I
needed to see for myself.
See what?
S--see who my
aunt really was.
I found the story online,
"Sideshow Performer Murdered,"
and it was Aunt Rachel.
To my mom,
Aunt Rachel was a ghost, but...
to me, she was like this...
force of nature.
You know?
She did what she wanted to do
and lived how
she wanted to live,
and I just felt this...
connection.
I mean, is that weird?
Look, I didn't kill
that man.
Why don't you tell me
what happened?
I went looking for where
Aunt Rachel had been living,
and I got lost.
And I wandered
into that tent,
and that's when I saw him.
I was so scared.
And then, they were
all staring at me.
I mean, they thought I did it.
So I ran.
And I hid,
but the officers found me.
I didn't do anything.
RUSSELL:
Do you believe her?
Sylvia? Yes.
Well, I don't know
what to believe anymore.
I think I made a mistake
about Major Willie.
I think I let my past
cloud my thinking.
Well, we're all
guilty of that.
Whoa, what do you mean?
You're not having doubts about
our Elephant Man, are you?
No. No.
I mean, I don't like
being called out
(laughs): about
my lack of romance,
but it's no argument
for innocence.
You still think
Elephant Man
had motive to kill Rachel?
Yes. Yes, and I think
Sylvia was sincere
about feeling a connection
towards her aunt,
which says to me
that she wouldn't
do her any harm.
Okay. But that doesn't mean that
she wouldn't go after the man
who she believed did.
Major Willie?
But why would she suspect
that he killed Rachel?
We're not even
convinced ourselves.
Maybe somebody whispered
Willie's name in her ear.
Maybe our real killer.
Okay.
What have we got here, boys?
Well, your carnival
barker's C.O.D.
was massive internal
hemorrhaging
due to an inch-and-a-half
laceration and perforation
of the stomach wall,
severing the left
gastro-omental artery.
Check it out.
Stomach wall's punctured
from the inside out.
That's bigger than a paper clip.
I found no injuries
to the pharynx
or esophagus.
So, it's not like somebody
shoved something
down his throat.
No, no.
Guy swallowed a sword.
Check that out.
SANDERS:
Well, that would do it.
Actually, our friend here
swallowed lots of things.
Bon appétit, gentlemen.
♪ ♪
Good thing for us,
Major Willie bit off
more than he could chew.
Gemini.
Sign of the Zodiac.
Take your shirt off.
You want to play,
you got to pay.
Oh, I got my ticket
right here, Muscles.
It's called a search warrant.
Now, take it off.
If you want a picture with me,
your friend right there
I'm sure will take it.
No, that's all right. I'll pass.
We're done here.
Check him for warrants
while you're at it.
Catherine, it's Nick.
No go on Zodiac.
We're gonna need
a pile of warrants.
We're gonna need to bring
the whole freak show down here.
I need to see
your chest, too.
You want some help?
Remove the bandage.
(groans)
Dog bite.
I hope you had
all your shots.
Sergio the Strong.
Where do you people
come up with the stage names?
I mean, I get it, I do.
Because "Seth the Strong"
doesn't look good on a poster.
But "Seth
Soon-To-Be-Convicted"--
that has a
ring to it.
We got back the DNA profile
on your ounce of flesh.
Looks like you and the Elephant
Man were fraternal twins.
I got to admit,
I didn't see that coming.
And let me guess, mom
always liked you best.
We know Rachel broke
your brother's heart.
You made her pay for that.
And then when Willie found out
what you did,
you shut him up, too.
Is that about right?
Our mom
died during childbirth.
Dad dumped us
before we could walk.
And when Joshua
started to... change,
the relatives we were
staying with got freaked out.
Said that Joshua and me
were born of the devil.
For my brother, there was only
one path to salvation.
Major Willie's Rambling Carnival
and Curious Extravaganza.
Willie was no saint,
but he was better than most.
He didn't treat
my brother
like a monster.
He was... he was good to him.
Until...
Until what?
What the hell happened?
I don't know.
I just found her like this.
Maybe she OD'd or something.
You call the cops?
You crazy?
They'll close us down.
You got to help me, Seth.
We need to make this go away.
Think about your brother.
No show.
Where does that leave him?
SERGIO:
So I did what he asked me.
I made it all go away.
But it didn't go away.
And we all know that
Rachel didn't just OD.
You people found out
what was going on
between Joshua and Rachel.
You hauled him in here,
you questioned him.
But he didn't do it.
How do you know that?
'Cause I know who did.
Cops picked up Joshua.
Don't sweat it.
That's just what they do.
Josh will be fine.
Best thing you can do
is to keep your mouth shut.
Trust me.
Not this time.
(grunting)
(both grunting)
(screams)
I didn't mean to kill him.
I thought that if
I made it look like
he killed himself, that it all
would really go away.
You don't believe
me, do you?
We believe the evidence.
(grunting forcefully)
There's your evidence.
Willie killed Rachel.
Heard the suspect coughed
up the smoking gun.
Yeah.
What, did Nick leave you
to do the dirty work?
No. Actually, I wanted
to run this myself.
So, Sergio found
the propofol when he was
cleaning up Rachel's tent?
Yeah, he had doubts
about Willie,
so he decided
to hang on to this.
In his stomach?
Better than
a safety deposit box, I guess.
Little messier.
So the propofol
belonged to Willie?
That's what Sergio thinks.
I'm not so sure.
Why not?
Willie was the resident
Dr. Feel Good.
Well, if we're to believe
Sergio's story,
Willie talked him into
dumping a body for him.
I mean, come on.
Guys like Willie are
the consummate con artists.
They're, like,
the best salesmen in the world.
So my question is: if he was
worried about losing Rachel,
why wouldn't he just
talk her out of it?
If he could talk her out of it,
there'd be no reason
to kill her.
Right.
So back to the
Elephant Man?
(computer beeping)
Nope.
WILLOWS:
We traced the drug that
killed your sister Rachel
to the Clark
County Zoo.
To you.
Why?
My daughter always
worshipped Rachel.
Even though she was
barely a part of our lives.
To Sylvia,
Rachel was this adventurer,
this nonconformist,
a free spirit--
everything I wasn't,
everything I wasn't
allowing Sylvia to be.
Rachel was just a fantasy.
Until she wasn't.
She wanted to come back
into our lives.
To insert her twisted self
into our home.
Sh--she was having sex
with that... that thing.
What kind of
a sick person
would do that?
She was your sister.
No... she wasn't.
She was... she was a freak.
I told her there was no place
in our home for her.
But she wouldn't listen.
She tried to go through Sylvia
to get to me.
She used her.
My own daughter.
Who always loved my sister
more than she loved me.
My sister left me no choice.
And you left her to suffocate.
I did what I had to do.
I protected my daughter.
You don't understand.
She's the only family I have.
I would've done anything...
anything to protect her.
Sylvia's safe now.
She's safe from the monsters
in this world.
Yes, she is.