(thunder crashing,
wind whistling)
What do you see
in the sky, Harper?
Planets.
The red one is Mars.
The one with the rings around
is called Saturn.
And the smallest one is Pluto.
Oh, my little astronomer,
it's time to go to bed now.
Okay.
(thunder rumbles)
(siren approaching)
Okay, we have
a reported kidnapping.
A five-year-old boy,
Harper Riordan.
His nanny, Shelby Buress,
is also missing.
What about the parents?
Uh, parent. Single dad.
A "T.C. Riordan."
Said he was sleeping when
the nanny put the kid to bed.
What time was that?
Around 10:00.
Woke up at 11:30,
went to check in on the boy.
Did he make the 911 call?
Yeah. 11:35.
Half past midnight.
Clock's got the
head start on us.
Didn't you just say
he was asleep at the
time of the abduction?
Yeah.
Is that how you
dress for bed?
I dress a little less formally.
Where's the boy's room?
Upstairs.
Okay, got some blood.
Not a lot of it.
Definitely a struggle.
Blood's tacky.
Consistent with
the dad's timeline.
I got a print... in blood.
Definitely not
a five-year-old's.
Our kidnapper, maybe?
(camera clicks)
Morgan, yeah,
I'm sending you a print.
I want you to run it.
I'm on it.
(thunder rumbles)
Look at that.
FINLAY:
Blood on the ceiling.
No, Saturn's missing.
Metal particles.
Could be transfer
from the kidnapper.
Okay, I gotta get that
back to the lab.
Why don't you have Hodges
come pick it up?
I need you here.
Hey, evidence coming through!
Hold the door!
What part
of "Hold the door"
don't you understand?
I understood
all of it.
(thunder crashing,
power whirring off)
(alarm buzzing)
Oh, brother.
Oh, that is not good.
BRASS:
It's not.
A storm blew out
three generating stations.
Power is out
in half the state.
They say for how long?
Could be a while.
God, we already
lost enough time.
You know the rule.
If we don't find this kid
in three hours, he's dead.
If the lights don't come
back on,
we'll find the kid in the dark.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
RUSSELL: Make sure the backup
generator's running.
And check the freezers.
If we melt evidence,
bad guys walk.
And lock down the guns
in Ballistics.
Generator, freezer, guns.
Copy that.
All right.
FYI, AFIS is out.
So is CODIS and IBIS.
Basically, all the "IS'es"
are down.
We're just gonna have
to get used to it.
Until the lights
come back on,
we might as well
be back in grad school.
Remember your basic
chemistry.
Use your head, use your hands.
And these cell phone batteries,
they're our only lifeline,
so let's not waste 'em.
We got a missing boy
and a nanny in the wind
and we don't have much time.
Head and hands. Got it.
I got another call.
Yeah, what?
Yeah, heard the whole city's
blacked-out.
What is that noise?
It's the sound of...
It's the sound of fear
and futility.
Hey! You break that case,
you own it.
This thing won't budge.
It's not an escape hatch
if you can't escape.
Where are you?
We're trapped in elevator hell.
Who's "we"?
Me and-and... Henry.
I was on my way to the lab
to process that metal trace
that you and Finn found,
and, uh, well, let's just say
it's gonna to have to wait
until help arrives.
I'll get Morgan
call Maintenance.
Yeah, um, she might dial
the phone a little faster
if you omit the part
about me being in here.
Just a thought.
What are you guys,
in high school?
(camera shutter clicks)
Hey.
So, we got blood splatter
on the ceiling,
spatter on the sheets,
and we've got this white
residue here.
Go ahead and bindle that.
Yeah. That's gonna be
the easy part.
You know, if this turns out
to be important evidence,
who knows how long
it's gonna take
before we can process it
and get an answer.
I know, I know, I know.
Okay...
no ladder outside the window,
no tree that someone
could climb up.
Dust along the ledges doesn't
seem to be disturbed,
so our...
our kidnapper was already
inside the house.
FINLAY:
Hey, look at this void.
Blood pattern is interrupted
right down this line.
What do you think,
rug?
Yeah.
Maybe somebody took the rug
out of here
with somebody inside of it.
And if this blood
is the boy's,
that means he put up a fight.
And lost.
And that would explain
why there is no blood
trailing out of the door
or in the hallway
or down the stairs.
Yeah. Wait, wait, wait,
let's back up.
We don't know for sure that this
is the boy's blood, right?
It could be the nanny's.
We can't run the DNA
until the power's back on.
So what do we do?
We go old school.
ABO typing. I like that.
See, that's why you're here.
I'll call Greg.
SIDLE:
Hey, Nick?
Yeah, I'm back here.
Checked all points of entry--
no sign of a break-in.
We could be looking
at an inside job.
STOKES:
They look happy in this photo.
I wonder what happened
to the wife.
This is some serious
candle power.
I mean,
it looks like T.C. Riordan
is used to being unplugged.
Got blood drops
on the table here.
And a couple more
on the floor, see?
SIDLE:
Mm-hmm.
You know,
could be the same
source as the blood upstairs.
The boy.
STOKES:
Yeah.
Spines suggest directionality.
Heading for the door outside.
Let's see where the trail goes.
How long has Shelby Buress been
your son's nanny, Mr. Riordan?
From the minute
Harper was born.
Shelby didn't do this.
You sound pretty sure of that.
I am.
This is a very
big house.
You must have a lot
of people working for you.
Yes.
And I trust all of them.
I'm gonna need a list.
Do you and your wife share
custody of your son?
My wife... my wife passed away
five years ago.
I'm sorry.
And you said
that you were asleep
when Harper went
missing.
I fell asleep in the den.
In a tux?
I was planning on
going out tonight.
I changed my mind.
So what woke you up?
Nothing. Why?
You didn't hear anything?
No. I just...
I just woke up.
Well, we're gonna have
to take your fingerprints.
It's just
a standard procedure.
You know, so we can
exclude yours from
the kidnapper.
And we'll need a blood sample.
Fine.
One last question.
What is your son's blood type?
I don't know.
No, it's fine.
Uh, did he cut himself,
scrape himself recently?
Maybe a bloody nose?
He cut his chin
just the other day.
The Band-Aid might
still be in the garbage can.
And how did that happen,
the cut on the chin?
He fell.
BRODY:
The Palermo?
Seriously?
Okay, when do you think
engineers can be here?
Oh, okay, thanks.
For nothing.
Henry and Hodges still
in the elevator?
Hodges is in there?
Just focus on Henry.
And this.
What is it?
Residue from the
missing boy's room.
Oh, Without the Mass Spec,
what am I supposed
to do with it?
I don't know.
Be creative.
Russell has me doing
ABO blood typing.
Want to help?
Sure. Tonight,
everything old is new.
♪ ♪
I got clumping.
You?
Yeah.
Based on the Band-Aid exemplar,
the boy's blood
type is O.
You sure about that?
Yeah.
Why?
FINLAY: What are you
doing out here?
What, are you, uh,
communing with the stars?
My cell phone's communing
with a charger.
So what's your take
on T.C. Riordan?
Why? What's yours?
Wouldn't be
the first time
that a parent tried
to cover up abuse
with a phony kidnapping report.
Yeah, but let's not get
too far ahead of ourselves.
Kidnapper hasn't contacted
Riordan with any demands.
I know.
I just...
have a feeling this case is not
going to follow the rules.
STOKES:
Blood trail's gone cold.
No drops since the house.
Rain probably
washed them away.
(thunder rumbling)
SIDLE:
Hey, Galileo.
Yeah.
No blood,
but check it out-- 11:00.
STOKES:
Saturn.
Planet from
the boy's room.
(sighs heavily)
Nick... and the missing carpet.
(camera shutter clicks)
It's awfully convenient.
It's like we were
meant to find him.
(sighs)
STOKES:
Whoa.
It's Harper's nanny.
STOKES:
Got a knife right here.
And something else.
"We have Harper."
Till I can see what I'm doing,
I'm going to have to hold off
on the autopsy.
But my initial exam says
the missing boy's nanny
suffered two sharp force
injuries to the chest
and...
two more
to the upper back,
all from
a double-edged blade.
SIDLE: That and the width
of the wounds
looks consistent
with the knife that we found.
(electrical buzz)
Things just keep getting better.
Someone ask
for a light?
Yeah, a light.
That looks like
a moonshine still.
Actually,
it's a slightly different kind
of white lightning.
Behold...
Not bad, huh?
In college, I
found that R &amp; B,
with just a little
chemiluminescence,
really set the mood.
I can see it.
I can't.
What's in there
anyway?
Luminol.
With just a splash
of permanganate.
Great job, Dave.
It's nothing.
What do you got, Doc?
Could be
an abrasion to the lip.
Doesn't look like
blunt force trauma.
Pressure wound, maybe.
Kidnapper
clamps a hand
over her mouth to silence her.
(muffled grunting)
The boy wouldn't
have heard a thing.
Suggests a sequence.
Kill the nanny,
take the boy.
And carry them both
out of the room.
I think our kidnapper had help.
Whoa. Watch out.
Oh, God, I'm sorry.
This thing's already
killed someone.
Oh. You'd just be putting me
out of my misery.
Why? What's wrong?
That white residue
from the kid's bedroom--
I was able to run
all the standard color tests
for an unknown white powder.
Got zip, zero, nada.
So it's a negative.
No, I should have
gotten a result.
Color tests cover 90%
of all narcotics.
Narcotics?
Yeah.
Nanny murdered,
kid grabbed up.
Dad says he
didn't hear anything.
Kid could have been
sedated, right?
Russell said
use head and hands.
I'm using my head.
Hands not so good.
Okay, well, maybe I have
another thought
for your hands.
A crystal test-- it might cover
the other ten percent.
Without electricity
for the scopes?
Forget old school.
Go ancient.
RUSSELL:
How we doing
on the metal trace
from the boy's bedsheet?
Um, we are still trapped
in the metal box.
You remember
that, right?
Didn't Morgan make that call?
Yes.
And, uh, apparently,
the people who
could extricate us
from our metal box are
themselves stuck in a metal box
in the Palermo.
I need that trace processed.
If our kidnapper brought it
into that house,
it may be our only way
to find him.
So, if you can't
get yourself out of there,
find a way
to get the evidence out.
How are we supposed to do that?
I don't know, Henry.
Figure something out.
Any more stupid questions?
Do you have to go to
the bathroom as badly as I do?
♪ ♪
Awesome.
BRODY: Nice call on
the crystal test.
White substance from
the kid's bedroom
screened positive
for ketamine.
Used as a veterinary
anesthetic,
but also as an
injectable pain med.
One Sara found...
in T.C. Riordan's
medicine cabinet.
You were right--
the kid was doped.
What'd you find
on the knife?
ABO results indicate
two blood types.
Blood type
on the blade is AB,
which matches the nanny,
Shelby Buress.
Fits with the rest
of the evidence.
Blood on the handle
is type O,
which matches
T.C. Riordan.
Location is everything.
Suggests the father
was holding the knife.
BRASS: So I called the
police department
in your old hometown,
San Francisco.
We were really just checking
on the nanny.
But it turns out you're the
more interesting story.
When you told us
that your wife
passed away
five years ago,
you neglected
to mention how.
Very suspicious drowning
in your pool.
What does this have to do
with finding my son?
Well, Frisco PD thinks you
murdered your wife in a rage,
and I think you did
the same thing to the nanny.
And then you disposed
of the only witness.
We're not going to find
your son alive,
are we?
This kidnapping crap...
...is just that. Right?
I'm going to tell you
the same thing
I told the cops
in San Francisco.
I'm innocent.
And I'm telling
the truth.
BRASS: Yeah, but you're leaving
out some important facts.
Like who Harper's
real mother is.
Your nanny,
Shelby Buress.
RUSSELL: See, we, uh,
confirmed that
with the hospital
in San Francisco.
She is Harper's birth mother.
BRASS: I mean,
it all adds up.
Your wife found out
you knocked up Shelby.
She wants a divorce,
she wants money,
she ends up dead in your pool.
Flash-forward
to your mistress, Shelby,
who ends up dead
in your backyard.
You got a way with women, buddy.
You ever see
this knife before?
Yes. It's mine.
It's in my house.
How about it's in
Shelby Buress's back?
RUSSELL: See, we found
her blood on the blade,
but your blood on the handle.
How do you explain that?
That's my blood.
But I didn't murder anyone.
I was making an offering
to the dead.
What?
I opened my vein
during a séance.
You do know that you're not
in San Francisco now.
The knife was part
of the ritual.
For my departed
Natalie.
(thunder rumbling)
I give you this gift
from life unto death.
A séance?
Okay.
I'm all done here.
(door closes)
Okay.
Who else was at the séance?
Shelby,
my mother-in-law Patricia,
and Karen, the medium.
Well, how... how come we're just
hearing about this now?
Because I knew you'd jump
to the wrong conclusions,
just like the cops
in San Francisco did.
Well, it's a hell of a story,
isn't it?
It's not a story;
it's the truth.
I love my wife.
I miss her.
I brought together the people
who were closest to her
to try to... make contact.
And did you do that?
Did you make contact?
I'm not a murderer.
I'm a father
who needs you to find my son.
Boy's been missing for
over five hours now.
If he's really
missing at all.
You know, Brass seems to think
this whole thing is a hoax.
That the father killed
the nanny
and that the kid
was just collateral damage.
Where are we at?
Got a good fingerprint
on the kidnapper's
note here.
All right, that
plus the headboard.
If they are T.C.'s prints,
Brass's theory is looking
pretty good.
Yeah.
Man, computers have really
spoiled me.
It's been a while
since I've done this by eye.
Uh-huh. Me, too.
All right, tell you what,
you take the note.
I'll take the headboard.
Okay. There you go.
Thanks.
A plain arch.
No, wait a minute.
Got a tented arch here.
That's pretty cool.
I got the same thing here.
That's very rare.
Good for us.
Maybe bad for T.C.
Let's check him out.
Ulnar loops, radial loops...
a few whorls.
Interesting ridge pattern.
It's a real smorgasbord, but...
No tented arches.
No.
The prints we found on
the kidnapper's note
and the boy's headboard
did not belong to T.C.
And there were no prints
on the knife.
So if the prints don't fit,
you must acquit? Bull.
Yeah, I'm right there
with you.
We've got Riordan's knife,
his drugs.
I mean, I'm not saying that
he necessarily did it alone,
but we know he's got plenty
of people working for him.
Yeah, and we checked them
all out, though.
But he's got the money
to buy their silence,
maybe even their alibis.
Yeah, you were in
the interrogation room.
Didn't you feel
the presence of a con man,
a lying sack of shinola?
The whole séance story?
Yeah, it's far out.
I know that.
I'm just saying, if the guy's
telling the truth,
there's a shot that his boy
is still out there alive.
Were you able to follow up
on his story?
Oh, you mean was I able to
conjure up the mother-in-law
and spirit guide?
No, I'm still working on it.
We all know
how this is gonna end.
BRASS:
Look, D.B.--
are you thinking like
a dad here or a CSI?
Call just came in.
Kidnapper.
MAN:
Get yourself a pen and paper,
Mr. Riordan.
Write this down.
I need to know...
is my son all right?
Who's asking,
you or the cops?
Me. I'm asking.
HARPER:
Daddy?
Harper.
I'm scared.
Hey, pal...
Tell me something.
Who lives on the Moon?
The lady in white.
That's right.
Harper, are you okay?
MAN: Palermo parking lot,
level three.
All the jewels from the safe.
8:00 a.m.
Your contact will wear
a red hat.
(line beeps off)
8:00 a.m.
That gives us four hours.
RUSSELL:
So you keep over
$2 million
worth of jewelry
in your house safe?
Yes.
Most of it belonged
to my wife Natalie.
You couldn't think of a better
place to keep it?
I like to keep her things near.
There are some nights that...
RUSSELL:
Okay, um...
anyone else know
about Natalie's jewelry?
My mother-in-law, Patricia.
Patricia Lydecker.
RUSSELL:
You were at the séance
last night, is that
right, Mrs. Lydecker?
Yes.
What time did you
leave the house?
Around 10:00.
Before they took Harper.
"They"?
Well, I just assume
there must have been
more than one person.
Okay. Um,
and you were aware
that T.C.
still had possession
of your daughter's jewelry?
Yes. Why do you ask?
Just trying to, uh...
get the facts straight.
And I'm also trying
to understand how
a woman whose son-in-law
is suspected of murdering
her daughter, how she
could still be so cozy
with the alleged killer.
See, we called the San
Francisco police department,
and they told us that after they
dropped charges against T.C.,
you actually brought a
wrongful death suit against him.
Which I withdrew.
Because you thought
you might lose?
No, because I came to understand
that my son-in-law is innocent.
Okay.
How'd that happen?
My daughter,
Natalie, told me.
Natalie?
Through Karen.
Karen has helped me,
helped me to find peace.
So you've communicated
with Natalie?
Yes.
On several occasions
at T.C.'s house.
Karen allows me
to understand what it is
that Natalie wants.
And what is that?
Mr. Russell,
grief put my husband
in an early grave.
Were it not for Karen,
I might have joined him.
T.C. came to me in grief.
Said he was unable to accept
the death of Natalie.
But peace comes
not from the acceptance of
death, but from an understanding
that death is
just the beginning.
I sense a disturbance
in your chakras.
Yeah, I get that a lot.
What I want from you
right now is
a straight answer.
When did you leave
the Riordan house?
A little after 10:00.
After the communion
with Natalie.
Mrs. Lydecker and I
shared a taxi.
And Mr. Riordan went to bed?
Oh, no. I doubt that.
What do you mean?
Look, if you know
something,
it's in your best interest
to play medium with me
right now.
During the ceremony,
T.C. became agitated.
Natalie wants to speak.
What is it, my love?
My love,
you have betrayed me again.
You must let me go for your
sake, for the sake of Harper.
Your grief is
not an act of love.
It's an act
of selfishness.
My husband was upset.
He ended the
communion.
Your husband?
I mean T.C.
I'm sorry.
Natalie's spirit force
is quite strong.
I feel her presence now.
Say hi for me.
Let's get back to T.C.
T.C told us all to leave.
He was angry.
The last I saw him,
he was in the den.
When you say angry,
how angry was he?
Natalie just wanted T.C.
to find peace.
I'm afraid her words
had the opposite effect.
HODGES: Henry, I'm not sure
your brute force
is gonna get this evidence
to the lab.
You're doing in wrong.
Really?
'Cause you took
that elevator breakout class?
(grunting)
It's moving.
Okay, yeah.
Come on.
Aah!
(groans)
(groans in pain)
Damn.
What are you doing?
Calling Russell,
admitting defeat.
What?! No.
Hey!
No more stupid questions,
all right?
We are CSIs.
Well, sort of.
Let's come up with answers.
In here?
We have your kit.
You're right.
We could do a spot test,
identify the material,
then maybe it'll tell
us where it came from.
I've got potassium hydroxide
in my kit.
Perfect.
Oh, wow.
That's all of it?
It's enough to test.
Yeah, but the test consumes
the whole thing.
If we're wrong,
there's no do-overs.
If we're right,
we may save a boy's life.
BRASS:
8:20.
Red Hat is late.
I knew this was bogus.
I hope for the kid's sake
you're wrong.
BRASS:
Look at this.
That bastard has been here
the whole time.
What...
What's he doing?
What's he doing now?
You think the boy's in there?
I don't know.
STOKES: I don't like this.
Me, neither.
Hold on.
All units be advised,
suspect is wearing a black
leather jacket, red hat.
On the move.
Gray van.
Do not engage, visuals only.
What happened
to the rear window?
What window?
There isn't any.
Exactly.
Hey, where you going?
STOKES: Somebody got
out of that van.
Stop the van.
Lock down
the parking structure.
(siren whoops)
Step out of the vehicle!
Hands on your head!
Step away from the van.
Put you hands
where I can see 'em!
Van's clear.
Where's the guy?
I don't know.
He told me to drive
to an address.
He said I'd find Harper there.
He said no cops,
no surprises.
You people
just got my son killed.
(gunshots)
DISPATCHER:
434, shots fired at the corner
of Altos and Fairway.
Units responding.
(sirens wailing)
Same jacket,
same face.
It's Red Hat.
Must have had an accomplice--
put two bullets in him.
No Harper.
Looks like somebody
forgot to get paid.
Not good for the kid.
SIDLE: Address the kidnapper
gave Riordan was bogus.
Empty lot; no Harper.
Red Hat's name
is Trevor Raymond.
He's got a Henderson address,
and he's got a nice set
of tented arches.
His prints are the ones that we
found on headboard and the note.
Which puts him
inside the house
as well as outside,
dumping the nanny's body.
Two bullets in Raymond
confirms our theory
that he wasn't working alone.
Yeah, and Trevor Raymond
wasn't on T.C.'s list
of employees or staff.
Okay, so if this is an inside
job, who's our insider?
Nick and Brass are searching
Raymond's place now.
Hopefully they'll find
a link to the accomplice.
Forget the three-hour rule.
We're into hour nine now.
Yeah, but...
No, I'm saying, look,
we've got a dead nanny,
now we've got a dead kidnapper.
And the fact that
the accomplice panicked
and left the loot behind,
the kid's got to be dead, too.
How's that help us right now?
SIDLE:
Well, actually, the guy
didn't leave
all the loot behind.
Morgan's got the last
iPad standing.
Still has some juice.
I was able to pull up
the inventory photos
of the jewelry that we took
before we made the exchange
with Red Hat.
There is something missing.
Let's take a look.
Oh, yeah. Wedding ring.
Well, from the size of it,
I'm guessing it's Natalie's.
I'm guessing that the ring
isn't the only thing
that belonged
to Natalie.
Why? What do you got?
I was adding
Trevor Raymond's blood type
to our ABO findings,
when I noticed something.
Harper Riordan's
blood type is O.
Yeah.
Check out Shelby Buress's.
"AB."
Let's get a few things straight,
Mr. Riordan.
First, your son Harper is really
your wife Natalie's son,
isn't he?
Shelby Buress's
blood type
is not compatible with Harper.
She may have given birth to him,
but she was not his mother.
She was a surrogate.
So there wasn't an affair,
was there?
For five years,
the world's thought I'm
a murderer and a philanderer.
What happened between
me, my wife and Shelby
and my family--
that's my business
and no one else's.
What do you mean,
what does it matter?
$2 million worth of jewelry,
and the kidnapper
takes this.
A simple
wedding band.
Your wife's ring.
Why?
I don't know.
No, you have to know.
Look, T.C.,
you have a choice here.
You can either stay
shuttered up in your house
with your ghosts,
feeling sorry for yourself
or you can open the damn blinds.
This ring is
important.
It's important to you and to
the person who took your son.
Now, come on.
That ring is the reason
why Natalie's dead.
We'd been at a party.
(both yelling at once)
We were both drunk.
We had a fight.
Natalie took off her ring
and she threw it in the pool.
Go. Go!
Yes!
Few hours later, we made up.
She went to get
the ring back and...
she was still drunk.
I didn't even hear her.
It was an accident.
But the world blamed you.
The world was right.
It was my fault.
W-What are
you gonna do?
You gonna
make your son
pay for your sins?
You think someone took Harper
to punish me?
My vote:
Natalie's mother Patricia.
Yeah, but she claims that
she's forgiven T.C., so...
(scoffs)
That's ridiculous.
I would never forgive
somebody who killed my daughter.
Yeah, but we know your
history with forgiveness,
so that...
Oh, that's nice.
No, I didn't
mean it,
I didn't mean
it that way.
Come on, now, stop
it, focus. Patricia.
Okay, she was there that night.
She was in the house.
She knew about the jewelry.
And maybe she knew about Harper.
He was her daughter's son,
therefore her grandson.
Who should be living with her
and not her daughter's murderer.
Yes, it's a twofer.
Get the boy, kill the nanny.
And with T.C.'s history,
he becomes the obvious suspect.
And maybe this time he
goes down for the crime.
STOKES:
Hey.
What do you got?
Brass and I tossed Red Hat's
place pretty thoroughly.
Somebody sent him ten G's.
We found a receipt
for the wire transfer.
So we got our accomplice.
Depends if
you believe in ghosts or not.
Check out the signature.
Signed by the late
Natalie Riordan.
(computers beep, whir)
Okay, that's freaky.
(elevator clicks, whirs)
(gasps)
Yes.
(chuckles)
CSIs.
Well, sort of.
So?
Got it.
Hodges and Henry were able
to I.D. that metal trace.
It's a specific composite
of magnesium
used primarily in
the production of mag wheels.
Where do you find a mag
wheel factory in Las Vegas?
Well, there's
only one,
and luckily for us,
it's across the street
from the wire
transfer office
where the ghost
of Natalie Riordan
sent money to Trevor Raymond.
Northeast Las Vegas.
A lot of abandoned buildings and
homes in that part of town.
If I was looking for
a kidnapper's lair,
that's where I'd go.
Boy, that's a lot of
territory to cover.
Maybe I can help narrow
down the canvass.
What do you got?
A line on our ghost.
She used a fake I.D.
to make the wire transfer.
Karen Chavera.
Our ghost is
the ghost whisperer.
Karen Chavera!
LVPD!
SIDLE: Guess we know
how Karen met Trevor.
Clear. No lady, no kid.
Same here.
But you gotta see this.
Whoa.
SIDLE:
That is some crazy wallpaper.
STOKES: It's a shrine
to T.C. and Natalie.
Looks like
our medium's research
turned into a bit of
an obsession, don't you think?
SIDLE: Yeah. She helped herself
to Natalie's things.
And to T.C.'s meds.
"Dear T.C.,
"By the time you read this,
Harper and I will be gone.
"I thought
we could be together,
"but again you rejected me,
"gave your love away
to Shelby, even Karen,
"who reunited us.
"You left me no choice
but to take them away from you.
Now, you feel my pain."
It's signed Natalie.
I think that she became
Natalie Riordan.
Problem is, Karen thought T.C.
had an affair with Shelby.
So when Karen became Natalie,
she took revenge
on the one woman
she blamed for
stealing T.C. away.
And then she took her kid.
(thumping in distance)
(thumping continues)
That hutch is
blocking a door.
Let's move it.
There he is.
Hey, bud.
SIDLE:
Harper.
It's okay.
It's all right, all right?
We're with the police.
Everything's going to be okay.
Russell, it's Stokes.
We found Harper,
alive and well.
No sign of Karen, though.
RUSSELL:
Yeah, I know.
I've got eyes on her right now.
I guess she felt she
had to... join Natalie.
Let's bring the boy on home.
(chuckles)
It's good to have all the
"IS'es" back, isn't it?
It's good to have
everything back.
You, uh, sure about that?
You never know when it
might come in handy.
Hmm.
Why go old school...
When you can go ancient.
(chuckles softly)
Hmm.
(car door shuts)
♪ ♪
(mouthing)
No three-hour rule on this one.
Nope.
Glad none of the rules applied.
How do you do it?
Do what?
Never lose faith.
Some things I hide
better than you do.