♪ ♪
(bubbling)
(exhaling)
Dearly beloved,
we are gathered here today
to join Andrew Milner
and Lisa Kravitz in
holy matrimony.
Marriage is the
gift of all gifts.
It is the promise
of all promises.
It is commended to be
honorable among all men
and should not be
entered into lightly,
but discretely, reverently,
advisedly and solemnly.
(cocks gun)
Into this glorious estate,
these two now come to be joined.
So if any person here
has just cause as to...
(screaming)
GUNMAN: Everybody up!
To the front!
Move!
(siren whoops,
helicopter flies over)
God, I love big weddings.
FINLEY:
Ugh, not me.
The minute the
invitation comes, my feet hurt
from the shoes
I'm going to have to wear.
Oh, come on, how can you
resist the unabashed
splendor of a
storybook wedding?
Hey, Conrad, whatcha got?
ECKLIE: Two armed
assailants in full costume,
took all the gifts, cash,
wallets, jewelry...
Did anybody see
how they got away?
No, three separate witnesses
called in the gunshots
but nobody got eyes
on the getaway car.
Response time?
Under five minutes.
That's a small window
to do your thing.
FINLEY:
Why are you here?
Beg pardon?
Well, you're the,
uh, undersheriff,
you're second in command.
Well, I'm here
for two reasons.
First, as the mayor
just reminded me
there are 300 weddings
a day in Las Vegas,
bringing millions of out of town
dollars into our economy.
What's the second reason?
This isn't just a robbery.
It's a robbery homicide.
Good Lord.
So much for
your storybook wedding.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
One bullet hole.
No spatter.
Must be the only one.
Can you lift the head?
Yeah.
(grunts)
No exit wound.
Bullet must
still be in there.
Hey, guys, there's something
missing, right?
Isn't there a...
Never mind,
I found it.
Oh, yeah.
Gunshot residue on the
Mad Hatter's card.
Pattern puts it
at close range.
So the groom was shot
execution-style,
on his wedding day.
What kind of person
does that?
Maybe somebody who doesn't much
care for the institution.
I take it from your tone
that you don't either.
I like weddings;
I've had two of them, but...
marriages, they don't really
agree with me.
If you think about it,
a wedding's
a pretty good
place to rob, huh?
You'd be the wedding
expert, I guess.
Your mom's a multiple
offender too, you know.
But her second one stuck.
I noticed you're
light next week.
You want to grab
a bite to eat?
Next week's a ways away.
We'll see.
NANA OF THE BRIDE:
It was a beautiful day,
like a fairy tale.
Then, all of the sudden,
we hear gunshots,
and we all turn and see this
smiling cat and
this white rabbit.
Like in the book?
They didn't have
guns in the book.
(gunshots, screaming)
GUNMAN: Everybody up!
NANA: They yelled.
Told us to
take out our wallets,
our phones, our jewelry,
they even pulled off my brooch.
Well, we'll see what we can do
about getting that back for you.
I'm sorry.
Thank you.
All right.
They split up
as soon as they got in.
The rabbit gathered up
all the gifts.
They just barked out orders.
And assured everybody that it
would all be over soon.
And for a while, it seemed
like it would be.
Then there was that scuffle.
(people arguing)
Move!
What kind of a scuffle?
I don't know, it was on the
other side of the crowd.
I didn't get a good look.
Can you think
of anyone that did?
(sighs heavily)
Go ask Alice.
Andrew and I met
in an English class--
Literature of the Absurd,
and Alice in Wonderland
kind of became our thing,
our way of saying
"I love you."
It's stupid. I know.
No, no, I think
that's very sweet.
When he proposed,
on the table was a bottle
labeled "drink me,"
a cake labeled "eat me,"
and this antique engagement
ring labeled "marry me."
So, when the rabbit
came for the ring...
I couldn't let go of it.
The rabbit got angry
and hit me in the leg
with the end of his gun.
Andrews very protective of me.
And he didn't even slow down
when there was
a gun to his head.
(all screaming)
He saw me...
before the wedding.
(sobbing):
It's bad luck.
Oh, I... I don't know.
Ho, ho, ho, hey, listen to me.
Listen to me. Listen to me.
This was not your fault.
This was theirs.
Okay?
I'm going to be right back.
CSI Finley's going to
stay with you here, okay?
Mrs. Kravitz,
can you show me where
he hit you
with the gun?
Find anything interesting?
Found a little
of everything:
old, new, borrowed,
and hey, something blue.
What do you think
that is?
I have no idea.
Let's get all this to Mandy.
Our two robbers were
quick as a bunny.
Maybe they got sloppy
and left a paw print.
Hey... you got anything
to calm down our bride
inside a little bit?
PARAMEDIC:
Sure. Go ahead, Kyle.
Okay.
This is Haloperidol.
Five mils should
take the edge off.
Where is she?
Dressing room.
Thanks.
WEBSTER: What part of "no"
do you not understand--
the N or the O?
It's an hour of your life.
Of lying. About being
your girlfriend.
(shudders)
No offense.
Oh, no, it's okay.
None taken. Really.
Sorry to interrupt.
Don't worry about it.
He's just working on
his mommy issues.
Oh, I really don't want
to know about that--
HODGES: My mother is visiting
CSI for the first time
before she gets on a plane,
with her boyfriend,
to go to Italy.
And it's possible,
well, probable,
that I may have mentioned
I was dating someone.
Someone at work.
HODGES: She's a woman
of expectations.
The highest of which she
reserves for her son.
I'm all she has.
I don't want to
disappoint her.
WEBSTER: Then tell her
the truth.
HODGES:How would that
not disappoint her?
Mandy, I am desperate.
One date,
and then she's
out of your life.
Ah, yes.
My favorite part.
D.B.
Well, the apparent C.O.D.
is traumatic brain injury,
caused by projectile
penetration of the skull.
Bullet to the brain.
But the X-ray doesn't show
what looks like a bullet.
What did it show?
I'd rather not say till
I get a closer look,
at the risk of sounding mad
as a hatter myself.
It certainly doesn't
look like a nine mil.
No, it is, in fact,
a button.
How the heck did
it get in there?
Well, it's roughly the
same size as our entry wound.
Penetrating trauma
to the skull and gray matter
is consistent with
a gunshot wound.
Our victim had a button
fired into his head
at 400 meters per second.
Pretty absurd, but that's
the tale his body is telling.
Curiouser and curiouser.
WEBSTER: I ran every bullet,
bouquet and tea cup
that Morgan brought me.
Prints at the scene
matched a guest.
There's no outliers.
But there was one discrepancy.
I ran everything
through AFIS
and there was one set that
matched to an Alan Widcom.
What's the discrepancy?
Well, the name
he gave you when
you interviewed him
was Charles Dodson,
who doesn't
actually exist.
Huh.
And Alan Widcom
is an ex-convict.
Good find, Mandy.
WEBSTER:
Does he look familiar?
Maybe.
Can I borrow your marker?
Thanks.
SIDLE: Last time we spoke,
you were a caterpillar.
ECKLIE: Looks like you
came out of
your cocoon a little
more colorful.
Another day, another avatar.
Elvis is a big
cliche these days.
And Liberace's
all the rage, so...
Is, uh, Charles Dodson
another avatar?
SIDLE:
Birth name of Lewis Carroll.
Were we supposed
to think that was clever?
Well, maybe a little.
We dug up your
real file, Mr. Widcom.
Prison records,
rap sheet,
ending with a count
of armed robbery.
I waved a wrench in the face
of a crooked mechanic
to get my car back.
It was stupid, yes,
but I'm not a thief.
Then why the pseudonym?
Because the state
doesn't allow
felons to be ordained
ministers for ten years--
way too long
to deny my calling.
Calling?
Is that what it is?
Are you married?
I am.
It's... special.
Isn't it?
Yes, it is.
You want to keep your license?
More than anything.
Then help us get these guys.
In prison, you've seen
your share of criminals.
Anything at all
stand out with these two?
Yes.
They were very efficient.
They locked the right doors,
crowd control.
Everything was very intentional.
Very practiced.
This wasn't their first rodeo.
No, these guys were pros.
♪ ♪
So what was
your other one like?
Your first wedding.
(chuckles):
Oh.
Big affair.
Probably dropped
300 G's.
It was beautiful, it was grand,
but it was missing something.
What's that?
Love.
(sympathetically):
Oh...
(car horn honking)
(laughing):
Okay. Okay!
Hi.
Dearly beloved,
we have gathered here today
to marry Walter Gersh to...
Crystal Hasselbeck.
Walter, do you take Crystal
to be your lawfully wedded wife?
You bet.
(laughs)
To have and to... holy...
(guns cocking)
Babe, what is it?
Hands up in the air.
Now!
RUSSELL: The advice from
our caterpillar was spot-on.
These guys are pros.
Look at that.
Took the couple
down quickly,
got all their stuff
in no time.
Got the car, too.
Beelined it right across the
street to that service alley.
Lucky move.
Any longer
or in any other direction,
we would've gotten them.
Please tell me you got
something on the SUV.
It was stolen
about an hour earlier
from a mall parking lot.
It's official.
These two are starting
to piss me off.
I feel so violated.
My purse, my necklace,
my engagement ring.
Anything else?
His wallet and watch.
Uh, don't forget the car.
Well, yeah,
but it's just a car.
It's a Rolls Royce Corniche.
It was custom;
it had everything.
Well, great.
So, uh, you had LoJack?
Of course not.
Think I want the government
tracking me?
Uh, did you see any faces?
Scars? Tattoos?
Hear any voices?
The one on my side talked.
Uh, he had a deep voice,
but it was muffled.
Okay.
Um, the ring...
approximate value?
You can't put a price on love.
A little over half a million.
That's a lot of love.
Only the best.
Anything else lost or damaged?
They tore his jacket.
Oh.
And stained my dress.
Which is an original.
I know it's not technically
your wedding night,
but, uh...
I'm going to need you
to take off your clothes.
OLIVIA: Gotta love a
man in uniform.
Look at you.
Like a real doctor.
Mother.
You're here, now.
Well, I told you I was
coming eventually.
Besides, I am
dying to meet her.
Actually, they're
very particular about
who they allow access
to in the lab.
She's all taken care of.
I got her
a full-access badge.
Thank you, Mandy.
I am just so happy
that you found someone, David.
Um, funny story.
Hilarious, really.
I was beginning to worry
that I had held onto you too
tight after your father left
and didn't give you enough space
to become your own man.
I'm my own man.
Look. Lab coat.
My own office.
I expected it to be a little
bigger, given how important
you are around here.
Mother, I-I think
we need to talk.
Hi, sweetie.
Hey, you.
BRODY:
You must be Mrs. Hodges.
I'm Morgan Brody.
I'm so excited
to finally meet you.
Oh! Well, call me Olivia.
(mouthing)
Crazy day at the office, Olivia.
(Hodges chuckles anxiously)
I just came by to see
if you got trace on the dress.
Yes. Uh, I was able
to isolate sodium bicarbonate,
citric acid, everlace enzyme
and potassium monoperchlorate.
You put them all together
and that gives you...
Denture cleaner.
You finish
each other's sentences.
That's adorable.
Why denture cleaner?
Hazards of dating
a septuagenarian?
Mm. Right.
I wish I had more time to chat.
I just, I gotta go.
Have a great trip.
Thank you.
Bye... David.
Bye.
Bye. Bye.
Love her.
Uh, me, too.
C-Clearly.
Hey.
Hey. Good.
Come here.
I think I finally
figured out
the mystery of the
button in the brain.
Great.
The gun bruise on
our Alice's leg
Yeah?
matches to this...
this World War II gun,
which corresponds to casings
that Morgan found at the scene.
Right? Like this one right here.
Nine-mil.
She also found an
overpowder wad,
that fit in here like this.
Keep the powder in, because...
They were using blanks.
No projectile,
but you get the same
amount of force
as your everyday 400-
meter-per-second bullet.
Now, that force
usually comes out
in the form of a loud
but harmless
muzzle flash.
Unless the barrel
is obstructed...
FINLAY:
By a button.
Fire in the hole!
(gunshot)
Projectile by proxy.
FINLAY:
Okay, so we have the "how,"
now we need the "who."
Same rifle showed up
in the drive-thru video.
So we've connected the gun
to both scenes, right?
Mm-hmm.
So it's safe to assume
that it's the same twosome.
Yeah.
Same M.O., generally.
Armed,
disguised, wedding hits.
But the two targets
couldn't be more different.
Wonderland was, like,
this grand scheme, right?
Carefully planned.
Drive-thru was smaller.
More spur of the moment.
So, think.
What's the common denominator?
The ring.
Hi.
Do you have an appointment?
We're on the list.
Thank you.
Are you two together?
Yes, we are.
We're from the crime lab.
Do you recognize
these two people?
Insurance tells us
that they were here
buying a ring a while back.
Yes, of course.
Hard to forget.
Because of the
age difference?
Age difference?
This is Las Vegas.
I'm talking about the ring.
For starters,
it's a Gartreau.
Gordon Gartreau.
Designs ten rings a year,
using the finest gold.
Non-conflict diamonds.
Well, this diamond
found a conflict.
Armed robbery,
last night.
So if we stole a ring like that,
how would we go about
reselling it?
You wouldn't.
It's one of a kind.
Distinct.
Well, that would be
kind of hard
for your average thief
to fence it
and make any kind of profit.
Too high-profile
to sell at auction.
So what are we looking at here?
Thank you, thank you.
Sorry we wasted your time.
Uh, just one more thing.
The woman that bought that ring,
she's been here before.
A few times.
SANDERS:
Do you recognize any of these?
Yes.
I think these rings were all
mine, at one time or another.
And at this time,
where are they?
This one I sold.
This one I lost.
And you know
this one was stolen.
You insured it.
Immediately
after buying it.
Is that right?
That's when
you get things insured.
Is getting engaged
a crime now?
No.
But fraud is.
You declared its value
at $1.1 million.
That's twice what your
fiancé told me it was worth.
And this one
that you lost,
sold online to
some guy in Jersey.
His receiving account
points to you.
The first time
was a bad breakup,
so I kept the ring.
The second time was easier.
More of a business transaction.
Times are tough.
And love...
Is what,
recession-proof?
Did you set up this robbery?
No, I didn't.
I swear.
I would never
put Walt in danger.
But you had no problem
setting him up
to buy you an expensive ring.
At first... yeah.
But then, when we were
pulling up, I realized,
well, I really wanted
to marry him.
Be married to him.
Why should I believe you?
I don't know.
But you have to believe
in love, right?
You are the greatest.
Glad I could help.
Mom off to Italy?
Well, uh, good
news and bad news.
Her boyfriend's
flight was delayed.
Oh, hope that's the bad news.
Yeah, and since
she's available,
she wanted to have
brunch with me and you.
Oh. That is bad news.
Oh, that's not
the bad news.
She also wants your
father to join us.
The last time I had a meal
with my father
was 14 years ago, when he
tried to explain divorce
over a milkshake.
You don't expect me
to call him up for this?
No, no, no, no,
y-you don't have to.
Mother made me call him.
And he's very excited.
Albeit a little confused.
Yeah, he's not the only one.
You saw her face.
The way that she lit
up when she saw you.
Sh-She was happy.
Proud.
Please?
I'll do anything you ask.
All my cases.
Front of the trace line.
For a year.
You're the greatest.
Ooh. Sweet ride.
The sweetest.
Custom everything.
Where'd they find it?
D Street and Hudgins.
Sticking out like a sore thumb,
pre-pillaged.
Got something here.
Fabric.
It's polyester.
And they didn't take
the high-end sound system.
That's worth what,
a couple grand on the street?
Easy.
So what did they take?
I noticed the hood ornament.
And the... whatever
these emblem things were.
They're on
the steering wheel, too.
And the glove
compartment.
Why these
and not the radio?
I think...
that they were gold.
I got filings.
I bet they wanted to make sure
that they were solid
and not plated.
Yeah, but wouldn't filing them
make them less valuable
and harder to sell?
Russell said the ring
was one of a kind.
That's hard to sell, too.
So maybe they're not
stealing the gold to resell it.
Maybe they're melting it down.
So where do you go
to melt stolen gold in Vegas?
ECKLIE: Had all my detectives
reach out to informants
in the stolen
jewelry trade.
Several pointed
to a Fredrick Ladd.
Runs a cash-for-gold store
in some nearby strip mall.
Yeah, like the ads.
"Market crash.
Cold, hard cash."
Seriously,
you watch too much TV.
I work the night shift, and
my husband's living abroad.
Cut me some slack, please.
ECKLIE:
Anyway, knocked on the door.
No answer.
Strange burning smell.
Unis found him dead.
Gold poured down
his throat.
Looks like
it's connected
to the Wonderland Robbery.
How can you be sure?
Educated guess.
RUSSELL:
Hey. What do you got?
Looks like our victim
was a modern-day alchemist,
turning stolen jewelry
into untraceable gold.
Yeah, because our job
isn't hard enough, right?
What's all this stuff?
All that doesn't glitter--
separated before the melt.
Nana of the bride
had a dragonfly brooch.
It was torn
from her blazer.
The brooch is here.
The gems are here.
Empty wallet
belonging to the driver
of the Rolls-Royce.
This is like a land
of smoking guns.
It looks like the feline
was in mid-melt
when somebody
turned up the heat.
(grunting)
(camera shutter snapping)
Looks like the cast iron's
our murder weapon.
What is that
on the handle?
I don't know.
So why kill
somebody like this?
What are they doing,
sending a message?
We were looking for two robbers.
Maybe the partnership
hit a rough patch.
Maybe.
RUSSELL:
Hey, Doc.
How goes it?
I'll tell you this--
I'm not bored.
Confirm cause of death yet?
Thermal injuries.
He was alive when the gold
was poured down his throat.
Cooked him from the inside.
RUSSELL: Gold melts
at 1,850 degrees Fahrenheit.
(grunting)
Soft tissue didn't
stand a chance.
So what's with the XRF?
I want to test
this guy's metal.
If you're so into gold
that you pry it off a
poor bride's finger,
why would you waste it
by pouring it
down your partner's gullet?
I figured it
was heat of the moment.
Those two seemed like
they were as cool
as the center seed
of a cucumber.
A little out of character,
don't you think?
(beeping)
Iron pyrite.
Fool's gold.
We're the only fools
around here.
I mean, he's not
our Cheshire cat.
Yeah, but why
would they set it up
to look like
a busted partnership?
Exactly. You know,
they should be halfway
to China by now,
but they stop and they do this?
Only one reason
I can think of
to go to that much trouble.
And what's that?
They're planning another job.
I'm sorry about this.
I-I was really just trying
to do a favor
for Hodges, and he...
Is an
irrepressible,
but ridiculous human being?
Yeah, that.
Sorry.
No, don't be. It's a... it's a
nice thing you're doing for him.
And as good an excuse as any
for us to finally catch up.
You fold your napkin
just like your mom.
You used
to do that when we
went to Choozy's Chicken.
Do you remember?
How's she doing? She okay?
Yeah, she's doing great.
Jerry, he's, uh...
he's good to her?
Kind?
Oh, yeah.
She practically owns him.
Well, that sounds about right.
Well...
I'm happy she's happy.
Yeah.
I know you are.
(door opens and closes)
Hi.
Good to see you again.
Hello.
Hi. That's where Morgan
gets her looks.
Oh. (chuckles)
Olivia Hodges.
Conrad Ecklie.
My pleasure.
Well...
Here we are.
Yeah.
This is nice.
Maybe we should
order champagne?
Celebrate?
BRODY:
Oh?
What's the occasion exactly?
Young love.
David is my only child.
Handsome, clearly;
charming.
But he's had a bit
of a dry spell.
Mother!
What?
It's a natural
parental concern.
Back me up here,
Conrad.
Well, I'd, uh...
I'd be lying if I said
I didn't have fantasies
about walking Morgan
down the aisle.
Someday.
So tell me--
how did you two meet?
Uh...
You.
I'll take it.
Yeah.
Well, um...
I was called down to L.A.
on the trail
of this sinister man called
the Dick and Jane Killer,
and Morgan was assisting
on the case.
And when the smoke cleared,
the only thing left
was this pent-up...
cross-jurisdictional
sexual tension...
I'm going to hit
the restroom
real quick.
OLIVIA:
Great. I'll join you.
So...
David,
your mom-- is, uh...
is-is she...
She has a
boyfriend.
He's a count.
They're going to Italy together.
What, are you
working out your commute?
(chuckling)
Hell, no. I gave up
on that years ago.
I'm trying to
figure out
how these wedding
robbers got away clean.
From which robbery?
From both of them.
When they took off
from the drive-thru,
they headed east
into oncoming traffic
and got away
by the skin of their teeth.
Now, it seemed like dumb luck,
but if you look at the map
on the left--
that green square
is the chapel, okay?
Gotcha. And the red square is
where we found the Rolls Royce.
Yeah, yeah, and radio cars
saturated the area between,
but nobody saw two people
in gas masks in a high-end ride.
They're not lucky;
they're good.
Exactly. They pulled
the same disappearing act
when they robbed
the Wonderland wedding.
So the map on the right--
I reverse-engineered it
from the dispatch tapes.
Now, in this case,
the net was even tighter.
Five radio cars
and an eye in the sky.
And no one
saw the getaway car?
No. No.
And all the main roads
were blocked off.
You know,
I think maybe our bad guys
know some shortcuts.
We could look at cab drivers,
high-end liveries, limousines.
Yeah.
That's a good idea.
You're still here?
Yeah.
You know,
you should really
go home
and get some rest.
I can't stop thinking
of my wife.
Supposed to be
the best day of your life,
and-and your soul mate is killed
right in front of you.
You imagine that?
No.
I never got a chance
to marry my soul mate.
Come here. Come here.
Let me...
Let me just show you
something here.
Uh, Liberace Caterpillar guy,
right, he said that...
that those two were practiced?
Well, I think
I finally figured out
where they got their practice.
New York City.
Three years ago, three
wedding robberies.
And then I couldn't
find any more.
Until...
Chicago,
last year.
Yeah.
Three wedding robberies.
Bing, bang, boom.
Okay, look at this.
It's not just three in a row.
It's three robberies
on three consecutive days.
New York--
Friday, Saturday, Sunday.
Chicago--
Las Vegas.
Friday was
Wonderland.
Saturday...
The drive-through.
Right, so today, Sunday.
So that means their hit
has to be today.
There are hundreds of weddings
going on today.
We got to
narrow it down.
We have reason to believe
that these wedding robbers
are due for one more hit
by day's end.
Okay, we got
three teams.
Team A, with Finn,
going to the chapel on
top of the Palermo.
I'm with Sanders,
hitting the black-tie affair
at the Mediterranean
with Team Bravo.
Sara and I are headed
to Temple Beth El.
All right,
we got one more chance
to get these guys,
then they disappear.
Good luck, everybody.
Hey.
Hodges around?
Oh, his mom dragged
him out of the lab.
Ah.
Uh, do you know if he
got trace on the cast iron?
He did.
That latex there
was next to the
seared flesh here.
Which got me thinking--
latex could be a glove,
and maybe the charred skin
is a finger.
Can you get a print off that?
Well, I better
at least get a partial.
(camera shutter snapping)
Or a partial of a partial.
Minimal ridge detail.
And it matches about...
almost 4,000 prints on AFIS.
Latex glove.
Polyester
from the car,
Maybe a uniform.
Is there a database
for ambulance drivers?
Yeah, there's a National
Paramedics Registry.
BRODY: Nick said something
about how the robbers
really knew all of the roads.
Pay dirt. Kyle Hartley,
paramedic EMT.
I know him.
He was at the first
crime scene.
That's how they got away
so clean.
No one notices an ambulance.
And they certainly
don't blink
when you run a red light.
They just get out of the way
for you.
He moved here
eight months ago
from Chicago.
He has no
criminal record.
He's married.
And look who he's married to.
(door opens)
OLIVIA:
Come on.
We're just looking.
Mother, I feel
that this is a bit
presumptuous.
You don't let a keeper
like Morgan get away.
Now, your co-worker Mandy
said that this was the place.
Hello. Can I help you?
Yes. My son, a big deal
over at the Las Vegas Police
Crime Lab,
would like
to purchase a ring.
Huh, look at that.
Denture cleaner.
We use it to de-oxydize
the metals.
Gives it a real shine.
That's funny. I was just...
You were just what?
I was just... nothing.
Mother, come on.
We're leaving.
(guns cock)
Yeah, I don't think you are.
(muffled groaning)
David, what's happening?
I believe we've just found
our wedding thieves.
But don't worry,
Mother.
Okay.
I know for a fact
they only shoot blanks.
Oh!
Not anymore.
OFFICER 1: Clear?
OFFICER 2: All clear.
You okay?
Do I look okay?
Someone call the paramedics.
Gunshot wound.
They blindsided me,
Emily and her husband.
How long ago
did they leave?
Four or five minutes ago.
They had me disable the
surveillance and the alarm,
and they cleaned
the place out and took off.
Listen to me-- one of
our guys was headed here.
Did you see him?
Crime lab guy and his mom?
Yeah... yeah,
they had them
toss their phones
over there,
and they took 'em with 'em.
Do you know where
they were going?
They just said "Out of town."
Control 101, we've got
a 444 originating
at Van Der Meer Jewelry.
DISPATCHER:
This is Code Red channel--
444 in progress.
Suspects may be driving
a white EMT vehicle.
Point of origin Granholm
and Wells Avenue.
Babe, they know
where we started.
They always do.
We're always fine.
Did you take
the number off the roof?
Did one better.
Switched it for another rig.
They're scrambled,
but looking for him.
And they're giving us
the heads up.
OFFICER (over radio):
2-Charlie-34,
proceeding eastbound
on Sahara towards Kings Road.
The radio.
That's how you always
knew where to be.
And where not to be.
Plus, getting away is
always easier
when you can
change traffic lights.
What are you gonna
do with us?
We're driving to the desert
where we have a car.
We're leaving you there.
Next stop, Fiji.
How on earth are we gonna get
back from the desert?
We're not, Mom.
OFFICER: Patrol, 2-Charlie-7,
west from Lonnie Avenue.
No sign of anything yet.
Copy that,
2-Charlie-7.
Don't worry. We'll get 'em.
Your dad scrambled
the entire department.
Good guys are everywhere.
Yeah, they were there before.
Yeah, but listen to 'em, uh...
on a red channel,
open to everyone.
They're all talking
back and forth.
Air Three, Control.
Are you up?
Control, Air Three.
Beginning sweep...
BRODY: They're talking
to each other.
And if we can hear them...
so can an ambulance.
(over radio):
Copy all. This is Charlie-12,
465 and I-15 southbound exit.
Hey.
I need your help.
(over radio):
2-Charlie-2, we have a visual
on possible vehicle.
We need backup
to Tropicana Way.
They're heading to the
other side of town.
We should be good.
(over radio): ...proceed to
northwest corner of...
Please,
do something.
Like what?
I don't know.
You're this big police person.
I'm a criminalist.
Lab rat, Mom. That's it.
You know what
I do all day?
I measure and analyze
tiny bits of tiny.
Is it exciting?
Not always.
Is it fulfilling?
Very much so.
David...
No!
...I don't expect...
No, I need to get this
off my chest before we die.
Sit down! Sit down!
My office is exactly
the size it needs to be.
Morgan is not my girlfriend.
Sweetheart, what...?
And I can't save us.
I'm not this great police guru
that you make me out to be.
I can't.
I'm not perfect.
All I have is
a love for my job
and a very
detailed knowledge
of the physical limitations
of duct tape.
(gasps)
What the hell did you do?!
Haloperidol.
Thanks for keeping it handy.
Now pull over.
(over radio):
I have visual on an ambulance.
(siren wailing)
What are you doing?
You won't shoot me.
Not if I keep it at a speed
that will kill us all if you do.
They're tracking a decoy rig
to the other side of town.
Nothing between us and
the desert, not even tr...
Traffic.
David!
(siren wails)
Dispatch, this is 2-Charlie-25
in pursuit of suspect
northbound on
Tipper Drive.
2-Charlie-6, lost visual
on suspect vehicle.
2-Charlie-12,
do you have a visual?
Control, 2-Charlie-22,
negative visual.
DISPATCH:
Unit 15, can you get eyes on?
(sirens wailing)
Control, 2-Charlie-6,
suspect is evading pursuit.
(over radio):
All units converge.
2-Charlie-12.
Vehicle is cornered.
(over radio):
Do we have eyes on the hostages?
Are they safe?
Come on!
Dispatch, this is Unit Four.
Suspects have been apprehended.
I repeat,
suspects have been apprehended.
Yeah!
(sirens wailing)
Yes, sir!
(over radio): 2-Charlie-22.
Suspects apprehended.
DISPATCH:
Do we have eyes on the hostages?
Go.
Okay?
Okay. Yeah, thanks.
How did you...?
Morgan called me.
Had us switch channels
to flush them out.
You have to admit it,
as far as plans go,
this was damn well
thought-out.
Yeah, she had
a jewelry storefront.
She could ask all
the right questions,
and wait for
the perfect weekend.
While he gets
comfortable as an EMT.
Learning the roads in
whatever city they're in.
Police procedures,
escape route.
Yeah, then the money runs thin,
and they just steal some more.
Move to a new city.
Uh-huh.
Did you get
the husband to crack?
No. In fact, he's taking the rap
for the whole thing.
Well, he did promise
to love and protect.
Yeah, which is ironic,
because she threw
him under the bus
five minutes in.
Women.
I, uh, found some other stolen
things in the ambulance,
and if it's okay with you two,
I'd like to return
one tiny piece of evidence.
On what grounds?
It has sentimental value.
I didn't know you had
sentiments.
I didn't say they were mine.
I'm sorry...
...for the ruse.
I just wanted you
to be proud of me.
Proud?
You saved my life.
You're great at what you do,
you're loved by so many.
I couldn't be prouder.
Besides, I haven't been
totally honest with you
about my romantic situation.
What, the Count?
He wasn't a Count.
It's possible he doesn't
even know how to.
He dumped me weeks ago.
Oh. What about Italy?
Oh, the trip's still on.
Non-refundable.
So it's penne
Bolognese for one.
(both chuckle)
You know, I have a few
vacation days saved up.
Would you like
to have
a travel amico?
Ah, David, that's okay.
You don't have to.
I know.
I want to.
(both laugh gently)
You found it.
ALICE:
"The sun was shining
on the sea,
"shining with all his might.
"He did his very best to make
the billows smooth and bright.
"And this was odd because it was
the middle of the night.
"The moon was shining sulkily
"because she thought the sun
had got no business to be there
"after the day was done.
"'It's very rude of him,'
she said,
"'to come and spoil the fun!'
"The sea was wet
as wet could be,
"The sands were dry as dry.
"You could not see a cloud
"because no cloud was in
the sky.
"No birds were flying overhead,
there were no birds to fly.
"The Walrus and the Carpenter
were walking close at hand.
"They wept like anything to see
such quantities of sand.
"'If this were only cleared
away,' they said,
"'it would be grand!'
"If seven maids with seven mops
swept it for half a year,
"'Do you suppose,'
the Walrus said,
"'That they could
get it clear?'
(voice breaks): "'I doubt it,'
said the Carpenter,
and shed a bitter tear."