(grunting)
Yeah, baby!
Hey, it's Carrot Top.
Welcome aboard
the inner casino tram system.
This takes you from the
Palermo Hotel all the way down
to the Mediterranean Hotel.
This is the best way to get
from hotel to hotel.
Just take the tram.
It's easy, it's smart, too.
It's like 150 degrees outside
in the shade.
It's like 4:00 a.m., and you're
like... " I think my heart's..."
(woman screaming)
CARROT TOP:
Don't spend all your kids'
college funds at one hotel.
Spread the wealth, you know.
Put a little bit everywhere.
Drinking, gambling, smoking,
prostitution.
Bring the kids. It's great.
And when you're in Vegas,
go see a movie,
maybe go shopping.
go check out a show,
but save room for carrot cake!
(growls)
Looks like we're
at our destination.
Remember, go explore the wonders
of the Mediterranean.
Remember, in Vegas,
anything can happen.
Hey, next time we break in
a new supervisor,
I'm in Hawaii,
toes in the sand,
drink in my hand.
And I won't be looking at bugs.
Have fun in there.
Aloha, stranger.
Aloha.
Did you have
a good training session?
Yeah, you know, three weeks
of sand, surf and scarabs.
Well, I hope you got some rest,
'cause it's looking like
a serious Tower-Caper.
Oh, yeah? Whose tower,
the sheriff or the mayor's?
Both.
Mm, I'm excited.
Well, good.
Shootout at the LV corral.
Two dead, three injured.
Whoa, I thought
you said two dead.
I did.
Well, wh-what's,
what's going on?
Should I be worried
about something here?
Welcome back.
You must be Stokes.
Yeah.
Yeah, you, uh...
you must be contaminating
the crime scene.
No, no, no.
I already cleared the area.
Give me a hand, will ya?
Yeah.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Oh, uh, D.B. Russell.
New guy.
D.B.-- really?
(chuckling):
Right. Crazy.
Platform surveillance.
Party at the Palermo.
Hangover at the Mediterranean.
Time stamp.
Wow, the whole ride
only lasted 73 seconds.
That's about as long as
it took you to size me up.
Which is not bad,
'cause he's still working on it.
Am I right?
(chuckles)
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
Hmm. What are you doing here,
little buddy?
EMTs said the wounded mom's face
was covered in ants.
Spilled Mai Tai
right where she went down.
Explains the ant face,
but how'd they get here?
These are red harvesters.
Pogonomyrmex barbatus.
They're really the showgirls
of the ant kingdom.
They're perfect
for things like...
Ant farms.
Yeah.
That would explain the sand.
The kid must have had it
and dropped it.
Six years old--
seeing all of this.
What's the, uh, what's
the cowboy telling us, Suit?
A single gunshot wound
to the chest.
Not a lot of blood.
Game over in seconds.
His right hand tested
positive for GSR.
The security guard
had a .357.
So the Beretta belongs
to the cowboy.
And let me take a look
at this.
(magazine clicking)
Two shots fired.
How did Baseball Jersey do?
Well, there's a lot of blood,
but it looks like a single
shot near the liver.
It's a really awkward angle.
A crossfire hit, maybe.
Bled out.
Thank you, Suit.
Thomas Finnerty.
Locust Valley, New York.
No cash.
Credit cards still here.
What is all this stuff?
It's slimy.
It's like the tram puked.
Ah.
The rust pattern
on the thing up here
looks exactly the Centaurus
constellation.
(chuckling):
How cool is that. Huh.
And that looks like a ricochet.
Maybe.
(cell phone chiming)
Russell.
Okay, where?
I just finished up
my shift at the Palermo.
Minding my own business.
I hear a shot.
I look up. The guy
in the cowboy hat's got a gun.
So, I took
a deep breath,
went by the book.
How many rounds did you fire?
Two or three.
They tell me you didn't know
this guy, right?
No, I didn't know him.
What I know is, he pulled
a nine mil in a crowd.
Yeah, I didn't hear anything.
I was in the car
in front;
it was quiet.
Did you see anyone or anything
odd on the Palermo platform?
No. I'd lost my rent in keno,
so I was a bit dazed.
I heard people died.
The sheriff will be
making a statement soon.
Thank you for your time.
His first mistake
was playing keno.
It's the worst odds in town.
Good to know.
All right, we've accounted
for all the passengers
in the kill car
except for two.
They're in the wind.
WILLOWS:
Any word on the mom?
Yeah, she's out of surgery.
She's going to be fine.
I just got a call.
A 419 in...Brim County?
Brime.
Brime. So, probably
a two-person job.
What do you think?
What do I think?
You're the boss.
I think you should stop
asking me what I think.
I'm glad we got that
out of the way.
I'll take it. I haven't been
to Brim County in a while.
I just heard
"Brime." Wh...?
(chuckles)
Take Saunders with you.
Sanders.
I'll get it.
♪ ♪
You were right.
Ricochet?
Yeah.
SANDERS:
All right. Thanks a lot.
Camper found him.
No I.D.
Did you see the look
on Nick's face
on the tram when he saw Russell
just lying there?
Awesome.
Yesterday, Russell put on
a murder victim's watch,
but he kept asking me
for the time.
And so finally I was like,
"Russell, what time is it?"
And he just looked at his watch
and walked away.
He did catch
that Gig Harbor Killer.
Maybe it works for him.
Do you want to lie down
on the ground and play
dead or should I?
(laughing): No sign
of animal activity.
SANDERS:
Now, the coroner said that
he had puncture wound
in his belly.
So where's the blood?
(camera shutter clicks)
Ew, never seen
that before.
Face of a Jonas Brother,
body of my Grandpa Pete.
Shirt's stretched out.
incremental tears.
SANDERS:
Most of the buttons missing.
Ripped off during the scuffle?
SANDERS: Now we just need
to find our primary.
Hey, the casino's all over
my ass about this tram.
They want their
tram back pronto.
No people mover,
no money in their pockets.
So I told them
it was your call.
So what's it going
to be, D.B.?
Okay, let's wrap it up.
But we haven't even
collected all the blood yet.
Yeah, exactly.
Let's wrap it up to go.
What, you want to take
the whole tram back
to the CSI lab?
The whole thing?
Why? Where
would you take it?
Excuse me
just a second.
(belches)
Oh, too many bubbles.
BRASS:
Yeah, I'm at the hospital now.
I got to run.
Hey, Albert, thanks
for coming in, man.
You know, the ER doc
looks like...
Hey.
I've got some questions
about the mom's wounds.
Well, it's a pleasure
to be here.
Somebody alive
is a nice change.
Yeah.
Hey, hear anything
about Ray Langston?
Yeah. Gloria's doing well,
so he's doing well.
Baltimore's proven to be
a potent medicinal
for both of them.
Medicinal?
You call being railroaded
by IA therapeutic?
A serial killer
is dead.
The world's a better
place, right?
Jim, Ray's back
with the woman he loves.
He's got a second chance.
I think killing Haskell
may have saved his life.
Before she blacked out,
she told the paramedics
she felt paralysis in her legs.
The gunshot didn't do that.
Well, something
on that tram did.
Well, this is strange.
What?
A puncture of some kind.
Needle mark? Bug bite?
That's a hell of a big bug.
Here you go.
I think this is yours,
isn't it, pal?
Hmm?
Secret Seal, right?
Boy, I loves me
some Secret Seal.
Hmm.
Say, who's your favorite
character on there?
Okay, I'll tell you what.
I'm gonna leave it right here
till you're ready for it.
Yeah, you're doing great, bud.
Hey, Nick.
Have you seen my tennis ball
anywhere?
Hmm?
You know, the invisible one?
Um...
No, I, uh,
I haven't seen it.
Oh, for goodness' sakes,
it's right here.
God, I love these things.
Still got it.
Oop.
Hey.
See if you can
get one by me.
Yeah.
Oh, you're gonna play
that way, are you?
Whoop, Emmett, heads up.
Where'd you get it?
Uh...
That was, uh...
Target, yeah. On sale.
You can keep it
if you want.
Thanks.
(chuckling):
You're welcome.
Listen, I-I know it's hard,
but Emmett...
if you can tell us anything
you saw on the tram,
it would be very helpful.
It's okay if you can't
remember anything.
(sighs)
I saw an alien.
Wow.
Big one, or...
a little one?
Little one.
Was it by itself?
Okay.
ROBBINS:
Got an ID on our cowboy.
Robert Mundler.
Tolleson, Arizona.
In town for the gun show.
And he decides
to start his own.
I recovered a bullet
from his chest.
It severed
the ascending aorta.
Sent it off to Ballistics,
came back a .357.
Well, it's the same caliber
as the two we collected
from the mom.
Confirms that our security guard
got off at least three shots.
So, who ruined
Mr. Finnerty's night?
The cowboy or
security guard?
Neither.
He had other complications.
He was suffering from
advanced mesothelioma.
The lungs are encased by
a dense, fibrotic mass.
Tumors infiltrated the ribs
and intercostal muscles.
How much time did he have?
Three months at best.
Mercifully
cut short by sharp-force trauma,
transecting his liver.
Wait a minute.
He wasn't shot?
Nope. Another crime,
another assailant.
Somebody brought a knife
to a gun fight.
RUSSELL:
Okay. So in 73 seconds,
we have a gunfight
and a guy getting stabbed.
STOKES:
Yeah, and don't forget
about Mom's bug bite.
What the hell didn't
happen on this ride?
Okay, all right. Let's
start with what we know.
Go ahead.
Red strings are the
security guard's.
He saw the cowboy
draw his gun.
Got off three shots.
STOKES:
Two shots missed
and hit the mom;
the third kills the cowboy.
How'd our cowboy do
at the rodeo?
STOKES:
Well, the green
strings are his.
He returns fire. One shot was a
total miss, hitting the window.
And then the other one went
through the security guard,
and kind of just
takes a tour of the tram.
And the bullet goes...
up and ricochets.
(cell phone chimes)
Oh. Sorry.
Hold that thought.
Could be my wife.
(chuckles)
Hey, honey.
Uh... well, I'll ask.
Um...
My wife's calling about
a farmers market.
You, you guys have
those here, right?
Um, you know what? I'm going
to have to call you back.
All right.
Explain this to me:
If the stabbing victim,
Tom Finnerty,
is standing right here,
in the middle
of the crossfire,
how come he's not Swiss cheese?
Well, he must have gone down
before the shooting started.
I'll buy that.
Yeah, and don't forget
about the slime.
Yeah, all right.
So the...
the slime path goes
over the Mai Tai,
which means the slime event
came later in the ride.
Did someone
say "slime"?
Actually, uh,
what you're looking at
is a concentrated mixture
of mucus, tyrosinase,
lysine and sodium chloride.
Meaning...
Meaning... there was
an octopus on board.
A cephalopod mollusk,
technically.
Uh, how'd you know?
The kid said he saw an alien.
And we found saltwater
trace in the slime.
Not sure how the alien part
factors into the equation.
All right. Look.
Slime path heads
towards the door, right?
What if our ricochet
left the scene?
(gunshot)
(sloshing)
I think that our
'pod got winged.
Well, it's all perfectly
logical, except for one thing.
What's an octopus doing
on a Vegas tram?
SIDLE:
What do you make of
the Shar-Pei chest?
Exposure?
It's more like
the skin was stretched.
That's odd.
Connective tissues separated
from the subcutaneous fat.
Falls right off the muscle.
Dark residue along the
stratum germinativum
It's curious.
Ugh.
Just got results back from
Shar-Pei's shirt and pants.
Found traces of "Bambi blood."
Huh.
You know, he had
GSR on his hand.
Maybe he was a hunter.
SANDERS:
That doesn't look like a knife.
Barely penetrated the skin.
Wait a sec.
This...
is so incredible.
I think I know what happened.
I gotta make a call.
Thanks for the heads-up,
Catherine.
Nicky, I'm sorry.
There's just been a hell of
a lot going on around here.
New boss needed an office;
I gave him yours, I'm sorry.
You know he's growing
'shrooms in there, right?
They're supposed
to be medicinal.
Medicinal?
Don't get me started.
This is great.
Ray Langston screws up,
and we all gotta pay for it.
Awesome. This is
really fair.
Hey, guys.
Morgan.
Good to see you.
(phone ringing)
Um, that's my phone.
Excuse me.
I'm sorry, Morgan.
Good to see you.
How's it going?
You know... it's going.
You're not leaving?
No, no. I'm just, uh,
moving offices, I guess.
I heard about Langston.
Yeah. Yeah.
So what are you doing here?
I'm due for
a little Vegas action.
STOKES:
Oh, well...
all the action's at
the Strip, it's not
around here. Hey, Greg.
Come here, I want you
to meet somebody.
Morgan Brody,
this is Greg Sanders.
Greg was our L.A. expert
on the Haskell case.
Oh, right!
Great work.
Good to put a face
with the name.
You don't look
like a history nerd.
Neither do you.
I mean the nerd part.
Not that you are a nerd.
Or that there's anything
wrong with being a nerd.
Right.
I'll catch you guys later.
Yeah.
That's Ecklie's daughter?
Don't even think about
it, I'm telling you.
I finally found him under the
tracks at the Palermo station.
PHILLIPS:
Hmm, good shape,
considering.
I do love a good "octopsy."
Hodges, please.
Sorry.
(sighs)
COD is... hearts failure.
They have three.
Looks like the bullet
perforated the bronchial hearts
and lodged right in the
oxygenating heart.
...four, five, six.
Right twist. Nine mil.
Consistent with
the cowboy's Beretta.
(bullet clinks)
Oh, my.
Looks like human
tissue on the beak.
I think he bit somebody.
Somebody's mother.
That would explain
Mrs. Drake's paralysis.
Huh.
Got something you like?
I do. Look at our
missing couple.
I think I can explain
why Señor Ocho
was on that tram.
Look at the tattoo:
vintage diving helmet.
Japanese woman.
Octopus.
Two words:
shokushu goukan.
Tentacle erotica.
Ancient Japanese secret.
Men will pay money
to watch women...
Make love with
Señor Ocho?
Ew.
Oh, come on.
Eight times the pleasure,
eight times the fun.
I don't get it.
So... Red Dress had
Octopus on a leash?
No. No, as a matter of fact...
in her purse.
Purse looks full going in,
empty coming out.
Let me, uh... let me
ask you something real quick.
I'm kind of new in town.
Do you know any good
shokushu goukan parlors?
♪ ♪
SeaWorld's closed.
So you want to tell me about
your little tram ride adventure
last night?
I wasn't on a tram.
I was in a tub.
So, that's not you
fleeing a crime scene?
I didn't feel like getting shot.
BRASS: No, who does?
I don't feel like getting shot.
You know, I've
always wondered.
What do you feed those guys?
Crayfish, mostly.
Ah.
Claude actually had a thing
for shrimp.
He was fussy.
But he was worth it.
So Claude was on the tram?
I'm sorry for your loss.
So you found Claude?
Forget about Claude. Okay?
Let's talk about the guy
with the knife in his gut.
Look, I had nothing to do
with that.
Oh, well,
maybe your boyfriend did.
Boyfriend? You mean the psycho
with the blade?
Look, one second he's drooling
all over me,
shoving a room key in my...
Next second,
he's got a knife out.
...like magic. I'll
show you a magic room...
Hey.
(groans)
The poor guy
in the baseball jersey.
Do you still
have that hotel key?
That depends on what you're
gonna charge me with.
We're gonna charge
you with... (stammers)
Wh-What?
(sighs)
Do you want to see Claude again?
Yes.
I can make that happen,
but we'll need
to see that hotel key.
Okay?
Okay.
The room's registered
to Tom Finnerty.
The victim?
Yeah.
Las Vegas Police.
Open up.
Got the knife.
Suicide.
(snorts, snores)
Whoa...
(gasps)
Am I dead?
I swear to God,
I didn't kill my brother.
Tom was my brother.
I'd never hurt my b...
Why would I hurt my brother?
You do know that we
found the murder weapon
in your hotel room, right?
With your fingerprints
all over it?
Look, man, my brother
only had a few months left.
He was dying of
lung cancer, so...
I was giving him
a make-a-wish weekend.
It says here, Jimmy,
that you served two years
in juvie for auto theft,
and two in Ely for assault,
and that you're currently
out on parole
from Corcoran
for another assault.
And do you know that it's
a violation of your parole
to be in Vegas?
JIMMY: All that's true, except
the part about killing Tom.
I don't even know
how it happened.
We were heading to the tram.
And I see this
hot Asian chick
in a tight red dress...
Tom catches up to me and, uh,
he's got this friggin' knife
sticking out of him,
and so I pulled it out.
Then the guy in the cowboy hat
started shooting.
Tommy was dying. Um...
Nothing I could do.
Well, if I really loved
my brother,
I would have stayed with him.
I wouldn't have just
left him alone to die like that.
You're right.
Tommy deserved better.
A lot better.
(sobbing)
(sighs)
This is embarrassing.
Sorry.
Here you go.
Why don't you take that?
I'll tell you what.
Why don't we back up
and tell me how this whole day
started, all right?
It was a 51's game, right?
We, um... we both played
in high school, and...
Tommy was a hell
of a first baseman.
Yeah, I played in
college little bit.
I wasn't very good.
What about you?
Were you any good?
He's not playing good cop
right now, is he?
No. That's what
I'm talking about.
They all think
they're social workers.
They are good, though.
Yeah, but that's not the point.
I know. I know.
JIMMY: ...medication,
and, uh...
I like Nick.
...I went down to play
a little black jack.
I'd hate to lose him.
(speaking Norwegian)
Hey.
Oh, hey, I uh, ran
into Morgan Brody today.
She's really...
What are you watching, Greg?
Norwegian YouTube.
So, our Shar-Pei Doe
got me thinking.
He's a deer hunter, right?
Like a long line of Sanders men.
Don't worry, the bucks
stop with me.
But meet my cousin Jerker
from Nesoddtangen.
He's got this deer-skinning
technique that uses
an air compressor to separate
the skin from the muscle.
That is disgusting.
Well, that also
might be our COD.
Our vic had a puncture
wound in his torso.
I'm thinking he was "Hulked."
You mean like inflated.
It's possible. Probably
take one big-ass air compressor.
You know, you and your cousin
Jerker may be on to something.
It's Jerker.
The trace report
on the black residue
we found on our deer hater--
polyalphaolefin.
It's a lubricating oil.
It also kind of sounds
Norwegian.
It's found in commercial
air compressors,
like the ones they use in truck
stops to fill big rig tires.
And I think there's a truck stop
a few miles
from our crime scene.
Your jacket
is impressive.
So, uh, what
was it this time?
I think you know.
Langston fallout...
it had a far reach.
There are hundreds of other
crime labs in this country.
This one's the best.
It's your call.
Hey, Nick.
Let me talk to
you for a second.
Yeah, sure.
Look, I don't know how things
were done before I got here,
and I like to think of myself
as an easygoing
kind of guy.
Mm-hmm.
I like it that way.
But when I ask for something,
I expect to get it.
Oh, yeah, I'm sorry.
I'm still working on my field
investigation report.
I don't see a pen in your hand.
All right, man,
I'll give you the report,
but it's not gonna have
the right answers in it.
It's a start. It's a form of
communication,
and I shouldn't have to chase
you down here to get it.
Yeah, you're right.
It won't happen again.
Oh, it probably will.
Hey, college baseball, huh?
Yeah, how'd you know that?
Well, I watched you get
all cozy with our suspect.
Why don't we talk about
the tram ride, instead?
I was a pretty lousy
baseball player.
I think that'd be a good idea.
Okay, 73 seconds
station to station.
And in that time frame,
Tom Finnerty is stabbed.
We assume the cowboy sees Jimmy
with the knife,
(gunshots)
pulls out his gun.
Security guard sees that,
pulls out his.
Bullets start flying.
Both the security guard
and the cowboy get hit.
And the mom's collateral damage.
Now, that part is in my report.
I'm glad to hear that. Okay.
So we know what they did.
We don't need them anymore.
Adios, folks.
That leaves the stabbing.
But now, you don't think that
your best friend Jimmy did it.
Red Dress said
Jimmy stabbed his brother.
Jimmy said he was only trying
to pull the knife out.
Personally, I think that
she probably saw the knife
in Jimmy's hand
and just filled in the rest.
Okay, I'll buy it.
Red Dress can go.
You're Jimmy.
Yeah, and I see my brother with
a knife sticking out of his gut.
I got to help him.
So, I run over.
I go to pull the knife out,
and that's when
all hell breaks loose.
The shooting starts as the tram
pulls to a stop.
Self-preservation
kicks in.
As I'm running out...
I deposit two blood drops
on the door here from the knife.
And we know that
that's Tom's blood.
Yeah.
Hang on now, wait a second.
There's a third blood drop here,
and it's different
than the others.
Come take a look at this.
Looks like they were all
deposited at the same time.
But this droplet
has a ghost ring.
Blood drops dry
from the outside in.
It takes at least 30 seconds
to form a ghost ring.
If this blood came off the
knife as Jimmy was running out,
there wouldn't have been enough
time to form a ring.
73 seconds
is plenty of time.
And the only way that could
have happened if it was
on the door before
the tram ride even started.
I don't think there's any way
my old pal Jimmy
could have done this.
Well done, Nick.
We're still looking
for a killer.
Well, we do have a witness with
the best seat in the house.
Oh, yeah, we do, don't we?
Emmett, you're doing great.
Okay, so you sat down.
Tram started to fill up.
I'm the guy in the 51's jersey.
Come walking on.
Then what?
Did you see anyone
try to hurt him?
No.
Did anyone bump into him?
All right, uh... what...
Hey...
Emmett?
Oh, Emmett, what
are you doing, buddy?
Where you going?
You all right?
What's going on?
I did something bad when I was
going to the tram.
Oh, okay.
Well, I-I bet
it wasn't that bad.
Some money fell
out of a man's pocket.
It was right... right
here on the floor.
I took it.
Okay.
Can you look for him
and give it back?
Sure.
Why don't you give
it to me, Emmett?
And I'll make sure it gets back
to its rightful owner, okay?
Now let me ask
you something.
Did that belong to the
man in the 51's jersey?
No. He was smaller.
Smaller. All right. Well...
Well, when people
help the police,
they always
get a reward.
So I'm gonna make
sure that you get
a brand-new one-
hundred-dollar bill.
All right?
And right now, I want you to
go over, and that nice lady--
she's gonna buy you
an ice-cream cone.
All right?
If this blood's Tom Finnerty's,
he was definitely stabbed
before he got on that tram.
But he couldn't have been
stabbed on the platform here
or in the casino,
or we would've
seen that on the
surveillance cameras.
You know,
I'm thinking they don't have
surveillance in bathrooms.
Oh, yeah.
I think we just found where
Tom Finnerty was stabbed.
SIDLE:
It's quite an operation
you run, Mr. Gibbs.
Service over 30 trucks a day.
Found this picture on your wall.
Who's your
hunting pal?
That's Del Hartley.
Have you seen
Del lately?
Think he's
on a fishing trip.
Nice air compressor.
Who has the key?
Me.
You forgot
to clean it.
Tested positive for human blood.
SIDLE:
I got a feeling
that the DNA will be
a match to Del.
How about you?
When you were cleaning up,
you missed a button.
It was an accident.
I swear.
We had a deer come to.
It happens.
Del tried to restrain it,
but he forgot
that the deer had a weapon.
The deer was
carrying?
Yeah. Ten points.
Del, I'm gonna
pop some holes in here.
Del gets cut,
and he's worried about
rabies or-or deer worm
or something.
He grabs the nozzle
to clean the wound.
Seemed to make sense.
Oh, God!
It got stuck
with the nozzle on.
Air's blowing in his body; his
body's popping off his muscles.
And I yank the thing out,
and he's dead.
He was my friend,
but I got a... a business.
I can't have dead bodies
lying around.
And, uh, it was...
it was out of season.
I think poaching is probably
the least of your problems
right now.
Yeah.
DNA confirms that
the blood on the money
as well as the stall door
was Tom Finnerty's.
And I went through the ID logs
from all of the Palermo's ATMs.
At 12:53 a.m.,
our bloody hundred was spit out
from Tom's account.
(phone beeps)
That was right before
he got on the tram.
Hold on a sec.
All right.
Print came back
to an Allen Krick.
Why do I know
that guy?
Because I talked to him.
He was in
the next tram car.
BRASS:
Krick is in the wind.
The address he gave is bogus.
We're checking the hotels now.
I found
an interesting connection
between Krick
and Jimmy Finnerty.
They were partners in crime.
They were busted in a chop shop
scam in Tahoe in '07.
Krick got two to five;
Jimmy got the hell out of town.
Took the money and ran.
Of course he couldn't
stay out of trouble.
When did Krick get out?
He was paroled from NCC
five days ago.
Thank you.
I'm sorry, but NCC?
What...?
It's the correctional facility
in Carson City.
Okay.
Which is exactly where his day
started out yesterday.
We were able to obtain
Krick's phone records.
He had a long day,
made quite the drive.
Carson City at noon.
Yerington by 2:00.
Now, that's when
he first called Jimmy.
Went straight
to voice mail.
About 4:00, he was in Hawthorne.
And then by 5:00,
he was all the way down
in Indian Springs.
Called again
and straight to voice mail.
Now, the last
hit was at
a cell phone tower
on Flamingo Road.
That's just four blocks
from the Golden Nugget.
Where Jimmy was staying.
Right.
WILLOWS:
He drives all that way,
but when Krick
finally gets here,
he kills the brother.
Why?
What are you looking at?
The Big Dipper?
The last thing Tom Finnerty saw
before he died:
his brother.
Let me, let me try this.
Okay, so--
Oh, yi.
Head rush.
Okay.
Tom's dying of cancer,
and yet he flies 3,000 miles
to be with his screwup brother.
He gets stabbed, and he
walks another 300 feet
just so he can
be with him at the end.
So, where does Krick
fit into all this walking?
Jimmy pulls a knife out of Tom
trying to save his life,
and Tom pulls cash out of
an ATM to try to save Jimmy.
I'm with her.
Where's this going?
Krick's phone records, right?
Follow it all the way through.
All day long,
from Carson City
to Vegas,
Krick's calling Jimmy, right?
Over and over, getting closer.
Obviously, he wants something.
That's why he's at the Palermo,
why he's
shadowing Jimmy.
But-but Tom is with Jimmy.
And what did Jimmy tell you
about-about big brother?
That he spent a lifetime
looking out for little brother.
Yeah. See, I think
Tom saw Krick first.
And given
Jimmy's past,
you got to figure little
bro owes Krick big money.
So, Tom gets money out of the
ATM, and when Jimmy's distracted
by a hot red dress, he follows
Krick into the men's room.
Hey, look, let me
make this all go away.
I don't need
your money.
I need the last five
years of my life back.
You stay out of it.
This is between
Jimmy and me!
Now it's between
you and me.
Bitch, get out
of the way!
Hey, hey, hey.
(groaning)
(panting)
Oh, man.
He was trying to clean up
another one of my messes.
What about Krick?
You know where he is?
I'm not telling you that.
I roll, he rolls,
I do serious time.
I'm not, I'm not
doing that again.
Okay, so you're gonna cover for
the guy who killed your brother.
Who died stepping
up for you.
Don't you think
it's time
you stepped up for him
just a little bit here?
Krick's got a girl
in Boulder City.
Thanks.
Thank you, Emmett.
That was a really good thing
you did.
Make sure you spend it
all in one place now.
You like basketball?
Yeah.
Well, I got a,
I got a boy,
little bigger than you.
Plays college ball here.
Maybe the next time
you and your mom are in town,
we could go to a game together.
You like that?
Okay.
Brass picked up Krick.
Genius still had
the blood money on him.
That's real smart.
Yeah, I called
Jimmy's probation officer.
Tried to get him
to cut Jimmy a little slack.
This will be his
third strike.
Call him back.
What do you mean?
I mean that we are doing things
by the book now.
What book, Catherine?
I'm just trying to
help the guy out.
You're not listening, Nick.
There are no more
under-the-table deals,
no more going rogue,
no more personal vendettas,
no more L.A.
Now, what does this
have to do with L.A.?
I wouldn't change anything
about what I did there.
I would!
I'm not in charge anymore,
because this is our problem.
We lead with our hearts
instead of our heads.
And then we justify it
after the fact.
Why you so pissed off?
I got demoted, Nick!
I got demoted!
I mean, you're setting up shop
here in the break room,
and D.B. Moonbeam
is running the show.
And you know what, maybe he's
just what this team needed.
STOKES:
I disagree. It's not
what this team needed,
it's what Ecklie
and the sheriff...
Hey, sweetheart,
I'm just leaving.
Yeah. How was your day?
WILLOWS: You always blame
other people for what
you're responsible for.
Stop with the excuses.
Don't give me
that, Catherine!
Think the team is
really starting to...
Well, you can add me
to that list.
...starting to gel.
Honey, I'm gonna,
um, I'm gonna go.
I need another hour.
I'm sorry.
19 years is a very long time
to be doing this job.
What are you trying to say?
What am I trying to say?
Well, I'm saying that this team
has to move on.
We got to get back
to what we do best.
And if you can't
handle that,
then, you know,
there's the door.
I know where the door is.
I've used it a couple times.
(cell phones ringing, beeps)