That's it?
(chuckles): All right,
I'll take it from here.
Okay, Grandpa.
Okay.
Time for bed, Katie.
Mommy, I'm not tired.
Boy, I am.
You need to listen
to your mommy, Kaitlyn.
We're gonna have
lots of fun while you're here.
So you got to get
lots of rest.
And that goes
for your grandpa, too.
What? Yes.
Yes, definitely.
Grandma's the boss;
you know that.
And we're gonna have
so much fun,
we're gonna go
to the lake,
we're gonna see puppets,
we're gonna go to the museums.
Ice cream?
Ice cream, yes.
Tons of ice cream.
Thanks, Dad.
Emergency numbers
are on the fridge.
And we're not gonna
be that late.
Okay.
Right?
Right.
MAN:
I came to this town
with five bucks in my pocket
and big dreams.
Las Vegas was different
back then.
It was all about the hustle,
all about scoring and moving on.
And some guys did that.
But me...
I planted my roots
right here in the desert.
I got married, had kids,
got married again...
(laughter)
Olivia, Conrad,
I-I didn't know you guys were...
No, Olivia and I...
we're just friends.
Good friends.
Right.
Like us.
Not quite.
More champagne?
Yes. Mother?
Nice to see you,
Barbara.
You, too. I know
you're usually his date
at these functions.
Yeah,
but people started to talk.
Well, uh, so much for
the Russell family mantra, huh?
Separation of
home and work?
Well, no, it's still in effect.
I'm pretending I'm not here.
MAN:
Ladies and gentlemen,
I give you my good friend,
the current and future
Sheriff of Las Vegas,
Sheriff Liston!
Didn't like the speech?
No, guy giving it.
Gilmore loves playing
the "self-made man."
Truth is, he started
his empire running
a sports book
for "made men."
RUSSELL: Well, it looks like
he cleaned up his act, then?
So he says.
Undersheriff, it's good
to see you here tonight.
You remember
David Winnock, my
money man, right?
Putting together
fundraising
for the Vegas Silver
Strikes' new arena.
GILMORE:
Oh, yeah. What can
I say, you know?
Ex-hockey player;
I love my hockey team.
Well,
that project's not approved yet,
Jack, you know that.
Yeah, well, the city has
their time line, I got mine.
Speaking of which,
I see Councilman Romano.
Hey, enjoy the
free drinks, guys.
WOMAN:
Since I took office
four years ago,
crime in Las Vegas is down!
Allow me to share
a few stats with you.
In the past four years...
(applause)
prostitution is down by 32%.
Drug offenses--
all are down by more than 40%!
In the past four years,
murder down 28%.
Assault down 35%.
Rape down 48%.
(screams)
The numbers are good,
but they can be better.
I ask you all tonight...
for yourselves,
for your families,
for Las Vegas,
give me four more years!
(applause)
RUSSELL:
That was fun.
Let's do that again
in about four years.
Oh... (laughs)
(beeping)
I got a text.
From Maya.
Aw, Katie's not asleep.
She's waiting for her
grandpa to come home.
Aw...
Let's not disappoint her.
Hey.
What happened to
the Hodges clan?
I sent them home.
But our night's not over yet.
What do you mean?
We got a situation.
Triple.
I'll explain to Katie.
All right, let's roll.
Actually, we walk. Crime
scene's just down the alley.
Hey. I'm sorry.
(whispers):
It's okay.
Detective Moreno.
Undersheriff. You know
my partner, Mike Crenshaw.
Undersheriff.
Care to tell CSI's
Russell and Brody
what you told me?
Uh, Mike and I
have been working
undercover, a drug op.
Our target is a dealer
named Donny Price.
Small-time hood,
big-time scumbag.
Not anymore.
We had a buy
set up here tonight.
Found him and his bodyguard
shot in the head.
Yeah, the
girlfriend's
dead, too.
Drugs and cash gone.
Sounds like
a textbook drug rip-off.
I agree.
What-what's the situation?
This is our situation.
Who is she?
ECKLIE:
Veronica Gilmore.
Jack Gilmore's wife.
As in... our friend of
the sheriff, Jack Gilmore?
Yep.
Whoa.
So much for statistics.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
Nice dress.
(laughs)
Yeah? Thanks.
Got an I.D. on the bodyguard.
Alonso Seal.
Doesn't like he was
much of a bodyguard.
BRODY:
Couldn't even get his gun out.
No sign of forced entry.
Suggests he knew the gunman.
STOKES:
And it looks like
Mr. Price here got caught
with his pants down.
Beat in the kneecap
before he was
put out of his misery.
Working theory:
our bad guy
steals the drugs...
makes a break
for the door.
Shoe impressions are indistinct.
There's no discernable
tread pattern.
Hey.
Come over here and
take a look at this.
What do you see?
BRODY:
Impressions end at the doorway,
but he didn't track
any blood outside.
The guy was
wearing booties.
Just like us.
Suggests planning,
premeditation.
Mm-hmm.
You know, the one thing
I don't think he
planned for...
What's that?
Eyewitness in the bathroom.
(camera shutter clicks)
What can you tell me?
I've never seen
anything like this.
I can't get a liver temp.
Fin, I can't
even find her liver.
That's really weird.
Yeah.
You know, for a drug rip-off,
somebody went
to an awful lot of trouble
to silence her.
I mean, they could've
just shot her,
like the other two.
Last call went out at 9:07
to her husband,
Jack Gilmore.
Lasted four seconds.
GILMORE:
I met Veronica
when I was, uh...
going through my divorce.
It was a low point
in my life, and she...
she saved me.
Even back then,
she, uh...
was drinking a little too much,
partied too hard.
So I've just spent
the last year trying to...
trying to save her.
So you knew that
your wife was...
having an affair
with Donny Price?
She left about four months ago.
Shacking up with the guy.
It's hard for me
to even say, you know.
Jack, I'm so sorry.
One more question.
When was the last time
you spoke to your wife?
I don't know, it was
at least a week ago.
Uh, minus seven days.
Apparently, Mr.
Gilmore's wife
called him tonight, around
the same time that she died.
RUSSELL:
Mr. Gilmore, CSI Finlay.
Couldn't have been
much of a conversation.
It lasted about four seconds.
That's 'cause there
wasn't any conversation.
My wife had
the unfortunate habit
of drunk-dialing me
and hanging up.
Assuming that
it was your wife
and not someone calling
to tell you that she was dead.
Excuse me?
Finlay, you're out of line.
Let's clear it up right now.
No need to get a warrant.
Let's look at your phone.
Am I a suspect?
RUSSELL: No,
sir, you're not.
No, we're still just
gathering information.
I'm sure you'll...
you'll work with us
when the time comes.
Let's get you
a ride home.
Always the politician.
Boy, you never learn, do you?
Really.
Looks like a nine-mil.
Same as the others.
ROBBINS:
And the stippling indicates
close-range shots.
Mr. Price... sustained an
additional GSW to his knee.
Skull fracture suggests
he was beaten
with a blunt object,
like a pistol.
Somebody enjoyed their work.
Even more so
with our female victim.
C.O.D. is massive
internal hemorrhaging.
Now I know why David
couldn't get liver temp.
Looks like soup.
She was hit
so hard and so often,
her internal organs
disintegrated.
I did find
a fleck embedded
in her skin.
Appears to be some
sort of synthetic.
SIDLE:
We'll get it to Hodges.
We'll see if
we can identify the weapon.
The undersheriff is
a friend of mine,
and I like him, and I
like that you like him.
In fact,
I'm so glad about that
that I think you and he
should go on a date
by yourselves.
(whispers): Oh, yeah.
Uh, Mother, Mother,
I... Hello?
I can't... I'm losing you.
Yes. I-I'll call you back.
(exhales)
Any news on
the fleck?
It's a work in progress.
Oh, yeah, well, text me
when you got something.
Hey, um...
how are you doing
with this whole my-mom-
your-dad thing?
I mean,
who knew when we had the
"Meet the Parents" dinner
that our parents
would actually meet?
Let's just hope they don't drag
us on any more dates with them.
Or a wedding.
I mean...
these things keep up,
and we could end up
as some sort of Bizarro
Brady Bunch brother and sister.
Maybe we should start dating
and throw a wrench
into the works.
I-I can't.
I was joking.
But why can't you?
Let's just say...
that my trip to Italy
was life-changing.
(beeping)
Ah. The fleck has spoken.
Doc was right--
it is synthetic.
Polyparaphenylene
terephthalamide.
Kevlar combined with
aluminum and carbon.
RUSSELL:
Sounds like an aluminum bat.
Very... old-school, like the
Goodfellas or something.
Yeah, guy walks into
a drug den and takes
care of business.
Pops the first two guys,
silences the witness.
He did more
than silence her.
Autopsy shows that
Veronica Gilmore sustained
more than 50 blows
to her head and body.
Look, I know you think
that Jack Gilmore's
behind this, but...
No, no, I don't think
he's behind it.
I think he did it.
Oh, come on, whoa,
stop, listen to me.
Boy, you don't learn, do you?
What?
Let's not repeat history here.
Please.
I'm not talking about history.
I am talking about this case.
So am I.
FINLAY:
Good. It is no coincidence
that Jack Gilmore's wife
was murdered at that motel.
Okay, all right, all right.
I will give you
that the guy might have
hired somebody to kill his wife,
but he was not at that motel.
No, no, he was at the
fund-raiser, right?
RUSSELL:
Where every major figure
in Vegas law enforcement
was present.
They all saw him.
I saw him.
You only think you saw him.
RUSSELL:
What am I looking at?
FINLAY:
Jack Gilmore
in the alley between
the casino where the
fund-raiser was held,
and the motel where
his wife was found.
9:07.
That's right around
the time of the murders.
Two minutes after he gave
the podium to the sheriff.
Did you get all this
from his phone records?
Yeah, I did, and I
got a warrant from
Brass. Don't worry.
I also got the sheriff's speech,
and I timed it.
18 minutes and six seconds.
Plenty of time to slip away.
I saw Gilmore at that reception
right after the speech.
Not a hair on his
head was out of place.
FINLAY: Mm.
So you really think
that he could commit
three gruesome murders
in an 18-minute time span.
Get in, get out,
get back to the party.
Well, you know,
there's only way
to figure out
if that's even possible.
Yeah, you guys need
to take a walk.
STOKES:
How we doing?
Uh, 36 seconds
from the ballroom
to the kitchen to
the loading dock.
Killer's moving
at a deliberate pace,
but doesn't want
to attract any attention.
Yeah. He's taking his own
sweet time, just like us.
What's that supposed to mean?
Well, I think it's a good
idea that we take a walk,
but shouldn't somebody
be putting pressure
on Jack Gilmore,
like, right now?
Hey, I'm down, but do you think
D.B.'s gonna go for it?
No way.
So,
tell me, what is the deal
with you two?
What is all this, "don't repeat
history" stuff about anyway?
Well, you know that he
fired me in Seattle.
Really? I heard
he asked for your resignation.
(laughing):
Yeah. What's the difference?
Yeah, well, what's the story?
Well, there was this
girl, Janet Warren.
Mm-hmm.
And she worked for this really
powerful venture capital,
Tom Cooley.
He was a real
son of a bitch.
And one day, she
went missing.
We never found her.
I had hair,
carpet fibers and semen,
and all I needed
was Cooley's DNA.
And what, you couldn't get it?
Oh, I got it.
I just couldn't test it.
Oh, why not?
Oh, some BS technicality.
It was really that Cooley had
very powerful friends, and
they protected him.
And Russell?
Russell.
Russell was Russell.
Huh.
What was his sage advice?
Oh.
"It's not who you know.
It's what you can prove."
Yes. Live to fight another day.
That's always a great thing
to tell the victims' families.
Exactly.
Been there.
We're at two
minutes, 40.
Show time.
STOKES:
Gilmore shoots the bodyguard.
FINLAY:
Two minutes, 43 seconds.
STOKES:
Gilmore then takes
care of Price.
FINLAY:
Three minutes, 18 seconds.
STOKES:
And now, the main event.
(crying):
No!
STOKES:
Gilmore beat his wife Veronica
over 50 times.
FINLAY
Even savoring the moment,
eight minutes, tops.
So, what, that
gives him ten minutes
to make it back
to the party?
Yup.
Yeah, but not enough time
to change your tuxedo.
Mm.
I mean, look at this.
There must have been
blood flying around
all over the place.
Yeah, he must have worn
something over his tuxedo.
He must have gotten
rid of it somewhere.
Let's suit up,
retrace our steps.
Okay, your turn.
Come on.
What happened to chivalry?
It died
about five dumpsters ago.
(garbled radio transmission)
(grunts)
(chuckles)
Oh, so gross.
Yeah.
Ew! Creamed corn.
Hmm.
Think I found something.
What do we have here?
Oversized warm-ups
with blood on 'em.
Easy to pull over a tuxedo.
Hey, I think
I found the murder weapon.
Kevlar, carbon fiber.
It's not a baseball bat.
(camera shutter clicks)
It's a composite shaft
of a hockey stick.
(sighs)
With the logo, Las Vegas
Silver Strikes on it.
Same logo on the warm-up.
The Silver Strikes
are Gilmore's hockey team.
Hope he's got a good defense.
GILMORE:
Let's go! Keep it
on the edge, guys.
Take us to the net.
Come on, keep it moving.
(grunt)
Man-to-man!
You're supposed
to be playing zone,
fellas. Come on!
BRASS:
Looks like somebody
needs a time-out.
Our practices are closed
to the public.
Oh, we're not
the public.
We have a warrant
to search the arena.
I get the picture now.
This is harassment!
This is crap.
The scope of the warrant
is for the arena.
What about Gilmore's office?
His car?
His home?
Well, we're getting there.
One step at a time, Finn.
Yeah, I'd say
that was good advice.
We need his DNA,
because we cannot
tie him to the warm-ups
without an exemplar.
Jack Gilmore is still
just a person of interest here.
He is not a suspect yet.
Friends with benefits.
I'm gonna pretend
I didn't hear that.
I know what
you did in Seattle.
Walked into a black-tie event,
walked out
with Tom Cooley's
champagne glass in your purse,
illegally obtaining
his DNA evidence.
I think you need
to remind your CSI
that that's not how
we do things here.
Oh, I think she heard you.
(Stokes sighs)
Kevlar,
aluminum and
carbon fiber.
Looks like
our murder weapon.
Yeah.
It's the wrong
brand, though.
All these players have
the same type of duffel,
same team warm-ups.
Yeah.
Our killer did
his shopping here.
Reb-2.
Now, we're talking.
Ooh. Hold that for a second.
There's an extra blade in here.
But the stick you found
in the Dumpster was
missing a blade, right?
Was it broken off?
No.
It wasn't broken
off, actually.
It was removed.
See, these aren't your Papa
Olaf's sticks we're talking
about here, buddy.
Like everything else,
hockey's gone hi-tech.
Sticks are composite now.
Blades can be switched
on and off pretty easily.
We found scratches
inside the throat
of the stick
our killer used.
Check it out.
Now, is it just me, or do those
markings look very similar?
Whose locker is that from?
Peter Gagne.
BRASS:
Gagne's been benched
a few times before.
He's got a rap sheet.
Assault, gambling debts.
But also an alibi.
Oh, yeah?
What's that?
Dinner with the wife and kids.
Okay, how does he explain his
stick ending up a murder weapon?
Now that's an interesting story.
The equipment manager
for the team is Dominic Bruno.
Now, why does that
name sound familiar?
Well, he was a leg-breaker
for Lou Gedda
back in the day
when Jack Gilmore
was more friendly
with the mob than the sheriff.
You know, if Gilmore
is such a changed man,
why's he have a guy
like Bruno on the payroll?
MAN:
I figured
you'd be showing up
on my door sooner or later.
I'd prefer sooner.
But I'm a patient man, Dominic.
And guys like you are always
making the same mistakes.
Same could be said for you.
I heard about
the boss's wife.
'Course you probably think
I had something to do with it?
You know, you took the words
right out of my mouth.
And the evidence
right out of that locker.
You're losing your touch, Dom.
It's not your style.
Trying to pin it
on a down-on-his-luck
hockey player with obligations.
I had nothing to do with it,
and I can prove it.
Oh, yeah?
How you going to do that?
Oh, like I said,
I figured I'd be seeing you,
so, a few months back,
I recorded a conversation.
See, you're not the only
one that came around here
looking for the old Dom.
GILMORE:
Hey, Dom. It's Jack.
You give some thought
to our last conversation?
BRUNO:
Yeah, boss, I did, and
I don't think you're going
to like the answer.
JACK:
Come on, Dom. You owe me.
When you got out of the joint
and couldn't get a job,
I was the only one
who hooked you up.
I took you in
when all of our old friends
had turned their backs on you.
You said someday
you'd repay me.
If I ever needed anything,
anything, you'd be there.
Scumbags like Donny Price
deserve to die.
So, I'm asking you,
I'm begging you,
do this for me.
BRUNO:
Boss, uh,
that guy you knew
before I went in the joint--
I'm not the same guy anymore.
I've changed.
JACK:
You're not leaving me a lot
of options, Dom.
I think this is the place
where you lean over
and give your client a little
whisper in the ear there.
I can do my own
talking, thanks.
Yeah, we heard.
All right, look,
I reached out to Dom, okay?
But that's all I did.
He and I go a
long way back.
Yeah, we know.
All your old pals,
like Gedda and McKeen,
are all either dead or in jail.
Yeah, and there's a reason
I'm neither.
Look...
I loved my wife,
and I wanted to protect her.
But when Dom said, "Hey,
I'm not that guy anymore,"
I realized that
I wasn't, either.
No, I think you realize
that now's the time
you were gonna
take matters in your own hands.
RUSSELL:
The evidence is kind of
stacking up.
Hockey stick swiped from the
locker of one of your players.
Team warm-ups with your wife's
DNA on the outside,
your DNA on the inside.
Also on the inside is
a little black thread,
which I'm pretty sure will match
your tuxedo.
See, I think you planned
this whole thing four months ago
when your wife, Veronica,
left you for her drug dealer.
You planned it right down
to the perfect alibi.
When all of Las Vegas
law enforcement
was at a party passing the hat
for the sheriff.
(door opens)
FINLAY:
Sorry to interrupt.
I have a
question for you.
Oh, I thought maybe you
could use a fresh cup.
Your, uh, cell phone
put you in the alley.
What exactly
were you doing there?
If you weren't on
your way to the motel
to kill your wife?
I was meeting a guy.
BRASS:
A guy?
That's the best you can do?
(laughs)
His name's Bobby Connor, okay?
He's a labor consultant,
works for Turlington, L.L.P.
Usually, we meet
at Al's Diner.
He's, um, helping me out with
the soccer arena project.
So, this Bobby Connor
can vouch for you?
(sighs)
Actually, he never showed up.
Oh, gee,
that's not good.
I checked on his alibi.
There's no Bobby Connor.
There's not consulting firm,
Turlington, L.L.P.
Looks like
your boy's going down.
And it looks like CSI Finlay
was right.
Thought you'd be
a little happier about this.
Is there a butcher shop nearby?
I think there's one
over in the mini-mall
on Spring Mountain.
Great. Thanks.
Batter up.
We've got soup.
What's that?
That's liver soup.
Macerated like
Veronica Gilmore's organs.
He didn't do it.
That took me 54 blows
and all of my strength
to make that soup happen.
Well, how's this let Gilmore
off the hook?
I mean, he's a big guy, right?
Ex-hockey player.
Who now has ALS.
Whoa.
He's been keeping it hidden.
His lawyers were very happy
to turn over his
medical records,
which say that he
has lost over 40%
of his upper-body strength.
Which is why
you brought him coffee.
Yeah, he couldn't even lift
his arms beyond his shoulders.
Remember, he used two hands
to carry the cup.
I do.
All right, wait, whoa,
wait a second here.
Wh-What about the evidence?
We have his DNA on the warm-ups.
The killer must
have stolen them,
because Gilmore's got an
open locker at the arena
like everybody else.
Okay, what about the tuxedo
thread that Hodges found?
He ran it.
It does not match Gilmore's
tuxedo or any tuxedo.
The thread is nylon
with traces of neoprene.
Neoprene.
Like a wetsuit.
Yeah,
a protective shield
that our killer wore
under the warm-ups
to preserve Gilmore's DNA
and only Gilmore's DNA
while he was committing
the crimes.
So, if you think about it,
you've got the hockey stick,
the warm-ups, the phone call
from his wife's phone
to Gilmore in the alley,
while he's waiting for
the mysterious stranger.
The whole thing was a frame-up.
So,
if Gilmore's not our killer,
then who is?
And why set him up?
KAITLYN: Grandpa,
when are you coming home?
Grandma and I made cookies.
Want to see?
BARBARA:
Oatmeal raisin, your favorite.
Oh, wow.
Tell me you can resist these.
Uh, something tells me
desert's gonna have to wait?
I'm sorry, sweetheart.
I'll try to get home
by dinner time.
Don't worry,
you do what you have to do.
Right?
Yes.
Mwah. We'll see you soon.
Bye, Dad.
(chuckles)
Saturday night was fun.
It was really fun.
I didn't even hear you leave.
You didn't.
Hmm-mm. I hope that's not
an omen for the future.
Oh.
Oh, your boyfriend.
Yeah, yours, too.
Who's he with?
My boss.
He runs vice.
What's up?
Kimball's gonna do
the briefing.
Told us to go back
into the field.
Catch you later.
Bye.
LISTON:
So, we're not talking
about a husband killing
his wife anymore?
No, ma'am, but that is what
somebody wanted us to believe.
They took advantage
of Jack's marital problems,
set him up.
So, I guess
we're back to square one.
We're talking about drugs.
Which is why I asked
Lieutenant Kimball to join us.
He was in charge
of the undercover op
against Donny Price.
What do you got for us?
Price was
a mid-level distributor.
We had a confidential informant
inside the last four months.
We were getting closer
to IDing his supplier.
Four months?
That's about the same time
Veronica Gilmore...
Dumped her husband
for her drug dealer.
I guess we know who
your informant was,
right?
Veronica Gilmore?
She got popped for possession.
She made a deal;
only me and the D.A. knew.
I should have been
looped in on this.
'Cause Jack Gilmore's
your friend?
Because I'm your boss.
Well, we got
a lot bigger problems
than Jack Gilmore's
sullied reputation.
Why? What do you mean?
Dead C.I.,
blown undercover op.
We got a leak in our department.
Hey.
Hey, I'm just
running the bullets we pulled
out of Donny Price
and his bodyguard.
The whole thing's
crazy, right?
I mean, a frame job
this elaborate,
that makes you wonder
who's behind it.
Yeah, I heard the department
may be compromised.
We've been there before.
(beeping)
I don't believe it.
Looks like we're there again.
You texted me?
I think I may have just found
this Bobby Connor guy.
Brass checked out
Gilmore's story.
He said the guy
doesn't exist.
Well, Gilmore's been meeting
with somebody
at Al's Diner.
The ATM across the street
gave us a snapshot.
That guy was just here.
That's Lieutenant Paul Kimball.
He was running the undercover op
on Donny Price.
Seriously?
And if this is our
fictional Bobby Connor,
then he's the guy
who set up the meeting
in the alley with Gilmore.
Hey, Russell?
Yeah?
We need to have
a family meeting.
IBIS report came back
on the bullets
that killed Price
and his bodyguard.
Gun was traced back to a cop
who discharged the weapon
during a domestic disturbance
back in 2008,
but the case was tossed.
Weapon was returned
to the officer.
Hey, guys, where are we going
with this?
Who are we
talking about?
It's Jeffrey McKeen.
You got to be kidding me.
Who's Jeffrey McKeen?
RUSSELL:
Former undersheriff,
now serving life.
I read his file
when I first got here.
Yeah, he murdered
a good friend of mine,
CSI Warrick Brown.
He was
a good friend of all of ours.
So, if McKeen's in prison,
how does his gun
end up committing
all these murders?
He must have had
someone do it for him.
Yeah, but what does
he have to gain?
Yeah, I got an idea.
Didn't McKeen
take over Lou Gedda's turf?
Start running his drugs
and prostitution?
Yeah, before he went to prison.
So, maybe he hasn't stopped.
Like Gotti.
Godfathering from the inside.
If that's the case, then he's
got people working for him
on the outside.
People like Paul Kimball.
You asked me
to check him out.
Long before Lieutenant
Kimball ran Vice...
guess who his first partner was?
Jeffrey McKeen.
If Kimball has ties to
McKeen, then he's the one
who set up Gilmore;
he's our guy.
Yeah, so let's pick him up.
Undersheriff has eyes
on him right now.
No, no, no, let's just
keep eyes on him for now.
We got to play this smart.
Kimball's dirty, but we have
no idea how deep this goes.
So, you buy Kimball
as the shooter,
but not as the guy on
the outside calling the shots.
Kimball's an errand boy.
All we have to do is just see
if he can takes us
to whoever is calling the shots.
Let's bring McKeen in,
all right?
Shake him up
a little bit.
See who he reaches out to.
Russell, right?
You're the CSI that
Ecklie brought in
to right the ship.
How's that working out?
Great. How's prison
working out for you?
Eh, you know, I get by.
Must be hard.
The walls, the distance.
Hard for a guy who likes
to control things,
do things himself.
Just like you murdered Warrick.
Now come on,
you know I didn't
enjoy that, Stokes.
And Warrick
didn't give me a choice.
Is that what happened
with Donny Price
and Veronica Gilmore?
You know, I'd heard
Veronica had died.
Is that why I'm here?
Who told you that Gilmore
wanted his wife killed?
I don't know what
you're talking about.
You screwed up, McKeen.
Your people tried
to pin it on Gilmore,
but they used a gun that traced
right back to you.
Triple homicide.
So, you help us,
we help you
or it goes the other way.
I'm a lifer,
and you got nothing.
Oh, I don't know, we can get you
out of the general population.
Caged with all
those animals.
The cage is just fine.
You see, this
is the thing.
On the inside, I'm a cop.
I'm also
a cop-killer.
And those two bullets
that I put in your friend,
Warrick, well...
That made me a hero.
(stammering)
I'm gonna get some air
before I tear your head off.
Boy, he's got that
bad cop thing down.
Here's the deal.
I figure that you're providing
for your family
from behind bars, right?
Cash. One phone call
from me,
and your family
is living out of a car.
You leave my family
out of this, D.B.
Up to you, hotshot.
Sure hope Russell
knows what he's doing.
Everyone's got
some weakness.
Especially when it comes
to family.
MAN: Here's 200 grand cash;
McKeen wants you out of town
now.
It's all there;
you can count it.
KIMBALL:
I don't trust you.
I trust McKeen.
MAN:
Trust me when I tell you, if you
show your face, it'll be me
signing the contract.
I guess we just found
our shot-caller.
Yeah.
Russell really did
rattle McKeen's cage.
And Kimball led us
right to him.
Mm-hmm.
MAN: Your Vegas privileges
are pulled.
New passport,
first-class tickets.
You'll be having margaritas
by morning.
ECKLIE: I don't get it.
That's Gilmore's finance guy,
Winnock.
That's the last person
I would have expected.
We just got made.
(tires squealing)
(siren blares)
Drop the gun, Winnock.
Do it now!
I'm not McKeen.
I'm not going to prison.
He's dead.
Yeah, and we just
lost our best shot
at bringing McKeen down.
RUSSELL:
So, where are we
on Kimball?
Well, Moreno and Crenshaw found
his car abandoned,
but they they got him
on this watch list.
They said he never hopped
on that plane to Mexico.
$200,000-- he can go
pretty much anywhere he wants.
That's true.
We need to talk.
Another family meeting?
No, but family is the issue.
I got the autopsy results
on David Winnock.
C.O.D. was two gunshot wounds
to the chest.
Yeah, tell us
something we don't know.
No, keep reading--
the DNA part.
Hit on CODIS.
(hums)
Familial match.
Exactly.
David Winnock has 13 alleles
in common with Jeffrey McKeen.
Yeah, Winnock wasn't just
McKeen's shot-caller,
he was his son.
What could you possibly
want from me
that you don't already know?
His mother was a
dancer at Pigalle,
married to a pit
boss named Winnock.
The boy had his name
but my blood,
and as he got older,
I realized he had my heart, too.
I took care of both of them.
And when he grew up,
your boy took care
of business for you,
didn't he?
You're damn right.
He was my son.
He was family.
And now you know how it feels,
you son of a bitch.
ECKLIE:
Karma, Jeffrey.
Your son paid
for your sins.
And I know you're the one that
put the bullet in him, Conrad.
Hey,
you're the one that put
the target on his back.
If you want to blame someone,
look in the mirror.
Don't get
smug with me.
Your dead pal
was no saint.
I should have killed your punk
ass when I had the chance.
Yeah, you should have.
A real man would have.
Nick.
I might just get
that chance again.
I'll make sure
to clear my calendar.
The guy lives up
to his reputation.
Yeah.
You got anything?
Detectives went over
to Winnock's office.
Somebody beat us to it,
cleaned out his files.
Still nothing on Kimball.
Only five roads
lead out of Vegas.
We got eyes on
all of them.
If we can trust
our eyes anymore.
I mean, who knows how deep
this thing goes, how many cops
McKeen has
his hooks into?
Sheriff's called a
press conference.
Storm's coming.
Heads are going
to roll.
Yeah, hers may
be the first.
LISTON:
Thank you all for coming.
The district attorney and I
are here to announce that,
as of tomorrow morning,
a commission will begin
investigating allegations
of corruption, bribery,
and murder
within the Las Vegas
Police Department.
Four years ago, when I took
office, I promised change,
that the misdeeds of the
past would be just that.
What a load of crap.
The investigation
or the department?
Both.
I hate to
say it,
but the sheriff's right.
We went through
this four years ago
when McKeen was exposed,
and things got better.
Liston was elected,
made changes.
And now she's talking
about changes again.
That's what I'm saying.
Warrick's dead and McKeen's
still in business.
It's all just talk.
I vow
tonight
to clean up this department
once and for all.
No one will be above suspicion.
No one will get a free pass,
not even me.
Hey.
See this?
(sighs) You know, it's
going to get ugly.
Hope you don't regret
me dragging you here.
Hey, I make my own decisions.
Look, I-I know
the Gilmore case dragged up
a lot of stuff between us
from the past,
but,
for what it's worth,
in Seattle
I never said
you were wrong.
Well, then, why did you fire me?
Oh, come on,
you got to admit,
it was a little...
Just don't say that
it was complicated.
All right,
I won't say it.
I really hate you sometimes.
Hey, you know
what you should do?
Come on over to the house
tonight, have dinner with us.
Maya and Katie
are there.
They'd love
to see you.
I have plans.
Okay.
As of tomorrow morning,
LVPD will no longer function
as an independent
law enforcement agency.
Conrad, are you okay?
Yeah, sure.
You enjoy
your dinner?
And the company.
We have to do it again,
just the two of us.
ECKLIE:
That'll be nice.
HODGES:
Ah, here's your car.
I'll drive, Mother.
Uh, I'd rather you didn't.
Good night, everyone.
Night.
You were kind of quiet
at dinner.
I, I just got a
lot on my mind.
Want to take a walk?
Yeah.
(clears throat)
Another one.
No.
Yes.
You are on your own.
Ooh.
I'm very happy
to be on my own.
All right, what's going
on with you tonight?
It's complicated.
Yeah?
You ever think that
maybe you're the one
that's a little bit
complicated, hmm?
You know what? It's so much
hotter when you don't talk.
(scoffs)
Think I'm gonna go home.
RUSSELL:
You knucklehead,
you've got your
pajamas backwards.
I wear them that way.
Oh, I see.
Little Miss
Free Spirit.
Oh, wonder
where she gets that.
(chuckles)
Charlie just called.
Team bus got in from the
tournament, so he's on his way.
Bet he'll be hungry.
I'll warm him up a plate.
And I'll read a
bedtime story.
Any takers?
Me.
Anyone else?
Uh, you go ahead.
I think Mr. Merlot is
going to put me to bed.
(Barbara and Russell chuckle)
Go on, scoot,
scoot, scoot, scoot.
Good night.
KAITLYN:
Dad just never
changes, does he?
No.
SANDERS:
What are you saying?
I mean, it's not like it's
going to make any difference
'cause in this town
it's all about the game.
The game never changes,
just the players.
I'm starting to think
that Catherine was right.
What,
leaving?
No, Greg,
quitting.
SIDLE:
Oh, come on,
Nick, I know things have
been crazy right now, but...
Hey, she once told me,
"If you can't handle this job,
there is the door."
You know what?
I'm out.
Nick.
Hey.
CRENSHAW:
I've seen that look.
Try driving around
with him all day long.
(chuckles)
You look like someone
that doesn't need
to talk to someone
right now, right?
I could be persuaded.
Good.
(phone rings)
Is that a girlfriend?
Not right now.
Can I see?
Ah, whoa, she
wouldn't like that.
I'm gonna go
to the bathroom.
You gonna be here
when I get back?
If you're lucky.
It's under control.
Got eyes on the package
right now.
Where are we
going, anyway?
Remember when I was a little
girl and I'd come visit you
and you would drag me
to ride
the roller coaster
at New York, New York?
I thought you hated
that roller coaster.
I wanted you to think
that I hated it.
I'm sorry.
I was a brat.
No, no, no, I
deserved it.
Not anymore.
Hey, Undersheriff.
(screams)
(tires squealing)
Dad, Dad... Dad!
BARBARA:
I think you missed
your calling.
Always good to have
something to fall back on.
(chuckles)
(phone chirping)
Oh...
Oh, do you have
to get it?
Don't move,
I'll be right back.
(phone continues chirping)
Hey, Sara, what's up?
Where?
(phone rings)
Oh, God,
all right, oh.
Hello.
All right,
rally the troops.
I-I'll be there
in five minutes.
What?
He said to look upstairs.
Katie.
Kaitlyn.
Hey, Kate.
(grunts)
Oh, no.
They've taken her.
(grunts)
Don't touch anything.