♪ ♪
What?
Go on.
Hmm.
(slot machine beeping)
(cackling laugh)
(two gunshots)
(panicked shouts)
Oh!
Hey!
Somebody! Hey!
WOMAN: Come on! Somebody!
No, I can't comment.
No.
(siren wailing)
Casino's on lockdown.
Nothing goes out;
nothing comes in.
So, the security here
is all ex-cops.
30 seconds after the shooting,
all the exits
were sealed.
You call this
locked down?
No, I know.
Split hairs-- locked in.
A fire couldn't
stop these people
from gambling away
their money.
The shooter's
still in the casino,
am I right?
Somewhere on this floor.
And Archie's already
tapped into
casino surveillance.
He pulled a still photo
from the footage.
Brown hair, orange shirt.
Hey, guys, okay, I got facial
recognition up and running.
Scanning the casino floor now.
STOKES: Helps to know who
you're looking for, yes?
Guys, got a hit.
97% match.
Looks like he's heading east
towards the video arcade.
Okay, all units, we're
heading towards the arcade.
Let's go.
You can run,
but you can't hide.
STOKES:
Out the way. Move, move, move.
Out of the way. Clear out
of there, clear out of there.
Hey!
(woman gasps)
Oh!
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
Archie, are you sure
that computer's working?
'Cause all I'm seeing is
a woman in an orange shirt.
I don't get it.
I swear, I just had him.
Hang on a second.
I got a hit.
He's over by the nightclub.
BRASS: How the hell
did he get over there?
This is Sara.
I'm in the club now.
I don't see anybody.
Sara, sit tight,
wait for backup.
Copy that.
(sets case down)
(running steps approaching)
You see him?
No.
(panting)
I lost him again.
Come on, Archie,
tell me something
I don't know.
(beeping)
Oh. Hang on a second.
Oh, I got him.
Heading to the elevators.
Are you sure about that?
Ninety-seven percent.
Come on.
Yeah.
Clear out, clear out.
Did you see our suspect?
Nothing.
Archie.
No, I lost visual.
He just disappeared.
Disappeared!
How does a guy disappear
in a locked-down casino?
BRASS: What's behind there?
(frustrated sigh)
An unlocked lockdown.
Beautiful.
Archie,
you got eyes on the stairs?
That would be a negative.
Great. He's in the
tower with a gun.
We'll have to go
room-to-room.
No problem.
I got 65 cops
and 40 security guards.
Yeah, and cameras
everywhere.
So how the hell
did he get away?
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
I know that this is
the last place in America
where you're still allowed
to light up, but do you
think it's a good idea
with the oxygen...
You got a thing against smokers?
Smoke.
You don't know
what you're missing.
Okay, Gladys, tell
me what happened.
First, I heard two shots.
Saw that poor man fall
after the second shot.
Must've been a fight.
Why do you say that?
I saw the gunman.
His nose was bleeding.
(gunshot, panicked shouts)
What happened
after that?
The guy tosses the man's wallet
and tears off into the crowd.
Pretty ballsy,
trying to rob someone
on a casino floor.
You're just asking
to get caught. (laughs)
I mean...
you have caught him, right?
We're working on it.
The detectives will
have more questions,
so please don't
go anywhere.
Don't worry about me, hon.
I hit the jackpot: $4,436.
I ain't budgin'
till I get my payout.
I wouldn't either.
Thank you.
Cash, credit cards
are missing.
But they left a license;
that was nice.
Dennis Kiel,
58 from Los Angeles.
Medical I.D.
He was a doctor.
And he has a family.
I'll have Sara
check with the hotel,
see if they're registered.
Roll him?
Yep.
PHILLIPS:
Single GSW to the chest.
There was no exit wound, so the
bullet's still inside him.
Black Lung Betty over there said
that she heard two shots.
RUSSELL:
So there's another bullet
still out there.
Yeah. She also said
the assailant had a bloody nose.
Maybe the victim got a lick in.
FINLAY:
Ah, that would explain the blood
right over there.
Yep, gravitational drops.
RUSSELL:
All right, it's too far away
from our victim to be his.
Yeah.
Okay, so...
our shooter pulls
a gun on our victim.
Give me your money.
(gunshot)
You punch me in the nose.
Head jerks back,
my gun goes up...
Look at that.
One shot in the doctor,
one shot in the slot machine.
Think I should wrap it up
and take it back to the lab?
Took the words right out
of my mouth, smart-ass.
I'll go clear it
with the casino.
Unbelievable.
So, how many
more rooms to go?
Oh, only 1,200.
LVPD! Open up!
WOMAN:
LVPD?
(laughs):
Oh, that's
hilarious.
It's about time
you show... Oh!
Whoa.
How you doing?
Fine.
(Brody clears throat loudly)
Uh, y...
We're, uh, we're
looking for a man.
Uh, me, too.
This man.
That's him-- I've been
waiting for him for hours.
Yeah? Well, you might be waiting
a little bit longer than that.
He just shot a guy
in the casino.
What?
I met him in
the casino bar
last night.
He was cute;
perfect gentleman.
Until later.
Which is what
you want, right?
(quiet sigh)
Did he use
protection?
Yeah. Why?
Means we got DNA.
BRODY:
And...
he left behind a wrapper.
BRODY:
Maybe a print.
Did this perfect gentleman
have a name?
Kind of. Called
himself X-Man.
(laughs) Pretty cool.
Kind of 9√ Weeks,
foreign identity.
Why are you taking my sheets?
Why do you think?
Oh.
I hope you don't
think I'm a slut.
I mean, I am not a slut.
No, no, of course not.
Did X-Man leave anything else
behind we should know about?
Well, I...
I kind of made a video.
We're gonna...
kind of need to watch that.
(knocking)
BRASS:
Mrs. Kiel, Las Vegas Police.
(video game sound effects)
BRASS: Well...
So, the front desk
called up here to Kiel's room
and nobody answered.
(weapons firing on video game)
Somebody's here.
(gunfire continues
on video game)
(game stops)
It's okay.
What's your name, son?
Avery.
Avery Kiel.
Is your mother here?
My mom...
she died last year.
Where's my dad?
What happened?
Somebody robbed
your dad, Avery.
Where?
In the casino.
This is my fault.
I begged Dad to come out
this weekend to see Kanye.
Last night...
after he won all that money,
I told him to be careful.
What money, Avery?
At the slot machines.
He won, like, 800 bucks.
All these people
were watching.
So, after your dad
won all the money,
did these people
follow him anywhere?
No.
I mean... I-I don't know.
He bought those sneakers
for me.
He was always
buying me things.
Is that your dad's computer?
Yeah.
We're gonna need to
take it with us, okay?
BRASS:
Avery, do you have
any relatives who live nearby,
you know, an aunt
or an uncle, anybody?
I have cousins in Wisconsin.
I haven't seen them
in, like, forever.
What's gonna happen to me?
You'll be okay.
We're gonna
keep you safe.
This officer here is gonna
stay with you, okay?
I'm gonna come back
and check in on you
in a little while,
all right?
I promise.
Hey, Doc, what
you got?
A bit of a puzzle.
Our victim sustained a single
GSW to the center torso.
Bullet entered the abdomen,
penetrated the liver.
Does that look like
a penetrating wound to you?
Looks like chopped
liver to me.
I found these lead fragments
and this copper jacket.
Looks like a .38 hollow-point.
In most cases,
when you find only the jacket,
it means the core had separated.
I didn't find any core.
All I found was this.
That is weird.
Hourglass shape.
Never seen that before.
Interesting.
♪ ♪
(cell phone ringing)
Slots R Us.
You shoot it, we trash it.
How can I help you?
How's it going?
Having fun?
You know how I like
to break things.
So far, I've only found
the jacket of a hollow-point.
No core, right?
I hate it when you do that.
Did you find a little red thing,
hourglass shape?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I found that.
I'm looking at it right now.
Well, go ahead and bindle it.
I got a feeling
that's all you're going to find.
What is it?
No idea, Jules.
That's your next job.
So annoying.
(chuckles)
(knocking)
LVPD! Open up!
Can I help you?
Yeah, yeah.
We're with the Crime Lab,
and we're looking for this guy.
You seen him around?
Um, no.
Never seen him before.
You mind if we come in
and take a look around?
Yeah, I do mind.
That wasn't really a question.
This is hotel property;
we have the authority.
Step aside.
Size 13s?
You look like you're
no more than a ten, tops.
Who's your roommate?
He's a friend from back home.
You got some I.D.
on you, bud?
Lee Jacobs.
Hey.
Familiar?
What?
I didn't do anything wrong.
STOKES:
Need a little backup
in here, Paul.
Check him for weapons.
We're looking for your roomie,
Jordan Brentson.
Yeah, well, he's not here.
He took off.
Without his shoes
and his wallet?
You're coming downtown with us.
Why don't you grab a jacket.
Yeah, well, you know,
I know my rights.
Anything in plain sight,
you don't need a warrant.
If you that closet opened,
then you should open it.
You a lawyer?
No.
Well, you're gonna need
a good one, serving 15 to 20.
Okay. I'll get a jacket.
Wait, hang on a second.
Open it.
If this is about the bar fight
in Ashtabula, dude hit me first.
Get your ass out of there.
Take a nice picture, Jordan.
That might look like me,
but that's not me.
Look, the guy's got a gun.
I'm opposed to guns, the
whole Second Amendment thing.
That's you, Jordan.
Your girlfriend Shelley--
she already gave you away, man.
Who's Shelley?
Really?
Let me show you something.
(chuckles)
I want to get this on record.
Say, "This is not
a one-night stand."
This is not a
one-night stand.
(giggling)
No, no, no!
Now say, "I promise
to take Shelley
to dinner tomorrow night."
JORDAN:
I promise to take this
gorgeous piece of ass to
any damn place she wants.
Ooh.
(laughs)
As long as it's
under two bills.
Hey!
Chick's smokin',
but that's not me.
You met her
in the bar last night.
We found your DNA
in her room.
And you robbed this guy.
We found your blood
in the casino.
Now, why'd you shoot him?
Because he resisted?
I didn't shoot anybody.
Where were you
at 10:30 a.m. this morning?
I don't know. Out.
Having a good time.
I won a free trip to Vegas;
I'm going to enjoy it.
Can anyone verify that?
No.
I was alone.
Just like you were alone
last night... not with Shelley.
I'm telling you,
I don't know her.
Last night,
I was with my buddy Lee.
Where'd you guys go?
Ballgame. The 51's.
We didn't get back to
the hotel till midnight.
Look, I'm telling you,
that is not me.
(sighs)
Hey, Arch.
How's it going?
(sighs)
I'm going blind.
Yeah, well, you can
give your eyes a rest
just as soon as you make
a liar out of Jordan
and place him at the bar
last night with Shelley.
Well, already did that.
Casino bar.
Just after midnight.
Just where he
said he wasn't.
Gotcha.
Well, gotcha a problem.
Same time.
Same guy.
Coming into the hotel
with his friend.
Just where he said he was.
How could a guy be in two places
at the same time?
He can't.
RUSSELL: I know, I know that.
Sweetheart, that's not
what I'm saying.
I'm...
Well, tell them I'm sorry
I missed the breakfast.
They'll understand that.
My in-laws are in town.
Hey, here's what we'll do,
all right?
Let's take them out to dinner
on their way to the airport.
They'd like that.
All right, I love you, too.
(sighs)
I love my wife's parents,
but, oh, Lord.
Houseguests and fish-- after
three days, they got to go.
All right, who's up?
Me.
Uh, DNA from Jordan
Brentson was a match
to the blood at
the crime scene,
as well as the semen
in the condom in Shelley's room.
He's our shooter.
I hate to rain on
your conviction there, Gilligan,
but the fingerprint
on the condom wrapper
was not a match to Jordan.
Same DNA
and different fingerprints...
Would you like
to hear my theory?
Yes, please.
Identical crime twins.
(snickers)
You should check
Jordan's birth records.
Already did that.
According to Columbus General,
Jordan Brentson
was a single birth.
Guy's an only child.
Ouch. You got
another theory?
Doppelganger.
Mm-hmm. In doppel polo shirts?
Well, that's how
doppelgangers roll.
BRODY:
Doppelganger, identical
twins separated birth.
Either way, I had Archie
track Shelley and her date
after they left the bar.
Our guy's getting cash
from the casino ATM.
Yeah, so I pulled
the bank records, got a name:
Xavier Marx.
Tucson address.
Xavier Marx checked into
the hotel on Friday.
According to his room bill,
the only thing he's been doing
since then is watching porn.
Guess murder makes him horny.
(knocking)
Las Vegas Police!
Open up!
WOMAN:
Can you come back in an hour?
Let me see that key.
(giggling)
Whoa. What the hell?
You married or something?
Talk about seeing double.
You Xavier Marx?
Yeah, that's right.
Put some clothes on, man;
you're coming with us.
You sure know
how to wreck a party.
Or you can
join in, handsome.
Uh...
You into twins, Mr. Marx?
XAVIER:
Oh, come on, who isn't?
Right, Officer?
Just get dressed, dude.
I don't know a Jordan Brentson.
I don't have a brother.
I'm an only child.
You're telling me that you
weren't born September 18, 1987?
A Virgo?
No. I'm a Gemini.
Of course you are.
May 22, 1989.
Hammond, Louisiana.
St. Joe's Hospital.
Look it up.
What are you doing in Vegas?
I won a free trip
on the Internet.
All expenses paid.
You know him?
No.
Who is he?
He's the guy
you shot this morning.
Excuse me?
I think you saw
what I was doing this morning.
All morning?
Twins are very
demanding.
I think I remember at one
point, I had to step out.
For a smoke.
So when was that?
All I know is, it was
after the strawberries
and the caramel sauce
were delivered.
You should check
with room service.
I don't care what these guys
say, they're identical twins.
STOKES:
How do you explain
the birth records
not matching up?
Well, they're
probably fake.
Look, they both have
criminal records...
FINLAY:
Dressed the same.
Both in Vegas the same time.
Both claiming to have
won free trips online.
I'm with Sara.
It's a scam.
What about their alibis?
So far, we can't verify
either one of them.
They have to know each other.
They have to have planned this.
It's the perfect crime.
Twins defense.
Identical DNA, no way to prove
which one pulled the trigger.
There is one way.
Antibody profiling.
ANDREWS: I didn't even know
we had all this stuff.
Guess it doesn't get
much use anymore.
So you haven't used antibody
profiling in a while, huh?
I mean, I know it's a procedure
that's not used that much,
but I've read some
journal abstracts.
It's kind of like DNA, right?
It's different, but in a lot
of ways, it's better.
Right, because every person
develops their own unique
antibody profile in response
to their environment.
Yeah, so even identical twins
can have the same DNA,
but different antibody profiles.
Okay, so when we are done,
we are gonna know
which one of these twins
left their blood
on the casino floor.
Which one is
our killer.
Mm.
♪ ♪
(computer trills)
(beeping)
You and Finn find us our twin?
Well, actually, we
found a little more
than we bargained for.
What do you mean?
Antibody profiling
didn't match either suspect?
Jordan
and Xavier are off the hook.
Well, someone with their DNA
put a bullet into Dr. Kiel.
Yeah, agreed.
So, what are you saying?
We've got a third one now?
Look on the bright side.
At least we still know
who we're looking for.
FINLAY:
Okay, so, we're talking
identical crime
triplets?
Oh, not quite.
If we go by
the birth records,
our twins,
maybe even our mystery triplet,
were born at different times
and in different places.
RUSSELL: So we're talking about
in-vitro fertilization, right?
I mean, frozen embryos.
That's the only way
you can get identical triplets
from one set of parents
born to three
different families.
In different years
and in different cities.
So, we're saying, one fertilized
embryo split three ways.
Is that even
possible?
Some might call it a miracle.
You know what
this reminds me of?
What?
That movie.
Um, Gregory Peck.
Uh, "We're gonna build
our own New World."
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Um... Boys From Brazil.
Yup.
Right here in Vegas.
That movie is about
cloning. Hitler.
Right?
Yeah, yeah,
but it's also about
a doctor who played God.
Yeah, but our victim, Dr. Kiel,
was a pediatrician,
not an IVF guy.
All right, but do we know
if he was always a pediatrician,
you know?
Where did he do his internship?
What was his first job?
I want to know more
about this guy.
I'm on it.
That movie is also about
planning. In this case,
these guys weren't planning
the Fourth Reich, but they...
They were planning
a murder.
Yes.
And how to get away with it.
And they still think
they've pulled off
the perfect crime, right?
They can hide behind their DNA.
Which makes them overconfident.
That third guy
is probably
trying to
wait us out.
And I bet I know where.
Diamond Dust Casino.
Yeah. All right.
(phone chirps)
You better fire up
his facial recognition, right?
Like Henry said, at least
we know who we're looking for.
What?
(laughs)
Jordan Brentson's lawyer
just walked into PD.
She's also his mother.
WOMAN: My son Jordan
called me from jail.
It's not the first time.
He's had his...
troubles with the law.
But he's never been accused
of murder.
Conspiracy, actually.
He had a partner. Well,
partners.
Look at this.
Seeing double?
'Cause we are.
I don't understand.
Maybe this will help. Um,
do you recognize this man?
I've never seen him before.
I get it. It's...
It's been, what, 25 years?
It must be...
very hard wanting
a child so much.
The struggle to conceive.
And then a miracle happens.
It was a miracle.
And then some.
A single embryo split
three ways.
The doctors told me
there were multiples.
But I told them that I...
I could only care
for one child.
It was the hardest decision
of my life.
BRASS:
So, you instructed
the clinic to dispose
of the other embryos?
That's right.
A mother knows her son.
It's way beyond biology.
I would know Jordan anywhere.
But this boy--
I don't him.
I want to see my son.
BRODY:
I looked into Dr. Kiel's
work history.
Russell's hunch
was right.
Before he was a pediatrician,
he did an internship
at an IVF clinic
in Columbus, Ohio.
BRASS:
Vivian and Jordan
Brentson's home town.
You think she's lying?
You think she knew Kiel?
BRASS:
I think she's more than lying.
I think we're looking
at a modern Ma Barker here.
You know, Ma Barker
had four sons.
Herman, Lloyd,
Arthur and Fred.
Masterminded her own Little
Crime House on the Prairie.
Wow. You're like a
World Book of Crime.
Well, I'm, like,
not impressed with her story.
I don't know. I mean,
she's a defense attorney.
She's not a criminal.
I don't see the distinction.
And I see plenty of motive.
She had a kid in a dish,
wanted the extras tossed.
Somehow found out
they weren't.
Blamed the doctor
for playing God,
and giving away what was hers.
Then Ma Barker rounds up
her boys for payback.
BRASS:
Well, like you said,
she's a defense attorney.
Pretty good plan.
Unless we catch the shooter.
Fire in the hole!
Lose something?
No. I think I found the answer
to our ballistics mystery.
Oh, yeah?
Our little red hourglass.
Found only in No-Rico Shells.
As in, "no ricochet."
It's the exact type of bullet
our killer used.
They were originally developed
for air marshals.
So that it doesn't go
through-and-through
and puncture the fuselage.
(gunshot)
FINLAY: No-Rico shell
breaks up on impact.
The hourglass tip
is like a cork
that pops and releases a lethal
shotgun blast of pellets.
Okay, well, that would explain
Dr. Kiel's macerated liver.
Yeah.
What do you think? We're
looking for an air marshal?
Or at least
an air marshal's gun.
(computer beeps and trills)
Hey, Arch, you still on
the hunt for the third man?
(sighs)
Yeah, going into hour 14.
Can't take a break
till I find him.
Hey, I think I
got something.
Those free trips to
Vegas our suspects won...
At first, I thought it was
just a line they were using.
Then I thought, if
they've been so careful
to create so many
cover stories,
maybe they created a free
trip to cover their tracks.
Which they did?
Checked with
the hotel.
Three trips were booked
online via Sunview Travel.
Sent via e-mail to Jordan
Brentson, Xavier Marx
and again, a familiar face.
Kevin Chance.
Minneapolis address.
Check out the birth
date on the license.
July 30, 1989.
Makes him the youngest,
and a criminal record.
Interesting
employment history, too.
Before being dropped
for drunk and disorderly,
he was training
to be an air marshal.
I think we got our shooter.
And according
to the Diamond Dust Casino,
he's still checked in--
room 2211.
LVPD! Show me
your hands!
Hands!
Heard the man, Mr. Chance.
Hands on your head.
Yeah, he's
ice cold.
He's been dead for a while.
Looks like an overdose.
Credit cards.
Belong to Dr. Kiel.
Smith &amp; Wesson .38,
just like the murder weapon.
No-Rico Shells.
Same as the shells we pulled out
of that the slot machine
and Dr. Kiel.
(sighs)
I killed Dr. Kiel.
He's to blame.
If it wasn't
for him playing God,
I wouldn't have existed.
Had the miserable life
that I've had.
This whole thing was my idea.
I thought that killing
Dr. Kiel was the answer.
But this...
This...
This is the answer.
(sighs)
Do you think this is our answer?
We've been chasing the wrong guy
this whole time.
Why should we have
the right one now?
Preliminary tox indicates
Kevin Chance died
from a massive overdose
of alprazolam and alcohol.
Well, that fits
with the suicide video.
Right?
I'm not sure
that video
captured the whole story.
What do you mean?
I found signs
of blunt-force trauma.
Looks like a blow to the head.
And I also dissected
the victim's neck.
See the abrasions
on his trachea?
Look like circular patterns.
The diameter's consistent
with the mouth of a bottle--
say a bottle
of Scotch shoved
down his throat.
As for pills,
I found no solid
remnants in his stomach.
Ah. Well, how-how did the drugs
get into his system, then?
Henry tested
the Scotch bottle
and found toxic levels of
alprazolam.
So, somebody ground up
the pills, dissolved them,
spiked the drink...
And faked the video.
What do you estimate
time of death?
Approximately
12 hours ago.
About an hour after
the shooting of Dr. Kiel,
while we were still
chasing our tails.
Yeah, I smell the twins
at work here.
Did you get it?
Yeah, well, Kevin
didn't shove that bottle
down his own throat,
and he didn't make
the bogus suicide video.
Right, but whoever did,
maybe they left behind
some touch DNA.
And their antibodies.
Yeah.
I'll get Henry on it.
STOKES: Hey, Morgan,
I got your text.
What's up?
You and Sara were right.
Doc Robbins said
the suicide was fake.
So much for brotherly love.
Well, I do have some love.
I figured out who bought
those "free trips" to Vegas.
Yeah, who's that?
Dr. Kiel.
Booked his own vacation
with his son
at the same time.
Take a look at this.
I got these files
off of his computer.
For the past few months,
Kiel's been keeping
track of the triplets.
Got the contact information
for the parents
who received the embryos.
And he took it from there
and tracked them down.
But for what?
Some kind of weird
embryo doctor reunion?
I mean, why do it?
Jordan's mother said
that the clinic
was supposed to
destroy the embryos.
But, obviously, Kiel
didn't follow through.
Based on these
criminal records,
these triplets' lives
didn't go so well.
And you think that Kiel
felt guilty and was trying
to make it right somehow?
Take a look at this.
Two days before
he was murdered,
Kiel withdrew 150 grand.
Compensation for pain
and suffering.
But maybe not enough.
He was a very successful
pediatrician.
A rich man.
With one unethical chapter
in his past.
He makes a great target
for blackmail.
Blackmail gone bad.
I heard Russell put
you back to work.
Yeah.
What'd you find?
This is good.
Profiling confirms it was
Kevin Chance's blood
on the casino floor.
We have our shooter.
Look at page two.
Antibody results
on the scotch bottle
from the touch DNA.
You've got to be kidding me.
There's a fourth man?
Yep. Antibodies
on the bottle
excluded Kevin,
Jordan, and Xavier.
You're telling me that we're
looking for quadruplets?
Yeah. Number four
is alive and well,
and dressed to kill.
I'm guessing in an
orange polo and blue jeans.
Do you think he's
still at the hotel?
Well, Archie's got
facial recognition
watching all the exits,
so he has to be.
Where are you going?
If Kiel arranged the reunion,
it stands to reason
that he met with those guys
before they killed him.
Okay, so?
So maybe we have a witness.
Can I give you a hand?
Got it. Thanks.
The policeman said
you found the man.
We did.
You know, you told me
that, um...
your dad brought you here
to see Kanye.
Did he have any other reason
to be in Vegas?
He did say
there were some people
he was gonna meet.
Did you meet them?
When they were coming over,
he gave me money...
told me to go to the arcade.
So that's a "no"?
I did come back
a little early.
Saw him talking
to these two guys.
It was really weird.
They looked exactly alike,
even dressed alike.
Did they look like this?
Yeah.
I asked my dad
about them.
He told me they
had two brothers--
they all looked alike.
My dad...
helped deliver them as babies.
Was it one of them?
Yeah...
it was.
Listen, um...
we were able to contact
your family in Wisconsin.
And you're gonna be staying
with them for a while.
I don't want to go to Wisconsin.
I'm sorry.
You know, um...
I could really...
go for an ice cream
right now. There's, um,
a great place downstairs.
Would you like some ice cream?
Sure.
(sighs)
Earning your money
on this one, huh, Arch?
Oh, man,
I am so sick
of looking for this face.
Well, look at
the bright side.
Oh, we still know who
we're looking for.
Ha, ha, ha.
Yeah, man, I am tired
of that joke and I am
getting really
tired here.
Whoa.
Got a hit.
How is it?
Good. Thanks.
Yours?
Good.
(phone rings)
Oh.
Excuse me for a second
Hey, Nick.
What's up?
We got a hit on our suspect.
Where is he?
Sitting right behind you,
eating ice cream.
Are you sure?
Relative position of
features, proportionality,
by age ten,
facial metrics are set.
Yeah, I'm sure.
We're sure.
You all done?
Yeah.
I'll take that.
Can we go now?
Yeah.
BRASS: So we ran
your DNA, Avery.
Big surprise--
it matched your brothers.
I guess you
could call them brothers,
certainly brothers
in crime.
We thought it
was your dad
that arranged
those "free trips."
Turns out it was you.
Contacted the ISP,
while you were booking
flights and hotels,
you were also doing
a little shopping online--
skateboard, video games...
oh yeah, and a nice
new pair of kicks.
BRASS: So I guess you like
spending your old man's money.
Uh, just like when
we found you at the hotel
running up the
room service bill
on cake and ice cream.
This weekend's my birthday.
I told you my dad
liked to buy me stuff.
Well, forget
cake and ice cream.
Forget sneakers.
Your dad's a rich man.
You're the sole beneficiary
in his will.
You have 25k a year
until you're 18,
then you get the whole nut:
six million bucks.
I don't know
anything about that.
What about the
$150,000
transferred from
your dad's savings
into a money market,
with two payments
scheduled for exactly
24 hours after he was murdered?
75K goes to your bro,
Jordan Brentson
and 75K to your other bro,
Xavier Marx.
Poor Kevin got stiffed.
And let me guess.
He wanted a bigger cut
for being
the trigger man, and that didn't
sit well with the family.
I'm the one who took the risk.
I was the one who
pulled the trigger.
It was my ass
hanging out there.
Still is.
How do you guys feel about
splitting 150K two ways?
Whose idea was it to make it
look like a suicide?
Yours?
We all have the same DNA.
There's no way of knowing
who was in that room.
That's the
thing, Avery.
We do know.
You planned
this very well.
You knew you could hide
behind the DNA,
but you missed something.
It's called
antibody profiling.
And that puts
that bottle of scotch
that was jammed down
Kevin Chance's throat
in your hands.
(sighs)
There was some bad seed
in that petri dish.
This couldn't have been
just all about the money.
You wouldn't understand.
Try me.
When my mom died...
at the funeral,
I heard my cousins
talking about how sad it was
that she couldn't get pregnant.
How she had to go and thaw out
somebody else's kid
to put in her.
I confronted my dad.
He told me
about the four brothers,
all from one embryo.
Identical, perfect.
He had taken
the last one.
Given it life.
Me.
I was his final miracle.
What miracle?
It was all a lie.
Still doesn't explain
what you did.
My dad...
was always so cold.
Now I know why.
My mom's the only one
who really loved me.
And she wasn't even my mom.
And that day she was
taken away from me again...
I blame him.
I'm 12 years old...
what jury's gonna put me away?
Don't be so sure.
Last year an 11-year-old boy
was put away for murder,
life without parole.
You can help
yourself here, Avery.
You created
the prefect crime.
SIDLE: Perfect.
Except that it was perfect
for Jordan and Xavier.
The only physical
evidence we have
points to Kevin
killing your dad...
And you killing Kevin.
Come on, kid.
Save yourself.
Give up the twins.
No.
I'll take my chances.
Like you said...
they're my brothers.
They're my only real family.