♪ ♪
(sizzling)
(man whispers indistinctly)
♪ ♪
(blipping)
CROUPIER:
Okay, folks.
Ball is on the wheel.
This is the last call
for betting.
(indistinct chatter)
CROUPIER:
We have a winner!
BRASS:
Are you getting this?
Huh?
Blue plaid shirt,
past posting
chocolate chips
at table R49?
We gotta shut him down.
CROUPIER:
Round and round she goes,
where she stops, nobody knows.
(wheel clicking, blipping)
Sir, can I help you?
Sorry, yes.
You can help me.
You have change for a penny?
(gasps)
(explosion thunders)
(people screaming, clamoring)
This is Federal, sir.
It's a bomb.
I know it's not my jurisdiction,
but it is my casino.
I'm on the next plane.
(reporter speaking indistinctly)
(sirens wailing, horns blaring)
SIDLE:
Hey.
Oh, great.
All right, all hands on deck
on this one.
Blast circumference
roughly 18 by 12.
We got three dead
and several dozen injured.
So, let's-let's get on it.
All right, I'll look
for bomb parts.
I'll shoot the overalls.
Henry and I will document
the detonation blast area.
I'll measure,
you photo.
So, uh, I know
you're applying
for the directorship.
Oh.
Stage doesn't get
any bigger than this, Sara.
You want this case?
Good.
It's yours.
I know this is gonna
sound insensitive,
but don't you think a
bomber wearing a vest
would've taken out
way more people than this?
Yeah.
So, what, faulty bomb?
You put a vest on like
that in a public place,
I gotta think that
you're planning on taking
as many people with
you as possible.
Yeah.
So, what do you think?
First blush.
Terrorism.
Why do you say that?
Vegas is terrified.
OFFICER (whispering):
Let's go to the bow.
Sir?
Harbor Patrol.
I'm Officer Scinta.
These men are from San Diego PD.
I have orders to remove
all trespassers.
Please show me your hands.
I'm gonna give you about
two seconds to turn around,
or I'm gonna
consider you a threat
and shoot you right here
on this boat.
(sighs)
Shark fins.
Looks like somebody
jumped a shark.
(siren wailing, horn blaring)
(siren approaches)
Well, you got here fast.
WILLOWS:
FBI has its perks.
How many dead?
Three.
A lot are injured.
We don't have a count.
Anyway, she's one of ours.
Her name is Romina Gonzalez.
I saw the surveillance video.
You want to talk to her now.
She was the last person
to speak to the bomber
before he self-detonated.
Romina,
hang in there, honey.
WILLOWS:
Mrs. Gonzalez,
I'm Catherine Willows,
Special Agent with the FBI.
(groans in pain)
I wasn't even supposed
to work today.
I just needed the money.
I just need to ask...
could you recall
your conversation you had
with the bomber?
BOMBER:
Are those your kids?
Ah, yeah.
Those are my babies.
Oh, cute.
Cubano cigars--
50 bucks a stick, right?
Could you come with me
to the cage?
I just need to cash
in a few chips first.
Sure.
So, he was listening to someone
on the other end
of an earpiece?
FIREMAN: All right,
check the fentanyl?
(gasps, groans)
FIREMAN 2: Yeah.
FIREMAN: Tourniquet
still in place?
FIREMAN 2: It is.
My daughters' names...
are Helena and Maria.
All right.
FIREMAN 2:
B.P.'s dropping.
(flat line tone sounding)
FIREMAN 2: Doctor, we need
some help over here.
Romina?
Ma'am, please step back.
Start compressions.
Go ahead to the hospital,
prepare for arrival.
DOCTOR:
Let's start a line.
FBI Special Agent Willows.
I've been authorized
by the L.A. Bureau
to take over
this bomb sight.
Sara!
Catherine, hey.
I am so sorry.
Hey.
What a mess.
Just got in from L.A.
I saw the footage on the news.
How can I help?
Well, I'm not exactly sure.
It's a conflict of interest.
Legally, I'm the owner
of the Eclipse.
This building and everything
in it is my responsibility.
Of course, yes.
Yes, it is.
But... you and I both know
you can't be in here.
Three of my employees are dead.
What am I supposed to do?
Wait in the
hospitality suite?
Look, Sara...
I'm not here to cause trouble,
but I'm also not here
to sit on the sidelines.
And as long as
there are bodies
on the floor of
my father's casino,
I need to continue
to work this case.
Okay?
Okay.
I ran your name.
Says you used to run
the Las Vegas Crime Lab.
Long time ago.
Do you mind telling me
why you're unlawfully
on this vessel?
Well, see, that's
my boat over there.
The poacher who owns
this boat has violated
Fish and Game Code 8599,
which states:
"It is unlawful to
slice the dorsal fin
"off a Carcharodon
Carcharias
unless you bring the
whole carcass ashore."
But white sharks
can only be taken
for scientific or educational
purposes under permit.
This boat has no permit.
My job is to confiscate
the evidence,
document it and prepare it
for international
and/or domestic court.
I had to ask.
So, now you're what,
a CSI at sea?
Kind of.
Shark fin soup is bad.
It's worth getting
arrested for.
(Willows scoffs)
Bastard lied about needing
to get money from the cage.
He lured Romina over after
he found out she had children.
BRASS:
Pretty cruel.
Whew.
I'm good here.
Just release
everything back to Sara.
As far as this
piece of work--
just grab his photo and run
it through NCIC, BICTOF,
local DMV-- I want a name.
Would you have assumed
this if I was a nun
or a Hasidic Jew?
They also cover themselves
based on religious belief.
Considering what your husband
did, Mrs. Karmimi, I would.
Hijab or no hijab,
terrorism is not a stretch
if you're on my side
of the law.
My husband converted to Islam
because we fell in
love, Mrs. Sidle.
I came to America
so that I could live
free as a woman.
Here, women have a chance
to live and to love
without being
stoned to death.
To you, he's a criminal.
But to me, he was a husband.
He was my salvation.
Sorry.
Um, I-I didn't mean
to offend you.
I'm sorry for your loss.
That does not forgive what
he did to those people.
I know.
Mrs. Karmimi, help me.
If not terrorism...
then why would your husband
strap a bomb to his body
and do that?
I don't know.
My husband is not a terrorist.
If anything, he had
a gambling problem.
I took him to our Imam to
speak to him at the mosque.
I even took him to therapy.
Therapy for his addiction?
Yes.
He was doing well
for a while.
But then,
the therapist of his,
she unexpectedly
quit her practice.
And then he
just spiraled.
What the hell is that?
Hey, you garbage men find
anything gold and square,
about yea big?
Something gold and metal flew
out of the bomber's vest.
Chest-high, right side?
Yeah.
Why?
Uh...
I noticed this
hand-stitched lining
on the inside of
the bomber's vest,
almost like
a homemade pocket.
Gold metal piece.
I found it earlier,
but I wasn't sure what it was.
This flew out of the bomber's
right breast pocket,
but this vest doesn't
even have inside pockets.
Looks like this gold
God-knows-what
was purposely sewn
into the vest.
Good catch.
Now, there's some kind
of etching on it.
Maybe I can lift it.
♪ ♪
(whirring, grinding)
Forgive me,
but who is Lady Heather?
Uh, she's a sex therapist
Grissom had a thing with
back in the day-day.
Not, like, a sexual one,
more like...
an intellectual one.
Anyway, he worked a
couple cases with her.
And against her.
So what do we think?
That she could be involved
in this somehow?
We don't know,
but we'd like to find out
why this piece of metal with
Lady Heather's initials on it
flew from the
bomber's jacket.
ECKLIE:
Sara.
Wait.
This is gonna sound
like an odd request,
but do you know
where Grissom is?
Grissom?
Yeah.
Uh, let me see, grab a globe,
spin it, look for the blue,
and pick an ocean.
He could be anywhere.
Why?
We think Lady Heather
might have something
to do with the bombing.
Lady Heather?
Well, even if she did,
what does that have to do
with my ex-husband?
Lady Heather is
in the wind, all right?
We're getting a warrant
for her house, as we speak.
Come on, if anybody knows
this woman inside and out,
it's Grissom; I figured he could
provide some deeper insight.
Conrad, with all due respect,
this entire building
is working the bombing case.
Greg and I have history
with Lady Heather.
We-we got it covered.
I know, Sara, but this bombing
is international news now.
I'd feel better if we
exhaust all resources.
Do you at least
have his cell?
(scoffs, chuckles)
(cell phone rings)
(phone ringing, buzzing)
GRISSOM: Well, if that's
the case, Conrad,
then I need to come up there.
But you're gonna have
to get me out of this first.
Hello.
Let him go?
Are you sure
about this, Sheriff?
Okay.
I'll arrange transport
and relinquish him
into your custody.
(sighs heavily)
It's your lucky day, pal.
I'd tell you
not to leave town,
but I guess you're
going to Sin City.
Vegas.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
♪ ♪
(indistinct announcement
over P.A.)
Mr. Grissom?
Oh, my God.
Hi. Welcome back.
It's been a long time
since I saw you last.
Oh, but, hey, check it out--
CSI Level One.
I did it. (chuckles)
You know what
the crazy thing is?
(whispering):
It's my first day.
Do you want to take my blood
or offer me a chocolate-covered
grasshopper?
Oh, but, uh, anyway,
I gotta run.
It was great
to see you, as always.
See ya.
Sara.
Gil.
I'm back.
(chuckles)
I see that.
ECKLIE:
Grissom.
Hey.
Thanks for coming.
Uh, let's step
in D.B.'s office. Sara.
(whispers):
Who's D.B.?
D.B., Grissom.
Hi. I'm-I'm
Diebenkorn Russell.
Pleasure to finally
meet you, Gil.
My brains used to
sit on that shelf.
Yeah, I, uh, traded
brains for mushrooms.
Hope you don't mind.
ECKLIE: Gil, we could
really use some insight
on Lady Heather.
The most pressing
issue is this.
At the blast site, we found
a piece of gold metal
with the letters LHK
inscribed on it.
It flew out of
the bomber's suicide vest.
Well, that's her logo,
but I don't know what this is.
ECKLIE: When was the last
time you spoke with her?
A few days ago, by phone.
Guess your cell service is
better than it used to be.
Who wants to catch me up?
Gil!
GRISSOM: Hey.
I heard you were coming by.
RUSSELL:
Catherine...
because your name is
on the deed to the Eclipse,
it might be cleaner if you work
other avenues for us, okay?
Sure.
I'll work up
a chronological timeline
and psychological profile
on Lady Heather.
Good luck with that.
ECKLIE:
Sara, your warrant came in.
Lady Heather's house
is all yours.
Perfect.
Grissom and I'll
check it out.
Wow, 30 minutes in
the car, no words.
If you were playing that silent
car game, you definitely win.
I thought we were talking.
All right, uh, listen,
you know, before we go in there
and deal with Lady Heather,
I-I just want to acknowledge
that you and I haven't
spoken much since the divorce,
or before it, for that matter.
We both went our separate ways.
You're doing your
Jacques Cousteau thing,
I'm in the field.
Things end, I-I get it.
But-but you and I
are professionals,
and as professionals,
I think it's in the best
interests of the case
if we put on a unified front.
You know, work as a team.
So, uh, let's put on
our game faces
and-and keep it professional.
See? Mine's on.
You ready to go in?
Seeing you again left me
a little speechless.
Come on.
Dr. Kessler?
Las Vegas Crime Lab.
WILLOWS:
From 2000 to 2006,
Lady Heather ran a role-playing
Red Room out of her home.
Whips, chains, pig masks,
the whole ball of sex wax.
SANDERS: In 2006,
she shut down the Red Room
after her daughter
Zoe was murdered.
Overnight, her Red Room clients
became therapy patients
where she started her
own psychiatry practice.
And three months ago,
she abruptly shut down
her practice.
Why?
Well, here's a thought:
This year, Lady Heather's
granddaughter Alison,
daughter of Zoe,
was hit by a car
while walking to school.
She died three months ago,
right around the time
she quit her practice.
SANDERS: You think the two
incidents are related?
I don't know yet.
(sighs)
Lady Heather told me something
a long time ago,
that I never forgot.
She told me that
there are many things
that you can give a man--
your body, your time,
even your heart--
but that one thing that
you could never, ever,
ever let go of is your power.
I think that she lost everything
that mattered to her--
her daughter and
her granddaughter?
I mean, it's painful enough
to lose one child, but two?
I mean, what else does
she have to live for
but to wield
her power of revenge?
Not to mention,
we're dealing with
a master of the human mind.
Yeah.
If anybody can convince someone
to blow themselves up, it's her.
Hmm...
What?
Do you got something?
Just put my pole in the water
and I got a hit.
What is that?
Sorry, I wish I had better news.
Especially given
all the blood
you guys found
in Lady Heather's house.
None of these blood samples
belong to Lady Heather.
Not one.
Amelogenin is XY.
Donor's male.
DNA from the carpet doesn't
even match the bomber.
So there's another male
out there.
Along with Lady Heather.
WILLOWS:
Robbins found the other half
of the gold metal piece
inside one
of the female victims.
Looks like a key
of some sort.
Not just any key.
This is a key
to Heather's Red Room.
Where's that?
The dungeon.
♪ ♪
(door creaking open)
Oh, Heather,
what have you done now?
Am I interrupting
anything?
Only my precious
thoughts, Henry.
Did you bring the movie?
Thumb drive.
What are you, Henry,
about five-ten,
160 pounds?
164. Why?
I'm gonna make a bomb.
We're gonna blow you up.
Oh.
Okay.
Great.
ANDREWS:
So, um, where did you learn
how to build homemade bombs?
And, um, does the bomb
you're currently working on
have, uh, any chance
of blowing us up?
If our organization fails
to put poachers in jail
for pillaging our oceans,
we've been known to blow holes
in their boats.
You can do that?
Not legally.
There.
Put the vest on.
(sighs anxiously)
I see I'm right on time.
(beeping)
Okay, bomb's hot.
Behind the wall.
GRISSOM:
Three, two,
one...
Look at
the blast circumference.
Now, look at the blast pattern
from the casino.
SIDLE:
Yeah, they're identical.
Hmm.
Now look at this.
See the outline
on the brick of
the C4 wrapper?
The rectangle?
There's enough explosive here to
level the entire casino floor.
Well, based on the tool marks
in the stick of putty,
the bomber only used a quarter
of the explosive.
Explains why there weren't
more casualties.
What's bothering me is
all the C4 we can't account for.
(piano playing upbeat melody)
♪ I'm a little caterpillar
inching along ♪
♪ I munch on leaves ♪
♪ Is that so wrong? ♪
♪ I sleep in trees
July to June ♪
♪ Hear me snore in my cocoon ♪
♪ When I wake up ♪
♪ I'm not a worm ♪
♪ Nature kicks in ♪
Closer to the kids.
♪ And then I learn ♪
Sure.
♪ I have wings ♪
♪ Oh, my, my ♪
♪ I'm a beautiful butterfly ♪
♪ Fly, fly, butterfly ♪
♪ High, high, up in the sky ♪
♪ High up in the sky ♪
♪ When you see me in the sky ♪
Sit down!
♪ ...how I fly ♪
(kids continue singing;
parents murmuring, whispering)
Should I pull it now?
I'm gonna pull it now.
MAN:
Hey, down in front!
WOMAN: Your seat's
back here, ma'am.
MAN: Hey, lady!
Pull it now?
Hey, you're blocking the view.
My God, she's got a bomb!
(everyone screaming)
Oh, my God! Go!
(screaming, clamoring)
(screaming, clamoring
fade into distance)
(door creaks shut)
♪ ♪
ANTHONY HURST:
Ma'am?
(over radio): I'm here from the
Las Vegas Bomb Disposal Unit.
Is it okay if I approach?
(sirens wailing in distance)
Are you doing okay?
(siren approaching)
You're doing great.
I just want to
check you out.
Can you tell me your name?
Ma'am, I...
I'm gonna have to get
a little closer to take a peek.
I'm gonna get you out
of here in no time.
Correction.
I'll get us out of here
in no time.
Oh, no, no, no,
no, no, no.
You don't want
to do that, ma'am.
You're already
a hero today, ma'am.
All the children
got out alive.
Why would she make me say that?
Someone's feeding her commands,
just like the male bomber.
Can you get audio on
the voice, male or female?
Anthony...
can you establish gender
of the voice in her ear?
No, negative.
The voice is too soft.
I got four
colored wires here.
I'm gonna have to
cut them in order.
WOMAN:
Okay...
I will. I'll tell him.
Sir?
I'm almost there.
Stop!
Time's up.
I just got one more.
I'm here for Lady Heather.
(explosion thunders)
(car alarms wailing)
OFFICER: Let's go! Move!
Inside! Move out!
Let's go!
Oh, my God.
(sirens wailing in distance)
(indistinct radio
communication in distance)
SIDLE:
It doesn't make sense.
Why wouldn't
the bomber take out
every man, woman and child
when she could?
I think whoever was on the
other end of that earpiece
was in the process of trying
to exercise control.
I think...
he was sending us
a message.
"He"?
You don't even think
there's a possibility
that Lady Heather was on the
other end of that earpiece?
I don't.
Gil, she's a puppeteer.
She's been controlling people
for a living for years.
So, according
to your theory,
Lady Heather is
the dominant in this scenario,
giving orders.
And the female bomber
is the submissive,
taking orders, right?
Right.
By rule,
the dominant is not allowed
to hurt the submissive.
And if, for some reason,
they do,
the submissive is allowed
to use the safe word
and discontinue the pain.
This is not some fetish game.
Sara, Heather
would never hurt anyone
with the intent to kill,
especially innocent people
and children.
It goes against everything
she stands for therapeutically.
What was your safe word
with her?
Stop.
We certainly could've
used that word today.
Hello, girls.
My name is Catherine Willows.
I'm a special agent
with the FBI.
You're probably wondering
why you're here.
(sighs quietly)
At school today,
did you hear
about anything happening
in the news?
Some kid said a bomb went off?
That's right.
There was an explosion
at the Eclipse hotel.
Mom works there.
I know, sweetheart,
that's why I'm here.
Is she okay?
I'm sorry, honey...
your mother passed
away earlier today.
(both crying)
But listen...
I want you to know that
I was with your mom
before she died,
and she held my hand
like I'm holding yours
right now...
and she told me
how proud she was
of her daughters
Maria and Helena.
What's gonna happen now?
Who's gonna look after us?
What about your father?
Mom was all we had.
We don't have anyone else.
I talked to the principal.
The woman who blew herself up
was a teacher here.
This is her classroom.
According to him,
she'd been put on
administrative leave twice,
for mental instability.
The school district
paid for a therapist.
You'll never
guess the name.
Dr. Kessler.
What kind of a person
straps a bomb to her chest
and self-detonates it
at a school?
Perhaps someone
under the influence
of Devil's Breath.
Burundanga.
The most dangerous drug
in the world.
It's a flower that grows rampant
in South America.
One whiff of its airborne
pollen, and the recipient
relinquishes all control.
They'll do anything
on command
from emptying their bank
accounts for strangers
to putting on a suicide vest.
I found these on
the teacher's desk.
My theory is that
who's behind the bombings
gave her these flowers
right before
she went into that school play.
Wow... (laughs)
Thank you.
Um, that's so sweet.
Uh, are you, are you a parent?
(inhales, exhales)
GRISSOM: Neurologically,
the drug is so potent,
it literally turned off
the judgment receptors
in her brain,
'causing her to kill
without processing
the consequences.
So, did the first bomber,
the male from the casino,
have Devil's Breath
in his system?
According to tox, no.
BRASS:
Well, I don't think
the male bomber
needed any extra flower power.
He was already pissed off at the
casino for losing all his money.
SANDERS:
So, what are the connections
between the two bombers?
Both were patients
of Lady Heather.
WILLOWS: Is she
the co-conspirator
in all this,
or the mastermind?
I think she's being framed.
SIDLE:
Uh, Grissom has this theory that
Lady Heather's being framed even
though he doesn't have a motive
and making every argument
to validate her innocence,
when everything
that he's ever taught us
about the
sanctity of evidence...
points to her.
Everything you say is true.
But we still
don't have proof.
So, what if it's not her?
Who else could it be?
Who might have access to things
they shouldn't have access to?
(device beeping
intermittently)
(device beeping continuously)
(beeping stops)
♪ ♪
Three months
of cassettes missing.
Hey, Jim.
(clunk nearby)
BRASS: Go ahead, Sara.
What's up?
Hello?
Jim, are you still outside?
I'm here.
There's someone in the house.
Dr. Kessler?
Dr. Kessler!
Stop right there!
Heather!
Stop! Don't move!
(engine starts, revs)
Heather!
You okay?
Yeah, I'm okay.
I'm all right.
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
Hey, hey.
You have some
thermal burns, okay?
We need to get you
to the hospital.
Just stay with me, all right?
Hold onto me.
This is CSI Sidle.
I need an ambulance
and the fire department.
DISPATCH:
Copy that, CSI Sidle.
(continues indistinctly)
...ambulance and fire.
♪ ♪
I'm sorry, Gil.
WOMAN: Ah...
MAN: Yeah, I mean,
we're hiring, so...
WOMAN: Hmm, yeah, well,
I know that, but...
you weren't paying
very much.
Hello, Heather.
Thank you for coming.
You still have your rings.
You never take
your rings off.
Why would I?
I have to bring you in.
Everyone in law
enforcement
thinks you're responsible
for these bombings.
I am.