Come on. Come on.
Let's go. Come on.
Don't fail me.
Come on, baby.
I'm feeling this one.
Don't fail me.
Don't you let me down.
Alright.
Black 22.
If this happens,
I'm buying you a shot.
No more bets.
Yes!
( screams )
Yeah.
WOMAN:
Give me my money.
Let's cash out.
Why? I, uh,
I thought we were going
to take some risks tonight.
Come on...
I want to go dancing.
Really?
Mm-hmm.
Okay. As long as
it's lap dancing.
What has gotten
into you?
Hey, buddy,
when you get a chance,
can I get a couple more
of these martinis?
One with an olive,
one with a twist.
Thank you.
Why don't we, um...
take those
up to the room?
'Cause I'm feeling a little...
( whispering ):
frisky.
Do you know them?
( chuckling ):
No,
but how frisky do you feel?
Hmm?
( both chuckling )
I'll try anything once.
Oh, really?
( dialogue inaudible )
Housekeeping coming in.
( screams )
( indistinct
radio transmission )
GRISSOM:
Her throat's been slit
by what appears
to have been
a very sharp implement.
The room is completely stripped.
No bedding, no sheets.
No towels, either.
Someone took a few souvenirs.
I'll check the
surveillance tapes.
Alice Dominguez.
She wasn't robbed.
It's not her room, either.
It was registered
under the name of Parker.
Wedding ring.
Where's the husband?
( faint, electronic whirring)
( sighs )
I think your cell phone's
vibrating.
You heard that?
Mm-hmm.
You're back.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
There's only two reasons
why people get murdered
in a casino.
Sex or money.
Well, on the money side,
the room was booked yesterday,
under a stolen credit card
belonging to a Mrs. Parker.
She's a 75-year-old
living alone in Henderson.
As far as sex goes, well,
I want to be a believer.
Room closest
to the exit.
Imagine that.
BROWN:
Quick escape.
Murder central.
Security cameras?
Uh, not in the hallway.
Only in the elevator.
We're on it.
Take the exit.
I'll take the money trail.
And I'll, uh...
go door-to-door.
This is very weird.
Yeah, usually when someone
gets their throat cut,
it's from behind.
Yeah, and it starts there,
ends there.
It's not very deep.
No ligature marks.
No defensive wounds.
I think whoever did this
was sitting in that chair.
She sat there and allowed
someone to slit her throat?
Hey, girl.
Hi.
What you got?
Not much.
Mrs. Dominguez checked in
with her husband yesterday.
Room 869.
869? That's, like,
two floors away
from where she
was found dead.
Anybody heard
from the husband yet?
He's MIA, but he left
a gambling paper trail.
Really?
I have a signature
and a thumbprint
from where Mr.
Dominguez signed
a $5,000 cash-advance check.
Cash advance, huh?
It was cash advance
on a credit card.
It's not cheap.
It's, like $90
every thousand.
That's a rip-off.
Not if you're desperate.
He must have
had a bad night.
Yeah, and Mrs. Dominguez
had a worse night.
You know, nobody's checked
their suite yet.
Would you care to join me?
Let's do it.
I heard some voices raised
and a door slamming.
Mm. How many voices?
Two.
No, wait.
Uh, maybe it was three.
Definitely a man and a woman.
What were they saying?
Uh, it was hard to tell.
You know, the walls in these
joints are pretty thick.
They were definitely arguing
about something.
Did you get a look at them?
Uh, just through the spy hole.
MAN:
Obviously he's insane.
They're both crazy.
WOMAN:
Why would you put me
in that situation?
I didn't put you
in that position with...
What time was that?
10:35.
10:35?
You seem to be
pretty sure about that.
Well, I-I had just ordered
a pay-per-view movie,
and it was just about to begin.
Oh, yeah? Which
one was that?
Arma-get-it-on.
You mean, Armageddon?
No. Arma-get-it-on.
Oh.
Good movie?
Worked for me.
Hey, guys.
How you doing?
Uh, I'm with the Las Vegas
Crime Lab, and I'm...
Nick Stokes?
Yeah.
What's up?
It's Kenny!
Kenny Richmond.
Rebel baseball.
I played backup catcher.
Kenny. Yeah!
Hi, Kenny!
Yeah!
How you doing, man?
How you doing?
Good to see you.
Good to see you!
Look at you, man.
Yeah. Yeah.
What are you
doing here?
You a cop now?
Uh, Crime Scene Investigator.
I'm on a case.
Crime Scene?
Rock on, man.
You're here on the
tenth floor thing, right?
Right.
Yeah. I heard
about that, man.
Everybody's talking about it.
Somebody, uh,
bashed some chick's brains
in, I think, right?
Yeah, actually, uh,
she had her throat slit
and bled out
all over the room.
I'll know more when I check
the surveillance camera.
Well, what are you
doing down here?
Uh, I'm just checking
possible escape routes.
She was murdered in the room
closest to the exit.
Murder central.
Murder central, huh?
Cool.
ROBBINS:
Cut began at the right carotid.
Severed the artery
and the jugular vein
and terminated at the trachea.
It's not as deep
as I would expect
for this kind of crime.
He sliced her gently?
Well, yeah.
Oftentimes,
the only thing intact
is the spinal column.
This did the job
and nothing more.
And what did the tox report
give us?
Alcohol count
was .20.
Double the legal limit.
There was no limit
to this woman.
Blood work showed
heavy traces of MDMA.
Ecstasy? And alcohol?
Party mix.
Yeah, it might have made her
docile.
Well, maybe it explains
why she was cut from the front.
That may explain
her head.
Now let's move
down to the toes.
Glitter?
Yeah.
There is a...
a strip club,
um, named Shimmer
on Industrial.
I, uh, recognized the "S"
almost immediately.
You go, Doc.
( knocking )
Hello?
Mr. Dominguez?
( sighs )
Looks like the bed
wasn't slept in.
Yeah.
Stopped for gas in Barstow.
Big tank. $43.
Clothes are still here.
Ford Explorer.
California plates.
Two-Paul-Charlie-Edward-329.
Really?
( horn honking in distance )
Hey, Warrick.
Take a look
at this wound.
It's different than the wife's.
She was cut from the front.
Yeah, this one looks like
he was cut from the back.
( screaming )
Hey, guys?
I got a knife.
Use this, uh...
cash-advance check
Warrick found as a reference.
Hmm. Ink pads make
for great exemplars.
And compare that
to the print I pulled off
the exit door
and the knife... please.
Here you go.
Good characteristics here.
Match to the door handle.
And a match to the knife.
One print on the knife.
One print on the exit door.
Both belonging to the husband.
But we have two victims.
GREG:
Speaking of twos...
I found blood from both victims
on the knife.
So it's possible
the husband killed the wife.
Who killed the husband?
( dance music playing )
WOMAN:
Yeah,
they look familiar--
from the neck up.
I must've given them
four, five
lap dances each.
They made my night.
So, they were George.
Big tippers.
No.
They weren't the ones
paying for it.
The other couple was.
The other couple?
Yeah, we were all
in the VIP booth over there.
The four of them--
they came in together.
The other couple
just wanted to watch.
So I assumed
they were friends.
Good friends.
I didn't get a good look
at the other two,
but they slid that money
across the table...
mmm, brick this big.
So, like I said,
they just wanted
to doggie in the window.
Watch.
And they were subbing drinks
left and right.
Ordering clear drinks
to keep the party going.
What'd they order?
Two vodkas, two soda waters.
Guess who got the hard stuff.
( cell phone rings )
Hi.
Would you like a dance?
Uh, I got to be
at the courthouse.
Apparently, there's a last-
minute evidentiary hearing
in the Sam Braun case.
I need to be there.
You sure
you don't want a dance?
I could be your specimen.
You could be my mad scientist.
He already is, sweetheart.
Thanks.
JOHNSON:
So, this is the last footage we
have of the Dominguezes alive.
SIDLE:
Who were they with?
Don't know,
but check it out.
Brass's witness said he heard
a couple arguing at 10:35.
This must be them, going down.
But coming up...
They're with the same
mystery couple
who brought up
the Dominguezes.
Can you make me a still
of the 10:35 couple,
the ones that went
up and down?
Freeze it there.
What's in his hand?
That's a room key.
Tangiers Hotel.
Do me a favor, Archie.
Call Grissom.
New leads in the double homicide
at the Sphere Hotel and Casino.
According to sources
within the crime lab,
the killer or killers
most likely fled the room
CSIs call "Murder Central,"
the nearest room
to the emergency exit.
CSIs are currently checking
surveillance footage
in an effort to identify
possible suspects.
What the hell?
What?
Kenny Richmond, that's what.
Who's that?
This valet at the Sphere.
I played baseball in college
with this guy.
I bumped into him
for, like, two seconds.
Don't tell me you opened
your mouth to the guy.
Hey, man.
You could lose your job
over something like this.
Hey, it's not like I ran
my mouth to the press, okay?
Best thing you could do
is go to Grissom and 'fess up.
'Fess up to what?
There were a hundred people
at that crime scene.
Anyone could have gone
to a reporter and told them
what was going on
with the case, man.
Or what, you going to wait
till he comes to you
and then lie about it?
Lie about what?
REPORTER:
Does this mean your murder case
will not be going
to trial, Mr. Braun?
Are you and your
representatives
in discussion with the
District Attorney's office?
Could you elaborate
on those discussions?
Do you feel vindicated
by the judge's decision?
My client has no comment
at this time.
Mr. Braun is looking forward
to putting this whole
unfortunate business
behind him.
Mr. Braun, do you have
anything to say at all, sir?
Mr. Braun, could we
get a comment?
Mr. Braun, do you have anything
to say at all, sir?
( siren wailing )
WOMAN:
It was first names only.
Mandy and... Cameron?
BRASS:
Where'd you meet them?
Uh, at the roulette tables.
We were, uh...
We were drinking
and they, uh,
invited us
back up to their room.
It was Vegas.
We were looking
for a little excitement.
And did you find it?
No, not at all.
They... creeped us out.
How?
He, uh...
He asked me
how much I loved my wife.
Is that a crazy question?
It wasn't the question.
It was...
the way he asked it.
How much do you
love your wife?
Sobered me right up.
I mean, he didn't
just ask it once.
He asked it... over and
over again, and then
Mandy asked how far
we'd go to prove it.
Prove what?
To-to prove that.
To prove how much
I loved my wife.
And, uh...
The next thing I know,
she's naked.
Then she starts
undoing his belt.
Which is the reason that we went
up there in the first place.
Yeah, but you liked it a lot.
You could've waited.
Yeah.
We argue about everything.
And they saw
us fighting.
And they kicked us out.
I don't know how fighting
works for your marriage,
but it probably
saved your lives.
Need some help with that?
Help with what?
That weight on your shoulders.
That obvious, huh?
Yeah.
What's up?
Oh...
Sam Braun.
Mm-hmm.
I heard about that.
He made his bones in Vegas.
I mean, what do you expect?
The guy's bulletproof.
I'm not.
Want to talk about it?
Sam told me it takes a lifetime
to establish a reputation
and just a second to ruin it.
When I suspected that Sam
was my father,
I didn't go to him.
I didn't go to Grissom.
I went to Greg
and had him run a DNA test.
On who?
On me.
What'd you use as an exemplar?
Blood evidence from his case.
That's why they kicked it.
Yup.
And I'm just afraid.
Of what?
A backlash.
You got a gut feeling
on this one?
Well, if it's
our serials,
they've downgraded.
BRASS:
Well,
we've got some ID.
Found her handbag.
Wendy Laggerman,
aged 24.
She's not
registered.
GRISSOM:
Where's her husband?
( shouts )
Oh, geez.
BRASS:
What was all
that about?
False alarm.
Apparently, the guy
just drove in
from Fresno.
Fell asleep
in his car,
and didn't even
check in yet.
Jesus!
Help!
Whoa. Hey. Hey, buddy.
Geez.
Take it easy.
This one's different.
Something's not right.
Okay, be careful, David.
The body's frozen, and
it's in full rigor.
You're going to
have to tilt it.
Tilt it, sir?
Yeah.
Downward
90-degree angle,
then up, tilt,
and out.
Okay. Uh...
All right, man.
Um...
I'll take the shoulders,
you take the feet.
Okay.
Okay?
You ready?
On three.
One, two, three, up.
And now tilt.
Come on. Up.
Okay, now tilt.
Oh, God.
Up more, tilt more. Now.
Uh, God.
Oh, down, down,
put him down.
One more time.
Ready, one time. One...
two, three, up.
Oh, God.
S-Sir, we can't get him.
Uh, his knee's bent.
Put him back
down carefully.
( sighs )
( train whistle blows )
( bone cracking )
( groans )
There.
Now try.
( distant sirens )
( garbled radio transmission )
Do we have to do the
inventory on all this?
Yeah. What, 15 buckets?
This is our first bucket
brigade together, gentlemen.
Try and say that
ten times fast.
Bucket brigade.
We have to do this quickly.
It's 120 degrees outside,
and our crime scene is melting.
Hold on a second.
I got something.
Whoa.
GRISSOM:
Would you like
to bag this
for me, Warrick?
My hands are little numb.
Sara?
Yeah.
Would you take
a sample of
this blood for me?
Sure.
Warrick, help her
process this.
Nick?
Yeah.
Come with me.
Shut the door, Nick.
You want to talk?
No.
I want to see the room
the way they left it.
You know, if it's anything
like the Sphere,
we're probably not going
to find much.
We're still
going to look.
Bathroom's clean.
Haven't you ever
seen one of those
before?
Not in person, no.
Magic Fingers.
25 cents for 15 minutes
of vibration.
Died a slow death in the '70s
due to vandalism
and seedy connotations.
Good for sex.
Good for sleep... too.
Good for us.
Given the killer's
appetite for sexual persuasion,
maybe they blew the circuit.
Overloaded it with coins.
And their prints
on those coins.
( camera shutter clicking )
( clicking )
Is that it? We're done?
I think so.
Well, power's back on.
So, why this place?
How do you go
from the Sphere to the Fez?
What do you think, Nick?
A reporter got some inside
information.
Killer probably heard
about himself
on the news,
changed his MO.
Oh, great.
Help the bad guys.
I'm sure the Laggermans
appreciate that.
I should probably
get those quarters
back to the lab,
work on the prints.
( vibrating )
I need 15 minutes to think.
Enjoy.
Hey.
Your spot of blood
on the ice
machine lid?
Yeah?
We've got
three alleles
on several loci.
Is it a mixture of more
than one stain?
One blood came
back the vic's.
The other came back unknown.
Oh.
Chances are that's our killer.
( beeping )
GRISSOM:
So they lure
their victims with
the promise of sex.
And then they get
them to the room.
And they say,
"Just kidding.
We don't want sex.
We want your life."
MAN:
It's about trust.
How much do you
love your wife?
Which still
doesn't explain
how they get
the husband to
kill his wife.
They had to have been
in some kind of situation
where they couldn't say no.
They had a gun
to his head.
MAN:
If you want to live,
you kill her by
your own hands,
or you both die.
They didn't think
he was just going to walk away.
Maybe he was hoping
to save his wife
from something worse.
MAN:
Tell me.
Do you love
your wife
enough to spare her
the suffering?
Rape, torture,
then murder.
MAN:
If you want
to live,
you kill her
by your own hand.
Or you both die.
( sobbing )
It's just so sick.
Why did he stick him
in the ice machine?
Well, I checked
with the manager.
The vic was
not registered.
No car.
So he had to improvise.
Where's your car?
We took a taxi.
Please don't kill me.
( grunts )
Well, knowing now there was
an odd mixture of blood,
it's safe to say
that someone cut themselves.
Someone's got blood
on their hands.
( computer beeps )
Mandy Klinefeld.
11546 Blackbird Lane.
Mandy and
Cameron Klinefeld.
I just pulled their
license photos off the DMV.
Brass showed them
to the motel manager.
Couldn't ID, so...
APBs are on the horn.
Come on, Grissom.
It's got to be them.
Who stays at a motel
when you live here?
Assume nothing, Nick.
BRASS:
Who found the car?
MAN:
Green Valley Ranch
security guard,
the one that actually bothers
to check the APB list.
( Brass sighs )
Let's see,
cabana number four.
GRISSOM:
There they are.
Cameron Klinefeld
and Mandy Klinefeld?
Now that's not
the cocktail waitress.
You and you go with
this officer, please.
Thank you.
You checked into
the Fez last night
under a false name.
We also suspect you
of identity theft
and felony fraud
at the Sphere Hotel as well.
They don't have the magic
fingers bed there, do they?
CAMERON:
We were at the
Fez last weekend.
I got a hooker. She watched.
She likes it.
It gets her off.
What's the problem?
BRASS:
The problem is,
people keep showing up dead
in your hotel rooms.
What are you looking at,
my feet?
No.
His feet, actually.
Shiny.
Isn't this harassment?
How much do you love your wife?
"Love is not love."
Shakespeare?
"Let me not the marriage
of true minds..."
"...admit impediments
Love is not love..."
"...but bears it out
till the edge of doom."
One of the sonnets.
Love is conditional.
For most people.
But not for you.
Okay, here we go.
We've got a husband-and-wife
serial team killing couples.
So, let's see where we're at
starting
with the first double murder.
Sara?
Bloody knife linking back
to Alice Dominguez.
WILLOWS:
We suspect
that Mr. Dominguez
was forced to kill his wife
for the promise
of freedom.
MANDY:
Come on. Do it.
Just cut her throat,
and you can walk
out of here.
STOKES:
That explains
the thumbprint
I found on the exit door
leading to the garage.
What, they take him for a walk?
They were never going
to let him go.
Doc Robbins
found evidence
of glitter
on Mrs. Dominguez.
I also found glitter
on Mr. Dominguez.
I found some
on Mr. Klinefeld's shoes,
so it's possible
the Klinefelds
picked up
their first couple
at Shimmer.
Did anyone at Shimmer
ID the Klinefelds?
I didn't get a good look
at the other two.
We didn't know who they were
at the time.
Okay...
that's it for the first murder.
What about the second?
Uh, we've got prints
on quarters.
We do have
an admixture of blood
off the ice machine.
What about prints
on the ice machine knife?
BROWN:
Forget it.
Ice destroyed it.
WILLOWS:
Okay, so, uh,
we're going to have
to get into
the Klinefelds' house.
If they haven't tossed
the towels and sheets...
we may have something.
BRASS:
No. Uh, look,
there's got to be some mistake.
We are this close to busting
a pair of serial killers
and the judge won't issue
a warrant?
Hey, I'm just the messenger.
BRASS:
Give me the affidavit.
CLERK:
He won't sign it.
It's not the first time.
Sorry.
MAN:
Look, I have signed hundreds
of search warrants
for Captain Brass, but...
this affidavit
lacks probable cause.
Prints on quarters,
an admixture of DNA...
DNA, if given a warrant,
will clear or convict...
...are not enough for me
Your Honor,
to invade the Klinefelds'
right to privacy.
with all due respect, you've
signed warrants for less.
Yes... and where did it get me?
Just last week,
the Appeals Court overturned
one of our convictions,
based on a search warrant
I gave to one of your sidekicks.
We make a habit of this,
I'm never going to get
to the Foley Building.
Federal appointment.
What if they kill again?
All the more reason
we need to get this right.
Unappealable.
The affidavit is thin.
You give me more...
I'll give you more.
Funny, doesn't look
like a doghouse.
Grissom
ratted me out, huh?
Um, no, you ratted
yourself out.
Hey, Nick, I know you're
proud of what you do.
You're good at what you do,
and you want people
to know what you do,
but once you open your
mouth, it's all over
'cause what we say
ends up in the news.
I guess I'm learning that
the hard way, huh?
All right, ( clears throat),
let's take a look.
You see, it looks
like something
got a little bit
more interesting
than roulette here.
So, if that's the lure,
where's the catch?
( taps keyboard )
Mm-hmm.
Clear drinks.
What do you want to bet the
Rifkins are drinking vodka
and the Klinefelds club soda.
Hmm.
Did you see that?
That was a little tongue
action right there.
So, if we're
creatures of habit...
If she stuck her tongue
in Mr. Rifkin's ear,
chances are she stuck it
in Mr. Dominguez's ear, too.
Mr. Dominguez
has already been autopsied.
Washed from head-to-toe.
What about the ice man?
( softly ):
Coroners.
He's not picking up.
Oh, hey, Doc. Doc.
Where's the ice man?
Uh, David's
cleaning him up.
David...
Whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa.
Drop the hose.
What did I do?
Did you go from head
to toe or head to toe?
Toe to head.
Good.
Good answer.
You run with it.
We get it yet?
Any minute now.
SANDERS:
Here it is.
Affirmative
for female DNA.
Where are the admixture results
from the ice machine?
Right here.
This is the same woman.
Whoever was in his ear
was on that ice machine.
STOKES:
She's the killer.
Please, let me go.
You guys...
( thuds )
This should get us a warrant.
Okay, split up.
Go around the back.
( sighs )
( doorbell ringing )
( TV playing in background )
Las Vegas Police.
Mr and Mrs Klinefeld...
We have a warrant.
We got a problem...
Somebody got to our killers
before we did.