I heard you got some head.
Just came in.
How'd you know?
I arranged
house seats
for David to see Celine,
so he pages me the minute
you get anything
perishable.
Sellout.
Oh... formaldehyde.
Yeah, it fixes tissue,
but it destroys DNA.
No ID through CODIS.
Quite a bit of leaf litter.
Puncture wound
above the orbital plate.
That looks like
animal activity.
Heavy decomp.
It's going to be, uh...
virtually impossible
to determine time of death.
This neck wasn't severed.
It was disarticulated.
No skill involved.
Oh-oh.
I take that back.
That took skill.
"The unkindest cut of all."
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
There's more plant material here
than geological.
Hair roots and scalp
are relatively clean.
So the vic wasn't buried?
You tell me.
I will.
Leaves and needles and dirt--
that's good as a map.
Any idea
when Grissom'll be back?
Nope.
It's going to be a while.
WILLOWS:
Jackpot, Nevada.
Where the hell is that?
( country music plays faintly)
Good morning.
I'm with the Las Vegas
Crime Lab, and I...
Hey, Alan!
This guy's here about the head.
MAN:
Bet a wolf got him.
MAN 2:
There's no wolves
around here, dumbass.
Bears.
Ten bucks says
satanic cult.
Lieutenant Alan Brooks.
This is my brother Leland.
How do you do?
Gil Grissom,
Las Vegas Crime Lab.
May I?
Have a seat.
Things must be
pretty slow
in Vegas to get one of
you guys out here so quick.
Well, the Elko County Sheriff
made the request.
We were happy to respond.
It's an interesting case.
Mmm, not particularly.
LELAND:
It was probably some hiker
or transient who got lost,
took a bad luck fall.
Must have been a heck of a fall.
His head's in a plastic jar.
BROOKS:
Listen, I filed
the report.
I sent in the head.
Five'll get you ten,
there's not much left
of that body out there
but coyote turds.
( chuckles )
Look, nobody from
this community's
been reported missing.
And I just don't
have the resources
to go searching
for what might be left.
Well, you do now.
There'd better be
a whole lot more
of you out there.
Have a good one, Marty.
Lieutenant,
the preliminary autopsy
revealed a single,
straight, two-inch cut
on the victim's jaw.
It was a blade mark.
So, there's not just a body out
there, there's also a killer.
HODGES:
Of all the plant life
gathered from the head,
the conifers are the key.
The one on the left--
Abies zasiocarpa.
The one on the right
is Picea engelmannii,
Engelmann spruce.
Spruce and fir trees.
Typical mountain forest.
Typical for 9,000
feet above sea level.
The wood fragments are
either cottonwood or aspen.
And aspens only grow in areas
that have been cleared.
Fire, roads or... logging.
After a major forest fire,
manzanita bushes
grow like weeds for decades.
No manzanita leaves here.
Which means
that the head
was on a damp north-facing
slope, at least 9,000 feet up,
cleared, but not recently
exposed to fire.
( phone rings )
Grissom.
WILLOWS:
Is the service
actually bad out there
or are you just
keeping your phone off?
I'm sorry.
I should've called.
This trip wouldn't
have anything to do
with you ducking case reviews,
now would it?
How can you think that?
You wouldn't mind taking care
of those for me, would you?
Oh, your job, my pay.
Why would I care?
I'll make it up to you.
Yeah, you had better.
Hodges ID'd your leaf litter.
Good. Thanks.
I owe you one.
Trouble with the wife?
Yeah.
She hates it
when we're apart.
GRISSOM:
So your dog found the head?
WOMAN:
Well, Tripper's not exactly
a Chihuahua.
Goes where he wants,
comes back for dinner.
Sometimes he brings
dinner back.
Tripper!
Come on, buddy, dinner.
Oh, what is it this time,
a rabbit or a possum?
Is he okay?
Well, he got a little lethargic
after chewing on that head.
Took him to the vet,
ran some tests.
He got better.
I just want to keep
him that way.
Where there's a head
there's got to be
hands and feet, and sooner
or later, he'll dig 'em up.
Or what's left of 'em.
No offense, Sylvia,
but he's not exactly
a scent hound.
GRISSOM:
All animals can smell
rotting flesh.
Studies have shown that
when domestic pets bring back
human body parts,
usually the remains
are within
a half-mile radius.
They do studies on that?
It occurs more than you think.
Have you noticed any buzzards
or vultures around?
All the time.
Thanks.
BROOKS:
So, are we done here?
This slope faces north,
doesn't it?
BROOKS:
Yeah.
You know that old expression,
"heads will roll"?
It's true--
especially downhill.
Barry, drop the doughnut.
You gotta earn your pay today.
BROOKS:
Afraid you're going to
trip over something?
GRISSOM:
I'm hoping.
Bodies make good fertilizer.
You often see fresh,
green shoots
near a gravesite.
Must be nice to know the answer
to every little thing.
I prefer questions,
actually.
And I don't,
I suppose.
Remember that
waitress, Doris?
Well, she's got an ex-husband
likes to smack her around
every once in a while.
High school's got
a dozen meth-heads
who like boosting
motorcycles
and then drag racing 'em
down Main Street, when they
think nobody's watching.
Fire chief's a closet pyro,
and so forth.
See, I don't have a lot of time
to ask questions about
buzzards and such.
That's an aspen tree,
in case you
were wondering.
Lieutenant!
Over here.
GRISSOM:
Step away from there,
would you please, fellas?
Don't disturb the scene.
( retching and coughing )
GRISSOM:
Carabid beetles.
Second instar maggots.
Formica obscuripes.
BROOKS:
Let me guess.
You like bugs?
Yeah, I do.
They're perfect.
They always do their jobs.
This body's been here
four to seven days.
How deep would you say
this hole is, Lieutenant?
I'd say about four feet,
depending on...
how he's stuffed in there.
Takes a fair amount
of dedication
to dig a hole this deep up here,
don't you think?
Unless the killer had help.
Maybe.
It's like you said--
he was cut.
This blood's not from a cut.
The drops imply
directionality.
The stellated circles imply...
perpendicular impact.
This spatter
is in direct line with
the victim's carotid.
It's arterial spurt.
Are you saying he was alive
when he was buried?
I think that the cut
we found on his jaw...
was a lure
to draw predators.
( screaming )
This wasn't just murder.
It was torture.
BROOKS:
Hey, Einstein, we going
to stand here all day or what?
You're going to have
to be patient, Lieutenant.
The scene hasn't been
released yet.
You know, this may be
a variation on an old Native
American form of punishment.
The body was bound
and buried up to its neck.
Tree sap
was poured over the head
to attract ants.
Punishment for what?
You see?
That's a good question.
About time, Dale.
You are the coroner,
I presume.
Mr. Grissom.
Dr. Dale Sterling.
I sent you the head.
How can I help?
Well, we can't touch the body
until you authorize it.
Oh.
He's dead.
You're authorized.
Thanks, Doc.
That's nice work.
Can we get it out now?
There may be evidence
in the gravesite.
We need to preserve it.
Okay, so what do you want
to do, call your lab?
Have them send
the right gear,
the right guys, what?
The site's already
been compromised.
We'll make do
with what we have here.
Now, for each foot of dirt
that's removed,
go on a separate bag.
I'll sift through it later.
All right. Out
of the way, Doc.
Pardon me.
Hold on.
Make sure your shovels don't get
within six inches of that body.
Can we please get on
with getting him out of there?
We're losing light.
I was in the
99th percentile
on the MCATs.
I could have gone
to med school.
I chose to be a vet.
Well, veterinary school's harder
to get into than medical school.
That's not
what I was looking at.
This is you and that gal
from the diner.
Doris.
We were married.
High school
sweethearts.
Didn't work out.
It's not all just cats and dogs
and spays and neuters.
I've delivered half a dozen
foals by C-section.
I know how to cut.
I could... I could do
the autopsy right here.
Only a licensed pathologist
can perform an autopsy.
All we're
allowed to do
is search for evidence
on the body.
And then what?
Then we take
it to Vegas.
Tonight. We'll need someone
to drive the body.
Barry, it's your lucky day.
Get your car.
Come on.
Our medical examiner
will send you
his report.
You'll need to sign
the death certificate
as to cause and manner of death.
No wallet and no ID.
What have you got there?
Well, I'm not sure yet.
No ligature marks.
Well, he wasn't tied up?
Apparently not.
Well, no one just
lets themselves
get buried alive.
Well, maybe the killer
had a gun on him.
Well, you can't dig a hole
and hold a gun
on an unbound victim
all at the same time.
Well, maybe the hole was dug
earlier?
That would imply premeditation.
Or more than one killer.
Maybe the victim was drugged.
Sylvia Rogers's
dog got sick after
chewing on the victim's head,
correct?
That's right.
Did you do blood work?
I sent it off
to a lab in Reno.
Still waiting for the results.
Call the lab.
Have them do a full drug
and tox panel on the blood.
Maybe whatever was
in this man's body
is also in the dog's.
Hold on a second, fellows.
Okay.
Say cheese.
Oh, what the hell
was that for?
Souvenir.
Why, is that French
for evidence?
Straight drive, Barry.
Stay out of the casinos.
You got it, boss.
You boys have a good night.
( engine starting )
Man.
It was one hell of day.
You need a place to sleep?
I need a place to work.
( door opening )
Did I miss a memo or something?
Oh, no.
Grissom's on a safari.
He's got you pushing
his paperwork, huh?
Oh, no. I'm trying
to avoid that.
His headless D.B. had
a Western LVU bookstore receipt
in his pocket.
Grissom just unraveled it.
Really?
Wow!
Some of these books
are 100 bucks a pop.
Tuition,
plus room and board--
that's at least another 10K.
You got to have money
to go to college these days.
Yeah, well, I missed that boat.
So, most of these
are freshman textbooks.
Core curriculum.
Well, that's at least
2,000 students.
Maybe you'll get lucky
with the victim's prints.
Oh, wait. Hang on.
Chiaroscuro Theory
and Technique.
It's a sophomore-level
Fine Arts text.
Freshman in a sophomore course?
Narrows the field.
BRASS:
Actually, we're here
about your roommate,
Ross Jenson.
Do you know where
we can find him?
Uh, I actually haven't even
seen him since last Friday.
I had Wheezer tickets,
and we were supposed to go,
but he, uh, he blew me off.
Gone almost a week.
That normal?
Yeah, he's an art student,
you know.
He goes off a lot,
and for days sometimes.
Uh-huh.
I've been, uh, studying my ass
off for this American History
midterm, but, uh,
feel free to have
a look around.
That's not mine.
I don't know what that is.
Relax, buddy.
This is a homicide
investigation.
Are these Ross's shoes?
What do you got?
Aspen leaf.
A little piece
of the countryside.
Has Ross spent
a lot of time up
in northern Nevada?
Yeah, he liked the scenery
up there.
We're going to need
to take that computer
and a few things
back to the lab.
Okay.
( whirring )
WOMAN:
Yeah.
Came in here last week.
Handsome boy.
Nice clothes.
Just passing through.
There's, uh, fried chicken,
me...
Coffee's about all
I can handle right now.
Maybe some other time, okay?
WOMAN:
Guess you weren't his type.
MAN:
Wasn't he the guy
driving that gutless
little four-banger?
What kind of car was it?
I don't know.
Kid's car.
Something to drive
around the city.
It's no good
for hills.
Black, or, what,
blue, maybe.
Lieutenant?
Yeah.
The victim was on his way
out of town.
We know he didn't get very far.
So where's
his vehicle?
Anybody here
seen a black or blue
mystery vehicle?
No. Uh-uh.
No.
Well, I'd say that car's
long gone by now.
If the killer
was a local,
he could have ditched the car
somewhere near here.
Do you have a local suspect?
It's a theory.
Oh.
And like any theory,
it doesn't mean anything
unless you can prove it.
Yeah.
May I borrow this?
The victim was last
seen here, right?
Yeah.
We found his body
here.
Mm-hmm.
This is the only way
out of town.
The killer had
to intercept him
somewhere along this road.
Knock yourself out.
( car alarms beeps )
( creaking )
( car alarm blares
in distance )
( car alarm blaring )
( alarm stops )
( sighs )
Hey, Doc, I need to use
some of your medical supplies
and make a telephone call.
It's local.
Uh... okay.
Did you tint these windows yourself?
M...aybe not the best job
in the world,
but it does the trick.
Do you have
any tinting film left?
Think so.
May I use it?
Okay. I'll have to go check.
Oh, good, the police.
I'd like to report a crime.
No kidding?
Yeah, my vehicle
was broken into
and my field kit
was stolen.
That's going to
cramp your style.
Not necessarily.
( bell dings, door creaks )
Would you keep an
eye on this for me?
Sure.
Thanks.
Excuse me.
( bell dings )
Listen, why don't you
come on by
and fill out a report
about that kit.
You think that would help?
( chuckles )
It wouldn't hurt.
I, uh, found the victim's car.
Well, I am impressed.
Wh... Where was it?
It was, uh, ditched
in an old barn up in the hills.
Uh-huh.
I know you don't have
any men to spare,
so I called the
Highway Patrol.
They're sending troopers
up there to secure the site.
Oh, well,
nearest station's in Elko.
Should take 'em a couple hours
to get here.
Well, that should, uh,
give you enough time
to burn down the barn.
You going to just
stand there,
or are you coming in?
Oh, I don't want
to disturb the scene.
You carry on.
Shame to see so much work
go to waste.
What does that
mean exactly?
Well, unless
you've managed
to improvise yourself
a warrant as well,
this is an illegal search.
This barn had been broken into,
which makes it a crime scene,
even without the murder
victim's car inside,
so I don't need a warrant.
Who owns this place?
Nobody.
Owner died
a few years ago.
Well, then who's responsible
for the property?
His nephew.
Marty Cooperman.
Runs the gas station.
Is that who you're protecting?
Hey, you think you
can fix this window?
Yeah, I think I can fix that.
You know that kid
that got murdered?
We found his car
up in the hills.
In your uncle's old barn.
Oh, I haven't been up there
for years.
That's understandable.
It's hard to get to.
Not too many gas
stations around here.
You must do pretty
good business.
Yeah, I got the only pumps
for 23 miles.
I do pretty good.
You know, uh,
the victim's car
was full of gas.
So you must've
seen him, right,
even though you
said you didn't?
I can have your window fixed
in a couple hours, Mr. Grissom,
and then you can
get back home.
I think you should do that.
( phone rings )
Grissom.
Everybody in Sleepy Hollow
still drawing a blank
on the victim?
More or less.
Well, then somebody's lying.
Ross Jenson was having
a relationship
with someone in Jackpot.
Greg traced a series
of romantic IMs
from your victim's computer.
Greg did?
Yeah, he knows stuff.
Pretty hot stuff, too.
Sounds like he was in love.
Brass is still working
on a court order for the name.
You ever coming back?
Hopefully.
Ms. Willows,
this came for you,
certified mail.
Oh. Thanks, Judy.
( footsteps approaching )
STERLING:
Just got the
blood test results
back from Sylvia's dog.
There were traces of GHB
in his system.
I thought GHB
was a party drug.
It is.
It's also a powerful sedative.
Could be what was
used to subdue him.
You know anybody in town
that would use this?
( chuckles ):
Uh, weed and speed
are the drugs of choice
around here.
Hey, Doc, take a look
at the scope, will you?
I found some hairs
in Ross Jenson's shirts.
That is cat hair.
Tricolored.
Probably...
Abyssinian.
You wouldn't happen to have
any Abyssinian patients?
One.
Uh... Ah.
Here she is.
Isis.
Her owner has allergies.
He needed an aggressive,
shorthair
mouser.
Excuse me, Lieutenant.
We need to talk.
So talk.
Privately, please.
Just call them.
What?
Ross Jenson was having
a romantic relationship
with someone in this town.
And you can you prove that?
Yes.
I believe he was up here
visiting that person.
I found cat hairs
on his T-shirts.
From an Abyssinian cat.
The kind your brother owns.
Just what the hell
are you saying?
Does your brother live alone?
Yes.
Is he gay?
That is nobody's business.
I realize that,
but it's relevant
to this investigation.
No, he was married.
He has a kid.
Was married?
She left him flat,
ten years ago. So, what?
Look, whether you like it
or not, Leland is a suspect.
But you already
knew that.
I'm giving you
an opportunity, Lieutenant.
So far, you're only guilty
of being a good brother.
Get in.
What are you worried about?
You do have a gun, don't you?
( engine starting )
Look, um, just give me
a minute with him.
Hey, Bubba.
Leland.
We need to ask
you a few...
What's he doing here?
Never mind him.
You and I need
to have a talk.
( door closes )
( cat meows )
Put that down!
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Put that down!
I don't know what
you're talking about!
( gunshot )
Let me do this!
Don't you...!
Leland!
Let me do this!
( sobbing )
You're going to keep Leland
in there, right?
Yeah, until
he's ready to go home.
He took at shot at me,
and he tried to kill himself.
That's not the way I saw it.
FYI,
Leland's always run pretty hot.
That's no secret.
Matter of fact,
back in high school
he and Marty Cooperman
played football together.
One Friday night,
after a couple of beers,
Marty started
busting on Leland.
And Leland just busts him back.
And I helped.
And we fractured Marty's leg
in three places.
So I should be grateful that
you showed restraint with me.
No, I didn't do it for you.
A man shouldn't go through life
ashamed of who he is.
What is this?
A way to get you to talk to me.
Well, I didn't come here
to talk.
I came to give it back.
Not enough?
You're a murderer.
Not in the eyes of the law.
You look good, Mugs.
How's Lindsey?
She likes horses, right?
Lindsey's none
of your business.
You keep her out of this.
I'm her grandfather.
Yeah, well,
nothing I can do about that.
Catherine, it's just a gift.
You need the money.
And the next time you stab
one of your showgirls
and you need CSI to cover it,
I'm supposed to help you out,
right?
Take a good look at me.
Plenty of fresh air,
sun on my face.
You think I need your help?
I don't need your charity.
You know what
your problem is?
You enjoy making life hard.
You're lucky Lindsey's
too young to understand that.
Cash it,
or tear it up.
Do whatever you want.
I have one son in jail...
another in the ground.
I never did right
by your mother.
But I'm damn sure going
to try to do right by you.
Hey, Catherine...
Hey.
What's up?
A possible inconsistency.
Hey...
you have a phone call.
Line two.
I think it's your wife.
Thanks.
Hello, dear.
The day Ross Jenson left Vegas,
he used MapQuest
to get directions
from his dorm to Jackpot.
Well, that makes sense.
From what I've been able
to gather, this was
his first and only visit
up here.
Well, that doesn't make sense.
He was involved with someone
in Jackpot for several months.
There were traces
of aspen leaves
in his dorm room closet.
I just assumed
he'd been there before.
Well, if I believe this was
his first and only visit,
how do we explain the leaves
in his closet?
He has a roommate.
Does the roommate have a name?
Yeah, his name is...
Eric Brooks.
Eric Brooks?
Oh, yeah,
that's Leland's boy.
You guys going to tell him
about his dad?
BRASS:
Did you know your
father was having
a sexual relationship
with Ross Jenson?
My dad's not gay.
Was Ross?
We never talked
about it.
BRASS:
Were you in Jackpot,
Nevada last weekend?
No.
Ross Jenson was...
visiting your dad.
We found his car
ditched in a barn
outside town.
We got your fingerprints
from a former
ROTC commander of yours,
and...
they matched a print
that we recovered
from the steering wheel.
He let me borrow his car
all the time.
We were roommates.
BRASS:
That's right.
You don't own a car.
You ride a motorcycle.
Yeah.
So?
Could I see the bottom
of your shoes, please?
Well, that's an
unusual wear pattern.
Matches the shoe print
we recovered
from the barn
near the vehicle.
Put a lot of miles on your bike.
It shows.
You were there.
GRISSOM:
Eric must've known for a while.
How did you intend
to keep the relationship
from your own son?
I've been hiding it
my whole life.
You knew.
Yeah...
I figured you'd tell me
when you were ready.
I saw you
with Ross.
I stopped by here
last weekend.
You and he were taking a walk.
I'm sorry.
You got nothing
to be sorry about.
Nothing.
Lee, it turns out
Eric...
Mr. Brooks, your son
killed Ross Jenson.
That is not possible.
According to the evidence,
it is.
WILLOWS:
We tested the thermos
and found traces of GHB.
You used Ross' drugs
to subdue him.
BRASS:
It's a long drive
from Jackpot to Vegas.
You knew he'd stop for a refill
before he left town.
( horn honking )
Eric never could deal
with the fact
that his mother left.
She just wanted a husband.
All I wanted was a family.
ERIC:
People in town...
they said my dad
was "different."
But he wasn't.
He was just lonely.
And Ross, like, totally
used that to ruin him.
It was all Ross.
That why you drugged him?
Drove him
into the woods?
Put him in a hole...
buried him up to his neck...
cut him...
ROSS:
What are you doing?
( screams )
Why didn't you go the distance?
Why didn't you
finish him off
yourself?
Because I wanted him to suffer.
Because he was in love
with your father?
Or because
he wasn't in love with you?
I don't suppose
that comes with a warranty?
Nothing around here does,
Mr. Grissom.
Thanks for the business.
Hey, Marty.
Does he ever
talk to you?
Not one word
since high school.
Listen, when we found
that torso in the hole,
on the crest
of that hill...
I recognized the kid's shirt,
and I knew he'd been
with Leland, so...
So you assumed your brother
was capable of murder.
Didn't even ask him
what happened.
Questions, remember?
Not asking them
is what got everybody
in trouble here
in the first place.
You don't keep any secrets,
Mr. Grissom?
Not even from your wife?
I used to.
I'm trying to change.
It's a bitch.
Have a good trip.