( siren blares distantly )
♪ ♪
( police radio plays
indistinctly )
( siren blares distantly )
BRASS:
Ready for us?
For now,
no one enters this house
except CSI.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
Warrick, you got the car.
Which one?
Both.
Uh, take the Honda.
The VW belongs to the victim's
friend, over there.
She called it in.
BROWN:
Aw, that's too bad.
This will be a day
she'll never forget.
Sara, you take the perimeter.
What?
You just did
a one-hour walk-through.
The perimeter cannot be
a priority.
I need you to work the outside.
Catherine and I will be inside.
I'll go talk
to the friend.
Find out where she walked
and what she might
have touched in there.
Hey, Jim.
Hmm?
Did you talk to that guy
across the street?
The neighbor?
He's on my list.
Yeah, he looks like he
has something to say.
Hi, I'm Catherine Willows.
I'm with the crime lab.
What is your name, miss?
Kelly McNeil.
Deb and I
are best friends.
We were supposed
to get together yesterday.
It was our day off.
You're a nurse?
Yeah. Both of us.
Desert Palm Hospital.
We made lunch plans,
but she canceled.
She give a reason why?
Michael.
!
Michael?
Michael Clark.
Um, she's been seeing him
for a month or so.
He's a surgical intern.
When she didn't show up
for work today,
I called the house.
Her cell... no answer,
so I drove by after shift.
And how did you get in?
We have each other's keys.
Did you touch anything inside?
No.
I walked in and...
I saw her and I ran out.
Kelly, this, uh, Michael--
is he just a guy, or is he
somebody special?
He was the first guy that Debbie
ever blew me off for.
And did you see him today,
at the hospital?
No. I figured they were both
playing hooky.
MAN:
Moved in about two months ago.
Single girl.
Alone in the house.
Got my attention.
I'm running for captain
of the Neighborhood Watch.
I'll probably have
to self-appoint myself,
but I'm going
to put out a flyer,
you know, about shutting doors,
locking windows,
I mean, the thing is...
you just don't think
it's going to happen to you.
You know what I'm saying?
On your block...
Listen, Pike.
Stop talking.
I never seen somebody
so excited
about their neighbor
being killed.
Let me tell you something:
I know the business of everyone
up and down this block,
all right?
Who's cheating on his wife,
who's behind on his bills,
whose kid's going
to become the next Manson.
Let's talk about Debbie Marlin.
You know what they say
about nurses.
What's that?
That-that they like to party.
Hey, look. You see
a stethoscope around this chest?
No. You want to know why?
I'm not a doctor.
So I couldn't even
get close to her.
Well, who is getting close?
It's like a fricking
doctor auto mall over there.
You know, hunky surgeons,
board certified,
lots of dough.
And if you want my opinion,
I think they were
dropping quarts.
Okay, did you notice
any automobiles,
any cars out front?
You know, as a matter
of fact, sir, yes.
Black Mercedes, E320.
2004 model,
been there about a month.
Rolls in all hours.
I'm figuring on call,
booty call.
That kind of thing.
When's the last time
you saw the Mercedes?
Two days ago. Around lunch.
And, uh, I think he stayed
for a little bit of dinner, too.
Thanks a lot.
Yeah, this is
Detective Jim Brass.
See if you can find a 2004
Mercedes, black,
registered
to a Michael Clark, M.D.
Thanks.
I have absolutely nothing.
How are you doing?
I got a lot.
Check out the backseat.
Bananas.
Stuffed Mushrooms.
Chocolate syrup,
a six-pack of soda,
a box of condoms.
No surprises there.
Fresh bag of groceries
in an unlocked car?
Maybe she was interrupted.
One thing I can never
get over
with this job:
anything can happen to anybody.
That's why we're here.
I bet this bathroom was the
reason she bought this place.
What am I smelling?
Cleanser.
Bleach maybe.
Arterial spray is neck high.
Indicates she was standing
when she was attacked.
And the highest gush of blood
has the most volume.
Definite lack of lividity.
She must have bled out.
The killer had
to get something on him.
Had to be a bloody mess,
but there's no...
footprints,
there's no handprints,
no smears.
She looks like
she was placed
in this position.
What's the message?
What do we got here?
Pendale's Milk.
Non-fat. Half a gallon.
Unopened.
Groceries that
made it inside.
Fancy crackers...
brie.
Coupons with no receipt.
No receipt?
This milk expires on the 23rd.
Eight days from now.
Milk is delivered daily
to the supermarket.
That's a ten-day window.
People usually reach back
for a fresh one.
Hmm...
Subtract ten from the 23rd?
She was at Pendale's
two days ago.
Well, according to Brass,
that was the last time
her boyfriend's car
was seen out front.
Positive for both.
Same here.
So there's blood
in all four drains,
followed by bleach.
He kills Debbie in the shower.
Then he washes up
in both sinks
and in the tub?
Why?
The answer is in the drains.
♪ ♪
He cleaned everywhere
but inside the shower.
WILLOWS:
We're never going to know
where the blood ends
and the bleach begins.
Where's all this blood
coming from?
Dr. Clark is
on my surgical rotation.
He was scheduled
to assist this morning.
No show.
Oh.
Was that like him?
No. It's completely
out of character.
See, half of these interns
come in here so scared,
they couldn't carve a turkey.
I have to give them scalpels
with training wheels.
Clark was different.
He, uh,
he's a real artist,
a steady hand.
Yeah, he has a gift.
How about outside the O.R.?
Was he socially gifted?
He turned a lot
of nurses' heads,
but it never interfered
with his work.
Why the questions?
Debbie Marlin,
one of your nurses,
was murdered.
Throat slashed.
You didn't know this?
Dr. Clark and
his "steady hand"
haven't been seen
or heard from since,
so you don't have to
be a brain surgeon
to guess what I'm thinking.
( pager beeping )
Uh... all I can ask
is that I...
I hope that you're wrong
about Dr. Clark.
Excuse me.
No cleansers.
No rags, no sponges,
no paper towels...
You'd think that she restocked
when she went shopping.
Well, I'm thinking the killer
used everything the victim had.
And then disposed of it.
( trash can lid thuds )
WILLOWS:
Nothing.
( flies buzzing )
( lid thuds )
BROWN:
Nothing here.
( buzzing )
I think I found
the victim's internal organs.
This guy meant business.
I think I can confirm
the victim's male.
It seems he vacuumed
to remove any trace
from the house.
WILLOWS:
City picks up the evidence
and spreads it
all over the dump.
We have the victim's clothes.
Very neatly folded.
BROWN:
Well, if this is
our boyfriend, then...
...Brass is looking for a ghost.
( sighs )
♪ ♪
Heard about the shower.
Nurse, huh?
Multiple hairs,
multiple donors.
Looks like she had
a few "friends" over.
A little Nurses Gone Wild.
Blanched.
Killer poured bleach
down all the drains.
Talk about sucking all the life
out of DNA.
If there's anything left,
it's probably denatured.
( quiet dripping )
Wait a minute.
Wait, wait, wait...
Bleach might have missed
this one.
( gurgling )
Lucky for us...
we got a skin tag.
She's exsanguinated
Time of death is
anybody's guess.
Rigor's past,
so it's over 24 hours.
Deep incised wound
of the anterior
and lateral neck,
transecting
both carotids
and the anterior trachea.
Cut's clean.
Extremely sharp,
short instrument.
Scalpel?
That's what I'm thinking.
You know, I caught
a 25-pound yellowtail
last year off the
coast of Mexico,
and it took me
half an hour to filet.
Dismembering
an adult male
with this precision
and without cutting
through the bone,
12 hours minimum.
Half a day.
That's patience.
The, uh, patella
was cleanly removed.
And with one slice,
the femur was separated
from the tibia and the fibula.
There's a perverse elegance
to this butchery.
Oh, I'm not so sure
I see it that way.
A killer with knowledge
of anatomy
whose tool
is a scalpel.
I think the butcher
was a doctor.
So David, isolate
all ten fingers, ink them,
give Jacqui the ten-card.
We need to know who he is.
( cell phone ringing )
Grissom.
SIDLE:
Hey.
Sara, uh, listen,
I'm in a bad area.
I'll call you back.
I got a skin tag
off the bathtub drain pipe.
Skin tag? That's great.
Uh, give it to Greg.
Yeah, I did.
Hey, do you want me
to come over there
and give you a hand?
No, I-I'm fine.
I'll-I'll, uh...
I'll talk to you
back at the lab.
( phone beeps )
Hey, where'd Brass find the car?
Long-term parking
at McCarran.
Ran the plates.
R.O.-- Dr. Michael Clark.
The head of security
is giving us a copy
of the surveillance tape.
So, he kills her
and whoever she was with,
and then he hops a plane?
Well, it seems like that.
You know what they say
down at P.D.
The quickest way
to get a car stolen
is to leave it at the airport
unlocked.
( door clunks open )
See what I mean?
Who doesn't know that?
Black powder on a black dash.
I know.
Let's just superglue it, huh?
♪ ♪
Wipes and swirls.
He cleaned everything
but the driver's seat.
Well, he had to drive himself
to the airport, right?
He put something on the seat.
Whatever he put,
he took it with him.
The black,
plastic bag.
He missed a piece.
SIDLE:
He puts a bag on the seat,
and then he adjusts it.
How tall was he?
Five-nine, according to
the DMV report?
Wow. I'm six-two, and this is
more than enough room for me.
So, whoever was driving
this car,
was way taller than five-nine.
Two days ago, Debbie Marlin
is off work.
Sometime in the morning,
she buys groceries.
It's from Pendale's, the closest
store in West Charleston.
Brass talks
to the box boy,
remembered her,
saw her just before
his lunch break at 11:15.
Pendale's is about
20 minutes from her house.
Where's Nick?
American Academy of Forensics
Science convention.
GRISSOM:
Hey, guys,
can we continue, please?
She comes home
from the grocery store.
She parks in the driveway,
and she begins to unload.
Puts down her perishables first.
She has to go back
for second shifts,
so she probably leaves
the front door open.
Explains why
there was no forced entry.
WILLOWS:
Getting ready for a date.
Lighting candles.
Multitasking.
BROWN:
She opens up a bottle of wine,
two glasses.
WILLOWS:
Her girlfriend said that
she was locking down
for the afternoon
with Michael Clark.
Nosy neighbor puts the Mercedes
in the driveway
sometime around noon.
Thought you guys
would want to know.
The hair Sara found
is a match to the bags
of human tissue.
Prints confirm it.
Per Jacqui, it's Michael Clark.
WILLOWS:
So, um, most of our efforts
have been
towards identifying
another victim.
GRISSOM:
Michael Clark.
But can we place him dead
at the house?
Greg, what else can you tell us
about that hair?
You mean hairs?
There were two.
Ancillary, maybe
arm or leg hair.
Found it in the tub drain.
The abattoir of choice...
for dismemberments.
According to Jacqui,
there were no prints found
on the scalpel blades or handle,
but the blood's
a match to both victims.
So Michael Clark was dead
in the tub.
We just don't know
how he got there.
Well, I KM'd the carpet at
the threshold of the bathroom.
It's negative for blood.
So all the violence took place
in the bathroom,
at least anything
that had to do with blood.
WILLOWS:
The bathroom is big,
but it's not big enough
to kill two at the same time.
GRISSOM:
She lights the candles
in the shower.
Her back is to the door.
He grabs her from behind...
...and slits her throat.
Then he positions her body
so that her face
is the first thing
the boyfriend sees
when he walks in.
So he takes seconds
to kill Debbie.
So why does he spend so much
time cutting up Michael Clark?
Most likely because
Michael Clark was the real focus
of his rage.
♪ ♪
Don't tell me
you never went home?
Okay.
I just got started in here.
I haven't even gotten
to the other rooms yet.
You know you lose your edge
after 16 hours.
You're into your third shift.
I mean, I'm all for overtime,
but this is just plain greedy.
My knees can't take this
anymore.
Have you eaten anything?
What did you bring?
I'll see what's in the fridge.
We have to replace that,
you know.
( coughs )
( coughing )
Hey... black lung.
Ha, ha.
I've been sifting
through this trash
for about six hours.
You coming to rescue me
or make fun of me?
I am just looking. Relax.
What are these
white fibers here?
They must be
from the spare bedroom
because all the other carpets
are green.
Spare bedroom wasn't on
his entrance or exit path.
Look, all I know is that they
were near the top of the bag,
so it must have been one of
the last things he vacuumed.
I did happen to find
this butterfly pendant,
with some white fibers
on it.
It looks like it's from
a necklace or a bracelet
and it has this link
that snaps,
so I'm thinking...
sign of struggle?
The killer was in
that spare bedroom.
Feel better?
Well, now that we fed you,
we should probably
talk about a shower.
I mean at your place.
You need to go home.
As soon as we find
some evidence, I promise.
With fresh eyes,
you won't miss it.
Just talk it through with me,
will you?
What do we know?
All right.
The bathroom is where
things got started--
candles, oils,
steam shower,
cleaned up, oiled up,
sexed up.
Let's go back to the bedroom.
No, nothing on this sheet.
She changed her sheets
for her date-- I would.
Hey, Cath?
Got silk?
Why, yes, I do.
( wood creaking )
I don't mean to
embarrass you,
but, um...
...some guys need leverage.
( wood creaking )
They do?
I'll dust for prints.
( phone ringing )
Grissom.
Hey, Warrick.
Butterfly? Where?
I haven't checked
the spare bedroom.
I'll call you back.
♪ ♪
Hang one.
Toe print.
I'll have Sara compare it
against both victims.
Good.
Warrick found a
butterfly charm
in the vacuum bag.
I think I just found a piece
from the same chain in this box.
Butterfly, huh?
She had a collection.
Gifts from her...
gentlemen callers?
Maybe the killer was taking
his gift back,
as in leave no trace.
Maybe he finally
ran out of patience
and got sloppy.
And this is why
I didn't leave.
♪ ♪
Hey, you seen Grissom?
He's still at the crime scene.
I eliminated both victims
from the print you pulled
off the bed.
Well, we know she was fishing
off the company pier.
You, uh, seen Debbie?
Yeah.
And?
Yeah, I compared her toe prints.
If I didn't know better
I'd think that was you
on that table.
I didn't really
look at her face.
When you see Grissom,
will you tell him?
MAN:
Oh, that feels nice.
Do you have something
to take this off?
Just step
on the card, please.
Good thing you caught me
early in the shift.
Yeah, lucky for me.
I think I could probably tell
who pulled a double.
Listen, I've got a
patient waiting in pre-op.
We'll have you out in a minute.
We appreciate
you providing your
prints voluntarily.
Well, there's probably
a little bit
of a lot of us
in Debbie's house.
Oh, we'll know soon enough.
Thank you.
You understand, right?
The police aren't the only ones
with a code of honor.
Now, some of these men
are married,
and if this gets out...
Nothing gets out unless
it needs to get out.
Got a match.
Dr. Tripton.
BRASS:
I'm afraid your
patient in pre-op
is going to have to wait
a little while longer.
Don't really know
why I'm here.
Your toe print was
found in Debbie
Marlin's house.
Same house
she was murdered in.
Her car was in the shop,
and I gave her
a ride home one night,
and she invited me in
for a cup of coffee.
She didn't like anyone
wearing shoes in the house.
Some Feng Shui thing.
So, you Feng Shuied
your way to the bed?
She was provocative.
You take your coat off,
she has her clothes off.
She came on to me.
Come on, Doc,
let's do it.
Take a look.
All right, well, let's talk
about what's not open
to interpretation.
Yours were the
only prints found
in the house.
Michael Clark was
on your rotation--
he was on your
surgical team
the day he was killed.
You called in sick.
Surgery was canceled.
Freed him up to
be with Debbie,
who also had the
day off. What luck.
My son had a ball game.
My daughter
was at a swim meet.
My wife was at a conference,
and the surgery was elective.
Not a stretch.
Your wife know about
you and Debbie?
No.
She asked for sex, right?
She also asked for the
bracelet, too, huh?
No, but... I gave it to her.
This one.
She loved butterflies.
Uh, I figured if I gave
something special to her,
she'd give
something special to me.
Hmm.
So it was a long-term
relationship?
SANDERS:
That's the spare bedroom hair.
There's an oily film
on the surface of the hair.
Propylene glycol.
Active ingredient in Rogaine
for male pattern
baldness.
Personally, I
don't use the stuff,
but my grandfather,
Papa Olaf--
he was Bruce
Willis at age 16.
Lucky for me,
baldness comes from
the mother's side,
so I'm safe...
Greg, please,
I'm very tired.
Well, maybe the guy we're
looking for is going bald...
or trying not to.
According
to Papa Olaf,
a lot of guys who
use Rogaine also
use Propecia,
kind of like
a cocktail.
I ran the hair through MassSpec.
I got four peaks: ethyl alcohol,
propylene glycol, minoxidil,
and finasteride.
Finasteride,
the chemical name for Propecia.
But wait, there's more,
and it's a family secret.
Sexual. Happens in less
than two percent of users.
( whispering ):
Papa Olaf was one of those guys
that needed hydraulics.
Oh.
The prodigal CSI returns.
You get any sleep?
Not yet.
So, uh, Brass
had to let Dr. Tripton go.
The old sex alibi.
Too bad he didn't leave
a toe print on a scalpel blade.
You got a take on him?
Balloon head, but credible...
like most adulterers.
Is he going bald?
Not really.
Grey hair?
No.
Anything else?
He's a lefty.
Okay, keep in mind,
this is just a theory.
It's a hot button issue
among forensic pathologists.
What's the consensus?
Most doctors say
it's impossible
to prove handedness
based on the wounds inflicted
on a victim.
Forget hard science.
What's your hypothesis?
Based on micro-incisions
and hesitation marks,
the victim was lying face up
when he was killed.
Take a look
at the right knee.
The cut on the cartilage
of the right distal femur
has slight angulations
from the, uh...
left distal
to the right proximal,
which suggests the killer
was left-handed.
This angulation
is consistent
with cuts made to the acetabulum
and to the wrist,
but bear in mind, it's not going
to be admissible in court.
I don't care about court.
My mind's on a left-handed,
Propecia-using surgeon
who's probably on staff
at Desert Palm.
There was no need
for the light show.
All you had to do was ask.
Good.
Since we're being
completely honest...
are you losing
your hair?
I'm a 48-year-old man.
I'm not unique.
Your hair is, though.
We found it at the crime scene.
Minoxidil absorbs
infrared light.
I-I take Rogaine
and Propecia.
Again, not unique.
Well, we think
that Debbie Marlin
and Michael Clark
were killed by a surgeon
who is left-handed,
and we know of two
left-handed surgeons
at Desert Palm:
Dr. Tripton, who has
an alibi, and you.
Well, if you're going
to make accusations,
you should really do
your homework.
Howard and I are
the only lefties on staff.
Dr. Randolph, who has privileges
at the hospital,
he's also a lefty.
We play tennis every Wednesday.
He's got a heck of a back-hand.
If you want me
to name more names,
I could, but you don't want me
to do your job
for you, do you?
Gentlemen...
we're here as
a courtesy,
so if you're quite through
wasting our time,
I think that the doctor
would like
to get back to the
business of saving lives.
Not so fast.
Is this a link
from a bracelet
you gave Debbie?
Mm-hmm. It looks like it.
Where's the rest of it?
This link was vacuumed
from the floor
of the spare bedroom
after the murder.
The other link was
in her jewelry box.
The funny thing is
that all the bracelets
from the other guys she
slept with are intact.
Well, all I can tell you
is when I gave it to her,
it was in one piece.
Do you have any other evidence?
No, we don't.
We might not have any other
evidence, but we have a theory.
That's not admissible in court.
Oh, no, no, it's worth a listen.
We think you killed
Debbie Marlin because
she rejected you,
and Michael Clark
paid the price.
Thank you for your time
and your theories,
but you said it yourself:
you don't have a case.
Doctor.
It's sad, isn't it, Doc?
Guys like us.
Couple of middle-aged men
who've allowed their work
to consume their lives.
The only time
we ever touch other people
is when we're wearing
our latex gloves.
We wake up one day and realize
that for 50 years
we haven't really lived at all.
But then, all of a sudden...
we get a second chance.
Somebody young and beautiful
shows up.
Somebody...
we could care about.
She offers us a new life
with her...
...but we have
a big decision
to make, right?
Because we have to risk
everything we've worked for
in order to have her.
I couldn't do it...
but you did.
You risked it all...
and she showed you
a wonderful life,
didn't she?
But then she took it away
and gave it to somebody else,
and you were lost.
So you took her life.
Debbie, it's me,
Michael.
GRISSOM:
You killed them both,
and now you have nothing.
I'm still here.
Are you?