( glass breaking )
Hey man, this place is a dump.
I'm telling you,
this bitch is loaded
and no one's seen her
for weeks.
Come on, this place is trashed.
You trying to make
me look stupid?
No, man. I swear. Somebody
must have beat us to it.
What the hell is this?
( short, abrupt siren sounding)
I'm out, man.
MAN:
Gentlemen,
put your hands
on your heads, please.
Smudges.
Nothing but smudges.
Doesn't anybody use Formica
anymore?
MAN:
First thing
we did when we saw this
was call you guys.
Didn't touch a thing.
( sighs )
So you going to open it?
Eventually.
( quietly ):
This is going to take all day.
Sun Tzu once said,
"If you wait
"by the river long enough,
the bodies
of your enemies will float by."
But those were brutal times.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
Hey, hold up.
Warrick?
Hey, David.
Give me a minute
and let me clear a path
here, okay?
All right,
I'm not going anywhere.
All right.
There's at least four weeks
of mail here, Grissom.
Four weeks of 100 degree days,
zero percent humidity.
Eventually,
the body tissues sublimate.
Cell fluids vaporize,
and all that's left --
Proteins, fats and minerals.
BROWN:
Turns a grape
into a raisin.
Well, the desert
was making mummies
long before the Egyptians.
Take a look at this.
And look at
her fingers.
She tried to claw her way out.
Yeah.
Which means
she was alive
when she
was entombed.
She was supposed to be,
like, this old widow, right?
Like, always going out
to dinner
and coming home
with shopping bags.
Bitch had insurance money
and word was that she kept it
in a box hidden under her bed.
A retired grade-school teacher
living on a pension...
Listen, man, we didn't kill her.
No, I know that.
What I want to know is,
other than the back door,
did you or your partner touch
anything in the house?
No. There was nothing left
to touch, man.
Hey, Griss.
Seem kind of odd to you?
A woman who spends the time
making tea like this
leaves a chunk
of chocolate cake
on the counter.
With a big bite out of it?
Yeah.
Some crack head
brutalizes an old lady,
leaves her in a closet,
and grabs
a snack on the way out.
Hopefully.
Take it back to the lab.
Shut up, get in there!
Oh!
( labored gasping )
( groans )
( groaning )
( weak groan ):
Oh.
Fluoroscope showed no
bullet or stab wounds,
and apart from
multiple fractures
of her fingers and hands,
no other apparent injuries.
So whoever boarded her up
in the closet
maybe didn't intend
to kill her.
Yeah.
They must have thought
somebody'd find her--
a friend or relative.
She lived alone.
Only relative was a nephew.
Brass is looking for him.
Live alone, die alone.
In this case, from
massive dehydration.
Rule of Threes:
Three minutes
without air,
three days
without water,
and three weeks without food.
Three days must have felt
like three years.
Warrick said you found a
possible print at the scene.
Need to rule hers out?
Yeah. Also need
a dental impression.
Well, that'll
be easy.
WILLOWS:
So, what do we have here?
Well, boy was out playing,
found the weapon,
fired one shot,
dropped the weapon.
No one's touched it since.
Hmm.
Okay, thanks.
Yeah.
Hey, Nathan.
How's your foot?
I got a rocket ship Band-Aid.
Hmm.
Yeah, I see that.
Mrs. Timmel, does
the gun belong
to someone in the house?
No, absolutely not.
My husband and I don't believe
in guns.
We moved here from the city
because it was supposed
to be safer.
Nathan, where did
you find the gun?
Seymour found it.
Seymour?
( whispering ):
His imaginary friend.
So, you were playing
with Seymour,
and he found the gun
where?
Over there.
Well, where exactly?
In the backyard.
Was it buried?
Did you dig it up?
Nope.
( gunshot )
Will you ever play
with guns again?
Nope.
We don't need an I.D..
Oh, the nephew said
he wanted to see her.
Insisted on it.
Made me curious.
You Connor Foster?
Yeah.
I'm sorry I'm late.
I got lost.
This is the morgue, huh?
You have to prepare
yourself for this.
Your aunt was found
in an advanced state
of decomposition.
Oh, this is messed up.
This is really
messed up.
Whoa! She just moved.
Did you see that?
I'm telling you,
she just moved.
Sometimes, when you see the body
of someone you know,
someone you've seen move before,
you want them to move.
That's not her.
This lady's too thin.
That's not her
skin, either.
My aunt always wore sunblock.
Dry mouth.
Diaphoresis.
Red eyes,
dilated pupils.
Huh?
It means you're high.
I got to go.
We'd like you to stay.
BRASS:
Where are you living
these days, Connor?
At the YMCA
off Industrial,
near the underpass.
Nice.
How's work?
I don't have a job.
I used to.
Yeah.
Yeah, two years ago,
your aunt reported
a pearl necklace stolen.
You were busted trying
to hock it at a pawn shop.
She dropped those charges.
Oh, sure.
Anything
for her favorite nephew.
And what have you done
for her?
She was lying in a coat closet
for over a month.
You didn't call.
You didn't stop by.
I don't call her much.
We only have
dinner on holidays.
Whenever she sees me,
it makes her kind of sad.
Do you get the munchies?
When?
When you're high.
Do you like cake?
( laughs ):
No, I go for burgers.
Sonic.
How would you like to make
a dental impression for us?
I'll do whatever
you guys want.
Hey, Rich.
Whatcha got for me?
Found this somewhere
where it didn't belong.
( paper crinkling )
Unregistered.
No prints.
Huh. Sweet piece.
Mm-hmm.
.32 Beretta Tomcat.
Titanium frame,
stainless steel barrel
and slide.
Super lightweight.
Yeah, light enough
for a five year old to use.
Ouch.
He's okay. Thank God.
Good.
.32 caliber.
Not many of these
in circulation.
Well, that's
a good thing.
Potentially.
( ammo rattling )
Okay.
Here we go.
( gun clicks )
Two shots!
( metallic clunking )
There's showing up for work
and there's doing your job.
Warrick brought in a
.32 auto Coroner's
bullet last week.
D.B. in Maslow Park.
You just found
the murder weapon.
WILLOWS:
Frank Maddox.
47-year-old white male.
He's a bounty hunter.
Single .32 round in
the side of his head.
Bruises on his
face and chest.
Autopsy ruled those premortem.
At least a day old.
It was a close shot,
noncontact, downward angle.
No primer residue
on the hands.
T.O.D. was
approximately 2:00 a.m.
No one found the body
until 7:00 a.m.
A lot of wind...
Warrick, your notes are great.
Let the case speak for itself.
I got to go
see my mummy.
You know, I could've sworn
I heard Grissom
telling you to do this.
Yeah?
You know what
rolls downhill?
Apparently
bloated fingertips.
Come on, you got a lot
of new skills to master.
Field work's
a little messier
than your test tubes
and your GCMS.
Yeah, and a lot
less accurate.
One continuous motion,
nice and easy.
That's not bad.
Keep practicing.
Nine more to go.
SIDLE:
Hey.
I heard about your mummy
in the closet.
Very cool.
Yeah, and we get
a 406 in Henderson.
Want to trade?
Nothing spells
excitement like
a B and E.
( knocking on door )
MAN:
Who is it?
OFFICER:
Las Vegas Police, sir.
Hey.
We received a phone call
from a neighbor
about a break in.
Yeah, yeah, I'm, uh,
sorry, officers.
There's been a
misunderstanding.
My daughter, she
had some friends
over tonight without
my permission,
and, um, they
started drinking.
They got out of control.
They broke some stuff.
A couple of windows,
but, uh, you know,
we got it under control,
we're cleaning it all up.
So I apologize for the trouble.
OFFICER:
No trouble at all, sir.
You have
a good night now.
Thanks.
( Stokes sighs )
"To protect and serve."
( chuckling )
Are you boys ready
for softball on Sunday?
Ready to kick
your ass, Stokes.
See you back
at the lab.
All right.
You're ready to kiss my what?
You heard me.
( Stokes and officer
continue talking )
( gasps )
I need to go to the hospital.
Please.
SIDLE:
Suzanna, if you were
sexually assaulted...
It was a party.
It just got out of control.
All I need is an AIDS test
and a morning after pill.
Date rape is
still rape.
Thank you for clearing that up.
Hey.
Hi.
SUZANNA:
Does she...?
Does she have to be in here
for this?
No.
Bye.
Thank you.
Okay.
Go ahead
and put this on, okay?
We're going to need
full-body photographs.
If she can't talk,
the kit's going to
have to do it for her.
Okay.
Your, uh, mummy prints.
Warrick's getting sloppy.
Yeah, someone should really
have a talk with that guy.
What's that?
Dessert.
MAN:
Look, I thought we were done.
STOKES:
Well, sir, we need a list
of all the kids
who were here tonight.
Why?
SIDLE:
Mrs. Kirkwood,
Mr. Kirkwood,
your daughter has been raped.
( sighs )
What did she tell you?
We're going to need
to search the premises.
You can't
It's my house.
You don't have a choice.
We have a warrant.
I'm going to have
to ask you folks
to step outside.
Thank you.
I'll take the girl's room.
Yeah, I'll take
the master.
So, how do we know
we're dealing with
the same suspect?
We don't.
Table against
the closet door,
chair shoved
under the knob.
It is the same M.O.
Any connections
between the victims?
Well, both victims
were left alive, we think.
I mean, the old lady's death
was probably
unintentional,
and the girl's
rape was...
Crime of opportunity?
If you're out
to rob somebody's house,
why would you do it
when they're home?
GRISSOM:
The difference between
burglary and home invasion--
infliction of terror.
Talk to the cops?
Say a word,
and I'll kill you.
I'll kill you, okay?
Bad guys leave,
fear just stays behind.
WILLOWS:
Maslow Park.
All fun and games
till the sun goes down.
So, the bounty hunter
is here at 2:00 a.m.
Like shooting fish
in a barrel.
Almost guaranteed
to run into one of his skips
or some lowlife
who knows where they are.
Well, apparently,
someone found him first.
Hunter becomes the hunted.
A dozen perfect dump sites
within a mile of here.
So, how does the gun
end up across town
in the hands
of a five-year-old boy?
Drive and dump.
Doesn't make any sense.
You never make it easy, do you?
The center whorls
look similar.
BROWN:
Can you generate
a composite?
FRANCO:
Well, it's all about gestalt.
When the whole of the pattern
is greater
than the sum of its parts.
SIDLE:
Once I pulled details,
I shrank it back down
to 100%.
Here's the thing.
Looks like the bite
came from behind.
Well, it was probably easier
to subdue her in that position.
( terrified moaning
and screaming )
You okay?
Yeah.
The occlusal plane
looks the same.
And the lateral incisor
overlaps the canine...
...in both cases.
Same person.
Definitely not
the old lady's nephew.
Hey, hey.
Two partials
equal one slimeball.
Jacqui got a hit through AFIS.
The guy with the closet fixation
is Steve Jansson.
Let's see if he has
an oral fixation as well.
BRASS:
Little Stevie Jansson.
How was the Home
of the Good
Shepherd, Steve?
Mac and cheese
was aces.
Juvie offenses
don't mean squat.
My record--
it's been expunged.
Expunged, huh?
So, what's this crap
you're pulling now?
SIDLE:
Two crime scenes,
two prints-- both yours.
BRASS:
And looking at
your adult record,
this makes strike two and three
with one pitch.
That's a real time-saver for us.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
Madeline Foster.
The Kirkwoods.
I do work for them sometimes.
Odd jobs.
So, if we asked
the Kirkwoods, they'd say
you were their handyman, huh?
Go ahead.
Ask them.
You always help yourself
to something sweet
while you work?
Bite it.
MADDOX:
I'm saying it now,
and I'm saying it loud.
I will bring Terrango
to justice.
INTERVIEWER:
What makes you think
you'll succeed
where so many others
have failed?
Failure's not
an option.
It never has been.
You feeling me, Terrango?
You can keep on running,
but I will keep coming.
I will never stop.
Them's fightin' words.
Did he get his man?
Actually, no.
Terrango killed
two more people
before another "recovery agent"
picked him up in Texas.
Well, that probably
hurt business.
Oh, yeah, it did.
After that case,
his recovery rate
went down practically
to zero.
What about suicide?
No.
It's a non-contact wound
at a downward angle.
It's a textbook murder.
Maybe too textbook.
A bounty hunter
would know how to fake it.
Let's check out
his right sleeve.
Very odd-- unbuttoned.
It's pulled way down.
It would explain
why there weren't any prints
on the gun.
Doesn't explain
how the gun left the scene.
Maybe someone found it
and grabbed it up.
Just to toss it in suburbia
a week later?
We're always looking
for a weapon.
You'd think it'd be easier
when the weapon finds us.
What's in the scope?
It's polypropylene film.
It was found
in the trigger guard.
It's ribbon, for
wrapping presents and...
You got a theory?
You got ten bucks?
Yeah.
Jansson's dental impression
is consistent
with the bite mark
on the girl's shoulder.
Consistent, but
not conclusive.
I spoke to Mr. Kirkwood.
He wouldn't confirm or deny
Jansson's handyman story.
He said he
couldn't remember.
And without that, uh...
Hey, guys, we're screwed.
The semen from the rape kit
doesn't belong to Steve Jansson.
No hits off CODIS either.
There was more
than one guy.
She was gang-raped.
This gets cheerier
by the minute.
Jansson's never going
to roll over on his partner.
They're going to do it again.
Yeah.
We've given them
no reason to stop.
( doorbell ringing )
Hi.
My name's Gil Grissom.
I'm with the Las Vegas
Crime Lab.
Suzanna, I said
I'd get it.
What do you want?
I already told the police
I have nothing more to say.
I think you do.
And I need you
to speak for someone
who can't speak for herself.
Another victim.
I don't care
about another victim.
Suzanna, please.
Look, we know that two men
broke into your house.
We have one suspect in custody,
but we can't hold him
unless you talk
to us.
I can't help you.
I'm shutting the door now.
Mr. Kirkwood,
I've done all that I can.
I need what you saw.
Mr. Grissom,
do you have a wife, children?
No.
Then you can't possibly
understand how I feel.
All I am to you
is a folder in a drawer.
And if I had
a wife and children...
Then you wouldn't be here.
I can't help you.
STOKES:
Man...
Mrs. Kirkwood was a Hoover.
She even bleached the sheets.
You know
what I don't get?
How do they get in?
There's no sign of forced entry
at either scene.
Ring the doorbell;
that usually seems to work.
Hey, hey, hey.
What?
What is that
you just threw over there?
Leftovers, I guess.
BROWN:
You know that piece
of half-eaten shark
with cake that
Gris and I found
at the old lady
Maddie's house?
This is from
the same restaurant.
Links the victims.
BROWN:
Same night as the home invasion.
Signed by Mrs. Kirkwood.
Dinner for one.
Single women, dining alone--
easy targets.
All you have to do is
follow them home.
Same restaurant...
Same waiter?
Uh...
sure, they're regulars.
I haven't seen, uh,
Maddie in a while,
but Mrs. K. comes
in every Thursday
while her daughter's
at soccer practice.
Well, you know all
your customers this well?
I try to chat up
the ones that
come in alone.
I feel bad for 'em.
BROWN:
So both women
came in alone?
Every week.
Where were you after
your shift on Thursday night?
Oh, uh... I was best man
at my friend's wedding.
The Luxor has
that new wedding chapel.
You get it at a discount
if you use it on a weekday.
I can give you a number
if you...
Down, boy.
Thanks.
Sure.
I kind of doubt that
a clean-cut guy like Ryan
is hanging out with
snaggletooth Steve.
No, but I'd bet
somebody here was.
Hi.
You here every day?
Seven days a week,
till the sun goes down.
I got a wife, a kid,
and 2.3 dogs to support.
Do you recognize this man?
Oh, yeah.
He was here
a few days ago.
A little bigger
than my average customer.
Did he buy any balloons?
Four big reds.
I'll take what he bought.
So, we know Jansson's
partner knew
the customers
at the restaurant.
Education, employment history
and a driver's license
are required
for all employees.
I've made a timeline of Steve
Jansson's illustrious life span.
Places he's lived,
the places he's been arrested--
you know, the highlights.
You find
any commonalities?
Well, Eric Shultz.
Lives in the same neighborhood.
BROWN:
Jose Cortez.
Worked at the Wilson
Street Grill
from '93 to '94.
But the busboy, Kelly James--
not only went
to the same high school,
but graduated
from the same juvie center.
SIDLE:
It's always nice
when they come out worse
than when they went in.
What do you think?
That's our guy, right?
GRISSOM:
It's a connection.
It's not enough to compel DNA.
So we have nothing?
No, we have a name,
and we know where he works.
STOKES:
I'll find out
where he was the night
the Kirkwoods were invaded.
( pager beeps )
Lineup's almost ready to go.
Listen, when she
IDs Kelly James,
we're going to need
a DNA sample
and an immediate
hold, no bail.
He's not a flight risk.
He's a risk.
SIDLE:
Hey, Suzanna.
Um, why don't we go hang out
until they're ready for us?
We'll get a glass
of water or something.
I'm really glad
you decided to come today.
Do you... you want to hear
something stupid?
Sure.
My boyfriend and I
had been talking about
having sex
for a of couple months.
I always said no
because I was afraid that
my parents would find out.
( sighs )
Mr. Kirkwood, I'm sorry.
The other day,
I thought you were saying
that you "wouldn't" help me,
and now I realize that
you couldn't.
I never got a good look
at them.
We're ready.
Can she come with me?
BRASS:
I already cleared it
with the public defender.
She's 16.
I only had two jobs left--
teach her to think
for herself,
keep her safe.
I got one right.
BRASS:
Here's how this works:
There are five guys
in a line.
We're going to ask
each of them to step forward,
turn to the side,
and then face forward again.
Now, if you want a second look
or you need more time,
just let us know.
When you're ready
to make a decision,
write it down
on this piece of paper.
Remember, you can see them,
but they can't see you.
Okay?
He already knows it's me.
SIDLE:
Suzanna,
you can do this.
I know you can.
Okay.
MAN ( over intercom ):
Number One, please step forward.
Turn to the left.
Step back.
Number Two, step forward.
Turn to your left.
MICHAEL:
You know, people say
you never forget.
Truth is... you do forget.
And then you remember.
It makes it worse.
It was like, uh,
it's like my brain...
doesn't know where to put it.
( screaming )
( man yelling )
( crying and pleading )
You know, it must've run
through a million times
in my mind...
Somebody breaks in.
I get a baseball bat.
Get everybody
out the back door.
Call the cops.
My family's safe.
And I just stood there...
MAN ( over intercom ):
Number Four, step forward.
Turn to your left.
( crying ):
No!
( screaming )
Suzanna!
My baby!
And when Suzanna was
a little girl,
Linda made me put those, um,
the child-proof locks
on all the kitchen cabinets.
I complained.
You know what
she said to me?
She said, uh,
"The least we can do is
make her safe in her own house."
Mr. Kirkwood...
you didn't do
anything wrong.
( sighs )
( whispers ):
Baby.
( sobbing quietly )
Oh, it's okay,
it's okay. Shh.
She froze up.
She couldn't do it.
Her reaction
should be enough.
What do you think?
BRASS:
Well, we've got
enough to hold
this Jansson kid,
but the other guy...
Unless she writes
a number down,
there's nothing we can do.
Hey.
I'm sorry to hear
about your case.
( sighs )
We were so close,
you don't even know.
Well, he'll be back.
We'll get him eventually.
Yeah.
Want to go for a ride?
Probably safer than anything
else I had planned. Yeah.
Frank Maddox--
badass bounty hunter
on his way down.
Loses his rep,
loses his edge...
Loses his manhood.
Guess he thought
he had nothing left to live for.
Except maybe
one thing:
going out with
his boots on.
He picks a known hot spot,
and waits until it gets dark.
Angles the gun down...
( gunshot )
And the balloons make it
look like murder.
BROWN:
On a windy night,
a balloon can go for miles.
Until...
You leave the city
to get away from crime,
and guns fall
out of the sky.
( classical music plays )
Get your kit.