Ready to go?
I'll get the paper.
You get the car.
Okay.
( zapping )
Ooh!
( screams )
Early morning call-out,
the worst.
Where did you
come from?
Home.
Did you get
any sleep?
No. You?
About a half an hour.
I was watching
the World Series of Poker.
Waiting for Sam Farha
to light his cigarette.
Ever been to the Acid Drop?
I try to avoid
those places.
The victims were
the owners.
Mike Trent and
his wife Laurel.
Both shot execution-style
back of the head.
A neighbor walking the dog
found 'em.
Mike used to own
a semi-pro hockey team
with some other guy.
He made a ton of money,
sunk it all into clubs
like Acid Drop,
uh, Psychedelic Hoe-Down...
Captain Brass.
Fun joints.
Looks like they
never got out
of the driveway.
( gasps )
( gunshots )
She dropped where she was shot,
but he looks
like he was dragged.
You drag a body away
to hide it,
not down a driveway
for the world to see it.
Unless that was the point.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
BROWN:
Bling-bling.
The ol' trophy wife.
You think?
Classic Vegas.
He pays for her boobs,
tummy tuck, Prada,
weekly spa,
French manicure.
And she's just
hanging on his arm
like she belongs.
Tell us how you really feel,
Catherine.
Oh, it's gross.
I wouldn't want
to be her for the world.
I wouldn't mind being her
for a day, I guess.
Not this day.
No.
Looks like it was just
the two of them.
Nobody I know lives
like this with kids.
( phone rings )
Brown.
I've been here for 20 minutes.
What's the code?
You on the East Coast
looking for a sunset?
I am.
You're at the wrong gate.
Drive back down the road,
make three lefts.
When you get to the main gate,
speak to Officer Ray
and tell her
you're with the Crime Lab.
When you get to the scene,
make sure I'm the first person
you speak to.
Okay.
Mike Trent?
Mm-hmm.
Boy, he's a big dog
in the club world.
You know I heard he paid
Lil' Kim $10,000 one time
just to walk into
one of his clubs,
turn around and walk
back out.
Yeah, Jah Rule
gets the same fee.
He told me.
Hey, uh, let me have
one of those, Sara.
Sorry, last one.
You have a cold, Sara?
I've been feeling
a little run-down lately.
Okay, it's a gated community.
The main gate has a guard
all the time.
The resident gate
is at the north end,
has punch-key access.
Those are the only two ways
in and out of this place.
I thought you moved
into communities like this
for this not to happen.
STOKES:
Hey, Grissom.
What do you got?
So far, an empty briefcase
and a purse.
You want us
to take the perimeter?
Yeah, please.
Catherine and Warwick
are inside.
The bodies were found
on the driveway,
so any evidence of the killers
is going to be out here.
I'll check the rear
for any sign of forced entry.
I'll take the side door.
You just get off a shift?
Catherine called me.
I'm here to help
with the case.
You look like a man
who just rolled out of bed.
You all right?
Yeah, why?
T-shirt, sneakers.
You're already
a half hour late.
Grissom will rip you
a new one
he sees you like that.
Serious?
Yeah, it's not a Rebel game.
It's a crime scene.
See, this is what I'm
talking about right here.
The battery's not changed
out of your flashlight.
Kit's open.
It's not stocked;
no swabs.
Did you sterilize
your equipment after
your last case?
Uh, no.
See, you know when I'm on call
because my clothes
are folded next to my bed.
Shoes, jacket, ball cap,
bottle of water,
pen, paper, Thomas Guide,
next to the phone.
That way, if I get a call
at 3:00 in the morning,
I'm not scrambled.
Everything's there
before the phone rings.
My game is tight, like my trunk.
Check it out.
Camera case, tripod,
film is in the fridge.
Markers, check.
Extra field kit, fully
stocked, sterilized.
Shoeprint lift kit,
wet weather gear.
Files "mama."
Forms for days.
First Call form,
First Officer form,
Consent to Search,
Bird's Eye View inside,
Bird's Eye View outside.
It's down to how
I like my lunch.
Picking up what
I'm putting down?
Yeah. See, no one ever told me.
You've been told.
Yes, sir.
( indistinct
radio transmission )
No sign of disturbance
in the rear.
Cigarette butts.
Orange peel, seeds.
Lying in wait, maybe.
You still sucking
on that same cough drop?
Yeah.
I'm a... a slow sucker.
So, assuming the killer
didn't live in the community,
how did he gain entry?
♪ ♪
Crime occurred in the driveway.
Nothing to indicate
that the suspects
were inside the house.
Yes, ma'am. I got it.
So, then,
what are we looking for?
Anything inside
that'll make the
outside make sense.
On your hands
and knees.
Check the carpet
for trace.
Hey.
Greg.
I'm going to need you
to photograph something.
Why, what'd you find?
It's what I didn't find.
Well, I found something.
Blood.
Blood?
Where?
Right here.
Ooh, I also found some videos.
Looks like amateur porn.
Porn. That figures.
Sunburn Sin. Ooh.
"Starring Laurel Lust."
That's Laurel Trent.
Isn't that the wife?
Yeah.
A few years back.
"A Goode/Mike T. Production."
"Mike T" as in Mike Trent?
Well, I bet he seduced her,
and then he produced her.
ROBBINS:
Laurel Trent definitely
had some work done.
Implants which she
later had removed.
She has a four-
centimeter-long scar
at the edge of the areola.
Collapsed fibrous capsules
in both breasts.
Fascinating.
Cause of death?
I was just getting to that.
Two gunshot wounds
to the back of the head,
just like her husband.
Close range.
Either one immediately
debilitating and fatal.
I sent the bullets to the lab.
But this is why
I sent for you.
Stun gun burns?
( zapping )
If you're close enough
to stun him,
you're close enough
to shoot him.
And we suspect
that there were two assailants.
Well, maybe they were
trying to buy time.
For what?
Now, the first order
of business is to
kill the Trents.
Then the suspects go
upstairs and rip off
Laurel's jewelry.
And bail on bikes.
That's a little low-rent,
don't you think?
Yeah, but I'm thinking,
in a neighborhood like this,
if you burn rubber
out of here,
it's gonna cause
a lot of attention.
If you roll quietly away
on a bike, though...
Ah, no one's the wiser.
Okay, I get it.
This is the resident gate
that Greg called me from;
he couldn't get in.
He needed a code.
Sara did find
an orange peel in the side yard.
What do you think,
sticky fingers?
Does citrus illuminate?
Sugar will,
if it's derivatized.
Do you have
any fluorescent reagents?
I've got ANTS.
Not the insect.
Amino-naphthalene
Trisulfonic acid.
trisulfonic acid.
You're trying to stump me.
I can feel it.
Let me check it out.
The ANTS should make it light up
under the ALS.
One, three...
five and six.
In some configuration.
They had the code.
We're mid-case.
Why do we have to do this now?
I have to get this
evaluation in,
or I'm gonna get written up.
Okay.
My goals.
Mm...
Oh, all right, okay.
For starters, I'd like
two consecutive nights off.
I would like to cut my triples
down to ten a year
instead of the usual 20,
and, uh,
I would love to find
a reliable baby-sitter,
so I could have myself
some kind of a personal life.
You don't have
a personal life?
I... Write this down:
I haven't had sex in six--
no-- seven months.
How can I help?
You. Advance, I mean.
Do you...
have any interest
in changing sections in the lab,
for instance?
Gil, how do you do this?
Honestly, how do you juggle
scheduling and vacations and...
The goal of any supervisor
is to teach someone
how to take his place someday.
Are you going someplace?
You never know.
Are you considering me?
Why not?
You're certainly
qualified.
But... a CSI who
uses the DNA lab
to establish her
own paternity...
calls into question...
her judgment,
don't you think?
You've left that out.
Are you covering for me?
I believe
that we've dealt
with this issue,
handled it internally.
As far as I'm concerned,
it's dead.
Besides,
you'll never do it again.
So just sign your
name by the red "X."
Before I sign, um,
since we're putting
all of our cards on the table,
there's something
you should know.
Sam Braun wrote me a check,
and... I cashed it.
For how much?
Enough to where Lindsay and I
can do anything and...
not enough to where
we can do nothing.
Sam Braun was a murder suspect
in one of your cases.
How does this not
look like a payoff?
I consulted an attorney.
It is a check
from a father to a daughter.
It is completely out of
departmental jurisdiction.
What about conflict of interest?
Not just for you
but for this lab.
Gil, I would never compromise
you or the lab.
Maybe not legally,
but ethically?
What else should I know,
Catherine?
That's everything.
Talk to me.
Orange peels, seeds,
cigarette butts.
I'm logging them in
and moving them to DNA.
Okay, so you've gone
through her purse,
uh, her wallet...
Yeah, everything's there--
money, credit cards.
Yeah. What about
the briefcase?
Empty. Stop.
I-I got a system here.
I found this wadded up
in her purse.
It's a release form--
permission to film
an adult movie
at the Acid Drop.
From Drake the Snake
Productions.
Signed by a Drake Snow.
( rock music playing )
I need to see your boss.
Follow me.
Tonight's for Mike.
We pay our respects
by ringing the register.
Now, I don't mind
if you're talking,
just as long
as they're drinking.
Watch the doubles...
Uh...
Watch the doubles. Be smart.
You do that, we're gonna
take this party
through till 6:00
in the morning.
And most importantly, have fun.
Okay.
Go make some money.
See you later.
You here about Mike?
Yes, I am.
Let's go somewhere private.
Sorry for the inconvenience,
everybody.
When you come back,
next bottle's on me.
Go ahead.
( clears throat )
Thanks, Chief. We're going
to shut her down
for about half an hour.
Well...
this is private.
It was,
um...
It was a real
shock, you know?
Mike and Laurel getting
killed like that.
But I got to say,
if they had a choice
how to go out,
it would have been
together.
For him, the sun rose
and set with her.
He didn't treat her
like a trophy wife?
No. You kidding?
No. He got her
off the VHS covers,
and she made a
home for him.
You know?
Have a seat.
( clears throat )
Um, and what was, uh...
What was your professional
affiliation with him?
I run his clubs.
Ever since he got out
of the partner business
with Kyle Goode.
Have you seen this Mr. Goode
lately?
He shows his face
every once in a while.
I just try to keep him away
from Mike, you know?
As much as humanly possible.
And...
what about this Drake Snow guy?
Drake?
( laughs ):
Drake the Snake.
I, uh...
I hired him.
He's harmless.
He saw one
Ron Jeremy movie.
Now the guy just sees
dollar signs.
( laughs )
Uh, and how did he get along
with the Trents?
Why don't you go ask him?
Reading my mind.
Mm.
You, uh...
You never gave me your name.
Oh.
Catherine.
Willows.
Chris Bezich.
Come on.
Mike and Kyle--
they made all their money
out of Laurel
taking it off.
She-She was a cash register
in panties is what she was.
And you wanted in?
No. Trust me.
The last thing that I wanted
was to be partners with Mike.
Guy'd... Guy'd chew you up
and spit you out
soon as look at you.
And Kyle-- forget it.
Guy'd tell you right
to your face
he's sticking it to you.
Pasadena, baby.
I got my own plans.
I-I just...
I just need a location.
One location.
And what?
Mike didn't agree to it?
Didn't ask him.
Last time I asked him
for something,
he took a swing at me.
Get the hell out of my...
I just want the same shot
that you had, Mike.
Laurel said that...
You two aren't
in business anymore.
( grunts )
In the kitchen, you said?
Yeah.
So, I wasn't going
to make that mistake again,
so I had to try
something different.
So, I pulled a Geffen.
I went straight to Yoko.
Oh, you gave Laurel
the release form.
Yeah. She was going
to give it to Mike.
He was going to sign it,
and they were going
to get it back to me.
So much for that.
All right. So, uh,
listen, Drake.
I'm going to help you
get that dream shot.
So that when you do get
into the porn biz,
you won't have a murder rap
hanging over your head.
Here.
Crime Scene 101.
Stick this in your mouth.
Hey, you can set
'em right there.
Can't believe that
there's this many
abandoned bikes
in Charleston Hills.
These were found
in the alley
behind the Fire Department,
so check them out.
Sugar on the handlebars
of both bikes.
Just like the keypad.
So we may have
our getaway bikes.
We could check
the serial numbers,
but they're usually
not recorded.
You know what?
I got an idea.
Hmm?
What are you doing?
Get me a pair
of tweezers, will you?
( laughs )
Now how did you know
that receipt was in there?
Well, I used
to read point spreads.
Now I read books.
Good for you.
Bad for Ross Davis, though.
This is a little intense
for getting my bike stolen.
I already got a new one.
Did you report it?
No. You're
kidding me, right?
I got jumped, man.
By whom?
By two bucked-ass brothers.
They were both
yoked as hell.
Ripped.
I thought for a second
they were going to kill me.
( tires squealing )
Hey, hey.
( yells )
BROWN:
Something wrong
with your neck?
Man, it's killing me.
I don't know
what the hell
they hit me with,
but my knees was
the first to go.
I believe you were hit
with a stun gun.
Just like Mike Trent.
I found something
on your butt.
Checking out
my butt again, Greg?
I was.
As well as the four butts
Sara got at the crime scene.
Oh.
Found something on them
that I can't explain,
so I sent them over
to Hodges.
Your butt's fine.
Switching gears.
Blood found in
the Trents' bedroom
is a match to Drake Snow.
So he told the truth
about the blood
and lied about
the kitchen.
Figures.
Three of the four
cigarette butts
are also
a match to Drake.
Puts him
at the scene.
And the fourth butt?
Female, not a match
to Laurel Trent.
Orange seeds?
Two additional donors,
both male.
Not a match to any
of our players.
No hits on CODIS.
So we're looking for
two guys and a gal
who might know Drake.
BRASS:
We already know you lied.
We found your blood
in the Trents' bedroom,
not in the kitchen.
So what were
you doing in there?
You putting
the shot in her, or what?
Hey, look.
I know where you're
going with this.
Okay, I was
in the bedroom.
She wasn't on
her knees. I was.
I was begging.
Not for sex.
I was begging
for my business.
Drake the Snake Productions.
Mike comes busting in,
goes ballistic,
smacks me
in the nose...
I mean, I know
I keep coming back
to this three-and-out thing,
but maybe because you're
in bed with his wife.
Laurel and I didn't
have sex in the bedroom.
We had it on the set--
past tense,
long time ago.
Then along came Mike.
Mike was good for Laurel.
Mike was not good for me.
She got carte
blanche-- Laurel.
Me, I got
a bar back.
Now I'm popping
blue pills
looking for something
to bring me down,
but I know the business.
I just don't have the capital
to get behind the camera.
So what does killing
the Trents get you?
Zero.
No one was more upset than me.
You're still pouring drinks.
Boo-hoo.
And what are you doing
smoking around their place?
What?
Yeah, we found cigarette butts
with your DNA on it
on their property.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
I don't.
I smoke one place, okay?
I smoke at work.
I'm down
to one a day.
Right after happy hour,
I have my one cigarette,
and it's out back
by the service register.
You ask anybody.
BEZICH:
Drake's telling
the truth, you know?
He smokes one a day.
Not on the floor,
right here, my rule.
Mm-hmm, well, still have
to verify it with evidence.
You verify
everything?
Everything.
Including you.
You're clear.
Can you blame Drake, you know?
He's trying to give
up cigarettes.
That's like me
trying to give up...
Sex?
Everybody needs to indulge
in a vice at least
once a day, right?
Yes, well, I did
happen to notice
those little waitress
girlies trying
to serve their way
into bed with you.
That's work.
I prefer women.
Speaking of work,
do you, um...
ever get a day off?
What?
You want to get
to know me?
Yes.
Um...
What?
Wait. Hang on.
I'm on the clock.
( chuckles )
You started it.
Yes, and when the time is right,
maybe I'll finish it.
( distant siren wails )
How you feeling?
Hey. What do you mean?
Well, you were popping
cough drops at the scene
the other day
a mile a minute.
I thought I was coming
down with a cold.
Ah.
Yeah, I, uh...
I understand colds.
You know, back in Jersey
when I was getting it
from both ends,
from my wife
and my work, things
started to get heavy.
I started medicating.
Cure my cold.
And, um,
and God forbid
I had an early
morning roll-out
and I had that tell-tale breath,
you know what I mean?
So I would dodge my supe, and
I started popping cough drops.
Huh.
I mean, what I'm trying
to say is that...
there's more problems
than answers
in the bottom of a bottle,
believe me.
Yeah.
( sighs )
Actually, I had a couple
of beers with breakfast
when I got off shift.
And then I got called in.
Just a couple?
Yeah.
I'm just looking out for you.
Hey, what are you
doing after work?
More work.
You got photos
of Laurel Trents' jewelry, huh?
Yeah, two-carat
diamond earrings,
ruby necklace, diamond
and sapphire bracelet,
lady's gold Rolex.
The insurance
company says
it's worth somewhere
north of two mil.
I got every pawn shop
in town on the lookout.
What?
You know that feeling you get
when you just can't quite
put your finger on something?
What can't you
put your finger on
besides the clock-out button?
Why did they drag his body
down the driveway?
Dragging's your racket.
But I can tell you
who's dragging
Mike Trent
into court.
His ex-business partner,
Kyle Goode.
HODGES:
Evidence.
Evidence in context.
Take a look.
Trace on the cigarette butt
is a match
to the sand I collected
from the ashtray.
At Acid Drop.
Now...
take a look at this.
I found trace amounts
of soil in the orange seeds
and the orange peel,
but not on any
of the butts.
So it's possible
that the butts were planted.
May explain why
there seems to be
so many suspects
at the crime scene.
Probably
clears Drake Snow
and your unidentified
female smoker.
Where does that leave you?
With two guys on bikes.
( gunfire )
Hit that ninja.
On the bridge.
That's it.
Kyle Goode?
Uh-huh.
I'm Detective
Jim Brass, Homicide.
I was wondering when you
guys would get around to me.
Why's that?
My ex-partner's murdered.
I got a lawsuit against him.
He owes me millions.
I'd like me for it.
Great, then we won't
have to pull teeth
to get to the truth.
Where were you
yesterday morning?
With my son, Alex.
Where?
( gunfire )
You're not going to believe
anything I tell you.
Why don't you ask him?
Okay.
Come, Alex.
Get off the game.
That's enough.
You cost me a man.
I got more quarters.
So, Alex, where were
you yesterday morning?
At Grandma's.
All morning?
No.
She lives in Laughlin.
My dad drove me.
What time did
you get there?
I don't know.
I was sleeping.
Maybe around... 11:00?
You sure about that?
Yeah.
When I woke up,
Captain Caveman was on.
Okay, Laughlin's
about 21/////2 hours away,
so you and your son
left home around 8:30?
More like 8:00.
Alex likes those
breakfast sandwiches.
We picked a couple up.
Ate them on the way.
Where'd you
pick them up?
Sunny Side's over on Eastern.
You looking for an alibi?
Something like that, yeah.
Come on, Alex. Let's go
over to Circus Circus.
They got a real arcade.
Thank you
for visiting Sunny Side's.
Next in line,
please.
Hi.
Would you like to try
the Sunny Side's Special?
No, I'm Nick Stokes.
I'm with the Las Vegas
Crime Lab.
Can I talk to you
for a second?
Um...
Are you Missy Wilson?
Are you a truant officer?
No.
Your manager said you
were working breakfast
the other day at
the pick-up window.
Yeah.
Do you remember
this guy?
Oh, my God.
That's the creep
who was hitting on me.
He was so repulsive.
You know what he said to me?
I'd like to bend you
over the counter,
baby.
And he said it
in front of his kid.
What kind of father
acts like that?
Sounds like he wanted
to make an impression.
Oh, he did.
I hope you're
going to arrest him.
One thing at a time.
Now this window...
I get all
the creeps
in drive-through--
teenagers, perverts,
walk-ups, and those
are my favorites.
"Hi, I'm on a skateboard.
Can I have a burger combo?"
"No, dork."
Does this window have
a surveillance camera?
Oh, yeah, we have cameras
all over here.
Even in
the cooler.
Confirms his alibi.
Every suspect
Brass leans on
seems to have a case
of the "airtights."
Hold it. Run that back.
Pause it.
What is that
around the kid's neck?
I don't know.
Let's enhance it.
Almost looks like
a canteen.
You bring a canteen
up to your lips,
not to your eyes.
I'll pull
some stills,
see what I can make of it.
( phone ringing )
AV Lab. Grissom.
I'll be right there.
( distant siren blares )
BRASS:
Well, he lived by the stun,
but I don't think
he died by it.
He didn't.
Uh, two gunshot wounds
to the back of the head.
TOD is within the hour.
GRISSOM:
Blood spatter everywhere.
Multiple directionalities.
You almost done, David?
Uh, yes, sir.
He's all yours.
Thanks.
I want to pick his pockets.
M...
and T.
Doesn't look like Michael Trent.
If he's one of our bad guys
on the bicycle,
where's his partner?
And where's the rest
of the jewelry?
That's probably what
his partner said
before he tossed the room.
( indistinct police radio
chatter )
Hey, look what I found:
a knife with blood on it.
Look what I found:
a dead guy.
( police radio chattering )
Nine-millimeter.
Pillowcase
full of jewelry.
Two stacks of $10,000 bricks.
Well, either they pawned some
diamonds at the US Treasury,
or they're
on someone's payroll.
You know what that means:
hit-for-hire.
And we're still looking
for somebody.
Who gets the honors:
him or him?
Eh, let's start
with Mr. Head Wound.
You've seen these before.
Stun gun.
The debilitator
of choice.
( zapping, screaming )
( screaming )
( gunshots )
Heard you found a nine-
millimeter at the scene?
Mm-hmm.
I sent the bullets
to ballistics.
How about his body?
Any lead in him?
No, but he took a blade
to the stomach.
The cut was shallow,
five or six centimeters
below the sternum.
Like the soft spot
in a dragon.
( screams )
( screaming )
Sounds like no honor
among thieves.
Well, I'll tell you
what they were fighting over.
The jewelry was hot.
Either you fence it fast
or eat the loss.
I'm thinking
more and more
it was never
part of the plan.
You know,
you could be right.
I talked to the Trents' bank.
They were on their way
to the safety deposit box
that morning
and then off to Hawaii
at the end of the week.
So it was Laurel Trent
who cleaned out
her own jewelry box.
Yeah. Murder was their wage,
and jewelry was their tip.
( computer beeping )
( sighs )
How's your hands?
Sore.
Document every
single bill. Fun.
I got to hand it
to these casinos.
They got it all figured out.
SIDLE:
What do you mean?
Well, this is
a $10,000 brick, right?
Mm-hmm.
I could either lose this
in a hand of blackjack,
or I could lose cranberry chip.
What's worse?
To me, losing's losing.
( chuckles )
Sara?
I got a bloodstain.
SANDERS:
You know,
the last time I checked,
defacing government property
was a federal offense.
Not when it's logged in
as property, Greg.
The blood might be
from a paper cut.
Okay, but you're my witness.
Run it against all our players.
Uh-huh.
I finished up
on those still photos.
The canteen around
little Alex's neck...
is really a set of binoculars.
If you keep flipping,
it tells the rest of the story.
Now, call me crazy,
but it looks like Daddy
doesn't like the little man
wearing the binoculars
around his neck so much.
I wonder why?
( distant siren blaring )
What are you thinking?
Stay right here
until I call you.
( cell phone rings )
Yeah?
Nick, would you move about
halfway up the driveway?
Back where Mike Trent was shot?
Exactly.
How's this?
Can you see me here?
No, I can't.
Thank you.
( phone beeps )
♪ ♪
( engine revving )
( keypad beeping )
( line ringing )
Jim? Gil.
I'm fine. How are you?
Would you put an APB out
on Kyle Goode's vehicle, please?
BRASS:
You recognize this?
That's my kid.
What's that
around his neck?
That's his binoculars.
Yeah. Zeiss,
20x60, BSGA.
4,500 a pop.
You know how it is.
You got your kid in the car,
traveling a long distance.
Whatever keeps them occupied.
According to your son,
he slept all the way
to Laughlin.
Kid falling asleep
in a car on the way
to his Grandma's house?
You guys won't even make it
through the courthouse door.
Court.
That's where
the lawyers get fat.
And you know
all about that.
I mean, you've got
a lawsuit with your
ex-business partner,
and your ex-wife,
who's suing you
for past alimony...
That's irrelevant.
Not according to his wife
it isn't.
She gave us permission
for a hair sample
from your son.
For what?
The good thing about drugs--
they work their way through
the bloodstream in the urine,
but not the hair.
Our lab found trace
elements of Ambien,
which is a hypnotic
sleep sedative,
in your son's hair root.
Until we see
the test results,
we're withholding comment.
No problem, counselor.
Okay, moving on.
The "buy" money,
the 20K that we found on
the two geniuses you hired?
What geniuses?
You know,
the brothers,
who are so cool
and laid back,
they're in the morgue.
Oh, what? You didn't
know they're dead?
Yeah, they greased each
other over the jewelry.
And that wasn't even
part of the deal
in the first place,
was it?
Good help is hard
to find, huh, Kyle?
He's not answering that.
I hated that son of a bitch.
Mike Trent was a scumbag,
worst of the worst.
Use you up
and blow right through you.
I brought him in
on my nickel.
And he throws me out?
Invests our money in clubs
and kicks me out? To do what?
To ride off into the sunset
with my piece of sushi?
And it's not just me.
There's a lot guys out there
got burned by him
who wouldn't mind
a little revenge.
I'll even go so far
as to say
I'm not sorry he's dead,
or rotting somewhere
in some box.
But I'll say this for sure:
I didn't kill him.
I'm not saying you did.
Or his wife.
But your $20,000 incentive
pulled the trigger.
And you know what--
you won't believe this--
a paper cut gave you away.
...ten makes 20 large.
When you do it,
I want to see it.
I'll be up here.
BRASS:
We did the DNA test
for the cigarette butt
you left at the arcade.
Plain view,
right counselor?
And we matched it to the
blood we found on the money.
He didn't hire two killers.
He only hired me.
Yeah, well, lawsuits
take a while.
I don't think you cared
about a verdict anyway,
did you, Kyle?
You wanted
much more than that.
( screaming )
God...
( whimpers )
( cocks hammer )
( gun fires twice )
( echoing ):
No!
( gun fires twice )
My client was with his
son all day that day.
Yeah, that's where
he screwed up.
Your hatred of Trent
was stronger than your love
for your own child.
You drugged your son
so you could use him
as an alibi.
And that's all a jury's going
to need to hear to convict you.
Kyle Goode, you've been bad.
You're under arrest.
Oh... you're still here.
Uh... ( clears throat )
so I'm leaving.
Need anything?
No, I'm good.
Are we good?
We'll be fine.
Okay.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Going out?
I've got some unfinished
business to take care of.
I'll see you.