MAN:
People say
that Las Vegas has no culture,
no history--
that we emulate, not create.
They forget
that this was once a desert
from which this city
was created.
Millions come
every week
and share their money with us.
Well, tonight, we give back.
An exhibition of rare
and valuable
Japanese antiquities.
Shown in the US
for the first time,
this 17th century
samurai collection
is owned by one
of the Mediterranean's
most special guests,
Mr. Yuri Yamamoto,
who sadly can't be here
with us tonight.
To his impeccable taste.
On behalf of my hotel
and the city of Las Vegas,
I thank him.
( cheering and applause )
( woman screaming )
( screaming )
The cable fell.
He was electrocuted.
Oh, my God.
( cries )
Excuse me.
Okay, folks.
I need everyone to stay back.
There's a live wire
in the pool, okay?
( electrical crackling )
Watch yourself, Gil.
GRISSOM:
This is odd.
Arms and legs become deadweight
in the water.
He should have sunk
to the bottom of the pool.
He wouldn't float
until after putrefaction.
Sara, would you see
where the source
of that cable is?
Yeah.
Found the power source.
Car battery.
This is not a crime scene.
( alarms blaring )
This is a crime scene.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
I'm sorry, but there's really
no gentle way to do this.
( alarms blaring )
Keep these people out.
And turn that damn thing off,
will you?
They only took the one piece.
Samurai sword, 17th century.
They say how much
it was worth?
Worth the risk
of walking past 100 guests
into a guarded room.
( alarms stop )
Hey, buddy,
you see anything?
No. I got hit
from nowhere.
Next thing I know,
I'm taped up.
Blood smear on the desk.
( groans )
I feel like an idiot.
Well, you may have a concussion.
Let's get you checked out.
Paramedics out there?
Check him up.
Well, none of my men saw
anyone suspicious enter
or exit.
The surveillance
cameras?
Our cameras only watch
the money and the exits.
Not rooms like these.
Damn, they got
the sword.
Most expensive piece
in the collection.
This is all
Mr. Caulfield needs right now.
Why is that?
9/11,
the depressed Asian economy,
Indian gaming in California.
Every casino
on the Strip's taken a hit.
I'm going to
want to talk
to the girl who
found the body.
Smells sweet.
The sign over there says
no food or drink
in this room, right?
Make sure you take it back
to Greg.
My third time
at this address.
Two suicides a few years ago,
and now a 419.
This house is cursed.
You don't strike me
as the type
who believes in curses.
Yeah, well, I'm not the type
to believe
in coincidences, either.
Is this house abandoned?
Bank foreclosed four years ago.
Been vacant ever since.
Neighbor heard a scream.
I was the responding officer.
( garbled radio transmission )
( door creaking )
Uh...
Oh, hey, David.
Yeah.
Oh, hey.
Uh, jugular's
been punctured.
Two marks.
Possibly bite marks.
Bite marks?
Punctures are
32 millimeters apart.
That's the average distance
between the eyeteeth
in an adult
male's mouth.
Right, but
those punctures aren't
consistent
with human teeth.
Yeah, well,
what about fangs?
Fangs?
Come on.
Wounds are deep.
She bled out.
Then where's all the blood?
Lividity tells me she wasn't
moved postmortem,
so, I don't know.
I'm going to take a look around.
WILLOWS:
David, I don't know
a whole lot about vampires,
but if she was bit,
there's spit,
and if there's spit,
there's DNA,
so swab the neck.
BROWN:
Catherine,
take a look at this.
Please tell me
that's not blood.
Negative.
It's probably just
house paint.
Well, we know one
thing for sure.
This place wasn't vacant.
Come on, nobody should have
been allowed to leave.
Your officers
didn't say anything
about detaining Mr.
Caulfield's guests.
Just give me a list
of names, okay?
Yeah.
Weird night.
That's not the only dummy here.
Yeah, it's a CPR
demonstration dummy.
Fully articulated.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah. You know,
paramedics, firemen--
they use these things
to teach lifesaving techniques.
Any prints?
Oh, no, no, no.
Been in the water
way too long, man. Sorry.
David says you found evidence
of vampires in North Las Vegas.
Well, let's just say evidence
at the crime scene suggests
occult, ritualistic activity.
I'm not sure
what we found.
Did you ID the vic?
Angela Sommerville, 20,
from Henderson, Nevada.
License was in her pocket.
Cause of death:
exsanguination.
You check out her fangs?
Well, her bark was worse
than her bite.
There we go.
Ah. They're acrylic.
Check out
her gum line.
Thin grooves carved
into the canine's enamel.
Fangs are clip-ons.
Multiple bite marks
on the tongue suggest
she was still
breaking them in.
Warrick, the symbol
on her ankle--
it's similar
to the one that
was painted
on the floor of
the crime scene.
BROWN:
The ankh.
Egyptian symbol
for eternal life.
I went on-line and found out
it's also the universal
insignia for vampires.
Dracula didn't drink
all her blood.
I sent a sample to tox.
I'm not sure if it's probative.
Multiple incised wounds
on the anterior
of both shoulders.
Some are fresh.
Well, the shoulder area
is rich in blood, right?
Heals quickly.
Yeah.
Relevance?
I figure, if you're going
to drink someone's blood,
it's a good place to start.
Then why switch to the jugular?
Hey.
Got anything?
A partial thumb, perhaps,
on the tape
that was used to cover
the security guard's mouth.
Not torn, either.
Both ends were cut.
Pre-cut,
in fact.
Indicates planning.
How about you?
Trace analyzed
the liquid
we found near the suit
of armor: glucose syrup.
Sugar water.
Why just the sword?
Well, it is the one piece
from the exhibit
you could hide on your person.
Down a pant leg, maybe, or...
Yeah, but if you're going
to steal from a casino,
why take an antique?
Why not take cash?
Good point.
How's your knowledge
of Japanese history,
particularly, antiquities?
Not good. Why?
To find the hunter...
know the game.
Angela was
the sweetest child.
She actually liked
spending time with us.
Her friends were always
over here, and then...
...puberty hit
and everything changed.
She shaved her head,
then she grew dreads.
It was like
she couldn't get comfortable
in her own skin.
About, um,
six months ago,
Angela went Goth.
Black clothing.
She only went out at night.
We tried to support
Angela the best we could.
We only wanted
her to be happy.
"The Black Veil:
13 Rules of Community."
MRS. SOMMERVILLE:
Guidelines for vampires.
She wrote them
down in there,
along with all
her thoughts.
So you've read what's in here?
Your daughter believed
that she was a vampire?
She was 18.
She wanted to stand out,
to be special.
I tried
not to judge her,
But I also wanted to
know what was going on
in her head.
She snooped.
( sighs )
Each time Angela
tried something new,
I would take
a crash course.
Lab results.
Angela's HIV test.
It was negative.
That was the one thing
we insisted upon,
not that it matters now.
Who's the guy?
Angela wouldn't say.
The statue's an incubus.
According to the legend,
incubi seduce young women
while they sleep...
and drink their blood.
Well, your
daughter was found
in an abandoned house.
And we believe
that there was, um,
someone there with her.
Do you have any idea
who that might be?
Her court.
I can give you their names.
Her court?
It's like a coven
for vampires.
Don't tell me,
they came back
and stole the rest?
No, not quite.
At Mr. Yamamoto's request,
the collection's been moved
to Mr. Caulfield's
office vault.
He was pretty upset.
He's on his way here now
from Tokyo.
We were hoping to take a look
at the rest of the exhibit.
Mr. Caulfield's vault
is off limits.
Okay, what about photographs?
You're in luck there.
Our hotel registrar
took Polaroids
of the collection
when she logged it in.
Can we talk to her?
Well, Miss Green
is on vacation,
but, uh, I can try
and contact her.
Well, this is just
a list of inventory.
How about the
insurance policy?
Yamamoto carried
his own insurance.
Our hotel registrar
just documents
the condition
of each piece.
We extended Mr. Yamamoto
every courtesy,
but weren't going
to assume responsibility.
We're a casino,
not a museum.
Alice,
you need to answer
the question.
GIRL:
She won't respond
to that name.
She goes by Luminessa.
Okay, let's start over.
Do any of you ladies
recognize this man?
BROWN:
When was the last time
you saw Angela?
Who?
( chuckles ):
Okay.
All right, I've had enough.
( clears throat )
Your friend is dead.
This is a murder case.
If you're not willing
to help us,
we will split you up
and treat you as suspects.
Hold you for 24 hours.
Is that what you want?
We called her Daegonna.
We were together
last night.
At court.
Being a vampire
is about feeding.
This is pathetic.
Angela had been going
to this blood bar.
Wanted us to join her.
Blood bar?
The people who go there,
they drink blood.
For real.
Hardcore.
And I guess you girls
don't do that?
Hell, no.
And that's what we told her.
She totally lost it.
She called us "gajas."
Which is...?
A fashion vampire.
Normal people
who just play dress-up.
You don't have
to drink blood
to be a vampire.
For us, it's spiritual.
We feed off
each other's energies.
Yeah.
Energy.
So, we voted her invisible.
Kicked her out of our court.
But she wouldn't leave.
So we did.
And that's the last time
we saw her.
SIDLE:
Other items in the exhibit
include a 17th century
decorated silk.
( paper shuffling )
17th century iron war mask.
17th century Kabuki robe
used in the first
Kabuki dances in Kyoto.
GRISSOM:
17th century suit of armor.
Wasn't the Japanese military
established long after that?
Let's see.
( metallic rattling )
1868, by Emperor Maji? Meiji.
So, this is out of place.
Just like the sugar water
we found nearby.
( phone ringing )
Grissom.
STOKES:
Grissom, I got a hit
on your partial print from
the hotel employee database.
Brandon Miller.
He's your duct-taped
security guard.
GRISSOM:
I thought he was unconscious.
How does his prints
end up on the tape?
All right. Thanks, Nick.
Sara?
Hmm?
Do you have any duct tape
in your kit?
Yeah, it's what I use
to keep it together.
Thank you.
He taped himself up.
We've been conned.
Well, you saw the paramedics
take him out of here.
If he'd had a samurai sword
hanging out of his pant
leg, you would've noticed.
( metallic rattling )
( rattling continues )
Huh.
Domo arigato.
So Brandon Miller
never made it to
the hospital, huh?
Concussion,
my happy ass.
It's an old trick.
Don't steal the item;
just leave it at the location,
come back and get it
when the cops leave.
Well, your timing's perfect.
Mr. Yamamoto just arrived.
Mr. Caulfield's
with him right now.
Mr. Caulfield.
You asked to be kept
up to date on our progress.
I'll be damned.
You found the guy?
Perhaps.
We found the sword.
See? I promised you this matter
would be resolved, Yuri.
Uh...
we'll need to take
this back to our lab.
No. You people have already
lost it once.
It's part of an
ongoing investigation.
We need to process it.
This sword is invaluable.
To us as well.
Surely this is open
for conversation, Mr...
I don't think so.
I do have a question
for Mr. Yamamoto.
Your collection is
primarily 17th century,
but we found one piece,
a suit of armor,
that our research dates
to the mid-19th century.
I don't have a suit of armor
in my collection.
What is going on here?
Mr. Caulfield,
we'd like to take a look
at your personal vault.
( beeping )
Oh, my God.
The cash-- it's gone.
How the hell did
they get in here?
How much cash
did you have in here?
90% of the casino's cash
is in the basement vault.
I only keep an
emergency reserve here.
Ten million...
...at all times.
The Trojan horse?
Someone was
inside the armor,
hiding in plain sight?
Maybe.
And you just
wheeled him in here?
Get me my lawyers. Assemble everyone.
I need answers.
Yes sir.
And the con goes on.
Well, this explains
the glucose.
Food source.
Probably didn't know how long
he was going to be in the suit.
What's in the other bag?
Urine.
He was in there
for a while.
How you doing
with those money bands?
$10,000 per band.
When I get to a thousand,
I'll let you know.
( tune-like beeping )
I think it's the code
from the vault.
Must've recorded it.
( beeps )
( beeping )
How did you open
the safe door?
The same way
our thief did:
using your musical code.
Mr. Caulfield,
you have video surveillance?
Nothing in my vault
or in my office,
but I'll get you everything
from this floor.
For you...
...and you.
Just in case.
Are Angela's
tox result in yet?
Blood alcohol level
of .14 percent.
Her friends didn't say
anything about drinking.
Well, I'm just getting
warmed up.
Tox panel
detected traces
of thujone.
Thujone is
the psychoactive chemical
found in absinthe, a liquor
distilled from wormwood.
Isn't absinthe illegal?
In the US. Banned in 1912.
Apparently, toxic byproducts
are released
during the distilling process.
Stuff's supposed to make you
a little crazy.
And how would Angela
get a hold of this?
Well, this is not coming
from personal experience,
but according to a
friend of a friend
of an acquaintance,
absinthe is rumored to be served
in certain underground clubs.
Like a blood bar.
♪ Are you ... ready
for the new ...? ♪
♪ Stand up and admit it:
tomorrow's never coming ♪
♪ This is the new ... ♪
♪ Stand up and admit it ♪
♪ Do we need it? ♪
♪ No! ♪
♪ Do we want it? ♪
♪ Yeah! ♪
♪ This is the new ... ♪
Mind if we join you?
Sure. What are you into?
We're into crime scenes.
And you are...?
Lazarus Kane.
Did Angela Sommerville
call you that?
I don't know
any Angela Sommerville.
What about Daegonna?
She file a complaint against me?
Why would she do that?
Look, everything we did
was consensual.
It's not illegal to
drink someone's blood.
She was into it.
That neonate...
she offered herself to me.
Did she offer herself
to you last night?
We had a drink
together here.
Absinthe?
What's this about?
Was that the last time
you saw her?
No. Later on,
I swung by
her court and daggered
the relationship.
How long had
the two of you
been together?
For the past three months,
she's been my donor.
And you were her donor?
No, it doesn't
work like that.
Daegonna belonged to me.
Okay... but you were
someone's donor.
Well, under the right
circumstances,
I'll do just about anything.
How 'bout murder?
Daegonna was killed
last night.
Well, I don't know anything
about that.
See, I follow very
strict guidelines:
Black Veil.
Principle 11:
you never mistreat your donors.
And that pendant
around you neck?
That wouldn't happen
to contain blood,
would it?
Yeah.
Whose?
It's Daegonna's, okay?
She gave it to me
couple weeks ago.
I offered to give it back,
but she wanted me to keep it...
said her psi belonged to me.
"Psi"?
Life-force, blood.
We're going to need
that pendant for evidence.
And a sample of your...
DNA.
Knock yourself out.
Oh, I prefer saliva.
Aw...
Open up.
Right.
STOKES:
There's our man.
And the time?
3:15 a.m.
He's certainly
aware of the cameras.
Yeah, you really can't get
a good look at him
from any angle.
He's walking like
he crapped his pants.
I'm thinking
that might be the money.
An employee ID card?
It gets better.
That's Brandon Miller,
the security guard.
Hmm.
Okay, so find the
best shot you can
of our mystery thief.
If he is an employee,
you should be able to ID him.
There's over 3,000 employees
who work at the Mediterranean,
and this guy is not really
giving me much to go on here.
Yes, but technology
is a wonderful thing, Nick.
Lazarus may have been sucking
on Angela's shoulders,
but he did not bite her jugular.
His DNA's inconsistent
with the saliva
swabbed from the
puncture wounds
around her neck.
Damn.
What about that pendant?
You know, nothing says
"I love you"
like an ounce of fresh blood.
It is Angela's blood,
and it's mixed with
a polyester base.
Polyester base
is an inert fluid
prepackaged in
test tubes used
for HIV testing.
It helps prepare
the blood
for centrifugation
by forming a barrier
between the blood cells
and the serum.
Angela's parents only insisted
upon only one thing...
That she be tested for HIV.
♪ Said he was man--
what did he know? ♪
♪ Spent his time
living in a casino ♪
♪ Never know ♪
♪ Couldn't get away,
couldn't ever get it anyway ♪
♪ Couldn't ever level 'cause
he's living like a devil, hey ♪
♪ Hey, you ugly people ♪
♪ I want you
to set my baby free ♪
♪ Hey, set my baby free ♪
♪ People, set my baby free ♪
♪ Set my baby free... ♪
Yeah, that's Nathan.
Do me a favor
when you find him.
Let him know
he's fired.
He hasn't shown
up in four days.
Will do.
You missing anything else
around here?
Like what?
CPR dummy.
Yeah. Had to cancel
a class on Sunday
'cause we couldn't find
Macaulay.
Macaulay?
Culkin. Our dummy.
You know, 'cause his
mouth is always open.
Is this Macaulay?
Yeah, that's him.
Can we get him back?
Soon as we're done
with him.
SIDLE:
Security guard put the sword
in the crawlspace.
It's got to be his prints.
GRISSOM:
Well, let's find
out, shall we?
Hey.
Nick, want to do me a favor
and tape-lift that?
Sure.
Grissom, how's our insurance?
I was being careful,
I swear.
Should 400-year-old lacquer
look this good?
And smell like acrylic?
( crunches )
What kind of
precious stone
breaks that easily?
A fake one.
This is nothing more
than a hardened ball of wax.
Do you think someone
switched swords on us?
Well, so far,
nothing's what it seems.
Smells like tea.
Sometimes
paper products
or other materials like silk--
they soak it in tea
to give an aged look.
The paint on this mask
is coming right off,
layer by layer.
I think this is boot polish.
Another aging method?
So it's not just the sword.
This...
This whole collection's a fake?
A what?
We believe
this collection
is worthless.
Well-made,
historically accurate,
but, uh...
probably worthless.
Your head of security said
that Mr. Yamamoto's collection
was documented
by an internal registrar.
Vanessa Green. I-I
thought you spoke
to her yesterday.
She was on vacation...
but even though she's not
an official appraiser,
she should've been able to tell
these were fakes,
don't you think?
Mr. Yamamoto?
I'd like a word with you.
It seems he's left.
Gentlemen, no luggage.
Nothing.
Son of a bitch!
He made a fool out of me.
Well, we have that
in common.
Find out when
he checked out.
I'm on it.
And Vanessa Green.
Where did she go?
Brandon Miller,
Nathan Pollard,
Vanessa Green,
and Yuri Yamamoto.
Three of your employees
and one whale...
all evidently disappear.
Along with my
$10 million.
Yamamoto never
checked out.
Vanessa Green
made reservations
at the Princeville
in Kauai.
She never checked in.
And he left
without his antiques.
Well...
he knew they were worthless.
Um...
I'll be right with you.
The tests will be mailed
to you in seven days,
and they'll include
a toll-free number
if you have any questions.
Thank you.
I didn't
feel a thing.
Walk-ins?
Or do you have
an appointment?
We're from the crime lab.
We're here about
a Miss Angela Sommerville.
Last month, your clinic
tested her blood.
Actually, we don't
do the testing.
Common mistake.
I'm contracted
by AdminaLab to withdraw blood,
and the lab processes.
And the whole thing
is confidential, so...
Oh, we've already seen
her results.
She's dead,
so, the confidentiality
privilege
no longer applies.
We need to know
which tech
withdrew her blood.
I'm the only tech here.
Oh.
Well, there was a pendant
with her blood inside it.
What does that
have to do with me?
Her blood was mixed
with a polyester base.
I think you know
what that means.
I... know
who you're talking about.
I have a favor to ask you.
Do you want to help?
I'd taken more than enough
for testing purposes,
so, I figured
it's her blood.
Why not just give it to her?
My bet is that
it's against your lab's policy.
Great.
You going to report me?
Uh, you can't go in there.
We have a warrant.
T-That's my personal fridge.
Now, what's this blood
doing in there?
Mr. Jones...
I'm going to need a sample
of your DNA.
I bet you don't have a warrant
for that.
Catherine,
I think we have
all we need here.
SIDLE:
Handle is molded plastic fiber.
Materials are used by hundreds
of manufacturers
throughout the country.
It's impossible to trace.
Vintage cherry red
leathers,
bronze PVC fabric, aged.
Countless furniture
and clothing suppliers.
Nothing really unique.
But the ivory
on the sword's scabbard
is unique.
In fact, it's not ivory.
It's treated bone from an emu.
Inexpensive,
but not widely used.
STOKES:
Only about half a
dozen US importers.
One did recently make a sale
to a business in Las Vegas.
That same business
also bought vintage leather,
molded plastics
and everything else
he used to make this collection.
Chen's Scenic
Prop House--
owned by Graeme Chen
of 1 Engelfield Road,
Las Vegas, Nevada.
Also his place
of business.
As of
five minutes ago,
no one's answering the phone.
Call Brass. Get a warrant.
You know,
I always imagined your house
would look like this, Gil.
Hey, Grissom,
check this out.
Prototypes, maybe.
Looks like Mr. Chen
tried a few times
before committing.
Well, he certainly
does beautiful work.
BRASS:
Want to see
a picture
of Mr. Chen?
I guess he lived here, too.
GRISSOM:
Mr. Chen is
Mr. Yamamoto.
He's not even Japanese.
So, this is how Ty Caulfield's
high rollers live--
a cot
in a warehouse.
Well, I'm guessing
he spent all his money
on the baccarat tables,
buying himself
a reputation.
You got to spend money
to make money.
Hey.
Take a look at this.
Brandon Miller,
the security guard,
the lifeguard,
Nathan Pollard,
and I'm guessing
the registrar,
Vanessa Green.
So, Mr. Chen made
their costumes,
their props
and their scenery.
WOMAN:
♪ Three little maids
from school are we... ♪
( tones beeping same refrain)
You ever listen
to Gilbert and Sullivan?
No.
Ty Caulfield does.
The code
from his digital vault.
Coincidence?
I don't think so.
How much does $10
million in cash
weigh, I wonder?
A lot.
Sara, I'm going to need the
money bands you collected.
Nick, you get to do the math.
The blood
in your personal fridge
belonged to
Angela Sommerville.
We found a lip print
on the rim of the container
we confiscated.
It's not a crime
to drink someone's blood.
How did her blood
end up in your fridge?
When Angela came in
for her HIV test,
she asked me to withdraw
an extra unit.
She paid me
20 bucks to store it,
and never came back
to pick it up.
And what, you just got thirsty?
Angela's test date
was 32 days ago,
and our lab determined
that the blood
from your fridge
was less than
a week old.
Would you explain that?
Most girls just turn away
when I stick the needle in.
She was into it.
I started... watching over her.
She was dating this... wanna-be.
A total Hollywood freak show.
Oh, so you're the real thing?
These don't come out.
Mr. Jones,
give me a file,
and I could sharpen my teeth
into fangs.
I was born with these.
Mm-hmm.
The night that
Angela was murdered,
you were
"watching over her."
I will not
be tied down.
No, Lazarus,
please don't go.
BOBBY:
The poser just took off.
She... invited me in.
Yeah?
She was glad to see me.
Who are you?
We kissed.
Get off me.
She, um...
offered herself to me.
Stop it!
You mean she offered her blood
to you?
Yeah.
( screaming )
She may have
offered her blood to you,
but you took
her life.
You murdered her.
You can't prove that.
DNA from your saliva
was on the rim
of the container.
It's consistent
with the saliva
surrounding the puncture marks
on Angela's neck.
I released Angela from her body.
She's inside of me now.
A part of me.
And she's very much alive.
What's this?
This is
what's left
of your $10 million.
Thank you for reminding me.
Do you know
how much
$10 million weighs?
220 pounds.
Your lifeguard,
Nathan Pollard-- 5'6",
140 pounds.
Strong little bastard.
Mmm.
Say, could I borrow $10,000
in $100 bills?
What?
Only for a demonstration.
I'm sorry.
I'm all out.
That's okay.
I brought my own.
It's only paper,
but it's
the same size,
weight and density.
Did you know...
money bands are wrapped tightly
around stacks of bills?
They're
very difficult
to slip off.
In fact, the only way
you can get them off
is to tear them.
What's your point?
None of your money bands
were torn.
Now, I don't know
how much money you had
in your vault, Mr. Caulfield,
but I'm pretty sure
I know
how much you're going
to be asking
your insurance
company for.
You see, that's why
you had your "thief"
leave the money bands
behind.
You hired Mr. Chen
and his merry band of actors
to rip you off.
I'm sure
you paid them,
but nothing close
to $10 million.
"Your notions, though many,
are not worth a penny."
Mmm. The Mikado.
Notions are all you have.
Otherwise, we'd be downtown
instead of here
in my office.
You know, I've always been
a big supporter of the arts.
Hence, Mr. Yamamoto...
Uh, Mr. Chen's...
Hence, the exhibition.
Over the years, I've financed
theatrical productions.
Including The Mikado?
Well, you know,
one of your "partners"
is going to come back
again someday.
He's going to miss his family,
friends,
the ensemble.
He'll be back.
And I'm guessing
he'll tell us all about
your latest
production.
Yes, well,
until then, Mr. Grissom.
Until then.
I'm going to hand my findings
over to your insurance company.
I wouldn't count
on receiving a payment.