I searched the vehicle
at the CSI garage.
I discovered the knife
under the passenger's seat.
Now, is this
the knife you found?
Yes, it is.
Hmm.
Who was the registered owner
of the vehicle?
Michael Fife,
the defendant.
Please describe the physical
condition of the knife
when you discovered it.
The knife was wrapped
in a white towel.
Both the towel
and the knife
were caked
with dried blood.
And how did you process
this evidence?
I swabbed the blood
and sent a sample
to the DNA lab.
The lab technician ran
the sample through CODIS.
The DNA sample was a match
to a recent rape and homicide
victim, Rachel Lyford.
Rachel Lyford who lived
in unit seven of the Saturn Arms
Apartment complex.
The same complex
as the defendant?
That's correct.
Is this knife
consistent in size
and shape to the fatal wounds
sustained by Rachel Lyford?
Yes, it is.
Thank you.
Your Honor, we have
no further questions
for CSI Brown.
Mr. Matthews.
Mr. Brown, you stated
that you found the knife
in Mr. Fife's vehicle.
Is that correct?
Yes, that's correct.
Why did you search his vehicle?
I received a call
from Officer Watson.
He informed me that he had
pulled the defendant over
to cite him
for a broken taillight.
After running his plates,
it was discovered
that the defendant had an
outstanding warrant for drugs.
He then arrested Mr. Fife
and ordered a respond and tow.
At which point,
he asked me
to search the vehicle
for drugs.
That's when I
found the knife.
Mm-hmm.
At what point
did you secure the warrant
to search Mr. Fife's vehicle?
Officer Watson
would have secured
the warrant prior
to calling me.
Officer Watson
never secured a warrant.
Did you?
No.
Your Honor, the knife
is a product
of an unlawful search,
and under NRS
Chapter 179,
we submit the knife and the
towel be ruled inadmissible.
Furthermore, all evidence
acquired as a result
of the seizure
must at this time
be excluded.
So ruled.
Fruit of the poisonous tree.
What else do you have?
Additional evidence
is pending.
The knife would've been
more than sufficient
for the purpose of a prelim.
You have no other evidence
to present?
Not at this time.
I find insufficient evidence
to hold the defendant over
for trial.
He's free to go.
Your Honor, the defendant
is accused
of raping and killing
a 19-year-old woman.
You can't just let him
back on the street.
Are you suggesting
that I violate
his constitutional rights,
Counselor?
Ask him for 24 hours.
Your Honor, we received
no prior notice of this motion.
Um...
we would ask for a continuance
and opportunity to reopen.
We're only asking for 24 hours.
Okay.
If you can't make your case,
Mr. Fife walks.
We will recess for 24 hours.
The murder weapon's been
excluded, that's all.
We still have a lab full
of evidence we can process.
We've been completely
blind-sided here.
Brown, what is going on?
You got to be kidding me.
You were unprepared.
All the evidence
you CSIs collect,
and all you bring
into this courtroom is a knife?
Come on.
I found the knife.
I processed the knife.
I presented the knife.
All you had to do
was the paperwork.
Yeah, blame it on the cop, huh?
Look, you wouldn't even
have a suspect
if I didn't pulled
that guy over.
If you'd've followed protocol,
our suspect would be
going to trial.
If you have
a problem with CSI,
file a complaint--
we're busy.
What about what you said
about never rushing evidence?
Well, for the next 24 hours,
we're breaking the rules.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
Grissom.
Sheriff.
We need to talk...
...about him.
Nice to finally meet
you, too, Sheriff.
Why don't you
go ahead
and start the briefing?
I'll be in in a minute.
Yeah.
Where to?
Warrick Brown
followed protocol.
You cannot pin
this mess on him.
Warrick Brown
was on the stand.
He's the face
of the case.
It's all about perception.
If Fife walks,
public only hears one thing--
"Evidence against a killer
was thrown out of court
because CSI conducted
an improper search."
You think I don't know that?
What the hell is this?
It's irradiated
fetal pig.
I used the tissue to determine
the effects of radiation...
Look, Grissom, you and your team
have done exemplary work.
Thanks to the Crime Lab,
some very difficult cases
have gone our way.
You've elevated the status
of the whole Bureau.
Uh-huh.
Then why are you here?
I'm holding a press conference
in an hour
where I'll be telling the media
that this case is
under your purview.
( chuckles )
Oh, it is about
perception, isn't it?
Glad we understand each other.
Uh... why don't you
call my office next week?
Put a little lunch
on the books, hmm?
I work nights.
So make it a dinner.
BROWN:
Impound towed the vehicle
to the garage.
Michael Fife's
outstanding warrant
was for marijuana possession,
so that's what I
was looking for.
I swabbed the knife and I sent
the blood sample to Greg.
I ran it through CODIS
and matched it
to another case.
My case.
Rachel Lyford, 19.
Murdered in her apartment.
The Assistant Coroner
examined the body.
Based on the vaginal introitus,
he suspected rape.
I processed
the scene.
There was nothing probative.
There were no prints, no DNA.
Everything I collected
is in the vault.
Now, once
Warrick found
the knife, the D.A.
thought there was
sufficient probable cause
and rushed the prelim.
Further processing
of the evidence
became a low priority,
pending the trial date.
This is a RUSH case.
Everyone's in the pool
for 24 hours.
Warrick, you need
to see Robbins.
Have him walk you through
his notes on the autopsy.
Nick, Sara, the judge issued
a warrant for Fife's vehicle.
Detail is towing it
back to our garage.
Hold on.
Warrick's already searched
the car
and the knife's been excluded.
What exactly
are we hoping to find?
GRISSOM:
I don't know.
But the knife and the towel
are invisible evidence.
The jury will never see them.
So we have to find something
that's visible.
Uh, listen, I recognize
the importance of this,
but I'm in the middle of my
own homicide investigation.
I'll talk to your detective.
Explain the deal.
Well, it's not
about the detective.
It's about my own
responsibility.
I'm handing out assignments,
Sara.
It's not a negotiation.
I'll go back to the scene
and look at it with fresh eyes.
GRISSOM:
Deadline's 4:00 P.M. tomorrow.
Once more into the breach.
STOKES:
That was Auto Detail.
There's a traffic jam
on Flamingo.
Tow truck should
be here any second.
You know
what pisses me off?
Lots of things.
Victims aren't equal.
High profile cases
get priority.
A ticking clock
gets priority.
Every case is
a ticking clock.
The only difference
between a cold case
and a hot case is time.
I don't care
if you're working
on the hottest case
of your career.
If your supervisor tells
you to leave a scene
to go wash his car,
you do it.
You don't have a career
without a job.
Heard you're on a RUSH.
Sorry.
That's not the right car, man.
Uh, registered owner
Michael Fife, BMW 325.
Impounded ten days ago.
What the hell happened?
It's been pancaked.
STOKES:
We can see that.
Why?
Hey, I just move 'em.
This is evidence
in an active investigation.
Paperwork mix-up?
Or some moron checked
the wrong box.
You can just
unload it here.
Sign here.
I got to get back to the lot.
Thanks.
ROBBINS:
Body was released last week.
Cremated at Desert Haven.
I.D.'d by the sister.
Pretty girl.
Couldn't stop crying.
Yeah, Rita.
They were real close.
Lived together up
until a couple months ago.
These stab wounds look
like they're limited
to the neck and upper
torso area, huh?
ROBBINS:
Fatal stab was
to the left side of the neck.
The blade traversed
the subcutaneous tissue,
sternocleido-mastoid muscle,
jugular venous complex,
the carotid artery
and the Vagus nerve.
She bled right out.
Raped.
No semen in the vaginal vault.
I don't know if it's relevant,
but check out the abrasion.
There was something
around her neck.
Noted.
What is this foreign substance
on her wrist?
Pre-autopsy.
David snapped the photo
before he washed her body.
He's in Clean Up.
Bringing your laundry
to work again, David?
I'm cleaning a pelvis.
Great.
I'm here about one
Rachel Lyford.
You prepped her body?
Yeah, ten days ago.
I thought it was
Catherine's case.
It's mine now.
You notice this foreign
substance on her wrists?
It was flaky.
Like the glaze on a doughnut?
I sent a sample
to Trace.
Trace. Thanks.
You're the man.
Have fun.
Sample's still running
through the GCMS.
I'll let you know.
How'd you know
that I was...
4-1-1 from David.
Hey, I heard about court today.
Must have been
embarrassing, huh?
Hodges, why'd you leave
L.A. again?
Never mind, it's probably
none of my business.
Hey, Rick, you okay?
'Cause I'm here to drop
some more pressure on you.
Yeah?
Rachel Lyford's sister
showed up at the police station.
Man, she was angry.
She was firing
on all cylinders.
I don't blame her.
Apparently, Rachel wore
a silver chain around her neck.
It wasn't with
her personal effects.
Had her father's
Army dog tags on it
and the family
wants it back.
You came all the way
over here for dog tags?
Well...
the Sheriff asked me
to find it.
You know, Rory Atwater's
been in office for--
what?-- four months,
so it's political.
He doesn't want
the victim's sister
bad-mouthing
his department.
Mm-hmm.
Check it out.
Dr. Robbins found
consistent abrasions
on the back of her neck, so...
that's probably
your chain.
Uh-huh.
Okay.
Killer took a souvenir.
I'll let the Sheriff know.
Thanks.
All right.
What do you got?
Got a print off this bottle
I found in the garbage.
It was the only
bottle like it.
None others
in the apartment.
Need a hand?
You could do the sheets.
You know, the steak knife
I found in that car
matches that set.
GRISSOM:
We only found five knives
in Rachel's kitchen.
Five's an odd number
of steak knives.
Exactly.
Weapon of opportunity, perhaps?
Perhaps.
Grissom, what do you
make of this?
We noted a similar type
substance on the girl's wrists.
GRISSOM:
Doesn't look like it belongs
on the victim or her sheets.
Stop it.
What?
Watching the clock.
It's just that new evidence
is coming in
and the old evidence hasn't
even been processed yet.
We're running out of time here,
you know?
If you're watching the clock,
you're not watching the case.
Well, not even you
can stop time.
Thank you.
Oh... I remember now.
I'm reading the same book.
Really? Any good?
Yeah, so far.
( phone rings )
( answering machine beeps )
Hi, it's Rachel.
Sorry I missed your call.
I promise to get back to you
as soon as I can.
Have a great day.
( machine beeps )
MAN:
Hey, Rachel.
It's Walter. Walter Burr.
We exchanged numbers at Diane's
party a few weeks ago.
Anyway, just thought you might
want to grab a drink sometime.
So, give me a call.
I processed this place
for 12 straight hours.
I never took a break.
Couldn't eat.
Yeah, my sister calls that
the CSI diet.
She's a CSI out
in Bakersfield.
Whole family wears a badge.
( sighs )
If you want to ALS again,
I'll grab the lights.
No, I went over every square
inch of this place.
I did the mattress, the sheets,
the floors, the cabinets.
If the rapist ejaculated, he was
smart enough to use a condom.
I'm no expert,
but most guys can't wait
to take off their rubber jacket.
You check the
wastebasket?
Yeah, I did,
but...
not every guy uses the trash.
Guy had sticky fingers.
Semen?
Oh, yeah.
Fresh eyes, new evidence.
I think we're done.
Then let's get started.
What do you got?
Parking placard.
"Saturn Arms."
It was affixed
to the rearview mirror.
It's the same kind of permit
we use at my
apartment building.
Hmm.
White threads...
It is impossible
to trace the source
of a white thread.
Reddish-brown stain
consistent with blood.
Really?
Mmm.
That could match
the bloody towel
that Warrick found.
Well, the towel is inadmissible,
but the threads
are still fair game.
So...
you still upset about your case
being put on hold?
( chuckles mischievously )
Jacqui Franco.
You responded to my page
in under 45 seconds.
Gotta be a record.
Tell me you've found
something probative.
Extremely probative.
Grissom lifted a print off
a beer bottle Catherine found
in Rachel Lyford's trash.
Print matches your suspect.
Oh, wicked.
You know, in the pretrial
interview, Fife denied
ever being in the
victim's apartment.
Let him try to deny
the print.
Thank you.
Mm-hmm.
Counselor, your client's
rights...
Detective, let me finish.
...will not be violated.
I want it on
the record
that my client has been advised
not to take this meeting.
I want to hear what
they have to say.
WARRICK:
Several hours ago,
we found
blood-stained threads
in the back
of your client's car.
DNA ran the blood.
It is consistent
with Rachel Lyford's.
It is admissible into evidence.
Now, what do you have to say?
I don't know anything
about any threads.
How well did you know
the victim?
That's an easy one.
Rachel was a neighbor.
I'd say, "Hi."
"How are you?"
That's it.
Were you ever
in her apartment?
We've been through that before.
Well, we're gonna
go through it again.
He's never been inside
the victim's apartment.
Were you ever in her apartment?
Your client's
fingerprints
were on a beer bottle collected
from the victim's trash.
You don't have
to submit to this, Michael.
Just say the word.
No, I got... I got this one.
The night before Rachel
was killed,
there was a party
in the courtyard...
( music playing,
people talking )
She must've taken the trash
back inside her unit.
( Brass laughs )
What do I look like, Mike?
Listen to me.
I don't know who killed Rachel.
I don't know how that knife
got in my car.
I didn't even know
my taillight was busted
until that dumb-ass
cop pulled me over.
I've been in jail for ten days
on something I didn't do,
and I am tired of this crap!
You might want to control
your temper, Mike.
It can get you
in a lot of trouble.
Detective Brass, if you were
ready to make your case,
we'd be back in court,
not an interrogation room.
Assuming without the knife,
you have nothing
to directly connect my client
to the attack,
in 12 hours, he's going to be
getting his street clothes.
I'd like to speak
to Mr. Brown.
I don't mind waiting.
Oh, ma'am, he's at P.D.
I can relay a message...
That's okay.
I'm just... I need
to talk to him, so...
Mr. Brown.
Yeah. Hi.
I know you must be
extremely busy...
but I need to know...
I need you to tell me
that Michael Fife
is going to pay for what he did
to my sister.
I'm doing everything I can.
My mother's been medicated,
and I can't sleep,
and you're, what?
You're on a coffee break?
Actually, it's the first
break I've had since court,
so, if you'll excuse me,
I have a lot of work to do.
What's going on here?!
Does anyone even care?!
Ms. Lyford? Ms. Lyford,
I'm Nick Stokes.
I'm also a criminalist
here in the lab,
and I want you to
know I understand.
I understand
your frustration.
This is not an easy thing to
deal with, but I can assure you
that this entire lab is
on your sister's case.
Okay? I can't make
any promises,
but we're doing
everything possible
to keep this suspect behind
bars, where he belongs.
Thank you.
That's all I needed to hear.
Okay.
Thank you.
Hang in there.
What's up, Warrick?
What's up with what?
With you.
This job is hard enough
without having victims' families
up in your face.
Her sister was raped
and murdered.
She watched the defense
decimate your case.
I think you could have
given her five minutes.
You want to hold this girl's
hand, that's fine by me.
That seems to be your M.O.
But when you empathize
instead of sympathize,
I don't judge you.
She just wants to know
that someone around here
gives a damn, Warrick.
You know what?
Lunch is over.
Time to go back to work.
( kicks trash can over )
Hey, you.
Hey.
How, uh, are you holding up?
I'm fine.
You sure?
Yeah.
You're in the women's bathroom.
Oh, God, I'm sorry.
No, I...
I'm all for it.
Oh, God...
( laughs )
Oh...
This case is twisting me up.
Interrogation room...
was a bust.
Fife can lie better
than I can tell the truth.
Better to know his lies
before we go to trial.
I don't think
it's going to trial.
We've got time.
Seminal DNA's being processed
as we speak.
This case can break any minute.
I'm not giving up.
I'm just being realistic.
Come on, you
know, Warrick,
we don't just call these cases
RUSH 'cause we're in a hurry.
It's a RUSH
'cause our pulse races,
it's a rush
when we nail the guy...
I like that.
Oh, hey! Hey, boss!
Yes?
I Just ID'ed the substance
from Rachel Lyford's wrist.
Same substance found
on the sheets.
Have you told Warrick?
He's the lead on this.
Yeah, about Warrick,
what exactly happened
in court today?
I tried to talk to him,
he just shut down.
He just shut you down.
What is the substance?
Uh... wax.
What kind of wax?
Uh, still
working on that,
but I can tell you
that it does have a
low melting point.
The GCMS doesn't
have a wax library.
I've ordered up a reference
from the New Jersey state lab.
RUSH.
Okay.
Cross-check the product labels
off the Internet.
And, uh, listen, if you need
someone to talk to...
Yeah, when's a good time?
We have a psychologist here
on Tuesdays and Fridays.
DNA on the toilet flusher.
On the Three-Ten,
we're five
seconds out.
Three, two, one.
Sorry.
Suspect's DNA is inconsistent
with the semen found
at the scene.
Great.
Hey, Grissom,
that sheriff's checked
with just about every tech
in the lab looking for you.
He's bugging for an update.
I suggest
you avoid him.
Why? What happened?
Our only suspect
may be innocent.
SIDLE:
You're saying that
the DNA results
exclude our suspect,
but couldn't the semen have come
from a prior sexual encounter
with another man?
STOKES:
Fife still could
have raped and murdered Rachel.
WILLOWS:
Well, the toilet
bowl was clean.
The semen belongs
to whoever flushed
the toilet last,
but there was a drop,
not a smear.
GRISSOM:
Look, we have
no evidence
that he raped her,
that he killed her, and even
if we consider
the invisible evidence,
it still doesn't give us enough
to put him at the scene
of the crime during
the commission of the crime.
Our trinity of evidence
is incomplete.
WILLOWS:
Okay, so, for
argument's sake,
let's assume that Fife didn't
put the knife in the car.
How did it get there?
Okay, um, does he live alone?
Yeah.
Recently separated.
His wife moved back
to Albuquerque.
And no one else had access
to his vehicle.
Was there any sign
of forced entry?
No sign of
forced entry.
And what evidence is still
outstanding?
GRISSOM:
The wax.
What's-his-name is still
analyzing it.
WILLOWS:
Well, I know that
there was wax
on the sheets
and the victim's body.
How about the murder weapon?
I didn't notice,
but I wasn't looking.
STOKES:
Doesn't matter.
Knife's excluded.
GRISSOM:
The exclusionary rule
only applies to the person
whose constitutional rights
were violated.
If we have another suspect,
then the knife is back
in play.
Grissom?
( heavy sigh )
I'm sorry. You look lost.
I've been calling your cell.
Well, we get bad reception
at CSI. Listen,
if this is about dinner,
I'm free next week.
I'll be having the fish.
We have nine hours
left on the clock, Grissom.
Well, the investigation,
which is under my purview,
has taken an
unexpected turn.
So, when I know something,
you'll know something.
I don't like surprises.
Me, neither.
What, you're not going
to tell me anything?
No.
Okay.
For now.
Mm-hmm.
Checking my work?
Oh, I'm just
looking around.
What are you thinking?
Well,
her body left
behind this void.
The attacker was on top.
He held her down by her wrists.
Which would explain the transfer
of wax from him to her.
Yes.
Pin me down.
She would have struggled.
Then, she gave up.
Afterward, when he got up,
he put his hands on the sheet
for leverage.
Like this.
Which explains how
the wax got from
him to the sheets.
Yes.
Grissom, um, I, um,
wanted to talk to you
about something.
Go ahead.
Well, you know, I applied
for the promotion
for the key position.
Your application's on my desk.
About that--
I, um... I needed to know...
I...
I wanted to make
sure, rather, that
anything that happened
or didn't happen between us
won't be a factor.
Never mind.
I-I shouldn't have said
anything.
I, um...
I'm always
over-talking around you.
Have you ever
heard of body wax?
Made with soy, burns clean.
Drip it all over
your partner's body.
I thought that we installed
a fire-wall
for sites like these.
This is research.
Body wax has been eliminated.
What have you got?
Well,
I've I.D.'d the wax.
But, per Grissom,
I am not allowed
to release any
of my results
except to
the lead CSI,
and that would
be Warrick.
I've already
paged him.
Give me.
Axion Car Wax.
Contains carnuba wax,
butyl cellusolve
and cationic surfactant.
Exact same ratio
as the exemplars.
Ah.
There's a little
souvenir for you.
Thank you.
GRISSOM:
Axion Wax is
industrial grade.
It's sold to car washes
for commercial use only.
Yeah. Fife's an electrician.
I doubt he would come
into contact with that at work.
Then, we need to know
where he gets his car washed.
WILLOWS:
Except, if we ask him,
we show our cards,
and his lawyer will know
that we're looking
in another direction.
Yeah, then he'll
petition Judge Brenner
for Fife's immediate release.
How do you feel
about letting him walk?
We've got, what,
less than seven hours.
Let's not pull any punches.
If the evidence is leading us
away from Fife,
I say we go with it.
Mr. Fife,
let's establish
a sequence of events.
Walk us through
the night of the party
at your apartment complex
right up until your
arrest the next day.
Don't skip a beat.
Devil's in the details, huh?
Could be.
I hung out until about midnight.
Drank my six pack.
Hit on a couple girls.
Struck out.
Went back to my apartment,
passed out.
In the morning,
I drove up to Green Valley
and installed a chandelier,
two sconces.
At noon,
I went back to my apartment,
and I made
a tuna fish sandwich.
Lettuce, tomato,
spoon of relish.
Wheat bread.
Then... I took a leak.
I don't want to skip a beat.
Outstanding.
So, then what?
So, I liked your
tough act yesterday.
Huh?
"I hand out
the assignments.
This isn't
a negotiation."
What, too much?
Not enough.
That afternoon,
I had a job
in Henderson.
On my way, I stopped,
uh, at a car wash.
It was a lunch-hour
discount.
What car wash?
Reliant,
on Chardon Circle.
It's about a block
from my apartment.
Why are you asking
about a car wash?
At Reliant, did the attendant
say anything
about your broken taillight?
No. Yeah, in fact, I mean,
they should've said something.
The tenor of these questions
leads me to believe
the focus of your investigation
has shifted.
This conversation is over,
Michael.
WARRICK:
I just talked to the manager.
Of course,
he didn't recognize Fife
from the six pack of photos.
We're cleared to look around.
By bringing your car
to a car wash, you pretty much
open it up
into the entire world, right?
Vehicles are most vulnerable
down that tunnel.
So, I'm thinking
that Michael Fife's
taillight was intact
when he arrived.
I'm sure the attendant
would have told him something.
They're liable, right?
Exactly.
So, his car proceeds
on down the line,
and then inside the tunnel,
someone,
presumably our killer,
stashes the knife,
breaks the taillight.
Busted taillight's
an equipment violation.
NRS 485.511.
Yeah, you'd get pulled over
for that pretty quickly.
And the killer
is banking
on some
ambitious cop
searching the vehicle.
Okay, so, a broken taillight.
The pieces fall into the water.
WARRICK:
The fragments
have to run off
through some kind
of drain.
Uh, excuse me, sir.
A-Are you the manager?
Yeah.
Does your drain have a filter?
There's a screen trap
behind the drain.
Catches everything bigger
than an ice cream sprinkle.
Well, when was the last time
you had it cleaned?
About a month ago. Why?
I'm going to have
to clean your trap.
Sorry, lady.
Can't just close down the shop.
I got customers.
I understand, sir,
but you know,
just let us shut you down
for about an hour or so.
Otherwise,
we can get a search warrant,
come back on Saturday, your
busiest day, and, well...
it's up to you.
Soon as that Porsche Cayenne
works its way
through the line...
I'll shut her off.
The Crime Lab
thanks you for your
cooperation, sir.
You're welcome.
All right, Sassy.
Look what I found.
A broken taillight.
Hey, could two cars
get too close to each other
and have an accident
in here?
There's no way.
Photocell technology.
Whole system shuts
down if the cars get
within three feet
of each other.
Believe me,
in this tunnel,
accidents do not happen.
Which means the taillight
was broken on purpose.
Okay, uh, thank you,
thanks for coming down here
and volunteering
to give a DNA sample.
We know you work hard,
so, in an effort to be nice,
we've provided some lunch,
some burgers and stuff,
compliments of the Las Vegas
Police Department.
Okay, let's form
two lines now.
Everybody
whose birthday
is from January
to June
in this line,
everybody else over here.
How long is this crap
going to take?
As long as it takes, okay?
Thank you.
All right,
you guys,
I'm going to be swabbing
your left cheek,
so, uh...
try not to bite down.
Uh, ma'am, I got
to take a leak.
Well, you just hold on there.
It's only going
to take a second.
Open.
Thank you.
Uh, Akers,
do me a favor and escort
this guy to the john.
Let's go.
( clearing throat )
MAN:
You guys are making
a big mistake.
I don't know a Rachel Lyford,
I swear.
Really?
Well, I swear
that you do.
I found semen on the toilet
in Rachel's apartment
that matches
your DNA.
You don't have to respond,
but if you can explain
the semen...
I know a Rachel, okay?
I never knew her last name.
Did the girl
that you guys are looking for
live at the Saturn
Arms apartments?
So, you do know her.
I... here's the deal, okay?
A car wax costs
60 bucks, okay?
We give you
discounts sometimes.
I'll show up early
and, you know,
I'll go to a girl's
apartment before work,
or whatever, you know,
and all the guys do this.
So, Rachel hired you
to wax her car, is that it?
I only charged her 25.
( laughing )
Hi.
Shiny as a new penny.
( laughing )
And your story
is that Rachel came on to you?
Yeah. She was all over me.
She answered the door
in, like, this sexy
little thing, and stuff.
Most of the time,
when a woman answers the door,
it's in sweats,
they got the money ready.
This was not
like that.
( laughing ):
What am I supposed to think?
I don't think so.
Hey, I'm all done.
Uh, hold on a second.
Okay, here you go.
( screaming )
Stop it! Stop it!
After raping her, you realized
she had your name,
knew where
you worked.
One call
to the cops
and you're looking
at 25 to life.
( terrified moaning )
You freaked.
So, you killed her.
( screaming )
Forget life; you're looking
at the death penalty.
Lady, you are whacked.
You didn't find
the murder weapon
in my client's car.
Your client
went from Rachel's apartment
to his job at the car wash.
He took the knife
with him.
A few hours later,
Michael Fife drove in,
and he planted the knife
in his car.
He just happened
to hide the murder weapon
in a car that belonged
to one of Rachel's neighbors?
It wasn't a coincidence.
It was your lucky day.
You recognized
the parking permit
in his car window.
You broke
the taillight,
you stashed the knife.
Instant suspect.
You recognize these?
The name on the dog tags
is Aaron Lyford.
That's Rachel's father.
She gave them to me.
She gave them to you.
Why did you try to hide them?
Why did you take off
to the bathroom
with the dog tags on?
And you came back
with them missing.
So, I checked it out.
This is an autopsy photo.
The abrasions are evidence.
Those dog tags
were ripped from her neck.
She gave them to you...
over her dead body.
The defendant
arrived at the station
on his own accord.
He provided us with a sample
of his DNA,
and we rushed that sample
to our lab for analysis.
You compared Mr. Quinn's DNA
to DNA from semen
recovered at
the crime scene,
is that correct?
Yes, that's correct.
It was a match.
CHIEF DEPUTY D.A.:
Judge, we have no
further questions.
Ms. Finn?
Your Honor, we have no questions
for CSI Brown.
JUDGE BRENNER:
Based on
the evidence,
I find sufficient
probable cause
to order the defendant
to stand trial
for the sexual assault
and murder of
Rachel Lyford.
( pounds gavel )
I'm terribly sorry
for your loss.
And your father's tags
are in a safe place.
I'll make sure
they get back to you.
Thank you for everything.
You're more than welcome.
ATWATER:
Hey, sorry I'm late.
GRISSOM:
Well, I think
you're right on time.
There must be
a press conference nearby, huh?
( clearing throat )
I wanted to include CSI Brown
in this.
There might be a few questions
outside my...
Purview?
Want to meet me
out in the corridor ASAP?
Sheriff, I'm not too good
with cameras.
You won't have to talk much.
Grissom, thanks.
For what?
See you back at the lab.