CLAY:
What do you need to get?
Actually, it's what
you need to get, rook.
Aw, come on, man.
We're off duty.
You're off
when I say you're off.
Don't forget the Ho-Hos.
Yeah...
I can help you
over here, sir.
That's not what
your light says.
Slow night?
Kind of.
Oh... can't forget
the Ho-Hos.
( gun clicks faintly )
MAN:
What the hell is wrong
with you people?
My wife is still in there!
Why isn't anybody
helping my wife?!
Body count's five.
Officer Clay
entered the store
unaware of a robbery
that was in progress.
Officer Fromansky
came in after he
heard a shot fired.
Engaged two suspects.
Lit the place up.
The ski masks
are John Does.
The rest
have wallet IDs.
Woman at the back
is Julia Reed,
cocktail waitress
at the Tangiers.
Man on Aisle Four
is Rufus Sanders,
cab driver.
How you want us
to handle this, Grissom?
Same way you'd eat
an elephant...
one bite at a time.
Hey, Jim...
did you know
that Charles Manson
is only 5'2"?
Yeah, little guys tend
to overcompensate.
Do you remember the, uh, story
about...
how and where the marshals
found old Charlie
when they raided
Barker Ranch?
Yeah. I always, uh...
I always liked that story.
We need a medic!
and Volkswagen.
On the road of life
there are passengers
and there are drivers.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
All right, tell me
what happened.
I was in my radio car
when I heard shots fired.
I called for backup.
I went in.
Clay, talk to me.
Clay!
( gunfire )
How many shots you fire?
Three. No, four. I fired four.
BRASS:
Then what?
I saw my partner
on the floor.
I went towards him.
Second gunman came at me.
How many shots you fire
at the second gunman, total?
Maybe-maybe five.
I'd taken a shot
in my vest.
Hard to count under those
conditions. Are you sure?
No, I'm not sure.
That's why I said maybe...
...but I know I shot four
at the third guy.
I was going to
check on my partner.
I caught movement in the back.
Black coat, ski mask, gun...
I put him down.
BRASS:
He fire at you?
Didn't give
him a chance.
All right, that's
all we need for now.
I need your weapon.
My partner...
I want to be the one
to tell his wife.
He was my responsibility.
BRASS:
All right.
All right, look,
if you're not going to say it,
I will.
Fromansky said
he killed three,
and there are two dead ski masks
in there.
Now, you
cranked him up
pretty good on that
vigilante case last year.
Is that going to be a problem?
No.
Everybody, could
I please have
your attention?
All right, folks, I know
that you've been through
an awful lot this evening.
If you could just bear with me
a little longer,
I need to talk
with every one of
you one at a time,
so I promise to get
you out of here as
quickly as possible.
Is the, uh,
guy in black the
cocktail waitress'
husband?
Yeah. Do you
want him first?
WILLOWS:
I don't think he's
ready for me just yet.
I'm going to get
to him soon enough.
What happened
to your assault
in Henderson?
I closed it.
Where do you need me?
There's two more bodies
over by the beer.
You got it.
Barely cleared the holster.
Reflex, maybe. Pulled the
trigger before he had a target.
( gunshot )
Not quick enough.
Those two guys came
out of nowhere...
made everybody go to the corner.
Where, specifically?
Uh... dry goods.
Then one guy grabs Celeste...
Which guy?
I was looking at his piece,
not his face, okay?
Shotgun or handgun?
Shotgun. He drags her
over to the registers,
makes her open 'em up.
She does.
They're pulling out the cash,
and then he sees
the cops roll up.
Second guy says,
"Everybody, get down
and don't say a freaking word,"
so that's what I did.
And then...
And then?
( gunshots )
Ankles and flashes and booms.
That's all I remember.
And you never moved
from that spot?
No, I didn't.
Do you have somewhere
you need to be?
I got to change my pants.
Sorry.
MAN:
Well, you know, we're not
the most modern store around.
How long is the
surveillance loop?
About 24 hours.
What, uh... what happened
to these tapes here?
Nothing.
These are active cameras,
right?
Those VCRs are busted.
Never got 'em fixed.
You know, cutbacks.
Over the register
and outside works.
That's all we really need.
Gotta keep an eye on
the employees, right?
They steal worse
than the customers.
You know, this guy
hit a $75 jackpot.
Probably shoving quarters
in his pockets
when this whole
thing went down.
The door was 20 feet away.
He probably could've
made a run for it.
You know,
after the MGM Grand fire,
they found people fused
to slot machines.
Never even made it
out of their seats.
This guy probably thought
it was his lucky day.
I'm sure he wasn't going
to leave without his money.
We all just started running
when those two psychos
started shooting it out
with the cop...
( gunshots )
( screaming )
I took a first aid course
about a hundred years ago,
so I-I-I tried
to keep pressure on the wound,
but it just kept bleeding,
you know?
I couldn't leave Rufus
all alone, scared, dying.
You were friends?
Mm, sort of.
He-he'd come in a couple
of times a week
and play the quarter slots.
From where you
and Rufus were,
could you see
Officer Fromansky?
Oh, the cop who saved us?
No. I couldn't see anything.
I just heard
all that gunfire
just blasting away.
Hey.
Entry wound's
on the left side.
There's no exit wound?
Skin's thicker on the back.
Captured the bullet.
We'll retrieve it at autopsy.
I was, uh...
holding Julia's hand
trying to find
a place to hide...
somewhere safe.
It was those stupid heels,
you know.
She was always forgetting
to bring her flats to work.
( automatic gunfire )
( shotgun cocking and firing)
( single gunshot )
They didn't have
to shoot her.
They were wearing masks.
We didn't even get
a good look at them.
Mr. Reed, you can't
look for reasons here.
We'll have it
out in a second.
The trick is to apply
even pressure all around.
Is there something wrong
with tweezers?
They can mess up
the striae.
You've got enough to deal with
without my toolmarks in the mix.
Here we go.
Huh.
Paper or plastic?
Officer Clay's
already been processed.
We wanted to get him
to his family.
Did you get prints
off the two suspects?
Uh, yeah.
They're right here.
And we also got bullets
from both of them.
Good.
Prison tattoos.
They weren't virgins.
Hi, I was wondering
if I might be able to speak
with Celeste Turner.
She, uh, has a gunshot wound.
She was brought in from
the grocery store robbery.
Right. Curtain Three.
Just out of surgery.
Stable.
She's still pretty
doped up, though.
You're going to have
to come back later.
You going to need these?
Yes. Thank you.
What can you tell me
about the little boy
who was also brought in
from the robbery incident?
Minor injuries.
He's fine. Mostly shock.
He's with his mom.
Hell of a night, huh?
Take your kid to work,
both end up shot.
Wait a minute. So, the little
boy's mother is Celeste Turner?
Yeah.
WILLOWS:
Son of a bitch was behind her
the whole time.
Yeah.
( sighs )
Okay, here's what
I got so far...
There's our two
DOA suspects.
Looks like they
just walked in
off the street.
WILLOWS:
Is there any sign of Fromansky's
mystery gunner?
No. All the cars
in the parking lot
were accounted for,
and the loading dock out back
was deserted,
so...
( typing )
This is the only view
of what went down.
And see here?
Here comes our cop.
Three, four feet away,
doesn't even see him.
The thing I hate the most
is the bad guys always know
if there's going to be
a gunfight.
Officer Clay's one shot
went into the floor.
The bullet fragmented.
That's probably how
that kid got hit.
But Officer
Fromansky's Beretta
and that suspect's TEC-9,
they both had hollow
.9 millimeters.
Between the two of them,
they shot off 18 rounds.
Shotgun was a Mossberg,
model 500.
Eight rounds fired.
Ammo was double-aught buckshot,
nine pellets per shell.
18 bullets, a total of 26
shells, 72 pellets. Enjoy.
Firing two shots!
♪ ♪
Warrick.
Grissom, we got
a problem.
Only one?
We've identified
all the bullets
recovered
at the scene.
There's no evidence
of a third gunmen.
It gets worse.
The bullet that killed
the cocktail waitress--
it came from
Fromansky's gun.
BRASS:
How you feeling,
Officer?
Little sore.
Desk duty hurts
a lot more.
Is there anything you want
to add to your statement?
What's he saying
I did this time?
A bullet from
your gun killed
a cocktail waitress.
A ricochet.
GRISSOM:
No.
A clean shot.
Not possible.
BRASS:
No one at the scene
saw a third gunman.
I would never shoot
at a civilian.
I saw a guy wearing a ski mask,
dark coat, holding a gun.
The girl was wearing a black
sweater, carrying a purse.
I didn't shoot at that.
You'd just took a full load
in the chest.
Maybe you were confused.
Wasn't confused.
Your statement says
that you fired four shots
at this third gunman.
Yeah.
Ballistics
evidence
shows that you spread five shots
over the back wall.
So I fired more than I thought.
So what.
I was engaged with multiple
hostile targets
You're not back
in the Gulf.
You're a police officer.
You're supposed to identify
a target.
And that's what I did.
What are you, pissed off
because the last time you tried
to jam me up
didn't work?
BRASS:
Hey, ease up.
What I said in my statement
is the truth.
The truth is,
we have a dead civilian
with your bullet in her.
This going to the next step?
It has to.
You're on
administrative
leave
pending an
IAB review.
There was no way
I could warn that cop.
I wanted to...
but the guy was right there,
under the counter...
pushing his gun
right into my stomach.
I'm sorry.
You're not the one
that pulled the trigger.
Ms. Turner,
what was your son
doing there with you?
Well, my ex was looking
after him that night.
Then the son of a bitch
shows up at the store.
Had a party to go to.
Practically shoved Henry
out of the car.
I mean...
I'm not allowed
to bring kids to work.
So I snuck Henry
into the office,
and I told him to stay there.
Then?
Then those two maniacs came in.
They shot that poor policeman.
And then everything
just went crazy.
I was running, and I ran to go
find Henry...
but I couldn't find him
anywhere.
Henry!
That's all I remember.
Henry likes his candy,
doesn't he?
He's got five cavities
to prove it.
How'd you know?
Well, we found him in a storage
cabinet, near the candy rack.
He never listens to me.
STOKES:
Double counts,
two people in the
room at all times.
When you're done, match
the total amounts
with the register
receipts, okay?
So, explain to me what all the
money was doing in the registers
and not the store safe.
See that light?
It's called a halo.
It's keyed to the sensor
in the cash register.
Now, at a preset amount,
that light goes off,
letting the store
manager know
it's time to transfer
the cash to the safe.
Now check this out...
( typing )
Most of the halos are lit.
Maximum cash,
just lying in the drawers.
So, those guys did
their homework.
They picked the
perfect time to hit.
Mm-hmm.
AFIS hits on our suspects,
both just recently released
from five-year
sentences at Lompoc.
California boys.
Born and raised.
Okay. Let's do this.
Officer Clay was killed
by a single close-range
shotgun blast
to the back of the head.
Excessive penetration
and laceration of the brain.
Suspect Clyde Tremmel...
The TEC-9 guy.
Two distant-range,
medium-caliber gunshot wounds
to the front of the chest,
with penetration
of the lung and heart.
Suspect Jack Delver...
GRISSOM:
Shotgun guy.
One distant-range,
medium-caliber gunshot wound
to the forehead.
The bullet
penetrated the brain and was
recovered in the occipital lobe.
Rufus Sanders,
bystander...
Five scattered
buckshot perforations
on the outer thigh.
One severed the femoral artery,
resulting in massive hemorrhage.
And Julia Reed,
cocktail waitress.
Single medium-caliber gunshot
wound to the left chest.
The bullet perforated the lung
and thoracic aorta,
then perforated
the opposite lung.
And that's it.
Thanks, Doc.
Catherine,
something bothering you?
A little.
Look, I came here to pick up
my wife's body.
I already gave you my statement.
Well, we just need
a few more details
before we can release the body.
I promise
this won't be long.
What?
Well, you said
that your wife fell
during the gunfight,
that that's how
you got separated.
Yeah.
Do you recall
exactly how she fell?
Well, what do you mean?
How did she land?
Did she land sideways,
backwards...?
She fell forward, I think.
She fell forward.
So her hands broke the fall,
landed on her knees?
Yeah.
Well, there weren't
any bruises or scrapes
on her knees or elbows,
which is leading me to believe
that she didn't fall.
Well, what's-what's
the difference?
She's dead.
Mr. Reed, there were
a lot of bullets
flying around that store
and a lot of victims,
and every detail is important,
but they don't help
if they're
not accurate.
Well, when we started running...
she was right behind me.
( gunshot and ricochet )
( five gunshots )
She froze up.
Just stood there
looking right at me...
scared out of her mind.
I... yelled at her to get down,
to come over to me.
Sh-She wouldn't move.
I mean I'm...
I'm pretty sure I yelled.
GRISSOM:
Highlight the shots
that killed the
TEC-9 shooter.
Fromansky said
that he fired
three or four shots
at that target.
He fired four.
That accounts
for those shots.
Okay, the guy with the shotgun
was killed with... one bullet.
Well, those four shots
were definitely meant for him.
But this shot
is closer to the second gunman
than it is
to the cocktail waitress.
Well, Fromansky was turning
when he fired
so his shots were spread out.
Okay.
( typing )
Which means Fromansky
fired four shots
at a target
at the back of the store.
Just like he said he did.
Yeah.
MAN:
At the walk-through
you said that you saw
a third suspect
at the back of the store.
Why did you make
the decision to shoot?
I was in fear for my life.
Did you see a weapon?
Yes.
What kind?
A semiautomatic pistol.
So you fired first.
Yes.
Four times.
Can you explain
the lack of evidence
for a third suspect
at the scene?
That's not my job.
Right or wrong,
there'll be guys on the job
who'll think this was personal.
They'd be wrong.
Did you see Julia Reed
in your line of fire?
No.
According to Supervising
Criminalist Grissom's report,
you had an unobstructed view
of Ms. Reed,
so how do you explain the fact
that you didn't see her?
I can't.
You don't deny that a bullet
from your weapon killed her?
I'm not denying that.
But you can't explain it?
No.
Look, your partner was dead.
You'd been shot.
You saw someone
you thought was a suspect
and you fired.
Under those circumstances,
any one of us
could make a mistake.
Did you?
Officer Fromansky,
answer the question.
He says yes, he's a bad cop.
He says no, he's a liar.
Maybe he really doesn't
know what happened.
BROWN:
A little over.
Perfect.
Let's say I'm Fromansky.
There's nothing
between Fromansky
and the cocktail waitress.
I got a clean view
and a clear shot.
GRISSOM:
Hey, take a look at this.
The cracks in the glass
from shot 22
are terminated by the
cracks from shot 23.
( glass shattering )
So, shot 23 had to occur
before shot 22.
Which means
that Fromansky was firing
from left to right,
not right to left.
Four shots on a level spread.
He was shooting
at a moving target.
According to Catherine's
witness,
the cocktail waitress
wasn't moving.
She was a stationary target.
So, if he was shooting
at a moving target,
where was it moving to?
We have the
surveillance tape.
Shows nothing going
on here before, during
or after the robbery.
Well, just because
it shows nothing
doesn't mean
it's seeing everything.
BROWN:
You can see me now, right?
Keep moving to your right.
All right.
Keep going.
I'm still in?
Right there.
NOW you're out.
Tell me what you see.
A getaway.
( metallic scraping )
We found metal paint
scrapings and skid marks.
Both recent on
that loading dock.
These guys definitely
had a wheelman.
Yeah, guy slips in
after everything gets started.
During the confusion,
nobody sees him.
Or no one that was alive
to tell anyway.
Except Fromansky.
Yeah.
Well, the suspects knew
there was a blind spot.
It has to be an inside job.
Oh, no doubt.
Matched the cash
from the garbage bag
to the register receipts--
$878 was missing.
Somebody came out ahead.
Inside guy?
Well,
I'll run the employees.
Maybe somebody's
got a record.
Ran your paint chips
through PPG and DuPont.
Got a hit.
Aegean blue Honda Accord.
Popular color.
They carried it over
for four years.
Go figure.
I'm a teal man myself.
You?
Stupid question.
Anyway, model years
'84 to '87.
I'll put out a broadcast.
Thanks, Hodges.
Sure.
Before this goes any deeper,
I want to hear it from you.
Are you going to try
to screw me on this?
Well?
I guess it depends on whether
I get stuck in traffic
on the way to your hearing.
BRASS:
So, this car was reported stolen
about, uh, oh, about
three weeks ago.
Why don't you take the front.
I'll take the back.
pH 13. Sodium hydroxide.
Got a cell phone.
There's a lot
of scung on it.
Won't be too good for prints,
but let me check
the call history.
Same number keeps popping up.
( recording on phone ):
Best Bargain
is temporarily closed.
Please check back tomorrow.
Well, this is interesting.
Before the
robbery went down,
somebody at the
store was very eager
to talk to our suspects.
Same number.
Yeah?
Maybe he can tell us who.
Todd Hallickey.
Look, I don't know why
you guys brought me here,
but you got no right
tossing my apartment.
We matched your prints
from a stolen car
off the prints
from a prior car theft,
and bingo, we had a match.
Got a warrant
for your apartment.
I don't boost cars no more.
( chuckles ):
Yeah, right.
Oh, wait. No, I...
I was looking into
getting some wheels
a couple of weeks ago.
I test-drove this old
Honda Accord this guy
was trying to unload.
An '86 Aegean blue
with matching velour interior?
Yeah, that was it.
Must be how my print got there.
Didn't buy the car.
Guy seemed kind of shady.
BRASS:
You wouldn't happen
to remember
this shady guy's name,
would you?
HALLICKEY:
Come on.
No one keeps track
of stuff like that.
Right.
You own any firearms,
Mr. Hallickey?
No, sir, I'm on parole.
Besides, I don't
believe in guns.
They're dangerous.
You know, that's a nasty injury
you got there, Todd.
Looks kind of painful.
How'd you get it?
It's a rash.
Looks like a chemical burn
to me.
You know
what sodium hydroxide is?
Never heard of it.
It's the active ingredient
in drain cleaner.
It opens up the pipes,
dissolves flesh
and fabrics.
Look, you want to
pin that car on me,
you go ahead and try.
I got this off the jacket
from your apartment.
What the hell is this?
BROWN:
It's a bullet wipe.
A test for lead.
Congratulations.
You passed.
Hallickey's got no connection
to the grocery store.
He was just the wheel man.
Still, he's looking at four
counts of felony murder.
But he's not talking.
He lawyered up.
We got a bullet hole
in a jacket.
That's not even enough to prove
that he was in the store.
What about the cash?
It wasn't in
his apartment.
Maybe somebody else took it.
Almost $900 in small bills?
We'd have noticed pockets
bulging with a wad like that.
What about
the calls
from the grocery store
to the suspect's cell?
That could have been somebody
giving the "go" signal.
There's no way to tell who.
The store runs
off of an old PBX system,
and every call that comes in
goes back to
the same number.
Every employee
was near a phone,
so, it could have
been anybody.
Hey, y'all.
Ran the criminal records
for the employees.
Came up with
a Raul Valdez.
Freight loader.
He clocked in for
work that night.
Never clocked out.
No one by that name
interviewed at the scene?
Here's the kicker.
A few years ago,
he spent some time in prison.
Lompoc.
So, Brass is trying
to find him now.
I got to change my pants.
You left something
in the store
besides a
urine stain.
Just a little
too tempting, huh?
All that cash
just sitting there
right in front of your face...
( gunshot )
Look, I go to that store
to bag groceries,
not to get my ass shot off.
I figure
I earned the money.
Kind of like working overtime.
Might as well get something
for all your trouble, right?
Considering the fact that
your nice little robbery
had gone straight to hell.
Whoa, wait a minute.
You think...?
No way.
It was an inside job.
You knew the
registers were full.
Those gunmen had help
from an employee.
Not from me, they didn't.
Look, you want to bust me
for the money,
go ahead, I took it.
But I did not set the thing up.
You know, Hodges
already analyzed
trace on
the bullets.
Yeah, I wanted
to take a look myself.
He'll take it personally.
Good.
The report says that the
cocktail waitress was wearing
a black wool sweater.
Was she also
wearing something polyester?
No.
Take a look at this.
WARRICK:
Black fibers.
Probably synthetic.
Mixed in with the wool.
If their gunman was wearing
a black polyester jacket...
Fromansky claims that he was
tunnel-visioned on the gunman.
So, it's possible
that he never even saw
the cocktail waitress.
You may have just
saved Fromansky's ass.
Hey, Catherine, how'd
it go with the bag boy?
He admitted to swiping the cash,
but he wouldn't cop
to the robbery.
Then I have something
you should see.
I was going back through
the surveillance tapes
covering the loading dock,
thinking I might find someone
scouting a blind spot,
you know?
But instead,
I found this.
Two nights before
the robbery.
There.
See that?
One more time.
STOKES:
That camera's stationary, so...
Somebody moved the camera.
You used to part-time
at the Forum shops.
We got your prints
off your work card.
It was the same print
that we got
off the loading dock
surveillance camera.
Raul Valdez,
an ex-con--
your co-worker.
You got him
to give you the names
of some guys to do the job.
You give them the best time
to hit the registers.
You tell them
where to park.
It's a good plan.
Until your ex
showed up
and leaves you
with your kid.
Then you panic,
and you call your guys,
try to call it off,
but they
won't listen.
If that's
what happened,
that could go in your favor.
When we find Raul,
he'll give you up
in a heartbeat.
I think I need to get a lawyer.
What you need
is come clean and cooperate.
And you better hope and pray
the DA doesn't want
to put a needle in your arm
for killing five people,
including a cop.
I have been working
at that store for five years.
38 hours a week.
38... not 40.
You know why?
Because my manager
won't give me
enough hours
to qualify for benefits.
I have a kid...
with rotten teeth.
I never meant
for anybody to get hurt.
( sniffling )
Officer Fromansky,
if you could smile,
please?
Thank you;
right over here.
BRASS:
Guy from
the mayor's office.
Fromansky's getting
a commendation.
What do you think?
Two dead felons,
two dead civilians
a dead policeman...
I don't know
what to think.