( car horn beeping )
MAN:
Come on!
Honey, just pass him.
Move it!
Calm down and just pass him.
WILLOWS:
Hey, Jim!
We got a call.
A possible 4-19.
Is there a dead body or not?
That arm crash-landed
on the windshield of the car.
According to the driver,
it shot out from under the bus.
Generally speaking,
where there's an arm,
there's a body.
What say we check out the bus?
Good call.
Now, the, uh, passengers
were on their way to
St. Matthew's Church in Pioche.
They were from
a work release program
at Nevada Correctional
Institution.
Okay, well, I got some blood
on the wheel well.
Oh, yeah, that's a
definite on the 4-19.
Um, well... appears
to be female.
Caucasian.
Tied to the
undercarriage...
maybe.
Hitch a ride under a bus.
Well, that's one way
to get out jail.
Yeah, and I bet this big boy
spit out body parts
all the way down the road.
So... the bus is traveling
65 miles per hour.
What's the distance
from the tip of her nose
to the tip of her toes?
and Volkswagen.
On the road of life
there are passengers
and there are drivers.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
Well, looks like
she used strips
from a white
cotton sheet.
Yeah, use whatever's
available
when you're breaking
out of prison, I guess.
Low thread count.
Average tensile strength
wasn't strong enough
to support her weight.
( gasps )
( screams )
The torque
of the spinning axle
ripped her apart
like the rubber
off a bad retread.
Yep. If she'd used a nylon rope,
she'd be on her way
to Tijuana.
Right.
I'll call Auto Detail, have the
bus sent to the garage, yeah?
Oh, hey, after that,
grab Sarah and go
directly to jail.
I'm going to supervise
this body part collection.
♪ ♪
Okay, David, I think that's it.
I'll get these parts
to Dr. Robbins.
He'll start putting her
back together.
( siren wails in distance )
Helter-skelter.
Yeah...
except there's
no blood spatter
on the walls
or the ceiling.
BROWN:
We have the murder weapon.
Stabbed in the chest.
( grunts )
There's two of them
in that apartment.
The name's Adanto Adams.
He don't live
in that apartment.
He's visiting
from out of town.
That's Zero's
little brother.
Zero?
Zero Adams. He's the one
who lives there.
Well, unless he was
bending over the sofa
with his chest pushed
against this cushion,
this bloodstain
is inconsistent with that wound.
Paul, would you
turn him over
for us?
Oh, yeah.
Stabbed in the chest
and the back.
So, uh, where is
this Zero now?
I don't know.
I'm not his mother.
I'm his landlord.
Well, if you see him,
give me a call.
Yeah, yeah, sure.
When I do a jigsaw puzzle,
I like to start
with a corner piece.
When the puzzle's a body,
the corner piece
is the pelvis.
Oh, uh, Nick
ID'd your vic.
She missed her
last bed check.
Convict #6920.
Antoinette Stella.
Two-year sentence
for identity theft.
She was due for release
next month.
Guess she was in a hurry.
No, she wasn't
trying to escape.
She was murdered.
I dissected her arm.
The blood in the brachial
artery is clotted,
which is indicative
of a post-mortem
laceration.
Have you determined
the cause of death?
Yep.
Cranio-cerebral
injury...
...due to blunt-
force trauma.
Depressed skull fracture
imbedded with tiny
white fibers.
Given the depth
and position
of the, uh, fracture,
I'd say she was hit on
the head with something
hard on the inside
and white and fuzzy
on the outside.
I'd like a clean look
at that fracture.
Sure. I'll start her bath.
Anything else?
Well, you might
want to check out
her left forearm.
Birthmark?
Rap sheet's
referenced
"dermatological anomalies."
According to her,
she didn't have any.
I'll take a slice
down to Histology.
WARDEN:
We locked down
as soon as we got the call.
We do bed checks
six times a day.
All inmates were accounted for
at 1300 hours.
STOKES:
What time did the bus leave
for church?
WOMAN:
1330.
Hey, sexy, how 'bout
you come back here
on your day off?
No gag reflex.
Watch it, Harris.
Got a drawer
full of C-9s
with your
name on 'em.
What are you lookin' at?
What can you tell us
about the vic?
WARDEN:
Antoinette? She
was popular with
the other inmates.
No enemies to speak of.
This was
Antoinette's cell.
Christine, you're
going to step out.
Officer.
When's the last time
you saw Baby Girl?
I'll need to check
my calendar.
Don't get stupid
on me, Christine.
Baby Girl--
was that a street name?
Yes. That's what
everyone called her.
Christine?
I saw Baby Girl at lunch
'bout an hour before
we got on the bus.
Hey, that's my locker.
I didn't take none
of Baby's stuff.
Didn't say you did.
Look...
I didn't hardly know Baby Girl.
She only lived up
in here eight days.
Eight days?
In this cell.
Few weeks ago, I found her
smuggling contraband.
It was just a silver necklace.
Inmates aren't allowed jewelry.
It wasn't a major infraction,
but I transferred her cell.
SIDLE:
Makeup, deodorant, shampoo.
Inmates are allowed
commissary visits
once a month,
unless they rack up
two weeks in nights.
SIDLE:
Do you keep track
of purchases?
I can get you a list.
And just for the record,
in the state of Nevada,
there's never been a homicide
in a female
correctional
facility.
Until now.
What are you doing?
I'm ruling you out
as a suspect, ma'am.
( sighs )
No evidence of blood.
I could've told you that.
Warden,
could you show us
where the bus was parked
before it left the facility?
The bus was stationed
right here.
Are you the only driver?
Only bus driver.
Got my CDLC last May.
MAN
( over P.A. system):
Attention, inmates...
Officer, before you drove
out of here,
did you inspect the vehicle?
Miss... Sidle,
I don't get time
to scratch my ass.
I haven't had a
junior officer
in my department
in two years.
Now, usually, I work the road,
and when the warden asks,
I take inmates
on field trips.
Did you know
the dead woman,
Baby Girl,
Antoinette Stella?
Start seeing 'em as real people,
start carin'
when they go back to their pimp
dealer scumbag boyfriend?
That's enlightened.
That's reality.
No sign of a struggle,
no evidence of a body drag.
If the attack didn't happen
in her cell or in here,
maybe it happened
on the bus.
SIDLE:
Who maintains
your transpo fleet?
Fleet?
We got three antique buses.
Inmates do
all the work.
You allow inmates to service
your prison vehicles?
You bet.
On Saturday, I even bring in
my SUV.
Juanita washes it.
Ain't that right,
Juana?
I've got to get something
on top of my $11.65 an hour.
Look, we're in the middle
of the desert.
We're a hundred miles
from the pit of nowhere.
Is that gate always unlocked?
It's not like someone's going
to hot-wire the bus
and hightail it
out of here.
Right, so essentially anyone
in the prison population
could have walked
into the garage,
onto the bus
and no one would
have said boo?
Boo.
♪ ♪
MAN:
I got a call at work
and was told to get over here
right away
and he's not here.
Detective,
I got your page.
Hey, we were canvassing
the area
when Mr. Samuels showed up.
He says he's the tenant's
guardian.
He's got questions.
So do I.
Mr. Samuels,
I'm Warrick Brown.
I'm from the Crime Lab.
What happened to Zero?
There's crime tape
on his door.
These guys won't let me in.
His brother was murdered.
Adanto.
Did you know him?
Yeah, I've known them both
since they were kids.
Frank...
Zero.
I'm so sorry.
I'm sorry.
Absorption.
Blood?
Yeah, and it's more
than just a paper cut.
I'll swab it for DNA.
Florescence.
Bluish-white.
Acid phosphatase tests positive.
What is semen doing
in the back
of a female prison bus?
FRANK:
It's okay, Zero.
Just answer the questions.
I said I was sorry
'cause I'm not supposed
to be out by myself.
So, why did you go out?
Well, I came home
from special school,
I found Adanto in the kitchen.
I love you,
I love you Adanto.
When was the last time
you talked to your brother?
Just before school.
What I'm about
to tell you,
you can't tell anybody.
No. No, I won't.
Scout's honor.
We're going to be rich
like we always talked about.
I love you, kid.
I love you, too.
Said he was going to
buy me a shiny new car
and a driver to take me
anywhere I wanted to go.
He said we were
going to be rich.
MAN ( over P.A. ):
Inmates, you have ten minutes
till bed check.
WOMAN:
Juanita's in charge
of bus detail.
I'm sure she'll be happy
to answer your questions.
Juanita?
Do you recall the last time
that you washed out
the interior of the bus?
Yesterday, a few hours
before we left for work release.
If something's missing,
it wasn't me.
You can check my locker.
Did you notice
anything unusual
in the back of the bus?
Like what?
Blood or... semen?
Didn't see any blood.
What about semen?
Don't they still do it
in the backseat
in the free world?
Yeah.
But I doubt
if conjugal visits are permitted
in a prison bus.
Conjugal visits
aren't permitted anywhere.
The ACLU was going
to bring a case that's...
The only men permitted in
this correctional facility
are the correctional officers.
It's a Class "D" felony
for a CO to have sexual contact
with an inmate.
Lots of things
are felonies,
but people still do them.
Otherwise, you and
I'd be out of a job.
HODGES:
The white fibers
from the head wound
were straight out
of any Wal-Market.
78% cotton, 14% polyester
and seven percent
nylon elastic.
Sounds like we're looking for
a lethal pair
of white underpants.
Yeah, or a bra,
pair of socks.
The skin discoloration,
that was a real challenge.
You know, uh,
on her forearm.
Looked like a birthmark.
Yeah, that skin sample
was supposed to be
sent to Histology.
Yeah, well,
they kicked it back to me.
Uh, the coloration
was an adulterant.
Aluminum chelate
of carminic acid.
Aluminum ch...?
I've never heard of this before.
It's a cochineal.
A what?
A cochineal.
They're scaled insects.
Carminic acid
is found in their intestines.
It's bitter,
so it discourages predators.
As a dye,
it's been prized for centuries.
Since when did you become
an insects expert?
Entomology textbook.
Grissom gave it to me
last Christmas.
When I can't sleep, I read.
Funny, I didn't get a
Christmas gift from Grissom.
Did you?
No.
Uh, so, assuming that she
was tattooed in prison,
how'd she get a hold
of the bugs?
Well, um, cochineals feed
on cactus plants.
They probably grow wild
in the prison yard.
SIDLE:
Baby Girl could've
smashed up a few bugs,
used the carminic acid
to tattoo herself.
Do you have a photo
of the tattoo?
Yeah.
STOKES:
Looks like a half moon.
Gang moniker, maybe.
Every woman knows what that is.
It's a heart.
Well, half a heart.
Oh.
Yeah.
Where's the other half?
BROWN:
Mr. Samuels,
we found your
prints on the knife
used to kill Adanto Adams.
Now, wait a minute.
I didn't stab Adanto.
Oh, my God.
Zero?!
( grunts )
But you didn't call 911.
Or the police.
You just took off?
That's a felony.
Look, I was concerned
about Zero.
He's a nine-year-old kid
in a man's body.
I didn't know
if he did it.
Zero's like a son to me.
I've been his guardian
since he was 14.
Everybody used
to make fun of him.
Called him "Zero."
I told him only special people
get nicknames.
Where's his parents now?
They passed away.
He left a small inheritance
for his boys...
Zero doesn't spend much.
Okay, I'll ask again.
You found the body
and then you went to work?
I just needed
some time to think.
Well, you'll get
plenty of that now.
24 hours in a holding cell.
Come on. Let's go.
ROBBINS:
It's very peculiar.
Take a look
at his chest wound.
No right or left angulation.
No up or down.
Straight in, straight out.
GRISSOM:
Well, the crime scene suggests
he was moving around his
apartment while being stabbed
so, "straight in, straight out"
doesn't seem likely.
Well, one time
is an anomaly.
Five times?
All four back wounds
are clustered and parallel.
And the chest wound
is at the same distance
from the crown of his head
as the other four.
What about defensive wounds?
There are none.
Okay, so, he's running around
his apartment
trying to get away
from his attacker
and he incurs no nicks or cuts?
Nope.
What else?
Well, I found this
in his stomach.
Looks like a paper wad
of some sort.
Maybe a treasure map.
MAN:
Good thing this guy's not
concerned with his cholesterol.
He ate fatty foods.
Paper's pretty well preserved.
Uh, most of the ink
is washed off.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
There's something there
in the corner.
( camera servo clicking )
Help me put it in there,
Warrick.
Uh... "P-A... L..."
Oh, The Palms.
I know what this is.
It's a receipt for a marker.
For ten grand.
MAN:
Oh, yeah, that's him.
Adanto Adams.
Said he wanted to play BJ
in the no-limit area.
So I had the cage check
his credit.
Qualified for ten grand.
Thank you.
And I wrote him up.
Did he have some kind
of a system?
They all got systems.
This one was
a small-time
double-up
type thing.
Bet 100, lose;
bet 200, lose.
Bet four, lose.
Double-up-till-
you-win type thing.
Now, don't you get anything
other than a 20?
Hmm?
( bangs table )
The one thing
about systems in this town--
if you got one,
we want you here.
Can I get a copy
of that footage?
Listen, you look familiar.
I seen you before?
You been in here?
Maybe just on a case.
How about that footage?
Hey, got your page.
What's up?
Oh, the warden
faxed over
Baby Girl's
commissary purchases.
She bought one 20-count
box of tampons
every month
like clockwork,
but check out
the last few months.
What are you thinking?
She might not have needed
any for, oh, nine months?
I think Baby Girl
was having a baby.
Skull's not ready yet.
Enzymes are still eating away
at the proteins.
Did you, by any chance,
do a pregnancy test
on Baby Girl?
I thought
she'd been incarcerated
for the last 23 months.
She had been.
Urine...
you're out.
Okay...
Home pregnancy test?
About ten times cheaper
than the brand sold
by our medical supply company,
and just as accurate.
Eye on the
bottom line.
I find that very...
Sexy?
Prudent.
But that was a good try.
Yeah, plus sign.
You know what that means.
Who's your daddy?
Archie?
Hey.
Got your surveillance tape
of Zero's brother.
Roll it.
Now, according
to the pit boss,
the kid was playing
a double-up system.
What I want to know is,
how many hands did
he back himself up?
Let's find out.
First hand,
hundred.
Loser.
Second hand,
200.
Lose.
Third hand,
400. Lose.
$800.
So he's doubling
every bet.
Yeah, that's the classic
double-up system.
Go back out wide.
Looks like
he's all in.
Tenth bet, $51,200.
Adanto has 20.
He sticks.
She has two up.
Another two, and
that's four.
Two, three, two.
That's 11.
Ace, ace, ace, ace.
Fifteen.
Six.
Ten-card
21.
What are the odds of that?
The record's an 11-card 21.
That was back in '78.
So he loses
$102,300 in ten hands.
What's the $10,000 marker for?
Try to chase back the 102.
He lost it all.
He swallowed his loss.
WOMAN ( over intercom ):
All correctional officers
report to reception.
All COs to reception.
Miss Willows.
My COs are Level 3
peace officers.
I will not
subject them
to a DNA lineup
that is nothing more
than a wild goose chase.
We have probable cause
to believe
that a correctional officer
was involved
with Baby Girl.
Involved
in getting her pregnant, maybe,
but that's a far cry
from homicide.
Nevertheless,
as you pointed out,
sex with an inmate is a crime.
Which is the basis
for my warrant.
Okay, everybody,
can I have your
attention, please?
Hey, I did some digging.
Withdrawal slip
from Zero Adams'
custodial account
the day of the murder.
How much?
$102,000 even.
Who are the signatories?
Zero Adams and Frank Samuels.
MAN:
Uh, this is not my signature.
This is Zero's
account.
I'm the custodian,
but, um,
I didn't sign this.
Adanto.
That son of a...
What?
You knew about this?
Indirectly.
We had it out.
Tell you something,
you degenerate.
All I've heard from you
is how much money
you blow day-trading,
and now you want
to touch your brother's
life savings?
You can forget
about it.
Don't you see?
If I play perfect blackjack,
there is no way
we can lose...
There is no
perfect blackjack.
I'm going to need, uh,
a sample of...
of your handwriting.
Also need a sample from Zero.
Just copy this?
Yes.
MAN:
London Letters
is one of my favorite
standard writing tests.
Uh, the paragraph has every
capital letter in the alphabet,
as well as numbers
one through nine.
Just tell me
who's lying.
Uh, okay.
Uh, Zero's not.
Uh, his signature is authentic.
Proof is in the "Z."
Okay, uh, look at the "F"
in "Frank Samuels"
from the withdrawal slip,
and then look at the "F"
from the London Letters.
Different.
As well as
the "S" in "Samuels,"
and the "S" in
"Switzerland."
Again, way off.
I hate to tell you, Warrick,
but I think
your guardian
might be telling you the truth.
And from what I can see,
Zero didn't forge it.
Well, then who did?
Adanto?
Without a sample,
I can't tell you.
Start talking.
The blood Nick
and Sara found
in the back
of the bus--
consistent with
the victim.
Not a surprise.
Semen found
in the back
of the bus matches
your bus driver's DNA.
Also, not a surprise.
Try this one.
Bus driver's DNA has
13 alleles in common
with the victim's
unborn fetus.
I don't believe you.
She was pregnant.
12 weeks.
And you're the father.
Your attorney
has reviewed
your case file.
It's in there.
STOKES:
When he said
he expected something
on top of his
$11.65 an hour,
I thought he was talking
about free car washes.
There's no evidence
of anti- or paramortem rape.
He'll claim
it was consensual.
It's still rape.
Under color
of authority.
She swore
she couldn't have kids.
Too many turns
at the coat hanger.
Her words.
Yeah.
I imagine
that you were pissed off
when she broke
the news.
It kind of changes
the power dynamics.
STOKES:
And she blabs
to the warden.
He's demoted from
officer to inmate.
That is motive.
I swear, I had no idea.
Doug, let me handle this.
If the DA had
sufficient evidence
to file murder charges,
he would have.
Well, your client's already
been charged with a felony.
DA has all the
time in the world.
Look, I can't fight
the evidence.
Doug, Doug, would you be quiet?
Look, I got her pregnant.
I admit it.
I'll do the time, okay?
But you can't prove
that I killed her
because I didn't.
How's the knife
handle coming?
Handled.
The substance
Grissom scraped off
was interior latex house paint
with titanium dioxide.
That would be
glossy, right?
Mm-hmm.
What's house paint doing
on a knife handle?
1984, William Bergstrom asked
old man Binion if he could come
into his casino and bet
a million dollars
on one roll of craps.
That November,
he put a briefcase full
of $1 million
on the "don't pass" line,
rolled a seven
on the come-up.
Loser.
Soon after that,
he killed himself.
So, what are you getting at?
If the wounds couldn't
have been made
by a handheld knife,
maybe the knife
wasn't handheld.
How else are you going
to stab a guy?
Well, put the evidence aside
for a second.
What was Adanto's state of mind?
You've had
a few bad runs.
Guy comes into town,
convinces his brother to invest
in some two-bit
double-up system,
ends up losing
his life savings
in a ten-card 21.
In a word: desperate.
So put that into context
with your evidence.
Greg.
Do you think
skin cells can survive
50 miles
of rough desert road?
That's what I asked you.
I analyzed every strip
of fabric from
the bus' chassis.
Zilch.
But I'm a guy who likes
to tie up loose ends,
so I asked Doc Robbins
to send over the scraps
that were tied
to the body parts.
That's where
I found them.
Fresh,
abraded epithelials.
So, if the epithelial DNA
matches
the bus driver,
this case
is closed.
One problem.
Double "X"
marks the spot.
It's female DNA?
Well, I guess
we're looking at an inmate.
Or female staff.
Excuse me. Am
I interrupting?
Oh, not if
the vic's skull
is in that bag.
Alas, poor Yorick.
I knew him, Horatio.
The occipital bone
retained the shape
of the murder weapon.
Desperation.
( gasping softly )
No way we can lose.
( voices overlapping )
This is Vegas.
Anything can happen.
( grunting )
( shouting )
I found a way
to make us some money.
We're going to be rich
like we always talked about.
I love you, kid.
I love you, too.
( grunts )
He killed himself?
I'm afraid so.
No. Why would he do that?
Your brother took out
an insurance policy
with an accidental death clause.
It means that
if he was murdered,
the beneficiary would be
entitled to a million dollars.
You're the beneficiary.
Unfortunately, the coroner
is going to rule
the case a suicide...
and not a homicide,
which makes that policy
worthless.
I-I was just trying to help
my brother.
Oh... I want Frank.
Listen to me.
Frank will be facing charges
of obstructing justice.
Do you understand?
The court will appoint you
another guardian.
No, I don't want
I want Frank!
( whimpers )
I'm sorry.
STOKES:
This program is scanning
the topography of the skull
and building a three-dimensional
image based on the data.
It should be done in a second,
but you can already see
two concentric arcs.
Inner arc is impressed
just a little bit deeper
into the skull.
Check it out.
Like a crater in a crater.
Yeah.
Can you enlarge to full screen?
There.
Small... evenly spaced
indentations
on the edge of the inner arc.
I know what that is.
Skinny-ass
feather worth
as much trouble dead
as she was alive?
I didn't ask her
to move in here.
No one asked you.
So, Warden,
Baby Girl was
transferred
to this cell
about a week ago?
That's right.
Where was she
last housed?
"D" block.
White fibers.
Warden,
how often do the inmates
have their laundry washed?
Twice a week:
one day for colors,
one day for whites.
Tomorrow's a white day.
You don't mind if I empty out
your laundry bag, do you?
Juanita, would you remove
your shoes, please?
WARDEN:
Now.
The other.
A lock in a sock.
Juanita, I read
your rap sheet.
Possession
with intent to sell.
Your old man was
using you as a
drug meal, right?
He was supposed to protect me.
He said if I got caught,
he'd take
the fall.
After the raid,
he disappeared.
Vanished.
I get locked up.
I should've known better.
( sighs ):
Well...
my ex drained
my bank account.
I was saving up for
this nice little house
for my daughter and me, and...
As soon as you let 'em in, huh?
Gets lonely in
prison, doesn't it?
Was it the first time
you had a relationship
with a woman?
Tattoo.
Baby Girl had
the other half.
I'm not... like that.
It wouldn't be the
first time to cross
gender lines
in search of some...
affection.
It was the first time
I felt that way about anyone.
And Baby Girl
ended up pregnant.
It's not like she could hide
that from you.
She said
she had the flu.
Yeah, right.
( gagging )
That's what you get
for lying to me,
for sneaking around.
I was just playing him, Juana.
I was doing it for us.
You're a liar!
Want to know
the truth, Juanita?
In one month,
I am out of this hole...
and away from you.
And then, later that night,
she said she was sorry,
and we made up.
The next day,
she got the warden
to transfer her...
out of our cell.
She wasn't playing Doug.
She was playing me.
So you killed her?
She promised to end it
with Doug.
( moaning )
( screams )
You tied her body to the
undercarriage of the bus
and assumed we'd
think that she died
while attempting to escape...
right?
If there's one thing I learned
in prison...
it's to stick up for myself...
because nobody else will.
I think that you should know
that Baby Girl was telling
the truth
about the transfer.
It wasn't her request.
It was Warden Hutton's
decision.
She was caught
trying to smuggle
in this necklace
and was reprimanded.
I'm guessing it was
for you.