Help!
I need help!
Ma'am, you all right?
There's a baby
inside the car!
Where are your keys?
It's not my car.
Help!
Somebody help us!
Get back!
Help!
( inaudible
radio transmissions )
Registration's not here.
Shopping plaza.
Mother can't
be too far.
When are parents
going to learn
a car is not a baby-sitter?
108 degrees outside.
You want to document
the inside temperature?
How many of these
have we had this year?
I lost count after ten.
This one makes 12.
MAN:
Hey, that's my car.
Look, what the hell is going on?
What are they doing?
Did somebody break in
to my car?
I'm Detective Brass,
Las Vegas Police.
Sir, do you have a son?
Oh, God! Joshua!
145 degrees inside the car.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
DEEJAY:There's a heat advisory
in effect.
Young ones and old ones,
say INSIDE.
Make sure you wear a hat,
and drink plenty of liquids...
If it's not babies
in cars, it's babies
in swimming pools.
That time of year.
MAN:
Body's fully rigid--
normally I'd say
infant's been dead
a couple of hours,
but in this weather,
it's possible
the infant died
no more than an hour ago.
I'm off for air, Catherine.
I brought a sheet.
All these lookie-loos,
I think we'd better
treat this
like the baby's still alive.
( softly ):
Thanks.
( engine starts )
MAN:
I spotted her from my boat
during a routine patrol.
Boot prints
and drag marks.
Did you move her?
Had to.
Didn't want her
floating away.
STOKES:
Board shorts, aqua sock shoes.
Dressed for sport.
No sign of bloating.
Chances are she's been dead
less than 24 hours.
Neck looks broken,
her head's split,
but there's
no cone of foam.
No what?
Uh, we have air
in our lungs--
add water, you get foam.
It means she didn't drown.
Well, apparently,
it's not the only way
to die out here.
( over speaker ):
I was supposed
to drop Joshua off at daycare.
My wife usually brings him
on her way to work.
It was a hectic morning.
My cell phone was going off.
Problems at the office.
Look, I don't care
how much pressure
we get from the financier.
Look... Oh,
can you hold on a second?
I have anoth...
I'm sorry,
I can't do this right now.
I'm driving.
Look, hold all the calls,
call my wife,
tell her I'll be...
I'll be home late.
I forgot he was
in the back seat.
How could you forget?
I'm not the one
who drives him.
Vickie does that.
I was distracted.
My-my job consumes
so much of my mind...
So, what kind of job you have
that's so distracting?
I'm an agent for the
gaming commission.
It's a 25-hour-a-day job,
eight days a week.
Your wife work?
She works as much as me.
Joshua made it all worthwhile.
BRASS:
Where's your wife now?
She's in L.A.
on business.
What am I going to tell her?
We need something.
No birthmark,
no scars, no tattoos.
It's a locker key.
You put in
for the promotion, huh?
Yeah. Yeah, last week.
I still haven't heard
anything about it.
Yeah, neither have I.
MAN:
Hey,
you ready
for me?
She's all yours.
Heard you had a rough morning.
I've had better.
Sara, take a look at this.
What is that?
I don't know.
You were right about
your dead swimmer.
She didn't drown.
Cause of death was
a palpable fracture
of the neck
at C1/C2.
SIDLE:
From the blow
to the head.
Probably.
Cerebral contusion's
beneath the skull fracture.
Savage hit.
Greg processed
the sexual assault kit.
Positive for semen.
There were no physical findings
for rape.
Not a lot to go on here.
Gastric lumen contained
dark, pasty material--
maybe slightly digested meat,
stringy vegetable matter.
Does it give us a timeline?
Emptying rates vary
from person to person,
but I'd estimate she ate
two to four hours before death.
All right, good.
Ranger Stone came through--
found our locker.
Ms. Willows, uh,
Chief Deputy D.A.
Jeffrey Sinclair.
Mm-hmm.
Personal visit--
must be important.
It is.
Joshua Winston,
the dead infant?
We're working on it.
How long was the baby
left inside the car?
Based on the time of death,
we estimate roughly an hour.
The 9-1-1 call came in
at 11:30 in the morning.
Okay, and what time does
Paul Winston start work?
According to Captain Brass,
uh, 10:00 a.m.
( scoffs ):
Hour and a half.
Come on, look,
I've got
a three-year-old at home,
and I've left him inside
a covered garage
with groceries for
two minutes, tops,
but two hours, in this heat?
I know. It's a tragedy.
You know,
cases like these
almost never see the
inside of a courtroom.
This one will.
Is there any worse punishment
than losing your child?
Yeah. Jail time.
I want him behind bars,
so the next time
a parent steps away
from their vehicle
in triple-degree heat,
they check the back seat
before they lock the door.
Doesn't change my job.
Look... I-I need you
guys to thoroughly
document this case.
I don't want any more
surprises in court,
so from the car to the kid,
just try to cross your T's
and dot your I's, okay?
I always do.
WILLOWS:
Car seat's fastened correctly.
Most aren't.
Hey, Gil.
Look at this.
What do you see?
Um...
Nothing.
Exactly.
There's no indentations
in the leather.
Well, maybe this wasn't
the primary vehicle
for transporting the baby.
Yeah.
Same thing
the father said.
What is that?
Oh.
Negative for blood.
( sighs )
What are you thinking?
I don't get people.
...reporting a record number
of heat-stroke victims.
Please be advised to drink
plenty of fluids...
( camera shutter clicking )
You with me?
I am now.
Catherine's doing the baby case.
It's hot in here.
Hell, yeah.
Super came in
to the check the A.C.
and he found him like this.
Wesley Jones. 33.
In his massage chair.
No signs of forced entry.
It doesn't appear
that robbery was a motive.
A small bruise
on his fingertip,
but no outward signs of trauma.
I had a case once
where a soda can
was the murder weapon.
Suspect used it
to bash in the victim's head.
Diet shake,
fitness magazine,
cookie crumbs
on the baking sheet.
This guy trying to start a diet
or falling off of one.
He's got a workout schedule.
And today...
a three-mile run.
Whew.
Fat metabolizers,
containing ephedra.
Scorching heat and ephedra--
that's not good.
( grunts )
( panting )
Sounds like a heat stroke to me.
Yeah. Feel the burn.
Hey, Greg.
Hey.
How we doing
on that swab?
It should be ready any minute.
Another baby.
Hear the D.A.'s
really gunning
for the father.
What do you think they're going
to charge him with? Murder?
Not likely.
Child endangerment,
child... neglect,
child abuse.
Sounds like a slap
on the wrist to me.
You and the D.A. can
shake hands.
( printer humming )
Your printout's ready.
The red stain in the car...
Brompheniramine maleates.
USP-one.
Cough syrup.
( coins rattle )
Dollar slots?
Is there truly no place left
in Las Vegas
without slot machines?
University student I.D.
Sophia Renatta.
20 years old.
SIDLE:
A guy's wallet?
No credit card.
No driver's license.
Well, this is too big
for Sophia.
It's a double extra large.
Well, that's
definitely a guy's.
Cold be a boyfriend
or beach buddy.
Suspect?
Yeah. I remember her...
and her punk
in shinning armor.
He wasn't a cool guy?
The dude stiffed me,
twice, bro.
Rents my Waverunner,
doesn't bring it back.
And his cheap-ass plastic's
got a 2-K limit.
I'm out five grand.
SIDLE:
Ouch.
Did they look like
a couple to you?
She was a pretty girl
with a problem.
He knew an "in"
when he saw one.
You got a credit card?
No, this is all I have.
No, why don't you ask dad.
We got a line here.
Why don't you step aside.
Maybe, maybe
I can help.
So you think
they just met?
It's a hot day...
something must've been
in the air.
We'll need to look at your
rental log if you don't mind.
Go crazy.
Thanks.
Here it is.
Mark Young.
Checked out the
Waverunner 11:45.
But he and Sophia
didn't hit the water
until 2:15.
Well, if he did just meet her,
he's a pretty smooth operator.
Bailed her out,
bought her lunch,
and still had some coins left
over to play the slots.
Classic lake date.
Boy meets girl...
girl ends up dead.
Mrs. Winston?
I asked my husband
to do one thing.
One thing.
I got up early.
I fed Joshua.
I got him changed, dressed.
All he had to do
was drop him off.
WILLOWS:
You flew to Los Angeles,
Mrs. Winston?
( sighs )
I had, uh, business in Anaheim.
I'm in horticulture.
My company is
designing a garden
for a new hotel.
How'd you get to the airport?
I drove my car.
I'm assuming you have
a baby seat in your vehicle.
Of course.
It's the law.
I...
I put it in Paul's car
before I left.
Mrs. Winston, did...
Joshua have a cold?
He had a slight cough.
There was a bug going
around daycare.
Did you give him
anything for it?
Cough syrup.
Last night.
How about this morning?
There's a rule in our house
that only one parent
medicates the child.
But I told Paul
to go ahead
and give it to Joshua
if he was still coughing.
Why?
Thanks for coming in.
We're all done.
Thank you.
Vicky...
What is wrong
with you?!
How could you leave
him in the car?!
What is wrong with you?!
( sobbing )
Mr. Young, your son
was last seen
with a young girl.
We know that he rented
a Waverunner.
Now that young girl is
in our morgue
and we don't know
where your son is.
I can't believe this is
happening.
Mark has a job.
There's no reason for him
to be on the lake
during a work day.
We contacted Mark's
manager at work.
He called in sick.
What are you saying?
That he killed this girl?
What is this?!
No, no. No one's
saying that.
We're just...
Mr. Young, when is
the last time
that you saw Mark?
Yesterday morning.
He came by, got something
to eat and he left.
I mean, at this age,
I can't keep track of him.
Hey, believe me,
I understand.
I've been there.
Mr. Stokes,
my son is not a criminal.
We're not saying
he's a criminal.
All we're saying is
your son had contact
with the victim
and now he's missing.
What we'd like to do
is get a warrant
to search your house.
A warrant?
But maybe we don't need one.
If we could just come
by there
and collect
some of Mark's things,
uh, we could get
a DNA sample,
exclude him as a suspect.
You can take
whatever you want.
Mark didn't hurt that girl.
Go ahead, pinch him.
There's no tenting.
So he wasn't dehydrated.
No, heat stroke.
Vitreous urea nitrogen
and creatinine were normal.
Same for sodium.
What about drugs?
Tox was negative.
Heart attack?
Organ was normal,
under 400 grams.
Left ventricle less
than 1.5 centimeters.
I've run out of questions.
Well, I would've missed
this one
if it weren't for you.
Oh, you sectioned off
that fingertip bruise.
Look at the scope.
The skin cells look
stressed out.
It's called
nuclear streaming.
It occurs
when an electric current
passes through tissue.
He was electrocuted.
But how come there's
no burn marks?
Low-power shock.
Uh, current crossed the heart.
No damage to the muscle,
but havoc on the rhythm.
Ventricular fibrillation.
A precision clock becomes
a bag of worms.
All it takes is
a little current.
And a point of contact.
The substance on her hips
is suntan lotion.
Waterproof, zinc oxide,
high SPF.
Well, that's odd.
The victim had a deep,
even tan.
We collected low SPF oil
from the locker.
It's a simple transfer--
him to her.
What about the green substance
in the head wound?
Mm.
Navicula, Hannaea,
Achnanthes, Cymbella.
Algae.
Yeah, not the
free-swimming kind.
These are epilithic diatoms.
Attached to rocks.
Girl's out at the lake.
She meets some random guy
she knows nothing about
and she goes off with him.
She places herself
in a bad situation.
WILLOWS:
And bad things happen.
( screams )
Sophia takes a header
off the Waverunner.
This algae grows
everywhere.
A Waverunner...
point and throttle.
( sighs )
We have no idea
where they went.
Heard you guys narrowed
your search area
to 44 square miles.
That could take like months.
And I'm sure you're here
to shed some light
on the situation.
Your case is
a boy-girl thing, right?
Right.
Mm-hmm.
Body was washed up
near Windmill Cove?
These two coves to the north--
Cotton Wood Island, Tequila--
huge make-out spots.
But nearly impossible
to get to by land.
And how would you know that,
Greg?
A gentleman never tells.
Anyway, I thought
that would be
a good place to start.
If you guys need
an extra set of hands...
Uh, no. No.
I think we got it, boss.
"Howard Aston Winston."
Reporting the record number of...
still advises all citizens
to stay hydrated and...
I got
the state medical records
for Howard Ashton Winston--
born August 12, 2000.
Would've been
three years old.
When did he die?
Last year--
Tay-Sachs Disease.
Oh, that's incurable.
Like MS, right?
Yeah, I worked with a cop
in New Jersey
whose son died from it.
Aw, the poor kid went blind,
couldn't swallow.
In the end, he couldn't even
lift his head up.
The Winstons never mentioned
they had another child.
Losing one kid is tough,
but two?
I know it.
These wires are all insulated.
No burn marks.
Current didn't pass
through this chair.
Whoa-ho!
What you got?
Ultimate power.
I could program this bad boy
to make me a cup of coffee.
Is there any sign
of electrical surging?
Well... this remote control's
got plenty of juice, but...
the board's clean,
no scoring.
You know, if I had my choice
about how I was going to go out,
it would not be
electrocution.
I think an aneurysm
in my sleep--
quick and painless.
I like surprises.
Bingo.
Look at that.
Current went through the phone.
From what?
Heat lightning.
Storm rolls through the desert,
sometimes it strikes in town.
( electrical current zapping)
( zapping continuing )
( groans )
Electrocution
through the phone line?
I thought that was
a myth.
This look like a myth to you?
STOKES:
Nice call, Greg.
There's our Waverunner.
Signs of sex; no sign of blood.
Half a tank of gas.
Why didn't he just take this
to get out of Dodge?
Well, if he leaves
the dock with Sophia,
comes back alone...
somebody might notice.
So...
he just hoofs it out of here?
How?
There's an access route
about two miles east,
but in this heat,
no way.
Well, if you kill somebody...
you find a way.
Check it out.
WARRICK:
Strike map from the National
Lightning Detection Network.
( computer beeping )
This is Vegas in yellow.
Hasn't had a lightning strike
in three days.
You got another theory?
All I got is a fried phone.
One point on the
electrical path
to ground.
If the phone wasn't the way in,
maybe it was the way out.
( grunting ):
You good on your end?
Yeah, fine.
All right. That's good.
Good. This about it?
Yeah.
Okay... now, electricity
is fickle, right?
Yeah.
One centimeter can
mean the difference
between a little
zap and dead.
So, let's assume that
the current went out
through his right index
finger and the phone.
For it to cross his heart,
it must've come
from the left side
of his body, right?
We've ruled out the fan
and the chair.
Can was in his left hand,
so...
the point of entry must've been
somewhere else on his body.
WARRICK:
His bare foot touched the floor.
Path of least resistance.
SIDLE:
That's got to be a 50-foot drop.
Yeah, but when
you're young,
it just looks like
a whole lot of fun.
Not for Sophia.
Come on, go for it.
No, I don't...
It'll be a rush.
I don't know.
( screams )
( water splashes )
Well, if that's
where she died...
the evidence isn't up here.
It's down there.
SANDERS:
Catherine...
Hey, I got your results.
Found a therapeutic
level of cough syrup
in the baby's system,
no more than the
recommended dosage.
So, between the cough syrup
and the heat,
Joshua probably fell asleep
and the father forgot
that he was there.
Maybe.
I also found
organophosphates,
more specifically
Disulfoton.
Pesticides.
What the hell's he doing
with pesticides in his system?
( locker closes )
( doorbell rings )
BRASS:
Mrs. Winston, we have a warrant
to search the premises.
WILLOWS:
Where do you keep
your gardening supplies?
Spiral search pattern.
The anchor chain is
your center point.
Do a 360, then
drop your depth.
Now, you're not done till
you hit the bottom, okay?
SIDLE:
You're looking for anything
she might've hit her head on,
probably something covered
with algae.
STOKES:
Good luck.
What do you got?
That's got to be Mark Young.
Yeah.
Mr. and Mrs. Winston,
why don't we get
out of this heat?
Why didn't you tell us
you had another child
who also died?
How dare you bring up Howard.
I'm a mother in mourning.
I've already buried one child.
I have to bury another.
One was in God's hands,
the other in the incapablehands
of my husband.
Show some compassion.
I'm not the guilty one here!
I'm guilty.
I'm not a bad parent;
I was negligent.
I take full responsibility
for what I did,
but leave Howard
out of it.
We found pesticides
in Joshua's bloodstream.
I'm going to have
to get a court order
and exhume the body
of your first child.
( sighs )
Vicky and I went through hell
watching Howard deteriorate.
Can't you let my boy rest
in peace?
I'm afraid not.
ROBBINS:
With exhumations, you always
hope for a good embalmer,
and I think we've got one.
Body's well-preserved.
Tay-Sachs is a genetic disorder.
You see
the retarded musculature?
Classic symptom.
Night and day,
compared to Joshua.
Quite a lot
of Vitreous Fluid left.
I stand corrected--
great embalmer.
Run this?
( whirring and clicking )
No cough syrup.
No pesticides.
Traces of monocycline.
Anti-inflammatory.
Sometimes prescribed
for Tay-Sachs.
Well, it's the same principle
of giving marijuana
to glaucoma patients--
doesn't really cure
the vision problems;
it just buys you time.
Band-Aid.
Yeah.
Maybe the Winstons
didn't want Howard
to suffer.
So, they don't kill
their first child, who's dying.
Why kill the second child,
who's healthy?
So both Howard
and Joshua Winston
were patients
of yours?
Yes. I was with them
when Howard died.
That was a dark time for them.
And, I must say,
it took a lot of
courage for them
to try again.
And since both
parents carry the
Tay-Sachs allele,
there was a 25% that the second
child would be born with it.
But Joshua dodged the bullet.
We tested Vicki early in
the second trimester;
the results
came back negative.
Had you seen Joshua recently?
A couple days
before he died.
It was a regular checkup, or...?
No. Vicki called in a panic,
said something was wrong.
I told her to bring
him right in.
And despite the fetal test,
Joshua seemed to be exhibiting
all the classic signs
of early Tay-Sachs.
Floppiness, poor head control,
unable to turn over,
decreased muscle tone.
When they brought him in
it was Howard all over again.
The only conclusion was that the
fetal test was a false negative.
What are the odds?
Under one percent.
When I saw Joshua's retinas
there were red spots--
classic Tay-Sachs.
I sent out an enzyme
test to confirm it.
And did you confirm it?
Results haven't come back yet.
ROBBINS:
Mark Young.
Cause of death is asphyxia
due to fresh water drowning.
No bruises or other injuries.
Except for a ruptured
tympanic membrane.
Hmm.
Tear's red.
It's ragged.
Ante-mortem injury.
In water, burst eardrums
typically result
from rapid decent.
Sudden changes in pressure
without equalizing.
STOKES:
She went in first.
( screaming )
Whoo-hoo!
And he jumped in after her.
This was an accident, Sara.
He was trying to save her.
That's a great theory.
But we can't prove that.
26 feet under with
a busted eardrum?
If not to save her,
why dive that deep?
I don't know.
Case is over.
Almost over.
BROWN:
Found this mineral residue
that led all the way
from the massage chair
to this burnt-out power strip
across the room... water stain.
Well, there's
your conductor.
I also found them
on the cookie sheet
and this water-damaged magazine
right here.
And I found this plastic bag
in the kitchen garbage.
"Ice Block."
Add that with the fan,
you got yourself
a homemade swamp cooler.
( electrical crackling )
( groaning )
Inventive.
Guy was just trying
to stay cool.
Thanks.
No,
it's my pleasure.
Hey, Nick.
Hey.
What are you doing?
What do you mean?
What did you
tell him?
His son died a hero?
Look, I'm just trying
to give the guy
a little peace, you know?
Oh, well, who
are you trying
to help feel better,
him or you?
Hey, let me
ask you something, Sara:
you're Mr. Young,
would you rather know this much
or nothing at all?
You know, if the evidence
doesn't support the answer,
a CSI shouldn't be
asking that question.
Well, okay,
if that works for you.
Be careful.
I was in the garden
this weekend.
Why are you so interested
in everything we do?
I mean, when did
our lives become
an open book?
When your second son
ended up dead.
When you were in the garden,
was Joshua with you?
No.
Yes, he was.
We had a fight...
Vicky, it's your turn.
I've had him for
the past four hours.
What, are you
counting hours now?
He's your son.
Look, if you're not gardening
here, then it's at work.
I've had him all day.
It's your turn.
Here. Thank you.
See the pretty flowers, Joshua?
( sighs )
I guess he was.
But the moment he
passed Joshua off
to me I went inside.
Did you wash your hands?
Honestly, I don't remember.
I'm in the garden a lot,
so I'm sure I
washed my hands.
Well, I met with your
pediatrician, Dr. Garner.
When you brought
Joshua in
on that emergency call,
it was because
you feared that
he, too, had Tay-Sachs.
PAUL:
We had the test
before he was born.
Dr. Garner said we were fine.
I can imagine for both of you
it must have been like
reliving the nightmare.
One child, now two.
WILLOWS:
Did you know
that repeated exposure
to certain pesticides,
even in small amounts,
can have an adverse effect
in infants?
Even mimic the signs
of Tay-Sachs?
BRASS:
The symptoms are similar.
Floppiness of the head,
arching of the back.
Blindness...
inability to swallow.
You know, like that.
WILLOWS:
You work with pesticides,
Mrs. Winston,
on your job
and in your garden.
And you handled Joshua--
we suspect that that's how
the traces
got into his system.
I'm just speculating here,
but I think this is
what happened next:
No, Paul. I went
through hell with Howard,
I can't go through
that with Joshua.
We'll wait for the enzyme tests.
No. No more tests.
No more drugs.
No more kids.
No more!
I can't live through that again,
and neither can you.
WILLOWS:
You gave Joshua
cough syrup, Mr. Winston.
Why did you medicate him?
BRASS:
'Cause, maybe, you just
didn't want him to suffer?
( car alarm squeals )
( softly cries )
You have no idea
what it's like to
watch your child die.
We couldn't
go through that again.
WILLOWS:
The shame of it is
you didn't have to.
( sighs )
The enzyme test that Dr. Garner
ran came back negative.
Joshua didn't have Tay-Sachs.
You killed
a perfectly healthy baby.