( thunder crashes )
I saw you with him.
I know you're lying.
You've got it all wrong.
I'm telling you. Nothing happened.
Nobody cheats on me.
( chokes )
WOMAN:
His fingerprints were
all over that belt.
That's the only way
it could have happened.
I'm with Lizette, all right?
We heard from the DA.
They called the cops last week
on a domestic disturbance.
Kimble was just getting
warmed up. Believe me.
I know the type.
Husband was a casino host.
Just happens to come home
in the middle of a shift?
Come on.
Oh, look, we've really
talked this thing
to death, haven't we?
Chris, can we please put this
to another vote?
The burden of proof is beyond
a reasonable doubt.
We don't have that.
There was somebody else
in the house that day.
The cable guy.
Cable guy's got priors.
He skipped town.
You're still on the cable guy
theory?
His fingerprints
weren't even on the belt.
He could have worn gloves.
I can't take this
anymore!
Who keeps shutting
this damn window?
Lunch will be here soon.
Let's take a break.
This guy is
driving me nuts.
We've got to get
Chris Gibbons replaced.
Oh, I pointed him
in the right direction,
but he didn't snap.
I'd kill for a candy bar
right now.
Hey, people.
Your lunch is getting cold.
( chattering )
Chris Gibbons,
UNLV grad student.
The jury's been sequestered
two and a half weeks
on a murder trial.
Twelve strangers...
stuck in a room
with no exit.
It's like Sartre said:
"hell is other people.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
What do you got?
My early opinion?
Blunt force.
He's got a, uh,
medical alert bracelet.
Allergy to penicillin.
Well... we got 11
potential suspects.
Do you have one with blond hair?
Yeah. There's one I know of.
Um, Miss Davis--
she's a stripper
at The Shimmer.
There's no tag cells,
and she's not a natural blonde,
and it looks
synthetic.
Hey, this is Vegas, baby.
"Guilty," "guilty"...
"not guilty."
11 "guilty," one "not guilty."
Now that's motive.
( chattering )
Excuse me.
May I have your...?
May I have your attention,
please?
Thank you.
I'm Catherine Willows.
I'm from the Crime Lab.
So it's a mistrial, right?
Can we go home?
No. I'm sorry.
No one is
going anywhere.
Ms. Davis.
I'll start with you.
Will you follow me, please?
( chattering )
Miss Davis, we found
a synthetic blond hair
on the victim's body.
Care to explain?
Girl to girl.
I'm a dancer.
I came off the pole.
I teased him a little bit.
I need a release,
so why don't you get us
out of here, and I'll...
( inaudible dialogue )
Did he take you up
on your offer?
Well, if you ask me,
arguing was his turn-on.
Lucky for you.
Attempting to influence
is a Category D felony.
It's up to four years in prison
and a $5,000 fine.
Am I under arrest?
Woman to woman?
The pole is there for a reason.
It's what you hang on to
so the creeps don't pull you
out of there.
Smarten up.
Thanks, man.
Stokes.
Detective.
Hey.
You've got a minute?
Yeah. Sure, what's up?
Four years ago,
you and Grissom
worked a missing persons
out in Moapa Valley?
She lived on a farm
with her husband?
Wow. Um...
Yeah, I remember.
Uh-uh, Rita?
Rita Westonson.
Found nothing suspicious.
Nothing criminal.
Figured she wanted
to skip town, disappear.
Rita's sister
is in interrogation.
She's claiming
Rita was murdered.
Faye, it's been four years
since your sister went missing.
Now, CSI conducted
a full investigation--
found nothing suspicious,
nothing criminal.
Why are you coming forward now?
I lied to you back then, and I
live with the guilt every day.
Miss Minden?
It's my duty to advise you
of your right to counsel.
I don't want
an attorney.
I admit I withheld
information.
That's why I'm here.
And if I have to go to jail,
so be it.
I just want to do right
by my sister.
Okay. Let's start
from the beginning.
Your sister disappeared
over a weekend...
Rita didn't disappear.
Her business trip
to Fresno got cut short,
and she came home early.
Found Aaron, her husband,
in the barn with another
woman.
Rita freaked out
and started screaming
and saying
she was going to leave him.
Aaron saw red and lost it.
( blows landing )
( body thuds )
Now if memory serves,
her husband had an alibi?
Yeah. He was camping in Red Rock
with Harris Mathey.
That's his business partner,
right?
Yeah, but Harris owed Aaron
a lot of money.
He would have said anything.
If that's true,
Mr. Mathey is guilty
of conspiracy after the fact.
He died last month.
And he's the only one who knew,
besides me.
Do you know what Aaron did
with Rita's body?
He drove her out to the river,
about a half mile from his farm,
and, um, set her on fire.
She burned all night,
and then in the morning,
he dumped her ashes
in the water.
Miss Minden...
how did you come across
this information?
You were the other woman.
Hey, Sara.
Any jurors have blood
on their hands?
WILLOWS:
Mr. Jervis.
Why are your fingers bloodied?
You ever been
on a jury before?
How many grad students does it
take to screw in a lightbulb?
I can't take this anymore!
It's the worst experience
of my life.
Would you hold your hands
up for me, please?
The case was a lock anyway.
I mean, Kimble obviously had...
Mr. Jervis.
I need to remind you
that you're still
under judge's orders
not to discuss the case.
That's great. This guy's dead,
and I still can't go home?
Let me tell you
something.
From the very beginning,
day one
day after day,
this guy is
the only holdout.
Do you want to know
what my boss calls me?
Mr. Replaceable.
I had to get back to work.
( yelling )
I lost my temper.
You sure it's lost?
Homicide just called.
They're reopening
the Rita Westonson case
based on new information
from the eyewitness?
File's thinner
than I remembered.
You think we missed something?
We figured she skipped town,
wanting to disappear.
At the time, that was
a reasonable conclusion
based on the evidence.
Does the witness
seem credible to you?
Well, if she's lying,
she's obstructing justice
and wasting my time, but
if she's telling the truth,
we may have closed
the investigation early.
At the time, you were
a Level Two, I believe.
So closing the case
would have been my decision.
Yeah, it would have.
I'm checking out her story.
I'll see if it holds up.
Let me know.
Mm-hmm.
ROBBINS:
Blunt-force trauma
didn't kill him.
But this might have.
Hives?
Whoo. Severe allergic reaction.
Cause of death:
anaphylactic shock.
Outer skin becomes irritated,
the eyes inflamed,
throat closes...
( gasping, choking )
He was allergic to penicillin,
but that's not the kind of thing
you can just
easily slip someone.
No, but you can inject it.
Puncture wound is consistent
with a hypodermic needle.
He wore a Medic Alert bracelet.
Everyone hated him,
and everyone knew
how to kill him.
( bird screeching )
FAYE:
Haven't been back here
since that night.
Sometimes it feels
like yesterday;
sometimes it feels like
it never happened.
Funny, the things you remember.
( birds chirping )
Who could've imagined?
( Faye sighs )
This is it.
This is the spot under the tree.
You sure?
Yes. This is where Aaron
burned her body.
I remember the...
yucca plant was flowering.
Right here?
Yes.
What are you doing?
Well, if Rita's body
was incinerated here,
the gasoline fumes would have
settled into the soil...
...and trace amounts
of hydrocarbon
would still be detectable.
Good.
♪ ♪
( beeps )
Mr. Dorsey.
I just analyzed your dirt.
Where there's smoke,
there's fire,
and where there's
no smoke...
There are no hydrocarbons.
Damn.
There's no evidence
of gasoline whatsoever.
Where's Hodges?
Conference in San Francisco.
Total boondoggle.
Three days of sourdough
and seafood.
By the way...
...I heard the rumor,
and I'm sorry.
What rumor?
Everybody on the day shift
says that you deserved
that promotion.
You ask me,
Grissom only gave Sara
a higher evaluation
because of their history.
He gave Sara...?
Hey. You get anything?
Well, science seems to have
trumped the eyewitness.
That story doesn't hold up.
I may know why.
I ran a background.
Faye had two sisters--
Rita, older
and Terry, younger.
Now get this--
a couple weeks ago
Terry and Aaron...
got engaged.
Hey, Gris.
So tox came back
on Chris Gibbons.
He may have been
allergic to penicillin
but didn't have any
in his system.
We sent a sample
of his pants to Trace.
The area around
the injection mark...
Epinephrine.
So maybe Mr. Gibbons
had an allergic reaction
to something else.
Such as...?
I don't know, but if
Gibbons knew he was
severely allergic,
I bet he carried one
of those auto-injector pens.
So we're looking for
a used hypodermic.
And another allergy.
I'm not the allergy ace.
I'm trying to get
out in the field,
and you're multitasking me
in the lab.
Rick, I'm the one that actually
put you on a case,
not just talk about it.
You're also the one
who took me off the case.
You know what?
You started, and you gave
me six strong innings,
and I brought in the closer.
What's wrong with that?
So what am I, fish or fowl?
Fish--
that's a good place to start.
I need you to check
the victim's blood
for shellfish, egg whites,
nuts and soy.
The biggies.
Got to start somewhere.
♪ ♪
( whirring )
That was Catherine.
What are we looking for?
Nuts.
Specifically those
that begin with a "P."
♪ ♪
Take me out to the ball game.
Buy me some peanuts.
There's peanut skins
under Mr. Durham's seat.
That's very interesting.
There's peanut shells
under Mr. Gibbon's seat.
Mr. Gibbons couldn't eat
peanuts.
What are they doing
under his seat?
Let's ask Mr. Durham.
Just 'cause he's allergic
doesn't mean I can't have them.
Chris Gibbons died
from a severe allergic reaction.
You were the only guy
in the jury room
who was eating peanuts.
You might have killed him.
I was only messing
with his head.
What are you trying to do,
kill me? I'm allergic!
You're a hypochondriac.
Does that look like
hypochondria
to you?
Look, I didn't know
that just by touching
a shell it would send him
into some kind of fit.
( gasping )
( coughing )
I apologized.
None of the other jurors
mentioned anything
about Chris throwing a fit.
Hey, look, it wasn't
that big of a deal.
I mean, we went back to work,
deliberated for
a couple hours...
the guy was fine.
STOKES:
You withheld information.
No, it's not like that.
You don't understand.
They why didn't you tell us
about your younger sister?
Because I knew it
would come to this.
I was dumped
by Aaron
for my younger sister.
I was hurt and angry
and jealous,
and I wanted
to get back at him,
so I falsely accused him
of killing Rita.
I am not jealous of Terry.
I'm scared for her.
I don't want her to end up
like Rita.
Did your relationship
with Aaron
end amicably?
It ended.
After the night
he killed Rita,
I saw him a handful of times.
I want nothing to do with him.
So why not
warn Terry?
Tell her what you told us.
Because she's in love with him.
If I told her what Aaron
did to Rita,
she'd run right to him.
"Crazy Faye always
causing trouble."
Aaron would like nothing more
than to drive a wedge
between me and my sister.
I've seen what he's capable of.
That night he made me help him.
Her eyes were still opened.
It was muddy?
Yeah.
Okay, was it raining?
No, not that night.
It was a wet winter.
Say you believe me.
One auto-injector... used.
That's substantiates
Bob Durham's story
that Gibbons had a
reaction to peanut shells.
What do you want to bet he only
brought one of these with him.
Well, he was sequestered.
He couldn't exactly go out
and get another one.
Ah, he was later
held defenseless
against the attack
of the killer peanut.
I guess it's possible.
We're not finding anything
in Chris Gibbon's chili.
No peanuts, no shells,
no skins.
What about peanut butter?
In an individually wrapped tube?
That could belong
to any of the jurors.
This looks like peanut butter
right here.
Someone was doing more than just
flicking peanut shells.
If Gibbons had that severe
a reaction to peanut shells,
imagine what eating
peanut butter would
do to him.
Yeah, that's more than just
messing with a guy's head.
That's murder.
Hey, defense motioned
for a mistrial.
Suspicion of
jury tampering.
Based on peanut butter
in the chili?
How does a juror benefit
from Gibbons' death?
I don't know.
Lone hold out, now
they get to go home?
That's nuts.
The risk
isn't worth the reward.
Well, Warrick's still
working on that print.
Good.
What are you working on?
( birds chirping )
( saw buzzing )
( buzzing )
So the soil doesn't support
the eye witness testimony.
No.
So I stuck a moisture testing
probe into the ground
at the burn site,
registered 18%.
Now anything over 10%
is indicative
of full saturation over
the last couple of years.
The river might have washed away
all trace of hydrocarbons.
Exactly, but before it washed
away, some of the hydrocarbons
could have
seeped into the ground
into the tree's
roots.
Roots carry nutrients
to the tree.
Some of the hydrocarbons
could have hitched a ride.
Oaks don't bear fruit,
but this one bears witness.
Every year,
a branch grows a new ring
composed of alike,
dark band.
Counting from the outside in,
going back four years--
one, two, three,
four...
The ring from
four years ago is thinner
and distorted.
Yeah, the same
distortion is present
in ring four of every branch.
And distortion could mean
evidence of a toxic event.
I'm thinking the burning
of gasoline under the tree.
How are you going to prove it?
Saw dust.
( buzzing )
Nick, I think you're
going to like this.
STOKES:
Affirmative for hydrocarbons.
Now we're talking.
Nick, no offense, but
proving the boss wrong
is not the quickest path
to career advancement.
The trial lasted four weeks.
They've been locked
in deliberations
for two and a half.
Sequestered?
Well, it's
a high-profile case.
Judge Slater limited contact,
censored newspapers,
no television, shuttle
between here and their hotel.
That's a juror's life.
What about the food,
how does that work?
This case, uh,
jurors had breakfast
and dinner at the hotel.
Lunch, I brought in a menu,
they order...
Gee, let me guess.
For the 17th day
in a row,
you're going to order chili.
Oh, now you're criticizing
my food choices.
Chris Gibbons had chili
the day he died.
Yeah, the guy had
food allergies.
We had one place
we ordered from.
He had chili every day.
Did jurors have access
to these vending machines?
Uh, yeah,
that's why they're here.
It's their nickel.
I mean, they got
to have something.
They're away from
their families.
I have all
their cell phone...
Well, almost all of them.
Caught a guy
double packing.
( beeping )
Can't anybody make a battery
that lasts more than
a couple of hours?
Hey, I confiscated his primary
at the beginning
of deliberations,
but I don't do cavity searches.
( chuckling )
How do you burn out
your cell phone battery
when you're not allowed
to use your phone?
They don't make cell
phones like they used to.
That's true,
actually.
Now they make
them better.
Did you know
that this one takes pictures?
And having met
your fellow jurors,
I think
you really captured them.
Okay, let's start
with the misdemeanor.
Cell phones
and cameras
or cell phones withcameras
are prohibited in the jury
room.
Somebody must have
told you that.
See, after a while
they're family.
I-I thought I could throw
a scrapbook together
for everyone for
after the trial.
Oh, and-and when where you
planning on handing that out?
At Mr. Gibbons' funeral?
I guess you would
consider the folks
at the credit company
family, too.
What?
Yeah, according
to them, uh,
you got a little bit of a
gambling jones, hmm?
$25,000 in markers
all over town.
So what's your game,
dice, cards, sports book?
Or all of the above?
Let's just say
it was a bad month.
Not that bad.
$30,000 deposit two days ago.
All right, now
the questions get hard.
I mean, you can't be
getting rich on jury duty,
40 bucks a day.
Or can you?
Look, I'm self-employed,
which means I've been unemployed
for the last
six and a half weeks.
You just made $30,000.
To deliver
the jury?
No. My story.
To a tabloid.
Hey...
it's one of
those cases--
high-profile,
jurors at each other's throats.
( indistinct shouting )
Why should the guy
that killed his wife
be the only one to make a buck?
Can I help you?
I'm Detective Artan.
This is Nick Stokes
from the Crime Lab.
Terry Minden?
Honey, who is it?
It's the police.
I remember you.
You were here
about Rita.
Yeah.
You found her.
No, no, not exactly,
but we have a
potential new lead.
And we have a warrant.
I'm an attorney.
You want a sample
of gasoline?
Uh, yes, ma'am--
eight ounces
from Mr. Westonson's pump.
Why?
This is
about Rita.
I have a right to know.
Warrant was issued
by Judge Brenner.
I'll make a call.
Say hello for me.
Four years ago,
you tore this place apart.
That was okay with me.
Now you come back
with no answers,
and you're looking at me
with that same face.
I'm going to tell you the
same thing I said before.
I had nothing to do
with Rita's disappearance.
Fuel pump's behind
the barn, right?
Yeah. Help yourself.
What are you looking at?
I was standing right
here four years ago
asking myself
the same question.
You know,
Aaron Westonson's
right about one thing.
Back then Grissom and I
processed every
inch of that house
and this barn and found
no signs of a struggle.
Aaron versus Rita?
He's twice her size.
Yeah, it would've been
over before it started.
Okay, fill her up.
I think
it's diesel.
Why is it red?
It's an EPA requirement.
Farm's don't have to pay taxes
on fuel, so refineries,
they mark their agricultural
diesel by dying it red.
I'm getting married
in five days.
Not if you can't explain
to me how your fingerprints
ended up
on this peanut butter tube.
We found it
in the jury room.
I just wanted to go home,
have my fittings.
I spent my bridal shower
with 11 strangers.
My sister filled in for me.
I'll never get
to experience that.
Mr. Gibbons
will never get to experience
the rest of his life.
We were on a break,
and the lunch order came.
Hey.
What did you order?
Don't worry,
I'll pass it out.
I got the peanut butter
out of the vending machine
a couple days ago.
I wanted to stuff it down
the guy's throat, but I didn't.
So you decided to put
it in his chili instead?
Great, food's here.
I'm starving. Where's mine?
But at the last minute,
I couldn't do that.
Oh!
Oh, I'm so sorry.
No, that's okay,
I'll take yours.
You can reorder.
Then I cleaned up
and I walked out.
You had to know
it was going to kill him.
No, I didn't know
it was going to be lethal.
When Bob was flicking
peanut shells at him,
it's not like he choked up.
I swear,
I didn't know
it was going to kill him.
I just thought that
it would get him replaced
with one of the alternates
who would vote guilty.
Well, Miss Newsome, you are
officially off of jury duty.
I killed him.
No, she didn't.
Greg, she told Warrick she put
peanut butter in the chili.
I don't care if Mr.
Peanut was taking a
bath in the vic's lunch.
It's not what killed him.
Be specific, Greg.
I got the
detailed results
back from the assay test.
The level of immunoglobulin E
was insufficient
to cause a lethal reaction.
Well, that does go along
with what the bride-to-be
said about
the victim.
That he had
a dermatological response
to the allergen and
not a respiratory one.
GRISSOM:
Did the assay test
show any other food allergies?
No, uh-uh.
So the cause of death
is still anaphylactic shock.
Okay, what caused it?
And who?
I got your page.
Who shot your dog?
Trace tech.
He analyzed the fuel
from Aaron's pump.
Confirmed it's diesel.
The hydrocarbons
found in the tree
were from unleaded gasoline.
Means the fuel
on Aaron's farm
was not used to
cremate Rita's body.
Maybe it pumped unleaded
four years ago.
Converted to diesel
at some point since.
Ah, I thought
the same thing myself,
so I called the NDEP.
Mm-hmm.
E Permit for Aaron's fuel tank
was specifically for diesel.
Where does that leave us?
NDEP's database
for Clark County.
Now, the red dots
represent the areas
of permitted fuel tanks.
Isolate Moapa.
Yeah.
Aaron's farm's located
at the cross streets
of White Oak
and Stansberry.
The burn spot
is a half mile east
along the river.
Mm-hmm.
Only two permitted
fuel tanks up in that area.
The one on the left
is Aaron's.
We can exclude
that one.
Who owns
the other one?
Faye Minden.
ROBBINS:
We've ruled out food allergy
as the cause of death.
If it was
an environmental agent,
I expect one
of the other jurors
had a reaction as well.
His body reacted to something.
It's why I'm reexamining
the exposed areas of his body--
face and the neck.
Look at this.
Apis Mellifera Linnaeus.
We're looking for another body.
Greg ran the assay test
for bee venom on Chris Gibbons.
IG levels were spiked.
Was Gibbons even aware
that he had a bee allergy?
Brass finally tracked down
his allergist.
Gibbons was allergic
to a lot of things.
The killer, I presume.
Or what's left of him.
( buzzing )
( gasping )
He had an immediate reaction
to a bee sting.
Lost consciousness,
fell forward,
hit his head
on the table.
You know how Gervis was
complaining that it was too hot.
He said he opened the window.
I can't take this anymore!
Who keeps shutting
this damn window?!
Well, that explains it.
It was an outside job.
Okay, good.
Thank you.
Hey.
Heard you were over
at Aaron's farm.
Yep.
I bet that
shook him up.
Thank you for
pushing forward
with the
investigation.
And we continue
to push forward.
We need to take a sample
of fuel from your pump.
Yeah. Yeah, you wouldn't mind,
would you, Faye?
My pump?
Yeah.
Well, what'd
he say?
Didn't I tell you
he'd turn on me?
Oh, he didn't say anything.
Just want to take
a look.
My trees are
Douglas firs.
The... the needles
grow in spirals
around the twigs.
It's amazing.
Any time you
guys want,
you come back here,
take your pick.
Free of charge.
The pump on Aaron's farm
is diesel.
Your sister was cremated
with unleaded.
You know what?
Thinking back now,
I-I remember
Aaron's pump was empty,
and, uh, he insisted
we drive over here.
He used mine.
Sorry for the confusion.
Excuse me.
Please say you believe me.
♪ ♪
I believe you, Faye.
You see, blood evidence
doesn't disappear over time.
Your sister was murdered...
by you.
Faye?
Faye, you in here?
STOKES:
Unleaded gasoline,
barrels for incineration,
cast off on the walls.
DNA consistent
with Rita Westonson.
Then he killed Rita
to be with Aaron.
And a couple of weeks ago,
hears he's getting engaged
to her younger sister Terry.
They couldn't
handle it, man.
She just freaked.
So she tried to pin
Rita's murder on Aaron.
Four years ago when I decided
to close the case,
did you agree
with my decision?
Well, you were
following protocol.
And now?
Now I'd fight you on it, yeah.
Why?
Rita Westonson
was a dependable,
predictable girl.
We never answered the question
why she just woke up one morning
and walked away
from the rest of her life.
It happens.
And that's what the evidence
was telling us.
Well, that's what the physical
evidence was telling us.
We should have dug deeper.
You can't just ignore
the human element, Grissom.
I agree, Nick.
But when you start
to have feelings
for the people involved,
you risk your objectivity.
So what?
You know, I'm always getting
criticized for empathizing
with the victims
and their families,
but that's who I am.
That's how I do my job.
And as far as the
promotion goes,
it's all good, man.
I can live without it.
I'm not you.
Good.
We certainly don't need
another me around here.