Previously on CSI:
You got a husband-and-wife
serial team
killing couples.
Mr. Dominguez was forced
to kill his wife
for the promise of freedom.
They were never
going to let him go.
WILLOWS:
It's just so sick.
We are this close
to busting a pair
of serial killers,
and the judge won't issue
a warrant?
Hey, I'm just the messenger.
The affidavit is standing.
You've signed warrants for less.
Love is not love.
Love is conditional.
For most people.
But not for you.
Then she stuck her tongue
in this jerk.
Rifkin's ear--
chances are
she stuck it
in Mr. Dominguez's ear, too.
Should get a warrant.
BRASS:
Las Vegas Police.
We got a problem.
Somebody got to our serials
before we did.
Are you carrying?
No.
Then get the hell out of here
while I secure the room.
This is Brass. Yeah.
I'm at 11546 Blackbird Lane.
Got two gunshot victims.
Send rescue.
There's no rush.
( sighs )
Are those your guys?
Yeah, they're UC.
How long they been
sitting on the house?
Oh, about the time
that Judge Slater didn't sign
the first warrant.
Two undercover guys outside.
Two dead bodies inside.
Makes you feel a little paranoid
right now.
Not paranoid enough.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
Alright, Captain.
What do you wanna know?
So, you guys been
here the whole time?
Almost.
What happened?
Tell him.
Around 7:00,
there was a 444 call...
Citizen reports officer down.
2529 Harmon Hill.
All units in the vicinity
respond.
We met up with a couple
black-and-whites.
UTL.
W... What is that?
Unable to locate.
False alarm.
We came right back.
Observed no activity
in the house
until you guys got here.
You know we're going to
need to see your guns.
Why would we off
two scumbags
when we know you're coming back
with a warrant?
It wasn't a question.
And you're not my supervisor.
I am. I want your gun.
Give me your gun.
( sighs )
Hey, help me out here.
( sighs ):
And your backups, too.
Come on.
Satisfied?
Just doing my job.
Here you go. Fellas,
check out the back.
Okay? Let's go.
These our serials?
So it seems.
Yesterday's suspects.
Today's victims.
We had 'em...
Take the inside.
No sign of forced entry...
on this door, at least.
Print the handle.
What do you think?
I don't know what that is.
Make sure you get all of it,
though.
You see any
cartridge casings?
Not yet.
85.5.
So TOD
was about 11:00 p.m.
Grissom,
I've got blood, but...
a lot of pheno-negative stains
as well.
We're going to bring
everything back.
What do you got,
Warrick?
If the killer went out
the back door,
this may be his print.
Good thing Brass had cops
watching the house.
Linens and towels
from the Sphere
on top of the washing machine,
and what I believe to
be sheets from the motel
inside the dryer.
Both positive presumptive
for blood.
Think they were being smart
taking the sheets,
or did they just get
off sleeping on 'em?
Either way, they were sick
and dangerous.
What does that say
about whoever killed them?
Wh-What's the big deal?
There's no humans involved.
I mean, look, Captain.
Come on. The way I see it,
somebody did us a favor.
Yeah.
They're dead.
Case is closed.
Hey, this isn't a favor, Bill.
This is a screwup.
Would've been a lot bigger
screwup if...
if we didn't break surveillance
and had an officer down
four blocks away.
All right, what else
did you see?
Kid in that house made us.
Thought we were bad news.
You are bad news.
I can't believe Grissom pulled
us off that serial murder case.
Yeah, well, let me
tell you how it ends.
They die.
Whoa, this isn't half
bad for college kids.
Yeah. Why live in
a one-room flea bag
when you can pool
your resources
and live like this.
Hey, how 'bout it: you, me,
Warrick, Nick, Grissom...
Oh, can't. Not Grissom.
What the hell
is this?
Ma'am, you may want
to take one of these.
Thank you. Thanks.
Where's the body?
Upstairs.
Upstairs?
It's raining man juice.
Hallelujah.
You might want to wear those.
Thank you.
Well, weather's clearing.
Yeah, if only
the smell would.
( groans )
It's like a sewer in here.
Oh, my goodness.
Oh, God.
Soup's on.
( clears throat )
How long has he been in here?
Roommates last saw him
Thursday night.
Took off for the weekend.
Came home to this.
Guy goes to take a shower
and DFOs.
He never got to the cold water,
did he?
Roommate said only the hot water
faucet was on.
Must've been a steam bath
in here.
Still is.
Well, any evidence
on the floor's been washed away.
There, uh...
( clears throat ):
could be something in the tub.
We got to take that body
and get it through that door.
SARA:
There's another option.
MAN:
I'm at the corner
of Harmon Hill and 25th,
just east of the intersection.
There's been a shooting.
I think a cop got shot.
John, oh...
Just occurred.
I heard the shots.
I received the call
and issued the 444.
Uniforms called back
a few minutes later,
said they checked the area,
said it was a UTL.
You want to hear that?
I'll hear it
when you give me a dub
of the original caller's
voice...
and his phone number.
I can get that for you
right now.
Good.
( phone dialing )
( line ringing )
Are we done?
If I'm not done,
you're not done.
We already gave you
our footprints,
and our fingerprints
are on file,
so what else
do you need?
Which way is Harmon Hill?
( phone ringing in distance )
BRASS:
So, Bradley, you saw our
police officer at that door?
Yeah...
and I was watching
these guys all night.
See, the two bad guys
drove away in the van,
and then the
policeman showed up,
knocked on the door.
Mr. Klinefeld let him in...
but he never came back out.
Did you see a police car?
Must've walked here.
Did you hear any gunshots?
Nope.
Okay, thanks, Bradley.
Good job.
No problem.
Ever see a beat cop
anywhere but the Strip?
And how'd he beat us
to the killer?
Trace evidence.
Definitely doesn't belong
in the wound track.
Did your guy get shot
through a window?
No.
We found a lot of this material
at the crime scene.
Absence of gunshot residue.
GRISSOM:
Maybe he was shot
through some sort of object.
Well, Mr. Klinefeld was shot
once in the front
and Mrs. Klinefeld
once in the back.
( yelling )
( gunshot )
Dare I say the couple
that slays together,
lays together?
This drain hasn't
been tampered with.
It's just clogged.
I think this is an accidental.
There's nothing
but young people stuff.
No meds, except some aspirin.
No prescriptions.
Well, I don't think
that means much.
Chances are he's not getting his
drugs from a medicine cabinet.
There's no sign of struggle.
Any prints would have
been washed away.
( sighs )
Where does that leave us?
Same place we were when
we walked through the door--
with a bloated floater.
Hey, you know that cell phone
Grissom found
at the crime scene?
Yeah.
Traced it back
to a public defender.
Said she lost it.
Made life hell for her
while she was in DC.
Mm...
Have you run a sample
of this through the GCMS?
Mm-hmm. Polyethylene.
Polyethylene.
I got the results back
from Grissom's ant puddle.
( beep )
Mm-hmm.
Corn syrup, glucose,
caramel and water.
Hang on a second.
Where do you keep
the sodium rhodizinate?
On top of the
file cabinet.
So, what's up?
You and Bobby switched or what?
Hey, Rich, whatever happened
with those bullets?
Six right nine-millimeter.
Beretta, amongst others.
Consistent with an
officer's duty weapon.
Consistent with Officer Commons
and Officer Nowlin's weapons?
No match.
That includes backups.
Well, thanks.
Hey, Warrick.
Yeah?
Polyethylene
plus corn syrup plus GSR
gives you what?
Polyethylene and corn syrup
is... cola in a bottle.
GSR on the inside
of a plastic bottle means...
Soda silencer.
Poor man's silencer.
Only good
for a couple shots.
So, that shooter was sitting
on the house
and the surveillance team.
Empties out
his bottle of soda...
calls in an "officer down"...
...drops the phone
and takes a walk.
What do you think?
Who do we have around here
that could find us
a somewhat used soda bottle?
Hey.
Floater's shirt.
Took it off his bed.
What does this look like to you?
A backwards seven.
Yeah, that's what I got.
What's it doing on a DB's shirt?
I don't know.
Some kind of greasepaint
or makeup.
How do you get paint
on the inside of your clothes?
Rubs off your chest.
Oh, what kind of guy
paints his chest?
Performance artist?
A clown maybe?
Sports freak.
Well, it's not like you
to have a one-track mind.
If the evidence points
to cops, we chase cops.
Jesse Commons
and Bill Nowlin
were doing what
I asked them to do.
They were sitting
on the house.
Until you can get
enough physical evidence
to support a warrant.
Somebody knew we were looking
at the Klinefelds.
They knew where they lived.
That's somebody inside.
Cops don't take the law
into their own hands.
Ha! In what city?
Oh, you want to hit
below the belt?
You know, a lot of people
had access to the Klinefelds.
Who knows, maybe
CSI III Nicky Stokes
opened up his mouth to another
parking lot attendant.
There was an eyewitness
who saw a uniform
at the front door.
Oh, come on,
a ten-year-old insomniac kid,
hyped up on sugar,
going blind on X-Box.
Who knows what he saw?
So, now you're discrediting
your own witness?
All right, let's break it down.
You got a public defender's
cell phone, no prints.
You got officers' weapons
taken from the scene, not fired.
You got officers' shoe prints,
not matching the
evidence print.
You got three
black-and-whites
confirming
that Commons and Nowlin
responded to a 444.
Give these guys a break.
Just because
they weren't the shooters
doesn't mean
they weren't involved.
Oh, what,
so it's a conspiracy?
Oh, please!
You got a bogus 444 call
two blocks away.
Oh, come on, you
know the deal.
You know better than that.
There's bogus calls
come in every day.
Well, maybe you don't,
because you're the kind of guy
who goes to serve a warrant
without a gun.
I'm not a cop.
Well, that's a distinction
that could be lost
when the suspect's
still inside the house.
Look, I had your back.
Now I expect you to have mine.
That's not the way it works.
In what city?
Hey, guys?
I found something.
Not now.
No. You need to see this.
Both of you. Now!
Please.
Sorry I didn't find
the soda bottle.
This'll do.
Star-1 Uniforms.
It's the biggest
uniform shop in town.
From casino
dealers to cops.
Shirt's wet.
I found it in a storm drain.
Where exactly?
Two blocks west
of the house.
Opposite direction
from the 444.
Buttons.
Meaning?
All the new uniforms
have zippers.
This collar's dry.
It's hot out--
at least
a buck twenty-five.
Let's hope whoever was wearing
that shirt sweats.
The badge looks legit.
I'll run the number.
MAN:
Roommates were unable
to make a positive ID
due to the accelerated
decomposition,
but dental records confirmed
Daniel O'Hannissey.
Laceration
on the forehead--
macerated, but not significant.
Contusion
with a small laceration...
here, below the ear.
That did some damage.
There's an obvious hematoma
in the subdural space
consistent with
a subdural bleed.
Herniation of the Uncinate
Process on the same side.
Doc, uh, why is his brain green?
He was steamed.
Turns the brain
into lime gelatin.
Cause of death?
Ruled out drowning.
There was no water
in the lungs.
He was dead before
he hit the water.
So, you are looking at it--
a blow to the back of the head.
Resulted in a
subdural hematoma.
Sort of like a slow
leak in a tire.
A slow leak in a tire?
Odds are Danny had no idea
he was bleeding
in his brain.
He probably felt fine.
Maybe a little woozy.
Then out of nowhere, he drops.
How long do you think
he lived after the blow?
12 to 24 hours.
Well, he had to have been
in the water
for a couple of days
to look like this.
Roommates last saw him Thursday.
So I guess we start there
and we work backwards.
Thanks.
Yeah.
I lost my badge years ago.
Filed a report.
Got issued a new one.
Yeah, I'm aware of officers
"losing" their badges.
Then we don't have
a problem, do we?
No, we got a problem
'cause your badge
was found in the proximity
of a crime scene.
How'd you manage
to lose your badge?
Such is life.
That's not the answer
I was hoping for.
BRASS:
I've been looking
at your jacket.
Reads like a novel.
You got a lot of entries
in here.
You got, uh...
beat-and-release.
You got some stick therapy.
What's up with this?
Show me a cop without a
few entries in his jacket,
I'll show you a pogue.
You referring to me?
Guys like you get to sit
on your ass behind a desk
because guys like me are
out there doing the real work.
BRASS:
Okay, tough guy,
tell me what you know.
I lost my badge.
End of story.
If I ever find the guy
who stole it, believe...
I want my union rep.
I'm it.
I want somebody impartial.
Well, I was impartial.
Now open up.
You went for a bottle
and found a shirt?
This swab is your new priority.
I was just filling
Nick in...
Fill me in first.
The sweat stain?
Uh, I was just
getting started.
I can do them
both together.
The shoe print?
Running it through Limbic.
How can you be doing that
when you're standing here?
MAN ( on tape ):
I'm at the corner
of Harmon Hill and 25th.
Just east of the intersection.
There's been a shooting.
I think a cop got shot.
John, oh...
Just occurred.
I heard shots.
Where are we?
Check it out.
I think a cop got shot.
John, oh...
Just occurred.
I heard shots.
I have never heard
a citizen that calm.
This 911 caller
knew the drill.
He's using officers code.
'J' becomes john.
'O' becomes ocean.
J.O.-- just occurred.
Old habits die hard.
I'm only halfway home.
I need a voice exemplar.
Did you get a name
off that badge?
Yeah.
You know, Daniel
was from Green Bay.
Big-time diehard
football fan.
He tried to walk-on
here, but, uh...
didn't make the team.
But, hey, come game night,
he was always at the stadium.
What about the away games?
He watched one game at home
and lost all of his
chill privileges.
It was ugly.
Define ugly.
Busted the couch,
jumping on it.
Neighbors called the cops
'cause he was so loud.
He was a real Bluto.
Where else did he 'Bluto'?
( loud rock music plays )
Everybody knew Dan-o.
He's the kind of guy
that keeps a place
like this in business.
I'm going to miss him.
When was the last time
you saw him?
When was the last Rebel game?
Thursday.
Did you notice anything?
Did he...
feel okay?
Better than okay.
He was pumped.
He was so pumped that him
and some of his buddies
got into it
with some other guys.
Wh-What do you mean?
He started a fight?
No, Shirley Temple
started the fight.
Right there!
( hooting )
Drinks for the guys down there.
Shirley Temples--
extra cherries.
Shirley Temples all around.
Hey, Wayne, those
are for you, buddy.
Those are for you
and your boys.
How did Shirley take it?
Not so good.
Come here, tough guy.
( cheering and applause )
( yelling ):
Yeah!
You know how guys are.
They scrap until someone
gets a touchdown.
Yeah. Yeah, right.
Do you see any of those guys
in here now?
There's a couple of Shirleys
over there by the big screen.
BROWN:
Jen, I need a sample
of Fromansky's voice.
What's it worth to you?
( chuckles )
Drinks?
I don't think you understand.
FROMANSKY ( on tape ):
Officer in pursuit
of late-model Honda Civic.
Possibly stolen.
Heading northbound
on Koval Lane.
( clicks off tape )
Hold on.
Now, I've got three full minutes
of Officer Fromansky here.
I was thinking of
maybe taking it
to the Dispatch Convention.
Oh, no, no.
Okay, okay.
Drinks at my place.
I can make that dub for you.
What time?
Got a second?
You're a suspect
in an ongoing investigation.
We're not allowed to have
a conversation.
Let me tell you something,
you arrogant clod.
I didn't shoot
your suspects.
Wouldn't waste my life on them.
Well, if that's true,
then your DNA sample
will rule you out.
Someday, you're going to need me
or my buddies at a scene...
and wouldn't
you know it--
we all hit traffic on the way.
Is that how you do your job,
Officer?
Have a safe night.
( multiple voice prints
running )
Officer in pursuit
of late-model Honda Civic...
Just occurred...
I heard shots.
Heading northbound...
Just east of the intersection.
There's been a...
Pitch, speed, volume--
they're all different.
It's not even close.
Maybe he disguised his voice.
There's no
distortion.
Fromansky didn't make that call,
Gris.
The, uh, sweat
from the uniform
not a match
to Officer Fromansky.
You're a hard guy to find.
I messed up, Jim.
I got ahead of the evidence.
I made it personal,
and I don't know why.
We both got a little stubborn.
Did a little head-butting.
I kind of liked it.
You were like
your old self there.
Anyway...
Fromansky was my idea, too.
I still think
it's somebody inside.
Pull off a murder like this,
it takes some practice.
So... one thing I remembered.
About six or seven months ago,
we arrested a couple
of gang-bangers.
They were popping
blackjack dealers
on their way home from work,
taking their toke envelopes.
Because of some
technicality,
Judge Slater
let them walk
right out of the courtroom.
I mean, they were talking
about this
in the precinct for weeks.
Now this morality play
has a very quick
and unhappy ending.
Somebody shot them.
Vigilantes?
Maybe.
But still,
I don't like a cop for this.
So take the cops out.
Who's left?
"All for
Our Country."
That's what
he probably told himself.
Like I told you before,
if you're here for a warrant,
you better have evidence
to back it up.
We're not here
to get a warrant, Judge.
We're here to serve one.
Wayne, you want to tell us
about the game Friday night?
You mean like strategy?
Chalk talk?
Start with the Shirley Temples
and go from there.
( laughs )
You're talking about
those idiots from UNLV.
We have a witness that said
you guys had a beef.
Specifically,
you and Number Seven.
Dude, I don't even
know those guys, okay?
They came in,
they tried to be funny,
and we set
them straight.
How?
Gave them a little talking to.
Any blows exchanged?
Physical contact?
Did that punk bitch rat us out?
It was harmless.
It was nothing.
Punk bitch?
A kid is dead.
What?
Dan O'Hannissey is dead.
I didn't do anything.
Hey, that guy left
before we did, and he was fine.
He was still running his mouth.
I suppose your buddies
will testify to that?
Yeah, they'll testify to that.
Look, you can ask anybody
who was in there.
Interesting ring you've got on.
The SMU Sharks.
That's a college ring.
Mind if I borrow it?
You want to borrow my ring?
Yeah.
Okay.
Take it.
I didn't do anything.
You're not under arrest.
You're free to go.
You have a lot of nerve
walking in my chambers
accusing me of murder.
I'm not accusing you
of murder.
I just want
to see your shoes.
You've a warrant
to search my closet?
We need to see
all your shoes.
That goes for your bailiff
and your clerk as well.
Gentlemen, please
remove your shoes.
I'm sure you'd want
to set an example for all
court employees.
The warrant is limited to me,
my clerk and the bailiff?
The Klinefeld
warrant was generated
from this office,
and only you three had access
to their personal information,
so... yeah.
I look forward to the day
you return
to my courtroom, Detective.
Who issued
the warrant?
Judge Correll.
Good judge.
Always count on him for paper.
Not this pair.
Not those.
You a smoker?
Is that a crime?
It's not good for you.
What tipped you to the ring?
Jaws.
Peter Benchley's Jaws?
No, it was in Steven
Spielberg's Jaws.
They had this mechanical
shark named Bruce.
And he kept swimming
round and round
in circles.
How come?
His dorsal fin was bent.
How did Bruce's
fin get bent?
Same way the kid's ring did.
It hit something.
Don't be pushing, buddy!
Come on!
( cheering )
Come on. Come on!
Come on!
Forget it, man.
You got to be kidding me.
You threw a punch.
Probably a sucker punch.
Look, I told you,
that guy walked away.
But he was already dying.
And you're responsible.
Now who's the punk... bitch?
This is Detective Jim Brass,
Las Vegas Police Department.
Interview Room "A."
I'm with Stuart Gardner,
County Court Clerk.
Please, um,
state your name.
Stuart Gardner.
G-a-r-d-n-e-r.
And spell it for the record.
That's right.
You used to be a cop.
Once a cop, always a cop.
You and I are brothers.
I'm not your brother.
You're a murderer.
I have a warrant
to search these premises.
This is crap.
You can't arrest me.
I'm not here to arrest you.
What, wait a second...
We also found
your old uniform shirt,
with your DNA on the collar.
What are you going to retire on?
Psych? Medical?
What?
Weren't you close to retirement?
After you shot that bystander?
Ah, you want
to talk about me, huh?
You're a clerk.
Get your facts straight.
He wasn't a bystander.
He was a passenger
in a felony pursuit.
So how'd you get promoted
to Captain after that?
Must be my good looks.
You agreed
to drive a desk...
at CSI...
with all the sleazy civilians.
Don't knock the CSI, Stuart.
They put a lot of bad guys away.
You know, I'm going
to give you
a little therapy for free.
You know, if you had only shown
a little restraint,
they would have processed
the DNA after Klinefelds'.
Slam-dunk case.
Lots of guys get off
on slam-dunk cases.
Yeah, I bet you saw
a lot of that working
for Judge Slater,
most liberal judge in the state.
Bet you saw
a lot of good cases go south,
while you just processed
those release forms,
huh?
Let me ask you
something.
Doesn't it piss you off
to put all your hard work
in the hands
of 12 people
too stupid to get
off jury duty?
Stuart, sit down.
WARRICK:
This guy's a nut job
vigilante.
He's making the whole department
look bad.
I guess he'd just figured
he'd take a shortcut.
You've thought about it.
Yeah... lots of times.
What about you?