♪ La, la, la ♪
♪ La, la, la, la, la... ♪
WOMAN:
Some girls want
to be homecoming queen.
Some girls want to be
Miss America.
I have always wanted
to be a showgirl.
I mean, I've been taking dancing
lessons since I was five.
I would, um...
I would pull my leotards
really high up on my hips,
and stick feathers in my hair,
put on my mom's high heels, and
then I would put on this show.
( woman laughs )
FEMALE REPORTER:
This is day six in the search
for Julie Waters,
the model and aspiring showgirl
reported missing by her parents
last Thursday.
Authorities are asking
for the public's help
in any information regarding
her whereabouts.
Where is Julie Waters?
That's the question authorities
are asking...
What is your emergency?
She's so beautiful.
Soft and... sweet...
like an angel.
What is your emergency?
I never meant to hurt her.
Sir?
I couldn't get the smile
off of my face.
I didn't even
see when the security guard
came up to me,
and he told me
that I had to leave.
You know, "All rehearsals
are closed."
So I got up,
and then he turns to me...
SWAT OFFICER:
He's coming out.
Be advised: suspect is armed.
We have visual.
MAN:
Drop the weapon! Freeze! Freeze!
Get on your knees right now!
Right now! Right on your knees!
Look for the girl.
( reporters clamoring )
Captain! Captain!
Captain! Captain Brass!
Where is she?
Huh?
See this face?
I'm going to be all over you
till you give her up.
Jim, the world's watching.
I want him waiting for me.
SWAT cleared the
house. It's empty.
So no girl?
What did he blow?
A .21.
Going to take him
a long time to sober up.
I'm not waiting.
Did he say anything about her?
He never actually
mentioned her name.
All he said was,
"I never meant to hurt her."
Six days missing?
He didn't just hurt her.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
MAN:
At this time,
the Las Vegas Police Department
has in custody
one Howard Delhomme,
whom we believe
to be responsible
for the disappearance
of Julie Waters.
Our forensic team is currently
combing the Delhomme residence
searching for clues
to her whereabouts.
REPORTER:
Sheriff, how long will it take
to find her?
SHERIFF:
I expect an answer to that
just as soon as the team
is finished processing
the house.
Attaboy, Sheriff.
Nothing like predicting
the future.
This guy was unraveling.
WILLOWS:
This is like a timeline:
day one
all the way up
until this morning.
I mean, I've been taking dancing
lessons since I was five.
I would, um...
I would pull my leotards...
More Julie Waters.
...stick feathers in my hair,
put on my mom's high heels...
Media's gone now.
Just you and me.
( sighs )
Where is she?
Nobody calls 911 unless
they're ready to talk.
Tell me.
Get used to this room, bud.
You're not going anywhere.
WILLOWS:
Who reported
Julie Waters missing?
Her mom.
She said she talks
to her every day.
Called the station when she
couldn't reach her by nightfall.
SIDLE:
Grissom sent Nick and I
to her apartment
on the "missing."
Her bills were paid,
ready to mail.
Doesn't look like any
of her toiletries were missing.
She even left
her birth control pills.
Strange.
Her mom said she had dinner
with the producers
of Real Vegas Showgirls.
What's that?
STOKES:
It's a reality-based show
shooting here in Vegas.
What about her car?
It was found four days ago
at Dante's Pizza
on Boulder Highway--
parking lot.
Locked.
No sign of foul play.
Purse?
It's the only thing
that was missing.
What about the drunk guy?
STOKES:
A professional
photographer.
Lives alone.
!
You collected
everything
at his house--
no evidence of Julie?
Although the place was papered
with articles about her,
all acquired after the fact.
( phone ringing )
MAN:
I was following protocol.
BRASS:
Come on, Joe.
I ask you to do
one thing, and
this happens?
I'm sorry, Captain.
I got called away
on a PCP...
Joe.
Where is he?
Getting stitched up,
but he left something for you.
"I'm sorry. I never meant
to hurt anyone."
WILLOWS:
"Anyone"?
What's that supposed to mean?
That Julie Waters
isn't his first victim?
He's done this before?
You want to take him
into the next room, please?
SIDLE:
Look, I know you want
to make this right.
You called 911.
BRASS:
What, do you think you're going
to walk out of here?
You're in
for the long haul.
SIDLE:
If you help me,
I can help you.
We already know
who you're talking about.
All we need to know
is where to find her.
BRASS:
Are we boring you?
Huh?
'Cause what you're not getting
is I got all night.
One of us is getting overtime
to be here, and it isn't you,
so talk to me.
I'll talk... only for the one
in the next room--
the pretty one.
How many yards did you say
it was from mile marker 15?
Why don't you take
off your sunglasses
and your hat?
Need your help here,
Mr. Delhomme.
Howard.
All right.
Are we in the right place?
You walk like a dancer.
Do you moonlight?
I'll bet you're
featured, huh?
High dollar.
Nice long hair
down your back?
What were you wearing
that day, Howard?
I like long hair.
You recognize any
of these rock formations?
You could grow yours
out more, but...
What are we doing?
Is this logical?
We have suspects picking
their criminalists now.
Well, we all want
the same thing, Sara.
Catherine may
have a way in.
It could be helpful.
So this looks
helpful to you?
We're not finding anything.
You said she was here.
I'm getting confused...
all these people here.
You'd be less confused
if it was just you and me?
I see pictures of her
on TV, in the magazines,
the newspapers...
Mr. Delhomme,
we're going
to take you back
to the station.
I'd rather go home.
Not yet.
Hey, uh...
Get in!
we need him in one piece.
All right, at least
we can hold onto him
for a while.
Well, the public defender
may have him out on bail
by tomorrow morning.
Meanwhile, we still
haven't found anything.
Now, did anyone stop
to think this guy
might just be nuts?
Well, until
we find the body,
he is all the evidence
we've got.
We don't even know
if he did it.
Oh, I've got a good feeling
about this.
So does the suspect.
The only reason that
we're out here today
on this wild goose chase
is because he wanted
to hang out with you.
It's weird.
Believe me,
I'd rather follow
the evidence,
but if it takes having
the evidence follow me...
The original
missing persons call
was mine and Sara's.
I'm the senior CSI here.
Uh, I'm the senior CSI here.
You want it?
Hold on, now.
This is a career
case, Grissom.
You know Sara and I both
put in for a promotion.
If we work this, we're on
departmental radar here.
I got the most
high-profile cases
under my belt;
I think that the sheriff
would rest easier
knowing that I was
heading it up.
It's a big department.
There's a lot
of room at the top.
We wouldn't
ask for it
if we couldn't do it.
Fine.
You going to have my back?
I always have your back.
He wanted me. He's got me.
Suspected murderer
Howard Delhomme
led police department personnel
on a fruitless search
for the body of Julie Waters.
The search was called off
in darkness with no indication
that law enforcement personnel
will continue to comb
the Red Rock area.
ATWATER:
Just don't make
me look bad.
Hey, you set the stage.
You know voters--
they like swift
resolutions.
If he's the guy,
I need to say it.
Well, let's find out
if he is the guy first.
Who's that with Cath?
Greg Sanders. DNA.
Is he on the case?
Yeah.
Hell of a time to break out
the "B" team, isn't it?
Remember, we're
looking for anything
this guy did
last Thursday, November 6.
Find out where he was seven days
ago, and we'll find Julie.
So, I know Warrick's off.
And Sara's pissed.
Why not ask Nick to help?
You want to learn.
And you can start
by not repeating my mistakes.
You mean Sam Braun?
I screwed up.
You covered me.
That's why I'm here?
No, you're here
because I want you to be here.
Oh.
He was hungry.
"Big Snax."
The chain.
He bought soda for 75 cents,
snack for 75 cents,
and a household item for $9.99.
Household item?
That could be anything.
Inucci Motors.
He checked out a car
at 2:00 that afternoon,
and returned it the following
morning at 9:00 a.m.
Why would Howard Delhomme
have a receipt
for one of your cars?
We hired him
to photograph it.
Did you instruct him
to hire a model
for the photo shoot?
Model? Never. Nothing
in the photograph
should be sexier
than the automobile.
Where is the car?
It's not just a car.
It's a Maserati.
Well, I appreciate that.
I still need to look at it.
Honey...
the car has been
detailed three times
since Howard
brought it back.
It's getting primed
for a whale tomorrow.
You're wasting
your time.
You know what I did the last
time I looked at a car?
I cut out
a 12-by-12-inch section
of leather from every seat.
Guy was a drug dealer.
You know, a salesman?
I need this car.
Untouched.
Oh, well,
I can't promise you that.
But what I can promise you
is that, for the next few hours,
that car is mine.
Boy, what I could do
with a car like this.
Take these
and compare them
to the toothbrush
that Sara collected
from Julie Waters'
apartment.
Hey...
you want to gawk,
do it on your own time.
You want to work with me,
stay focused.
Got it.
I don't believe this.
What does it matter?
We're all on the same team.
Nick, it was our case.
You said it:
you wait a career
for a case like this.
Put us on
the front line for promotion.
Let's just
find her, okay?
You know what the
worst part about
this whole thing is?
Catherine knows
I can do this case.
So can I.
I would take
you and me
over Catherine and Greg
anytime.
She's got Greg helping her?
Yeah.
Well, the only way to learn
is by getting out in the field.
And, if Greg
helps find her,
I'm okay with that.
The first day that I got here
I went straight
to the Tropicana.
I walked right past
all of the slots and the tables
to the Tiffany Theater.
I snuck in,
and I just sat there
in the back row, just watching.
( sighs )
I couldn't get the smile
off of my face.
( laughs )
I didn't even see
when the security guard
came up to me, and he told me
that I had to leave.
You know,
"All rehearsals are closed."
So I got up.
And then he turns to me,
and he says, um...
"Go ahead and stay."
Is there anything
on these tapes?
Nothing.
How's it going with the sheriff?
He wants
to know why
you're working
with young Greg.
You could have had
Warrick, you know.
Or asked Nick to help.
I need someone
without an agenda.
Like when Fung
brought in Mazzola?
Everybody lost.
This isn't O.J.
Could be.
A trainee on a career case...
I know what I'm doing.
SARA:
12 missing
girls so far
over the last two years--
ten of them found dead.
How many were models?
Just this one.
Robyn Knight.
Day shift found her skeletal
remains six months ago.
Washed up during heavy rains.
Furnace Creek.
Left in the morning
for a photo shoot.
Has a list of photographers
in her day planner.
Guess whose name is on the list?
Howard Delhomme.
Hey.
How's it going?
Your case.
You tell us.
The odometer of the Maserati
had 142 miles on it.
The car dealer
said that
the vehicle only
had nine miles
when Delhomme
picked it up.
That means that Delhomme
drove it for 133 miles.
If you do the math,
that makes
the search radius
approximately 66 miles.
Julie's vehicle was found
in the parking lot
of Dante's Pizza,
off Boulder Highway.
That's what?
12 miles away?
It's probably where
she hooked up with Delhomme.
So they hopped in the car
and went to a photo shoot.
If they did do
a photo shoot,
and we don't even
know that they did.
Where are the photos?
I finished the DNA
from the car.
It matches the reference
Sara got from
Julie's apartment.
And the snack shop?
It's the one on Granite's Pass.
I also found out
what the household item
was on the receipt.
It was a shovel.
He'd already killed her.
That explains the blood
and the hair
in the back seat
of the Maserati.
He drove her body
to the snack bar
and went back
and buried her.
Question is, where?
Robyn Knight washed up
near Furnace Creek.
That's "Devil's Smile."
I understand why
all these cadets are here.
They have to be.
But what's up with all
these off-duty cops?
Chance to be a hero.
Girl's beautiful.
These guys don't
get many chances.
For what?
To rescue a princess.
CADET:
I think we may have
found something!
Hey, hey!
Hold on.
Nobody touch the crime scene.
We do this right.
All right...
I want you to search
every trash can,
drainage ditch, dump site
between here and the city.
We're looking for a shovel,
a purse,
anything else that looks
like it belonged to her.
NICK:
Okay, Greg, diagram
every rock on the pile.
By trial time,
defense will make us
recreate this whole crime scene.
( sighs )
Sleeping beauty.
Julie Waters.
Nature preserved her.
Loose, sandy soil, shady area,
November temperatures--
it was like a freezer.
A girl this beautiful
wouldn't zip
up this far.
She's not wearing
any makeup.
Maybe he cleaned her.
Yeah, and then he used
these rocks to cover her
so that she wouldn't
wash up in a storm
the way the other girl did.
What other girl?
We think there
may be a connection
to the Robyn Knight case
from last year.
Can we prove it?
Well, only skeletal remains
were found.
There's nothing definitive
to connect Delhomme
to the murder.
Then we better
make this one stick.
BRASS:
You lost your
bargaining chip.
We found her body.
And smart, too.
MAN:
I advise you
to remain silent.
Howard,
just help us with one thing.
How did this happen?
BRASS:
You're pretty
composed, Howard.
I mean, you kill her,
you go buy a
shovel, a soda.
It's thirsty work,
digging a grave, huh?
That's not how it happened.
I understand.
Photographer. Model.
Had to get the light just right.
I'd like to photograph you.
Mmm... can't do anything
until we figure this out.
It was an accident.
I wanted to move
the car... and I didn't see her.
Why was she even there?
Miss Waters had modeled
for my client
on previous occasions.
Well, the problem
I have with that
is the dealer representative
specifically stated
that no model was hired
to appear in the photos.
I was shooting...
new head shots for her.
She was all out.
It was a favor.
I'm a professional.
Ask any of my models.
So, you took photographs
of Julie?
A couple of rolls.
Any idea where they are?
Mmm... no.
Well, if
you remember,
let me know.
Okay.
She has no injuries
consistent with a car accident.
Cause of death
is, uh, positional asphyxia.
( screaming )
Guy we're looking
at was 180-plus.
Sufficient weight.
He must have hit her, which
ripped her earring out.
Occurred antemortem.
Close to time of death.
Only bleeding injury.
Was there any evidence
of sexual assault?
Lots of trauma.
Collected a kit.
Anything else?
Yeah, tox came back
with a blood alcohol
content of .18.
On the day of her dinner
with the producers
of Real Vegas Showgirls,
she'd be like Dorothy
racing for Oz.
There's no way that
she slowed down to get drunk.
Decomposing blood can generate
ethanol postmortem.
As the cell walls lyse
and contact
with the sugar in alcohol,
bacterial growth
produces the byproducts
of carbon dioxide and ethanol.
It's inexact, but the body's
capable of producing
somewhere around .08 grams
percent on its own.
But in order to have
a postmortem level of .18...
Well, she had a head start.
So, that's three shots
in an hour?
He could have forced
her to drink.
Robbins rushed
the protocol.
Released Julie's
body to her parents.
So they could take
her home to Provo.
Mmm.
Thousands of girls come
to Vegas every year
just hoping to
beat the odds.
Mmm. Some of them do.
And some of them don't.
Multiple abrasions
on her cervix.
Sexual assault kit had no semen,
no trace evidence.
So, it's possible he used
a foreign object on her.
Now I'm confused.
Julie Waters died
of positional asphyxia.
That means that someone
sat on her chest, and...
two years ago, you were arrested
for forced oral cop.
You don't think I'd ever do
something like that, do you?
My client went to trial
and was found
not guilty.
HOWARD:
I liked Julie.
I took a lot
of photographs of her.
Even Julie's mother said
that no one ever captured her
on film the way I did.
Just one
more thing
from the autopsy report.
Julie was drinking.
She wanted to loosen up,
you know?
( laughing )
You got what you needed.
Now, get what you want.
Come on.
She never said stop.
Why didn't you
tell me this before?
I was afraid
of what you'd think of me.
The sheriff has tried my client
in the media.
But, right now, evidence that
will exonerate Howard Delhomme
from these false charges
is being handed over
to the authorities.
RECEPTIONIST:
CSI Willows,
you have a visitor
at the front desk.
Willows, you have a visitor...
My brother sent
this to me,
and his attorney told
me to give it to you.
Just set it on the counter.
Could you please get me
a pair of gloves
and an evidence bag?
Sure.
Thanks.
I can show you what's in there.
Okay.
When did
you get this?
Today.
It was mailed
two days ago.
There's no
return address.
How do you know
your brother sent this?
That's his handwriting.
Was there a note
in the envelope?
Yeah. Uh...
"If I get arrested..."
Now, why would he think that?
How are these supposed
to help him beat a murder rap?
I'm guessing
he's trying to
create an alibi.
Four rolls,
all of Julie.
Something's
off, though.
White shoes,
black stockings,
and all ripped up.
Not to mention these
aren't the clothes
that we found her in.
Now, what is this?
It's a nude.
Is that Julie's body?
If it is,
it's a double exposure.
I'll have to get them printed
to be sure.
Cadet got a hit
off a trash can.
I brought it in.
You want me to get Greg?
Archie, let me know when
you've got these printed up.
Yeah.
There's a lot
of head shots here.
WILLOWS:
Here's our little lie.
Delhomme said that he took her
out to photograph her
because she had
no more head shots.
Needed new ones.
Explains how he cleaned her up.
Doesn't explain why.
Here's her day planner.
There's only
two things written
in her book the day
she disappeared--
Real Vegas Showgirl
producer's dinner 7:00 p.m."
And the other--
"Meet Howard,
Dante's Pizza, 2:00 p.m."
That would have given her
plenty of time
to get back
for the producer's dinner.
Here's her clothes.
First thing you learn
as a model--
bring several outfits with you.
You never know what
the photographer might like.
Here's our big lie.
Delhomme said
when she injured her earlobe,
she was in
her underwear
and she was barefoot.
I think Howard's
been lying to you.
$65? Ooh.
Capital investment.
Our victim hadn't made
it to the show yet.
Her life was all
about after the show.
The right guy,
the right meal,
and, after that...
It's a tough way to get ahead.
Did your father ever tell you
you were pretty?
I guess.
He ever tell you
you were smart?
Yeah.
So, it probably
never occurred to you
that you wouldn't be successful.
If all you
ever hear
is that you're gorgeous,
you can let everything else
fall away, and it can leave you
in a very dangerous place.
All right,
the bloodstain
on the top of the foot
is round.
Gravitational.
On the bottom of the foot,
it's smeared.
There's no blood in these.
She wasn't wearing them.
The only way
we can get this guy
is if the evidence counters
every one of his lies.
That matches the drop
on the top of
her stocking.
Separate bloodstain.
Separate drop.
She was standing.
And there was no one
to help her.
This is from the
fifth roll of film
Delhomme took
with your vic.
STOKES:
It's a double exposure.
It's two separate images.
Separate them.
Do you have Catherine's
crime scene photos
of the car?
Mm-hmm.
Just give me
the instrument panel
and put it side-by-side
with the double-exposed
instrument panel.
( beep )
Now just the speedometers.
Does that look like
the same car to you?
SIDLE:
She looks fine here.
And here, it's like
she's not quite sure
what's going on.
Then here, uh...
She knew.
We have
looked through every piece
of evidence on this case.
Whatever caused
these abrasions is gone.
Well, it's got to be here.
We found this guy in pieces,
and he's been
putting himself together
ever since.
If we don't find something,
he's going to walk out of here
and forget about this
like a bad dream.
Hey, y'all.
I got something
on the double-exposed
roll of film.
WILLOWS:
The odometers
don't match.
STOKES:
No, on the left is you.
Crime scene photo
from the Maserati.
What about
the other one?
Well, it's unknown.
Must have used a picture
he already had
for the double
exposure.
Guys, if it's a different car,
maybe it's a different girl.
WILLOWS:
What's on the rest of
the double-exposed roll?
A female body, naked.
No face to go
with an ID.
Archie, do you have
the SART photos
from the autopsy?
Yeah.
We need to
compare bodies.
Uh... why don't you guys
take a break?
Uh... it's okay.
These photos don't bother me.
They bother me.
Well?
The naked pictures
weren't of Julie.
So, what? Delhomme fakes
a bunch of nude pictures
and sends them to his brother?
At this point, I don't
care why he did it.
What do you have?
Nothing.
Absolutely nothing.
If he raped her
with a foreign object,
it is not on this table.
Do you want me
to leave you alone
so you can do it yourself?
Look, the entire lab didn't need
to see pictures
of Julie's vagina
plastered all over the screen.
So, Nick and I
are the whole lab now?
That's not it,
Catherine, and you know it.
I saw the look in Howard's eye.
I used to make my living
off that look.
He wanted me.
We needed him.
I decided
to exploit that situation.
And, as angry as
that made you,
when you're in my shoes,
you'll do the same thing.
I already checked that.
We're looking
at the wrong evidence.
His initial arrest was
for brandishing a firearm.
I fired my lawyer.
We waiting on a new one?
No.
( dropping papers on table )
Is that what you like?
Being alone with a woman?
( laughing )
One like you.
Take her out
in the middle of nowhere.
You know, I think I got to go.
Howard, it's getting late.
I got to go.
I have a meeting
back in town.
She posed naked for me.
My brother gave you
the pictures.
I never forced her
to do anything.
You slapped her.
( screaming )
Then you violated her.
No more pictures.
( whimpering )
Julie Waters' cervical tissue
was on your gun sight.
What's the matter?
Couldn't swallow it
when you saw her
all over the TV?
( loud grunt )
God.
You bitch.
You... bitch!
( panting )
FEMALE REPORTER:
Prosecutors will seek
a life sentence
without the possibility
of parole for Howard Delhomme
in the murder of Julie Waters.
GRISSOM:
You did good, Cath.
I had help.
How are things with you
and Nick and Sara?
They're good.
They're pros.
This case has been one
of the most high-profile
in this reporter's memory.
Never before have I seen...
All he had to do was stay quiet.
Unlike Robyn Knight,
Julie Waters became Las Vegas'
postmortem sweetheart.
...and beautiful
Julie Waters...
The media as moral conscience.
She couldn't get away
from him.
Then he couldn't get away
from her.
I think that is why
I would be perfect
for your show.
Well, at least,
that's what my dad thinks.
He always says, "Julie,
people can't help but love you."
And it's true.