MAN:
Thank you.
Have a good night.
Eagles covered, bruh.
Cough up the 20.
Man, backdoor touchdown.
Man, kills you every time.
Ha-ha!
Alright no more martini's for you.
Welcome to the Orpheus.
You checking in
or just donating?
Checking in.
Any bags, sir?
I got this one.
Grab the one in the trunk.
( screaming, glass shattering)
( clamoring, screaming )
( siren wails )
Car bomb.
Driver and valet are dead.
Another valet
is critical.
Got at least a dozen injured.
I was having dinner here.
Was on my way out.
It'd gone off
a couple of seconds later,
you'd be picking my badge up
off the ground.
Thank God you're all right.
Sheriff, did they, uh, sweep
the area for secondaries?
Bomb squad says
it's all clear.
We'll photo-document the scene.
Overalls from all angles.
Aerials as well.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
Guess it wasn't a sniper.
Fixed ammunition
in the trunk.
The gunpowder
must have
heated up, and the,
uh, rounds cooked off.
( rapid gunfire )
I'm going to start marking
the evidence.
I believe the, uh,
glass pressure
traveled from the
rear of the vehicle,
through the front...
...and evidently separated
the driver's body at the ankles.
David, we have body
parts in the car.
I've been looking
for the feet.
I found 'em.
We gotta ID the driver ASAP.
Well, the VIN number's
still attached.
Write that down.
Call in the DMV.
Yes, sir.
Sorry, Catherine.
Traffic's backed up all
the way to the Strip.
Got a SIG-Sauer.
Probably the driver's.
I'll start bagging.
Gather the detritus and separate
out the bomb components.
Okay.
( tires screech )
GRISSOM:
Here's press.
You're on.
Wish I could help, but, uh,
I got a vehicle to process.
Come on, Grissom--
a bomb goes off these days,
they're going to assume
it's a hit.
What are you thinking?
I'm not thinking.
I'm just looking.
That's good.
Can I use that?
Amelia Rueben. 25.
She a guest?
Or a guest of a guest?
Myles Rueben's wife.
SIDLE:
Who found her?
About 40 minutes ago,
a maid walked in
for "turn-down" service.
Called hotel security.
Still on a timer.
Got a wine glass.
Does Myles know?
He's still onstage.
( audience cheering )
♪ Hold up, slow to row ♪
♪ Let's lay low
before you go too far ♪
♪ Remember who you are ♪
♪ Why you want to start
givin' me the third degree ♪
♪ All of this
responsibility... ♪
Got a wine bottle.
Almost empty.
♪ Love ain't gonna get me
till I know I'm ready... ♪
Alcohol.
Hot tub.
A little bit too relaxed.
♪ ...that you see ♪
♪ You see ♪
♪ Just a part of me ♪
♪ Just a part of me... ♪
ROBBINS:
Temperature of the spa water
makes liver temp
irrelevant.
But given the redness
of her eyes,
I'd estimate she's been dead
less than an hour.
♪ You're having visions of
happy ever after, lost in love ♪
♪ Why you want the rush ♪
♪ Why you want the rush ♪
♪ But yeah, I care for you ♪
♪ But I can't trust my heart
the way that you do ♪
♪ 'Cause when it comes
to love... ♪
BROWN:
It just dawned on me
what's Rueben's biggest hit was.
What's that?
"Amelia."
♪ Girl,
love ain't gonna get me ♪
♪ Gonna get me ♪
♪ Till I know I'm ready ♪
♪ You think you know me ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ But I'm hopin' that you see♪
♪ You see ♪
♪ Just a fantasy... ♪
I'll handle this when Myles
breaks for the encore.
Been the kid's manager
since '97.
♪ But I'm hopin'
that you see... ♪
I should be the one
to tell him.
♪ Just a part of me ♪
♪ I'm always gonna be ♪
♪ Just a fantasy ♪
♪ A fantasy. ♪
( cheering and applause )
How was that, Sam?
Sound good?
Great, Myles.
The best.
What?
What's wrong?
I missed
a high note, huh?
Man...
No, no, no.
Everything
sounded great.
Listen, Myles,
these are
crime scene investigators.
Myles, uh...
there's been
an accident.
An accident?
What, is it
my mother?
Did-did something happen
back East?
No, no, no.
Your mother's fine.
Look, Myles, it's, uh...
Mr. Rueben,
I'm very sorry
to have to tell you this,
but your wife is dead.
AUDIENCE ( chanting ):
Amelia! Amelia!
( chanting continues )
Turn the houselights up, Sam.
There's no encore tonight.
I heard about the bombing.
I'm here to help.
I located the seat
of the explosion.
The bomb was attached
to the fuel tank.
Gas-enhanced.
Bomber maximized his bang.
You really want to help,
climb under here
and find the initiation switch.
SANDERS:
Got a stray wire.
Leading away from the gas tank,
right into the center
of the dash.
Nowhere near the loom.
GRISSOM:
The digital clock
was the switch.
It was time-activated.
What's next?
Nick has to reconstruct
the bomb.
STOKES:
It was a pipe bomb.
Initiated by a
lightbulb filament.
Bomb was attached
to the fuel tank.
There were still magnet
and solder fragments
attached to the pipe.
Did you find any kind
of timing device?
Digital clock in the dash.
What about the type
of explosive used?
Not yet.
I was about to analyze
the chemical residue
left on the bomb frags.
Be sure to do an organics
and inorganics test.
Will do.
So...
what does it all mean?
What does what all mean?
Don't play dumb with me, Gil.
Explosions
lead the news.
I need to know who,
and I need to know why.
Well, the evidence is only
teaching us about the bomb,
not the bomber.
What about a signature?
Is there anything distinct,
unusual about this
particular bomb?
No.
Nothing.
ROBBINS:
Amelia Rueben didn't drown.
If she had,
there'd be fluid
in her nasal sinuses.
Clear as a bell.
What was the cause
of death?
Cardiac arrest.
She was only 25.
Was there some kind of defect?
No, her heart was
in perfect condition.
In fact, I have it over here.
See the myocardium?
There's no evidence
of hemorrhage,
infarct or scarring.
No coronary occlusions.
I can't explain it.
It's like a mystery
of the heart.
DAWSON:
So, that SIG-Sauer
you found...
Yes.
Relatively nondescript.
Uh, the blue stuff,
sent a sample to Trace.
Pretty sure
it's from some sort of bag
that melted in the explosion.
Right. And the bullets
from the Camaro's trunk?
A-ha.
Pre-fragmented ammo.
Now they're unique.
Exemplar's
under the magnifier.
Copper jacket
contains lead shot
sealed with a clear
epoxy plug.
I've never seen anything
like that.
It's designed
to enter a target,
but not exit.
( gunshot )
( bullet impacts )
Penetration, not perforation.
Why?
Well, say you're
on a commercial flight.
Plane gets hijacked.
US Air Marshal needs
to take down the hijacker...
But not the plane.
Nowadays, MagSafes
are sold commercially,
but there's really
not much of a market.
So chances are, your driver's
a Federal Air Marshal.
( computer bleeps )
It's a match.
Print on the hot tub dial
was Sam Hopkins.
Rueben's manager?
Amelia was butt-naked
in the hot tub.
What was he doing in her room
tweaking dials?
While her husband's onstage?
Spectroscopy just got back.
Hydrofluoric acid in her system.
Isn't that
an industrial solvent?
High-powered stuff.
Mainly used to remove rust,
clean glass, brighten aluminum,
dissolve silicas...
and commit murder.
She was poisoned.
That would explain
her heart attack.
You're killing me, Jimmy.
You're killing me.
All night the spotlight was off.
Way too hot on his face.
It's too hot on me right now.
They guy's not Wayne Newton,
all right?
Can you see it
on my face, Jim?
I need... Jimmy.
Thank...
I need a cast shadow on him
for all the love songs.
Mr. Hopkins, could you answer
the question, please.
Sorry.
Yes, I was in Amelia's room.
I'm in there all the time.
We're like family.
We know you were close.
Do you always turn on
the hot tub for her?
I represent one of the biggest
headliners in town.
Wear a lot of hats:
Manager, marriage
counselor, confidante.
I kept Myles happy
by keeping her happy.
HOPKINS:
Amelia,
anything else I can get for you?
Look, sweetheart.
Here's how this works.
You give him his space,
he sings his heart out.
Honey, we all prosper.
Let me set up a dinner
for you two--
quiet, alone-- after the show.
No work.
Never happen.
Relax.
Give me an hour.
But you must admit,
the boss' wife,
naked in a hot tub,
looks kind of funky.
Look at me.
Do I look like a threat?
The reason I've succeeded
in this business,
I don't squat where I eat,
you know what I mean?
All right,
let's talk about drinking.
There was a bottle of wine
found near the tub.
Did you have a drink with her?
No. Never.
I don't touch it.
I'm on call 24/7.
Myles can pick up the phone,
have me do anything, anytime.
Fly to L.A.,
pick someone up at the airport.
So, you'd do just about anything
for him then?
When it comes to Myles, yeah.
What's this all about?
Mr. Hopkins,
Amelia didn't drown.
She was poisoned.
Poisoned? By who?
That's what we're trying
to find out.
BRASS:
According to the DMV,
the Camaro was one of yours,
is that right?
Yeah, it was rented
to an Adam Watson.
Waived insurance.
Government discount.
Well, we have reason
to believe
Mr. Watson
was a US Air Marshal.
Right. How could I forget him?
He threw it in my face
when I told him
we were out of compacts.
I'm a US Air Marshal, okay?
I travel for a living.
I don't need this crap.
But you found him a car.
I'll put you in a full-size
and won't charge you
for the difference.
No, forget it.
I'll take the Camaro.
What time was that?
Vehicle entered the lot
at 9:31 p.m.
Mr. Watson drove out
nine minutes later.
Thanks a lot.
Guy worked for
Homeland Security.
You think maybe
some terrorist blew him up?
You'll be the first to know.
Well, it's been confirmed.
The driver, Adam Watson,
was a Federal Air Marshal.
So, one of us
needs to call the sheriff.
I'll flip you for it.
Well, before we make that call,
what time did the Air Marshal
drive off the lot?
9:40. Why?
Well, the bomb went
off 30 minutes later.
It takes that long to get
from here to the Orpheus.
So you're saying the bomb
was already in the car
when he drove out?
Well, that can't be.
According to the manager,
the Camaro was only in the lot
for, uh, nine minutes.
Well, it takes longer than
that to hard-wire a bomb.
Which can only mean that the
bomb was already in the car
when it was returned.
So, who rented the car
before him?
BRASS:
Roger Dunbar! Open up!
Las Vegas Police!
Clear.
Stand down.
Good job, guys.
Okay, well.
This guy was obviously
on a week-to-week lease.
WILLOWS:
Left some clothes behind...
and a paper shredder.
No sign
of any bomb-making material.
I'll go check the garage.
WILLOWS:
"Dr. Amerian, 4:00 p.m."
Oh, today.
I'll make an appointment.
You drag me out
of my dentist's office.
You throw me in a squad car.
Now you're accusing me
of planting a car bomb?
Mr. Dunbar, you rented a Camaro
from Thrift Rite Rental.
Returned it last
night, 9:30 p.m.
It blew up a half an hour later
in front of the Orpheus.
It's all over the news.
That was my Camaro?
Yes.
But this is crazy.
So, what happened?
You have a beef
with the rental car company?
No. I-I get double miles.
I'm a Premier Card member.
Oh, I'm sure you are.
You know what,
I'm not saying another word
without an attorney.
That's your right, Mr. Dunbar.
Warrant for your clothes.
Strip.
Everything in the bag.
ID'd the explosive.
Ammonium perchlorate.
Yeah, rocket fuel.
GCMS picked up the other half
of the equation-- gasoline.
Combination of the two
creates an unstable mass.
Both shock-
and friction-sensitive.
Ammonium perchlorate's available
at any chemical supply store.
You can gas up on every corner.
Anyone could've made this bomb.
Sheriff?
What can we do for you?
Need a little clarification.
I know Captain Brass
has a suspect in custody.
Where it get
a little hazy for me,
is I'm not getting his
connection to the Air Marshal.
Well, it's entirely possible
that Mr. Watson was just in the
wrong place at the wrong time.
Another thing, you said that
the switch was a digital clock.
The bomb had been set to go off
at a designated time, right?
How do we get
a wrong time?
I can answer that, too.
Take a look.
Short in the wire.
Compromised the
timing device.
Made the bomb
unpredictable.
We may never know when that bomb
was supposed to explode.
I got your page.
You'd be a good maitre d'.
Checking glassware for spots?
You know, a hot tub is just like
a dishwasher.
Washes away
all of the impurities.
Including hydrofluoric acid,
huh?
'93 Pinot.
( French accent ):
Either it was a bad year
for wine
or a bad year for Amelia.
I found trace amounts
of hydrofluoric acid
in the vino.
So, somebody did spike the wine.
Oui.
BROWN:
We just want to know what
happened the other night.
Did you open the
bottle for her?
MAN:
Hey, Amelia requested me.
I was up there every night.
I hooked her up.
And she wasn't drinking
no Italian rotgut either.
She was ordering '93 Pinot
from Russian River Valley.
That's 350 a bottle,
20% delivery charge.
You do the math.
Was anyone there with her?
No.
What about Sam Hopkins?
No, that mutt wasn't there.
"Mutt"?
Yeah, that manager scumbag.
You bring a bottle of wine when
he's there, forget about it.
He signs for the bill
and stiff city.
Now, when the Prince of Soul
is there,
that's a different story.
He'd give you $500
just to get lost.
But you didn't see Myles
the other night?
Yeah, I saw him for a sec.
He came in between shows.
He showed me the door.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
My man.
There's only one man
who practices chivalry
around here,
and it ain't you, Ducky.
Hey, I could tell
they were in love, you know?
But he was never around.
I mean,
I felt bad for Amelia.
She'd have me up three,
four times a night.
"You forgot the fork.
Can you bring some salt?
How about some ice?"
If you ask me,
I'd say she was lonely.
Did you ever see them fight?
No, but I heard 'em.
And I'm sure 2202
and 2206 heard 'em, too.
Hey, but I don't bite
the hand that feeds me.
Thanks.
There was rocket fuel
in the bomb
and rocket fuel on your T-shirt.
That you need to explain.
Well, I'm not really
sure, but my son,
he's got this
science project due.
You're right,
I'm not supposed to help,
but, really, all the parents do.
We made a volcano.
Spilled some of the chemicals.
( sizzling )
( gurgling )
( clatters )
We've been to your apartment.
What volcano? What kid?
Timmy. Third grade.
Mesquite Elementary.
You're divorced?
No.
No, well, look,
here's the situation
is the family,
they live in Mesquite,
and I'm there on the weekends.
And during the week?
I-I'm in sales,
so I travel
all over the country.
Which is why he rents a car
when he's in town.
It's cheaper than leasing.
Cheaper.
All right, but it still doesn't
explain the empty apartment.
Look, I... like being married.
I... love my wife,
my kid,
but... I need my space.
I don't want to hurt
anyone's feelings,
so I just tell them
that I'm out of town
even when I'm not.
We're going to need
your home address.
No, look...
I'm begging you.
Please don't blow things for me
with the wife.
Mom, what's going on?
I don't understand.
Mrs. Dunbar, could you and
your son wait outside, please?
Ma'am, come
with me.
I'll fill you in.
Catherine, there is a volcano
on the table.
Aluminum powder.
Polyvinylbutadiene.
Ammonium perchlorate.
The three ingredients
to make lava flow.
In fifth grade,
I built one of these
as my science fair project.
It was awesome.
First place should've been mine.
But they ended up giving it
to this kid with some lame
red ant colony.
That was you.
Yeah, only my ants
were Black Argentinians.
Uh-huh.
I learned at a very early age
that the bugs always win.
Right.
Trust me, Roger
didn't build a bomb.
I love my husband,
but he's inept.
Just last week,
the hose bib
cracked.
Front yard was a river.
Roger was helpless
till I got home.
Well, what about that volcano?
Your husband said
that he helped
your son build it.
He watched.
I'm a teacher.
Timmy knows which parent
to go to for help.
Mrs. Dunbar, your husband
told us that he was in sales.
He's with the State Department.
You know, all
that sensitive
government stuff.
Keeps him on the road.
He doesn't say much about it.
As far as you know,
has he talked about his job
with anyone else?
Any other family members?
Friends?
His parents are dead.
Roger's an only child.
He doesn't have
time for friends.
There was this one night,
years ago.
We were both a little drunk
and...
Roger confessed he was CIA.
Hey, I made one of those
in third grade.
Science fair.
Should have won, too.
Got to let it go, Nick.
Bomb end-cap with tool marks.
Given the orientation
and spread of the marks,
consistent with pliers,
vise-grips.
There were no vise-grips
in the Dunbars' toolbox.
But given that the bomb
and the volcano
were similarly
constructed...
We can compare the tool marks
on both end-caps.
Doesn't matter what you make;
it's what you make it with.
Not even close.
Mm-mm.
So, whatever tool
made the volcano
did not make the bomb.
Okay, I reconstructed
the contents of
the paper shredder.
Five bills.
All in Roger Dunbar's name.
Addressed to 2175 La Pressa.
Mm-hmm.
His apartment.
Okay, top two are
credit card bills.
Both VISA.
Separate accounts.
WILLOWS:
Roger A. Dunbar.
Roger B. Dunbar.
That's an easy way
to separate out expenses.
Check out the gas bills.
Three different meters.
2175 La Pressa.
822 Devon, Mesquite.
1845 Galewood, Henderson.
Hey, got the DNA results back
from that bloody
Band-Aid
that Grissom found
at Dunbar's apartment.
Compared it to his DNA.
Not a match.
But I did find
seven alleles in common.
His son.
No. It's female.
Mother, sister, daughter.
Well, according to his wife,
his mother's deceased.
He's an only child.
So, that leaves a daughter.
Well, there's no way there
was a kid at that apartment.
Well, maybe she was living
in Henderson.
Forget "secret agent."
Roger Dunbar was living
a secret life.
Can I help you?
Good evening.
We're with the Las
Vegas Crime Lab.
Oh, God.
Did something happen
to my husband?
He was supposed to be home
on Monday night.
I've been calling his cell.
He's not at work.
Is this your husband?
Yes.
You're currently
married to him?
Yes. What is going on?
WILLOWS:
Well, your husband is a suspect
in a criminal
investigation.
Currently, he's
in police custody.
GRISSOM:
Mrs. Dunbar?
Do you have a daughter?
Amy.
Is she entered
in the science fair?
You can't take it.
Amy, did you use this the tool
to work on the inside
of your volcano?
Yeah, my dad did.
He helped you build it?
Yeah.
I teach yoga.
I have no idea
how this works.
It was all Roger.
When's your science fair?
Friday.
Well, we'll do our best
to get this back to you
by Friday, okay?
Okay.
BROWN:
Which side do you want?
SIDLE:
I'll take the west wing.
It's a nice place.
Uh-huh.
You could record a whole album
in this studio.
This guy's got it made.
The life of a celebrity.
( plays jazz riff )
I don't know, I think
it sounds kind of isolating,
living in a fishbowl.
Wouldn't be isolated.
You'd have a butler, a maid
service, laundry service.
Sheet music.
Guy writes his own stuff.
Dishwashing gloves.
Dry erase markers.
Slate Industrial Glass Cleaner.
The ingredients--
distilled water
and hydrofluoric acid.
Fatal if swallowed.
You're sure you want to waive
your right to an attorney?
I got nothin' to hide.
Do you recognize this product?
Yeah.
I use it to clean my windows.
Don't you have a maid or someone
to do that for you?
I write songs late at night.
Windows are my chalkboard.
♪ Only what you feel ♪
♪ Now I can... ♪
♪ Clearly see... ♪
Mr. Rueben...
your wife was poisoned.
We suspect window cleaner
was slipped into her wine.
It can't be.
I was there.
I opened that wine.
Did you have a fight?
Not lately.
But you have had fights
in the past.
Who doesn't?
I mean, fighting, loving,
laughing... it all comes
from the same place, man.
It's passion.
And we loved each other
passionately.
When we met, it was fate.
But you know
what I need right now?
I need a woman.
I need a woman to come up here
and be my inspiration.
You, baby.
Second row.
Come on up here.
♪ I can see by the love
in your eyes ♪
♪ You've been hurt by love ♪
♪ So it's hard for you
to trust a guy... ♪
I was looking for love.
She was looking
for the same thing.
She loved my music.
I loved her smile.
It's hard being on top,
you know?
I mean,
everybody loves you.
Wants their piece.
That's why we fought.
The time.
She knew she could never
have me to herself.
Look, I got sound check
for the late show in an hour.
Can I go?
Sure.
We might want to talk
to you later.
Wife's been dead
less than 48 hours.
Well, there's a man
who definitely has
his priorities straight.
Okay, three people have admitted
to being with Amelia
the night that she died.
The room service waiter,
Myles, and Myles's manager.
Room service guy's out.
He left before the cork
was popped.
So, did Myles kill Amelia and
the manager's covering for him
or did the manager kill Amelia
and Myles doesn't have a clue?
BRASS:
Bigamy is a Class D Felony.
If convicted,
you could be sentenced
from one to four years
in prison, do
you know that?
I'd just married Beth,
when I met Debbie.
She was a student.
UNLV.
She got pregnant.
I did the right thing.
Ever since, it's been
Monday through Friday
with Debbie
and weekends with Beth.
They both think I travel
for a living.
I know I keep
coming back to this,
but, uh...
I mean, I got to ask you.
What's with the empty apartment?
Do you have a girlfriend
on the side as well?
No.
Just tell them the truth.
My life is really
a balancing act.
Early on,
I took Debbie to dinner
and Beth saw it
on a credit card statement.
So instead of a P.O. Box,
I figured why not rent
a cheap apartment, you know?
Have a night to myself
once in a while.
We found a Band-Aid with
your daughter Amy's blood
at your apartment.
So, you bring your daughter
there, but not your wives?
Oh, no.
It's not like that.
You know how kids are.
Dad, take this.
It keeps falling off.
I emptied my pockets
at the apartment.
Mr. Dunbar, we collected
both of your
children's volcanoes
and supplies.
And we found a pair of pliers
at your home in Henderson.
Those pliers were used to make
both of the volcanoes.
That's right.
I needed pliers in Henderson,
so I borrowed Beth's pliers
from Mesquite.
There's no crime in that.
I'm just really confused.
Um... your wife, Beth, told us
that you couldn't build
a volcano to save your soul.
Yet your wife, Debbie, claims
that it was all you that made
your daughter's volcano.
So, what is it?
Well, I watched Beth
when she made Timmy's volcano.
So, then when Amy had
a science project,
I knew the drill.
Now, granted, it wasn't
as symmetrical as Beth's
and the lava flow
was a little anemic,
but... Amy liked it.
When did you borrow
those pliers?
I don't know.
Couple weeks ago.
Why?
You never returned them
to your wife, Beth?
I've been meaning to do that.
Same characteristics.
We got a match.
Take her in.
I got prints.
I've got burns.
You first.
Sam or Myles?
Amelia's.
Well, you're
just in time.
She gets shipped in an hour.
This should just
take a second.
Could you give me
her right hand, please?
SARA:
Three acid burns.
This is not a murder.
It's a suicide.
I knew she wasn't happy.
I guess I just
didn't pay attention.
You shouldn't blame
yourself for this.
Shouldn't I? Why shouldn't I?
I spend most of my time
making them happy.
I never...
I never took the time
to make her happy.
( chanting ):
Amelia, Amelia!
What do you
want to do, kid?
The show must go on, right?
It's your call.
( chanting continues )
( cheering )
♪ Amelia ♪
♪ Ooh, Amelia ♪
♪ Oh, Amelia ♪
♪ I see the love
in your eyes... ♪
CATHERINE:
We found these pliers
in your car's glove box.
You used them
to fix the faucet.
And to...
make a bomb.
Mrs. Dunbar...
how long have
you known
about Roger's double life?
His other wife's name is Debbie.
Once or twice a year
he'd call me by that name.
I ignored it.
It's very difficult
for two people to live a lie,
let alone three.
Look, when Roger and I
were together,
he was a good husband.
Terrific father.
It was almost like
being in a state of
suspended honeymoon.
Really?
So what changed?
He asked me
to get his dirty laundry
out of the trunk of his car.
There was a plastic bag with
all the makings of a volcano.
Including the stars I had
hand-cut for my son.
I'd always suspected
there was another woman,
but never...
another family.
Two weeks ago Sunday,
I followed him.
He, uh, dropped off
his rental car and walked
to some apartment
building.
Then he changed
his clothes,
and got into a nicer car,
and drove out to Henderson.
Why didn't you just leave him?
Turn him in?
He made a fool out of me.
A mockery of our life.
Mrs. Dunbar, you killed
three innocent people.
That was never my intention.
That bomb was supposed
to go off at 8:30.
On his way to the airport.
Why a bomb?
It, it's not much harder
to make a bomb than a volcano.