♪ ♪
( "Chariots of Fire" plays )
( music continues )
What the hell kind
of music is that?
Inspiration.
Sedative.
Okay.
( changes radio station )
( country music playing )
How's this?
How about something
that doesn't twang?
( changes radio station )
♪ I said are you gonna
be my girl? ♪
Better.
( rock music playing )
♪ One, two, three,
take my hand and come with me ♪
♪ Because you look so fine ♪
♪ That I really wanna
make you mine ♪
♪ I say you look so fine... ♪
Grissom!
( panting ):
Grissom.
What, are you taking a leak?
The follow car is supposed
to stay with the runner.
We've been training
for months, man.
20 CSIs.
120 miles.
Don't blame me.
Blame him.
I saw his flasher
from the road.
Good call.
Got a cut
on his forehead.
Looks fresh.
But usually takes
a couple of days
for the corneas
to cloud over.
The race just started.
L.A. County PD.
Special Enforcement Squad.
Badass.
Hardcore badass.
Give me some more light here.
That looks like
a recent injury.
There's no scab.
Fight?
Maybe.
Would you give me your phone?
( phone beeps )
Uh...
Uh, this is CSI Willows.
I'm at Highway 160,
halfway through Leg 16
of the Desert Relay.
We got a 419, officer down.
Notify Captain Brass.
Barehanded, huh?
Well, collect it or lose it.
Ten years ago nobody would've
known the difference.
Ten years ago
we wouldn't have been able
to get DNA off that fiber.
I'll find something
in the car to bindle it.
Time of discovery: 4:32.
I'll put it in the report.
( exhales )
So much for the race.
Well,
at least we didn't come in last.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
So much for
that shoe print.
This could be blood
on this rock.
How many cops are in
town this weekend?
20,000.
And the road is closed
to civilians.
Spring break with a badge.
Well, this
ought to be fun.
Every suspect's
in law enforcement.
So, how was your run?
I'm still alive.
That's everything.
ATM receipt.
No card, no cash?
Well, he was in a race.
Maybe someone
took his wallet.
So, Lieutenant Mendez,
tell me about your teammate.
Tim Coleman.
Newest boot. Two months in.
Came right out of patrol.
Best cop at Carson Station.
Well, I mean,
he's got to be in shape.
I heard your training's
as tough as SWAT.
SWAT's LAPD.
We're SES. We're better.
Better conditioned,
better prepared.
Those the best you got?
Yeah. Yeah. You got lucky.
If they're not,
I'll fly mine in.
( Brass chuckles )
Let me put it
to you this way,
I'd want them
investigating my murder.
ROBBINS:
Other than the fact
that he's deceased,
this guy is in excellent
physical condition.
Except for
that head wound.
Eh, superficial.
Could be from a fall.
Your bloody rock
may be incidental.
What about
the bloody knuckles?
Injury on the
back of his hand.
Maybe an altercation
of some sort.
So cause of death?
No cerebral issues.
No primary indicators.
We go to
the fallback position.
Cardiac arrest.
This guy was 25 years old.
Didn't say I was finished.
Clouded corneas
tipped me off.
Look at the liver.
His serosal surfaces
are unusually dry.
His urine was minimal
and dark brown.
Dehydration.
Well, the race isn't
the only reason
these guys come to town.
It's a good party.
Too much running,
too much partying?
L.A. SES.
They go all out.
Work hard, play hard,
die young,
leave
a good-looking corpse.
WILLOWS:
Grissom.
Tox came in.
Tim Coleman
had 75 mics per mil
of furosemide
in his system.
Blood pressure
medication?
There's no history of that
in his medical records.
And it's was a high dose,
but not a lethal one.
But it is a diuretic.
Could explain the dehydration.
And the drug
can also cause muscle cramps,
dizziness, confusion,
blurred vision, restlessness.
That could explain
how Tim Coleman
ended up where he did.
How'd the furosemide get in
his system in the first place?
ANNOUNCER ( over P.A. ):
Listen up, people.
...are one hour away
and the party's raging
here at the finish line.
Too bad you guys
bet on the wrong horse.
Maybe you forgot.
One of our own died
out there in the dirt.
Yeah,
I'll drink to his memory.
You want
to make the toast?
Am I interrupting something?
No.
Later, pogue.
Um, are those bags
brought in from the race?
Yeah.
I'm going to need
Tim Coleman's.
Sure.
On the job,
we come across
a scene like this,
we call them
a bunch of degenerates.
We'd be rounding
half these guys up.
I am not going to miss this.
You're not going to
miss the competition?
I just made lieutenant.
I got nothing to prove anymore.
A man with nothing to prove.
Now that would be a first.
Got a second?
Sure, what's up?
On a hunch, I ran
a bank trace on Tim Coleman.
I got a hit.
$300 withdrawal
on his ATM card,
4:06 a.m. today.
That's about nine
hours after he died.
Good hunch, Grego.
Thanks.
I also got surveillance video
from the bank.
This ATM's on the corner
of Holyfield
and Maryland Parkway.
Since that's definitely
not Tim Coleman,
maybe it's our killer.
Or at least a thief.
Well, all we got to do now
is match a name with the face.
Write up a description,
send it off to Dispatch
for broadcast.
There might be an easier way.
Huh?
HODGES:
This is the thread
you pulled off
the runner's body.
GRISSOM:
Natural fiber?
Mercerized cotton.
Extremely strong.
Fibers are placed
in a caustic solution,
splitting the fibers apart
and providing an increased
surface area to absorb the dye.
Once it dries,
it's exponentially stronger.
This kind of thread is used in
machine quilting and embroidery.
Like on a sports uniforms.
( cheering )
ANNOUNCER ( over P.A. ):
120 miles through Baker
and SWAT and SES neck-and-neck.
( cheering )
SWAT and SES!
LAPD SWAT wins the first time
in eight years.
Coming in at 13 hours,
24 minutes.
For the last six years,
I ran the toughest leg
of the relay...
against the same
guy from SES.
But this year,
there was a new guy.
Yeah, this cocky kid shows up.
You're my competition?
I thought this was supposed
to be the hardest leg.
Typical SES, all mouth.
What'd you do?
Ignored him.
Looks like you got
in a fight?
Hey, I was here to race.
He cold-cocked me.
I never threw a punch.
We found red fibers on him
that may match your jacket.
I'm SWAT. I subdued him.
( grunting )
Mind if we take your jacket
to confirm?
Knock yourself out.
Not going to find
any blood on it.
Had a real good talk
with your manager, Clyde.
How's Fast 'N Fresh
treating you?
I'm up to $8.75 an hour.
I guess this kind of beats
saving up, huh?
Look... is my wife here?
Is she behind the
glass or something?
I'll be talking to her
soon enough.
Oh, come on, now.
Is that really necessary?
I mean,
I'm just a regular guy...
Hey, regular guys
don't steal $300
with a dead cop's
ATM card, man!
Dead cop?! What are
you talking about?
Those three bills--
that's-that's my money.
All right, technically,
it's my wife's, but...
I sell this tight little
Asian chick a $3 Tasty Meal.
She says for $300,
I can get a very tasty meal.
I was about to go
on my break anyway.
My wife's not behind that glass,
right?
VARTANN:
Hotel security came up
on a noise complaint.
Found two DBs.
Room's registered to a uniform
officer, Manny Senteno.
One of ours?
Laughlin PD,
but he carries tin,
so that makes him family.
Female vic's
Patricia Fielding.
Also PD.
Bakersfield.
He check in alone?
VARTANN:
Yeah, day before yesterday.
Issued one key,
but his itemized bill
shows lots of room service
for two.
SIDLE:
A wife or
girlfriend
would probably be
on the register.
Looks like it's all
his stuff.
I don't see a
purse around here.
Guy's away from home,
unwinds
with some opportunity sex...
Looks like he came
before he went.
Glock 19, standard police issue.
There's something
on the slide.
14 rounds left.
15-round magazine.
Any good cop keeps
one racked
in the chamber.
Two bullets, two bodies.
Put it down!
You dare me?!
I'm thinking
straight-up murder/suicide.
Tim Coleman's gym bag.
Gym clothes, towel,
vitamins, pocket knife.
Protein bar wrapper,
empty water bottle,
banana peel.
Why the trash?
Well, you know,
there's a five-minute penalty
if you litter the race course.
Oh.
What's the best way
to get chemicals
into your system?
Injection.
But there was no
evidence of that.
Second best?
Ingestion.
♪ ♪
Trace amounts
of furosemide
in his water bottle.
Someone spiked his drink.
♪ Bad boys, bad boys ♪
♪ Whatcha gonna do? ♪
♪ Whatcha gonna do
when they come for you? ♪
♪ Bad boys, bad boys,
whatcha gonna do? ♪
♪ Whatcha gonna do
when they come for you? ♪
♪ Bad boys, bad boys,
whatcha gonna do? ♪
♪ Whatcha gonna do
when they come for you? ♪
♪ Bad boys, bad boys,
whatcha gonna do? ♪
♪ Whatcha gonna do
when they come for you? ♪
♪ When you were eight
and you had bad traits ♪
♪ You go to school
and learn the golden rule ♪
♪ So why are you acting
like a fool? ♪
♪ If you get hot,
you must get cool ♪
♪ Bad boys, bad boys,
whatcha gonna do? ♪
♪ Whatcha gonna do
when they come for you? ♪
♪ Bad boys, bad boys,
whatcha gonna do? ♪
♪Whatcha gonna do
when they come for you? ♪
Jim.
Will Marshall,
this is Catherine
Willows
from the Crime Lab.
Hi.
There is something
very wrong in the world
if a woman like you
is only handling
test tubes.
Well, if you think
that's all I handle,
you're not as smart
as you think.
So, you're the L.A. County
team medic, right?
That means you're responsible
for making sure
that all your teammates
are well hydrated.
Yeah.
Including
Tim Coleman.
Yeah. Hell of a thing, that.
You're currently #1
on the SES's
transfer list.
Same spot you were
two months ago
when they bypassed you
to transfer in
Tim Coleman, right?
Six months I'm on the top
of the list.
January 31 comes, and they reach
over me and take Coleman.
That's the cutoff date
to run in the race.
Coleman was a ringer.
Ding-ding.
SES transferred him
in for speed, not skill.
Might not be another
opening for years.
I'm not getting any younger.
And after all of that,
Coleman doesn't even run.
He had a good excuse.
Did you give it to him?
If I'm going to kill a guy,
I'm not going to do it
with 20,000 cops around.
Well...
sounds like
you've been giving it
some serious thought.
Well, every cop does.
My way?
A sniper shot...
200 meters out.
Coleman'd
never even hear
the "am" in "blam."
Okay?
Mrs. Senteno, is
this your husband?
He doesn't wear his hair
like that.
There's some forms for you
to sign, then we can talk
in the lounge.
What happened?
Mrs. Senteno,
we haven't finished
our investigation yet,
but your husband died
from a gunshot wound.
Who shot him?
We don't know.
Where was he found?
In his hotel room.
He wasn't alone, was he?
No.
I married a cop.
With that comes alcohol
and women to take
the edge off.
First time...
he said it meant nothing.
He promised never
to do it again.
By the third time...
I told him to stop confessing.
I wasn't going anywhere.
Don't ask, don't tell.
I wasn't willing to trade
my family
for the flavor of the month.
That doesn't make me pathetic.
What happened?
Break the bad news
to the wife?
Oh, I didn't have to.
( sighs ):
Women always know, huh?
Not always.
I think so.
Women always know when
the man is straying.
What are you,
the voice of experience?
( laughs ):
No. I'm a really
nice guy.
Oh, I believe you.
Well, you need
to believe this.
There was one bullet
in each of the bodies.
They both came
from the Glock.
And the prints on the
Glock are from a female,
so it's still looking
like a murder/suicide.
All right.
Hey. You anywhere
on my fibers?
I'm dealing with a lot
of things today.
My phone has been ringing
off the hook.
CSI is taking a ton of crap
because we didn't finish
the race.
There was a dead
cop in the desert.
That's what I kept telling them,
and they tell me, "Good excuse."
The white fibers found
on the gun slide
is tissue: the common
nose-picking variety
with gun oil residue.
Are you saying that
the gun was wiped down
and the prints were planted?
No, you're saying that.
I don't get to say that.
But somebody else
could've pulled the trigger.
FRANCO:
Manny Sentero's prints
are all over the room,
including the champagne bottle
and one of the glasses.
What about
Patricia Fielding's?
Hotel room door,
inside knob.
And the murder
weapon.
That's it?
Are you sure?
I-I'm sorry.
It just doesn't make any sense.
The sex kits came back negative,
and now this.
I mean,
that room reeked of musk.
Well, maybe he swapped fluids
with someone else.
There was
a third set of prints.
I ran it through AFIS.
Got a hit on a cop.
Another one.
SIDLE:
Lydia Lopez,
Bakersfield PD.
That's the same division
as Patricia Fielding's.
Well, according to Histology,
Tim Coleman's muscle cells
were hyper-hydrated,
yet his body was dehydrated.
Well, that condition's
normally associated
with drug abuse.
Right. But apart
from the furosemide,
his tox was negative.
So, I took another
look at the guy.
Buff, cut, aggressive.
Made me think steroids.
Kind of risky for a cop,
considering they're subject
to random drug tests.
Well, steroids are controlled,
but creatine isn't.
It's a legal way
to bulk up.
Tim Coleman was using it.
Creatine pulls
the potassium from the blood
and moves it into the muscles.
Dehydrating the body
in the process.
Exactly.
And you add furosemide to it,
and you get a severe
electrolyte imbalance.
Leading to arrhythmia,
and consequently cardiac arrest.
So, what's our problem?
The dose.
There wasn't enough
furosemide in the water
to make that happen.
Lydia Lopez--
the girl next door.
( knocking )
CSI. Hello.
Her division captain
wants every
professional courtesy
extended to her.
Interesting.
Yeah.
Her clothes
are still here.
But I guess if you
offed two people,
you're not going to
stick around to pack.
Adjoining door's open.
Maybe they wanted it that way.
So, Manny and Lydia were boning.
How does Patricia Fielding
fit in?
I don't know.
Isn't the prevailing
male fantasy two on one?
So, let's say three of them
were going at it.
How did two out of
three end up dead?
Well, if Lydia said no,
and Manny went for it anyway...
Well, someone was pissed.
This is,
like, a two,
$300 La Perla nightie,
ripped to shreds.
Oh, looks comfortable.
It's not designed
to stay on that long.
This is a man's wedding ring.
( phone ringing )
Yeah.
Manny was
wearing a ring.
Was Lydia Lopez married?
I'll ask her.
She walked into LVPD
ten minutes ago.
My CO calls and tells me
that Patty Fielding's
been murdered,
and you're about to broadcast
a citywide for my 20.
What the hell's going on
in this town?
That's what we'd like to know.
I hope you've got
your story straight.
Didn't know I needed one.
Patricia Fielding was killed
in the room adjoining yours.
Manny's room?
Where's Manny?
Manny's on a slab
next to Patricia.
Look,
we know that you and Manny
were together.
Once a year
for seven years running.
Desert Relay
is our time together.
Then we go back to our lives.
That's sweet.
What was Sergeant Fielding
doing in your lover's room?
I don't know.
You don't know.
You know, I heard
that Manny Senteno
was a real player.
Maybe he moved on,
and you didn't like that.
Who told you that?
Manny doesn't mess around.
Except with you.
Yes.
How could you know that
if the only part you know
is his body?
Pedestal's a little high,
don't you think?
Your best friend,
your lover are dead.
What do you expect me to think?
I don't know what happened.
I do know
that Manny loves his wife
just like I
love my husband.
It's just an itch we scratched
every 12 months.
It doesn't mean anything.
It meant enough
to someone to trash your room.
Archie.
Archie-- your husband.
Mm-hmm.
Did he catch
the two of you together?
No. He wasn't even supposed
to be in Vegas.
This is my time.
I heard he was
looking for me.
He must've got a key
from the front desk.
Probably took one
look at the room
and went ballistic.
Did you see
what he did to my teddy?
That was Archie's gift to me.
Hey, most husbands
who buy lingerie
expect that they're the ones
who're going to be enjoying it.
I look good in it.
Archie didn't do this.
He couldn't.
The manager says Clyde Grimes
took a break around 3:00.
That's consistent
with bank records.
$300 withdraw to
Clyde's account
registered at 3:06.
But the video shows him
using Tim Coleman's card
at 4:06.
Yeah, one hour later.
Well, maybe
I'm not the only one
who gets screwed up
by Daylight Savings Time.
What if the ATM and the camera
were out of synch?
How? The camera's
part of the ATM.
Video is controlled
by the branch office.
ATM connects
to the national network.
Separate systems.
If the clocks
weren't synchronized...
Then the guy who used
Tim Coleman's card
should be on video
one hour later.
He's, uh, emptying the ATM.
Hey, is everybody all right?
Hey, you stupid jackass!
I'm with the Vegas Crime Lab.
Yo, yo, where's
the fire, my man?
( grunting )
Ha!
No wonder you were in a hurry.
STOKES:
Well, Mr. Drake,
I suppose this is one way
to make eight years
in an injection molding factory
pay off.
You're certainly good
with plastics.
STOKES:
It was a good scam.
Your reader transmits
the card number to you,
and the camera records
the sucker's PIN number.
I should have used
better transmitters.
I wouldn't have had
to stick so close.
You raked in over
$13,000 off 62
skimmed accounts.
That was just
the first two days.
And I checked the bank records.
All of the cards you stole
belonged to cops.
I know.
You know, I'm facing
multiple felony counts here.
Comprehensive theft,
card fraud.
I'm going away for years.
Everyone here knows that.
But when I got booked,
they wrote me up
for two moving violations.
I hate cops.
I picked up Lydia Lopez's
husband at Cheetah's.
He was groping the strippers.
Classic drunk-and-disorderly.
When I got there,
the bouncer was just about
to tune him up.
For what?
Yakking on his suit.
( laughs )
( man coughing )
VARTANN:
Archie Lopez.
So what?
BROWN:
Your prints were found
in your wife's hotel room,
including the doorknob
to the adjoining room.
Yeah.
Patricia Fielding was killed
in that room.
So was Manny
Senteno.
Hmm. My heart bleeds.
Are you still drunk?
( laughs )
Yeah, I'm
probably still drunk, yeah.
Must have been the tequila.
I don't drink that much.
Well, it takes a lot of drinking
to forget a murder.
( man coughing )
I didn't kill anyone.
I wanted to surprise Lydia.
Manager gave me a key.
And then I left.
Where did you go?
I went to the hotel bar.
That's where I saw Patty.
That woman's been to my house.
She's eaten my food.
She smiled in my face,
all the time...
All the time knowing that
Lydia was banging someone else.
( laughs )
So, where did you go then?
I went somewhere else.
I drank some more.
I drank...
A lot, I guess.
I don't...
I don't remember anything.
We're going
to need your clothes.
Tim Coleman drank
from this bottle.
What does this look like to you?
Backwash.
♪ ♪
MENDEZ:
You know, I don't appreciate
being kept
in the dark this long.
We don't release
details of our
investigation
until we're sure
of our facts.
Now we're sure.
Tim Coleman died
of a drug-induced
cardiac arrest.
If I'd known he was on drugs,
he'd never have gotten into SES.
Actually, he was
only on one drug.
Creatine.
You made it plural.
You gave him
a protein bar
that was laced
with furosemide.
Hey, you got
to keep up your strength.
Don't make us
look bad.
The combination of the two drugs
is what killed him.
I want my union rep.
That's your right.
We're going to need
to see your pocketknife.
On the table, please.
I said I want my union rep.
We're done here.
( computer beeping lightly )
SIDLE:
Archie Lopez's
clothes are negative
for GSR and blood.
Ditto on his
personal effects.
But I know Archie
was in Manny's room
because he has
Manny's luggage tag.
Guy wants to find out
who was sticking it
to his wife.
Is there an address
and phone number on that?
Yeah.
What do guys do
when they're drunk,
and they have a number
burning a hole in their pocket?
He called this number
six times.
The last call was 12 minutes.
Maybe Archie found someone
who can share his pain.
SIDLE:
It must be
very hard to hear
that your husband's
been cheating on you.
We've been through this.
I didn't care
about Manny's indiscretions.
Even when you hear about it
from the other woman's husband?
Archie Lopez called you.
So I talked to him on the phone.
He was drunk.
He was raving.
I didn't understand half
of what he said.
I think you heard him
loud and clear.
You got in your car,
and you tore ass
to Vegas.
I was in Laughlin with my son.
Highway Patrol
caught you speeding
on Interstate 15.
Southbound.
Most cops won't
issue tickets
to fellow cops
or their families.
Professional courtesy.
But your tag still
gets logged.
You were leaving Las Vegas
before you even found out
that your husband was dead.
I don't understand
what you're talking about.
Yeah, you do.
Oh, you bastard.
You can't prove that.
Well, that's why
we got a warrant
to search your house.
And
we found Patricia Fielding's
blood
in the lining of your purse.
From the tissue that you used
to wipe the gun.
She was nothing.
He jeopardized our family
for that?
Not for her.
Patricia wasn't the one having
the affair with your husband.
Oh.
( sniffles )
I caught her with him.
She answered the door
like she belonged there.
Mrs. Senteno,
you killed the wrong woman.
MANNY:
Wendy, it's not what you think.
( gunshot )
Where's your kit?
Actually, we have all
the evidence we need.
Then what the hell
are you doing here?
I have a question.
Off the record.
I wasn't trying to kill him.
Then why did you do this?
Leg 16 was mine.
I ran it eight years in a row.
I won every time.
Then the bosses transfer in
that kid,
kick me upstairs,
and give him my race.
No way I was going
to let him do better than me.
Sooner or later,
everybody gets replaced.
Talk to me
when it happens to you.