Wow, that had to hurt.
Well, robbery wasn't a motive.
His eyes took the brunt
of the punishment.
If you can't see,
you can't fight back.
No. But he may have tried.
Tony Sciarra.
From Philadelphia.
So much for brotherly love.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
Our victim Tony just checked
into the hotel.
He hadn't even unpacked.
He made enemies fast.
Yeah, old man at the casino,
who he knocked down,
said the same thing.
He was hauling ass.
Why?
Blood drops are medium to large.
Low-velocity spatter.
No castoff.
Maybe he wasn't beaten
with a weapon.
Hand to hand?
I know this guy's yoked.
He's what? 6'2"? 6'3"?
Size doesn't matter
when you're outnumbered.
Damn.
SIDLE:
Here's our vic.
Leaving the floor.
And the cameras. No eyes in
the corridors or the rest rooms.
Yeah, well, we know
where he went.
Just show us where
he came from, please.
Whoa. Whoa.
That's good.
Start it from right there.
Did you see that?
Yeah, the little
guy on the right
just snaked him.
You've got
to be kidding me.
He just did it again.
Two for two.
That guy has got stones
going after a mark
as big as Tony.
He knows he has backup.
Is the third time a charm?
Yes, it is.
Busted.
Accusations from Tony.
He's getting hot.
Some kind of denial
from the little guy.
Tony got worked.
Just wanted his money back.
We're going to need a still
of the little guy's face,
if you could.
You got it.
ROBBINS:
Fractures to the zygomatic,
ethmoidal, nasal bones.
Also the maxilla and mandible.
How many teeth did you
find at the scene?
Two.
He's missing six.
I found one in the back
of his mouth.
He probably swallowed
the other three.
I'll check his stomach.
Blood evidence at the scene
suggests that his attackers
did not use a weapon.
Contusions are nondescript.
No foreign tool marks.
Bare knuckles?
That's what I'm thinking.
Multiple blows
to the head
produced angular acceleration
and deceleration in the brain.
Twisting of the brain causes
the bridging veins to rip.
From there it's all downhill.
The axons within the white
matter of the brain
begin to snap.
Officially, COD is
diffuse axonal injury.
Unofficially...
it's the most brutal beating
I've ever seen.
Neck bruises were made
by a left hand?
What about these bruises?
Well, there's no
defensive wounds
on the hands or forearm.
So I'm guessing
it was restrained.
Bruises could be somebody's
knees on his chest.
So a hand on his throat,
knees on his chest,
his head was butted up
against a wall,
and all the blows
were directed at his face.
That doesn't leave much room
for any other attackers
to get their licks in.
Maybe there were
no other attackers.
( grunting, groaning )
One guy did all this?
So you're sure this
was the man you saw?
Yes. I was in the bathroom.
I waited for him to leave.
Then I called security.
Do you see this man now?
All you have to do is nod.
Thanks.
ID's off. We're looking
for a blue shirt and jeans.
He could have
ditched the clothes.
Let's be smart about this.
Las Vegas Police.
Put your hands behind your head
and stand up.
Come on.
You're not much of a talker,
are you, Walter?
I'll tell you.
You must be a pretty
tough guy to take on Tony.
A guy as big as that?
He's huge.
That's his name,
you know?
Tony Sciarro
from Philadelphia.
Did you know Tony?
How come you left
his wallet
and $500 in chips
in his pocket, huh?
That makes me think
that this was about
something else.
Did he...
wrong you
in some way?
He hurt you?
Huh?
Maybe it was just a...
lover's quarrel.
I'm not soft.
That's okay.
This is Vegas.
But that's not what
we saw on the video.
You're at the crap table.
You swiped his chips.
And then you whispered
sweet nothings in his ear.
What did you say?
Give me a reason.
That a confession?
No.
That's what I said.
That stare doesn't work on me.
But save it.
Because they're going
to love you in prison.
Mr. Darien, may
I see your fingers?
Why?
Well, because you
may have evidence
underneath the fingernails,
and I'd like to collect it.
Mr. Darien,
do you have a fever?
( yelling )
You might want
to double-check that.
I did.
It's not as bad as it looks.
It never looks too good
when a suspects dies in custody.
What are you saying, Rory?
You'd rather it be one of us?
No, that's not
what I'm saying.
If I was here, I'd have been in
there with you, you know that.
I assume we're going to come out
looking like the bad guy again.
Yeah.
You okay?
I'm fine.
Nasty.
That kind of looks
like a hickey.
You want to tell me
what got this party started?
I scraped his nails.
That's it?
What was his liver temp?
101.5.
He's been dead an hour.
That means his body
temperature was 103.
I touched his skin, Catherine.
He felt like he was on fire.
How did Walter Darien
even drive this thing?
Where there's a will,
there's a way.
PD found it
in the Orpheus parking lot.
Blue shirt and jeans
right on top.
He didn't even try to hide them.
Positive for blood.
I'll get it to Greg.
So this scumbag, Walter Darien,
he beats a guy to death, goes
out to his car, changes clothes
and then goes back into the
casino, washes his hands
and just gets something to eat.
Just another day.
Wow.
Whoa...
Yahtzee.
Whoa.
Must be a few thousand dollars'
worth of chips here.
So, he grifts,
but doesn't cash in?
Maybe it wasn't about the money.
I got gloves,
a T-shirt and a jacket
all with the tags
still on them.
Maybe he just likes
to steal things.
"Road Side Diner, Libby."
Sara.
What does that
look like to you?
Burn holes.
The guy takes on five
cops in their house.
Makes you wonder
what he might have
done to a waitress.
Didn't get enough of this guy
in the interrogation room?
I have a question.
Yes?
Cause of death?
Well, it wasn't
the nightstick action.
Cardiac arrhythmia.
His heart rate increased
till he went into tachycardia.
Started throwing PVCs
and then V-fib.
Prior condition?
Nothing I could find.
The guy had a big heart-- 550
grams-- but otherwise healthy.
This guy was pumped up
before the fight.
White knuckles, veins popping.
Well, he could have been
on something-- tox is pending--
but there were no observable
effects of long-term drug abuse.
No atrophy, cirrhosis,
tissue necrosis.
I checked all the hot spots.
He had a temperature of 103
when he died.
Any pathology to explain that?
The organs showed no sign
of infection or disease.
So there was nothing wrong
with this guy.
Well, I'll send a tissue sample
to histology,
but 98.6 is just an average.
Some people run hot.
See, during questioning,
your brother became a little...
unruly, and, uh...
so for their own safety,
the officers had no choice
but to use force.
At which point...
I've heard enough.
Ms. Darien,
it's very important
that you understand
the situation here.
I do.
Walter was killed
in police custody.
( sighs )
Uh, let me introduce
Gil Grissom from the
crime lab.
This is Beth Darien, the...
I was in the room
with your brother.
Was that how he touched
your life?
The autopsy concluded
that your brother's death
was not the result
of the officers' use of force.
I don't care how he died.
I'm just relieved
that it's over.
Walter hurt a lot of people.
If you had something
he wanted,
he just took it.
And if you got
in his way...
I always kept my distance.
Ms. Darien, your brother's body
temperature was...
Hot to the touch?
He was always that way,
ever since we were kids.
I'll have someone
from the department contact you,
all right, Ms. Darien?
Always knew
that Walter
would end up in jail or dead.
I'm sorry.
Griss, what are you
hoping to find here?
Walter Darien lived here.
He owned the place.
Well, Greg ran
the DNA.
The blood on
Walter's clothes
is a match to Tony.
The hair in Tony's hands
is a match to Walter's.
This case is closed,
isn't it?
That case is closed.
We can't prosecute
a dead man.
"The evil men do
lives after them.
The good is oft interred
with their bones."
Shakespeare?
Julius Caesar.
Whew.
This guy never threw
anything away.
So, what do you think?
Obsessive compulsive
disorder?
Well...
if Walter viewed his world
as a threatening place,
according to the shrinks,
the hoarding of useless objects
may have made him feel
safe and secure.
Yeah, well, in
the real world,
Walter's the threat.
Guess he didn't like
what he saw.
Hey, Grissom.
This doesn't look like a patio.
Libby... Libby...
Oh, yeah, dish girl.
She have a last name?
Sure, she does,
but I don't know it.
When's the last time
you saw her?
Eight years ago.
The kid had no chops.
Ouch!
Burned herself real good.
That was her first and last day.
We need an ID.
Is there any chance
you still have a W2
lying around
or a copy of her
driver's license?
Girl wasn't here long enough
to refill the coffee pot,
let alone sign anything.
I don't know where
she came from, don't
know where she went.
What about this guy?
You ever see him
with Libby?
I ain't gettin' nothin'.
( bell dinging )
Sorry. Order's up.
( jackhammer continues
hammering )
♪ ♪
( shovel bangs
into hard object )
Only one thing makes that sound.
♪ ♪
Well...
I guess there was no more room
at the inn.
( garbled police radio
transmission )
It's a wedding band.
You think this is the waitress
Nick and Sara are looking for?
Well, there's no clothing left.
The wedding band
could be either/or.
There's nothing
gender-specific yet.
WARRICK:
Next to no tissue.
No hairs at all.
To get the bones,
what do you think, Grissom?
Been down here
at least three years?
( sniffing )
No, it's probably more
than three years.
You're kidding me, right?
Well, the rule of thumb
is if the skull smells bad,
it's usually under three years.
This one smells like dirt.
There's something
under the pelvic bone.
Oh, yeah.
GRISSOM:
Possible
murder weapon.
You think we could
still get any DNA
off of it?
Any blood's been exposed to the
elements longer than the inside
of these bones.
There's no skin, clothing
or tissue to protect it.
Doesn't fit.
Walter was a fighter.
Used his fists, not knives,
you know?
Well, we haven't known him
that long.
Forehead's
upright, smooth.
Mandible's small.
Lower face narrow.
Female traits.
Yeah.
Pelvis confirms it.
It's wide
for the birth canal.
No pits
in the pubic bone--
she never gave birth.
What about her race?
Zygomatic bones retreat,
slant back.
Nasal opening's long
and narrow.
Caucasian.
Mm.
Around 5'4".
I estimated her height
from the length
of the femur.
How old are we talking?
Well... third molars
haven't erupted.
No wisdom teeth.
So that would put her
in her late teens, early 20s.
Eh, it's a safe estimate.
Cause of death?
Strangulation.
Fracture to the hyoid bone.
What about these right here?
Fractures to the
zygomatic bone
and maxilla...
also the left ulna...
but no tool marks
on any of the bones.
So maybe she was punched
in the face
and tried to shield herself?
Yeah. Walter Darien strangled
a female Caucasian,
5'4", around
20 years old.
Yeah, but is it
our missing waitress?
Well, I, uh, did
dental charts, x-rays.
David's off and running
with 'em now.
I also excised a
portion of the femur,
scraped a tissue sample
from inside the pelvis,
and yanked a molar.
If there's any usable DNA left,
that's where it'll be.
Okay.
( sighs )
How'd you know there was
another body at that motel?
I didn't.
Tox and histology results
came back on Walter Darien.
Negative across the board.
No drugs, no diseases.
I don't get it.
The guy was 38 years old,
and this was his first arrest.
And you're wondering what
he'd been doing all his life.
( phone ringing )
Willows.
( laughs )
Why don't you hold that
thought until later?
( clears throat ):
Sorry.
A new friend.
Congratulations.
Got time for something
a little weird?
I recovered DNA
from your Jane
Doe skeleton.
Clean samples
from the molar and femur...
but no hits in CODIS.
So Jane Doe
was never reported missing.
Apparently not. I also pulled
DNA from the pelvic sample.
A mixture: foreign DNA
from a male.
Walter Darien.
No. That's where it gets weird.
The foreign DNA
was homozygous.
Hit all 13 loci.
One peep per marker.
Shared alleles,
so it was either a father
or a son.
According to the autopsy,
she never gave birth.
So it was a father.
Okay, so how'd it get there?
The tissue was
from inside the pelvis,
so even if Daddy's blood
or semen
got on her clothes or skin,
it never would've survived being
in the ground all that time.
So there has to be
an additional biological source,
'cause there was no one else
in that grave.
STOKES:
That's all I got.
No name, no tissue,
no hair.
I like a challenge.
Pull up the standard
tissue thickness scale
for female American
Caucasoids.
Use the normal figures.
Apply the midline
measurements.
Good. Now the bilateral.
That's the blueprint.
Mm-hmm.
Okay, you can take this.
( monitor beeping )
♪ ♪
Long skull.
Prominent nose and chin.
Maybe Nordic descent.
That means...
light complexion, hair...
...and... blue-green eyes.
( grunts )
Warrick.
These have got to be
maternity clothes.
WARRICK:
"And baby makes three."
WILLOWS:
Her name's not Libby.
Dental records confirm
our Jane Doe was Marissa Cleary.
Which leaves
our missing waitress Libby
still unaccounted for.
The foreign DNA in her pelvis
wasn't from her father.
It was from her son.
There was no evidence of a fetus
or a baby in that grave.
She never gave birth.
Not through her birth canal.
There's other ways
to deliver a baby.
Well, that might explain
the hunting knife we found.
( gagging )
The umbilical cord
contains fetal DNA.
Walter Darien never threw
anything out...
so where'd the baby go?
CLEARY:
Eight years.
I never thought she was dead.
I wondered where she was,
what she was doing
with her life.
What my kid was like.
Mr. Cleary, we haven't found
any evidence to suggest
that your son...
My son?
You mean it was a boy?
Yes.
Well, can
I see him?
Is he dead, too?
We don't know.
Marissa and I
had only been
seeing each other
for a few months,
and everything was great.
And then she got pregnant,
so we got married.
And all of a sudden,
she hates me, I hate her.
All we did was fight.
Then she calls me
one night at work.
( sobbing ):
You don't want me
in your life, fine.
I'm gone!
Good! It's the best news
I've heard all year.
That was the last time we spoke.
And you never reported
her missing?
I didn't think she was.
I was 19.
Barely out of
high school.
Last thing you needed
was a family.
She was in her ninth month
when she split.
I thought she'd cool off
in a couple of days,
come back,
we would work
things out.
But then I got this.
"You're not
who I thought you were.
"You don't want me.
"You don't want this baby.
"We don't want you.
Marissa."
All right, you see the long legs
she gives to her "M,"
and how it stands alone?
Mm-hmm.
Now look at the
Dear John letter.
This is not Marissa's
signature...
just a quick and dirty forgery.
My money's on Walter.
Well, I can't tell
you anything
without an exemplar.
Yeah, well, Warrick's going
through his stuff now.
From what I hear,
that's going to take a while.
So, what about this text?
Uh, not typed-- printed
uh, off an inkjet,
and so far, all of Walter's
accumulated printers
are dot matrix.
No match.
Warrick found
a baseball cap
in Walter's motel.
Yielded a blond hair.
DNA was still good, which means
the hair was
no more than
a few years old.
It was Marissa's son.
So, he'd be eight now.
Assuming he's still alive.
Hey,
guys, I've been working
on that John Doe envelope.
The postmark was Henderson.
The Bates Motel is in Sloan.
Why would Walter go that far
out of his way to mail a letter?
He wouldn't.
Well, I moved to Henderson
to get away from Walter.
I stayed out of his life,
hoping he'd stay out of mine.
Didn't matter
that I was his sister.
He treated me
like he did everybody else.
Do you recognize
this woman?
No.
Who is she?
Her name is
Marissa Cleary.
We believe she was a guest
in your brother's motel
eight years ago.
He killed her, didn't he?
We think so.
Oh, I wonder what she did
to set him off.
I don't know.
I'm sure it wasn't much.
( sobbing ):
You don't want me in your life.
Fine.
I'm gone!
Good! It's the best news
I've heard all year.
( sobbing )
Shut up!
Shut up. Damn it!
( screaming )
He could always find an excuse
for anything that he did.
Are we keeping you
from something?
No.
It makes me
really uncomfortable
talking about Walter.
( coughing )
Did Walter
give you
those burns?
No, that was, uh...
an accident on the job
many, many years ago.
When you used to be a waitress,
Libby?
Nobody's called me that
in years.
How did you know?
We found your old waitress
uniform in Walter's car.
I, I had that job for one day.
I was a lousy waitress.
Why would he keep that?
( kids yelling and screeching)
Hi, Mom.
Hey, baby.
Why don't you take your stuff
and put it in your room?
I'll make
you a snack.
How old is that little guy?
He's going to be nine
next month.
WILLOWS:
You're not his mother.
I'm the only mother
he's ever known.
I raised him; I had to.
( insistent pounding )
Middle of the night,
your brother shows up
and hands you a baby.
You don't ask
any questions.
You don't report it.
Walter said
that the mother was a runaway,
and that she didn't
want the baby.
I took him in.
I love him.
How did Martin get the scar
on his forehead?
I don't know.
I think you didn't want
to know.
Marissa Cleary
didn't sign that note.
And we don't think
Walter wrote it, either.
I'm not like Walter.
When I opened
the suitcase,
and I saw the photograph...
I didn't want the father
to suffer.
The suitcase
was in Walter's closet.
I took it back.
I didn't want it around me.
I knew that he
would never notice.
Giving me Martin...
was the only good thing
that Walter ever did.
I don't know why he did it.
But it wasn't out
of the goodness of his heart.