( indistinct
police radio chatter )
No watch, no wallet, no shoes.
This guy was picked clean.
BRASS:
In this neighborhood,
he's lucky to have
the fillings in his teeth.
Still there.
This guy was well-groomed.
I don't care if he was
lemon-scented and Martinized,
if he was on Washington and D,
he was copping.
He should have just said no.
Maybe somebody wouldn't take no
for an answer.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
SIDLE:
So, how long have you been
in Vegas, Detective Cavaliere?
CAVALIERE:
Couple of weeks.
Welcome to
Tranny-town.
This is
where the hustlers come.
Yeah, I can see why.
It's very romantic.
SIDLE:
This is new.
Don't get territorial.
It's for my own
personal collection.
Whatever blows
your skirt up.
Burn me a copy.
There's a small cut
on the forehead.
Yeah, it looks like
he's wearing makeup.
Blush on his cheeks...
lipstick.
Transvestite.
Fits the profile.
Hotel's across the way.
Anonymous sex
becomes anonymous sex crime.
Murder's usually personal.
Maybe whoever had the last dance
left behind a corsage.
I'd settle for his clothes.
Hey, I'll give you a hand.
You think a hacksaw's
going to do the trick?
No.
But that's why God
invented Sawzalls.
♪ ♪
All we got
is a decapitated doll.
That's still legal in Nevada.
WILLOWS:
Dave, what's up?
You find something?
I was just thinking I wouldn't
be caught dead in those shorts.
Yo, baby, look, why're
you rushing the day?
We got plenty
of night left.
I'm working, lady.
See, that's something
we already got in common,
'cause I'm working, too.
Oh, yeah?
Mm-hmm.
Were you working him?
Him? No. No, sir.
But I tell you one thing.
Good-looking
white boy like that?
I know plenty of women who'd be
tripping over their platforms
to get a little somethin'
somethin'.
But no, sir, he
wasn't nobody's customer.
This guy get here on foot?
I don't see a car.
They haven't found one yet.
I suppose nobody
saw it drive away.
They were all in the bathroom.
Multiple stab wounds.
The deepest of which
transected the thoracic aorta
and the right
mainstream bronchus.
Anything else?
His name is Ed Burnell.
Matched his prints,
prior for possession.
And it's not the first time
he stared death in the face.
Our man had a double
dose of cirrhosis.
That takes work.
Years of hard-core alcohol
abuse, plus hepatitis,
probably acquired
by dirty needles.
In Chinese medicine, the liver
is the organ of anger.
Addicts and alcoholics
medicate their anger,
consequently, destroy
their liver.
Actually, half the liver
is pretty healthy.
The new half.
Oh...
A graft from
a less angry donor.
Organ recipient procedure
is pretty clear.
They only do transplants
on people who test clean
for a year.
Well, he probably
got his new liver,
figured he could, uh,
start all over again.
Is that what you think?
That once an addict,
always an addict?
WILLOWS:
Don't let the scope
touch the garment.
You don't want
to contaminate the evidence.
And work systematically.
Up-down,
left-right, what?
Well, whatever works for you.
Just don't miss any spots.
All right, hang on.
What do those look like to you?
Semen stains.
Yes.
Which, on a man's underwear,
aren't exactly probative.
No.
Can't tell you
how long they've
been there,
or how often the guy
changes his shorts.
You know, I knew guys
that could go up to four days
on one single pair
of tighty-whities.
Thanks for putting
that picture in my brain.
All right, so...
I want you to outline each
individual stain with dots.
But keep them at least
an eighth of an inch
from the edge
to avoid contamination.
And then, cut out the swatches
and send them to myself in DNA.
You got it.
WILLOWS:
A fiber in his nose.
Yeah, I'll get it to Trace.
Petechial hemorrhaging.
I would've thought
he was strangled
during some kind
of rough sex-play,
but there's no marks.
Suffocation maybe?
That's why undertakers love
smother-victims.
He's got something
under his nails.
Looks like silver paint.
Vegas Brow.
A showgirl thing.
Eyebrows thin out
from all the plucking
and waxing and filling in.
Well, we can kind of rule
him out as a showgirl.
And, you know, he's hairy
for a drag queen.
Hey, David?
Yeah?
Could you
hit the lights?
His face looks painted.
Kinda looks like a clown.
MAN:
Yo, man, get these spiders
off my face, man!
I gotta beam up outta here.
I need my medication.
I'm a CEO of a Five-Bag-A-Day
Corporation, you know that?
Thank you.
Y'all look like cartoons, man.
Okay, thank you.
BRASS:
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Take it easy, pal.
You're not running
the four-minute mile
on those pins.
Nice shoes.
It's all good, it's all good.
Whoa! Who gonna pay
for that hole in my ride, man?
BRASS:
Your ride?
This was never your ride.
This car belongs to Ed Burnell.
Finders keepers, baby.
I gotta bag me some ho's.
What drug is he on?
I don't know.
Whatever it is, he either
took too much or not enough.
Just 'cause the guy
looks like a clown
doesn't mean he is a clown.
Description didn't match
anyone in missing persons.
If you've got a better idea,
now's the time.
I'd say we're in
the right place.
Yeah. Either that
or they're casting
a John Wayne Gacey revue.
And you can tell that putz
that Buddy Ween doesn't send
cruise ship talent
for Bar Mitzvah wages.
You got that?
Uh, strippers are down
the hall, girls.
This is clowns.
No kidding.
I'm Catherine Willows.
This is Sara Sidle.
We're with the Crime Lab.
Well, why didn't you say so?
We do lots of police parties.
The party has already happened.
What am I supposed
to do with this?
Identify the body.
Did that man ever
work for you?
Well, let me put
it this way:
I rep clowns.
That's Flappy,
that's Flappy Junior,
that's Allen...
He doesn't work
that much... Popo...
Get it? All I do
is book the face.
I don't care
what's underneath.
If our victim was a professional
clown,
would he be in this book?
Uh-huh.
What are these numbers for?
That's the National Clown
and Character Registry.
How do you register a clown?
Well, not the clown.
The look, the face.
Each one is unique.
It's like snowflakes.
We're going to need
to take this with us.
You got a warrant?
I'm kidding.
Okay, it's just
a loaner, though.
MAN:
I know you stealin'
my medication.
I am in pain, damn it!
Bring me some stuff!
What are you two ladies
lookin' at?
Uh... Jamal...
We're with the Las
Vegas Crime Lab.
It seems you were driving
a dead man's car
when you got
in your accident.
Half the peoples I know be dead.
It don't mean they can't own
a vehicle.
Hey, Vanilla Ice...
at this point you're lookin'
at a murder rap,
which may end you up
on death row,
and I'm not talking
about the record label.
Nurse, this be cruel
and unusual!
GRISSOM:
Look, pal,
right now
the evidence tells us
that you killed the man
whose car you were driving.
You want to explain that?
Explain what, B?
I was laid up shootin'
speedballs all day.
Look, man,
when I get off,
I'm gone.
Feel me?
I can't see nothin',
I can't hear nothin'.
Wherever high is, that's where
I take the elevator up.
Oh, you damn cow!
Took you long enough.
When I call you, you
come, you understand me?
Why you got to
do me like this?
That's right.
Man's dead.
What difference it make
how he got there?
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I got a date with Mrs. Jones.
Man's already dead.
Why he be needing shoes, anyway?
Was that a confession?
I think a plea of insanity.
DNA results on the blood
from Jamal's clothes.
It's his own.
Well, the blood spatter's
consistent
with a front-end collision.
So he didn't kill him
in the car.
Doesn't mean
he didn't kill him.
What I want to know is how's
a strung-out junkie like Jamal
get a guy out of the car
with just his knife?
Yeah, and why stab him
six times?
Well, let's just say
for argument's sake
that Jamal is telling the truth
and that Burnell
was already dead
when he took his wallet,
his shoes and his car.
Well, if the motive wasn't
robbery... what was it?
Maybe this'll tell us.
Heroin?
Negative
on marquis-mecke-froede.
So, if it's not an opiate,
what is it?
I don't know.
I've never seen it before.
I ran a color and crystal test.
Take a look.
All I can tell you is
it's an indole alkaloid.
Did you run it
through the GCMS?
Yeah, but it's not
in the library.
( computer beeps )
WEEN:
That's Doodles.
A.K.A. Donny Zanko.
So you know him.
There are two kinds
of clowns:
There's your ex-circus pros,
washed out of Ringling Bros.,
Barnum and Bailey,
and then there's your basic
chuckleheads.
Which kind was Doodles?
Basic chucklehead.
You know, buy a getup,
learn some tricks,
and grab some scratch
boring the crap
out of nine-year-olds.
He was a good birthday man,
except when he, uh...
So, he made money boring kids?
Parents throw parties.
They like clowns because they
think their kids like clowns.
Mm-hmm.
Lindsey's fourth... Bad scene.
Oh.
So, what was the last gig
you booked for him?
Uh...
Car wash, couple of weeks back.
Why?
Mr. Ween, he's been dead
less than 48 hours
and he was wearing his makeup
when he was killed.
That son of a bitch.
He was working
off the books.
I never thought Doodles
would try to stiff me.
He, actually, was the one
who got stiffed.
So, it turns out Burnell's
tox report was clean.
Not only that, he
works at some sort
of recovery center.
Well, that makes sense.
It does?
Well, the substance we found
in his car was ibogaine.
What's that, the stuff
that grows hair?
A choline-esterase inhibitor
that acts as a stimulant
in the central nervous system.
In the liver, it converts
to an active metabolite...
Noribogaine.
Noribogaine locks
onto addiction receptors...
blocking the feedback loops
that reinforce dependency.
In human speak?
Well, apparently,
in some cases,
one dose of ibogaine can cure
physical addiction.
Does it come with a free set
of steak knives?
It comes with a free trip.
Curing physical addiction
is a side effect.
Its intended use
is to facilitate
visual, tactile,
and auditory experiences
of alternate realities.
So it's an hallucinogen.
Mm-hmm. Used by the Bwiti tribe
of central Africa.
It comes from the powdered bark
of a tree growing in Cameroon.
No kidding.
Many ethno-botanists believe
that the iboga
is what the Bible
is talking about
when it refers
to the Tree of Knowledge.
The Bwiti consume
the powdered bark
as part of an initiation
ceremony.
After the ritual,
a man is called Baanzi, one
who has seen the other world.
No way it's legal.
Not in the U.S.
So, Ed Burnell
was a drug dealer.
Well...
He's either
dealing in
the addiction
or the cure, and a
dealer's a dealer.
And this guy's dealing
out of a halfway house.
SARA:
Well...
I can see why Doodles drank.
So, if he's hooking
up in Tranny-town,
you'd expect to find some
man-on-man porn.
All we've got is varying flavors
of Juggs.
Hmm.
Looks like Doodles was working
out some animosity.
Oh, an answering machine
with messages.
( beeps )
Friday, 11:02.
WOMAN:
Hey, Doodle-pie.
I can't stop thinking about
your enormous feet. Call me.
( beeps )
You know what they say
about big feet.
Saturday, 7:00 p.m.
MAN:
Okay, paddle boy,
you want a war, you got one.
And just so you know,
I do appreciate the irony
of me leaving you a message.
( beeps )
Sunday, 11:45 a.m.
MAN:
Hey, Mr. Doodles,
your taxi's here.
MAN:
Yeah, yeah, cool your jets.
I'll be right down.
( beeps )
He took a cab ride
two days ago...
and his costume's not here.
Makes sense if he's out of town
on a job.
I'll call
Detective
Cavaliere
and have him pull
the phone records.
MAN:
Ed Burnell worked here
for about a year.
We're a halfway house.
We provide a safe
place to live.
I mean, if they're
going to do ibogaine,
I'd rather have them do it in
here than out in the street.
And despite the fact that
San Quentin is your alma mater
and you have a record
as long as my leg,
you wouldn't do anything
illegal, right?
I wouldn't do anything
to jeopardize this place,
and we don't give out
illegal drugs.
We do a lot
of good work here.
You know, if ibogaine
is such a miracle cure,
wouldn't it make your life
easier?
The drug doesn't promise
anything.
You got to earn it.
If a user doesn't realize
why he used in the first place,
I mean, no power in the world
is going to make him stop.
Right here is a good
case in point.
So, you're going?
Yeah.
You sure that's what
you want to do?
Yeah.
This place just reminds
me too much of Ed.
Look, I really wish
you'd stay here a little longer.
I can't.
You did a good
job here, Mindy.
I'm still doing it.
What's her story?
Ed got her clean.
Let me show you
what she looked like
two months ago.
BURNELL ( on video ):
Why are you here, Mindy?
Wanna get off.
I... I don't got
another run in me,
but I can't stop.
My name is Ed Burnell.
I'm here to help you,
Mindy.
This place is nice.
Can I stay here?
Yes.
'Cause you're gonna
take care of me, right?
Yes, I'm going
to take care of you.
So, was it the ibogaine
or the months
she spent here?
You don't believe
in ibogaine?
I don't believe in miracles.
But Ed did?
Look, when Ed first came here,
he was an asset to the place.
And then he got...
religious about it.
You know,
there's a reason why Mohammed
kept his ass on the mountain.
It was safe there.
The thing about recovery
is it only works
for those who want it,
not for those who need it.
But Ed came down
from the mountain,
and he brought the ibogaine
with him.
Yeah, and he started pushing it
on everyone.
Sometimes he won,
sometimes he lost.
From one addiction to another.
WOMAN:
I can't believe Doodles is dead.
How did it happen?
We're hoping you can
help us find out.
Yeah, according
to Sunburst Taxi,
one of the drivers dropped off
the clown here two days ago.
Yeah, that's right.
My son was having
a birthday.
It's my own little tradition.
Birthdays, special occasions,
I always hire a clown.
The kids love them.
Except this time, I think
maybe we should've gone
to Circus Circus.
( chuckles )
What do you mean by that?
Well, we hired a clown--
squirting flower,
big floppy shoes and all that--
what we got was a smackdown.
Doodles was going through
his clown bit,
and, uh, then this mime
comes through our kitchen,
which at first we thought
it was part of the act.
What the hell
are you doing here?
( men grunting )
So, uh, I jumped in
and broke it up
and dragged the mime
into the kitchen.
I was going
to call you guys...
Mm.
...but he apologized
and said that, uh,
there was bad blood
between him and Doodles.
And he gave me a hundred bucks
for the damages,
which I thought was
a pretty stand up thing to do,
so I let him go.
Did you get his name?
I did better than that.
He, uh, told me
he'd give me a great rate
if I ever wanted to upgrade
from clowns.
And what time did
Doodles leave?
The kids were really upset
after the fight,
so I took them out
for ice cream.
Doodles stuck around
to help me clean up,
and then he asked me
to call him a cab.
Do you remember the name
of the taxi company
or the time of the call?
Well,
he'd been such a good sport
that I offered
to give him a ride home.
I dropped him off at his place
at around 8:30.
Hey, excuse me.
Take a look.
Look, you do have the right
to remain silent,
but unless you want
a trip to the station,
I really wouldn't keep it up.
You want to talk about Doodles,
fine.
Take a look at what that skeek
did to me.
You got that at Maguires'?
( grunts )
Stick a mime and a clown
in the same place,
it's like a cobra
and a mongoose.
You crashed Doodles' party,
he kicked your ass,
and now Doodles is dead.
I didn't kill him.
You left a threatening message
on his answering machine.
You declared war.
Look, the creep was a parasite.
When he wasn't bad-mouthing me,
he was horning in on my gigs.
Every time I line up
a job, "ring-ring,"
Doodles calls the mom,
gets her to hire him, too.
That's money out of my pocket.
So, yeah, I figured
a little payback was in order.
Yeah, what did you do
after you left the Maguires?
I had a strip mall opening
out of town.
You didn't stop by his house?
You know,
wait for him to come back?
No.
I got two hookers in
Pahrump who can verify.
GRISSOM:
We found prints
belonging
to three separate people
in Ed Burnell's car:
His, Jamal the thief,
and Mindy.
He could have
given her a lift.
Except we found her
print on a condom.
Well,
she said she loved Ed.
Yeah? How much, I wonder.
BRASS:
We're looking
for information
on Mindy Dupont.
This was her last
known address.
Yeah, she's here.
Mind if we
talk with her?
You got a search warrant?
You don't need a warrant
just to talk.
But if you want, we'll
go get one and come back.
Hey, it's a free country.
Yes, it is.
BRASS:
Mindy Dupont.
We thought you
cleaned yourself up.
I tried so hard.
He said I would feel again.
I never wanted to feel.
Ed saved my life.
How do you repay
a favor like that?
I tried.
We're going to clean you up.
What if I don't want
to be clean?
No.
I'm going to help you.
He was an angel.
He gave me that stuff.
And you didn't want
to get high anymore.
( whimpers )
Did you come here to remember
or to forget?
Well, the mime's alibi
checks out.
He took Polaroids,
with the hookers.
Strip mall opened at 7:30.
He didn't leave Pahrump
till the next morning.
Uh-huh.
So that leaves
us with what?
Nothing.
Hmm.
What about timeline?
Mrs. Maguire gives
Doodles a lift,
getting him home around 8:30.
As far as we know,
he didn't have
another job that night.
Doodles goes home,
having performing
all day for kids,
wrestling with mimes.
His costume would've
been a little skanky,
yet he doesn't
change out of it?
Maybe he never got inside.
And he walks around
town in his clown suit
until he gets killed?
Okay, what are the knowns?
Um...
Doodles was suffocated.
We found yellow fibers
up his nose.
Greg analyzed the semen
stains on his boxer shorts
and found an unknown vaginal
contribution in the sample.
Mrs. Maguire was the last person
to see him alive.
BRASS:
The night
Ed Burnell was killed
you never checked
into the halfway house.
Mindy, we found a knife
in your basket of clothes
with Ed Burnell's
blood on it.
Help us connect the dots.
We all have this secret,
terrible cave in our hearts,
and the more
we try to escape it,
the deeper we drive ourselves
inside of it.
This isn't
the halfway house, Mindy.
You're looking at a murder
rap, so let's talk specifics.
There were 57 micrograms
per milliliter
of monoacetylmorphine
in your urine sample.
That means you were
using for a while.
Ed gave me ibogaine.
That was months ago.
Where were you the
night Ed was killed?
It was like Adam and Eve
taking you to the movies
except the movie was your life
and you were watching it
and in it at the same time.
Why would you have a knife
with his blood on it?
I think Ed Burnell knew
you were using again
and he was out there that
night looking for you.
The spirits...
they protect you.
Well, you better hope so,
because you're under arrest
for the murder of Ed Burnell.
Sara. Excuse me.
Could you, uh,
help me out?
Yeah, with what?
A woman.
I need you to process
a female suspect for me.
Sure.
Palms down.
Would you hold your
arms out, please?
Thanks. You can get dressed now.
Samples from your suspect.
There's nothing but
a few track marks.
No defensive
wounds, no bruising.
Junkies usually
bruise if you breathe
on them too hard.
She is a pile of
twigs, very frail.
What?
I haven't seen you
for a while, have I?
You see me every day.
It's all yours.
SIDLE:
Thanks.
Yeah.
So, we're looking
for clown sex...
And clown murder.
This fabric is consistent
with the fibers we found
in Doodles' nose.
You notice
how everything matches
except this one pillow sham?
Yeah.
The white-faced clown
with a pillow covering his face.
There must've been
some transfer.
If a pillowcase like that
had grease paint on it,
would you throw it out?
I'd clean it first.
♪ ♪
You lied about driving
the clown home.
He was in your bedroom.
DNA on his boxer shorts
indicates that you
had sex with him.
We checked with the
Buddy Ween Agency,
and, uh, you hire clowns
on a fairly regular basis:
four, five, six
times a year.
That's a lot of clowns.
I already told you.
I like clowns.
I think you like them
more than most people.
( laughing )
Mr. Maguire, I hate
to tell you this,
but while you were off
driving the other kiddies home,
your wife was doing
the clown.
We figured you must've
walked in on them...
in flagrante.
( grunting )
You stripped the body
and dumped it in an area
frequented by
transvestites,
hoping that it would
just... go away.
Another forgotten
sex crime.
You covered
your tracks.
You cleaned the house.
You washed that pillowcase.
What I don't
understand, though...
Why did you keep
the clown suit?
You don't understand.
Merrill and I have been
married nine years.
We have two kids.
Not much left
to get excited about?
I love my wife.
When Al wore the suit...
it worked...
and it was good.
If you found
something that got you off...
wouldn't you keep it?
Man, there is something
so heartbreaking
about a woman
with raggedy drawers.
Mm-hmm.
Grissom, we've gone
through all
of Mindy's stuff twice.
There's no trace
of blood.
STOKES:
Doesn't make any sense.
If she disposes
of her clothes,
she's not just going to
forget about the knife.
Hey, guys, got a male
DNA skin sample collected
from Mindy's hair.
Burnell?
Yes and no.
The blood is Burnell's,
but the skin belongs
to another guy.
Do we know who?
SANDERS:
The gods of CODIS
have blessed us
with a hit:
Riley "Boom-Boom" Renaldo,
proud owner
of two assault and battery
charges and a possession
with intent
to distribute.
Current occupation:
apartment manager.
What do you bet
Boom Boom's estate
is on the corner
of Washington and D Street?
Renaldo was Mindy's landlord?
That'd make her
a bag-bride...
a strawberry.
Paid her rent
horizontally.
As long as a dealer keeps
a strawberry high,
the strawberry
does whatever
the dealer wants.
BRASS:
Las Vegas Police. Open up.
GIRL:
Riley...
you said I could have a taste
when we were done.
Riley!
Shut up, Sunshine.
Nice. We keep Mindy
for a couple of hours,
and you've already
moved on.
What's the matter?
Lose faith in Mindy?
She always comes
back to you.
Guess Burnell
was bad for
business, huh?
Yeah, Old Ed gets enough people
in the 'hood clean,
you get no love.
GIRL:
Riley...
I need it.
I said shut up.
Mindy didn't need
it anymore, right?
That's why you
helped her remember.
I don't need that anymore.
What do you mean,
you don't need it?
Just one more, and that's it.
Burnell wasn't hard
to find, was he?
Yo, man... that jackass
who be messin'
with Mindy is back...
You've got nothing on me.
Yeah, we do: Burnell's
blood on your skin.
BRASS:
So, come on, let's go,
let's go.
Come on, you have the
right to remain silent.
Anything you say...
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
It's her choice, right?
Unfortunately.
What do you want to do,
take her to lock up?
Lateral move.
She's already there.
One guy's dead.
One guy's going to jail.
Well, you're free to go.
Go where?
You got my message.
Yeah. You sounded hungry.
I was thinking... dinner
at the Bellagio.
All right.
What are you in
the mood for?
Room service.