( thud )
( tires screeching )
( screaming )
You can breathalyze me
all you want,
but the broad
came right at me, I swear.
It wasn't my fault.
Ooh, that's
what happens when
6,000 pounds of thrust
meets three
feet of hood.
This was not a fair fight.
Well, now, how
did she end up
way over here?
There must
be 20 feet
of rubber burned
into this asphalt.
She was braking hard.
She definitely swerved
out of her lane.
I think I may know why.
What kind of animal are
we talking about here?
A big one.
The victim could have
clipped the animal
when it ran in
front of her.
Well, it can't
have gone far.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
Hmm. Ooh. Not much padding.
Whoa.
This is incredibly detailed.
Eyelashes, nostrils...
Oh, yeah.
That's what you see out of.
I once dated
the Detroit
Lions mascot. Off-season.
Dutch was his name.
The breadth
of your social experience
never ceases to impress me.
Dutch never had furballs,
though.
Are you all right, David?
It's just... disturbing.
There was a big raccoon
who hosted
an after-school kids
show when I was little.
Stripey.
Everybody loved him.
I loved him.
Stripey's brother
suffered
blunt force trauma
caused by a violent collision
with a moving vehicle.
The eternal question--
why did the man
in the raccoon suit
cross the road?
Frozen stiff.
Looks like he died
trying to get out.
Trying to get to
the door, maybe.
It got messy.
Check out
the shotgun spatter.
Single blast.
Went in, went out.
Ooh. This has got to be
the coldest place in Vegas.
Let's go.
Vega's got the security guard.
Yeah, he's not going anywhere.
So, Peter,
when you checked in...
Not Peter.
Petey. P-E-T-E-Y.
Hey, how you doing?
Good.
The shooter may
have cleaned out
the machines.
Those things
hold a lot of dough.
Take was maybe, uh, $600.
They shot a guy
over a vending machine?
So, uh, Petey,
where were you when
all this went down?
I was in the guard shack.
Where else would I be?
You tell us.
If a guy walks
into a freezer,
shoots a guy
and smashes
six vending machines,
I think I'd hear that.
The shack's out there.
You don't make rounds?
Look, I'm not supposed
to leave the premises, okay?
Okay, but if you were here,
you're a suspect.
Come on, man.
Middle of the shift,
you're getting hungry.
You figure, "Hey, I'll duck out,
grab a bite to eat."
Who's going
to know, right?
I was gone five minutes, tops.
When?
A little after 11:00.
Grabbed a burger and came back.
What kind of burger?
In 'N' Out--
three blocks from here.
I always get the In 'N' Out
Double-Double, Animal Style.
That's what I get.
You grill the onions?
Hell, yeah.
Now, that is crazy,
Petey,
'cause you know, being
an In 'N' Out kind of guy,
I know it takes
at least five minutes
to grill the onions
alone.
Come on, man.
That time of night,
you're lucky
if you don't wait
20 minutes
just to get to the window.
Look, my boss
finds out
I'm leaving the site
every night to get my burger on,
I'm toast.
You keep lying to us,
you're going
to be toast in a jumpsuit.
Around 11:00,
this cat George--
he usually works days--
drives up and asks me
where Al is.
Al Sesto?
The guy in the freezer?
I told him he was back here.
I came back.
Everything was quiet.
So I ate my dinner in my shack.
Where'd George go?
Beats me. His car's
still in the parking lot.
Want to show me which one?
Sure.
Unless he was slick,
the guy that did this
definitely left behind a print,
and, frankly,
nothing about this looks slick.
Linda Jones, 35, single.
We're trying to track
down the next-of-kin.
No mystery in cause
of death, though.
Your basic
massive internal trauma.
And then some.
Anything unusual
about our furry friend?
We're about to find out.
Did you know that raccoons
have opposable thumbs?
Well, this one liked
to wrap his around a bottle.
"30 days: One Day at a Time."
He was a friend of Bill W.'s.
I'll send the blood work
down to Tox.
Oh, my--
hand stitching.
Lining looks
like some kind of latex.
GRISSOM:
Whoa. That's
a lot of blood
for blunt force trauma.
This isn't a costume.
It's a six-foot condom.
Explains why there was no blood
on the road.
Yeah, his tailor
didn't think of everything.
His suit's not bulletproof.
Shall we?
Through and through.
It's a high-velocity round.
Gives the bullet
a smooth entry in and out.
So, he was shot
and hit by a car.
Bad night.
Even for a raccoon.
The last time
this happened
they tried to
chop the guy out.
1989-- year the
Mirage opened.
How'd it go?
Lost an arm and a leg.
I miss the cold weather.
So, what are we going to use,
hot water?
Boiling works best.
Just, uh, spread it
around the perimeter.
Melt the ice.
Guys, let's
do it here.
To preserve the body?
That's right.
Close as you can.
All right, guys, let's go.
Hi, Warrick.
Hey.
Anything on Mr. Raccoon?
Yeah.
I got an AFIS hit.
Robert Pitt.
Court-ordered to AA
after a DUI.
Oh, that explains
the 30-day chip.
Maybe he fell off the
wagon after he hit 31.
If I had to walk around
dressed like Rocky Raccoon,
I'd be drinking, too.
I don't get this whole thing.
Oh, hey, Warrick, it's Vegas.
People come here to be animals.
I hear you.
Take a look at this.
Oh, yes, the blue fur
in the vomit.
Yeah, it's synthetic,
not natural.
Your manimal died sober.
No alcohol.
Really?
All this schmohawk
had in his system
was trace amounts of ipecac
and civet oil,
which, if you ask me,
is even weirder
than the raccoon suit
he was wearing.
Well, ipecac's an emetic.
I once gave it to Lindsey
when she swallowed mothballs,
but civet oil?
Yeah. Civet's a wild cat.
Its scent has been prized
since the pharaohs
for being an aphrodisiac.
Pitt was a computer programmer.
No next-of-kin.
Ooh.
Not an Architectural
Digestreader.
( chuckles softly )
If you want to know
what the man
really is all about,
check out his bedroom.
Now, this scares me.
A man lives alone.
Has no relatives.
No attachments.
So, he forms his own
furry little family.
"PAF Con meeting."
What's PAF Con?
I don't know,
but whatever it is,
it's still going on.
Minus one raccoon.
PAF Con?
The Plushies and
Furries Convention.
And we're looking for
a bright blue plushy, I think.
This is fascinating.
A whole tribe of people...
...who prefer to interact
as furry animals
rather than human beings.
I think I'm having
Hunter Thompson's
flashbacks.
This is weirding me out.
It's not that weird.
It's instinctual.
Many Native
American tribes
wore entire bearskins,
including the bead,
when they performed
their war dances.
They thought it
made them brave.
I'm not getting
the brave thing.
Well, think of
stuffed animals as
a Jungian archetype.
What's the one
quality they possess
that a man like Bob
Pitt might want?
A full head of hair?
They're lovable.
We better divide
and mingle.
I'm going to take in
a lecture.
SIDLE:
Uh, why did you page us?
Your wood sample
from the freezer.
The one we gave Hodges?
Yeah. He bounced
it back to me.
I'm lost.
It's from a
shotgun stock.
Probably a
Mossberg 500.
Probably our murder weapon.
Well, if you find
it, I can match it.
Till we do, anything else?
That's up to Hodges.
HODGES:
The gray stuff--
it's adhesive.
On the gun stock?
Cheap repair.
So,
some budget-minded
garage gunsmith
glues his gun stock together...
And then kills Al Sesto
for $600 in change.
Even Petey can do better
than that.
There's always
the elusive "George."
Can I help you, sir?
Yeah, I want to report a crime.
Let's start with
what you were doing
at Big &amp; Best Warehouse, George.
You're the day guy.
It was the night shift there.
Expired ice cream.
Trash for cash.
You're selling expired
ice cream?
It's still good.
Oh.
Go on, please.
I wanted to give Al
his piece of the action,
88 bucks.
We, uh, walked into
the break room, and
someone was smashing
up the candy machine.
Ski mask?
Yeah.
And he had a gun.
Better chill, bro.
Okay.
Get back.
Don't shoot!
Shut up!
Don't shoot.
( gunshot )
He shot Al.
Then the guy hauls off
and brains me.
And after that,
everything went black.
Everything went black?
SIDLE:
That's a pretty
nasty bruise.
Yeah, I told you.
VEGA:
So,
you blacked out.
Then what happened?
I was blindfolded,
shoved into the
trunk of some
car and, uh,
drove around for almost an hour.
It, uh, glows
in the dark.
Oh, yeah.
Hmm.
STOKES:
So, uh,
now, how did you get out?
Tire iron.
I felt around in the dark,
and, uh,
there it was.
STOKES:
Where?
Under the, uh,
the trunk liner.
I had to really twist
to get at it.
Which hand did you use?
Right.
VEGA:
And then what?
I popped the trunk.
( metal clanking )
I-I was in Pahrump.
I got family out there, but
nobody was home.
All right, MacGyver,
could you do me a favor?
Could you stand up
and hold your arms out?
I'm just going
to check you out here.
( soft chuckle )
I'm ticklish.
Oh.
George...
I'm afraid you
and your pants are going
to be here for a while.
In The Eight Ages of Man,
Erikson states
that the child often indulges
in fantasies of being a tiger,
but in his dream,
runs in terror
for dear life,
thus leaving the child
forever divided in himself,
as his true potential
is squashed
by the observing superego
of society.
Birth is-is not destiny.
And a human form doesn't
always come with a human spirit.
We gather here
to embrace our inner animal,
and to bring our true nature
to bear.
So to speak.
Five-minute break.
( applause )
Excuse me. Do you recognize
this man, Robert Pitt?
Oh.
Hello, guys.
Pardon me.
Uh, can you help me out here?
Do you recognize this guy?
Look-look again.
Uh-uh.
Hmm.
Nice dog.
There you go.
I'm Catherine Willows.
I'm with the Crime Lab.
( hissing )
GRISSOM:
I guess we're lucky
that blue's not a more
popular color.
Wait.
This is racial profiling.
Um, we're going
to need samples
of your fur.
We're also going to need
to talk to you
without the masks on.
Uh-uh.
You have a problem with that?
You wouldn't ask a human lady
to take her makeup off.
If you want
to talk to me,
this is the me
you're going to talk to.
Take this chair right here.
Do you a have a name,
Miss, uh...?
My friends call me Sexy.
Oh, lucky you.
Now, do you want some help
with the... your helmet?
I'm a lawyer.
I know my rights.
You can't sequester
a domestic animal
without due cause.
Well, it's coming off
one way or the other, so...
Fine, fine.
Hello,
Sexy.
Okay. Happy now?
Thrilled.
Let's start
at the top.
What's your
human name, sir?
Bud. Bud Simmons.
But I'm no criminal,
and I don't have to talk
to you people.
You have a very
musky odor, Bud.
Quite stimulating,
I imagine.
Look, we found
blue fibers
similar to the ones
on your costume
in the stomach
of a dead man.
Bob Pitt.
Huh?
You may know him
as Rocky Raccoon?
You think
my costume killed Rocky?
We think
it may have incapacitated him.
Rocky was...
skritching me.
That's one I haven't heard.
Skritching is like grooming.
It's friendly scratching.
People who don't know each other
can't just nuzzle
and trade tummy-rubs,
but for animals,
skritching is perfectly normal.
Well, killing is
perfectly normal for them, too.
It doesn't make it legal
for you.
Well, clearly, this
kitty costume is
where Bud felt safe
enough to skritch.
I wonder if he also
felt safe enough
to explore some of the more...
aggressive aspects
of his animus.
So, if we follow the ipecac
and civet oil,
maybe it'll lead us
to the shooter.
I don't see a compartment
for a concealed rifle.
( soft chuckle )
( whirring )
Okay, well... I've heard
of some guys getting off
in some weird ways,
but humping
an animal suit?
Well, whatever happened
to normal sex?
What is normal sex?
Uh, you think it's natural
for a grown human
to only be intimate
with a talking animal?
Well, Freud said that the only
unnatural sexual behavior
was to have none at all.
And after that,
it's just a question
of opportunity
and preference.
And evidently,
many prefer the feel of fur
to the texture of human skin.
Well, I like hairy chests,
but I'm not about
to bop a six-foot weasel.
Bud is starting
to look like
a pretty
bad cat.
Trace from
his costume.
Well, identical to the trace
we found
in Rocky Raccoon's vomit.
Ipecac and civet oil.
Well, that's what you get
for eating...
What kind of
a knucklehead
rolls into PD
wearing pants
with blood on them?
The kind
that knows eventually,
the cops are going
to want to talk to him.
Yeah.
Preemptive strike, huh?
There's only one drop here,
and it originated
on the inside of the cuff.
I don't think George knew
he had blood on him.
We need to get this
to Greg.
I was in that freezer.
Man, there was spatter
everywhere.
Now, assuming
that is Al's blood,
how does George not get it
on the outside of his pants?
Do you think George
is telling the truth?
SIDLE:
Room temperature:
72 degrees.
STOKES:
Okay...
...fire in the hole.
That's what blood spatter
looks like
at room temperature.
Now for the good stuff.
Changing one variable.
Dropping temperature
to 22 degrees.
That explains how only
one drop of blood got on
the inside of George's pants.
( gunshot )
When he left the freezer,
the drop melted.
Shooter was standing
in front of Al.
A spatter went back
and to the sides.
George is not the shooter.
So, who is
the masked man?
Well, Lone Ranger had Tonto.
Some doofus has George.
Tape lifts
from your suspect's clothing,
loaded with paint chips.
What kind?
Dual layers.
The bottom one's burgundy
vehicle paint.
Factory pigment
used on 1984 Monte Carlo.
What's the top layer?
In an unprecedented move,
whoever it was painted
over the burgundy with...
Want to venture a guess?
Bright blue house paint.
Doofus.
Why would somebody
use house paint on a car?
Maybe he remodeled
the breakfast nook
and had some left over.
Who knows?
I don't try to figure out
what people do anymore.
That's smart.
Yeah, I know.
Oil and water.
Love to be there when
his hood starts to peel.
Okay, first things first.
Let's go find the car.
BRASS:
Okay, Bud, I'm going
to get right to it.
Bob Pitt's semen was found
all over your kitty costume.
You lied to us.
You were doing a little more
than grooming.
It started as a skritch,
then everyone got in a furpile
and pretty soon,
we were all yiffing.
I get "furpile."
Define "yiffing."
In a furpile,
when all the animals
start rubbing and wiggling,
some of them start to do things.
The kind of things
that leave semen on your fur?
That never happened before.
( chuckles wryly )
Okay.
That happened before.
I know what you're thinking.
You couldn't possibly.
I didn't kill Rocky Raccoon.
Did you smear
ipecac and civet oil
on the back of your costume?
That's crazy.
I was there for the yiffing,
and that's all.
Look, if I don't
have my costume on,
I pretty much can't get yiffed.
Okay, Bud.
We're going to leave you
some time to think about it.
Enjoy your new costume.
( sighs )
Are you buying
this guy?
Oh, who the hell knows
what goes on in a furpile?
But if somebody doused their
special scent on Kitty's back,
I'm sure he's going to
want to know who did it.
Well, he gives us
all the furnames
of people in the pile.
What are we going to do--
put out an APB on Tom and Jerry?
Maybe we just ask him
where the hip, young
plushy-on-the-go
likes to hang out?
Password, please?
E-I-E-I-O?
This is a private party.
Uh, we have an invitation
from the Las Vegas
Police Department.
Uh, okay.
Whoa, Nellie!
Is this a raid?
It's a homicide investigation.
Look, we need you to stop
skritching or yiffing
or whatever, take
off your costumes,
and tell us your names.
Ooh!
These costumes
are pretty marinated.
Smokey could've used
some deodorant.
Well, you know, pheromones
are the basis
for mammalian reproduction.
When the female is in estrus,
the male picks up
on her come-get-me scent.
But most mammals only
copulate seasonally.
How boring.
For some.
No one else in that furpile
threw up, right?
Uh, Rocky was a target.
( blows air )
Smell this.
Civet oil and ipecac.
So I guess
we're looking for a wolf...
in wolf's clothing.
GRISSOM:
Mr. Lee, the concentration
of ipecac and civet oil
on your paws
speaks to application,
rather than accidental transfer.
Okay. Fine.
I... I mixed up some ipecac
and some civet oil
and I-I... I rubbed it
on Sexy... Sexy Kitty.
Why Sexy Kitty?
'Cause Rocky couldn't
get enough of her.
What did Rocky do to you?
He's a raccoon.
They're all lowlifes.
I mean, honestly,
what do they do?
Screw...
eat garbage...
screw some more.
Is this a, uh,
general observation,
or possibly
a personal grievance?
At last year's convention,
Rocky stole my girlfriend.
And in the wild,
wolves are monogamous,
but raccoons are promiscuous.
That's right.
And I just, I knew,
I knew since Sexy Kitty
was Rocky's fave, he'd have
his filthy raccoon mouth
all over her again this year.
All I wanted to do
was make him sick enough
so that he'd have to go home
and stop cheating on my mate.
Your ex-mate?
Yes.
I couldn't take seeing
what that wanna-be marsupial
put her through.
My Linda Lamb deserved better.
Mr. Lee, you're a wolf.
How'd you end up with a lamb?
I used to work with Linda.
And one day, I found out about
what she did on the weekends.
And she helped me...
become who I am.
I always knew
that I was a...
something else.
And... Linda made it real.
She was one of a kind.
Does, uh, Linda Lamb
have a human last name?
Jones.
Why?
GRISSOM:
Linda Jones is Linda Lamb.
Damn it.
This was here
the whole time.
Yeah, but evidence without
context is not evidence.
We had no reason
to search the trunk.
So she didn't just hit
Rocky, she knew him.
For the philandering raccoon
that he was.
GRISSOM:
Okay, assuming that
Linda and Bob were heading home
after Bob got sick
at the hotel,
how did he end up on
the side of the road?
You ever have
a car-fight?
Well, if a couple has
any kind of history together,
they know how to press
each other's buttons.
And you lock 'em up
in a metal box with wheels
on a bad night, they're going
to start pressing 'em.
You follow?
So, uh, either Bob told Linda
to stop the car and let him out,
or she told him
to start walking?
Yes. That one.
I mean, it's bad enough
that raccoon-boy
blows his girlfriend off
to go fur-piling--
he gets sick licking
some nasty kitty
and makes Lambchop
drive him home.
Which begs
the question:
why did she turn the car around
and head back toward the hotel?
Well, she wasn't heading back
to the hotel.
She was heading back
for him.
'Cause that's how
car-fights always end.
After about a mile or two,
you start to feel guilty
that you've abandoned
the person, and you turn around.
Except she didn't plan
on an 18-wheeler
finishing her off.
Mack truck ex machina.
But it still
doesn't explain
how Bob got shot
in the back.
No...
but I think I may know
the last person
who saw them alive.
Why don't we ask
the valet
if he remembers a couple of...
furriest conventioneers?
Hey, Sara, no
luck on the car,
but Hodges ran the
gunstock adhesive.
It's primarily an
epoxy polyester resin
with traces of styrene
and benzyl peroxide
and ground terra-cotta.
Is that supposed
to mean something to me?
Terra-cotta's the giveaway.
It's a granite glue.
Granite glue?
Yeah. It's used
for adhering joints
on big pieces of stone.
House paint on his car;
granite glue on his gun...
Well, he used what
was available.
That's what people do.
Well, I understand
the house paint,
but where do you get
granite glue?
I already checked.
There's not too many
places in Clark County
that specialize
in granite
installation, so...
Okay, I will bet you
a double-double animal style
that one of them employs a guy
with a blue 1984 Monte Carlo.
That's a bet.
Excellent.
( laughs )
Damn straight
I remember them.
How often do you see
a six-foot raccoon heaving
out a car window?
Dude was hammered, man.
His girl... she was pissed.
Thank you.
You've been
very helpful.
All right, no problem.
Hey, I got that.
So, there's
your car-fight.
Now she thinks
that he's back on the booze,
which he denies,
but the sicker he gets,
the more she thinks he's lying.
I can't believe
you're drinking again.
You promised.
I was not drinking.
( grunting )
Must be food poisoning.
( chuckling ):
Oh?
Didn't know they served
food in a furpile.
The Righteously Angry
versus the Wrongly Accused.
And the battle's just beginning.
( gagging )
Would you just take off
the mask and talk to me?!
No, just pull over
and let me out of the car!
You want out?
Ah...
( brakes squeal )
Get out!
Just get out!
( gagging )
Okay, so it makes sense
up to that point, but then what?
He gets out and...
...she shoots him?
I'm not so sure that people
who dress up like cuddly
forest creatures carry guns.
You don't think they allow
plushies in the NRA?
All right, then who shot him?
Well, we have
a grassy knoll...
but no Lee Harvey Oswald.
You're a triple threat--
robbery,
kidnapping, murder.
Big &amp; Best Foods,
Al Sesto, George Bartell.
Any of this resonate?
I don't know no Al Sesto.
( Stokes clears throat )
SIDLE:
Virgil, is that your shotgun?
We found it in your garage.
If, uh, you look,
you'll see a chip in the stock.
We found that in the freezer
at the Big &amp; Best Foods.
( chuckles )
Is this your car?
It was also
in your garage.
It has dual-layered paint,
identical to the dual-layered
paint chips
we found
on your kidnap victim.
Anything to say, tough guy?
Yeah.
I want a lawyer.
( beeping faintly )
Hey, Grissom.
Over here.
I found the bullet.
GRISSOM:
Well done.
So, we got a sick raccoon
with an abdominal
through-and-through
who was shot from what appears
to be a fairly steep trajectory.
WILLOWS:
So, either he was shot
by a giant...
or he was, uh, on all fours.
( gunshot, ping )
Or both.
I mean, imagine
what it must have
looked like out here at night
and from a distance.
We've been looking for...
a person who
shot a person,
but...
...maybe we should be looking
for a person who shot an animal.
Hey, Virgil.
What are you doing here?
What am I doing here?
Yeah.
Why, you guys
know each other?
Yeah, that's my cousin.
Pahrump?
My own blood, and you set me up.
After I saved
your ass.
I should have shot you
in that freezer.
You son of a bitch!
VEGA:
Hey, hey!
You looking
for more time?
Now come on.
GEORGE:
Oh, man.
I'm so stupid.
Ah, you're not stupid.
Man, your cousin
just set you up.
Bowling night.
Is that where you told him
about the vending machines?
And
Petey's burger runs?
My own cousin.
Well... George,
sometimes people, they, uh,
disappoint
us.
Why?
( barking )
How you doing?
Can I help you?
We're with the
Las Vegas Crime Lab.
This your place?
Yeah.
Must be here
about that accident.
Terrible thing.
Like I said
to the wife,
the way these 18-wheelers
fly down here ballin' the jack,
I ain't surprised.
I'm surprised
there ain't more accidents.
Why don't you give us
a brief history of your evening?
Ah, well, I had dinner
with the missus.
Uh, fed the scraps to the dogs.
Uh, watched Jeopardy.
Could hardly hear it,
the dogs were, uh,
so stirred up.
Went outside to take a look,
spotted a coyote.
This is my business.
Purebreds.
Wouldn't want to lose one.
So, I, uh,
took care of it.
Came back inside in time
for Final Jeopardy.
So the raccoon was mistaken
for a coyote.
You gotta be kidding me.
He was dosed intentionally,
but killed accidentally.
We got the ranger's rifle,
we collected a bullet
at the scene,
and ballistics
made a match.
Bob Pitt was sick
when he got out
of the car,
wounded when he
got onto the road,
and dead when
he hit the dirt.
Get out!
Just get out!
( gagging )
( retching )
( cocking rifle )
( gunshot )
Well, the rancher's going
to get off,
Linda's dead, and Wolfie...
skates with a misdemeanor.
We took one look
at those furry suits
and thought "foul play,"
but this was really just
a domestic dispute gone mad.
Hmm. Fur and loathing
in Las Vegas.