I'm going to make this really simple.
Who are you workin' with?
I'm, uh, unemployed
at the moment.
You got any idea
what we did to chumps
like you back in the day?
Uh, no.
Look, could you put the A.C. on
in here
or somethin'?
That, or just, uh,
let me go.
I mean, you can't keep me
in here.
It's against the law.
There's no law
in this room.
You can't touch me.
Two shots to the back
of the head.
Double tap.
He's wearing a wig
and a fat suit.
It's not Halloween, is it?
In this town,
it's always Halloween.
BRASS:
"Ernie Menlo."
Well, he wasn't carrying
a very "fat" wad.
CATHERINE:
Rolex is still on his wrist.
Probably rules out
robbery.
What do you think?
I don't know.
I'm looking for a sign.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
He's not in the system?
Yeah... gotta be.
Okay. Thanks.
So, uh...
Brass ran the ID.
There's no "Ernie Menlo"
in the system.
Fake.
GRISSOM:
GSR in the wound track.
No stellate tearing.
Gunshots appear
to be close range,
but noncontact.
PHILLIPS:
No exit wounds.
Well, I don't see
any shell casings either.
So maybe the killer
picked them up.
Professional hit?
PHILLIPS:
Major fractures and lacerations
on his hands.
Lividity's consistent
with body position.
I don't think
it was a body dump.
So either he walked in
or he got a ride.
Either way,
this gravel and glass
makes good evidence.
GRISSOM:
I'll go ahead and bag a sample.
"Rampart Casino."
Well, his day started out good.
He won $436,278.
Rampart's always been lucky
for me.
So where
is this money?
I found some tire treads.
I think the vehicle
was making a three-point turn.
And it seems that robbery
may be a motive after all.
CATHERINE:
Wow!
"Rampart."
Guess I'll go check that out.
You can't.
We found the body
under the Whiskey
Town sign
and the guy
just cleaned out
the Rampart Casino.
Coincidence.
Even if it is,
they're still
Sam Braun's casinos.
Why is that a problem?
He's your father.
You can't be
on this case.
Gil...
Catherine,
you have to go home.
No ticks.
It's authentic.
Logo sticker isn't worn down.
Watch could be new.
Guy hits the jackpot,
has to celebrate.
Goes and buys
some bling-bling
to impress
the strippers with.
What have you got?
Air conditioned socks.
♪ ... I can hear the sound
of violins ♪
Insurance?
♪ Long before it begins... ♪
Dealer wins.
CROUPIER:
Seven!
( players groan )
24 is even.
So, I talked
to the pit boss
who signed the vic's W-2.
He was pulling surveillance.
He remembers
the big winner.
Sam Braun!
What a surprise!
The fat kid...
he was cheating.
What do you do about it?
Well, we had
a little chat.
I didn't kill him.
Did you take him to the box?
Gentlemen, these
days, we call it
the holding room.
Smells like
the cleaning crew
just left.
Security brought
the kid
down here around 2:00 a.m.
I came in.
We talked.
He walked out around 3:00.
It's all in there.
Well, good.
We'll look at the tapes
a little later.
Would you turn off
the lights, please?
It's well within my rights
to have a discussion
with anyone
in my place.
The kid was cheating.
I wanted to know how.
Nobody wins 400K at roulette.
What's your system?
Clean living... good karma.
But either you call
the cops
and book me now,
or I'm out of here.
You're no longer welcome
at the Rampart.
Awesome.
Okay, I'll take
my money and go.
Do you have any idea
the house advantage
in roulette?
5.26%
Albert Einstein
had a theory
about roulette.
He said the only way
to win at roulette
is to steal the money
from the table
when the croupier
isn't looking.
There's always someone looking.
GRISSOM:
Well, maybe it was
an inside job, Sam.
Maybe somebody bought off
one of your guys.
I'm curious.
What bothers you more?
The fact that you couldn't
pin a murder on me
or that Catherine
cashed my check?
There were no strings
on that money.
Just because you can't
see something
doesn't mean
it's not there.
Believe whatever you like.
That kid walked out
of here with my money.
If you figure out
how he ripped me off,
would you let me know?
ROBBINS:
For what it's worth,
these bruises correspond
to the holes in his sock.
Well, he's been worked over
pretty good.
He's got a
nice fat lip.
Yeah.
There was a good clot
in the wound,
and the tissues
were contused.
I'd say it occurred
at least an hour
or two before death.
I teased out
a couple of small-
caliber projectiles
from his brain.
One was embedded
in the right
frontal cortex.
The other lodged in the
first cervical vertebra.
It's copper-washed
lead.
Must be a .22.
You know,
historically,
.22s were the hit man's
bullet of choice.
They have the energy to enter
into the cranial vault,
but not enough to exit,
so they just ricochet around
inside, shredding
the gray matter until they stop.
Nice.
There's also extensive
crush injury to both hands,
with fractures of
the metacarpals
and the phalanges.
Bruises appear perimortem.
Any idea what might have caused
that kind of damage?
Given the
fracture pattern,
I'd guess it was some
sort of blunt object.
Maybe
a ball peen hammer.
What gets you to that?
They used to tell me
back in the days,
the first time
you got caught cheating,
they'd give you
a couple whacks on the hand
with a ball peen hammer.
Ow.
The second time,
you'd lose a limb.
Third time?
A long walk in the desert
with a shovel.
A computer in his shoe.
As far as I could tell,
it's a wireless receiver.
It picks up a signal,
solenoids drive the points
up against the guy's foot,
tells him
what number to bet.
Based on what?
I don't know.
Archie's working on it
right now.
Well, if our vic
was the receiver,
there has to be
a transmitter.
Hey, I got an ID on our vic.
A Teddy Keller.
Everyone who buys a Rolex
gets registered
at the point of purchase.
So I ran the serial number.
He bought the watch
at the Forum Shops two days ago.
And I got his home address.
Well, his driver's
license was fake,
so, this could
be fake, too.
A fake ID
is for scamming a casino.
A baller puts his real name
on a Roley.
What? He rubs off.
MAN:
Teddy Keller.
That's Apartment 27.
Is he in some kind of trouble?
Hey, John.
Hey, Mr. Green.
When was the last time
you saw him?
I don't know.
He's got a roommate--
Davis Mullens.
Oh, yeah, they eat
a tremendous amount of pizza.
Tremendous amount of pizza
and calzone.
I feel like bopping
that delivery guy
every time he
buzzes the gate.
Here we are.
( knocking at door )
Anybody home?
( knocking )
Hello?
I guess the roommate's out, huh?
It's freezing in here.
Get a load
of this wheel.
It's regulation.
These things run
about 1,500 bucks.
Well, they cleared
almost half a mil.
It's a good investment.
Yeah.
These guys
definitely had a system.
Hey, Rick, you might want
to check this out.
Looks like the roommate's home
after all.
Two taps to the head.
Deja vu.
These guys liked to play
dress-up.
You find any shoes
back there?
I'm looking.
Blood smear here.
Maybe the killer tried
to clean up.
That's ridiculous.
Why bother?
Okay.
Have a distinctive white mark
on his right shoulder.
What do you make of that?
You already shot me down once.
Look, uh, it could be right.
Thanks.
Can you make sure
that gets to Trace?
Yeah. Sure.
Hey, what're you doing,
touching that?
You got gloves?
Relax. I got
it covered.
Hey, Rick, remember
the time you said
you could get
a print off of air?
Yeah.
So you just got
the day off?
Just... Just like that?
Are you complaining?
No.
You just seem a little
pissed off about it.
I like it.
You like that?
Depends on what you're
gonna do with it.
Pretty expensive taste
for a public servant.
She can afford it.
You going to introduce him?
Mr. Braun.
Chris Bezich.
It's a pleasure
to meet you.
Your hosts,
send a lot of your whales
to my club, Acid Drop.
That's great.
Just give us a minute.
Okay.
What do you want?
Mugs, I heard
you had some time off
because of me.
I could get fired for even
having this conversation.
Relax.
Vegas is a small town.
I'm always running into people
I know.
Just cut to the chase, Sam.
Some people in this town
think I'm a murderer.
know you're a murderer.
I did not kill those kids.
I did not!
Kids?
How do you know
there's more than one?
Cath...
I'm fine.
You're not impressing her.
I'll be in touch.
You and Sam Braun...
He slept with my mother.
HODGES:
The glass fragments you found
at the apartment building
are primarily lead-based.
Different curvatures
and textures
with traces of
florescent powder,
phosphorus
and mercury.
Neon glass.
I checked out
that graveyard once.
Pretty interesting.
The comparison?
Your sample's consistent
with the glass collected
from the first crime scene.
See?
That connects the two murders.
We've got a timeline.
Hey.
Everything okay?
This is about the key
CSI position.
Grissom recommended me.
Congratulations.
It's not necessary.
Position was cut.
Budget had room
for the new promotion
or a new Qiagen,
Bio Robot EZ-1.
Greg will be thrilled.
Yeah.
Oh, well, it's just an honor
to be nominated, right?
Grissom, I have been in Vegas
my whole life.
I've known guys
who counted cards,
hedged bets,
crushed a poker table
with a lowball pair.
I've seen guys beat the
house with their hands...
but never with their toes.
Transmitter and receiver.
I was reading about
these Silicon Valley
types in the '80s
called the...
Eudaemonic Enterprises.
Have you heard of them?
The Eudaemon.
Aristotle's presiding
spirit of rationality.
They say they figured
out a way to beat
the roulette wheel.
Not through a betting system,
but through physics.
It's simple in principle.
A fixed mass in a known orbit.
As long as you can account
for all the forces--
air resistance, friction,
gravity--
you can land a probe on Mars.
WARRICK:
Every roulette wheel
is a little different.
Tilt, wobble, bounce...
The guy with the transmitter
does the calibration,
clocks the position of the
ball,
hits the switch...
and the computer does the rest.
Plays out the spin
in milliseconds,
Predicts the result,
then transmits a code
to the receiver about
where that ball will land.
All right, big money,
big money!
$1,000 on four, 22, five and 17.
It's number 22.
( cheering )
This setup gives you
a 44-percent advantage
over the house.
For every hundred
these guys bet,
they're pulling in $2,200
an hour.
Nice return.
But it's a complicated system.
STOKES:
Complicated, huh?
Maybe for a couple
of pizza majors.
But not for an electrical
engineering grad student.
AFIS got a hit on the print
off the transmitter
in the shoe.
Seth Landers. WLVU.
Got busted a few years
ago for making fake IDs.
BRASS:
Seth Landers
doesn't have a roommate.
No answer at his door.
Guy's in the wind.
If someone hit my
boys all mob-style
I'd disappear, too,
you know?
Yeah, I guess we're gonna
have to do this the hard way.
I'll put out a broadcast.
Wait a minute.
Hey, kid...
you know Seth Landers?
Uh-oh.
Stop!
Don't kill me!
Please! I'll do whatever
Mr. Braun wants!
Please don't kill me!
Please!
Las Vegas Police.
You Seth Landers?
Yeah.
Seth Landers?
Yes!
Let's go.
BRASS:
Jacking Sam Braun's
casino at roulette--
that was gutsy... and smart.
And since you weren't
the one placing the bet,
I guess that makes
you the smart one.
BROWN:
Your boys
right here--
Teddy and Davis,
the candid camera.
They came to me.
It was their idea.
Judging from what we
found in your apartment,
looks like you made
their idea work.
I built the computers
to put in the shoes.
That's all.
BRASS:
Your partners
cleared half a mil
on your skills.
Dollar signs get involved,
things get ugly, huh?
Scam was 20 to 30K
a night, max.
We hit Pike's.
Next day, Tangiers.
Everything was great.
We made 50 grand,
and then Teddy and Davis
got greedy.
You can't crush a roulette table
like that,
and not expect someone
to notice.
The Tangiers, Pike's, Rampart...
these are all
Sam Braun's places.
You got something against him?
No.
His casinos are old school.
They're low tech.
There's less interference
for my gear.
Your gear...
What was your cut?
I didn't get one.
I just got paid
for my supplies and my time.
That's all.
( scoffing ):
Yeah, picture that!
It was a challenge.
I just wanted
to see if I could make it work.
Any idea where the money is?
Why don't you ask Sam Braun?
When they took Teddy
to the "box,"
I was sure we were busted.
Davis freaked.
He split.
And then when he came out
with the money,
everything was great.
For about two seconds.
They grabbed him
and led him outside.
That was the last time
I saw either one of them.
( insistent knocking )
What are you doing?
I'm testing
my podiatric dexterity.
What are you doing?
Uh, you know those tracks that
we found at the neon graveyard?
The ones from the case
you're not working on?
Yeah, those.
Sam...
used to be a Caddy man.
He would drive a
new one every year.
These days, he's being driven.
And you know this
because...?
I saw him.
He came to me.
And you walked away,
I hope.
I made him walk away
from me.
Right into a stretch limo
with a big turning radius.
That doesn't prove anything.
Besides, any evidence
that comes from you is tainted.
Then have it come
from you.
Warrant shouldn't be hard
to get.
Especially if the call comes
from someone
whose character is
above reproach.
Nick said the budget
for the promotion was cut.
240 inches-- 20 feet.
He also said
you recommended him.
I did.
Possible neon glass fragment.
You said you didn't have
a problem with me.
I don't.
I thought that Nick was the best
candidate for the position.
Why?
Because he didn't
care whether he got
the job or not.
That's a stupid reason.
We've got blood.
Handle your scandal.
Sam Braun?
You're under arrest
for the murder of Teddy Keller.
Is this some kind of joke?
I'm not laughing.
Call my lawyer.
This won't take long.
Sam?
I'm parked out front.
As much as my client appreciates
your flair for the dramatic,
the show's over, gentlemen.
What do you have?
The tire patterns at the scene
of Teddy Keller's murder
are consistent
with the wheel base
and turning radius of
your client's limousine.
As well as
every other limo in Vegas.
We also found neon glass
embedded in all four tires.
LAWYER:
The whole town's
a construction site.
It's a tenuous link, at best.
Well, then...
how did his blood end up
in the back
of your client's limousine?
BRASS:
You waited until
Teddy cleared
the security cameras...
( grunting )
We're not through talking, kid.
And then you took him
for a ride...
Vegas style.
Just like
the old days.
( panting )
Let me show you
what I do to cheaters.
( panting rapidly )
( wailing ):
No, no!
My client offered the young man
a ride home.
They stopped briefly
at the neon graveyard,
where they held
a private conversation
regarding the ethics
of defrauding a casino.
( Brass chuckles )
That must have been
some chat.
We know he left the casino
with the money.
The young man returned
the money
as a sign of respect
for my client
and his position
in the community.
I'm sure he did.
So, what next?
You gonna tell me
you're being set up?
It happens to you a lot,
huh, Sam?
Your smudge from that
second kid's shirt--
I got a spectral
library match
to Sherwin-Williams
EverClean interior
paint, Navajo White.
Anything distinctive?
I would have
mentioned it.
Sometimes a paint sample's
just a paint sample.
Yeah.
You still liking Braun
for these murders?
Yeah, why? Something change?
I'm thinking Seth Landers and
his pals had a woody for him.
I went back to the
Rampart, and I took
some electronic
noise measurements.
The place is a mess
of interference.
Electronics in
old casinos
aren't shielded.
So, you're saying
that the shoe computers
would've worked better
in one of the new casinos
on the Strip?
Definitely.
A kid as smart as Seth
wouldn't make a mistake
like that.
Then it was intentional.
Maybe personal.
( coins feeding )
So, this is your
casino of choice?
That's what your
tenants said.
Sir, could you tell us
about Seth Landers?
That's my son.
Is he okay?
( sighing )
Let's stop playing dumb,
Mr. Greene, huh?
Would you mind
stepping away from the machine?
You're staring over my shoulder,
you're looking at me.
You're jinxing me,
and I'm gonna have to...
How's that? Is that better?
What happened to your hand?
I had an accident
a long time ago.
Sam Braun do that
with a hammer?
I'm sorry, I don't know
who that person is.
Who is that?
I don't like to talk
about my hand, okay?
BRASS:
Well, that's too bad.
'Cause you know what?
Today... this is your life.
BRASS:
Joe Greene-- AKA Joe Landers.
They're old friends.
Sorry to break up
the reunion, fellas.
Mr. Greene... Mr. Landers...
Which is it?
It's Greene.
Come with me.
Do your hands hurt
when it rains, Joe?
Do I know you?
The exclusion/exemption clause
means you don't get to gamble.
Period.
Not even the quarter
slots at the Gas-and-Go.
Don't you have
something better to do?
Like find out who murdered
those two kids in number 27.
You got any theories?
It was your apartment building.
Your son Seth fingered the guy
you were sitting next to.
A guy you don't know.
The guy who put you in
the Black Book.
No. The Gaming Commission
put me in the Black Book.
Yeah, for cheating, Joe.
I did not cheat.
I didn't have
to cheat.
I beat the casinos.
I beat 'em, and they ganged up
on me, and, uh...
that was it, they didn't want
me there anymore.
You beat Sam Braun's casino
and he ended
your gambling career.
You're barred from the casinos
for life.
That sounds like
motive to me.
Motive for what,
playing the quarter slots?
Come on.
Okay, look, here's a quiz.
Teddy Keller,
Davis Mullins
and your son Seth
were caught fleecing
the Rampart.
Now two of 'em are dead.
I had no idea what
those two boys were doing.
But I will tell you this--
I will tell you that my son is
a good kid, he's a good boy.
Then why'd you put him
in the middle of your action?
Why'd you use him
to settle an old score?
Maybe Sam Braun's innocent.
Maybe Seth whacked his partners
because he got caught.
Stop looking at my son,
stop looking at me,
and start looking at Sam.
MAN:
Garbage detail
called it in.
Says they
didn't touch it.
Well, this is
Seth Landers' dorm.
There's a lot
of garbage build up.
When was the last pick-up?
Day before yesterday.
End of finals party last night.
Looks like blood.
Let's hope the killer left
his DNA behind.
.22 revolver,
two live rounds, four expended.
Should be able to pull
some prints off it.
Gun's a relic.
Doesn't matter
if it still works.
There you go.
The test fire matches the bullet
found in Teddy Keller's body.
So we've got
our murder weapon.
Yeah, we found
I don't know.
The kid thinks up
this elaborate scheme
to cheat the casinos.
Then he kills his partners.
But he dumps his gun
at his dorm?
An RG .22.
That's not a very bad ass'
first weapon of choice.
No, it's a small caliber weapon
for an up-close-and-personal
hit.
I don't really see
the kid pulling a Gotti.
Okay, two victims,
two taps to the head.
But the loads are different.
Well, maybe he ran
out of ammo.
Went back and bought
another brand.
And reloaded, yeah.
The bullets that were found
in Teddy Keller's skull,
were copper washed
CCI .22s.
And the two rounds found
in Davis Mullins
were Remington brass washed.
So, based on
the position
of the cylinder
Remingtons were fired first?
But that would mean that
Davis Mullins was killed
in the apartment
before Teddy Keller was killed
in the Graveyard.
The timeline's off.
Blood on the shirt
is a match to Davis Mullins.
Epithelials from
inside the shirt
belong to Seth Landers.
What?
That means Sam Braun's
innocent. This time.
Are you disappointed?
It's the evidence.
What's up, man?
Am I going
to get out of here?
No.
Where did you go after
Teddy Keller was taken?
You know what, you keep on
asking me all these questions,
but my lawyer says I'm not even
supposed to talk to you.
Okay, you don't have
to talk to me.
But you got to know you're
looking at two counts of murder.
What?
I didn't kill anybody.
This is crazy.
Then talk to me.
Tell me what happened.
Where did you go?
For real.
I waited outside
the casino for an hour.
Teddy didn't show up
so I went to his place.
Davis, where are you, man?
Braun got Teddy.
Davis, wake up, man!
We found the murder weapon
that was used to kill
your two partners.
It was wrapped
in your bloody T-shirt.
Can you tell me about that?
I have never used
a gun in my life.
It was found outside
of your campus apartment.
That can't be.
Can be.
Unless you clear it up.
Um...
The rule was
that if something
went wrong,
we were supposed
to just go home.
Uh... so I found the body,
got blood all over my shirt,
so... I gave it to my dad.
I gave my dad the shirt.
He's the one who had the shirt.
Dad! Dad!
Davis... Davis is dead.
I think they got
Teddy, too.
Braun's on to us.
What am I
going to do?
Give me your shirt.
Go back to school
and lay low.
Are you trying to tell me
that your own father set you up?
The truth is, I just wanted
him to like me.
But I'm not him.
You know, I'm never going
to be him.
Counting cards
and the poker face.
They say it's a skill,
but it's a gift.
Till Sam Braun took it away.
So you went after Sam Braun to
prove something to your old man.
I mean, I went after the whale,
but I skinned it.
I did
what my dad could never do.
Does your father own a .22?
I got nothing.
Maybe he was expecting us.
You think he cleaned up?
Well, if he did...
he missed a spot.
Nice and new in here.
Sherwin Williams,
latex flat.
Navajo White.
What do you know.
Same as the paint
on the shirt.
What's in the bag, Dad?
Money from...
the Tangiers...
Money from Pike's.
Bet there's 50 grand in there.
Plus...
what could be paint
and blood smears.
That blood could match
the stains we found
on Davis' shirt.
I don't understand why
he had to kill his kids.
They were making a lot
of money off of Braun.
Dad was getting his revenge.
My guess, stopped being
about the money.
( phone ringing )
Yeah.
Hey, Joe, it's Teddy.
Oh, hi, Teddy.
Sam's on to us.
He took me to Neon Graveyard.
Slow down, slow down.
I had to give him the money.
I thought he was going
to kill me.
Don't move. I'll be there
in a minute.
Mr. Greene,
what's up, man?
Hey...
( gunshots )
Why settle for the money,
when you can frame up
your worst enemy for murder.
Hey, what the hell
took you so long?
Joe... Joe we
got a problem.
Sam... Sam he...
Turn around and walk.
( gunshots )
Sam.
Could I buy you some dinner?
Feeling a little guilty?
Hey, Sam, where's
the ice?
BRAUN:
Next to the TV, kid.
You want to catch a cheater--
hire one.
Right.
He gets to work off his debt.
On way or another, I always get
my money's worth.