( hammering )
Boss!
We-We got a problem.
( indistinct radio chatter )
( exhales deeply )
Well, clean surfaces
make for good
analysis.
Yeah.
Well, that may be
the only good thing.
I checked for
a wallet, no ID.
Nothing on him.
The kid looks like
a minor.
Coroner's investigator
says he's been dead
for over 12 hours.
Happened sometime
this weekend.
You going to pry
that piece of cloth
from his hand?
Not just yet.
Help me
out here.
Got any ideas on this one?
Well, based on
his pants around the knees,
I would say
a crime of passion.
Given the brutality
of it...
seems to me an act of rage.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
You know, I lose
an hour a day
cleaning up their
beer bottles
and their
cigarette butts.
Kids use it as a hangout, huh?
Oh, sure. They think
the house doesn't
have a lock,
it belongs to them.
Well, it's a crime scene,
so it belongs to us now.
Yeah. How long?
As long as it takes.
You know, I got two
teenagers at home,
and they know how to respect
other people's property.
Now, who's going
to feed them
when I don't get
paid for today, huh?
Huh?
I can't tell you that.
Take a look at his head,
tell me what you see.
Definitely blunt force.
That's a hammerhead.
I thought you might say that.
Well, we know
that people often
commit crimes in places
they're familiar with.
You got to be kidding me.
BROWN:
I'll swab
the blood
and see if it's all his.
Grissom?
Well, that should help.
I'll trade you a hammer
for a screw.
Name, please.
I'll tell you mine,
you tell me yours.
Oh, come on, baby.
I'm stuck with these ugly fools
all day.
A pretty girl comes by.
Just having a little fun.
Yeah, murder always makes me
feel a little randy, too.
Ooh.
( garbled radio transmission )
Fellows.
Hey, uh,
Mrs. Marlene Mitchell, 32.
Apparent gunshot wound
to the chest.
Entry, no exit.
No other apparent
injuries.
Do we know who shot her?
I patted down all her friends.
Nobody's carrying.
Got a couple officers
scanning the neighborhood
in case the,
uh, weapon
got tossed.
She was breaking
up a fight
when she went down.
Nobody saw anything?
Nobody heard anything?
No.
Somebody's lying.
That the husband?
The current one.
The other one--
he's the ex.
Interesting family reunion.
Whose brilliant idea was that?
The Mitchells
were moving in.
The ex stopped
by to say hi.
Don't you hate it
when hello leads to gunfire?
I'll need to GSR both.
Sir?
I'm going to need to
test your hands for GSR.
What's that?
Gunshot residue.
Why?
To rule you out.
You think I shot my wife
the day after our honeymoon.
We were just moving our stuff.
Her ex, Todd, shows up.
He knows
he's not supposed to come
within 100 yards of her.
But he did.
Please?
Marlene?
Call 911.
I thought it was a heart attack.
Then I saw the blood.
Yes, but there was
a restraining order against you.
Why were you here?
Thank you.
WOMAN:
Distinguish!
You ready to run?
She does all my running.
Thanks.
Trail!
It's a hell of a place
to get lost.
Yeah. We have
five million
olfactory sensory
receptors.
Penny's got
220 million.
She sees the
world differently.
The suspect
stopped here.
Trail is still strong here.
( barking )
She's got a hit
on the Dumpster.
( barking )
She's getting nothing,
but Penny will pick up
on anything they touched.
( barking )
There's something
in the silver bag.
What do you think?
Bought new clothes,
ditched the old ones?
What's missing
from that sweater's
what that dead kid had
in his hand.
So, we're looking for a girl
who bought a new outfit...
some earrings and a latte.
Oh, an iced cappuccino,
actually.
Congealed blood
in the pericardium.
Heart's what took the bullet.
Explains why she
just dropped.
Yeah, she was dead in seconds.
Hmm.
Bullet's still in the heart.
Here we go.
There.
Well, it looks
like a nine millimeter.
I'll let Vega know.
Fairly intact.
Want to do the honors?
Sure.
That's it.
Four inches?
That's shallow.
Standard handgun bullet
penetration's 12.
Right.
Give me a hand, will you?
Sure.
85 degree downward angle?
Well, that's, uh,
fairly standard.
Most gunshot wounds
are 90 degrees,
give or take.
Oh. Thanks, Doc.
Right.
JOHNSON:
They say in America,
you're on camera
an average of
seven times a day.
Go to a mall,
and you can
at least triple that.
I guess that's
good for us.
I'm going to
think twice
the next time
I try on a shirt.
Well, legally,
they can't put cameras
in dressing rooms,
but there's legal,
and then there's what people do.
Our girl bought her clothes
at 8:31.
Let's scan the dressing room
footage
from 8:00 on.
Hold it.
That's our sweater.
And that's our girl.
She did a walk out.
A "walk out?"
Yeah, my girlfriend does it
all the time.
She finds something she likes,
rips the tags off
in the dressing room,
hands them
to the clerk,
and walks out
wearing the
new stuff.
You go shopping
with your girlfriend?
That's nice.
Well, you can get her
prints from the receipts.
DNA from the sweater.
And you've got a face.
You're close.
Well, look at her.
She's a minor.
She paid in cash.
She's not going to be
in any database.
Without a name,
we don't have much.
Okay, one of our hammers
had blood on it.
It matches the victim's.
Did Greg analyze the clothes
from the Dumpster yet?
Yeah. Blood's a match, too.
Okay. So, the question is,
what is the connection
between this girl
and a construction worker?
BRASS:
Mr. Curtwell, where were you
this weekend?
I was fishing in Tahoe.
Catch anything?
No. Nothing
was biting.
Anyone go with you?
No.
How long were you gone?
Friday to Sunday.
Look, I thought I was just here
to pick up my hammer.
Do you ever leave your tools
at the job site?
No way. That hammer--
it's perfectly balanced.
BRASS:
Then how do you explain
the blood on it?
And your injuries.
Well, it's a construction site.
People get hurt.
BROWN:
The blood
that we found
on your hammer...
matches this kid right here.
( sighs )
Is that the dead kid
from the house?
Yeah.
I never got a
look at him.
I-I I didn't go inside.
What about her?
That's my kid sister, Ashley.
Why? What's she got
to do with it?
You tell us.
My parents died in a car
accident four years ago.
SIDLE:
I'm very sorry.
Your brother Gregory
is your guardian, right?
Yeah.
And he left you alone
all weekend?
He goes away a lot.
Okay.
Why don't you tell me
what happened last night?
I was on my way to the mall
to get something
to eat.
I always cut through
the construction site.
My brother tells me not to,
but it saves me,
like, ten minutes.
That makes sense.
What happened after that?
Well, this guy from school,
Brian, comes out of nowhere.
Do you know Brian's last name?
Yeah. It's, um...
Haddick.
We were in homeroom together
freshman year.
So, anyway,
he says his cat
ran away...
and will I help him find it.
And you did?
( sobbing softly and sniffling)
A cat. I'm so stupid.
You're not stupid,
Ashley.
I know this is hard.
If we could just go over it
from start to finish
just one time.
So, we walked into the house...
( starting to sob )
I think I saw
him come in here.
What color is he?
BRIAN:
Gray.
Here, kitty, kitty.
You're going to like it,
you dirty bitch.
You're going
to like it.
( sobbing )
It was like the more I shouted,
the more he liked it.
Rape is not about sex.
It's about violence.
You were against the wall.
( crying ):
No!
Did you see who hit Brian?
Ashley, after all
that had happened,
you went shopping?
He was all over me.
I just had to get him off me.
( sobbing )
And you got some coffee
and some earrings.
What?
I bought that stuff?
All I remember is getting
new clothes and going home.
Why does all
this bad stuff
keep happening
to my family?
She's covering for her brother.
He's got a non-
confirmable alibi.
I'm sure she
doesn't want to lose
the only guardian she's got.
It's pretty obvious
the initial blows
were to the head.
Well, according
to Sara,
that's consistent
with the girl's story.
Whoever attacked him
just kept going.
Used some real force.
Severed his spinal cord
at Cl, C2.
Well, that would have
rendered him immobile.
Right, so why
keep hitting?
The epidermis
was disturbed,
leaving areas
of exposed derma,
which we'd normally see
as red or purple
abrasions.
But in this case,
no blood rushed to the area.
He was beaten
postmortem.
Right.
So, Gregory Curtwell
sees Brian attacking his sister.
His adrenaline starts going,
and he can't stop.
Well, Brian may have gotten off
a punch of his own.
I can't identify
the pattern,
but I sent
blood and skin transfer to Greg.
And you're going
to need these.
Thanks.
That's our son.
Who could
have done this
to my baby?
Do you recognize this girl?
Did Brian ever mention
the name Ashley Curtwell?
He got a little out of hand
for a while.
We couldn't keep track
of his friends.
"Out of hand"?
I found some marijuana
in his room.
Broke curfew.
The nipple piercing
was the last straw.
I told him
he could do anything
he wanted to the body
God gave him
once he moved out.
Until then...
He was grounded.
But he was doing
so much better.
His grades were up.
He got a job.
Where did he work?
MR. HADDICK:
My brother
owns a restaurant.
Got him a job
bussing and waiting tables.
500 bucks every two weeks.
Cash under the table.
Pretty good for a
kid who can't drive.
( sobbing )
DAWSON:
No GSR on either the husband's
or ex-husband's hands.
STOKES:
That's not
definitive.
One of them still
could have fired the gun
and washed his hands.
Yeah.
Well, you know,
you asked me to check
Marlene Mitchell's bullet
for trace?
Well, there isn't any.
It's in pristine condition.
The only reason for
shallow penetration
is loss of momentum.
Yeah, and it was a standard
full metal jacket,
not a pre-fragmented.
So, assuming
that the bullet
didn't come in contact
with any intervening object,
what slowed it down?
Hey, Sanders, you
got anything on
that knuckle sludge?
Grissom's asking.
Yeah, a skin sample
taken from Brian Haddick's
defensive wounds, hair samples
from Ashley
Curtwell,
and buccal swab
collected
from Gregory Curtwell.
No match to the brother
or sister.
Construction worker
didn't do it.
Or he didn't do it alone.
72-degree impact angle
puts Brian here
for the initial blows.
Width is three millimeters.
Length is six.
Arcsine gives us
30 degrees.
So, Brian was crawling.
That must be
where his neck was exposed.
He ended up here on the floor
with his spinal cord severed.
Well, if he
was laying down,
this looks too high
to be a spatter.
Must be cast-off.
SIDLE:
On three walls.
Assailants tend to move
only in reaction to a target,
Brian was stationary.
Why would the attacker
keep moving?
It doesn't make sense.
It does
if there were three hammers
and three attackers.
Hey, Catherine,
feel like doin'
some real work?
And leave all this?
I got a woman who DFO'd
in front of her house
trying to break up a fight.
It's a single gunshot wound
to the chest.
The penetration is...
shallow.
I want to know why.
And you want me to cook?
( whirring )
( snaps )
Okay, boys.
There's always room
for Jell-O.
Oh, yeah.
Uh, Catherine,
technically,
that's just gel.
I wasn't planning on eating it.
Okay, let's shoot it.
Betty Crocker.
Firing one at 100%!
Standard velocity
is 1,100 feet per second.
All right, that is a... 12-inch
penetration.
So...
a, um...
100% load gives us 12 inches.
Firing one
at 70%!
Seven and three-quarter inches.
Firing one at 40%!
STOKES:
500 and...
50 feet per second.
Four inches.
Same as Ms. Mitchell.
So Mrs. Mitchell was shot
by a bullet
traveling 550 feet per second.
Now that we know the speed,
we can calculate the distance.
Thanks, Catherine.
So standard velocity
for a nine millimeter bullet
is 1,100 feet per second.
How far does a nine millimeter
bullet have to travel
before it slows down
to 550 feet per second?
Let's see.
1,800 feet.
Whoa. We're talking
six football fields.
Yeah, that would pretty much
eliminate anyone
that was in the Mitchells'
front yard.
Can a nine millimeter bullet
even travel that far?
Hang on.
All right.
If a nine millimeter
were fired straight...
it'd go about 600 feet
before gravity brought it down,
but if a bullet
were fired
at an angle...
could go a heck of a lot
further.
That would account for
the distance, but Ms. Mitchell
was shot
at an 85-degree angle.
That's basically perpendicular.
Um...
bullets are predictable.
People... aren't.
No, stop it!
I assumed she was standing.
Okay, this is the
Mitchells' house,
and by all
eyewitness accounts,
she was standing
in front the house,
facing away north,
when she was shot,
so this line
represents
the 1,800 feet
our bullet traveled.
It had to have come
from somewhere...
...on that arc.
Good luck
knocking on doors.
Here I'm looking
for three guys,
but you only found
one hammer with
blood on it,
so who do you
want me to follow?
Me.
What's up?
The shoe tread I
found at the scene--
it's a World
Industries Diablo.
It's a skate shoe.
Size 11.
On a construction worker?
Screams teenager, I know.
Why is Gregory Curtwell
hanging out with teenage boys?
Well, he has a teenage sister.
And the sister
and Brian Haddick
were both students
at McKinley High.
I bet the shoe
also goes to school there.
Nice kicks. I like those.
You guys play ball?
BOY:
Yeah.
Yeah?
BOY:
Uh-huh.
Nice backpack.
BOY:
Thanks.
We're treading
a razor-thin line
of illegal search
and seizure here.
Now, I'm not arguing
with you,
but shoes
are a plain-view item.
Anyway, here's the guy who's
going to be investigating...
Tyler, come on, we're going.
Are you crazy?
Do you know
what my law firm does?
You can't question these kids
without a parent present.
We're not questioning
them, which is why
you're here--
so we can.
Oh. And I'm holding you
responsible.
Clark County Law
Enforcement and I
have taken every
precaution to make sure
that these students'
rights were not violated.
You are sequestering
these kids
without probable cause.
I hate
that I've been called
out of work to come down here,
and I'm going to be
so far up your ass,
you're not going to be able
to sit down straight.
You know what I hate?
People who hurt kids.
And you know who those
people sometimes are?
Cops?
Other kids.
If it had been your son
whose skull was smashed
in with a hammer,
you'd be asking
me where I was
when I should've
been protecting him.
Kids bring guns
to school to
shoot other kids,
so who are you
protecting?
Let's discuss it in court.
Well, way to clear a room.
Those of you
with parents here
are dismissed,
and the rest of you
please wait here.
Brass.
Check this out.
Hey, bud.
What's your name?
Benny.
Benny, where's your father?
Is he around?
Uh, he's at home.
Probably called in drunk.
Well, lucky for you,
we make house calls.
BENNY:
Dad?
You good for nothing
little bastard...
I knew you stole
that game thing.
125 bucks, my ass.
I told you. I bought that
with my own money.
You talkin' back to me?
Huh?
Hey...
BRASS:
Let's sit down.
Let's all sit down.
Come on.
Look, I'll take this.
Let 'em argue diminished
capacity after the fact.
You think they know
how a DNA test works?
I don't know.
Let's find out.
Mr. Lizzio,
do you mind
if we test Benny's
sneaker for DNA?
You do what you got
to do, officers.
Lift your right shoe, please.
We got a problem.
The blood on your shoe
is a match to
Brian Haddick's.
DNA doesn't lie.
So, do you
want to tell us
how a dead kid's blood
ended up on the bottom
of your sneaker, Benny?
Yeah, Benny. Why don't
you tell us that?
Sometimes I go
to the construction site
just to hang out.
So, you just, uh...
happened upon it?
Didn't report
it to anybody?
I was trespassing.
I didn't want
to get in trouble.
Mr. Lizzio, would you mind
if I took a look around?
Be my guest.
Mr. Lizzio,
why don't you sit down?
We're going
to be a while, okay?
You been drinking today,
Mr. Lizzio?
Couple of beers.
Practice makes perfect.
So, Benny, for the record,
you've waived your right
to have your parent
or an advocate present.
Yep.
So, how do you know Brian?
We hung out a few times
when we were freshmen.
You know Gregory Curtwell?
Ashley's brother? Yeah.
He bought me beer
a couple times.
Oh, so you know
Ashley, too?
Yeah.
I'm a friendly guy.
Well, that's
good, Benny,
because...
( clears throat )
...you're looking at murder.
And if you're friendly
and you cooperate,
and you tell me
what happened to Brian Haddick,
maybe I can cut you a deal.
Ain't gonna happen.
I'm no snitch.
You want to tell me about
those melons at your house?
You looking to be
another Gallagher?
You know who that is?
Since when is whacking fruit
a crime?
When it's practice
for whacking people.
Your hammer had Brian's
blood all over it.
Understand something, Benny,
I'm talking about months versus
years of juvenile detention.
It's your call.
They got cable?
Food?
My dad locked on the outside?
Sounds good to me.
Besides, I'm a minor.
By the time
I'm 21,
it's like it never happened.
Did he roll?
Brass says the kid is looking
forward to going to jail.
Hmm.
So, what do we got here?
It's hard to tell
what's relevant
and what's trash here.
This is everything
we brought back
from Benny's party room.
Are these...?
SpaghettiOs?
I don't think so.
SANDERS:
Nah. Nah, those would be
orthodontic rubber bands.
Hook 'em to your braces,
uh, upper to lower.
Helps pull the jaw
in the right direction.
Also great for flinging.
Yeah, I had
it all--
palate expander,
braces,
retainer, head gear.
Ah, five years of misery,
but worth every penny,
don't you think?
Um, there might be
some saliva residue on them.
I can see what I can pull off,
if you want.
SIDLE:
Yeah. Would you?
SANDERS:
Well, you're going
to need something.
Strike three
on the knuckles.
Benny's DNA doesn't match.
Gregory's doesn't match.
Ashley's doesn't match.
Who did this guy hit?
Greg, test both of these.
If a third guy has braces,
it may explain the
strange pattern
on Brian's hand.
It's probably another student,
but Benny's not talking.
BROWN:
Benny has a party room, right?
You can't have a party
without the music.
I found some new CDs
in his room.
What's "C &amp; D"?
It's like a music club,
12 CDs for the price of one.
And Aaron Gilbert was...?
The deejay maybe?
SIDLE:
You know,
at this time of year,
watermelon isn't cheap,
particularly organic.
Maybe the music
isn't the only thing
that Aaron Gilbert
brought to the party.
WOMAN:
Yeah, I heard gunfire
a couple of days ago.
Johnnie, the idiot behind us,
was playing like G.I. Joe
in his backyard.
I screamed out my window.
I got kids, you know?
Why do you want to know?
Just curious.
She called
you guys, right?
It's like having a wife.
Gun's brand-new.
Shot it one time.
She told me to
stop, I stopped.
Sir, you're going to have
to tell us where that gun is.
And this is the gun
that you fired?
Yeah.
Empty ten-round magazine.
It was full when you started?
Yeah.
( gun clip clacking )
I, uh, only count nine holes
in your target.
I must have missed one.
Oh, you didn't miss.
Hey! You want to kill someone?!
( gunshot )
Put that thing away!
( yells )
VEGA:
Just nice and easy.
You see, your neighbor
didn't lose her kid,
but six blocks away,
a guy lost his wife.
It was just
a little target practice.
And that's why
it's illegal
to discharge firearms
within the city limits, genius.
Aaron Gilbert?
Yeah.
I'm Detective
Brass,
Las Vegas Police.
We need to talk.
Oh, dude, I got to get home.
My mom's waiting
for me and my brother.
Oh, we talked to your mom.
Yeah, she gave us
your hammer and this.
BOY:
Yo, dawg,
we going or what?
Or what... dawg.
That's a nice Walkman
you had.
What'd that cost?
125 bucks?
Same as Benny's Gameboy.
Same as your brother's
secret stash.
Speaking of Benny,
he's not too smart, is he?
He wouldn't give up
you and your brother
for a lesser sentence.
You know what?
There's an opportunity here,
and I think you got
more on the ball
than Benny.
Tell me what happened.
Jared...
ain't braces a bitch?
I see that cut on your lip.
Is that where Brian hit you?
They do make
for a good impression though.
See all these grooves here?
It's perfect
for storing DNA.
That would be your DNA.
Look, Jared, I'm not a cop,
but if you tell me
what happened,
I will put in a good word
for you.
SIDLE:
We have a problem.
We have three hammers
and four suspects.
BROWN:
Well, the
Gilbert brothers
both seem ready
to go down for it.
BRASS:
And Benny can't wait
to go to jail.
If they were defending Ashley
against an attacker,
why not say so?
GRISSOM:
They weren't.
The smashed watermelon
suggests the whole thing
was premeditated.
Making the motive robbery?
BROWN:
Well, Benny,
Aaron and Jared
each had about $125 worth
of cash and assorted prizes.
GRISSOM:
$375.
Brian's parents said that
he was being paid $500
every two weeks.
Cash under the table.
It was payday,
so who got the other $125?
Well, Gregory Curtwell
makes good money.
125 bucks
is a spit
in the ocean
for a construction
worker.
If he wasn't
defending his sister,
then he has no motive.
BRASS:
Well, if he
didn't do it,
how did his hammer end up
with Brian's blood on it?
Clothing-- $85; earrings - $30;
coffee-- four dollars.
Getting away with murder...
Priceless.
SIDLE:
That hand that holds
the wallet
is the hand
that rules the world.
Huh, Ashley?
Your fingerprint
in Brian's blood
on Jared's money.
This is what we call
"completing the triangle."
Okay. So he attacked me,
and I did see who defended me.
But I didn't want
to get my friends
in trouble,
and the money was for, like...
like, pain and suffering.
You weren't attacked, Ashley.
Brian was.
We figured
none of the boys
wore cotton candy,
so we had it tested.
Turns out you were
at Benny's house, too.
Let's do it!
( hard rock music playing )
ASHLEY:
Come on, guys!
Whoo!
( grunting and shouting )
At the mall,
you weren't in shock,
you were celebrating.
Your brother was up in Tahoe
this past weekend, wasn't he?
He goes away almost
every weekend.
You know, I'm done
with the Ashley pity party.
My guess is
Aaron and Jared
only had one hammer,
but you had access
to your brother's tools.
Why Brian?
Before he went straight,
we were buds,
but then he got too good for us,
but he wasn't too good
to want to get with this.
Where do you want
to do it at?
Right here.
In here?
Yeah.
( Ashley laughs )
You set me up?
ASHLEY:
They have to do it!
( Ashley shouts )
You're not a victim,
you were a lure.
Do you know
how many people
don't report a rape
because they're afraid
that no one will believe them?
Of course.
It's what I was counting on.
I'm going to do everything
in my power
to make sure that
you're tried as an adult.
Good luck.
I dress up real nice--
couple barrettes,
little lace collar,
two dead parents.
I'll be the saddest
little girl in the world.