( light buzzing )
( glass shattering )
( sirens approaching )
( people shouting )
Sam?
FIREMAN:
Knock it down.
WOMAN:
Sam? Where is Sam?
What about Sam?! Sam!
I'm going to need you
to stay right here, ma'am.
Sam.
Where is he?
Where is...?
Okay, we got him.
Here you go, pal.
You stay right here
with your mom.
( talks quietly )
Ma'am,
is there anybody else in there?
No.
( firemen shouting orders )
Hey.
STOKES:
What's with the 911 page?
Fire's not even out yet.
Jack's an arson investigator.
We were here on this same street
ten days ago.
Garage fire a few houses down.
Deemed intentional.
So you think it's a serial?
I don't know,
but I'm keeping my eyes peeled.
Maybe they came back
to take a look.
FIREMAN:
We got another one.
Got another one.
Sabrina?
We need a paramedic
right now.
She's not breathing.
Sabrina,
what are you doing here?
You weren't supposed to be here.
Sabrina?
( woman sobbing )
I think our arsonist
just turned into a murderer.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
She wasn't even burned.
WILLOWS:
Smoke inhalation
happens really fast.
I'm so sorry.
I heard you say she wasn't
supposed to be home tonight.
Was she with her dad?
My husband died five years
ago in a car accident.
She...
was at her friend Molly's
house for a sleep-over.
At least she was
when I went to bed.
What time was that?
I don't know, 11:00, 11:30.
Mrs. Abernathy,
do you have any idea
what may have caused the fire?
I go to bed,
I make sure the lights are off,
lock the doors.
Do you know anyone who might
want to set fire to your home?
I go to work.
I take care of my kids
and my mother,
and that's my life.
Thanks a lot.
Okay, folks, any information
you feel like you may have...
How am I going
to get my Fosamax?
Oh, well, I'll make sure
you have your medications
by breakfast, okay?
You're going to
be all right.
Everything's okay.
This man will take care of you,
okay?
What does that one do?
MAN:
That one?
That turns
on the siren,
so we can get to
places really fast.
To help people burning inside?
That's right.
But not my sister.
Yeah.
I'm sorry, buddy.
It's okay.
BRASS:
So the morning cleaning
crew found him.
No ID,
but this was in his pocket.
Looks like
some kind of code.
"735"?
His goal weight?
I'm going to talk
to housekeeping.
( latches clicking )
That's a nasty head wound.
It's always reassuring
to see an empty soap dispenser
in a public bathroom.
So I'm thinking this is how
the vic got his head smashed in.
( glass breaks, man yells )
Thank you.
It's common to find something
in blood.
Uncommon to find
something on blood.
Petechial hemorrhaging.
Asphyxia.
Head bashed in
and asphyxiated.
No soap
was the least of his problems.
JACK:
The smoke detectors'
batteries are all dead.
Sabrina's was the only bedroom
that sustained any
fire damage at all.
Her mother thought
that she wasn't home.
( camera shutter clicks )
WILLOWS:
But she wasn't asleep.
Not in her bed.
That would explain
why the firemen
didn't find her right away.
But it doesn't explain
what she was doing down there.
If you can explain the behavior
of teenagers, more power to you.
The adhesive they use
to put this stuff down
is highly flammable.
Crack in the linoleum,
the fire will just seek it out
and go for it.
This door's unlocked.
The firemen said they only used
one point of entry and exit:
the front door.
Mrs. Abernathy said that she
locked all the doors before bed.
Well, this could be
how Sabrina got in.
Comes home late, forgets
to lock the door behind her.
It's an opportunity
waiting to happen.
Check out the living room.
A few cheap,
wood panel walls.
Polyester curtains,
couple of fake plants.
All highly flammable.
Plus...
a bar full of liquid fire
with a low flash point.
( bottle clanks )
Coffee table.
Couch?
At some point, I think
this was a couch.
This looks like
a liquid pour pattern.
High-intensity burn.
You think this could be
the point of origin?
I think this is the area
of heaviest damage.
The fire spread up and
out towards the kitchen.
How'd you do?
Uh, couple of
weak partials.
What you got, partner?
Newspapers.
I found them
in the carport.
That's on the other side
of the house.
Yeah, it's kind of weird.
Completely
out of the path of the fire
and the firemen said
they didn't put them there.
You know the fire down
the street was in the garage.
Well, maybe he started
in the carport,
Sabrina came home,
provided access
to the inside of the house.
Did they find an accelerant
at the first scene?
Lighter fluid in the garage.
So maybe part of the MO.
is that he uses accelerants
that are present.
Let's hope he stuck around long
enough to witness the damage.
STOKES:
This is home video
from the first fire.
It looks like
everybody's neighbor.
Well, they say arsonists
often commit crimes
where they feel
most familiar.
The last fire was set
during the day in the garage
when the family was out of town.
A neighbor would know
when people were out of town.
Or when the door
was left unlocked.
If this is a
serial situation,
to go from an empty garage
to a whole house full of people,
we're talking
about a major escalation here.
Well, a match was found
at the first fire.
If we could find a match in
the debris of the second fire,
then we may know for sure.
Oh, she looks familiar.
Hang on. I may have something.
She was at both fires.
I got her name
off the canvas.
Let's run her.
She has a record.
STOKES:
You were arrested
for attempted arson?
I was exonerated.
I have you on film
at both fires on
Cell Crook Road.
I am not an arsonist.
That's not what your file says.
The law doesn't make
much of a distinction
between arsonists
and pyromaniacs.
What is the distinction?
I don't set fires for money
or with the intent
to cause damage.
But you do set fires?
( chuckles )
Mm.
You go home at night,
and you feel a little lonely,
you put in
a racy video.
No, no, no.
We're not talking about me.
I go home,
I rip open my junk mail,
and I put it in the fireplace.
It's an impulse control
disorder...
but it's private.
I don't burn down houses
and kill children.
Maybe not on purpose,
but accidents do happen.
You rang?
Yeah. Greg, how'd you
like to be listed
as an assist
on an arson case?
Is that
a rhetorical question?
Cool.
I collected these matchbooks
from the pyromaniac's house,
who was...
kind of hot, actually.
Really? You dig chicks
who dig fire?
Yeah. This, uh... this match
was used to start a garage fire
a couple of weeks ago.
See if you can find
a match to...
...one of those.
Thanks, Dell.
All right, David.
The three most common ways
to asphyxiate:
strangulation,
suffocation and...
Choking.
Good.
With this guy,
my money's on choking.
Scissors.
Hmm.
An "S"?
Cause of death.
Found it in the trachea.
So, he swallows a tile and tries
to give himself a Heimlich?
Or not.
I found these
in his stomach.
You don't swallow
six of them
by accident.
Your hottie's matchbook
collection came up dead.
Hmm. Doesn't mean
she didn't do it.
True.
You know, arson's
usually a property crime.
Did you ever find out
the Abernathys'
financial situation, Warrick?
According to Catherine,
Jessica Abernathy had
major credit card debt
but minimal insurance--
not even enough
to cover what she had.
Besides, people tend
to remove mementos
when they know what's coming.
So, if the pyro
didn't do it for love,
and Mrs. A didn't do it
for money,
who's left?
Maybe the high school
baseball team.
McKinley High School Gazette.
This is tomorrow's edition
with the lead story
by Editor-in-Chief
Sabrina Abernathy, entitled
"Varsity Hazing Ritual."
Now listen to this...
"The question is not whether
the so-called student athletes
should be expelled, but whether
or not they should be arrested."
Why, what'd they do?
Apparently,
something with several hookers
and a lot of testosterone.
Whatever happened
to toilet paper and trees?
Hey. DNA came back.
Blood from the bathroom floor's
a match to the vic.
Blood from the bathroom mirror
is not.
That's interesting.
What are you doing?
Anagrams.
You think
the letters
might be a message
from the killer?
Six letters.
What is that?
That's 720
possible combinations,
not all of them
words, of course.
Hmm.
You, uh, missed one.
Hey. We got an ID.
off your DB's prints.
His name is
Adam Brenner.
That guy has a record?
Well, sort of.
He's a civil servant.
He's a postal worker
from Orlando.
Do we know why he came to Vegas?
Oh, you're going to love this.
WOMAN:
Challenge.
Adam Brenner was one
of our top Division One players.
Ranked in the high 1,800s.
Is that like
the ELO system
in chess?
Logos has all the skill of chess
combined with the cruel whimsy
of fate.
Adam once set
a tournament record
by scoring 735 points
in a single game.
It was on his T-shirt.
Justifiably.
It's an incredible achievement.
So, how did the
other players feel
about that kind
of smack-down?
You actually suggesting
that somebody here killed Adam?
BRASS:
Cruel whimsy of fate.
Guy's from out of town,
takes a cab
from..., checks
into the hotel.
The only thing
on his hotel bill
is four meals a day.
No phone calls.
So everybody he talked
to is in this room.
We're going to need a
list of his opponents.
Yes...
What's with the cop?
We're just talking.
Yeah, about what?
Sabrina Abernathy died
in her home in a fire
on Saturday night.
Hey!
What'd I tell you--
you don't waste
a good pitch!
Cody, where were you
around 1:00 a.m. on Saturday?
In bed.
Cody's in bed every
night at 10:00.
He gets up at 5:00
to go running.
Except for the nights the team's
pulling a train on a hooker.
Cody, keep hitting.
This is Vegas.
Who hasn't been
with a hooker?
Well, most high school seniors
who are being scouted
by Division One schools.
I don't think
an expulsion
and an arrest
would look too good
on a scholarship application.
It's a tradition.
Happens every year
with every team,
and why that little bitch
had to scapegoat Cody,
I'll never know.
How 'bout you, Cody?
Do you know?
Look, I'm sorry the girl's dead.
Yeah, but you're not real sorry
the whole mess died with her,
are you?
Yeah, but burning
the kid's house down?
Come on. Give my son
a little credit.
( fence clangs )
Thanks for your help.
MAN:
Hey, hey, hey,
no flash drawing.
Challenge.
Challenge over here.
WOMAN:
Illegal word-- that's
a minute penalty.
MAN:
Time's up.
Game over, baby.
Gaboons? Like I'm really
not going to challenge that.
Wilson Janek?
Yeah.
Want to try your luck?
Step up, baby.
And you are?
Gil Grissom.
Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you,
Gil Grissom.
So...
what do you hear
about Adam Brenner?
Mr. 735?
Heard he's dead.
Well, he was alive last night
when he beat you.
Gil...
you think that trash talk's
going to break my focus?
You must be new.
Actually...
I'm from the Las Vegas
Crime Lab.
I'm just here to
collect your DNA.
You're a quick study.
But if you think I killed Adam,
why don't you go ask Uncle Sam
for my DNA?
I served my country.
Gulf War Senior.
Memorized word lists
for a sanity check.
Some guys did ping pong;
I did this.
I saw enough killing
over there.
I'm a "Make words, not war"
kind of guy now.
Word on the floor
is Adam Brenner really had
your number, Craig.
The universe ebbs
and flows.
More ebb than flow
in your case.
I guess you lost to Adam your
last three tournaments in a row?
14 points...
times two is 28
plus 10 bonus points
for full Logos.
38 points.
At least you're a good sport.
Loss for one
is a win for another.
So what if I was
the last person
to play Adam?
You were the last player
who saw him alive.
What are you thinking,
that with Adam
out of the tournament,
I could abscond
with the big cash prize?
( chuckles )
You tell me.
Oh, first prize here is $2,000.
Even if I win,
the remuneration
barely covers my airfare,
accommodation
and food.
No, no, I don't play
for the money.
You play for the glory.
You ever attempt a New York
Times crossword, Captain?
Nah, you probably
wouldn't make it
past Tuesday.
I do Sunday... in pen.
I can still spell this.
GC/Mass Spec found no trace of
accelerant on the couch residue.
Well, how can that be?
It was an obvious
liquid pour pattern.
Well, my dear, this is why
you should never pick up the
couch left for curbside pickup.
Polyurethane foam.
Outlawed in 1988 due
to its highly incendiary nature.
You light that crap on fire,
it heats up,
creates a burning pool
of liquid,
and acts as its own accelerant.
Disaster waiting to happen.
All it needed was a spark.
We've got no accelerant.
We've got no match.
We have no idea
what started this fire.
Maybe this will help.
It kind of smells
like a menthol.
Hmm, looks like a 100.
Longer the cigarette,
longer the filter.
Cigarettes are a terrible way
to commit arson.
Unreliable. They take too long.
Possible DNA
trace, but...
it just doesn't make any sense.
It makes sense
if the fire was unintentional.
I'm sorry about this.
Typically,
I leave with Sab...
with Sabrina, but...
It's fine.
Well, why are
we here, exactly?
Well, we think
we might have
figured out
what caused
the fire.
Ms. Abernathy,
does anyone
in your house smoke?
I don't.
Well, don't look at me.
I quit 20 years ago.
Sabrina maybe?
I don't think so.
Well, we found
a cigarette filter
in the remains
of your couch.
And we need a urine sample
from each of you
so that we can rule you out
for nicotine.
My house burned down,
and my daughter is dead.
And you're asking me
to pee into a cup?
Sure. Why not?
♪ ♪
Everyone except
for the little guy
was getting high
and getting by.
The girl's on uppers,
Mom's on downers,
and Grandma sucks
on the cancer stick.
Ritalin, Valium,
and Grandma's a liar.
Pants on fire.
That's the black trace
you found in the blood pool.
It's a mix of PVC resin
and liquid plasticizer.
When heated together,
they form a solid
elastomer film
called Plastisol.
What's it used for?
Mostly Greg Sanders wear.
Uh, names, hair band
logos, inane sayings,
anything that can be put
on a T-shirt.
Well, that narrows it down
to just about everybody
in the tournament.
Hey, we got a match
on the blood
from the bathroom mirror.
Look, just 'cause I was there
doesn't mean
I killed Adam Brenner.
Put your hands on the table.
SIDLE:
You know,
that's seven
years bad luck.
More like seven to ten.
Yeah, I'm not very proud
of that.
Of what?
I'm ebullient, you know.
I-I feel the wins
and the losses.
The other night, I lost
to a Division Two blue-hair.
But it's not my fault.
She was... she was
coffee-housing the whole time.
I'm sorry?
Coffee-housing?
You know, yap, yap,
yap-yapping.
So when I was
at the Southern Regionals
in Dallas last year,
I went to the
book depository.
Have you ever
been there?
Zip it, lady. I'm trying
to make a play here.
I never should have lost
that one.
What, are you an idiot?
What, are you stupid?
You're so stupid!
What about Adam Brenner?
No, he wasn't there.
But you lost to him, too.
BRASS:
Maybe you took
that loss even harder.
Adam?
No way.
He's ranked, what, 1,890?
It's like getting art lessons
from Picasso.
I was honored to even be sitting
at the same table
with him.
Ma'am, earlier you provided us
with a urine sample.
We found traces
of nicotine in yours.
That's odd
because I don't smoke.
Really?
Would you mind
opening your purse for me?
You know what?
I do too smoke cigarettes.
WILLOWS:
Mrs. Abernathy,
did your daughter have
Attention Deficit Disorder?
Sabrina?
No.
That girl had the focus
like you can't believe.
Well, we found Ritalin
in her system,
and as I'm sure you're aware,
Ritalin is used
to treat kids with ADD,
but acts as a stimulant
in older kids and adults.
Teens use it as an upper.
So, Sabrina was taking drugs?
As were you.
Valium.
Fair enough.
You know,
Sabrina used to scream at me,
"I can't wait
till I'm old enough
to move out of here."
And I would scream back,
"Yeah, me either."
What kind of mother says that
to her kid?
One with a teenage daughter.
You know what
I pictured
for this part of my life?
S... Saturday night,
leave the kids with Grandma,
date night with my husband.
Instead, I'm stuck home alone
with two kids
and a 70-year-old infant.
Mrs. Abernathy...
are you covering
for your mother?
Part of me wants to say yes,
please just
take her away.
Let her be the
state's problem.
You know,
she leaves the stove on,
and she leaves
the water running.
I come home, and I find
little burn marks in things.
But I was with her
the whole night.
I never saw her smoke.
Maybe
after you went to bed,
she came out
into the living room.
I doubt it.
But it's a possibility?
No.
It isn't.
Miss Willows,
you can go ahead and judge me,
but after my mother falls asleep
at night,
I lock her in her room.
Any luck?
Yeah, the bad kind.
My burn scenarios don't match up
with your data.
Did you try
different variables?
Yeah. Open windows, uh,
drafts from vents, all of it.
Here's the problem.
Demagnetized.
I'm not following.
Okay, the Curie point
is the temperature
at which all materials lose
their magnetic properties, yeah?
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
For the iron in these,
the temperature would had
to have been 932 degrees
in that kitchen.
With the fire starting
in the living room,
no matter how hard I tried,
I couldn't
get it that hot in there.
It just doesn't make sense.
Unless the fire didn't start
on the living room couch.
WILLOWS:
An incandescent
lightbulb will soften
at around 900
degrees, and distend
in the direction
of the original heat source.
How did we miss that?
Living room was crammed
with combustible materials.
It received the most damage.
It seems like the point
of origin.
Let's dig in.
Yeah.
♪ ♪
WILLOWS:
Do you fondue?
The accelerant was ethanol,
methanol and petroleum jelly.
Chafing dish fuel, like Sterno.
So it has gone
from intentional
to accidental
to personal.
Who have we got?
Nick's girlfriend.
( chuckles )
She's got no personal connection
to the family.
Well, Rick Chilson
did call Sabrina a bitch
when we were talking.
Charming.
Yeah, he's an ass,
but his alibi checks out.
Surveillance
at The Mirage
has him playing poker
the night of the fire.
What about Cody?
He was right there
with him.
But I don't think
that kid takes a breath
without Daddy's
nod of approval.
What about suspects
within the house?
Well, who's there? Grandma?
I mean aside from
being on lockdown,
she's arthritic.
I don't see her
writing on the floor.
What about Jessica?
She seems more frustrated
than desperate.
Frustration shows
you still care.
And the son, Sam?
I don't think so.
"Bitch."
It's such a teenage girl word.
That brings us back to Sabrina.
Well, she did think
the baseball team
had it in for her.
Her family life
was no picnic.
What are you saying,
she's on a kamikaze mission?
Trying to take the whole family
down with her?
I might be willing to buy that,
but how do we prove it?
♪ ♪
SIDLE:
Adam Brenner
was a meticulous note-taker.
He documented every turn of
every game he ever played.
How many words used the letters
we found in Adam's body?
None, actually, at least none
with that exact combination.
But here's the weird part.
One of the games
didn't add up.
When Adam played Craig,
he had 60 points written down
that I couldn't account for.
And on that same page
of his notebook,
I noticed that something
had been erased.
So I ran it through ESDA.
Adam played "Exvin."
Everything but the "S,"
60 points.
What's an "Exvin"?
You know,
I was kind of hoping you'd know.
It's not in the OED.
Well, according to the rules,
if you play a bluff
and your opponent challenges,
you have to take the tiles back,
you lose a turn
and a minute
off your game clock. No points.
Right,
and later in that same game,
Craig played an "X."
"Loxodrome."
Now there's only one "X"
per game.
How did he get it?
What are you
looking for?
A six-letter word.
P-I-S-T-O-L?
It's not the word
we were looking for,
but it's interesting.
With blood on it.
It's a replica.
I belong to a Communist club.
We collect replicas
from the fall of
the Soviet Union.
And I found that Tokarev
downtown at a pawn shop.
Hmm. A fake gun for a fake word?
Exvin?
A wine aficionado
who no longer drinks.
Exvin.
Exvins.
Challenge!
There are six letters missing
from your game box.
E-X-V
I-N-S.
You made Adam eat his word.
Yeah, huh?
You think
you're so clever?
I'll let you have
some Exvins for dinner.
Here.
Huh?
( groans )
( choking )
I just wanted to make it
as hard for him to swallow
as it was for me.
Karmic retribution.
Did you do anything to help him
after he started choking?
No. I thought
it was another fake-out.
How about after he fell down
on the floor
and stopped breathing?
Out of words?
This is old school
hydrocarbon detection.
Oh, yeah.
WILLOWS:
Chafing dish fuel
is alcohol-based,
but water would have washed away
any trace.
Let's just hope
that whomever wrote it
touched something else.
Well, it's the only shot
we've got, I guess.
WILLOWS:
Hmm.
Take a look at this.
Well, that's good shooting.
Oh.
Hit the jackpot.
I've got some smudges
over here, too.
Mom was locking the wrong door.
They're going
to ask you some questions
about the fire at our house.
And you'd better
start talking, mister.
Mrs. Abernathy,
would you come with me, please?
Hey, Sam.
You okay?
So tell me,
what kind of things you like
to do on the weekends?
Watch TV, hang out,
play.
Like to play with matches?
Sometimes.
Why is that?
Fire is cool.
Yeah.
You ever have trouble
sleeping at night?
Only when I got woken up.
Is that what happened
Saturday?
( knocking )
I lost my key. Let me in.
Thanks, dude.
Couldn't go back to bed?
I got a little bit hungry.
What'd you find?
Purple jelly.
Purple jelly?
Did you eat it?
No.
Mom uses it for the chocolate
pot on our birthdays.
That sounds like fun.
Yeah...
except stupid Grandma
isn't allowed to have chocolate,
so we couldn't do it this year.
Oh... that must've
made you mad.
Ever since Grandma moved in,
we can't do anything fun.
So, what happened next?
I played for a while.
Then what?
I went to bed... and then
the firemen came and rescued us.
You like when the firemen come?
Yeah.
They're so nice.
They talked to me and showed me
all their cool stuff.
This one named George--
he said maybe someday I can meet
his dog.
You know, Sam...
that word that you wrote
on the floor...
You know, that's
a really bad word.
I hear it all the time.
My grandma says it.
My mom says it.
And my sister says it.
Well... she used to say it.