( screaming )
I don't wanna go!
Whoa! Ooh!
Oh, Mommy.
We're all going to die.
Joey, put your
seat belt on. NOW.
Hold on tight, here we go!
( screaming )
Okay, guys, come on.
That was so fun.
All right, ladies and gentlemen,
welcome to Pharaoh's Fever.
Buckle up. Get ready to scream.
That was so awesome.
Um, we'll ride it
in a minute.
Um, four King Tut burgers,
uh, two Nile River ice teas
and two milks.
Milk is nasty.
Yeah.
( screaming )
( sirens blaring )
So, Dr. Thrillseeker,
you ever been
on this roller coaster?
GRISSOM:
Pharaoh's Fever, yeah...
but my ride ended
at the platform.
What do you know?
BRASS:
Six dead.
Park full of eyewitnesses
saw the train
fly off the tracks. 401B.
Accident with injury.
BRASS:
Uh-huh.
GRISSOM:
It's also a 418B.
A runaway?
A runaway train.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
Hey.
Sorry we're late.
There was a news van
blocking the entrance.
This is the first
time a roller coaster
has derailed in
Clark County.
Huge criminal and civil
liabilities issues,
so keep it quiet.
Photograph the scene.
Bag and tag all the detritus.
Forklift anything
bigger than Greg.
We're going to
put up a tent
on the other side
of the parking lot
for accident reconstruction.
Questions?
Yeah. What's that guy doing
so far away from the others?
Curious, isn't it?
So, when he asks
if anybody has any questions,
he's not really asking?
Well, I don't know much
about roller coaster accidents,
but in auto collisions,
the victims found
furthest away from
the car usually
weren't wearing
a seat belt.
That'd be my bet.
( screaming )
STOKES:
Okay, let's go to work.
What should I do?
Photo-evidence log-- just record
everything we collect, okay?
Couple of mountain
bikers called
in the body.
Coroner just arrived.
WILLOWS:
Hi, David.
Hey.
Tessa Press.
School I.D. was
in her pocket.
She's 13.
I hate these cases.
Now... the body position
is inconsistent
with her lividity.
After she died, blood settled to
her anterior and lividity fixed.
So she had been facedown.
Yeah.
And someone dumped her face up.
How long has she been here?
I'll defer that question
to the insects.
WILLOWS:
Instar maggots.
Given the ambient
temperature
and last night's rain,
I'd estimate she's been
out here 24 hours.
Takes that long
for blowfly eggs to hatch.
I guess the rain would've
washed away any trace evidence:
tire prints,
shoe impressions.
Let's just hope there's
some evidence on her body.
If you're going to drive
all the way out here
to dump a body,
why not take another ten minutes
and bury her?
Guess it wasn't worth
the killer's time.
( metal screeching )
So, how long you been operating
the roller coaster?
Couple of months.
I got a promotion.
I used to work
the merry-go-round.
That's a promotion, huh?
Yeah. Only little
kids go on the
merry-go-round.
Oh, I see. So you get to meet
girls your own age
on Pharaoh's Fever.
Yeah, something
like that.
What kind of training
do you get to be an operator?
Training? I
release the brake.
I press a button.
It's green and
marked "start".
I get the picture.
All right, look,
there are six victims.
It'd be helpful to know
where each of them was sitting.
Um...
front bench was a girl.
She was blond.
Yeah?
Cute.
Uh, followed by a punk,
old folks and some other dude.
That's only five.
That's all I remember.
BRASS:
"See yourself
scream"?
What's this about?
We got a digital camera.
It's mounted
right over there.
BRASS:
How does that work?
Camera's on a trigger.
Train passes by,
automatically
snaps a picture
and stores it in the
computer's hard drive.
The train was airborne.
Never even got close
to the camera.
I'm still going to want
to take that computer.
I'm the park's
chief engineer.
Been working on coasters
since before I was tall enough
to ride 'em.
GRISSOM:
You responsible for maintaining
this roller coaster?
I keep all the rides up to code.
You have any idea
what would cause this train
to go off the track?
Well, in theory, I didn't think
it was possible.
There's never been
an accident like
this anywhere.
So, you're an expert?
On roller coasters? Hell yeah.
Ten years of service
on Six Flags'
American Eagle before
moving to Vegas.
Do you know what that is?
That's a nut. It, uh... secures
the wheel to the screw.
Well, one loose screw...
couldn't cause a train
to derail, could it?
No, no, there's, uh...
eight wheels per train.
They-they'd all have to be
loose, and, uh...
that just doesn't happen.
"There are three things
in human life
"that are important.
"The first is to be kind;
"the second one
is to be kind;
and the third one
is to be kind."
Henry James.
Very good. Author of one
of the greatest horror stories
ever written:
Turn of the Screw.
And I'm looking for one.
SIDLE:
A screw?
Yes.
Oh, well...
technically, these
are eccentric shafts,
not screws.
Well, as long
as you can screw a nut on it,
it's a screw.
Turn of the Screw
isn't really a
horror story.
It's more of a mystery.
Did the governess
kill the little boy,
or did the ghost do it?
Well, it's only a mystery
if you believe in ghosts.
End threads are stripped.
Means the nuts were loose.
Excessive play on the screws
would've worn down the threads.
And the nuts
would've popped off.
Nuts don't just pop off
by themselves.
GRISSOM:
We got tool marks.
Vertical striations,
evenly spaced.
Could've been a pipe wrench.
Maybe whoever maintains
the roller coaster
uses a pipe wrench
to tighten the nuts.
Or whoever loosened the nuts
screwed up.
It's Tessa.
I don't understand.
How could this...?
My baby.
I'm very sorry.
She's beautiful, isn't she?
Ma'am, the coroner
believes that Tessa died
over 24 hours ago.
Had you reported her missing?
Couple nights a week, she'd
sleep at her friend Carrie's.
There's just
the two of us.
I'm a waitress. Work nights.
That way I can...
make her breakfast and be there
when she gets home from school.
When was the last time
that you saw her?
Yesterday morning.
I got home
around 6:00.
We made pancakes.
I packed her lunch
and kissed her good-bye.
When she didn't
come home from school,
I just figured
she was at Carrie's.
I should have called,
but I didn't
want to be a nag.
I want to see her.
Officer,
could you please
escort
Ms. Press... to the morgue.
When's the last time
you went 24 hours
without talking
to Lindsey?
A single mother,
working nights.
I'm just saying,
she didn't check
on her own kid, you know?
Ah, you do the
best you can.
Introductions.
Shelly Hoffman, 25.
Cause of death--
lacerated ventricle.
Noah Nuland, 15.
C.O.D.-- head contusion.
The swelling of the brain
killed him within minutes.
Now, Gary Clodfelter
died of shock.
His wife, May,
exsanguinated.
And their son, Cameron--
another
head contusion.
What about this guy?
Jim Nevins, 20.
Park employee.
Died from a temporal herniation.
Impact to the
head caused the
brain to swell,
which, in turn,
put pressure on the brain stem.
According to the ride operator,
there were only five passengers
on the roller coaster,
and no employees.
Right.
So...
maybe Nevins was just
an unfortunate bystander.
Hit in the head
by a falling roller coaster.
The Chicken Little theory?
But here's the hitch.
The others died
roughly ten hours ago.
Mr. Nevins' rigor
mortis is fixed.
Body temp
puts the time of his death
approximately 16 hours
before the others--
right around 1:00 A.M.
( sighing )
Albert... dead men
don't ride roller coasters.
We're going to need to see
the underside
of the loading platform.
Oh, follow me.
Rumor has it
the park's going to shut down
Pharaoh's Fever for good.
You know anything
about that?
GRISSOM:
No.
Newspaper called it
"a death trap."
An accident
waiting to happen.
You disagree
with that?
Well, she's old
and wrinkled, but
I took good care of her.
Uh, Woody?
We'd like to be alone.
Holler if you need anything.
Well,
easy access.
Wheels are in reach.
Anyone could have
loosened the nuts
from down here.
Check this out.
Is that lubricant,
maybe?
It's a funny place
for lubricant.
It's not even on the track.
I'll swab it.
( flapping )
Hey, look at that.
That's worse than
just a wrinkle.
It's got a support
beam under it.
It's just a cosmetic problem.
Sir, you need
to step away.
We need some time.
This is an active
investigation.
Were you aware that
that support beam was detached?
Well, hell, yeah.
Fixed it a half dozen times
this year.
It's in my maintenance log.
But like I said, that cross bar
is supported
by the metal beam.
But since my hours
were cut back last November,
I've had to prioritize
my "fix-ums."
Hmm.
Woody, we'd like to requisition
your pipe wrench.
It's, uh, not technically mine.
Are you the only one
that uses it?
Yeah, but it's the property
of the park.
Well, I promise
we'll get it back to you.
( phone ringing )
Thank you.
Yeah?
I'm processing the dead
park employee's clothing.
The shirt and the pants
are covered in red fibers.
GRISSOM:
Anything distinctive?
Well, they're trilobal.
Very good.
Thanks, Nick.
Well, we need to find a car
with a red interior.
SARA:
Hi.
The roller coaster
broke into 106 parts.
I just logged
the final piece.
Good work.
I found something
a little unusual,
for a roller coaster.
Not a sailor,
but a...
Semen?
Sex on the
roller coaster?
Or some kid
shaking hands with Shorty.
The release of epinephrine
and adrenaline
while riding a roller coaster
can produce a
stimulatory effect.
It enhances ejaculation.
Right.
But is it probative
to our
investigation?
Well, um,
why don't you
swab a sample,
and you can tell us.
Greg, do we know who the R.O.
of this T-Bird is?
Uh...
Jim Nevins.
The dead employee.
I didn't realize
the cars were relevant
to our investigation.
Everything's
relevant
Greg, until it's not.
Grissom.
Take a look at this.
A pipe wrench.
Blood.
Greg, may I?
Blood pool.
Camouflaged by the red carpet.
That explains
the autopsy findings.
Nevins may have never been in
the roller coaster.
Possibly killed
by that wrench
and stuffed in his own trunk.
And, uh, then what?
A renegade roller coaster
comes along
16 hours later,
and propels Nevin's body
from the trunk to the blacktop?
I'm just following the evidence.
I'll call Brass, see if he
can find an eyewitness
that can place the car
in the parking lot
at the time of Nevin's death.
Uh, so, Woody said
that I might be able to help you
with your investigation.
Zack, you close up shop
at the Sphinx at night.
Yeah, Monday to Friday.
Uh, class till 3:00.
Tutor kids in math
till 5:00, and then
I head over to the park.
We close at 10:00.
Did you notice any cars
in the parking lot
after closing on Thursday night?
Jimmy Nevins.
His red T-Bird was out there.
Oh, you know Jimmy?
Yeah, sure; pretty cool guy.
Worked the bumper cars.
I still
can't believe
what happened, you know?
I mean, I must
have rode that
coaster, like,
100 times, maybe more.
Anyway, sometimes
Jimmy stayed after closing.
Why?
Look, I'm not trying
to get anybody in trouble,
but occasionally,
Jimmy would
take his... dates for rides
on The Fever, you know?
Everybody knew about it.
It was really no big deal.
Do you happen to know
the name of his date
on Thursday night?
No, sorry.
How did Jimmy
get access to the park?
I mean, all the power
is shut down at night.
The same key that opens up
the men's room door
opens up all the power boxes
at the park.
No kidding.
It's just hanging
outside Woody's office.
What about security?
Nope. Night guy got laid off.
Budget cuts
last winter.
It's not like anybody's going
break into an amusement park
and steal a coaster, you know?
DAVID PHILLIPS:
X-rayed Tessa's neck.
Blade appears
to have perforated
her fifth cervical
intervertebral disc,
lacerating the spinal cord.
Type of trauma suggests
we're looking at asphyxia
due to diaphragmatic
paralysis.
It looks like there's soil
inside of her wound.
Well, we did find her outside.
Right.
Should be soil around the wound.
And on the wound,
but not inside of it.
♪ ♪
Oh, I am the man.
Are you?
I microsilled the pipe wrenches
you and Sara
turned into evidence.
I excluded
Woody's wrench.
Take a look at
the tool marks
from the wrench
found in the T-bird.
On the left,
the sabotaged nut.
On the right,
the test marks.
Perfect match.
I have a theory.
Maybe Jim Nevins
sabotaged the roller coaster.
When he left the park,
someone attacked him,
grabbed his wrench
and hit him over
the head with it.
Did you any prints
off the wrench?
I got a partial.
And I had a tech
print the T-Bird.
Found two sets of prints
on the trunk's lid.
One belonged to the vic,
the other unknown,
but it did match the partial.
That semen
from the coaster's cab
was just processed in my lab.
All I can say is,
Nevins was a cad.
Semen match the dead guy's?
Yup. And Sara spoke to Brass,
who says Nevins was known for
taking girls on private rides.
Pharaoh's Fever
was his Spanish fly.
Well, there goes my theory.
No one tampers
with their sex machine.
( typing, computer beeping )
Multitrack digital camera
snaps photos
of all the passengers.
The park finally sent
over their computer,
so I'm scanning through
the day of the accident.
Can you go back in time,
to the night before?
Yeah. Why?
Jim Nevins
may have been on that coaster.
I want to see
if anyone was with him.
( typing )
( computer beeps )
Oh. So much for safe sex.
Who's the girl?
Reverse one more pic.
( typing )
Now, that picture's
worth five bucks.
Last time stamp of the night
was 12:45 a.m.
Coroner placed Nevins' T.O.D
at 1:00 a.m.
We need to find that girl.
WILLOWS:
Hey.
BROWN:
Got your page.
What's up?
Tessa Press took the bus
to and from school,
not far from here.
Mm-hmm.
I showed her picture
to the mini-mart manager.
She remembers seeing her
the day that she was killed.
Wow.
This place is crawling
with kids.
She remembers her?
She says she came
in every afternoon
and bought a Little
Debbie and a soda.
Have we tracked down
her friend, Carrie?
Officer Ray did speak
with Carrie and her parents,
and they confirmed
that Tessa spent at least two
nights a week over their place.
And was she supposed
to sleep over
the day that she was killed?
I don't think
they had any kind of a schedule.
She would just show up,
and when she didn't,
they'd assumed that
she was at home.
Warrick.
I've already
secured the footage.
Oh, roller coaster
wacko at 12:00.
I heard you were
looking for someone.
Sir, do you recognize
this young woman?
Oh, sure, it's Cleopatra.
She works
in food services.
Second pyramid on the left.
Thank you, Woody.
MAN:
Hey, can I help you?
Actually, we're looking
for Cleopatra.
She's on break.
But can I get you anything?
No, thanks.
Quadratic equations?
That's not easy.
Glad you think so.
I have a "D" average.
If I fail the final,
my family's going to Hawaii
without me.
We're with the crime lab.
We have some questions.
I had no idea
those cameras worked at night.
Is your name really Cleopatra?
Lisa. Lisa Hunt.
Lisa, you know your friend
in this photograph is dead,
right?
Right.
You don't seem
too upset about that.
D.L. on Jimmy Nevins:
Four years ago,
when I was a frosh
and he was a
senior, he was
my Jordan Catalano.
Know what I mean?
But he didn't
know my name.
So four years later,
when I started working here,
he's still working here--
total loser, but
still really hot--
so when he asked me out,
there was only one answer:
"When and where?"
After hours
at the roller coaster.
I know, I thought
the same thing--
Cheez Whiz.
But, I mean, what the hell?
I'd never done it
on a roller coaster.
It was your first date.
You sound like my mother.
Oh, God, you're not going
to tell her, are you?
I just turned 18.
There is nothing statutory
about it, I swear.
Lisa, we need to know
what the two of you did
when you got off the ride.
We talked.
I mean, not that
he had much to say.
He offered to drive me home,
but I only live a
few blocks from here,
so I told him I'd huff it.
Mm, we kissed-- way
too much slobber.
And that was it.
Was there anyone else around?
I-I didn't see anybody,
but I wasn't really looking.
I found Tessa.
WILLOW:
Yeah, you're not
the only one.
Yeah.
Can you enlarge it?
( typing )
( machine whirring )
Yeah, that's me.
And who's that with you?
Tessa Press.
You two were friends?
We sat next to each other
on the bus.
She was 13.
How old are you?
What's that supposed
to mean?
No, Mom, it's okay.
I-I'm 15.
I felt sorry for her.
The girls picked on her.
Made fun of her frizzy hair,
her old clothes.
Stuff like that.
She'd sit next to me,
and they'd leave her alone.
In the photo,
you're grabbing her arm.
It wasn't like that.
I just got my learner's permit.
My mom was waiting in the car.
We were just going
to get slushies.
I saw Tessa in the parking lot.
Hey, Tessa. Hey.
Henry.
You want a ride,
just door to door?
No, that's okay.
Oh, come on.
You're not scared
to drive with me,
are you?
No, it's okay. I got it.
She said she was getting a ride
from someone else.
Did she say who?
No.
But when we pulled away,
I saw her getting into a truck.
I didn't see the driver.
I've got a question for you.
What substance contains
the following ingredients:
Sorbitol, cetyl alcohol,
isopropyl myristate,
glyceryl, stearate,
PEG-100 stearate,
petrolatum,
benzylalcohol,
titanium dioxide
and purified water?
Okay, I assume that you've
identified the substance
we found
on the roller coaster track?
Correct.
It's doxepin ointment.
( chuckles ):
Sounds Klingon, huh?
Anyway, uh, it's
prescribed by doctors
to treat dermatological
inflammations
caused by contact
with certain types of plants.
Maybe whoever
messed with the tracks
transferred the ointment
when they loosened the wheels.
( metallic clanking )
Your killer has a rash.
And we need to catch it.
I've been
looking for you.
What's up?
Hodges analyzed the trace
from inside Tessa's wound.
It seems it was ZooDoo.
Come again.
Hoof stock.
It's a combination
of feces
from rhinos, zebras,
and bison.
You're kidding?
They say that the smell
of wild animal crap
keeps the deer away.
Who knew?
Uh, so can we track
the source of...?
There is a zoo in Auckland
that exports it.
And there's only
one landscaping company
in Clark County
that imports it-- ADL.
I contacted ADL,
and guess what they told me?
Couple of months back,
they were hired
by the victim's mother.
BROWN:
Hmm.
ADL Landscaping.
( camera shutter clicks )
Must've been a big job--
she hired them months ago.
ZooDoo.
( camera shutter clicking )
Hello.
Hi.
I just
left you a message.
Any news?
Honey, these guys are
from the crime lab.
Justin Mack, my boyfriend.
How you doing?
BROWN:
Hey.
Could I have a word
with you outside for a moment?
Why?
Why not?
May I?
How can you be sure
it was Justin's truck?
At this point, we're
just following a lead.
How long have you known Justin?
Uh... few months.
Hired him to lay sod.
Now we're in the midst
of an outdoor overhaul.
And where's Tessa's father?
L.A., maybe. I don't know.
I haven't heard from him
since the divorce.
He'll find a way
to blame me for this.
You see, Raina said
it was important
for Tessa to take
the bus to school.
Said it helps
build independence.
But sometimes I'd pick
her up at the bus stop,
buy her an ice-cream cone,
and drop her off here.
Did you pick her up
that afternoon?
Look, I know there are a lot
of whack-jobs in the world,
and you're just doing
your job, but watch it.
You mind if I take a look
in the back of your truck?
Don't you need a warrant?
Only if you deny me access.
Go ahead.
Thanks.
Have you ever left Tessa
alone with Justin?
Sure.
He's over here all the time.
He's a good man.
He wouldn't hurt anybody,
especially not Tessa.
( voice cracks ):
Damn, I keep expecting her
to walk
through that door.
In 1988, your client
was arrested
for a drunk and disorderly.
Your fingerprints were then
entered into our database.
They match the fingerprints
that we found on this shovel.
WILLOWS:
The blood
on the blade matches
your daughter's DNA.
My client is landscaping
her backyard
with her boyfriend.
Explains her prints
on his shovel.
They were the only prints
on the shovel.
Justin wears work gloves.
Which explains the absence
of his prints.
That's possible.
But your client's fingerprints
provided a sufficient basis
for a warrant
to search her vehicle.
The choice of weapon
and the manner of disposal
suggest that this was not
a premeditated murder.
You can help yourself here.
You can avoid
Murder One by telling us
what set you off.
You wouldn't understand.
Try me.
I bought Tessa a bus pass,
and that
little slut still gets my guy
to pick her up
after school.
Raina...
Shut up!
We all know why.
Why don't you tell us?
She was trying
to steal him from me.
Bye, thanks Justin.
What the hell
were you doing with him?
Mom, he just gave me
a ride home.
You think you got him wrapped
around your little finger?
He's just being nice, okay?
Were you nice back?
Don't do this again, please!
You don't talk to me like that,
you little bitch.
Mom, you're being ridiculous.
Where the hell do you think
you're going?
I've given you
everything.
Justin was the best thing
in my life.
No.
Your daughter
was the best thing in your life.
You didn't know her.
( scoffs )
I know she was 13 years old.
A child.
( sighs )
SIDLE:
I just got the court order
from the
pharmaceutical
database.
Fortunately, Dioxipin
isn't widely prescribed.
FDA only approved
it two years ago,
and most dermatologists
don't even know what it is.
How many names on the list?
Well, in Clark County,
twelve prescriptions
were filled.
I cross-referenced them
with the employees
from the Park,
and I got a hit.
You want a clue?
Her death ended
the Ptolemy
dynasty's reign
in Ancient Egypt,
hence making her
the last Pharaoh.
Ah, the lovely Cleopatra.
I had a rash.
So what?
That's not a crime.
I read the court order.
Uh, you found trace amounts
of some ointment
on the roller coaster tracks?
Is that the only reason
for this conversation?
Your client had a prescription
for doxepin.
May we see your arms, please?
Rash was on my legs.
Went away days ago.
You want to see?
Uh, that's okay.
Unless you want to argue
that my client stood on her head
and held a wrench in her toes,
we're done here.
Do you know how
you contracted the rash, Lisa?
Best guess, I was getting
some help with my homework.
We were studying outside
on the grass.
Took a break, went for a walk.
I think I brushed up
against something.
Who's we?
My math tutor.
And what's his name?
Zack Lawrence.
Do you know if he contracted
the rash, as well?
Yeah. Actually, I gave him some
of my ointment.
BRASS:
Hey, Zack.
Oh, hey, guys.
We spoke with Lisa.
She said she gave
you some ointment
for some nasty rash you have.
Yeah, yeah.
SIDLE:
You know, it's illegal
to use someone else's
prescription medications.
Is that why you guys are here?
Not exactly.
Um, you guys mind if we talk
about this somewhere else?
Hey, good idea.
Why don't we
go downtown?
We can talk there.
Come on. Come on.
All right.
You coming?
You know, I'm going to catch up.
Okay.
Yeah, it's, uh,
just a little bit of a rash.
It's really no big deal.
Zack, what do you have
against roller coasters?
What do...?
I-I don't understand.
This a
fingerprint
analysis.
Zack, I lifted
some fingerprints
off your broom
back at the Park.
Turns out, they're
a match to prints
that we lifted off of
Jim Nevins' T-Bird
and the wrench that
was used to kill him.
Circumstantial evidence at best.
I also talked
to your school principal.
You're a straight "A" student,
Mathalete.
Science Team.
You had a full ride
to Stanford next year.
You don't sound like
the kind of kid
that would mess with a roller
coaster just for kicks.
GRISSOM:
You're a smart
guy, Zack.
So, uh...
let's talk this out, logically.
According
to your previous statement,
when you locked up
on Thursday night,
Jim Nevins' car was the only one
in the parking lot, right?
Yes, sir, that's correct.
And you knew he was staying
in the park
to ride the roller coaster.
I don't care about Jim Nevins.
What about Lisa Hunt?
You tutor her, right?
Did Lisa tell you that
she had a date with Jim?
No, she didn't say anything.
It was all over the park.
Jim was going to take Lisa
on one of his coaster dates.
I asked her about it.
She said it was a rumor.
It seems to matter to you
that she had a date with Jim.
Lady, I make $20 an hour
tutoring.
Why do you think
I'd take minimum wage
at The Sphinx?
I'm thinking,
you want Lisa to see you
away from the textbooks.
We started hanging out
at breaks.
Having dinner.
And then last week,
after tutoring,
we went for a walk.
And she grabbed my hand.
Did you think
that meant something?
Of course.
But...
you didn't trust her.
No. I wanted to.
You tampered
with the screws.
If she wasn't lying,
she wouldn't be on
the roller coaster.
No harm, no foul.
Oh, but you see, she was lying.
Uh-huh.
But you didn't loosen the wheels
enough, did you?
Don't answer that.
So when the roller
coaster didn't derail,
you took things
into your own hands.
Lisa walked home.
Jim walked over to his car.
What I don't understand is
why you didn't go back
and fix the roller coaster.
Guess I just didn't think
about it.
SIDLE:
You'll be
thinking
about it now.
And for the rest of your life.
( crowd chatter )
I should have caught
those loose screws.
Used to check 'em
every morning,
but since management
cut back on my hours...
You're not to blame
for this, Woody.
Oh, I just hope
they don't blame the coaster.
It may not be the Manhattan
Express at New York, New York
or the Desperado in Primm,
but it-it...
It still makes
grown men scream.
My first week in Vegas,
I road the Desperado.
My first coaster marathon.
I rode that monster
for a week straight.
Hmm.
The Steel Phantom,
Kennywood Park,
Pennsylvania--
I actually hold
the marathon record there.
Uh, uh.
My-My favorite's still
the, um, King's Island.
The Beast.
Mm.
I presented a paper
at an Entomology convention
in Cincinnati just so
I could ride Son of Beast.
Head over heels
on a wooden track.
Ah. So, you prefer wood
over steel?
No. Not really.
For me, it's not
about the track.
It's about the thrill.