Help!
( dog snarling )
Help me!
Somebody help me!
Nobody knows who she is.
The Andersons, they called
the security company.
They thought somebody
was trying to break in
their back door.
Southern Highlands
is a new development.
There's really not much
around here.
Some of my guys
are talking to everybody,
trying to find out
what's going on.
She has severe lacerations
on her feet.
She was running hard
from somewhere.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
No skid marks,
no signs
of another vehicle.
The engine's running,
no flat tires.
Why'd she stop?
If you could just push.
I'm going to take
the SAE kit to Greg.
You don't want
to take the statement?
Do you mind?
No.
She's ready.
Thanks.
Lily Barker,
I'm Catherine Willows.
I'm with the Las Vegas
crime lab.
I know that you've
been through
a horrific ordeal.
4-4-6.
That's all I got.
Nevada plates.
Some kind of SUV.
Black, I think.
Can you start
from the beginning?
I was, um, driving home
from work.
There's hardly any traffic
once you cross Horizon Ranch.
He was tailgating.
I slowed down
to let him pass
and he hit me.
I wasn't going to stop,
but he did,
so I pulled over.
You're not supposed to leave
the scene of an accident.
He looked like a normal guy.
He asked
if I was okay.
Apologized.
He went to his car to get
his insurance information.
I was looking at my bumper.
He punched me in the face,
threw me over his shoulder.
I lost my shoes.
He threw me on the ground,
took off my jacket,
ripped open my shirt.
He kept trying
to kiss me on the mouth,
and I kept turning away.
So he bit my ear.
He wanted me to look at him.
He was going to kill me.
He ripped off my skirt.
He raped me.
He didn't use a condom.
He got up to zip,
and I kicked him
in the groin and I ran.
And the rest,
I guess you know.
Thank you.
That was very specific.
You said that
you looked at him.
Could you describe him
to a forensic artist?
Yes.
WOMAN:
What do you remember most
about the face?
He had bright eyes.
What about the shape
of the eyes?
Almond.
Tiny pupils.
What about the rest
of the face?
He had a baby face.
High forehead, thin lips,
clean-shaven.
Like a crewcut?
No, like he had
a regular haircut.
What?
How many vacation days
do you have on the books?
About ten weeks, I guess.
Why?
I think you should
take a week or two.
I'm still on the case.
I just didn't do the interview
for once in my life.
When was the last time
you took vacation?
Never, right?
Okay.
Grissom,
I have some
information
that will be
of use to you.
But before you get it,
I need a decision.
What?
I'm tired of being
on the fence here.
Either I'm in the lab
or I'm in the field.
Which is it?
Well, as soon as you can find
and train a replacement,
you can be in the field.
Until then, I need you
in the lab.
Now give.
I got a CODIS hit
off the semen from your victim.
DNA matches
a rape-murder case
from a year ago.
Still open?
Warrick's pulling the file.
Thanks.
No, thank you.
Victim was a 32-
year-old Caucasian
female, Emma Dobbins.
Sexually assaulted.
Cause of death,
strangulation.
They used her pantyhose.
Where'd they find
the body?
Off of Blue Diamond Road,
southern highlands.
That's not far from
where Linley Parker
was assaulted.
Other than the semen,
the only evidence
at the scene was a shoe
print-- man's size nine.
I talked to Nick.
They also found a
print-- size nine.
Did she have a car?
A vintage Pontiac.
Registered in her name,
never recovered.
GRISSOM:
So apart from
geography and age, what else
did they have in common?
BROWN:
Emma Dobbins ran
a movie memorabilia
place downtown.
My vic was a pit boss
at the Monaco.
Emma was married.
Linley Parker was single.
Blonde.
She was brunette.
The only thing in common,
the guy who raped them.
There's something wrong
with the nose.
Which one looks right.
That one.
This one?
Now, close your eyes,
and tell me everything
that happened
up until the point
that he raped you.
( man grunts )
( screaming )
Yeah, look at me.
Open your eyes.
( gags )
( vomiting )
WOMAN:
My husband keeps
dropping hints
about my anniversary
present.
Says he hopes
I like calypso music.
I think it's a cruise.
You don't like cruises?
I feel guilty.
Because you don't
love him anymore,
or because you think
he can't handle knowing?
Dr. Todd Coombs.
Excuse me, I'm
with a patient.
Honey, I told him...
Crystal, what's going on here?
Las Vegas Police.
Sir, we need to talk.
( camera shutter clicks )
TODD:
This is insane--
you've got the wrong guy.
Well, if that's true, you
got nothing to worry about.
I-I'm going
with him.
No, you're not.
This is where he'll be.
( panting ):
I'm gonna need a lawyer.
Who do I call?
I don't know, call Roger--
he'll know what to do.
The victim said
the car was black.
Well, blue looks black
at night.
MAN:
Single file, stop
at your number on the floor.
When I tell you to
turn, you're gonna
face the mirror.
When you hear your
number called,
step forward.
Turn.
Number one,
step forward.
Step back.
Number two,
step forward.
Step back.
Number three,
step forward.
It's number three.
That's the guy who raped me.
He's been like that
since the lineup.
You know, the guilty ones
always fall asleep.
( keys jangling )
Dr. Coombs, my
name's Gil Grissom.
I'm with the crime lab.
I'm here to collect
a DNA sample,
so if you'd open
your mouth?
DNA?
I-I think I should talk
to my lawyer.
Well, we have a warrant,
so we can compel a sample.
Either way I'm gonna get it.
I haven't done anything.
The good news:
if you're innocent,
this'll prove it.
Thank you.
♪ ♪
( liquid bubbling )
( whirring )
( copy machine whirring )
( beep )
( mechanical whirring, beeping)
STOKES:
I compared
the eight pairs of shoes
we collected
at Todd Coombs' house
to the shoe print
at the crime scene.
Mm-hmm.
No matches.
Well, he could've ditched
the shoes anywhere.
Yeah, true.
So, uh, what do you got, Greg?
Well, according
to the DNA results,
Todd Coombs is
not your rapist.
You're kidding.
There's only
seven out of 13,
which means
we're looking for a sibling.
I believe the semen
would indicate a brother.
Could explain why
she picked Todd
out of a lineup--
strong family resemblance.
She was so sure.
Dr. Coombs.
You're free to go.
So that's it?
Yeah.
You people think
you can do
whatever you want--
come into our homes,
turn our lives upside down.
Who's gonna explain this
to our neighbors, our friends?
TODD:
Come on, honey,
let's get out of here.
You're letting him go? Why?
He's not the man
that assaulted you.
Yes, he is.
I identified him.
DNA ruled him out.
Then you made a mistake.
That man raped me.
We have some additional leads,
and we're working on them.
I promise to keep you informed.
I saw him.
He wanted me
to see his face.
Linley, it was dark.
You were under attack.
Under those conditions...
pupils dilate,
it's hard to focus.
You can't always
trust your eyes.
He wanted me
to see his face
because he was
going to kill me,
and now you're
letting him go?
This is my
cell phone number.
Call me if you
need anything.
This isn't gonna
keep him away from me.
What I need is protection.
I need a gun.
If you don't feel safe
in your home,
stay with a friend.
I hear you're looking
for Todd Coombs' brother.
Or brothers.
I'll work out
the family tree.
♪ ♪
Yeah, I read all about it
in the paper.
I'm just sorry our parents
weren't alive to see it.
Hey,
your brother's being
hauled in on a rape charge.
Does that seem funny to you?
A little.
Todd was due.
Due for what?
A reality check.
Most people go
through life, suffer
the ups and downs.
Todd only got
the ups till now.
I'm Roger Coombs.
What's going on here?
They're cops--
they want our DNA.
I'm gonna need the May Hustler
and a cup.
That won't be necessary.
ROGER:
We're not giving
you anything
until our lawyer
looks this over.
BRASS:
Let me tell you
how this works.
First things first.
We do the test,
and then the lawyers come in.
So you two are
fraternal twins, huh?
Accident of birth.
( beeping )
You want a sample of my DNA?
What for?
It's an ongoing
investigation, sir--
a rape.
Can't discuss it
any further than that.
Does your route include
the southern highlands?
No, I work this side
of the 15, Seven Hills.
Were you working
two nights ago?
You talked to my supervisor--
you know I was.
Look, I heard about
what happened to that lady,
and I know what you guys
put Todd and Crystal through.
You got something
against my family?
against cooperating?
Hey, how'd it go
with brother number four?
Nowhere. No Kevin Coombs
at the address you gave me;
no forwarding address.
PD's following up.
( phone ringing )
Willows.
LINLEY:
I can't wait 72 hours for a gun.
I need it today!
I need it now!
Linley?
Hold on.
( loud music playing over line)
Linley, I can barely hear you.
Where are you?
Fremont Street.
I-I know you can help me.
Just-just give me a name.
Tell me where to go.
( glass breaking, screaming )
Linley?
Linley?!
Where is she?
We just rolled up.
Hey.
There's no new damage
except for
the window.
Blood is
probably from
whoever broke the glass,
not the victim.
( screaming )
BRASS:
Okay, the pawn
shop owner
ID'd her, she was
looking to buy a gun,
and she wasn't in
the mood to wait.
Anybody see
what happened here?
Well, the problem is
that when the light
show starts,
everyone's looking up.
I mean, what's
the chance
that this crime is unrelated
to the first
attack?
It's the same guy.
He's getting rid
of the witness.
Who identified the wrong man.
Soon as the DNA comes back,
we'll know
which brother it is.
And until then we wait?
Well, I got every
police officer
downtown
looking for her.
Shoulda had eyes
on the brothers.
Yeah, in a perfect
world, yeah.
Didn't you say that
you were on the phone
with her and you heard
the window break?
Yes.
Did you find her phone?
I looked everywhere.
So where's her phone?
( over radio ):
The is Dispatch.
We have 20's confirmed
on Roger Coombs.
Monaco Casino,
last four hours.
Larry Coombs at his
place of employment.
And Bailey Coombs,
on shift, Seven Hills.
All right, fine, fine.
Search the whole house
if you want to.
I'm telling you,
Todd's not here.
His car was
in the driveway.
That's because he took my
car to The House Company.
You going to arrest him
for that, too?
I'm going to need
your license number
and a full description
of your vehicle.
STOKES:
How'd you guys know
Linley Parker's cell
was E-911 capable?
We just took a shot.
She's got a lot of
new gadgets in her car,
most new cell phones are
imbedded with a GPS chip.
Her carrier accepted
the Attorney General waiver.
I'm accessing her site now.
If her phone's on,
it should show up.
Okay.
Okay, got it.
Nearest
cross streets,
uh, Warm Springs
and Durango.
That's the middle of nowhere.
Hey, Catherine.
She's moving.
We got a location!
Put out a BOLLO on a beige,
2004 Ford Taurus.
Registration, Nevada,
3-9-6-R-G-F.
The driver's name
is Todd Coombs.
He's a white male,
38 years old.
I'm on my way to The House
Company in Green Valley.
Yeah.
( vacuum whirring )
You make a mess?
That's your job.
Unless you've got a warrant, you
can't even touch this car.
I'm just looking.
For what?
So how
was Wal-Mart?
I was at The House Company
buying some plants for
my wife, to cheer her up.
Oh, you think that's
going to work?
A gesture goes
a long way.
Never worked for me.
Hey, do you mind turning
that thing off?
When the quarters run out.
So when were you at the store?
Why don't you
ask my brothers?
I've got a cousin in
Phoenix, maybe he knows.
( vacuum stops )
Last time I cooperated
with you guys,
you put me in a lineup
and I spent
the night in jail.
That's right, that's right.
Hey, let me tell
you something.
12 hours after Linley Parker
ID'd you as her rapist,
she gets dragged out of
her car on Fremont Street.
Now she's missing.
Then why are you wasting
time talking to me?
Drive safely.
( phone ringing )
Crime lab.
Yeah, this is Jim Brass.
Can you send a CSI
to my location
for evidence recovery.
STOKES:
250 feet.
200, still moving.
Linley!
150 feet.
Eighty.
70, 60,
still moving.
Fifty.
Okay, okay,
she stopped.
30 feet, she's
right here.
30 feet.
MAN:
Over here!
SIDLE:
Checked with county records.
Crime scenes
on a 20-acre plot.
Guess who owns the property.
One of the
Coombs brothers.
Coombs brother's company.
Guy's an
artist.
You call that art?
SIDLE:
Black SUV.
( yelling )
You're on my property!
Put the weapon down.
Las Vegas Police,
drop it
or we shoot.
Turn around.
Are you Kevin Coombs?
I can see the family
resemblance.
Come on.
'Cause of death,
asphyxia due
to strangulation.
Victim has
a hairline fracture
of the right third
metacarpal
with some soft
tissue swelling.
GRISSOM:
Defensive wounds.
She was a fighter.
There's also fresh contusions of
the right labia.
She was raped again?
I did a wet mount of
the vaginal secretion
with a Christmas tree stain.
Slide's under the scope.
Sperm.
If he was trying
to silence a witness,
why not just kill her,
why rape her again?
Maybe rape was just
foreplay for this guy.
Maybe what he really
gets off on is killing.
( camera clicking )
What do
you got?
Maybe a missing
Pontiac Tempest.
So, you were home
last night?
Okay, well, doesn't
really matter.
Your DNA will
do the talking.
You know what happens
when the government
gets your DNA?
Enlighten me.
They put it in the database.
Then they look at your driver's
license picture
and then all those cameras--
traffic lights, parking lots,
grocery stores...
They can find you.
Whenever they want.
Dr. Coombs.
Mr. Grissom.
I suppose you're compelling
a DNA sample
from my brother now.
We are.
Why are you here?
Are you an only child?
I am. Why?
You've got my brother
in that room, he's family.
I didn't want him to be alone.
Well, what about
your other brothers?
Bailey only looks out
for number one.
Roger and Larry,
they do their
best to avoid Kevin.
They don't
understand him.
And you do?
He's harmless.
He chooses to live alone.
He lives off the grid.
He spends all his time
turning junk into art.
Where does he get his "junk"?
Mostly from my brother's garage.
Every once in a while,
Roger lets Kevin take his pick
of the wrecks.
Beats inviting him over
for Thanksgiving, you know?
Dr. Coombs, we found
a 1968 Pontiac
outside your
brother's house.
The VIN matched a car
belonging to a victim
who was raped and murdered
by the same person who raped
Linley Parker.
And we found Linley
Parker's dead body
on your brother's property.
You guys have been wrong before.
Whew, man.
Guys like Brass have it easy.
All they got to do
is call it in.
Check this out.
I just found it in the hose.
It's from a potted plant
purchased at the House Company.
Confirms
Todd Coombs' alibi.
WARRICK:
You saw this?
A pin from the Palms.
Linley Parker worked
at the Palms.
A lot of people
work at the Palms.
And it doesn't nail
Todd Coombs.
According to the DNA,
the blood from Linley Parker's
smashed window
matches the semen
from all the rapes.
Which means
it doesn't match
Todd Coombs.
Or Kevin Coombs.
Or any of the rest
of the Brothers Grimm.
Linley was absolutely certain
that Todd Coombs raped her.
That's not
what the evidence says.
Well, maybe the evidence
is wrong.
You can be wrong,
I can be wrong,
the evidence
is just the evidence.
Deep down, tell me you don't
think this guy is good for this.
I got the DNA on the hair
you lifted off
Linley Parker's body.
Get this. It's Todd Coombs.
Puts him with the body.
It doesn't prove rape.
I'll have Brass bring him in.
Would you strip down
to your shorts, please, Doctor?
Why?
I'm going to examine
your clothing
for any trace evidence,
and we're going
to document your body
for any injuries
that may have been sustained
during a recent struggle.
I don't have any injuries.
If you'd like,
this officer will
assist you.
I did not rape
that women.
I did not kill her.
You guys proved that
and you let me go.
Thank you.
Turn around, please.
That's an old scar.
I was a bone marrow donor.
My youngest brother Joss
had leukemia.
Hold still please.
Turn off the lights,
would you, please, officer?
What are you looking at?
This is harassment.
I've already given you guys
a DNA sample.
You know that bone marrow
donation you gave your brother?
I checked
your medical records.
His body rejected it
and he died.
My guess is that's
when you first found out
about your unique condition.
The doctors explained it.
I'm a creature of myth.
A chimera.
Head of a lion,
body of a goat,
tail of a dragon.
You're a genetic anomaly.
One person,
two completely different
sets of DNA.
BRASS:
State your name for the record.
My name is Todd Coombs.
I raped and murdered
Emma Dobbins and Linley Parker.
There are more,
but we'll talk
about those later.
How'd you pick your victims?
They picked me.
GRISSOM:
Sometimes fraternal twins,
two separately fertilized eggs,
develop into only one person.
In effect,
one twin dies in embryo,
but its DNA survives
in the other.
That's why the DNA
from his buccal swab
matched his hair
but not his semen.
So he had two strains
of DNA in his body.
Yeah, and the DNA in his semen,
was evidently from
his dead twin brother.
You never met Emma Dobbins
or Linley Parker.
I didn't have to meet 'em.
You go to a bar,
you see an attractive woman,
make your move,
she shoots you down.
You go home, you masturbate.
You get on with it.
But when I see a woman
who arouses me...
the whole world disappears...
except for her.
She can't say no.
WARRICK:
What a night.
You guys hungry?
Want to get something to eat?
No, I think I'm going
to call it a night.
Yeah, me, too.
I feel ya.
Get some rest.
All right,
I'll see you.
Hey, hey, Nick,
congratulations
on your almost promotion.
Seriously,
you deserve it.
Wow. That's really
hard for you, isn't it?
Yeah, it is.
( phone ringing )
Grissom.
Yes.
Is she all right?
( siren blips )
She was lucky
she wasn't on the strip.
That's Highway Patrol's
jurisdiction.
She blew .09.
Technically,
she's over,
but they just
lowered the limit,
so we cut her a break
and didn't book her.
But we did have to
call the supervisor.
Well, thank you.
I appreciate the courtesy.
No problem.
Come on.
I'll take you home.