WOMAN:
I don't know what it is,
but the vibe in this place
always gets me feeling hot.
Sexy.
Don't tell me
you don't feel it.
Do you want to take a ride?
(giggles)
Come on.
I know you want to.
That's why we're here.
Right?
The hiker called it in.
Saw something glittering
near the trailhead.
Glittering?
Yeah, first he thought it
was trash, maybe tinfoil.
Well, turns out it
wasn't tinfoil at all.
More like a tin-woman.
(cell phone rings)
She never found that
yellow brick road.
No.
This is Crawford.
Hey, Nick.
Talk about your
Silver Surfer, huh?
You get any I.D.
on her yet?
No purse.
The only thing on her
besides this dress...
...is blunt-force trauma.
Do we have any idea
on the time of death?
Jimmy, you got that, yeah?
Yeah, liver temp puts it
between 12:00 a.m.
and 3:00 a.m.
Midnight and 3:00--
okay, thanks, Jimbo.
That's one hell
of a sight.
Yeah.
That's straight out
of Goldfinger.
What do you make of it?
I hate to speculate before we've
collected any evidence,
but this is Vegas,
she could just be eye candy
for some rich guy's party,
for all we know.
Eye candy, really?
You can rent pretty
girls like this
and paint them up
for parties nowadays.
CRAWFORD: If she was
someone's eye candy fantasy,
she's not anymore.
They chewed her up,
and they spit her out.
Only in the Silver State.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
(camera shutter clicking)
♪ ♪
Looks like our
Silver Girl was more
than just silver
on the outside.
I found silver paint
in both lungs.
So, blunt-force trauma
was not cause of death.
No, she asphyxiated.
In silver paint.
Not something you
see every day.
No, but this is,
at least in this town.
Our girl here liked to party.
Nasal perforations
and irritations
in the lung passages
suggest chronic
drug use.
And besides the blunt-force
trauma, I found other evidence
of a struggle before
she succumbed to the silver.
There's a linear
contusion pattern
over the
trapezius here.
Looks like parallel lines.
Yeah, kind of like
a barbecue grill.
Whatever it was,
it impacted her strongly.
There's also a
strange bruising pattern
right here between
the lines.
Dug out some glass particles
from her elbow.
Might tell us
what we're looking at.
Thanks, Doc.
Hey.
Got an I.D. on
our Silver Girl.
Her prints were
in the system.
Ava Montrose, a local
with a long sheet.
Numerous burglary
and drug arrests.
Next of kin?
Her last known address was her
mother's place in Summerlin.
Her mom is on
her way here now.
Sara's going to do
the notification.
SIDLE:
Mrs. Montrose, when was the last
time you saw your daughter?
I haven't seen Ava
for months.
I was always afraid something
like this was going to happen.
Crowds she ran with,
places she'd go.
What places
would that be?
Places where you-you buy drugs.
Dangerous-looking drug dealer
once showed up at our door,
looking for her.
Did you catch
the drug dealer's name?
No.
And Ava wouldn't say.
We never had the
best relationship.
Why's that?
(father sighs)
She resented me.
For taking the place
of her father.
After Ruth and he split up.
It's not your
fault, Duncan.
Truth is,
Ava didn't listen
to anybody but Ava.
Do you have children,
Miss Sidle?
I don't.
It's not right for a mother
to bury her daughter.
It's not right.
(crying):
We are gonna find out
who did this.
Is there anyone that you can
think of that I should talk to?
A friend or boyfriend?
Ava had lots
of boyfriends.
Nothing serious.
I-I wish I could
help more,
but Ava, her life,
her friends,
she was always
a mystery to me.
Redecorating your
mother's house?
I am, actually.
But that's not
why I'm studying
these shades of gray.
The silver covering our victim's
body was indeed paint.
But not just
any paint.
Chromic potassium
sulfate.
Chrome?
Exactly.
It's a new environmentally
friendly chrome
that's being used
in the auto-painting industry.
This color is called
"silver zephyr."
What about the glass
shards in her elbow?
They follow
a similar road.
The glass is
from a car headlamp.
It's made of bisphenal
polycarbonate.
And it's suggestive
of a non-sealed beam headlamp.
Now, those were discontinued
by government mandate in 1939.
I'm thinking that Ava Montrose
was in an altercation
in close proximity
to a car.
Now, Doc thought
that these grill marks
might be from a barbecue,
but perhaps they're
from a car.
And not just any car;
a classic car,
pre-1939.
Doesn't exactly narrow it down.
Unless, of course, you know
what you're looking for.
♪ ♪
That is a beautiful car.
1938 Packard Touring Sedan.
Pushrod straight-6.
130 horsepower.
And a symbol
of a dying era.
You know, they went out of
business a couple years later.
So, what?
You thinking that Ava Montrose
had a run-in with this car?
Yeah, well, bruising
on her back says so.
And I believe that the trauma
to her neck
was caused by the famous Packard
"Goddess of Speed"
hood ornament.
All right, I buy that.
Can't be that many
1938 Packards in Vegas.
I found two
in the DMV.
First one is owned
by a collector
who kept it in his garage which
burned down six months ago.
Scratch Packard
number one.
Number two is
alive and well,
and owned by an investment
banker named Carlo Derosa.
What do we know about him?
He won't return my calls,
so he is either a very busy man,
or he may be hiding something.
(roaring engine approaches)
SIDLE: How much you want
to bet this is Derosa?
Maybe.
All right, you know, I say
that we just pay the fines,
and then we can tell
the regulators to shove it.
Excuse me, uh,
Carlo Derosa?
Hi. I'm Julie Finlay.
This is Sara Sidle.
We're with the crime lab.
We need to speak with you.
No, no, no, I'm busy.
Just call my office.
I got this.
(alarm whooping)
Oh, oh, I-I'm sorry,
did that just happen?
I can't hear you.
(alarm stops)
Oh, that's better.
What the hell is
happening here?
Do you own
a 1938 Packard?
Yes, I do. What's it to you?
SIDLE: A woman was
killed last night,
and the evidence traces
to your car.
What woman?
What-what are you
talking about?
Ava Montrose.
Do you know her?
Oh, my God, uh...
That's my ex-girlfriend.
Your ex?
Yeah, yeah.
No, we broke up
about a year ago.
I haven't seen
her since.
Hang on. What happened here?
Where do you keep
your Packard?
In the vault.
"The vault"?
Yeah, that's what
I said, the vault.
It's in a warehouse
downtown.
My dad was a classic
car collector,
and, uh, he built this place
to keep his babies safe.
Somebody forget to pay
the power bill?
Nope.
No, my dad liked
to show his cars off.
His favorite part was
the unveiling.
Welcome to car heaven.
Wow.
They don't make 'em
like these anymore.
Is that a '57 Chevy?
You got it.
Uh, V-8 engine
and twin barrel...
blah, blah, blah, blah.
All I know is that
it's old and it's slow.
That's one way to look at it.
Where's the Packard?
Oh! Um... yeah,
it's getting a touch-up.
It's in the mechanic's bay.
What the hell's going on?
What do you think
you're doing, Carlo?
I told you,
no buyers!
No, you need to back up,
dude, okay?
Who are you?
The owner of these cars.
This is my charming
brother, Aron.
And you are not the owner.
Neither are you.
They're not for sale.
We're not buyers.
CARLO:
They're cops.
SIDLE: We're CSIs.
We're investigating a murder--
a woman named Ava Montrose.
Ava?
My ex, Aron.
You remember her.
It's hard to keep track
of your bimbo parade.
I-I don't understand. What does
this have to do with the vault?
Hey, Sara.
Can you come here a sec?
Hey. You keep an eye
on them, please?
Is this our '38 Packard?
Yes, it is.
And there definitely
was a struggle.
That ended with
a fatal chrome bath.
FINLAY:
Oh, check it out.
Couple of drops of chrome.
Kind of looks like
they're heading out the door.
Yeah, maybe carrying
our Silver Woman.
FINLAY:
Yep, the trail ends
right over here.
The only empty
parking spot
in the whole place.
Hey, guys,
can you join us?
I assume
there's usually
a car parked here.
Oh, my God, where's the car?
What car?
The '76 Cadillac.
The most valuable car
in the collection.
CARLO:
God, I can't believe this.
Caddy's gone. Ava's dead.
What the hell happened here?
SIDLE:
Yeah, that's what
we'd like to know.
Along with, what is it
about your
stolen car
that was worth dying over?
I-I can't believe
this is happening.
I mean,
who would do this?
Aron, we found no signs
of any break-in,
so besides you
and your brother,
who else had access
to the place?
Uh, just Rubio, our mechanic.
Uh, he's the only
other person who would know
the security code.
And how well do you know him?
If you're asking if I trust him,
absolutely.
He's been with the family
for 20 years.
He's not even
in the country right now.
He left for Italy two days ago.
What about you?
Where were you last night?
I was at my studio, painting.
Landscapes, not women.
And Carlo?
Where was he last night?
Uh, I was in my office
until about midnight.
SIDLE:
Anyone with you?
No, I sent my assistant
home around about 10:00.
How long were you
dating Ava Montrose?
About a year.
I tried cutting it off
six months into it,
but, uh, she had
a hard time letting go.
If you weren't with
her last night,
then what was
she doing here?
That is a damn good question.
Is there any chance that
Ava knew the security code?
We used to come
down here a lot.
She could've, I guess,
easily looked over my shoulder
while I was punching it in.
I mean, she did
love this place.
She especially loved
my dad's old Caddy.
Enough to try and steal it?
Look...
Ava was a messed-up kid.
We both partied
way too hard back in the day.
I mean, I cleaned up my act...
but Ava did not.
What can you tell me
about this car?
'76 Caddy.
Sounds nice, but...
what, exactly,
makes it so valuable?
My father was murdered in it.
And that makes it more valuable?
There's a certain crowd
of collectors
who pay serious money
for so-called "death cars."
James Dean's Porsche,
Jayne Mansfield's
Buick Electra...
I'm sorry, I don't
recognize the name "Derosa."
Your father was famous?
You're not from
around here, are you?
No, I'm from Seattle.
My dad was Alfonz Derosa.
Kind of a Vegas legend.
Okay, so you're saying
that he was murdered
in the Cadillac?
He was gunned down by a hit man.
October 3, 1989.
Killer worked for Pete Bamonte,
a Chicago loan shark.
I've heard that
story, actually.
How much is the
Cadillac worth?
It'd be close to a million.
And the rest of
the collection?
All up, we'd be talking
about five.
I gather, from your argument,
that you're ready to sell,
but your brother,
Aron, isn't.
Yeah, we've been battling over
what to do with
the collection since, um...
our mom died.
When was that?
Two months ago.
According to the will,
we both own equal
shares in the cars.
I offered to split the...
the collection in half.
You know, I'd sell mine,
he could keep his.
Actually, you know,
Aron's the one
who could use the money, but...
Van Gogh won't compromise.
Van Gogh?
Kid's a starving artist.
(laughs)
The worst kind.
Talentless.
Anyway, he needs to grow up.
Talk about an icon
of Vegas history.
Hmm.
Didn't you write a book
about Vegas mobsters?
Alfonz Derosa had
his own chapter.
What was his story?
Savvy businessman,
ruthless killer.
He ran the skim at
the Tangier's counting room.
Guy was known as "The Vise."
I guess he didn't get his
nickname for his woodworking.
It's how he broke
his enemies' knees.
Mmm, they really
don't make 'em
like they used to.
Nope.
So tell me about
Derosa's murder.
Well, in 1989,
The Vise was in a turf war
with, uh, Pete Bamonte,
some hothead from Chicago.
One night, The Vise took
his mistress for a drive
up to a lovers' lane
near Mount Charleston.
That was his last ride.
♪ ♪
(both chuckling)
SANDERS:
They parked.
Romance was in the air.
Then the mood was broken...
and Alfonz Derosa and
his mistress were dead.
Some hit man
with ties to Bamonte
was eventually convicted
for the murder.
Some jailhouse snitch
dimed him out.
He eventually died in prison.
And what happened to the sons?
They must've been pretty young.
Their mother
raised them.
And as far as anybody can tell,
they didn't follow in
their dad's footsteps.
So now one's
an investment banker
and one's an artist,
and they hate each other.
And they both have access
to this place.
I don't believe a word
either one of them says.
So maybe our witness on wheels
can help us.
Looks like
we've got blood
on the hood ornament.
That would confirm
your theory
that Ava had a run-in
with the car.
(grunting)
FINLAY:
Got something else.
She broke a heel.
I think there's
some residue on it.
SANDERS:
Got a partial shoe impression.
Could be a man's loafer.
SANDERS:
Could be.
So Ava breaks her heel
trying to get away.
Killer grabs her
near the chrome vat.
(screams)
FINLAY:
Gives her a silver
dye job to die for.
SANDERS:
Puts the body in the Caddy...
...and drives away.
I know you don't
trust the brothers,
but if one of them did it,
why not clean up?
You have a point.
You got something?
Yeah.
It's a promotional magnet.
"Cienzo's Pizzeria."
Specks of chrome on it.
Says to me
this was here last night.
Maybe the killer dropped it.
Gives us something
to sink our teeth into.
Ah! Pizza party.
Thanks for
the invite.
All right, I've only got
a little while here.
What do you got?
Mmm. Mmm.
Yeah.
I ran touch DNA
on the security keypad
at the vault.
Besides the brothers,
I found a match to Ava Montrose.
Confirms she knew the password.
And suggesting
maybe she graduated
from stealing watches
to stealing cars.
Is that all you got there,
Papa John?
Far from it.
This is a slice of
Cienzo's pizza.
Uh, the pizza parlor
with the promotional magnet.
We were just there.
HODGES:
Thin crust.
Very New Yorky. Delish.
I don't suppose one of
their employees is our killer?
None of them has a record,
if that's what you're asking.
And none of them collects cars.
However, I did run the
credit cards for the past week
and came across
a very interesting customer.
Henry.
What?
The magnets, please.
Right, right.
I'm sorry.
We picked up
these exemplar magnets
at the pizzeria.
I think I can
use them to explain
what the magnet
that Greg found
was doing at the
classic car vault.
Allow me to
demonstrate.
You're showing me
how a magnet works.
Are you looking
to get fired today?
Wait for it.
Voilà.
The magnet sticks
to one side
of the fender,
but not the
other. Why?
Because this part of the
fender has been repaired.
It's made with
Bondo automotive filler.
So the magnet didn't stick.
It's a little trick
that car appraisers use.
ANDREWS:
And...
according to
credit card records,
there is a certain
Vegas car appraiser
who eats at Cienzo's
once a week.
Thanks for coming in,
Mr. Bixler.
I have a couple
of questions
about your car
appraisal business.
Whatever you need.
Are you familiar with
the Alfonz Derosa collection?
Intimately.
I was, uh, recently hired
by the estate
to appraise their cars, just
after Mrs. Derosa passed away.
When was that?
Uh, about two months ago.
Hmm.
So you haven't been back
to the vault since?
No.
I see.
I understand that
you're also a regular
at Cienzo's Pizzeria
on Flamingo.
Guilty as charged.
Uh, is that a crime?
I mean, I know that
it's not good for me...
Have you ever used one of their
magnets to appraise a car?
Uh, yes.
Uh, yeah, they're
quite handy.
Explains why we found one
in the vault.
Um, yeah, um, like I said,
I was there two months ago.
Mm-hmm.
Well, the pizzeria has
a great special right now.
Large, two toppings
for $7.99.
But it just started
this week.
And we found this magnet
in Derosa's vault yesterday.
It's the same place
where a woman
named Ava Montrose was murdered.
I do not like being lied to.
Were you there last night?
No.
I swear, no. I...
Come on, Mr. Bixler.
Uh, but I was there
three days ago.
So first it was two months ago,
and now it's three days ago.
Look, I realize I lied
to you. I'm sorry.
Um, I have a very
good reason.
What's that?
Carlo Derosa,
uh, he hired me to do
an updated appraisal
of a '76 Cadillac.
A very generous one.
He can be most persuasive.
Why did he want a new appraisal?
He wouldn't tell me.
I can only assume
that he had a
buyer lined up.
Did his brother Aron
know about it?
No.
No, if he found out, I'm sure
he would have blocked the sale.
Look, I'm a little scared
telling you all this.
Um...
Uh, you know who Carlo
Derosa's father was?
Yeah, I know.
RUSSELL:
You know, this whole thing is
starting to look more and more
like an inside job.
One that went
sideways.
Carlo Derosa wants to sell
his father's Caddy.
His brother gets wind
of the sale and stops him.
Right, so Carlo calls
his morally-challenged
ex-girlfriend.
But he doesn't want
to get his hands dirty,
and he needs an alibi.
So maybe Ava enlists one
of her sketchy friends to help.
Someone with experience
in auto theft.
Friend sees the car,
gets greedy...
Kills her, takes the
car, dumps her body.
Hey.
We need
to talk shoes.
Not yours.
Just got the result on the trace
we found on Ava's broken heel.
Elements of concrete
and titanium oxide.
Now, I've seen this before.
It's a unique road-paving
material they use
to eliminate
pollution.
It's found on a half-mile strip
of Verdugo Street.
That's an industrial
neighborhood, right?
Exactly.
And I did some searching--
it's the exact neighborhood
it'a the exact neighborhood
where Ava Montrose just rented
a 20-by-20 storage unit.
That's the perfect
size to hide a car.
STOKES: Busted lock--
someone got here before us.
CRAWFORD:
LVPD.
Anybody in here?
Here's our Caddy.
Yeah.
(clattering)
LVPD. Come on out.
Listen to me.
If you don't want to die today,
show yourself slowly.
Let me see some hands.
You're making a mistake.
No, you're the one
who's made the mistake.
Aron, you mind telling me
what you were doing
in a murdered woman's storage
space with a stolen car?
It's not what
it looks like.
No?
Well, I'll tell you what
it looks like to me.
You recruited
Ava Montrose,
your brother's ex,
the one you
barely remembered,
to help you steal
your Daddy's Caddy
before your brother
could sell it.
So, what happened?
Uh, Ava-- the whacked-out
drug addict--
did she try to
play you somehow?
You get angry.
Things get ugly.
You got it wrong.
About Ava and about me.
I do?
Oh, uh, okay.
Well, e-enlighten me.
I'm not a thief,
and I'm not a murderer.
And Ava?
She was an addict,
but she wasn't a whack-job.
She was a beautiful soul.
It sounds like you're the one
that had a thing for her.
She loved me.
She left Carlo for me.
Right.
No, that kind of thing
happens all the time.
Uh, girl dumps
a high-rolling,
Mercedes-driving
investment banker
for a...
I'm sorry, where
do you work?
I manage a copy store.
And there's nothing
wrong with that,
but maybe you
see my point.
Believe what you want.
I don't give a rat's ass.
All I know is Carlo
is the one who got to her.
He knew exactly how to do it.
With drugs?
Carlo's the one
who put Ava up to stealing
the Caddy. I know it.
He's the one who wanted
to sell it. I wouldn't...
It's a great story, Aron,
but it still doesn't explain
why you're the one we found
in that storage locker!
I was trying
to get my car back.
I set up a credit card
in Ava's name.
Bills came to me, I saw
she rented a storage unit,
I put two and two together--
that's why I was there.
That car means
everything to me.
It's the way
I remember my father.
Right, because that's
where he died.
No.
No, because that's
where he really lived.
I used to stay up
late drawing.
And Carlo would be asleep.
My dad would come in
and grab me,
and... and we'd go for a ride.
Just the two of us.
Will you buy me a car like this
when I'm grown-up, Daddy?
I'll get you 20
of them, Aron.
Sky's the limit, kid.
Aron, were you with your father
the night he was murdered?
It was our last ride together.
He, uh, dropped me off
at a diner.
Said he'd be back in an hour.
I mean, I know
my dad wasn't a saint,
but he was good to me.
What about Carlo?
They fought.
They were too much alike.
That's how I know
he stole it.
He's stealing from the house--
he learned that from my dad.
"Do you want to drive the car
where 'The Vise' was murdered?"
Yeah, not so much.
Well, someone wanted
to drive that car.
Where'd
you find this?
Carlo Derosa
posted it
a week ago
on Farringer's car
auction Web site.
According to Carlo's
bank records,
an anonymous buyer put down
$100,000 on the car.
But we know that brother
Aron stopped the sale.
Yes, but there's no indication
that Carlo returned the deposit.
Suggesting that he hadn't given
up on the idea of selling it.
So, where are we?
We got one brother
who's willing to steal
the car to sell it,
the other one willing
to steal it to protect it.
So which
brother did it?
I don't think it was
either one of them.
You remember the shoe impression
we found at the scene?
Yeah.
We compared it to all
the shoes the brothers owned,
and we did not get a match.
Doesn't mean that the
shoes weren't thrown away.
That's true.
But it's also true that we could
be looking for somebody else.
A scorned buyer, perhaps.
Okay, so a buyer's
interested in the Mob car,
maybe uses Mob
tactics to get it.
Any luck on following
the money trail?
No, it all leads
to offshore accounts.
And no names.
But I will keep
working on it.
How come you know so
much about classic cars?
Cute guy in shop class.
No, seriously.
Actually, uh, my brother owned
a '57 Chevy rust bucket.
Left it in the garage
when he went to college.
Totally forgot
about it.
And then, when I got
a little older,
I needed a way
to get to school, so...
You fixed it up.
Took the engine
completely apart
and reassembled it
piece by piece.
I found it really
interesting
to see how it all connected.
Carburetor as crime scene.
Yeah, it's all in the details.
I can't believe this backseat.
You could have
a picnic in there.
I think Alfonz and his mistress
were up to more than that.
Talk about a last ride.
(chuckles)
BRODY: I think
I may have found something
from our killer's last ride.
Some sort of fiber.
I think I found
a chrome flake, too.
Could be from
our Silver Woman.
We know this car was used
for the body dump.
Maybe she was transported
in the trunk.
You look in there yet?
Nope.
Let's check it out.
Oh.
A tarp with chrome
paint and blood.
Confirms that theory.
Yep.
Ooh, what's that?
A copy of Ken Bixler's
appraisal of this car.
Looks like it was printed
from the Farringer Web site.
Well, maybe this printout
will give us a print.
I got a partial.
Not sure if it'll be enough
for AFIS, though.
Well, then, let's hope
that our mystery buyer left
some epithelials behind.
Find anything?
Hey, Morgan,
what do you got?
I just got results on the touch
DNA from the appraisal report.
So who's the buyer
of the Cadillac?
Results come back as a
female familial match
to Ava Montrose.
And she doesn't have any
sisters or daughters.
That just leaves
her mother.
Ruth Montrose.
Ruth Montrose is our buyer.
And if our theory is correct,
she's not just our buyer;
she's our killer.
You must help me get this car.
Don't "must" me, Mother.
This fiasco's all yours,
not mine.
Darling, I have borrowed
a lot of money
from some very
disreputable men.
If I don't pay them, Lord knows
what's going to happen to me.
Do you understand?
I understand perfectly.
You need me.
I have never asked you
for anything.
SIDLE:
So you admit to using
your own daughter
to help steal a car.
Ava knew how to get
into the vault.
It's appalling, I know.
I can't argue with that.
Why did you need
to buy the car so badly?
I wasn't the buyer.
I was just an intermediary
for a wealthy gentleman
from Dubai.
I met him at a party
a month ago.
He loves Mob lore and cars.
I told him that Alfonz Derosa's
death car was for sale.
And he was interested?
He was ready to pay two million
when he came back from Dubai.
Double the appraisal,
double the purchase price.
That's not a bad profit.
So, you borrowed the money
from a loan shark
to make the deposit.
Yes.
And then that sentimental fool,
Aron Derosa, canceled the sale.
And that's when your problems
really started.
What happened to Ava
in that vault?
(chuckles)
I have no idea.
Yeah, see, I thought
we were getting somewhere.
I wasn't there.
I would never murder
my own daughter.
I wish I could believe
that, Ms. Montrose.
I've seen a lot over the years.
Nothing surprises me.
Believe what you will.
I think Ava brought
an unsavory friend to help her.
And then something
went terribly wrong.
RUSSELL:
Well, she's not gonna win
mother of the year awards.
But would she kill
her own daughter?
You believe her story?
Well, I think there's
a pragmatic woman
under all that crazy,
(phone chirps)
and her daughter's more
valuable alive than dead.
Mmm. Greg wants to know
if I feel like
taking a ride back to the past.
Boy, this looks like
it could all be part
of a new edition for your book.
Could be.
But I also think it relates
to Ava Montrose's murder.
This is Pete Bamonte.
Chicago loan shark and the guy
behind Alfonz Derosa's murder.
Right, he hired the
hit man to do it.
When I was researching
the Derosa murder from '89,
I discovered
that Bamonte had a son.
Bamonte got divorced.
His wife remarried,
and then his son
took his stepfather's last name,
which was Reidel.
Reidel, as in Duncan Reidel?
Ruth Montrose's boyfriend
is Pete Bamonte's son?
I'm saying maybe
we have a new suspect,
and maybe Ruth Montrose's story
about a buyer in Dubai
was just a story.
And the real buyer
is a little closer to home.
Okay, so where's our proof?
How are we doing
with the, uh,
trace that we got
from the Caddy?
Finn's working on it.
Where you headed?
I'm not sure.
So, if you're right
and Duncan Reidel is the killer,
then he must have done
restoration work
before he killed Ava.
What do you mean?
Well, I got the results back
from the fiber that we found
on the passenger seat.
Cannabis sativa.
Hemp.
It's used for
upholstery stuffing.
And the thing I know
about classic cars
is they did not use hemp
in the carpet
or in the seat lining.
Not in 1976, anyway.
Also, check out the result
on the chrome.
It's not chromic
potassium sulfate.
It didn't come off the girl.
It must have flaked
off the car.
But on what part of the car?
Yeah, that is
what I am trying
to figure out.
Well, we found both
pieces of trace here,
near the passenger seat.
The chrome on the
headrest post is flaking.
Someone messed with it.
Maybe the killer
swapped out
the original headrest
with a new one,
reupholstered with hemp.
There's one way to know
for sure.
After Alfonz and
his mistress
were shot,
this entire seat
was covered in blood.
When is the last time
someone was shot
in the head in a car
and didn't leave any
blood on the headrest?
How about never?
So, Ava's killer
replaced the headrest.
The question is: Why?
SANDERS:
The hit man who went to prison
for the murder of Alfonz Derosa
wasn't convicted on evidence.
He was convicted on the word
of a jailhouse snitch.
So you're thinking
he was set up?
Yeah, maybe there was
a different shooter,
someone closer to the guy
who ordered the hit.
In 1989,
Duncan Reidel was 18 years old.
So, Duncan could've
been the one to pull the trigger
for his father.
And maybe there was something
in that headrest
that could've proven it.
Like a bullet.
Exactly.
So let's see
if there's something
on this headrest
that will help us
make our case today.
♪ ♪
SANDERS:
Hey.
Did you get an I.D.
off the headrest?
Yeah, I did.
Not who we expected.
Reidel's off the hook.
So who is it?
RUSSELL:
You know, it's interesting,
what a car means
to different people.
You take this Cadillac.
To Carlo Derosa,
it means revenge.
Selling it's a great way
to get back at a father
who cared more about his
cars than about him.
Yeah, to Aron Derosa,
keeping it
is a way of remembering
that father.
To him, the car means love.
Right, we-we were
just wondering...
What did it mean to you?
Mr. Bixler?
Um... (chuckles) nothing.
I mean, I mean,
not a damn thing.
It was just a part of my job.
Wrong answer, Ken.
Yeah, we-we kind of
figured that, to you,
the car means heartbreak.
Heartbreak?
I... What are you talking about?
You see, Ken,
we found your DNA
on the passenger side headrest.
Well, uh, I inspected
that headrest, so...
No, actually, the headrest you
inspected was the old headrest.
The manufactured one.
We're talking
about the new headrest.
And that's because
you replaced it.
We, uh, recovered the old
headrest in the Dumpster
behind your appraisal office,
and your prints were on that.
We also found an expended bullet
that was a direct match
to a Beretta manufactured
in 1980.
Your Beretta.
It's the same
gun you fired
last year when you
thought an intruder
was breaking into your house.
RUSSELL:
Remember, the cops
were called?
The bullet and the gun
were processed and then put
in the system.
And it's also the same gun
that was used
to murder Alfonz Derosa.
Yeah, unfortunately, though...
The recovered bullets
were too degraded
to process.
Right, but in the cops' defense,
they didn't realize that you
fired three shots, not two.
A stray round
going into the headrest.
(laughter)
The cops thought
it was a professional hit.
They didn't realize it was just
an enraged car salesman
with a shaky hand.
What I don't understand is:
Why'd you feel like you had
to kill him in the first place?
You barely knew the guy.
I wasn't there to kill Alfonz.
I was there to kill Vera.
Vera Scanell.
Alfonz's mistress.
My fiancée.
What a beautiful wreck she was.
She never cared
how much pain she caused me.
The humiliation.
They both got
what was coming to them.
I didn't regret it for a second.
Until 30 years later
when you realized
that you left
some evidence behind.
Ken,
what about Ava?
How'd she play into this?
I've known her for years.
I was friends with her dealer.
I used to help him
launder money.
She came to me about a week ago,
telling me about her mom's plan
to steal the car.
They wanted help getting it
out of the country.
But with the car
being sold, you were worried
that the bullet in the headrest
would be discovered
and finally matched
to your Beretta.
I had to get it out.
I sent her away.
I sent her away
for an hour or so
so I could get
my work done.
Too bad she had to come back.
The vibe in this place
always gets me feeling hot.
Sexy.
Do you want to take a ride?
The hell you doing here?
I got bored. Let's go.
Now.
The car's not ready yet.
I thought you said you were
working on the engine.
What are you up to, Kenny boy?
You got an angle, don't you?
What is it? I want in.
Stay out of it, Ava.
(laughs)
Now I know it's good.
You want me to stay out of it,
it's gonna cost...
I told you to stay
the hell out of here!
Come here!
Get back!
Come back! (grunts)
(grunting and groaning)
Come here. Come on!
Just talked to Carlo Derosa.
He's sending someone over
to pick up the Caddy.
Well, Bixler did confess,
so the car's not
evidence anymore.
What about Aron Derosa?
Still doesn't want to sell?
Actually, the brothers
finally compromised.
They're donating the car
to the Mob Museum.
Oh, that sounds like
a good place for her.
Still such a shame that she's
never gonna see the road again.
One last ride?
I thought you'd never ask.