♪ ♪
(siren wailing)
(indistinct radio transmission)
PHILLIPS:
All right, fellas.
Well, looks like somebody went
for a little skinny-dip,
and things didn't go so well
last night, huh? Thanks, boys.
House has been on the
market for a couple months.
Just been sitting
here vacant.
Neighbors say they see
kids hop the fence,
use the pool,
all the time.
But nobody saw anything
last night?
Right.
Hey, Akers, do we even know
who she is, yet?
AKERS: No, not yet.
There's no I.D.
There's no car out front.
We knocked on doors.
She's not from the neighborhood.
STOKES:
She got here somehow.
Maybe she came with a friend,
and that friend took off.
I don't know if "friend,"
is the word I'd use.
There are bruises, looks like
finger marks, on her neck.
Take a look at this.
Got skin underneath
her fingernails.
She struggled.
Possibly while being
held under water.
Yeah, hang-hang on a second.
Greg, let me borrow
your mini-UV for a second.
Hold up that wrist for me.
Yeah, yeah.
There we go, Greg, look at that.
(camera shutter clicks)
Club bracelets and hand stamps.
Well, party didn't start here.
Looks like she made
the rounds last night.
Partied like there was
no tomorrow.
Unfortunately for her,
she was right.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
So, this is our party girl.
Wow, she's so young.
What a waste.
Did you collect
a sexual assault kit?
Yes, evidence of recent
sexual activity.
Can't say for certain
that it was forced,
but it was certainly
aggressive.
No semen, though.
Doesn't rule out rape.
Just means that her attacker was
smart enough to use a condom.
Any clue who
she might be, yet?
Still a Jane Doe.
But... trashy clothes,
lots of costume jewelry.
May have been a sex worker.
You don't know much
about women's clothes, huh?
These "trashy shoes"
go for about, uh, 1,200 bucks.
What?
Yep.
And this... yeah.
I saw that upstairs
at the Mediterranean.
Two grand, on sale.
For that little thing?
Yeah, this girl had
a lot of money.
Yeah, or somebody willing
to spend it on her.
Well, uh, if
that's the case...
...this thing might
actually be real.
Wow.
That is a very big rock.
It's probably insured,
which means it might have
a serial number etched on it.
SANDERS:
It's real, all right.
Nearly flawless.
Yeah?
How big is it?
Well, now, I thought
size doesn't matter.
Well, you
thought wrong.
Come on, how big?
It's nearly
four karats.
Wow.
I don't see
any etching, though.
No serial number
or I.D. markings.
So, it's not gonna help
us I.D. our victim.
You know, there are other ways
to identify a diamond
these days.
There, see that?
You mean the
refraction pattern?
Yeah.
That pattern is unique
to that stone.
Like a fingerprint.
And it can be registered
with an insurance database.
We just have to see
if this particular pattern
is in the system.
(whirring)
(beeping)
Diamond is registered
to Martin Fox, St. George, Utah.
That's my wife.
You know, the whole
drive down here,
I was hoping it was
just a mistake.
Who did this to her,
Mr. Russell?
At this point
in the investigation,
we're not ready
to name any suspects.
Can you at least
tell me how it happened?
Mr. Fox, we need more time
to study the evidence
before we can
actually...
She was wasted, though,
wasn't she?
That much you know.
Your wife's blood-alcohol level
was twice the legal limit.
And there's evidence of
several controlled substances
in her system.
Was there a man involved?
Wouldn't be the first time.
Daycia didn't like
to party alone.
Mr. Fox, I'm very sorry
for your loss,
but I-I'm not gonna give you
any details here.
$8,000 a week.
She was supposed
to be safe.
Hell, she was supposed
to be getting better.
What-what was $8,000 a week?
Rehab.
Daycia was in rehab,
here in Vegas.
Three weeks already.
(birds chirping)
(vehicle approaching)
This is rehab?
Seriously?
I'd be worried
about getting addicted
to living in a place like this.
Well, maybe
that's the idea.
You spend so much to stay here,
you don't have any money left
to support your habit.
You know, I checked out
their Web site.
They claim to have one
of the highest success rates
in the state.
Really?
Yeah, they're all
about pampering you
in a setting of luxury,
harmony and serenity.
They seem to have that covered.
Don't tell me I don't care
about my children, Zach.
They're the most important
thing in my life.
Are they?
'Cause it sounds to me
like you choose the pills
over your kids
every time.
Do I really have to sit
here and listen to this?
From him?
I know it's hard
to hear what Zach
has to say, Karen. But isn't
that the heart of the problem?
The addiction takes
over your whole life.
Pushes everything else out.
Or you could keep denying it.
That's what I did.
Until divorce papers
and the threat of losing
my children opened my eyes.
(doorbell rings)
I got it.
Hi there.
I'm CSI Stokes.
This is Finlay.
We're with the
police department.
We'd like to ask you
a few questions
if, uh, that's
all right.
Oh, God, this is about Daycia,
isn't it?
FINLAY:
I'm sorry, who are you?
Adam King. I run Desert Peace.
Daycia disappeared, she never
came home last night.
How bad is it?
It's as bad as it gets.
She's dead.
(sighs)
We're gonna
have to take a break.
This was Daycia's room.
So...
this is what eight grand
a week looks like.
Well, there's no reason
that recovery
should be a punitive
process.
We try to
pamper our patients,
make 'em feel as comfortable
as possible.
STOKES: And, hey,
the longer they stay,
the better, am I right?
In a clinical sense, yes.
But I get a feeling that's
not what you're implying.
When was the last
time you saw Daycia?
Right about 9:00
last night.
She was in the kitchen
getting something to eat.
Must've ducked out
sometime after that.
What do you mean,
"ducked out"?
Is that typical
of the care around here?
There's no such thing as typical
care here at Desert Peace.
Each patient receives
a personalized treatment plan.
And did Daycia
have a personalized
treatment plan that allowed her
to go out and get wasted?
What would you
have me do, Mr. Stokes?
Keep an eye
on her, for one.
They're not
locked up--
patients are here by choice.
I can't force people
to stay here.
Especially someone like Daycia.
What is that
supposed to mean?
She was already skittish
about getting clean.
If I'd have clamped down
on her--
if I would have
imposed restrictions--
she would've just checked
herself out of here, and I would
have had no chance
at trying to help her.
And no chance at getting
that eight grand.
So did
anybody else
duck out last night?
Any of the other patients?
No.
Zach, Len and Karen
were all here.
You know, they're committed
to getting sober.
So you're saying
that Daycia wasn't?
Daycia was here 'cause
her husband put her here.
Not because she wanted
to get better.
And I'm not saying that
as a knock. I flunked
out of six rehabs myself before
I took getting sober seriously.
As a straight numbers game,
most addicts end up like Daycia.
BRODY:
It's a hand stamp of a crown.
Can't you just tell me
if you guys used
a crown stamp last night?
How is that a
proprietary secret?
(chuckles) Do you even know
what "proprietary" means?
(line clicks)
Hello?
That maybe didn't go as well
as I might have liked.
Trying to figure out which clubs
our victim was at last night?
BRODY: So far, I have it
narrowed down to four.
Beautiful young girl
out by herself
getting more and more impaired?
Truth is, the killer
could have spotted her anywhere
along the way
and decided to follow her.
BRODY: And the problem is,
she went to so many places,
who knows how many hundreds
of people she met?
Hey. You got
something for us?
I've been working on extracting
the DNA from the tissue
found under
the victim's fingernails.
Please tell me
you found a match.
I wish I could, but no-- the DNA
in the sample
was degraded,
probably from
soaking in the pool.
I was only able
to type four loci.
It's not enough
to enter into CODIS.
RUSSELL:
No CODIS match.
You've got your work
cut out for you.
(chuckles)
Yes, I do.
I started without you.
I hope you don't mind.
No problem.
Only reason I called down
was to see if you'd found
anything yet.
Well, so far,
no surprises.
All indications are
she was a longtime drinker
and drug user.
As good as she looks
on the outside,
her insides paint a
different picture.
Get a chance to look
at the finger marks
on the back of her neck?
I did.
Definitely perimortem.
Consistent with someone
holding her underwater.
Lungs tell
the same story.
They're heavy.
They're filled with water.
Telltale sign she drowned.
(sniffing)
Greg, the pool
you found her in--
chlorine or saline?
Uh, it was chlorine. Why?
(sniffs)
If you get any closer,
you can literally be
breathing down my neck.
You wish.
So, what is going on
with the pool water
from our victim's lungs?
Greg said that there was
some sort of an issue.
I don't think
that it is pool water.
Certainly doesn't
match any
of the samples that
Nick brought in.
pH is about the same,
but the chlorine level
is far too low.
More in line
with regular tap water.
What did the GCMS find?
Oh, perfect timing.
(printer whirring)
Let's take a look.
Traces of sodium
myreth sulfate,
panthenol,
methyl glycinate.
All ingredients in soap.
What is the organic oil?
Extract of
Lavandula augustifolia.
Lavender.
The fluid in the victim's
lungs was bathwater.
Yep.
The ingredients are
an exact match
to what was in the
water in her lungs.
You guys can't just come
barging in here.
Yeah, that warrant
in your hand says we can.
We have every right in the world
to search the crime scene.
Crime scene?
What are you talking about?
Daycia did not drown
in any pool.
She was killed
right here.
♪ ♪
BRODY:
Hi.
So, I've been calling
cab companies.
Talked to a dispatcher
who's got a driver
who dropped off a fare
last night at this address.
3:00 a.m.
A couple--
man and a woman.
So Daycia brought
her killer home.
Okay, so... they came
in here at 3:00 a.m.
Daycia, as we know,
is messed up on pills.
And then they ended
up in the tub.
You know, maybe she...
maybe she refused
his sexual advances,
or... the sex got
out of control?
Either way...
...he ends up drowning her.
(muffled screaming)
Yeah, but look around.
The tub, the towels--
everything's clean and dry.
It's like nothing ever happened.
So, after Daycia was dead,
he cleaned up.
Took her body out of the tub,
and then erased
any sign that they had ever
been here at all.
If they came here in a cab,
how did the killer
get Daycia's body
all the way to the pool,
which is over a mile away?
That's a good question.
In the meantime,
the cab company is trying
to locate the driver,
and we got to figure out
where the evidence
from this room ended up.
All right, I'm
gonna go talk
to the other people
living here.
This is rehab--
nobody sleeps--
so I'm sure somebody
saw something.
Let's hope.
I was up the whole night,
crawling between hot showers
to stop the chills
and hugging the toilet
and puking my guts out.
I didn't hear anything.
I wish I would have, you know,
heard something.
Maybe I could have tried
to help her.
I was watching a movie
on my laptop,
and I had my headphones in.
THERAPIST:
So many addicts.
They can be really nice people,
but when they're using,
they make some
very poor choices.
Daycia was young
and immature and...
let her addiction
cloud her judgment.
Look, to me, Daycia
was never gonna get clean,
'cause she didn't have to.
No matter what, she had a rich
husband waiting for her at home.
You know, you... you're just
never gonna hit rock bottom
if you got a safety net
like that.
This is really messing
with my head.
I came here to get healthy.
This is not what I needed.
You know, last night
wasn't the first night
that she went out
drinking and partying.
She pretty much went
partying and shopping
any time she felt like it.
I was against giving her
so much latitude, but...
Adam's the boss.
I have to get sober this time.
I don't have a choice.
The stakes...
the stakes are just too high.
If I fail...
I lose my kids.
My biggest concern was Daycia's
effect on the other patients.
She was toxic in that way.
This sucks.
I can't believe she did this.
Frankly, if it'd been up to me,
she never would have
been in here.
Hey.
So, this is the cab
that brought our victim
home this morning.
Okay.
Now, if it was the killer
that rode with her,
then hopefully he left us
some kind of trace.
Yeah, hopefully,
'cause I just
got done talking
with the driver.
Give you a description?
No, not really.
The only thing
he could remember
is that the guy
was a white male.
Probably couldn't take his eye
off the pretty girl
the whole time.
Yeah, probably. Did say she
was in pretty rough shape,
but he didn't think she
was in any real danger.
I'm sure she didn't
think so, either.
Till the last second.
Give me a call
if you find something.
Okay.
I've seen, uh,
plenty of people
Dumpster-dive before,
but they never made
it look so good.
Why don't you let me
get that for you?
It's Zach, right?
It'd be better if you
didn't touch anything.
Ah, yes.
Evidence.
Uh, I just wanted to help.
You want to help?
You could tell me about Daycia.
We think she may have brought
a guy home last night.
Sounds like she's quite
the party girl.
May have not been
the first time.
You ever see her with anybody?
Ah, here at the house, no.
But somewhere else,
with someone?
Well, don't tell
Twyla, but, uh...
I let Daycia talk me into
going out one night.
See, one of the things
you got to know
about me is, pretty women,
they're like my kryptonite,
you know?
Maybe my deadliest
of addictions.
So you went clubbing
and you saw her hook up
with somebody.
There was this guy
at one of the clubs,
this cowboy who
was watching her.
Older guy.
I didn't think much of it,
because with Daycia,
all the guys watched
her, you know?
Little while later, I went
to the bar to get a drink,
and when I came
back, I saw Daycia
heading out the door with
this guy, the cowboy.
So she just picked up
and left, just like that?
She was in group
the next morning.
She didn't mention it.
I didn't, either.
Never came up again.
(sighing):
Well...
I'm gonna get this run in.
Got to clear my head.
All this talk of
bars and women--
start tugging me in the
wrong direction, you know?
Well, I may need to talk
to you again later.
Just, uh, take
it easy on me.
Remember what I said
about kryptonite.
How could I forget?
Wow.
(dog barking in distance)
Huh.
Bingo.
♪ ♪
ANDREWS:
Hey.
I've got slightly better
news than last time.
I was able to pull DNA
from your bath towels.
Two contributors.
One the, uh, victim, I assume.
What about the other?
An unknown male, not in CODIS,
but this is interesting.
The DNA from the towel
has the same four core loci
as the DNA under
the victim's nails.
Same unknown male-- our killer.
Still no way to put
an I.D. to him.
What are you working on here?
These pieces of wax were found
in the bag with the
rest of the evidence.
I think it came
from this candle.
Spilled while the wax
was still hot.
The bottom's smooth,
like the rim of a bathtub.
I'm thinking the wax
was knocked over
during the murder.
After the wax hardened,
the killer used this lovely
nail file to chip it up
and clean up the mess.
ANDREWS:
Looks like there's some kind
of impression there.
Mm-hmm. I'm thinking it's
the killer's hand or arm.
If I can get this whole thing
put together,
I might be able to...
Hey, have you seen Nick?
No, not recently.
Well, I got AFIS results on the
lifts from the cab. Yours, too.
They match a felony
DUI arrest from 2007.
The guy's prints
were everywhere.
Well, whose prints?
Adam and I were
just talking
about how we should
proceed in light
of Daycia's death.
And we both agree
that it would be detrimental
to your treatment
if we were to shut down,
even for a little while.
It's not
gonna be easy,
but we need to...
reestablish a sense
of normalcy...
Hey, everybody.
Knock, knock.
And before you start
spouting off again,
the answer's yes,
we have a warrant.
Only this time
it's an arrest warrant.
Oh, my God,
I don't believe this.
What are you talking about?
Arrest?
Hook him up, Akers.
Adam King,
you're under arrest for the
murder of Daycia Fox. Put
your hands behind your back.
Adam, what-what is this?
What's happening?
I don't know.
It's a mistake.
Hey, I didn't kill Daycia.
You know that.
Let's go.
You guys know that.
This is ridiculous.
I didn't kill her.
She was my patient.
I was helping her.
Hey, do you hear me?
Yeah, yeah, I hear you.
And you'll have plenty of time
to plead your case in court.
But right now... Mr. Fox?
(gunshots)
Down on your knees!
Get down on the ground!
(groaning)
Adam?
Adam.
Call the paramedics, Akers.
Call them.
This is Officer Akers.
Roll paramedics to my location.
Mr. Fox,
I had you pegged as someone
with just a little more sense.
Did you put any thought into
how this was gonna turn out?
I trusted him.
I took the thing most precious
in my life,
and I put it
in Adam King's hands.
He betrayed that trust.
So you...
you just go and you shoot him?
You know, you're lucky
you weren't shot yourself.
And you're damn lucky you didn't
hit one of my officers.
You didn't know Daycia,
Mr. Russell.
I know you know about her,
okay, her-her drinking
and partying
and her-her struggles.
You didn't know
the...
the person that she was
before this...
this-this sickness
took hold of her.
Destroyed her.
Destroyed everything.
God's honest truth, I don't
much care what happens now.
(door opens)
FINLAY:
Uh, he shouldn't have those.
He's a former drug addict.
Painkillers probably aren't
a good idea, right, Adam?
Guess you're just gonna
have to tough it out.
Thank you.
I know you think that
I'm some sort of monster,
that I killed Daycia,
but you're wrong.
This was taken
from a traffic cam
about five blocks away
from the house
where Daycia's
body was found.
This is you,
about to dump Daycia's body.
You want to tell me again
how you didn't kill her?
I didn't.
I only moved the body.
From rehab to the swimming pool.
But she was dead already.
I swear.
That is
not even a good attempt
at a lie.
We found your
fingerprints
all over the taxicab.
And, uh, you did clean up
the crime scene in the bathroom.
Yeah, I know all that.
Damn it, when Daycia didn't
come home that night,
I went out looking
for her, all right?
Not the first time
I had to hunt her down.
After searching
a couple of clubs,
I found her.
And I brought her home
in the cab.
I put her to bed.
That still does not get us
to here, Adam.
After a couple hours,
I went in to go check on her,
to see if she was okay.
She wasn't in her bed.
I found her in the tub.
Daycia. Daycia.
No. No. No, no, no.
She was dead.
Look, I figured
she had just passed out,
slipped under the water,
you know?
That it was an accident.
You still
should've called 911.
I should've.
But I panicked.
Daycia's wasn't the first death
at Desert Peace.
We had an overdose
eight months ago.
The backlash on the clinic
was a nightmare.
Oh, so that's why
you moved her body
because you were afraid
of the backlash?
Look, I had three other patients
that I had to think about,
who are fighting
for their lives,
who count on me.
So...
I cleaned everything up
and moved the body.
Made it look
like she was never home.
FINLAY:
He was telling the truth
about one thing.
Eight months ago,
Desert Peace did have
a fatality.
A female patient OD'd
on sleeping pills.
So Adam, covering up
Daycia's death,
was trying
to avoid bad PR
and maybe a hike
in his insurance premiums,
right?
The question is,
do we believe him
when he says
he did not kill her?
Well, personally,
I would not trust a word.
But I did swab
him, and his DNA
did not match what we have
on the bath towel
or underneath the fingernails
of the victim.
Which suggests he's not our guy.
So...
what are we looking at?
At some point between
the cab ride home
and when Adam went
to check on her,
someone else went into Daycia's
bathroom and killed her.
♪ ♪
Hey, Nick, it's a ring.
The impression in the wax,
it's two fingers and a ring.
Daycia was wearing a diamond
ring when we found her.
No, no.
It's not Daycia's ring.
It's something different.
I think it's the killer's.
STOKES:
You're right.
That is a man's ring.
Yeah, and it's got
an inscription on it,
or at least
a tiny part of one.
STOKES:
21, 12.
Like a class ring.
Or at least
that's what I was thinking.
But then that's, like,
a hundred years in the future,
so there's no way
it could be
a class ring.
Well, what if it's not the year?
What if it's a... score?
You know? From a game.
21-12.
Why would someone
put a score on a ring?
If it's a championship ring,
a lot of times
they'll put the score on there.
Zach.
Hmm?
Zach Alton, he's one of the
patients at the rehab center.
He-he used to be a jock at WLVU.
Football, I think.
Let's see.
Right here.
2007. WLVU Mustangs won
their conference championship.
21-12?
21-12.
♪ ♪
I, uh...
(clears throat)
I'm afraid I don't have
any good news for you.
Your DNA was a match
to the DNA we found
on the towels
in Daycia's bathroom.
It was also a match to the DNA
we found under her fingernails,
which is no surprise,
considering the scratches
on your chest.
As far
as your blood goes,
we found traces
of diazepam and oxycodone,
the same drugs that were
in Daycia's system
and the same drugs
that we found
in her bathroom.
So, as you can see,
the evidence pretty much
tells the story here.
Unless there's something
you'd like to add.
I mean...
wh-why would I kill her?
Why would I
do anything?
It doesn't even make sense.
Are you trying to tell me
you can't remember anything?
I only remember parts.
I remember
I was in bed, asleep.
I don't know what time it was.
And, uh...
Daycia comes in the room
wearing next to nothing.
Zach.
I'm gonna
take a bath.
And it is an
awfully big tub.
You want to join?
You know this is a bad idea.
Ooh. Then I guess
this is a bad idea, too, huh?
Pretty women.
They're my...
Kryptonite. Yeah, I heard.
We get it.
So you ended up in the tub...
(squeals)
(chuckles)
ZACH:
One drink leads to another,
she brings out the pills and...
I don't know, I guess
at that point I figured,
might as well go all in.
But the rest...
I cannot
for the life
of me remember.
It's... a blackout.
I woke up the
next morning
by myself in my bed,
and Daycia was nowhere around,
so...
So you just went about your day?
I had no idea I killed her.
Unfortunately,
that doesn't make it
any less of a crime.
Got your text, Doc.
Why the 911?
Just examining a tissue section
from your drowning victim's
organs.
Have a gander.
SANDERS: What am I looking at?
Lung tissue,
specifically alveoli.
They're the little sacs where
oxygen and CO2 are exchanged.
They're blown,
all popped like tiny balloons.
Well, why?
What would cause that?
Well, normally
I would say barotrauma.
You know, the bends.
A diver ascends too fast,
causing excess air pressure
in the lungs.
Only the damage here was
caused by excess water pressure.
From the drowning, right?
No, that's the problem.
With drowning,
you don't generate pressure.
Certainly not enough pressure
to pop the alveoli.
This young girl's lungs filled
with a rush of water
with enough force
to cause the alveoli
to expand
beyond their capacity.
So what are you saying happened?
The only scenario
I can think of
is that someone pumped water
into her lungs
forcibly, intentionally.
Like someone put a tube
down her throat.
And then pumped water into her,
I'd have to say,
after she was already dead.
So, she didn't drown.
The killer only wanted to
make it look like she drowned.
The more likely cause
of death was suffocation,
which ultimately yields
the same results as drowning--
asphyxiation
of the brain.
There was
foreign matter in the lungs--
organic flecks,
I couldn't identify--
and I sent those to Hodges
for analysis.
But the bottom line is,
we've been working with
the wrong cause of death.
And with the wrong
cause of death,
you most likely
have the wrong killer.
At the time of
Daycia's death,
the football star,
Zach, had been drinking,
and he had two different
prescription meds in him, so,
he was pretty
seriously impaired.
He's not denying
he killed Daycia.
He pretty much confessed.
He says
he blacked out.
So, you're thinking that Zach's
not responsible for the murder?
According to the doc,
the drowning was staged
by pumping her body
full of water.
Now, if that's the case,
that means
the killer had
to feed a tube down
her trachea, into her lungs.
That's not an easy thing to do.
Basically had to intubate her.
I've seen ER docs struggle
to do this.
It takes dexterity,
at the very least.
Zach was drunk and full of meds,
so, no way
he could have pulled that off.
FINLAY:
If Zach is not the killer,
where are we?
We know that Adam
brought Daycia home in the cab
at 3:00 a.m., and says
that he put her to bed.
Come on, Adam!
I'm not tired!
Everybody's trying
to sleep, okay?
Yeah, well, I'm not gonna
be able to go to sleep.
Okay, well, let's just
try to get you in bed.
STOKES:
And we know
that Daycia wasn't ready
to call it a night,
so she goes and convinces Zach
that it's a good time
to take a bath.
You don't see anything
that you want?
Come on, Zach.
In they go into the tub,
they have sex,
leaving the marks on Daycia's
neck, and the scratches on Zach,
but, also, leaving
Daycia alive and well.
STOKES:
Tub takes 45 minutes,
at the most, an hour.
That gives the killer plenty of
time to take care of business.
So, not counting Zach and Adam,
there were three other people
in the house
that we know of.
There were two patients--
Karen and Len--
and a staffer named Twyla.
At this point, any one
of the three is a candidate.
Morgan?
Hey.
Hodges, what's going on?
I could use a little
help as to context.
Doc Robbins found a foreign
substance in your victim's
lungs, sent me a
sample for analysis.
Okay, what did he find?
It's all organic.
Primarily a combination
of nitrogen, phosphorus,
potassium and carbon.
Some of the nitrogen had
converted into ammonia.
How can I help?
Well, it's
just that what's
suggested by the chemicals
and their particular proportions
is waste.
Specifically,
fish or bird waste.
Now, I don't know how
that could have gotten
into your
victim's lungs.
Fish waste.
But that doesn't make any sense.
Actually, Hodges,
it makes perfect sense.
Ah. Look at this.
Tubing.
Looks like it would
be the right size
to put down
someone's throat.
Yeah. Now,
all you would need is a...
pump...
(pump whistles)
to pump with.
The same set of prints
shows up on everything.
They come back to the
house therapist, Twyla Owens.
Oh, you said that she took
care of the fish tank,
so it makes sense that her
prints would be everywhere.
Well, everywhere
except for the plastic tubing.
There were no prints there.
It's been wiped clean.
And what about the pump?
Has tons of her prints on it,
and nobody else's.
Why would the killer clean one
and not the other?
Oh.
Because the killer
didn't use the pump.
There's a crack
in the housing.
Yeah, and it's bone dry.
There's no way this was part
of the murder weapon.
Yeah, but the killer had
to use something
to force the water
into Daycia's lungs.
I mean, Doc said her alveoli
were popped like balloons.
Well, then, maybe the killer
pumped the water the same way
that you'd blow up a balloon.
Maybe he used his mouth.
If that's the case,
maybe our killer left us
just what we need.
Come on, this is insane.
This is absolutely insane.
I'm two days away
from completing the program.
Two days away from...
holding my kids
in my arms again.
Is this some kind
of sick joke?
Look, Daycia's death
had absolutely nothing
to do with me.
Says here that you worked
as an EMT in college.
Is that right?
Yeah.
Taught you how to intubate
a patient, didn't they?
Yeah. Yeah. So what?
Too bad
they didn't teach you about DNA,
because you left yours
all over the tube there
when you blew in it.
We also found the pillow
that you used to
suffocate Daycia.
Look, we have
everything we need.
We know you did it.
Of all the people in that house,
you were the one
with the most to lose.
Why would you
do something...?
Because I had the most to lose,
because...
because of my children.
You know what Daycia was?
Day-Daycia was that, um...
She was that little devil.
And the little devil sits
on your shoulder,
tempts you to do bad things.
So, wait. What are you...
what are you saying?
Wh... Daycia tempted you
in some way? What?
With alcohol?
I woke up...
to go the bathroom
in the middle of the night.
It must have been
just past 4:00.
I got back to my room.
There was a bottle
sitting on my nightstand.
A bottle of bourbon,
my brand,
with a damn ribbon on it.
And-and you think that Daycia
put it there.
I know Daycia put it there.
Like I just told you,
she was that little devil.
So, I got up, and I went,
and I confronted her.
What the hell is this, Daycia?
Why did you put this
in my room?
Geez, Len, lighten
up. It's a gift.
You know how important
the program is to me,
that I stay clean
so I don't lose my kids.
You know you
want some.
Stop it.
Don't make me drink
all by myself.
Mmm.
She wouldn't stop.
She wouldn't back off.
She just kept at it.
She kept trying
to get me to drink.
Look, all I wanted to do
was shut her up.
with the pillow, I mean.
I mean,
come on, it was a pillow.
I put it over her face
just to get her
to stop talking.
Stop it! Stop it!
No, stop!
(muffled scream)
I've worked too hard. I'm not
gonna throw my life away.
(whispering):
I'm... sorry.
The bathtub in Daycia's room
was already full,
so I thought, why not...
why not just make it look
like an accident?
Make it look like
she just... slipped away.
I put her in the water.
I got the piece of tubing
from the fish tank,
and I made it look
like she drowned.
Insane part
of this whole thing is,
I made it, you know that?
I didn't drink.
Even after she was dead...
(crying):
...and it was quiet
in that room.
I took that bottle, and I poured
it in the toil... toilet.
(sniffles)
I didn't touch it.
(sighs, sniffles)
I didn't take a sip.
I needed to do that.
(sobs)
For them.
(sighs)
FINLAY:
So, we are just about
cleared out,
and I'm officially
releasing the rooms.
Good.
We got two new
patients coming in.
Wow. You don't waste
any time, do you?
We can't afford to.
A lot of people need help.
You know, I-I was really harsh
the other day
when I talked to you
about Daycia, and
I shouldn't have been.
She didn't understand
her addiction.
Didn't realize that
she was battling a disease.
Most people don't.
Patients come in here thinking
all they have to do
is put in the time.
Beating
addiction is work.
Really hard work.
And sadly, not everyone's up
for the challenge.
Well, I don't know how you do
what you do.
I was gonna say the same thing
to you.
Guess we just keep
doing it, though.
If we don't, who will?
Hmm. Good luck.