♪ ♪
This dress is sick.
You'd totally rock it.
It looks a little short.
Trust me, guys like
when you show
a little bit of skin.
I don't know,
it's not really me.
Cara, you can't wear
baggy jeans and skater
shoes your whole life.
It's $400!
Relax. I swiped
Dad's credit card.
Lexi...
Come on.
I'm giving you a makeover.
♪ ♪
(wolf whistle nearby)
People are staring at me.
You're hot.
Own it.
What's up, Lex?
Hey.
Your sister?
Yeah, that's Cara.
My buddy Pete.
Hey.
LEXI: Um, so,
Axel and I
are gonna split for a while,
so you just stay with Pete?
Can't we all
just hang out together?
Don't worry,
I'll be back in an hour.
So...
Do you want to
go somewhere?
I should probably wait here.
It's kind of crowded.
I know a place we can hang,
just the two of us.
Come on.
Let's go.
(camera shutter clicking)
PHILLIPS:
Nobody should have
to die like this.
Lot of blood drops
on the floor
over here, so I don't think
he puked himself to death.
Pretty big gash.
I-It looks like somebody
cut his throat and just
left him to bleed out
in the toilet there.
The body is
still warm.
The rigor hasn't
even started.
He's been dead
less than an hour.
Hang on a
second.
You see something?
Looks like some type
of bug carcass.
Could have
fallen off the killer.
I'll scoop it up,
get it back to the lab.
Yeah, now.
There's no wallet.
But we got...
a cell phone.
Maybe we could get an I.D.
Locked.
Use his thumb.
(beeps)
Got to love
technology.
According to the phone's I.D.,
the victim's name
is Pete Corday.
His camera app
was open.
Some of these pictures
were time-stamped
right before
he was murdered.
Maybe he got a shot
of the killer.
It's him and a girl.
PHILLIPS:
Looks like he's having
a pretty good time.
Mm. Right up
until someone ended it.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
Talked to the janitor
who found the body.
He said he got suspicious
when he saw
the "Closed for Cleaning" sign
on the restroom door.
STOKES: Killer was trying
to buy more time
till the body was found.
Got blood in the sink--
he must've cleaned up in here.
So the victim's
throat
was slashed over the toilet
to catch the blood.
Then the knife
was washed off in the sink,
put the sign on the door.
Smart.
You know, he was
with this girl right
before he was murdered.
I figure either
she was involved,
or at the very least
she's a witness.
Any idea who she is?
No. Finlay's pulling
surveillance now.
Seeing if we can
track her movements.
I mean, maybe
somebody knows her.
Well, that's
a Dempsey's bag.
Judging by the size,
I would say jewelry or makeup.
We could show her photo
to the store clerks.
If she paid
with a credit card,
we might be able
to get a name.
BRODY: Russell.
Yeah?
Got a lead on
our mystery girl.
The credit card that
she used earlier today
belongs to a guy
named John Nolan.
Nolan. Why do I know that name?
He's the director
of the crime lab
in San Diego.
Right. She used his credit card
here in Vegas?
Did he report it stolen?
Not yet, but according
to Nolan's assistant,
he's here in town
for a family wedding.
Nick's talking to him now;
says he knows him.
Nolan offered him a
job a few years ago.
Hey, John...
(clears throat softly)
sorry to drag you down here.
I thought you were investigating
the murder of a young man.
We are, and a
person of interest
has been using your credit card.
Do you recognize
that girl?
Oh, my God.
It's Cara.
Cara?
She's my 13-year-old daughter.
Do you, uh...
do you know the victim,
Pete Corday?
No, I've never seen him before.
Who is he?
23-year-old
from Phoenix.
He's got a couple
of misdemeanors
for drug possession.
Why would she be hanging out
with a guy like that?
Where is she, Nick?
Can I see her?
(sighs)
We don't know where she is.
What?
When's the last time
you saw her?
Uh... at 10:00 this morning.
She wanted to go
to the mall with Lexi.
Lexi?
Yeah, my oldest daughter.
She's 17.
They don't get to see
each other very often.
Why is that?
Well, after the divorce,
Lexi wanted to live
with her mother here in Vegas.
I was dead set against it.
Tori, my ex.
She'd rather be
a friend than a parent.
Have you talked to
either one of them
since this morning?
No, I was at a lunch
with out-of-town guests.
They didn't show up.
I texted them--
they never answered.
Okay, what about
the ex-wife?
Or family members?
No one's heard from them.
Give me their
phone numbers.
We'll ping their cells,
we'll track them down.
Of course.
And I need a current
picture of Lexi.
(wry chuckle)
It's a picture that was taken
at the rehearsal dinner
yesterday.
I'm gonna find your girls.
If anyone can, it's you.
Hey, boss.
Yeah?
What do you got for me, David?
Hadrurus Arizonensis.
Otherwise known as
the giant desert
hairy scorpion.
Nick found a piece of
the molted exoskeleton
next to Pete Corday's
body in the restroom.
You were able to trace it?
Unfortunately no.
The giant desert
hairy scorpion
is quite common in Nevada.
You know, last spring
my cousin Karen
went to go put on her
running shoes for her daily jog.
Didn't know one was hiding
in there; it stung her big toe.
Was she okay?
Oh, yeah.
But the venom
is no more harmful
than a bee sting.
Ah.
Hey, Doc.
Hey.
I just finished
Pete Corday's
autopsy.
He died from
exsanguination
due to massive
sharp-force trauma.
Can you
tell us anything about our
killer from the wound?
Depth and angle indicate
a right-handed individual
with considerable strength,
in all likelihood male.
That rules out
the Nolan sisters.
Okay. So what do we know?
Cara Nolan was
with Pete Corday
right before he was killed.
And now both she and her sister
are missing.
You think
Corday's killer
has the girls?
If they saw his face,
maybe he took them
to keep them quiet.
And if that's the case,
we need to find them, fast.
Hey.
Were you able to
pull up the footage
from outside
the bathroom?
Uh, that camera was
not working.
Figures.
Yeah.
So I retraced
the girls' steps.
We know that they bought makeup
at Dempsey's at 12:53.
'Cause that camera was working.
And look what I found.
SIDLE:
Oh, that's our victim,
Pete Corday.
Who's the other guy?
Obviously, a close personal
friend of Lexi's.
I'm putting him through
facial recognition right now.
(beeping)
SIDLE: He has a rap sheet.
Axel Vargas, age 25.
FINLAY:
Drug possession, burglary...
pandering?
He's a pimp?
No, worse.
Look at that.
Federal charge--
tried to take
an underage girl into Mexico.
That sounds like
sex trafficking.
Maybe that's what he's
got planned for Lexi and Cara.
What's that tattoo on his neck?
Let me zoom in.
A scorpion.
Nice tattoo on your neck.
You like scorpions?
They're cool.
Keep any as pets?
No. Why?
We found a piece of a
scorpion exoskeleton
on the body of
a murder victim.
Your buddy, actually.
Pete Corday.
We know you
were with him,
Lexi and Cara Nolan
at the mall this afternoon.
Now he's dead and
they're missing.
It's got nothing
to do with me.
You have a history of forcing
young girls into prostitution.
You'd get top dollar
for Lexi and Cara,
so what happened?
Did Pete decide he wanted to
keep the girls for himself?
Or maybe he decided
he wanted a cut.
I didn't kill Pete.
Where are the girls?
I'm telling you, I don't know.
I met Lexi a week ago
at a bar.
She wanted me to meet her
at the mall today, so I went.
We hooked up in a dressing room,
and I split.
Where'd you go?
Work.
I'm a bartender
at McCarthy's.
Cops picked me up
in the middle of a shift, too,
and I missed a whole day's pay.
I'm gonna need
to talk to your boss
and verify when you showed up.
Nick said Nolan's
putting on a brave face,
but, obviously,
he's upset.
Well, we've
both been there.
Father's worst
nightmare.
Our girls made it.
Hopefully, his will, too.
Listen, I want the department
to do everything in its power--
resources, personnel,
I don't care--
whatever it takes to bring those
girls back and close this case.
Absolutely.
Oh, and do
me a favor.
John's a good guy.
As a professional courtesy,
let's give him access,
keep him up to date.
Yeah, I'll make sure
everybody knows.
Thanks.
Any luck tracking down Lexi
and Cara's cell phones?
Thankfully,
they're still transmitting.
I've triangulated their location
to somewhere in North Las Vegas.
All right. Can
you get any closer?
I'm trying.
(computer trilling and beeping)
(beeping)
There they are--
off the 215 near Sahara.
Signals aren't moving.
Could be where
the girls are being held.
(sighs)
Or where their bodies
were dumped.
I'll call for backup.
(sirens blaring)
(sighs)
Big search area.
Yeah, but their phones
are still transmitting.
They should be
right around here.
I got one.
Screen's broken.
Here.
Their phones were tossed.
(sighs)
Yeah, but I don't see
any bodies.
It means the girls
could still be alive.
(phone chirps)
It opened up to a video.
Looks like it was taken
inside a vehicle.
(beep)
LEXI (crying):
Where are you taking us?
Please, just let us go.
Shut up.
My sister's only 13.
She's just a kid.
You don't need both of us.
Just please, let her go!
(tires screeching)
You stupid bitch!
(whimpering)
Ooh.
Give me the phone,
or I will slit her throat.
Lexi!
(crying):
No!
Lexi got her
captor on camera.
Couldn't see much of his face,
but no scorpion tattoo.
That wasn't Axel Vargas.
Then who was it, and what
does he want with these girls?
Nick!
Nick? Just heard
the suspect was released.
What the hell's going on?
Yeah, his alibi
checked out.
But he was with Lexi and Cara
right before they disappeared.
He has to be on the top
of the suspect list.
Yeah, I just saw the video
that Lexi shot in the
abductor's vehicle.
It's not Axel Vargas
behind the wheel.
Do-do you have any idea
who the guy was?
Actually, I was hoping you
could help us out there, John.
You've been running
that San Diego office
for a long time now.
You must have made some
enemies along the way?
Can you think
of anyone who...
who might want to
snatch up your girls
to hurt you
in some way?
God, I don't know. I...
A family member of someone
you recently put away.
Or someone who was recently
released from prison?
Something like that?
We-we just brought down
a biker gang
that killed a
city supervisor.
That's good.
Have your lab send
that file over
right away, and
we'll look into it.
In the meantime, I want
to take a look at that video.
(sighs)
If this is about me,
maybe I'll recognize the guy.
LEXI (crying):
Where are you taking us?
Please just let us go.
My sister's only 13.
She's just a kid.
You don't need both of us.
Just please, let her go!
(tires screeching)
MAN:
You stupid bitch!
Give me the phone,
or I will slit her throat.
Lexi!
LEXI:
No!
STOKES:
I'm sorry you had
to see that, John.
Do you recognize him?
No.
What if they're dead already?
I mean, he had a knife.
He's already
killed one person today, right?
You shouldn't even be
thinking like that.
Not when there's a chance
they're still alive.
We'll work it
till we find 'em.
BRODY:
It looks like
Lexi was trying
to send this clip
to somebody. She entered
this phone number, but
it didn't go through.
STOKES:
Well, it's a silent call
for help.
Whose number is that?
It's mine.
She was trying to send it to me.
You weren't in her
contact list?
I guess not.
Lexi and I haven't had much
of a relationship
since she moved here
to live with her mother.
Well, you were
the first person
she thought of to reach out to
when she was in trouble.
That's got to
mean something.
Okay, all right,
where are we?
Did you find out anything
about the motorcycle gang
that Nolan helped take down?
Yeah. Most of them
are in prison.
San Diego P.D. verified the
whereabouts of the others.
Is there anyone else who might
have had a grudge against Nolan?
Well, Nolan's lab
just cracked a series
of Mexican cartel murders
along the border,
but he hasn't received
any threats lately.
No, I think if
somebody wanted to get
back at him, why would they come
all the way here to Vegas?
Right. All right,
all right, look,
maybe this has absolutely
nothing to do with him.
The guy's got
two beautiful daughters, right?
They're young,
they're attractive,
they're in the mall.
The mall is like a hunting
ground for sexual predators.
Maybe this was a...
a crime of opportunity.
Well, I looked at all
the surveillance video
from the mall.
Cara and Lexi left
through the west doors,
but they were alone.
Okay, but that
doesn't mean that the kidnapper
wasn't already following
them, right?
I mean, he could have been
laying in wait outside,
and then forced them
into a car.
Hey.
I was looking through
Lexi's text messages,
and I found something
interesting.
Seems she has an admirer
who likes to send her
pictures of his... genitals.
I'll take your word for it.
Well, she told the guy to
stop, the images kept coming.
When she threatened to share
the pics with the cops,
the perv wrote back,
"You bitch, you're
just like your mother."
FINLAY:
He knows
Tori Nolan.
Did you run the number?
Yeah. Came back to a used car
salesman named Dennis Hayes.
Let's bring him in.
Police are trying
to track him down.
In the meantime, Sara's gonna
talk with Tori Nolan.
Please, let her go!
You stupid bitch!
MAN:
Give me the phone,
or I will slit her throat.
CARA:
Lexi!
LEXI (crying):
No!
Is that Dennis Hayes?
I'm not sure.
I-I've only met him
a couple of times.
How do you know him?
He was a friend
of my ex-boyfriend.
Oh, my God.
Do you think he did this?
Do you think he took my girls?
That's what
we're trying to figure out.
Mrs. Nolan, we found
some pretty graphic photos
and texts that
Dennis sent to Lexi.
What was the nature
of their relationship?
She barely knew him.
He came to our house
for a party once.
Lexi wasn't feeling well,
and she went up to bed.
I decided to go check on her
about a half an hour later, and
she was passed out on the bed.
And Dennis was on top of her
trying to take her clothes off.
What did you do?
Well, I pulled him
off of her, and I told him
to get the hell out of my house.
You called the police.
No, I didn't.
Why not?
Because we had
been drinking.
And taking E.
Lexi wanted to try it, and...
I let her.
(chuckles)
I didn't want the cops
to find out.
I didn't want them
to take her away from me.
You didn't report
Dennis Hayes,
and now, he may have abducted
both of your daughters.
Do you have
any idea
where he could have taken them?
I wish I did.
What the hell kind
of mother are you?
Mr. Nolan...
You brought that monster
into our daughter's life.
And now he's taken her and Cara!
I didn't know.
I should never
have let you
have custody of Lexi.
She didn't want
to live with you.
Hey, your daughters are missing,
and this is not
gonna help us find them.
Let's just focus on bringing
Lexi and Cara home.
Please.
All right.
(keyboard keys clicking)
We still haven't found Hayes.
Please, tell me
you got something.
As a matter of
fact, I do.
I've been analyzing the
video that Lexi took,
and from the dashboard,
I can tell that
the vehicle
they were abducted in was
a 1986 Chevrolet Suburban.
Does Dennis Hayes drive
one of those?
No, but I mean,
he's a used car salesman.
He has access
to all kinds of vehicles.
(phone chimes)
All right,
I'll call the
dealership and, uh,
I'll see if they have
a '86 Suburban in inventory.
(phone beeps on)
What is it?
(horn honks, siren toots)
Where is she?
In the Dumpster.
One of the construction guys
accidentally threw out
some lighting fixtures,
so foreman came back to
retrieve 'em, found the body.
(dog barking, siren toots)
She one of
the girls?
Yeah, that's Lexi,
the older sister.
Not the way we were
hoping to find her.
No, it's not.
Ecchymosis.
Means she suffered
blunt force trauma to the head.
Fresh cuts on the bottoms
of her feet.
Looks like she
tried to run away.
Any sign of Cara?
She's not in here.
Then there's a chance
she might still be alive.
♪ ♪
Hey, I thought Nick
was working this one.
He's at the morgue.
He wanted to be the one
to process Lexi's body.
I found a necklace.
There's not much blood
in the dumpster.
She was killed somewhere
else and dumped here.
They said they searched
the house under renovation.
No sign of Cara.
No evidence the girls
were ever held there.
What about the other houses
in the neighborhood?
Unis are still
canvassing.
One neighbor did report hearing
a metallic squeaking sound
around 10:30.
Hinges on the doors of
the dumpster, maybe?
By the time she looked out
the window, all she could see
were taillights speeding away.
Some type of SUV.
But if the killer
opened these doors,
he would've had to have
touched the latch.
I'll dust for prints.
I don't think
you should be in here.
I had to see her.
I'm really sorry.
JOHN:
Her fingernails
are broken.
She put up a fight.
That's Lexi.
Strong.
Fearless.
Yeah, just
like her old man.
That's probably why
we butted heads so much.
You know, when she was 12,
she wanted to camp out
all night for
concert tickets
and I wouldn't let her.
She snuck out of the house
and I found her at 2:00
in the morning at the venue
with her friends.
I dragged her home.
She didn't talk to me
for a week.
This is my fault.
No. No, it isn't.
I should've
fought harder to keep her
after the divorce.
But she was so unhappy.
She was acting out,
skipping school.
I didn't...
I didn't know what else to do.
Don't put yourself
through this, man.
What happened to Lexi
is not your fault.
It's not your fault.
You're right.
I shouldn't be here.
♪ ♪
(door opens)
Hey, Nick. Just
finishing up here.
Damn shame.
Nick, sometimes,
despite our best efforts,
we don't get
the result we want.
Yeah.
You have any news on her sister?
No.
We're still trying
to track down Dennis Hayes.
What's her
cause of death?
She had a significant
longitudinal fracture
on the back of the head.
Crushing blows causing massive
cerebral hemorrhaging.
And does the injury indicate
what type of weapon was used?
Her head was smashed into
a very hard, flat surface.
Okay. I found traces of stone
in the wound.
And the fingernail scratches
around the ligature
marks indicates
that she tried to get away.
Any evidence of sexual assault?
No physical
findings. She had
consensual sex
earlier in the day.
DNA can sort out
any multiple donors.
And what is that bite
on her shoulder?
Is that a sting,
some type of insect?
Based on the redness
and the inflammation,
I think you're right.
Hey, do you think it could
be a scorpion sting?
I don't know. Why?
I found a piece
of exoskeleton on
the dead body in the restroom.
Same guy Cara Nolan was with.
Will you extract some tissue
from around the sting
and have it analyzed
right away?
You got it.
SIDLE:
How's Nolan?
He's holding it together
as best he can.
This is a guy who sees
dead bodies in autopsy
every day, but when it's
your own kid laying there...
Oof. I can't even imagine.
John's a good guy.
He doesn't deserve this.
Didn't he send you
an autographed Chargers
jersey a few years ago?
Yeah, Dan Fouts.
One of the best
passing quarterbacks
in the NFL.
It was his attempt to
lure me to that
San Diego office.
You ever regret that?
Not taking the job out there?
No.
I mean, it wasn't a promotion
or anything like that.
Yeah, but the money
had to be better than here.
Uh, not really.
I mean, San Diego's
an expensive town to live in.
Besides, this is my home.
I got all my friends here.
This is where my family is.
And look, the Chargers
got a good football team,
but they're no Dallas Cowboys.
Those are my boys.
Go Cowboys.
Hey, Russell.
Mm.
Doc confirmed that the
sting on Lexi Nolan's
shoulder was from a scorpion.
Same type
as the exoskeleton
that Nick found?
No.
This wasn't
a giant hairy scorpion.
The histopath report
identified chlorotoxin
and maurotoxin,
consistent with a
deathstalker scorpion.
They common to Nevada?
Indigenous to Israel.
Well then how is she
stung by one of these?
It had to be intentional.
Some people keep them as
pets, which is crazy--
deathstalkers are
highly aggressive.
When they sting their victims,
the venom rushes
into the bloodstream,
causing increased heartbeat,
blood pressure, and,
if enough venom is released,
convulsions and death.
Well, now, Doc said
that Lexi Nolan died
from blunt force trauma, right?
Yes, but I think
the scorpion sting may have
contributed to her death.
See, Lexi had cuts
on the bottom of her feet.
If she tried to run,
with that venom in her system,
she wouldn't have
gotten very far.
Allowing her killer
to catch up.
So do we know if Dennis Hayes
has a thing for scorpions?
He's not our guy.
Police tracked him down
to a motel in Nebraska.
He's been there three days.
So we know that
whoever killed Lexi Nolan
had access to
a deathstalker scorpion.
And if they're
not native to Nevada,
then where'd the guy get one?
Hey, turns out there are
seven places in Nevada
that sell
deathstalker scorpions.
Seven places too many,
if you ask me.
I guess some people
get a kick out of
owning something
that can kill you.
Deathstalkers only live
two to six years,
so I got a list of everyone
who purchased one
from 2008
to now.
BRODY:
We cross-reference this
with everyone who drives
a 1986 Chevrolet Suburban,
and we might get our guy.
Great minds think alike.
Here--
Kieran Clark.
528 Cactus Ridge Lane.
LVPD.
OFFICER:
Kieran Clark, LVPD.
Clear inside.
All clear.
Nobody's here.
That means no Cara.
This is Clark's address,
but it doesn't look like
he lives here.
Terrariums.
A lot of them.
Oh! Oh, God.
Guess he's not just
into scorpions.
Hey, Morgan.
Check this out.
Stalker photos.
Cara Nolan was only in town
for the past few days.
What, has he been
stalking her the whole time?
Wait a minute.
That's somebody else.
That's not Cara Nolan.
Who is it, then?
Another victim?
I don't know.
But whoever she is...
she's a dead ringer for Cara.
I already heard.
You didn't find Cara.
No. Not yet.
But we know who took her
and we know why.
A guy named
Kieran Clark.
There was a-a shrine
in that barn.
It seems as though
the suspect
has an obsession
with a young woman.
We haven't identified her yet,
but she looks
just like Cara.
He took my two girls
because Cara
reminded him of someone?
That's what it
looks like, yeah.
But... only a
matter of time...
Before we get Cara back.
Is that what you're gonna
try and sell me?
John, I'm not trying
to sell you on-on anything here,
but I'm sure as hell
not ready to quit.
We're gonna find her.
No doubt we will.
Just like we found...
Lexi.
I'm sorry about Lexi.
But hey, you can't just fold
and throw in now. Come on.
I'm no tourist, Nick.
I've run a crime lab
for 17 years.
Cara's been missing
for 24 hours,
and that lunatic
already killed Lexi.
You and I both know how
this thing's probably gonna end.
I'm not about to quit.
And you're not, either.
(sighs)
You hear me?
Hey, look at me.
I will find her.
Okay, what do we know
about Kieran Clark?
He's known
as the Bug Guy.
He goes around to schools
and kids' birthday parties,
educating them
about insects and reptiles.
It's terrifying
that he works around children.
And the young woman
in these photos,
the one he's
obviously obsessed with?
SIDLE:
According to the police report,
her name is Jennifer DeMarcus.
She used to work
at a pet shop in Henderson.
That's where they met.
She had one date with Clark
before she realized
he was a head case,
and then she told him
that she wasn't interested.
Let me guess-- he wouldn't
take no for an answer.
SIDLE: He kept coming
around the pet shop,
and then he started
parking his car
in front of Jennifer's
apartment at night.
She called the police
on him several times.
Did she get a
restraining order?
Left town.
Moved back to Georgia.
Put as much distance between her
and Clark as she could.
Clearly, he's still
obsessed with her.
So, what do you think?
Kieran goes to the mall,
sees Cara looking
very much like Jennifer,
and he decides to grab her.
Except Cara
was with Pete Corday,
so Clark had to get rid
of him first.
And by the time he was done
with Pete, Cara was with Lexi,
so he had to
take them both.
Right.
The stone particles
that Nick found in Lexi Nolan's
head wound were coated.
I identified a mixture
of ethanol, alkylalkoxysilane
and isopropyl acetate.
Oxysilane?
That sounds like
a sealant of some kind.
Actually, it's an
impregnating sealant,
used to protect concrete
from water and staining--
uh, primarily
walkways, driveways.
There was no evidence of
sealant in the Dumpster
where Lexi's body was
found, which means
it had to come from where
she was actually murdered.
Lexi tried to escape.
She was still feeling distress
from the scorpion sting.
Maybe she was near a driveway
when Kieran Clark
caught up to her
and smashed her head into it.
The sealant in
Lexi's wound
wasn't entirely cured,
meaning that it was
probably applied
within the last couple of days.
Okay. All right.
Let's do a search within
a five-mile radius
of where Lexi's body
was found.
We're looking for
somebody who recently
had their concrete
driveway sealed.
STOKES:
Hey.
I heard you
got something.
Yeah. Lexi's body
was found right here.
Two miles away,
on Harvard Drive,
this house had their driveway
sealed on Wednesday.
Now, we know that when Lexi ran
she didn't get very far,
so Clark's got to be
holding Cara
somewhere nearby.
I should get out there.
Wait for backup.
I will.
♪ ♪
LVPD!
KIERAN:
Get over here.
Kieran Clark!
CARA:
No! Let me go!
Drop the knife.
Don't come
any closer.
Put the knife down.
I'll slit her throat.
Hey, me and you,
we can work this out.
But you don't need to hurt her.
What I need is
for you to leave.
Now, we both know that's not
going to happen.
Go!
I will kill her.
I know about the girl
from the pet store.
Jennifer-- I mean, isn't that
the girl you liked?
I love her.
Okay.
All right.
But she's not her.
Her name is Cara Nolan.
She's 13 years old.
She's never done anything
to hurt you.
I know...
when you saw her at the mall,
you thought...
"That's Jennifer."
(gasping)
But take a closer look.
It's not her.
She's a child,
and she...
she needs to go home.
You're wrong.
She's mine.
Let her go.
I can't let you take her.
It's okay.
It's all right. I'm a
friend of your dad's.
CARA:
Thank you.
It's gonna be all right.
(knock at door)
How's she doing?
Physically, she's okay.
She's been through
a hell of an ordeal, but...
...she's alive because of you.
You never gave up.
Thank you for
bringing her back to me.
You're welcome.
You know, Nick...
I've been thinking
about the choices I've made.
Working weekends and evenings.
Missing school plays,
soccer games.
Sometimes going days
without seeing my girls.
For years, I've been putting
other people's families
ahead of my own.
I don't want to do that anymore.
So, what are you saying?
You're gonna hang it up?
Well, Cara needs me.
Now more than ever.
It would be a big loss
for your crime lab.
Not with you there.
John, we've talked about this.
I've already got a job.
I'm not asking you
to just join the team.
I'm asking you to run it.
You want me to take over
the crime lab in San Diego?
I know it would be
in good hands
with you at the helm.
(sighs)
(stammering):
That's a big job.
You don't have to answer me
right now.
Just promise me...
you'll think about it.
Thank you, Nick.