Welcome to Jefferson High,
home of the Pelicans.
Pelican pride.
Pelicans are, by the way,
a shore bird--
Pelecanus occidentalis.
A water bird mascot
in the desert?
Ooh, here comes
Principal Meadows.
(laughs) Hi. Did you have
a good weekend, Mason?
Mm-hmm.
Um, what about
that football game?
Ah, Turk was fantastic.
Oh, go... Pelicans!
Wait!
Turk can't name
the vice president.
No joke.
And he's one failed test away
from flunking out.
Ooh, but don't take
my word for it.
Hey, Turk.
70 yards passing, not bad!
Oh, Chugga-Brew.
I want to talk to you.
Uh, I'm busy, Turk.
Come on, man. This vertex of the
para-boola is driving me nuts.
You're the only one who can
explain it to me.
Maybe next time.
I almost feel sorry for him.
GIRL:
What up, boy?
Aw, is Mason making a little
selfie video for his mommy?
Hi, Mason.
Come on, Hannah,
give it back.
Wow, this thing is, like,
five generations old.
Pretty lame for a tech geek.
What do you want?
World peace, Mason. World peace.
Great talk.
You know, I still can't believe
you don't have a girlfriend.
Right here, Mason...
Hannah's my next-door neighbor.
We used to play kick the can
and hang out,
but then she got her braces off.
Hey, sweetie.
Remember to take the car in
after school-- oil change.
I know.
You told me a billion times.
(sighs)
That's my mom.
She teaches earth science here.
Ah, famous Pelican cheerleaders.
Good news, bad news.
Bad news-- it's eighth period.
Good news-- it's eighth period.
(booming)
(screaming)
Holy crap, he's...
My God, someone call 911!
Grab a blanket, get some water!
Call 911!
I got you, Chet,
I got you.
Call an ambulance! Now!
Ed...
is he...?
PRINCIPAL:
Everybody, report
to your homerooms.
ED:
Everybody, go back
to class, come on.
(indistinct chatter)
SANDERS:
Hey, Dave.
Hey.
Any I.D. on our burning man?
Chet Messner.
Taught chemistry.
Sadly appropriate,
given his extreme thermal
and chemical burns.
Fourth degree charring.
No one's gonna
survive that.
Nope.
Any luck
retracing his steps?
Yeah.
Uh, looks like the vic was
in the classroom
when something went wrong.
That's an understatement.
Clearly there was
an explosion.
It appears he was doing some
prep work for an experiment.
So, we're looking
at an accident.
Maybe not, actually.
Look, I, um, I found
his cell phone.
He received an anonymous
text this morning.
"Epic fail, Messner.
"Do the right thing,
or suffer the consequences."
So much for an accident.
Well, looks like Messner
did the wrong thing.
And got burned.
♪&amp; Who... are you? ♪&amp;
♪&amp; Who, who, who, who? ♪&amp;
♪&amp; I really wanna know ♪&amp;
♪&amp; Who... are you? ♪&amp;
♪&amp; Oh-oh-oh ♪&amp;
♪&amp; Who... ♪&amp;
♪&amp; Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪&amp;
♪&amp; Are you! ♪&amp;
PRINCIPAL:
I still can't believe it.
I mean, my goodness, Chet's
always been so careful.
Makes an explosion in his lab
all the more puzzling.
So, I understand
it was eighth period.
Wasn't he teaching
a class?
Uh, no. He normally
grades papers then,
or makes his
lesson plans.
Did you know
Mr. Messner well?
Oh, yeah.
About five years now.
He'd always throw great
barbecues on the Fourth.
The whole
faculty would go.
And what about
his students?
Did he get along
with them?
You don't think someone
deliberately hurt Chet?
We don't
know yet.
But I am going to need a list
of all of his students' names.
The students
loved Chet.
He put in a lot
of time here.
In fact, right now he
would be setting up
for tomorrow's Pelican
rally if... he hadn't...
Well, I'm sorry
for your loss, Ms. Meadows.
Thanks for your time.
Yeah.
How was your meeting
with the principal?
According to her, everyone just
loved good old Mr. Messner.
Until someone didn't.
We need our, uh,
bunny suits?
I did a sweep.
Air samples are clear
of hazardous chemicals.
So you get to
be bunny-free.
Well, I guess that means
we're late for class.
Aren't you gonna
carry my kit?
No.
First responders said the
sprinklers put out the fire.
The gas was still on,
so they shut it off.
And it didn't look
like the gas line
had been tampered
with at all.
But take a
look at this.
Bunsen burner...
says that Mr. Messner
was working
on one of his
lesson plans.
The burn marks that are
radiating outwards
say that this may be
the point of origin.
Question is--
what set it off?
Fire needs
an accelerant.
So, what are
you thinking?
The scorching marks...
are going this way.
I think I might have found
our accelerant.
Whatever was in here
must have shot across the table
like a rocket.
Yep, singed
and blackened.
How am I doing so far?
Ms. Brody?
Hey, you're not
paying attention.
It's 'cause I'm forming
my own theory, professor.
It's here-- gummy bears.
On his crazy-tidy shelf.
You know the saying that,
uh, sugar gives you energy?
Yeah.
I think that Messner was
gonna try to prove that.
It's on his
whiteboard there.
Tomorrow's
lesson plan.
That's what he
was prepping.
Molten potassium chlorate
combined with glucose.
Potassium chlorate-- that's an
accelerant, used in fireworks.
Makes for quite a show.
BRODY: In fact, it's
such a powerful oxidizer,
that when you add
the gummy bear or the sugar,
it reacts violently.
Makes a loud noise,
causes lots of flames.
It's kind of
like a Roman candle.
Well, like
a Roman candle,
there should be
no explosion.
It was supposed to be a
controlled experiment.
Until you add the X
factor to the equation.
The killer.
(screams)
"Epic fail, Messner.
Do the right thing,
or suffer the consequences."
We traced this text
to your phone, Mason.
I-I'm sorry.
I was just...
venting.
I didn't really
mean it, I swear.
You sent a threatening
text, Mason.
In this day and age, these
things are taken very seriously.
Look, Mom, it was stupid.
I know.
Mr. Russell, this is
really unlike him.
I'm not just
speaking as a mom,
I'm speaking as
a faculty member.
Mason's on the honor roll.
He is a good kid.
You good at chemistry,
too, Mason?
I sent a text, all right?
But I did not inferno
Mr. Messner.
I-I was mad.
He gave me a B+
for the semester.
I missed a few days
here and there.
I was sick.
And he wouldn't give me a break.
Why didn't you talk to him?
I did.
Like a lot of people
around here,
he held me
to a higher standard.
Chet could be
very stubborn.
And that does not
justify what you did.
The consequences you said that
Mr. Messner would suffer,
what'd you mean by that?
I heard those lines
from a movie,
it was... it was
just a bluff.
I just wanted my "A."
Because people expect
big things from me.
(choking up): And I didn't want
to let you down.
And I know... I know how much
all this means to you.
And...
Mason.
You could never
let me down.
Mr. Russell, does my
son need a lawyer?
No, not at the moment.
Doc, can you explain this
text I got from Hodges?
Okay, "Nobody knows
what the nose knows
until the nose
knows it. See Doc."
Our friend, Hodges, has the gene
that allows him to smell the
bitter almond odor of cyanide.
It's a gift.
Mmm, he has
so many gifts.
Oh, yeah.
Note this pink lividity.
Indicative of cyanide poisoning.
Mr. Messner would have been
a goner, fire or no fire.
So, Messner was poisoned
before the explosion.
Killer did not push him
into the flames,
but he did dose
him with cyanide.
In sufficient quantity
to cause him to seize
at a most inopportune time.
(screams)
Well, that changes everything.
Killer didn't have to be
in the classroom.
Do you know how he was dosed?
Normally cyanide presents
in the stomach lining
and nasal passages.
But I found
no signs of this.
So he didn't eat it,
and he didn't snort it.
What else do you know about him?
Uh, he was single,
been in Vegas for
about five years,
no record. Why?
Well, he was wearing this.
It's called a life rune.
It's a gang symbol.
Two weeks ago,
I saw the same symbol.
It was tattooed
on a dead biker's ass.
Blended nicely
with his swastikas.
So, our lovable teacher,
Chet Messner,
may have had a dark secret.
This a bad time,
Russ?
I got something
for you.
Come on in.
I ran Messner's
credit cards.
Now, one thing
really popped out.
He's been ordering
monthly shipments
of red phosphorus powder.
Man's a chemistry
teacher, though, right?
He got it from some
shady supplier online.
And he got it
delivered to his house.
Some little place
out on Sloan Canyon.
What are you thinking?
We both know what red phosphorus
powder is used for.
Chemistry teacher dealing meth.
Good show.
I'm just saying,
Messner may have some enemies
we haven't considered.
Maybe he stepped
on the wrong dealer's turf.
Yeah, and then that dealer goes
back to that school,
and gives Messner
a big old fat "F" in meth class.
Go get 'em.
(siren wailing)
Main house is clear.
Really?
All right, we'll
check the shed.
STOKES:
There's a knife.
With what looks
like blood on it right there.
This doesn't look
like a meth lab to me.
Man, these are some
creepy-ass tapestries.
CRAWFORD: I think it might
be more than just that.
I've seen
this stuff before.
Double in
the Alphabets.
This, uh,
this whack-job...
he killed a couple
as a sacrifice.
To the moon god.
So, what is this,
devil worship?
No, not exactly.
Stokes.
Book of Shadows.
What's that?
It's like a book of spells.
This is a ceremonial altar
and a cauldron.
The only thing that's missing
is a broom.
Our chemistry teacher's a witch.
Air, fire, water, earth,
elements of astral birth,
I call on thee,
and offer these gifts.
RUSSELL:
"I call you now...
"Attend to me.
"This is my will.
So mote it be."
What happens next?
No, wait.
Don't tell me.
Let me guess.
Lightning strikes,
right?
No, coven meeting starts.
Sounds like you've been to one.
Actually, my parents befriended
a Wiccan couple
back in the '60s.
So I know a little
bit about it.
It's a pagan
religion.
They use spells to harness
the earth's energy
to grant positive wishes.
That's the sign of the devil
right there.
The five-pointed star?
No, that's a sign of balance
and strength, actually.
It's a protective symbol.
I always thought it was
a sign of the devil.
Well, you're wrong.
Yeah.
This is our red phosphorus
right here.
I think Messner was making
magic, not meth, in here.
Yes, the
question is--
did magic lead to murder?
Well, they were in here
mixing up potions.
Maybe one of them...
made a cyanide spell.
There's a singed
hair in here.
Looks human.
A burnt human hair
in a cauldron?
How does that work
in the hocus-pocus business?
Well, that's a little
disturbing, actually.
Why don't we turn
this place upside down,
see if they left more
than a human hair behind.
And he's wearing a robe.
Helps me get into it.
Come on, this is Vegas.
Anything goes.
Where can't you find
a relic Druid robe?
Well, did the robe help?
It did.
I think I know what
our witches were cooking
in the Wiccan
kitchen.
And if you'll step
into my Wiccan kitchen,
I'll be happy to explain.
Using a two-quart
cast-iron cauldron...
you add human blood,
a teaspoon of red phosphorus,
then garnish with human hair.
You heat it all up
until there is a gloomy smoke,
and then you have...
A group of sad lost people
inhaling toxic fumes?
No.
A banishment spell.
ALL (chanting):
Charge this by your powers.
Break this circle.
Banish the leper.
Let us be reborn.
Since when are you
a Wicca expert?
Dated one in college.
Uh, she was intense.
Perhaps too natural?
Truth be told,
uh, she didn't have
a bathing spell
in her Book of Shadows.
Okay, okay, let's just get
back to this... spell.
Are you saying that Messner
was being banished?
Thou art correct.
I found one drop
of unburned blood
on the lip
of the cauldron.
Now, per the spell, it means
that Messner was the target.
Suggests motive.
Maybe Messner wasn't willing
to go quietly
into that witchy night.
So, another witch concocts
a deadly brew to silence him.
Toil and trouble,
let the cyanide bubble.
Any luck with the hair
in the cauldron?
Henry found DNA
on the follicle.
Unknown female,
no hits in CODIS.
But the prints on the candle...
shed more light.
In fact, I.D.'s
four of our witches.
Turns out that Wiccans come
from all walks of life.
Our first witch is
a postal worker,
currently on vacation
in Florida.
Okay, postal
worker's out.
Witch number two is a
pharmaceutical saleswoman
with a DUI
on her record.
She's on the
road this week.
Alibis her.
But school was in session
for two of our other witches.
Requiring that their
fingerprints, too,
were in the system.
Witch number three is
our own Ms. Brewer.
Earth science teacher,
spell caster.
Ms. Brewer?
Didn't see that coming.
How about the man who
tried to save Chet Messner?
I call on thee...
SANDERS:
The janitor's a witch?
Why didn't you tell us that
you and Chet Messner were part
of a secret society?
There you go.
It's a secret.
Yeah, but secret-time
kind of goes away
when it's
a homicide.
Our religion had nothing to do
with what happened to Chet.
Maybe it did.
Could be a nervous witch, you
know, makes a cyanide potion
to stop a fellow witch
from outing your gang.
Isn't that what you guys
are really about?
Curses and revenge?
You have a wrong idea about us.
Okay. Well, give me
the right one.
Wicca saved me, Detective.
Saved you?
I came to Vegas to hustle cards.
It ate me up.
Left me a broke alcoholic.
I found serenity
in the power of nature.
Fact is, peace
is at the core of our belief.
That's what
we're about.
If someone
hurt Chet,
it came from the outside.
The whole thing
was a shock to me.
It was my second
gathering.
Oh, so you're new to the craft.
Yes, Chet asked me to join.
And then he's banished.
I didn't think that it was fair,
but I was new.
And who was I
to question the coven?
They all wanted him gone.
Chet had been
speaking publically
about coven
activities.
Shoot his mouth off
to complete strangers.
He thought it was a way
of getting out the message.
How'd that
make you feel?
Not good.
But not bad enough to kill.
Talking out of school is
why Chet was banished;
it's not why he was murdered.
A Wiccan doesn't kill.
We have one unidentified
female member of the coven,
but I need some names.
I'm not allowed
to divulge names.
I'm sorry.
Oh.
Well, I'm sorry, too.
Because talking to members
of the coven,
people who knew
Chet well--
that's our best shot at figuring
out who hurt your friend.
I have been lost...
since my husband passed.
And this might
sound corny,
but there is a holiness
to the cosmos.
A harmony.
It helps me get
through the bad days.
I owe it to them to
protect their privacy.
I can't break a sacred oath.
RUSSELL:
What did you think?
You're asking me--
do I think they're protecting
themselves or someone else?
Yeah.
(sighs)
I'm not sure.
Well, they could be
telling the truth, right?
I mean, I like to think
that society's a little
more tolerant nowadays.
Do we really think that a member
of a coven would be willing
to kill another member
for fear of being exposed?
I don't know, a banishment spell
for loose lips?
I mean,
that tells me
the first rule of witch club is,
"Don't talk about witch club."
Greg.
"Hop off
the broom,
join me back on Planet Earth."
He's very funny today.
Hilarious.
Hey, what do you got?
Well, I think Messner was making
more than just Roman candles
in his classroom.
He was also making
a synthetic brew.
I took a Dumpster dive behind
the school-- you're welcome--
and I, uh, found this vial.
Now, it's got to be
from Messner's lab
because his prints
are all over it.
Also found traces
of androstenedione
and clostebol in it.
So he was making drugs.
Just not meth.
Nope, steroids.
I also found
this dosing schedule.
His own "book of steroids."
He was supplying PEDs to a lot
of Jefferson student-athletes.
He even used code names.
Note the, uh, most
popular client.
"QB"?
Not very subtle.
No, apparently code names
weren't his strong suit.
"Quarterback" is
Rob Turkla.
Now this is
Mason Brewer's selfie video
of Messner's
last seconds.
Now, check out
the QB's locker.
What is that, a traveling
medical kit?
Complete with syringes
for your exotic destinations.
Yeah, I'm thinking
that Turk doesn't travel much
beyond the football field.
I, uh, pulled
Messner's phone records.
Was he talking with Turk?
Every Friday.
So, we have a teacher
and a student involved
in a highly
illicit scheme.
Could have been bad for either
one of them if it had come out.
But Messner had
other student clients,
so why Turk?
Well, first off,
Messner was broke.
He had big credit card problems,
five cards he couldn't pay.
Teacher's salary-- selling
drugs solves the problem, right.
Well, two days ago,
Messner sent
Turk an e-mail,
threatening
to expose him.
"No cash,
no college career for you
"if this comes out.
Be smart for once."
I think QB was
stiffing Messner,
and Messner wasn't having it.
So he called an audible.
Okay.
Nice work.
I'll have Crawford
pick Turk up.
(indistinct radio chatter)
Got your text.
I got your suspect.
I don't think
he's gonna be talking much.
Hey, Dave...
how's his head look?
Well, I'm seeing blunt force
trauma to the back of the skull.
I'd say about
15 pounds' worth.
PHILLIPS:
Yeah.
That would do it.
Well, the weight room's
just over there.
I'm thinking
that the killer
grabbed the murder weapon
from there, followed Turk
from the weight room,
then clocked him
here by the pool.
PHILLIPS:
I think he was alive
when he went in the pool.
There's a thin band
of foam at his mouth.
Suggests drowning.
One-two punch.
Blunt force trauma
knocked him down...
...pool finished him off.
Cleaning crew found the body
shortly after 6:00 a.m.
Are there any security
cameras around here?
No.
Swim team, they have the pool,
uh, up until 7:00,
so nobody
saw anything.
We have a suspect
turned vic.
So what do you think?
Two murders, two days,
one high school...
Maybe the QB knew something
about the Messner murder.
And drowned men
tell no tales.
BRODY:
This is one
sheet of 92
that were exposed to the fire
in Mr. Messner's classroom.
I processed
every single one.
Okay. Why is this
one special?
It's the murder weapon.
This is getting fun.
The one thing
we still haven't
been able to deduce
is how the cyanide got
into Mr. Messner's body.
But I have
an idea.
Contact...
with the paper.
This paper is coated
with a combination
of cyanide
and dimethyl sulfoxide.
DMSO.
A solvent.
One that can carry
substances into the skin.
In this case,
cyanide.
A massive
dose.
Kind of like a chemical
hypodermic needle.
I don't think Messner
was the intended target.
This isn't just
any piece of paper.
This is the answer key
to Mr. Messner's Chem IV final,
which was left in a drawer
for his worst student,
Rob Turkla.
Wait a minute.
How do you
know that part?
I found a very suspicious
VidTree image
buried in Turk's
deleted phone data.
RUSSELL:
"Touchdown. Your A+
is in Messner's top drawer."
Sent the day
he died.
Do we know
by whom?
VidTree
snapshots
disappear after
a couple seconds.
Kids use them, 'cause they think
that they can send something
without their parents
ever finding out.
But in
reality,
all the data is still
saved up in the cloud,
where we can
eventually find it.
I'm... doing a search
on the sender as we speak.
RUSSELL:
So, if you're right,
then this answer
key was left
in Messner's classroom
for Turk to find.
BRODY:
And Messner found it first.
Messner was a neat freak.
If anything was out of place,
he would've noticed.
With DMSO
acting as a skin absorbent
for the cyanide...
anybody who touched
that answer key was doomed.
Always better
to study, kids.
BRODY:
Oop.
Got a hit on the sender.
Oh, my gosh.
BRODY:
Nice résumé, Hannah.
National Honor Roll.
President of
the French Club.
Literacy Volunteer
of the Year.
Captain of
the swim team.
Is that right?
That's right.
Your specialty is
the butterfly?
Yeah, how'd you know?
This here is, um...
Mr. Messner's steroid
dosing schedule.
See the code there?
"B-fly"?
Look, I swear, I only
took the drugs once.
You'd do anything
to win, right?
On the field,
in the classroom...
I looked at your e-mail.
Looked like you
and Turk and
a few other kids
were planning on
stealing Mr. Messner's
Chem IV final.
That-that
was all talk.
Not for Turk.
And not for you.
In fact, you...
used it as
a murder weapon.
What are you saying?
The message you sent
to lure Turk to
Mr. Messner's classroom,
where you left an answer
sheet laced with cyanide.
Bad luck for you,
Messner touched it first.
So you scheduled
a make-up with Turk.
At the pool.
I didn't kill Turk.
And I didn't kill Mr. Messner.
Look, I didn't...
I didn't send this.
It's from your account.
Someone must've
hacked me.
I mean, it's-it's not like
it hasn't happened before.
Why would somebody
do that to you?
Hannah, you have
to talk to me.
You want to
know why...
someone would
hack my account,
and kill Turk
at the pool?
Because...
I am your best suspect.
I wanted him dead.
Why?
Because of
what he...
(clears throat)
Because of what
he did to me.
He...
...a-attacked me.
Why didn't
you report it?
To who?
The cops?
What, because they're
gonna believe my word
over Mr. Friday
Night Football?
Turk was the best
class I ever took.
Taught me what the
world's really like.
You wouldn't understand.
Just so
you know,
I leave early on Thursday
nights from practice.
Coach thinks
I'm at tutoring.
But really I'm at
a women's shelter...
...for counseling.
(sniffs)
I'll look into that.
Go ahead.
They'll tell you
I was there.
ROBBINS:
QB's lungs are overinflated,
heavy with fluid.
Confirms drowning
was C.O.D.
Jaundice and liver
damage are consistent
with chronic anabolic
steroid use.
All to score
a bunch of touchdowns.
Well, as
expected,
I found
syringe marks
on this QB's
posterior.
Usual target
for injecting PEDs.
Right. But I can't
explain this target.
Another injection site.
Why is that different?
Well, it's not his
usual injection site.
Needle hit
the median cubital vein.
Take a look here.
What's even
more unusual
is this two-inch section of vein
leading away
from the puncture site.
It's devoid of blood.
The killer withdrew blood
from Turk after he died.
There was no blood pumping,
otherwise the vein
would have refilled.
That's crazy.
The median cubital
vein tells no lies.
Can it tell us why somebody
took the blood of a dead man?
Afraid not.
Hey.
So I, uh, I made
some calls, and...
your story
checks out.
About the
counseling.
I'm so sorry
for what Turk
did to you.
You have every
right to be angry.
I'm not angry.
Anymore.
My eyes are just open now.
For what it's worth...
there are far more
good people out there
than there are...
Rob Turklas.
Don't close your
eyes to that.
STOKES:
Did you hear about Turk's body?
RUSSELL:
Yeah.
I know these folks are
your people, okay...
(laughs)
...but this
hocus-pocus stuff
isn't sitting
well with me.
Well, what are
you thinking?
Well, it's not what I'm
thinking, it's what I know.
I processed Turk's car
in the garage.
Found a used condom
in the backseat.
The DNA from
the vaginal fluid
was a match to the
hair in the cauldron
in Messner's shed.
Well, that-that's...
that's great.
That's our unknown female.
I think so.
So our quarterback was boffing
somebody in the coven.
Our mystery witch didn't
just leave behind her DNA.
She, uh, also left her prints
all over Turk's window.
Well, that begs the question...
which witch?
This is just dandy.
You actually think
I hurt Turk?
Nonsense.
Really?
Yeah.
You were sleeping
with a student
who's now dead.
Murdered
in your school.
I was not
sleeping with Turk.
My gosh.
We have your
fingerprints
on the inside of
his car windows
and your DNA on his condom
from the backseat.
Do-do I need to go on?
Turk was 18.
He was perfectly legal.
What we had was real.
Did your husband
find it real?
Your marriage,
your job...
you had a lot
to lose.
Mr. Russell...
every day, I play
pretend. Mm-hmm.
I pretend
that Pelican
sports matter.
I pretend not to
resent the fact
that I'm a failed
interior decorator.
Mm-hmm.
But mostly,
I pretend to not know
that my husband's having
a weekly tryst
with a stripper
named Tangerine.
Mm-hmm.
Now, I did not
kill Turk.
But I can tell
you this...
I would kill to bring him back.
Did you know
that-that Turk's blood
was removed from his body
after he was murdered?
And that suggests
a Wiccan ritual
or a spell,
and that suggests you.
Golly.
When you people secret-shovel,
you sure dig deep.
The coven said that
we'd be persecuted.
No, slow-slow down.
I don't care who
or what you worship,
I just care about the truth.
I didn't kill Turk.
You said that the killer
took Turk's blood.
Yes, that's right.
Our high priest thought
that my relationship with Turk
was-was a threat to the coven.
Your-your high priest?
Ed.
Ed, Ed Lusk?
The janitor?
He doesn't have power
in this life.
He's determined to find power
within the coven.
Turk was a threat to that power.
By having sex with you,
he could create a-a scandal.
Ed said I was a bit...
reckless.
He would do anything
to protect the coven,
but I'm afraid
if he took Turk's blood,
that this goes
way beyond that.
How so?
There's an ancient power spell
called "the Kratos."
It uses the blood
of a sacrificed youth.
It goes back to the Druids.
To perform
this-this "Kratos" spell,
Ed would have to take
Turk's blood to an altar,
if-if I'm right.
Yes.
The timing is very important.
The quicker the offering,
the more powerful the spell.
The two attempts on Turk's life
came at the school,
so maybe Ed had a-an altar
at the school?
Mm-hmm.
Do you know where it is?
Ed Lusk hasn't been
seen since lunch.
(school bell rings)
Well,
his ride's here,
so he's probably
around here somewhere.
(chuckles)
SANDERS:
All we have is an altar
to the cleaning gods.
Not a Wiccan candle in sight.
(grunts)
Looks like our janitor
missed something.
Directional blood drop.
Maybe a drip
from the needle he used
to draw Turk's blood.
I got another one here.
And here.
(sighs)
You don't belong here!
LVPD.
Put down the knife.
We need you to come with us, Ed.
Put the knife down
and no one gets hurt.
We just want
to talk to you.
May the blackest of darkness
smite you down into the ground.
Try me.
(knife clatters)
So, Ed Lusk has lawyered up.
High priest is not talking, huh?
The blood drops
in his closet are.
DNA matches Turk.
Hope he's got a good lawyer.
Yeah, really.
(rattling)
Ah,
my brethren.
I was about to use the
foul modern text device
to summon you.
What are you doing?
I beseech you to enter
my sacred domain.
I welcome you on the day
of the Mabon Moon...
David...
...whence we...
I'm tired.
I'm spell-casting to prove
a point.
Please.
Fine.
I understand
that our high priest is mum,
but his cauldron isn't.
I ran the ingredients
found in it,
discovered trace amounts
of cherry opal gemstone.
Wiccans believe
the cherry opal amplifies
vibrational energies
within the bloodstream.
We have been assuming
that this is a power spell,
but the truth is
this soup's
a healing spell.
So, what are you saying?
That Ed Lusk is sick?
No, but someone else is.
Someone who borrowed
Turk's blood
and availed themselves
to Lusk's altar.
As I expected,
I found Turk's blood
in the cauldron.
But unexpectedly,
I found
a second blood contributor.
Not Lusk,
but someone whose blood
contains traces of methotrexate.
That's a chemo drug used
to treat blood cancers.
Thou art correct.
And Henry hath
run said blood.
He found a male familial match
to touch DNA from
a candle recovered
from Messner's altar.
The match was not to Ed Lusk,
but to a different
wicked witch.
Ms. Brewer?
Haven't you asked my son
enough questions?
Enough is enough.
We asked you
to bring Mason here
because we're concerned.
Concerned?
About what will happen
to him.
I don't understand.
You need to come with me,
Mrs. Brewer.
Now.
We know that your son, Mason,
is sick, Rebecca.
That he has
Langerhans cell histiocytosis.
The blood cancer
that affects children.
He missed a lot of school
last semester.
His grades started
to falter.
We know that he was
receiving treatment,
but you were seeking help
of a higher power.
I'm not following.
We found Ed Lusk's cauldron.
We know that you're the one
who prepared the ritual
with your son's blood.
BRODY:
And Turk's.
You needed it to save Mason.
CRAWFORD:
You're the one who killed Turk
and Messner.
Your original plan
wasn't too bad.
I mean, you heard the rumblings
around school
that Turk was looking
for the Chem IV test answers.
It's pretty easy,
setting him up.
This is you
entering the school
library at 1:16.
That's the same day that
Chet Messner was killed.
And at 1:19,
you logged on to a computer
using Hannah Hunt's password.
You logged on to VidTree,
and you sent a message
to Rob Turkla.
Telling him where to find
the cheat sheet,
but Messner found it instead.
CRAWFORD: And so you had
to try and kill Rob again.
You knew Turk's schedule.
You knew where to find him.
Why, Rebecca?
Was Mason getting worse?
Why?
The cancer spread to his bones.
The doctor found
vertical lesions
and gave him six months to live.
So you were running
out of time.
We get it.
Why does a piece of crap
like Turk
get to live?
Why does a good boy...
Why does your Mason have to die?
Where's the harmony in that?
We searched your car.
We found your Book of Shadows.
Inside there was a healing
spell dedicated to Mason.
The spell's materials
were all the same items
that we found
in Ed Lusk's cauldron.
I can...
Please.
Listen, I know
that you love your son.
No doubt.
It's all right here.
"If I could set
my own soul free
"to save you, I would,
"but I'm earthbound,
"so I can call on thee, gods.
Let the rising sun sear
the cold serpent of disease."
BOTH:
"My child..."
"...let the wind carry
your pain away."
"Let the waxing moon alight
the darkness within you."
And let this blood of
the powerful allow you to heal.
My son, you shall be reborn.
You shall be reborn.
My son doesn't deserve to die.
(sniffles)
I'm not an evil person.
Ed told us
that they were healing spells.
And-and medicine hadn't worked,
and I was desperate
to try anything.
Two people died because of this.
The Book of Shadows
is very, very clear.
It says that a spell
will only work
if the sacrificed dies
so that the other one can live.
I had to save my boy.
And you ended up
losing him anyway.
Mason?
I'm so sorry.
Yeah.
There anybody
I can call?
Any family?
Ever since my dad died,
it's just been me and Mom.
This is when I get dumped
in an orphanage
with Oliver Twist, right?
No, that's not
gonna happen.
Sure.
You still getting
your treatments?
(sighs)
Yeah.
I start a new round
of chemo next month.
Doctors said they're gonna be
tweaking the protocols.
(sighs)
Think maybe things
might turn around.
I'm homeless,
but I'm not hopeless.
HANNAH:
He can stay with my family.
My parents already said
it was okay.
Hannah, what...
What are you doing here?
I heard about your mom.
I'm really sorry.
Yeah, me, too.
You've always been
really sweet to me,
even when I was so mean to you.
And I couldn't be more sorry.
So...
if you want to play kick the can
or something...
We're not
little kids anymore, Hannah.
I know that,
but...
what do you say?
(laughs, sniffles)
Come on, let's go.
(sighs)
Poor kid.
How could a mother's love
get so twisted?
Well, at least
Hannah stepped up.
Kind of gives you hope, right?
That'd be nice.