MAN:
I bake them all myself.
They're pretty damn tasty.
Pretty potent, too.
Of course, edibles are not
for everybody.
I would say about 80%
of our patients still prefer
their cannabis
in traditional form.
If anxiety is your
main ailment, I'd say
you go with Purple Diesel.
It's got the perfect balance
of alertness
and relaxation.
Leaves you functional, you know?
There you go.
(inhales deeply)
It smokes a little sweet
and sour, with just...
a hint of pine on the exhale.
Yeah, that's nice.
I'll go with that.
Great.
Your best deal,
full ounce.
It's $320.
Don't suppose
you take a card?
Cash only.
(doorbell rings)
(door buzzes)
Pretty, right?
Yeah.
MAN:
Get in there.
There you go.
Enjoy.
Thanks.
Absolutely.
No need to be shy.
We're all legal now.
I just need to see
your medical card,
and I will
set you up with the right strain
for whatever ails you.
(phone chiming)
You should get that.
No, it's... it's all right.
It'll wait.
(chiming continues)
No.
You need to get it now.
Uh...
(chuckles)
What the hell is this?
Please, Lloyd, please just do
what they say. Please.
Please, Lloyd, please
just do what they say. Please.
Don't, Lloyd.
Think of your family.
Why are you doing this?
What do you want?
Check your texts.
There should be instructions.
What about my family?
When am I gonna see them?
I don't know.
Soon, I hope.
Hey, what's going on?
Everything
all right there, Lloyd?
Hey.
Hey, hold it right there!
Stop!
No! Wait, no!
Please, Lloyd. Please just do
what they say. Please.
Please, Lloyd.
Please just do what they say...
SIDLE: The wonders
of technology, right?
The threats and the demands both
sent to the guy's cell phone.
So the kidnapping's legit?
We checked on that?
Yeah, cops confirmed.
Guy's wife never showed up
to work.
Kids never made it to school.
Whoever sent the video and
the text used the wife's phone.
We really got nothing
to trace here.
Yeah. So right now...
she's our only lead.
What do we know
about her, David?
At the moment, next to nothing.
She has no I.D., no car keys,
no cell phone.
There's not a single thing
to identify the body.
Did you run
her prints?
Yeah.
She doesn't have any.
What do you mean?
She has no fingerprints.
Her tips are completely smooth.
Let me see.
Yeah.
SIDLE:
Nick,
this woman is our
only connection
to finding that mother
and her kids,
to getting them back.
STOKES: Well, that
security guard only fired
one shot.
Let's hope he didn't kill
four people.
♪&amp; Who... are you? ♪&amp;
♪&amp; Who, who, who, who? ♪&amp;
♪&amp; I really wanna know ♪&amp;
♪&amp; Who... are you? ♪&amp;
♪&amp; Oh-oh-oh ♪&amp;
♪&amp; Who... ♪&amp;
♪&amp; Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪&amp;
♪&amp; Are you! ♪&amp;
Please, Lloyd, please just
do what they say. Please.
Please, Lloyd, please just do
what they say. Please.
Why would she do this?
Why would she take
my family from me?
My children?
You told
Detective Crawford
that you'd never
seen her before,
that she'd never
been in here.
What about your house?
She and... whoever she
might be working with
were probably watching you,
studying your habits.
Did you see any strange cars
on the street this morning?
No. Everything was normal.
Dina drops the kids off
at school on her way to work.
I... helped
buckle them in the car.
Kissed them good-bye.
What if that's the last time
I ever see them?
What if they're gone?
Mr. Bryant, I know
this is very difficult,
but it doesn't do any good
to think like that right now.
Right now...
let's just focus on getting
your family back, okay?
Yeah.
What do you think?
I don't know, man,
she's still a mystery,
all the way down to her
perfectly smooth fingertips.
I've never seen
anything like it.
You got something there
with the shoes?
There is a foreign sticky
substance on the soles.
I didn't see the source for
it anywhere in the shop,
so she could've picked
it up on the way in.
Could tell us how she got
here, where she came from.
You know what's bugging me?
Hmm?
The money.
Almost $300,000?
I mean, why did he have
that much cash on him?
Yeah, yeah.
Hey, Crawford?
CRAWFORD:
Yeah?
What's the deal with
all this cash?
These people
never heard of banks?
Yeah, banks, credit
card companies--
they didn't want anything to do
with the marijuana business.
They're afraid the funds
could be seized as drug money.
But this is a
legal dispensary.
Legal, according to the state.
The Feds--
they have different ideas.
So, these places
are "cash only"?
Yeah.
Well, it's no wonder
this place was targeted.
I mean, between the money
and all this product,
there's got to be
a million dollars here.
That explains the vault,
the cameras,
and that armed guard.
A lot of good that did.
Still couldn't protect
what really matters.
FINLAY: Jared Briscoe,
the Gig Harbor Killer,
murdered seven women.
RUSSELL: You think the brothers
were working together?
FINLAY: I think they still are.
RUSSELL: You want me to resign?
ECKLIE:
No, I don't want you to resign.
If Briscoe and his brother
really are the ones
behind these murders,
catch them.
Greg told me I'd find you here,
lost in Gig Harbor.
Are you thinking
what I'm thinking?
I have no idea
what I'm thinking.
I don't even know
where to begin.
It's like Seattle
all over again,
just waiting for
another body to drop.
I have an idea where
we should start.
Winthrop claimed that he didn't
know he had a twin brother
until he saw him on the news.
We both know
that's not true.
Yeah, but knowing something
and proving it
are two different things.
Yeah, so we need to prove
that their paths did cross
before the
killing started.
How we gonna do that?
We go back to
the beginning,
and then we follow
the road from there.
Start with the adoption.
Yes.
So, I couldn't find any
adoption history for Winthrop,
but Briscoe was--
as his brother said--
"consigned to the hell"
of foster care.
And we do have
records for those.
Yes, we do.
I'm not so sure that Ecklie's
gonna give us the resources
for this kind of
fishing expedition.
Maybe he doesn't
have to.
I have some vacation
days coming up,
and I would love to
take a trip to Seattle
and dig through some adoption
records and court files.
You know I like to fish.
Patrol unit spotted it
in response to the BOLO.
Belongs to Dina Bryant,
dispensary owner's wife.
Well, this street's
on the route
from their house to
the kids' preschool.
Kidnappers must've
followed them from home.
Cops said they spoke to a woman
who heard tires squealing.
She looked out,
saw a van racing away.
A dark blue van?
Yeah. How did you know that?
Looks like a fresh dent
on the bumper here.
Some blue paint
left behind.
(camera clicks)
Must have been
how they were taken.
Kidnapper bumped
the back of the car.
Okay, stay right here.
I'll be right back, okay?
(tires screech)
BRODY: And then grabbed them
when the mother pulls over to
exchange insurance information.
No, please! My babies!
STOKES:
Hey.
I can't figure
her out, Nick.
What do you mean?
There's just nothing
about her that fits.
This crime was
well-planned.
Despite the fact that
it went sideways, it was smart.
But watching her-- she has
no idea what she's doing.
She's nervous,
she's tense, hesitant.
She's way out of her element.
Well, I'm still trying
to figure out
how she even got there.
She didn't have any car keys,
the cops checked the parking lot
around the crime scene,
didn't find a car
that could've been hers,
so she must have had a ride.
What's that?
Oh, yeah.
This is the latest footage
from a check-cashing place
up the street
from the dispensary.
It's kind of hard to see,
but the dispensary
should be right up there.
Yeah, but look.
That car, double parked.
Looks like a Mustang, black.
Then it suddenly
takes off.
Check that time code.
That's just seconds after the
security guard fired his gun.
That's got to be it.
That's the partner right there.
There's no way in hell
to read the plates.
No.
It's molasses.
What is?
HODGES: The sticky substance
on the bottom
of her shoes-- it's molasses.
Blackstrap molasses
to be specific.
Come on.
Who uses molasses these days?
Interesting answer:
marijuana growers.
For what?
Molasses, it turns out,
is a common soil additive
to cultivating cannabis.
This lady was a grower?
I don't buy that any more than
I buy her as a kidnapper.
CRAWFORD:
The woman--
who could she have been
working with?
Did you have any problems with
anyone opening up your shop?
Do you owe money?
Do you deal with anyone
who could be trouble?
Are you kidding me?
I'm in the
drug business.
I may be legal, but it's
a gray area at best.
My growers are
technically outlaws.
My main competition
are street dealers
and-and delivery services
who think
I'm stealing
their business.
It's the Wild West
all over again.
Yeah, I understand that.
But was there
anyone in particular?
I don't know.
It could be anyone
who has any idea
how much cash involved.
What now?
What am I supposed to do?
We wait for
the kidnappers to try
to make contact with you again.
Now, we already have people--
police-- at your house.
They're setting up your phones.
We're gonna do
the same thing here.
That's it?
David said
you were done.
You find anything?
Not what you're looking for.
There are no surgical
or cosmetic implants,
nothing with a serial number
we could trace.
Her identity is
still a mystery.
Afraid so.
I can explain the absence
of fingerprints,
if it's any consolation.
She was on a drug
called capecitabine.
One of its side effects is
the shedding of fingerprints.
And what is the
drug used for?
It's given to
recovering cancer patients.
She'd undergone surgery
for colon cancer.
Successful surgery, it appears.
I thought it was interesting,
given how she got here.
Her tox report.
She tested
positive for THC.
She was a
marijuana user.
Medicinal, probably,
because of the cancer.
There was no evidence
of heavier substances
or intravenous drug use.
You know, maybe
we're not beaten yet.
Her axillary lymph nodes
are discolored.
I assumed it was due
to melanoma, given her history.
But it could be
something else.
Something else, like what?
Well, let's find out.
Well, the node is
easily enough removed.
(grunts softly)
BRODY:
That looks like ink.
It is. Tattoo ink.
During the tattoo process,
it's deposited in the dermis.
Microphages digest it,
and then migrate
into the closest lymph nodes.
But she doesn't
have any tattoos.
She doesn't now,
but she did at some point.
Why don't you
hit the lights.
Even if it's been removed,
we can still find it.
Why don't you
turn her head there.
There you go.
It was laser removed, but
there's no hiding from the ALS.
You know what? I've seen
this tattoo before.
RUSSELL:
Morgan said we had a lead
on the dispensary case?
Maybe. Turns out,
our mystery woman
had a tattoo
on her neck.
Ties her to a local gang set,
the Bridge Rock Devils.
And those are all devils?
I pulled
arrest records on
every female member arrested
in the last ten years.
Wait a minute.
What about that?
Could be.
That's her.
Seven years ago.
Allison Ball.
Current address?
SANDERS:
1217 Crescent, Boulder City.
Clear!
Bedroom's clear!
Sorry, Stokes.
No sign of any hostages.
Place is all yours.
Okay, thank you, Captain.
"Teacher of the Year"?
Yeah, something's not right.
Does this look like
the home of a lady
who would kidnap
somebody to you?
No.
Hey, Nick, her phone.
She got a video, too.
I'm sorry, Ally.
Please, just do what they say,
or they're gonna kill me.
I'm sorry, Ally.
Who is he?
I don't know,
but there's pictures of him up
all over the place.
Brother, maybe?
Yeah, either that
or a boyfriend.
She didn't go to that dispensary
to rob the place.
She was trying to save him.
She's not the one
we're after here.
And it looks like we have
one more hostage to find.
I'm sorry, Ally.
Please, just do what they say,
or they're gonna kill me.
I'm sorry, Ally. Please...
STOKES: The young man
tied up in that video
is Allison Ball's
little brother.
Stuart-- 24 years old,
no criminal record.
Greg's at his apartment
right now,
checking him out.
Can we trace the phone
that sent this?
No, no. Same as before.
The bad guys used
the victim's phone.
Same with the text with
the instructions on it.
Gave the address
of the dispensary.
Told her to
go there to be with the owner
at 10:15 a.m. exactly.
"If either of you fail
to follow instructions,
your brother dies."
Our dead teacher's just
a pawn in all of this.
Bad guys who are
using her to insulate
themselves from the crime.
Well, yeah, that way
they don't have to step
one foot in that dispensary.
You know?
They're never on camera.
It's ingenious.
Why these two?
Why were the teacher
and her brother chosen
for this robbery?
Must have just crossed paths
with the kidnapper
at some point.
Well, she's a teacher.
Maybe we're looking at a
parent of one of her students.
She just went through
a whole year of
cancer treatments; it could be
somebody associated with that.
Or...
could be the demon weed.
You know, Lloyd said
that he'd never
seen Allison before, that
she wasn't a customer.
You think he could've been
lying? You think he knew her?
If we can prove
a connection here,
then maybe we're having another
conversation with Lloyd.
The common denominator
in all of this?
Marijuana.
♪&amp; ♪&amp;
(sniffs)
There was this guy, lived
in my dorm in college.
Everybody used to
call him Space Bob.
Your lab smells
like his room.
That's not a compliment
to either of you.
Yeah, it is
pretty pungent in here.
Uh, especially the Skunkadelic.
Mmm, mm-hmm.
This is all from
Lloyd's dispensary?
All these strains?
I don't mean to sound
square, but is there really
that big a difference,
one from the other?
Absolutely.
Each strain has its own
unique level of, uh, countless
cannabinoids and terpenoids,
which gives pot
its medicinal value.
Believe it or not,
there is a legit medical basis
for marijuana use.
Uh, granted, the names don't
really help the credibility.
Yeah, well, that's true.
Yeah.
What else did you find out?
Well, I'm using
Near IR Spectrometry
to analyze
Lloyd's inventory.
Because of the varying
cannabinoid levels
of each strain,
it produces its own unique
wave form or spectrum.
Uh, fingerprint of sorts.
Ah.
Well, which wave form is
from our dead teacher's pot?
It's this one here.
Unfortunately, it's not a match
to any of Lloyd's stuff.
Allison Ball wasn't
buying her marijuana
from Lloyd's dispensary?
Well, that makes me wonder
where she was getting it from.
Well, there might be
a way to find out.
There's a database
being assembled
in Connecticut,
with help from the Feds.
They're cataloging marijuana
by its actual DNA.
CODIS for cannabis?
You know, if Henry can
isolate a DNA profile
for Allison Ball's marijuana,
then we might get lucky
and run it against
the Feds' database.
Hey. What's all this?
Allison Ball's life.
Her finances,
her health, her job.
All the little lives
that she touched.
Well, I, uh, just checked out
her brother's apartment.
I'm thinking that he might
be a little sketchy.
Oh, what do you mean?
What'd you find?
Well, it's more
what I didn't find.
No evidence of employment.
No check stubs, no bank
or tax statement.
Yet he lives in
this nice place.
Has a big TV, gaming
system and all that.
I don't know, maybe
big sister was, uh,
helping him out
financially.
I-I don't know how.
I... I mean,
from what I've seen,
it looks like
her cancer pretty much
obliterated her finances.
She basically
had nothing left.
Except...
Wow. This is weird.
Uh...
What?
How do you think that happened?
Hey, Russell,
you got a sec?
I do. What do you got?
Uh, bank statement
for Allison Ball
shows a $50,000-deposit made
to her account
just six weeks ago.
$50,000? From whom?
No record.
It was all cash.
So how does a teacher
who makes, what, 65K tops
come across $50,000 cash?
Maybe she wasn't just
an innocent victim.
All right...
Uh, gentlemen?
I've got something
you might find interesting.
"Us-2-U Wellness."
It's an online
marijuana delivery service.
There are dozens
that operate locally.
You can scroll through
their various strains-- indicas,
sativas, hybrids.
Point, click and the order's
at your door in two hours.
And-and what does
this have to do with our case?
The Feds recently raided Us-2-U.
And the pot
that they seized was entered
into their burgeoning
marijuana DNA database,
where they found a match
to the pot that you found
in Allison's apartment.
So that's where she
got her marijuana.
And the guy behind Us-2-U...
Calvin Reynolds.
Calvin Reynolds drives
a black Mustang.
Nick and Sara said
that they saw
a black Mustang in front
of the dispensary.
It took off
after Allison was shot.
CRAWFORD: You seem to be running
afoul of the law lately, Calvin.
What's up with that?
You mean the Fed bust?
That's crap.
My attorneys already filed
to have the case dropped.
The Web site was back up
and running in three days.
Medical marijuana use
is legal in Nevada.
Pretty soon,
recreational use will be, too.
You got a problem with that,
that's too bad.
To be honest, I really don't
care one way or another.
This isn't about
marijuana for me.
You, uh...
You know this woman?
That's Allison Ball.
Strange thing--
she had molasses
on the soles of her shoes
when she was shot dead
this morning.
Well, molasses is used in the
cultivation of cannabis, right?
Yeah, sure.
Lot of the growers use it.
Do you?
Hey, the only
reason I'm asking
is because
we had a look
inside of that black
Mustang of yours
and we found molasses
spilled all on the carpet.
Now, in my mind, that
puts Allison in your car
and you, Calvin,
in front of the dispensary
when she was shot.
Hey, buddy...
I get the motive.
You know, you used to be
the only game in town.
Now you have these
dispensaries opening up.
I mean, they're
stealing your business.
They're stealing your money.
Tell me,
why her?
Why would you rope
a poor, innocent girl
into your scheme?
Nobody ever roped Ally
into anything.
The fact is, she called me.
Oh, so she was the
criminal mastermind
behind all of this.
(chuckles)
Is that it?
Ally and me go way back.
We both grew up in Bridge Rock.
We were both Devils.
She got out.
Made a better life.
But she always called me
when she needed me.
Like when the cancer came
and the doctor
suggested pot might help,
she called me.
When her medical bills
started piling up
and the treatment became
too expensive, she called me.
So you gave her money?
$50,000. And I'd do it again
in a second, gladly, just...
...just because of
who she was.
So you helped her out
from time to time.
How does that
get us to today?
She called me this morning.
She was panicked, said...
said somebody had
grabbed up her brother.
And they had, uh,
you know, given...
given her instructions
on how to get him back.
But she was, uh...
she was scared.
She was... she was
too freaked out to do it alone.
So she called...
and she asked you to drive.
And I would've done the
whole thing for her if I could.
When I realized she...
she wasn't coming back out, I...
(sighs)
...I just left.
She should've just
let that bastard rot.
You're talking about
her brother-- Stuart?
Ally said he'd been running
numbers for some bookie.
She thought that's who
would be behind the kidnapping.
Okay, Calvin, do you know
who he was working for?
I need a name.
I need the name of the bookie.
No.
No, Ally didn't know the name.
What's going on?
Have you heard anything?
No. Not yet, Lloyd. I'm sorry.
This doesn't make any sense!
They should have called by now!
They should have
made contact!
Why haven't they called?!
Lloyd!
Listen to me.
Whoever the kidnappers are,
they are scrambling
right now, trying to
come up with a new plan.
We just have to wait.
For how long?
I don't know.
But I know
they're worth waiting for.
In the meantime...
maybe you can help me.
Have you seen this guy?
His name is Stuart Ball;
He's the brother of the woman
that was shot in here
this morning.
Do you know him?
Has he been in here, maybe?
No. I don't
recognize him.
Is he involved somehow?
He's in business
with some bad people.
That's all we know right now.
(phone ringing)
Hold on, Lloyd,
hold on. Not yet.
(phone continues ringing)
All right, I'm ready.
Go ahead,
answer it.
Hello?
No. We're closed right now.
I don't know
for how long.
I have to keep this line free.
(cell phone ringing)
This is Keys.
You got him. Where?
Yeah. You were just asking
about Stuart Ball?
Well, it sounds like
our guys just found him.
(indistinct
police radio chatter)
SANDERS:
Blue van.
BRODY:
Just like the woman saw
speeding away
from the kidnapping.
(flies buzzing)
It's just Stuart.
No sign of the mother
or the kids.
Well, now we know
whoever has them
isn't afraid to kill.
Just talked to the van's owner;
pretty much sure I ruined
his Hawaiian vacation.
He's in Hawaii?
So the van's stolen?
Mm-hmm.
Well, the shot
was at close range.
The shooter was in the van
with the victim--
most likely
in the passenger seat.
Although...
that's a good amount
of high-velocity
impact spatter up here.
Maybe a little luminol
will tell a better story.
There's blood splatter
all over the passenger seat.
Not all of it. Look there,
on the side of the seat.
There's a blood void.
From what?
The shooter wasn't up front.
He was in back.
BRODY: He reached
between the seats to fire.
His arm kept the blood from
hitting that part of the seat.
It settled on his arm instead.
But what about
the round?
The shot was
through-and-through.
Didn't break any windows.
It caught the A-pillar.
STOKES:
According to Doc Robbins,
Stuart Ball died between
six and ten hours ago.
Six to ten-- that's shortly
after the robbery went bad.
Yeah.
That can't help our chances
of finding the mother
and her kids alive.
Stuart Ball had
served his purpose, right?
Mother and the two kids
could still be worth some money.
That might be reason
to keep them alive.
Well, I hope
you're right.
Hey, guys, I think we just
caught a break with ballistics.
I got an IBIS hit off the bullet
that killed Stuart Ball.
It matches a round
that was fired five years ago
in a fatal carjacking attempt.
Did they catch the carjacker?
In a matter of speaking.
I guess the carjacker
was the fatality.
The owner of the car
shot him in self-defense.
So the gun belonged to the car
owner-- tell me you got a name.
Remi Volero--
he's kind of a low-rent
real estate mogul.
Mostly strip clubs
and mini-malls.
But take a look at the rap
sheet-- everything on it
is related to bookmaking
and racketeering.
Guy's a bookie.
Well, Stuart Ball was
running numbers for a bookie.
What are the odds?
It's got to be
the same guy.
That your handiwork, Remi?
That is not my handiwork.
I don't know
what the hell that is.
You don't know him?
Stuart Ball?
'Cause I'm pretty sure
he worked for you.
I said I didn't know
whatthat is.
I didn't say I didn't know who.
Yeah, Stuart worked for me
running errands.
He worked for you running
numbers and making collections
as part of your
illegal gambling operation.
You're not even gonna ask
what happened to him?
I can see what happened to him.
Someone capped him.
Yeah, somebody-- with your gun.
Did you forget, Remi?
Your gun's in the system.
You used it five years ago
to shoot a carjacker.
The thing is,
it's not my gun anymore.
I gave it to Stuart
a couple years back.
Where are they, Remi!
Where's Dina Bryant
and her children?!
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Yeah, you do.
You are underwater
on a dozen
real estate investments.
That dispensary
was an easy mark.
All that cash
just sitting there.
This isn't a conversation
I'm interested in having.
I want my lawyer.
RUSSELL:
It's awfully convenient
he gave his gun to Stuart,
don't you think?
Crawford's willing to
hold him for 48 hours,
but I don't know if that's gonna
help Dina Bryant and her kids.
You said that this Remi guy
had a lot of real estate, right?
At least 25 properties.
He could be using any of them
or none of them.
We have the kidnap van.
The odds are pretty good
that wherever the victims are,
that van was there.
We keep working the van,
figure out where it's been.
RUSSELL:
Right.
♪&amp; ♪&amp;
What do you mean he's gone?
Well, yeah, but how does
something like that happen?
I'm on my way right now.
BRODY:
Nick.
What's going on?
Well, Lloyd has
ducked out on the cops
that were babysitting him;
now nobody can find him.
The only reason he
would have taken off is
if the kidnappers
contacted him.
He must have gone
to pay the ransom.
Crawford's got a bead on
his cell phone; we'll find him.
What's up?
LLOYD:
No, no, no.
What are you doing here?
You can't be here!
They said no cops!
Who did?
No, no!
You have to go!
If you're here,
they won't bring my family.
Who's "they"?
Did somebody contact you?
Lloyd, where's the money?
I dropped it off to them,
like they said.
I gave them
what they wanted.
Where? And how?
Over at the tennis courts,
across the park.
Gonna be long gone by now.
Well, please tell me
you saw something.
I just want my family back.
But you didn't get them back!
You gave the kidnappers
their money.
And now they're
not worth anything anymore.
STOKES:
Well...
let's just hope you didn't
get your whole family killed.
All right, I-I'll pass
the word along.
See you when you're back.
That was Nick.
He said the ransom money
is long gone and Lloyd,
the shop owner, had no contact
with whoever took it.
Okay, so where's that leave us?
Remi Volero's lawyered up.
Right?
So even if he knows
where Dina Bryant
and those kids are,
he's not gonna say anything.
Any ideas?
Well, I may have something.
It's gonna be vague though.
The, uh, kidnappers
have been
really smart at communicating.
They use the victims' phones
to send the initial
videos and texts.
And when they're
not sending,
they keep the phones turned off.
Making it impossible
to locate, right.
They contacted Lloyd tonight
with the ransom demands.
How did they do that?
Well, they sent an e-mail
using Stuart Ball's phone.
It was on
for less than 20 seconds.
I've been going through
the cell carrier's
cached data to try and pinpoint
which cell tower they pinged.
There you go.
Like I said,
it's vague.
No, no,
that's a good start.
Let's look real
hard at this
Remi Volero,
see what we can link him to
inside of that circle.
BRODY:
Now, I know Nick is the expert,
but this just looks like
a common crane fly to me.
They're everywhere in Vegas.
I don't know how
they're gonna help us
pinpoint where
the van has been.
You having better luck
on your side?
You mean, am I having
any better luck
with the bird
excrement?
It's not lost
on me that,
of all the trace
that you pulled,
you gave me the poop.
Interesting poop though.
Contains a poison
called Meríasol.
Similar to hemlock.
So the birds ate the poison,
but they didn't die?
Meríasol is poisonous
to humans, not to birds.
It comes from the
berries they eat.
Where do the berries grow?
Apparently, only
in the rainforests.
Not in the middle of
the Nevada desert.
Unless...
there is a rainforest
in the middle
of the Nevada desert.
The Mediterranean Casino
has a rainforest garden.
100% humidity.
I went there once,
my hair went insane.
We just need to know
if they have a Meríasol tree.
Put the Mediterranean
on the map.
Why? It's not
in the circle.
There were bird droppings
on top of the van.
They contained a
specific type of berry.
Far as I can tell,
it only grows at
the Mediterranean.
You think the birds
were feeding there?
Yeah, probably starlings.
According to the
groundskeeper,
those birds have been
all over the berries.
Now, uh, put a circle
around the casino,
quarter-mile radius.
Apparently, starlings nest
within a quarter mile
of their food source.
That narrows the area way down.
Greg,
zoom in a little more,
just the wedge.
Volero owns
something there, too,
doesn't he?
Right here, off Bennett.
He bought it six months ago.
It's an old produce warehouse.
Morgan's starlings.
Yeah.
Nick.
CRAWFORD: It looks like
a kidnapper's kit to me.
STOKES:
Yup.
These are their phones.
This is definitely the place.
Hey, Nick, shh, shh.
(quiet creaking)
Listen.
(creaking continues)
Oh, my God!
Mrs. Bryant, calm down.
Are you okay?
Where are you children?
I don't know.
They're in some
room somewhere.
What...
Come with us.
Stay close.
Okay.
(TV playing quietly)
Stay back.
Oh, my God, my babies!
My babies! My babies.
Mommy!
My babies.
Everything's okay now.
Okay? I'm here.
I'm here now.
Mommy.
(mouthing)
Let me see you.
Oh, my God.
Hi, guys.
Dina.
Hi.
How are they doing?
Uh, they seem okay,
thank God.
Uh, I'm gonna show
you a photo lineup.
I want you to tell me
if any of these men
were involved in
the kidnapping.
I-I... I can't.
I mean, I never saw a face.
They always had masks on.
That's okay, take
a look anyway.
Maybe you've seen one of them
in your neighborhood
or around the kids'
school or...
(sighs)
Okay.
I... No, I don't...
recognize any of these,
I'm sorry.
They're here? They're okay?
Yeah, yeah, they
checked out just fine.
But I can't let you
in there just yet.
Why?
Well, they still have
to be processed.
What do you mean?
I have to see them.
I'm sorry, Lloyd,
but Sara has to
collect their clothes,
give them a quick once-over.
You know, even the
smallest detail
can help us catch the
guys who did this to you.
So just... sit tight.
Yeah.
(whispers): Hi.
What's up?
Haven't you already analyzed
every single frame of those?
Now I have more to work with.
All we had before
were the five-second loops.
Now we have the phones
that they were filmed on.
It's only
another second or two,
but there are
heads and tails on each.
At the end of this one,
the camera tilts up
and catches just
a piece of window.
And there's a
reflection in it.
Maybe I can enhance it.
Looks like you're
getting something.
I can see...
Oh, my God, Greg.
Last 24 hours must have been
pretty trying for you.
Not at all what you expected
when yesterday began, huh?
God, no. No, not in a million
years could I have thought
something like this
could happen to us.
No, no, you thought it'd be
quick and easy, didn't you?
Probably over
in less than an hour.
You and Stuart
would have the money.
Couldn't have guessed
that Stuart's sister
was gonna be shot.
Right? I mean, you just thought
she'd pick up the money,
drop it off where you and Stuart
told her to in the instructions.
(scoffs)
That's-that's, uh...
This is crazy. I...
(sighs)
Mr. Russell, you can't
honestly think that
I was involved somehow?
I was a victim.
My children were victims.
Certainly looked that way
in the video, I have to admit.
I mean, that was...
that was terrifying.
What was your plan if we hadn't
found you in the warehouse?
What-What were you gonna do?
Were you gonna
miraculously escape
and then flag down a car,
dial 911?
You know, I-I don't need
to listen to this...
Hey, you sit down.
Look, I have been through hell.
Okay? And I just...
I want to go home,
and I want to be with my family.
Mrs. Bryant, we know that
you and Stuart filmed the video.
Just the two of you.
No kidnappers.
No Remi Volero.
You filmed each other.
I mean, that is you,
isn't it?
Uh...
Look, you... you
have to know that
I didn't want to
do any of this.
It was Stuart.
No.
No, no, he-he forced me.
Stuart was just
some young kid
that you tricked
into helping you.
No, he...
Stuart had a gun.
And he threatened
to hurt us.
Well, he didn't have the gun
when you shot him
in the head though, did he?
See, what you don't realize is
that we found Stuart's blood
on the sleeve of your sweater.
Mrs. Bryant, we have
all the evidence we need.
You're done.
Mr. Russell,
you look the other
way on this...
...and half of
what I have...
is yours.
Mrs. Bryant,
you have absolutely nothing
I want.
Man, she's a piece of work.
Mm.
She's not gonna say
where the money is.
Well, she thinks
it's gonna be waiting for
her when she gets out.
Only, she's never getting out.
RUSSELL: I'm starting to wonder
if something's changed.
Some ripple of inhumanity
has built into this
wave of cruelty
and indifference.
Feel like we're being swallowed
by this darkness.
FINLAY:
Mm. That bad, huh?
(chuckles)
I'm a little moody today,
I'll give you that.
I could use some
good news, Jules.
I wish I had something for you.
But the, uh...
records clerk up here
hasn't exactly
been cooperative.
But I will get you
Briscoe's foster care files.
Don't you worry.
I'm just gonna have to be
a little bit more clever.
All right.
Do me a favor though.
Don't get into any trouble.
You have history up there.
I wouldn't dream of it.
Hey, hey, hey, I'm serious.
(phone chimes)
You be careful.
All right, I'll call you
as soon as I have something.
Take care of yourself.
Always.
Bye.