RUSSELL:
Previously on CSI...
FINLAY: Jared Briscoe,
the Gig Harbor Killer.
Murdered seven women.
RUSSELL:
He took the bodies.
Left processed crime scenes
for us to find.
We're investigating
the disappearance of my partner,
Keri Torres.
I have been enlisted
to defend a man
who has been
wrongfully imprisoned.
Says who?
WINTHROP:
Says me.
SHAW: Who knew that psychopath
Briscoe had a twin?
RUSSELL: You think the brothers
were working together.
I think they still are.
ECKLIE:
If Briscoe and his brother
really are the ones
behind these murders,
catch them.
This is Russell.
I just found
the Gig Harbor Killer.
Congratulations.
WOMAN:
CSI Finlay,
I'm gonna need you
to surrender your firearm.
Let the record reflect
that CSI Julie Finlay's
service weapon was received
with seven live rounds
in the magazine.
One live round in the chamber.
It was a good shoot.
Jared Briscoe
was about
to kill Lab Director Russell.
Understood.
What I don't understand
is what you
and the lab director
were doing out there.
We had a warrant,
based on evidence
that was recovered outside of
Maya Russell's apartment.
Lab Director Russell's daughter.
Evidence that confirmed
Briscoe's stalking of Maya.
I called Judge Vincent,
and he issued me a warrant
over the phone.
Judge Vincent?
Of course.
And what is that
supposed to mean?
I think we both know.
What the hell, Keri?
Well, you look like
you were gonna cry.
You know she doesn't
even know you exist.
Not true.
We had coffee last week.
With Lab Director Russell.
Baby steps.
For you or her?
Everyone knows she has
the hots for the boss.
He's married. Happily.
Whatever.
Take a little advice
from Dr. Torres--
stay away from that one.
She's trouble.
(knocking on the door)
Hey.
Thanks.
Did Eddie call?
No, not yet.
Hope you didn't bring me
all the way
up here to Seattle
on a wild-goose chase.
Don't worry,
Eddie's lead's gonna pan out.
Trust me.
Six weeks-- nothing.
If this guy's gonna drop
Keri's body on us,
why doesn't
he do it now?
Dan, I'm really sorry.
I know this is really hard.
If Paul Winthrop wanted
to get his brother free
by creating reasonable doubt...
another body, another
"processed crime scene"--
that's gonna help
his cause, right?
Yeah, I think you're right.
But I do not think that Keri
is gonna be the next body
that we find.
She just does not
fit the profile
of the Gig Harbor
Killer's victims.
You know, this guy gets off
on messing with our minds.
That's why it's
been so quiet.
It's not gonna be quiet
for long.
Russell.
You've got
to hear this.
MAN: Please, I can't help you
(woman screams)
if you don't give me
your location.
What is this?
911 call,
(woman screams)
came in a few
minutes ago.
Tracing it now.
This is how the call
started. Here.
MAN:
911. What's your emergency?
SCRAMBLED MALE VOICE:
I'd like to report a murder.
WOMAN:
Please!
Stop! Don't!
No! No...!
He's killing her right now.
He wants us to hear him do it.
Talk to me.
Got a cell tower.
Phone's pinging off it.
Northtown.
Pulling data now.
I got it.
Phone has GPS.
(woman screaming)
(woman crying)
Miss? Miss, are you still there?
911 operator,
this is CSI Sara Sidle.
On scene with officers.
Code Four.
He's back.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
Just like last time,
he took the body with him.
But the volume of blood says
that the victim is dead.
STOKES:
Blood's dry and flaky.
Murder could have
happened weeks ago.
So, he returns
to the scene of the crime.
He dials 911.
He knew we'd trace it.
He knew how much time
he'd have to get away.
That, plus all this,
again tells me we're dealing
with somebody who knows
police procedure.
Says to me he's feeling
confident, too.
Me, too.
We'll catch him.
These cameras are
old-school, huh?
Not digital.
Exposed film.
Found the same
in that camera.
It's probably in all of them.
So, what, this guy's
taking crime scene photos
for us now, as well?
It's been a long time since any
of us was in a dark room.
Yeah.
SIDLE:
Greek-- Theta Pi.
Theta Pi?
College sorority.
SIDLE: Probably a student
like the others.
Good bet she was moonlighting
in the sex trade, too.
Digital recorder.
Hit it.
SCRAMBLED MALE VOICE:
I'm standing at the north wall
where I'm finding blood
inconsistent with the crime.
Perhaps stringing
will yield more.
Strings.
But no blood.
Kill the lights.
"People lie.
Follow the evidence"?
Hmm.
We're really
good at that.
SCRAMBLED MALE VOICE:
Before I register
my preliminary findings,
I can't help but share
some thoughts on the suspect
dubbed "The Gig Harbor Killer,"
but whom I would
more accurately describe
as "The Crime Scene Killer."
Clearly our suspect is
intelligent, analytical,
creative-- an artist whose
medium isn't paint or plaster,
but flesh and blood.
Victimology suggests the women
are chosen carefully.
Young. Blonde. Seemingly
innocent. But far from it.
With nine victims already,
I see no end in sight.
No end to the violence
because our killer is a ghost,
untouchable,
who walks between the raindrops
and exists in the shadows.
Not a bad bit
of psychoanalysis.
Emphasis
on the "psycho."
So, his mocking us
has graduated
from crime scene
analysis to profiling.
Can we compare the altered voice
to samples of Paul Winthrop?
Unfortunately, no.
But I did find something
on the other recording
that the killer left us.
The one he made
of the murder.
(intermittent screaming)
Keep listening, I was able
to boost the background.
(metallic object drops)
You can hear the killer
drop the weapon,
begin to walk away.
(footsteps resounding)
And then there's
more footsteps.
Walking to the recorder
and turning it off.
Either our "ghost"
can fly...
Or there were two people
in that room.
If Winthrop is
the killer,
he's found a new partner
to sub for his brother.
Question is-- who?
(cell phone beeps)
Oh. Maybe I'll ask him myself.
I expected treatises
by Locard and Lombroso.
Dry volumes on criminology.
But you're a man of letters.
The Prince and the Pauper.
I've always
loved that one.
What do you want,
Mr. Winthrop?
The same thing you want--
the truth.
Mistakes have
been made.
The killer
is out there.
I'm sure you've heard
that my brother, Jared,
is going to have
a new day in court.
I heard.
Yeah. So, I've enlisted
an expert to conduct
a psychological evaluation
to explain why an innocent man
would confess
to crimes he didn't commit.
But that's only part
of the story, isn't it?
You tell me.
You discovered
physical evidence, DNA,
that exonerates my brother,
but that unfortunately
also casts
an unflattering light
on your previous findings.
I wouldn't go that far.
I'd like to give you an
opportunity, Mr. Russell.
Between you and me, I come here
requesting
your services
as a "friend of the court."
You want me to help you
and your brother?
Help yourself, as well.
Oh... how's that work?
We both know you'll find
more dead women.
Perhaps you have already?
Only by freeing
my brother
will you be able
to free yourself,
push away the clouds
of doubt you must feel,
enabling yourself to
have the vision you'll need
to find this predator.
Well, thank you for the offer,
but I think I'm going to pass.
Because,
just between you and me,
I think you're a sociopath.
Hmm. I thought we could have
a meeting of the minds,
but I misjudged you.
I make a better friend
than enemy.
SHAW: Eddie. Yeah, listen. Could
you have her come down to PD
for a conversation?
Just off the record.
It's not gonna be easy.
I know. I'll owe you one.
All right.
I'll see what I can do.
Thank you.
Told you Eddie
would come through.
What do you got?
His gal at the Hall
of Records in Tacoma
has a birth certificate
for Jared Briscoe.
Thing is, there's
no record of a twin.
How's that possible?
I don't know.
The mother's listed
as Cynthia Hughes, still alive.
Eddie's setting up
a meeting right now.
Cynthia Hughes?
That's right.
You're Jared Briscoe's mother?
I'm Daniel Shaw.
I'm a private investigator.
This is Julie Finlay.
She's with the Las Vegas
Police Department.
CYNTHIA: The detective
who brought me here told me.
But obviously,
he didn't tell you,
despite what it says
on the birth certificate,
I'm not Jared's birth mother.
He neglected to tell us that.
After I adopted Jared,
I petitioned the court,
I needed a birth
certificate.
They put my
name on it.
So, you don't know
who Jared's birth mother is?
No.
But I know I have to
live with the fact
that I'm responsible
for what's become of him.
"Responsible."
Why do you say that?
My husband and I didn't have
the best marriage.
He'd fly into rages.
And poor Jared...
he paid the price.
Is that why Jared went
into foster care?
I tried to get him back
many times.
Miss Hughes,
we haven't found any records
of adoption for Jared.
And you won't find any.
Jared was dropped at my doorstep
by a friend.
She worked at a convent,
a place where girls
in trouble often went.
So, you're saying
that Jared's mother was one
of these "girls in trouble"?
Yes.
Do you know that
Jared has a brother?
A twin.
No.
I did not.
This convent,
is it still around?
Do you remember
the name?
St. Gabriella's.
Nick was right.
The killer has added taking
crime scene photos to his M.O.
DNA from the blood at the crime
scene didn't pop on CODIS.
But now that we have a face,
maybe it can help us get a name
from another database.
You got anything?
Well, the first images on some
of the rolls all look the same.
As if the killer,
when loading the camera,
advanced the film
and accidentally popped off
a few exposures at the head.
And they're blurry,
but doesn't this look like
an "H" to you?
Yeah, maybe from a sign,
or a billboard.
Uh, there were no signs
or billboards anywhere
near the crime scene.
I think I know a way
to enhance these.
If we can figure out
where this is,
then this could help us find
where the killer is.
FINLAY:
St. Gabriella's Convent.
Wow. To be honest, I didn't know
places like this still existed.
SHAW: Nun I talked to
on the phone said
she might be able to help us.
FINLAY:
Well, let's hope so.
Sister Alice?
Mr. Shaw. Miss Finlay.
Any luck?
Unfortunately,
my predecessors here
didn't believe in computers,
but I found this.
It's a ledger listing births
to young mothers
during the years our convent
took in girls in need.
I found the entry
you're looking for.
June 18, 1976.
Twin boys born.
Given names "Jared" and "Paul."
Mother is listed
as "Nancy Harper."
Any indication
of adoption?
Uh... no.
Nothing.
It was before my time,
but I understand it wasn't
uncommon for babies born
in that sort of circumstance
to be given informally
to families deemed worthy.
Well, we know where
Jared ended up.
What about Paul?
I can answer that.
There was a fire some years ago.
Records were lost.
But a certain Sister Bernadette
made notations from memory.
There was a "C-13"
noted in the ledger
speaking to the fate
of a "baby Paul."
The child never left us.
I'm sorry,
I don't understand.
This is a cemetery.
Yes, for infants
that died
during childbirth
or shortly thereafter.
If you're searching for
this "Paul Winthrop,"
your search ends here.
FINLAY:
D.B., I got a court order
to exhume the grave.
Didn't make Sister Alice
very happy.
Well, she'll survive.
Just like Paul Winthrop did.
Which begs the question--
who's buried in Grant's Tomb?
Yeah. I'm working on that,
but, uh, there's something else.
You know how Winthrop claims
that he didn't have a brother
until he found out
about him on the news?
Right. So, what,
you got something?
Well, there was a fire here, and
all the records were destroyed.
But this one nun tried
to reconstruct them from memory,
and made a note
in the visitors log.
Turns out that we are not
the first people
to come around here asking
about Jared and his brother.
Was there a name?
No, but...
the visitor was from San Diego.
That's Paul Winthrop's hometown.
When was this?
One year before
the Gig Harbor murders began.
Let me know what you find
in that grave, will you?
I'll have an answer soon.
Interesting.
You isolated the
different colors.
I don't know how much good
it's doing me, though.
Well, first message was
in the green strings, right?
"Gemini," the twins' way
of announcing themselves,
daring us to catch them.
STOKES: Didn't find
any Gemini this time.
You're looking for
other constellations.
Yeah.
I've been spinning
these webs for hours,
just coming up empty.
Maybe the answer's not
in the strings.
"People lie.
Follow the evidence."
What are you thinking?
What's different
about this crime scene?
For starters, the cameras.
Yeah.
Last time, the message was
in the bird's-eye view
of the crime scene.
All these cameras.
How about...
we connect the dots.
Here's the
constellation.
Right?
It's Virgo.
The virgin.
The killer said that
the women were chosen
because they were
"seemingly innocent," virginal.
But they were all
in the sex trade, too.
So, this wasn't
about the killer or killers;
it was about the victims.
Madonna-whore complex.
First, Winthrop tells us
who's doing the killings,
then he tells us why.
Mommy issues.
♪ ♪
It's a doll.
Head's really loose.
There's something inside.
She looks like a teenager.
I'm guessing
we're looking
at Jared and Paul's
birth mother.
Well, look at this.
Think this could
possibly be
the hair of the mother?
Maybe DNA will confirm.
Yeah, but it still won't
tell us why somebody went
through this whole charade.
I-I get why Jared
was given up for adoption.
But why pretend
his twin brother died?
Maybe that's the same
question Winthrop was asking
when he came here
looking for his brother.
Looking for a partner in crime.
WOMAN:
Let's talk about your brother.
When did you first know
of his existence?
Physically, astrologically
or... otherwise?
WOMAN:
You choose.
Two little mutants,
clinging to each other
in a sack of blood
and urine and excrement.
There's an obvious bond there.
Until they reach in
and-and tear them apart.
WOMAN: You're talking
about your separation.
JARED:
Yeah.
They ripped me away
from my brother,
took me away from
the only mother I ever knew,
the only woman who ever...
wanted me.
WOMAN:
You mean your adoptive mother.
You know what it's like
to be handed
from foster family
to foster family.
They just want the check,
that's all.
I mean, come on.
How can they expect me
to be anything other than
a serial killer?
WOMAN: Is that
what you really think?
Is that why you confessed
to all these crimes?
I don't want to talk anymore.
I'm gonna ask you
one more time, Jared.
Do you really believe that
you are the Gig Harbor Killer?
If I'm not, then who am I?
Who am I?
Turn the camera off.
Turn it off!
Whatever Winthrop's paying that
psychiatrist, it's not enough.
Well, it is if this
performance convinces a court
that Briscoe's
mentally ill.
I'm not so sure
it is a performance.
Abandoned and abused
in the foster care system,
it would make him vulnerable
to a stronger will,
especially if that will was
a reflection of himself.
Dominant twin manipulates
the weaker,
uses him to commit his crimes.
Let's him take the fall.
Then why does Winthrop
save Briscoe from death row?
Without the reflection,
the narcissist dies, too.
BRODY:
Hey, Henry.
Heard Hodges found human tissue
in the strings again.
He told me
you found DNA.
Two contributors.
Both female. One was a match
to the blood at the crime scene.
Our victim,
who now has a name--
Pamela Kramer.
Ran facial recognition
against the college database.
She was a
student at WLVU.
Notified next of kin.
They're sending over
DNA exemplars to confirm.
Good.
Unfortunately,
I won't need exemplars
to identify the second
female contributor.
What do you mean?
I found a match in CODIS.
(cell phone buzzes)
It's Keri Torres.
I guess, given everything, her
fate should come as no surprise,
but still...
Are you sure
about that second DNA?
Yeah. I mean,
I ran it twice. Why?
'Cause Keri Torres was just
brought into Desert Palm.
RUSSELL:
Where was she found?
At the intersection of
Jefferson and Sahara.
She was staggering
through the cars.
Police said she was
combative, incoherent.
They thought she was
a meth-head until
they ran her.
Looks like she's
been through hell.
She's got ligature marks
on her wrists and her ankles.
An incision mark
on her abdomen,
where he opened
her up...
He didn't let her go.
He was still
playing with her.
But she got away.
Nah, she fought her way free.
BRODY:
He underestimated her.
He finally made a mistake.
Yeah.
Keri's going to make it.
Tox report says she was drugged.
Combination of opiates
and hallucinogens.
So there were
signs of torture?
RUSSELL:
Yeah.
Including taking a piece of her
to make more of his strings.
SHAW:
I don't get it.
Why didn't he
just kill her?
I'm sure Winthrop
was probably trying
to get information
out of her.
We know she was close
to learning the truth.
Did you get DNA results
on the hair you found
in the coffin?
Yeah. It was
a definite match
to Briscoe and Winthrop's
birth mother.
D.B., Winthrop was
definitely at that convent.
He was there searching
for his brother.
We can't prove that,
though, right?
FINLAY: Oh, we will.
We're gonna catch
the first flight back.
We're on our way to
the airport right now.
All right, fly safe.
I can't believe
she's still alive.
Can't imagine what
she went through.
♪ ♪
No... no.
No... stop...
Stop.
Please!
Stop!
Keri, Keri,
hey, hey.
(gasping)
It's okay.
You're okay.
You're safe now.
I'm Morgan.
I'm a CSI.
(exhales)
(sobs)
I got away.
Yeah, you did.
But right now,
I need your help.
Do you remember
anything?
No, I can't...
I just...
I just remember... a room.
(grunts)
There were strings.
Everywhere.
Strings?
You mean like trajectory
strings from a crime scene?
No, um...
they were just hanging there.
Like fishing line
hung out to dry.
How did you get away?
For days,
I thought there was water
all around me.
It was blue.
Like the ocean.
And then I realized
it wasn't water.
It was glass.
I was able to cut my way out.
I found a vent.
I saw light...
daylight.
And I just kept
crawling forward,
toward the light.
I didn't care where it led--
Heaven, hell...
I didn't care,
I just kept going.
I just kept going... (sobs)
I...
I can't remember
much more than that.
No, that's good.
You're-you're
doing really good.
I have just
one more question.
Before you were taken,
you met with a man.
At a coffee house.
Yeah, I remember.
His name
was, um...
Turner.
Mark Turner.
He was a lawyer.
This is a picture of him.
Do you recognize him?
No.
I mean, no,
that's not the man I met.
What about this man?
Yes. That's him.
(people talking, laughing)
Little young for you,
don't you think?
I don't think so.
But then again,
I don't have a daughter.
I hear that makes a difference.
You here because
you changed your mind
about helping my brother?
Or you need a lift?
You two meet
online?
That's none of
your business.
Young lady,
there's a taxicab
right over there.
I suggest
you go home.
Your client and I have
a few things to discuss.
Thank you for
dinner tonight.
I'll call.
Yeah, a little
heads-up there.
This guy's
a murderer.
So if he calls,
hang up.
That was subtle.
You lied to us.
It wasn't your
lawyer that met
Keri Torres at
the coffee shop.
It was you.
And that was right
before she disappeared.
I didn't lie.
Your people just never
asked me the question.
This is one big game
for you, isn't it?
You think you're
smarter than we are.
All those
crime scenes,
leaving your brother's
fingerprint under the table...
You don't see what's
going on here, do you?
Or maybe you
don't want to.
What's that
supposed to mean?
I confess.
Yes, I met with
Keri Torres.
Because she reached
out to my attorney
with evidence that
my brother was innocent.
Framed by someone
in Seattle PD.
Oh, is that
right?
That's right.
She was going to provide
even more information
the next meeting.
But she never
showed up.
So forgive me
if I chose
to be less than forthcoming,
especially when the person
who was asking me the questions
was the cop who
shot my brother.
I think you'd better leave
CSI Finlay out of this.
Kind of hard to.
I think you and I are
on the same side here.
You just don't know it yet.
Oh.
See, I almost
forgot to tell you.
We found your grave.
Nancy Harper, right?
That's your
birth mother?
Interesting.
You know what else
is interesting?
We have Keri Torres.
And she's alive.
That's great news.
I look forward
to seeing her.
FINLAY:
Hey.
Hey, welcome back.
Morgan said
you're working on
finding the killer's
location?
Yeah. And we got lucky.
He took photos of what
I think is the same landmark,
using different cameras
at different exposures.
How does that help?
Well, each photo
has detail
in the light
and dark areas
unique to that photo.
Mm-hmm.
So using high-dynamic-range
software, I can overlap them
to create a more
vivid composite.
Whole's greater than
the sum of its parts.
Hmm.
You know, before, I thought
this here was an "H."
Like on a sign.
But now...
it looks like
some kind of
structure.
Yeah.
I feel like
I've seen this place before.
So, I ran the glass
Morgan pulled
from Keri Torres's foot.
Refractive light index
found the usual
silicon dioxide
mixed with potassium
and zinc oxide.
But there was an element
that did stand out.
What's that?
Tin oxide with
hamachi indigo dye.
It's found in
Japanese Blue Bark
textured glass,
which is used in
making tiles, statuary
and objets d'art.
Which I am familiar with
because my mother's a collector.
In fact, funny story...
Hodges...
Hodges, you're a genius.
I am?
I got it.
I figured out what that is.
It's the gate that
you walked through
to enter The Mizu Hotel.
Built in '62.
Went belly up
in the '70s.
Developers tried to
renovate it but quit.
But the place was known for
its blue glass ceiling
and wall tiles.
They were meant
to resemble the ocean.
Which I would assume
came pouring down
during the aborted renovations.
The reason why this
place was abandoned
was because of
its lousy location.
The Alphabets.
♪ ♪
Strings.
Now we know how he makes them.
These, too.
Looks like we
found his workshop.
Now, where is he?
(sirens approaching)
(thumping sound)
No! (screams)
(screaming, whimpering)
It's okay.
We're the police.
We're here to help you.
The girls...
the girls...
What girls?
There's others.
He has them.
Where?
The room...
the room
where he does
things to them,
to us...
Where?
I... I...
Where is the room?
Uh... there.
I'm gonna
go find them.
All right, I'm gonna
stay here with her.
Uh, Dispatch, this is
Charlie-0-5-Sanders.
I need immediate
medical to my location.
Are you really
the police?
Yes.
And don't worry,
I'm not going to leave you.
Okay?
Oh...
I'm so cold.
(shuddering)
Please.
Okay, just let me
find something.
Uh...
All right, uh, here.
Just take this...
(yelling)
(groaning)
(panting)
Don't!
No, please.
You don't understand.
I'm here to save you.
No, you're not!
FINLAY: Yes, he is.
We both are.
Then why are you
pointing a gun at me?
Why don't we both
put our guns down?
And we can talk about how
we're gonna get you out of here.
MITCHELL:
Charlie-0-5-Sanders, respond.
It's just my police radio.
When it fell on its side,
it sent out an alert.
You're lying.
You're trying to trick me.
No, he's not.
We're here to help you.
Charlie-0-5-Sanders, respond.
You have to let me answer that.
Because if you don't
and they come in here
and see you pointing a gun...
They're gonna kill me!
I won't let that happen.
But you need to let me
answer that now.
Charlie-0-5-Sanders, talk to me!
Charlie-0-5-Sanders!
Are you there?
No!
Stop!
(gunshots)
MAN:
CSI Finlay, I need you
to surrender your firearm.
I know the drill.
Yes, you do.
Note: I've received
CSI Finlay's SIG Sauer P-232.
Four live rounds
in the magazine.
One live round
in the chamber.
So...
why don't you just start
from the beginning?
I've been in that room before.
We both have.
Any I.D. on that woman yet?
No.
All we know is that it looks
like she was being
held like Keri.
From what I heard,
Finlay did what
she had to do.
Yeah.
She always does.
(door opens)
Hey.
You okay?
I was trying to help her.
And I keep thinking to myself
maybe I could've said
something different.
Or maybe I could've
done a better job
of making her feel safe.
Greg, it wasn't your fault.
I mean, she was
probably drugged.
God knows what else
was done to her.
When the police found Keri
Torres, she was delusional,
she was aggressive.
I know.
But we were there.
And I could've saved her.
And now she's dead.
How am I supposed
to live with that?
You did the best you could.
You need to know that.
In time, you
will know that.
As far as how you live
with what happened...
I wish I knew the
answer to that.
PHILLIPS:
I could not imagine
what Greg and Finn
are going through.
I.A.'s put a rush
on this evidence.
Let's just hope they
don't rush to judgment.
You sent her DNA to Henry yet?
Yeah. Why?
There's scar tissue
in her pelvic area.
Our victim's undergone surgery.
It's not surprising.
The killer performed surgery
on all of his victims.
Harvesting their tissue
for his strings.
That's not what this is.
What do you mean?
Take a look for yourself.
Colovaginoplasty.
Our she was once a he.
Look, I know you
wanted to see me.
So, let me guess.
Two-week suspension with pay,
pending the outcome of
the I.A. investigation.
No, you're not gonna
be suspended, Jules.
Matter of fact, you're
probably gonna get a medal.
What?
Well, apparently you just
took down the Gig Harbor Killer.
The unknown male DNA
that we recovered
from the bodies
in the desert--
you remember that?
Well, that DNA's a match
to the woman you just shot.
I do not understand.
We still don't know who she is,
but apparently
Doc said that she had
a gender reassignment surgery.
Possibly as long
as a decade ago.
DNA's still XY.
No.
She's got to be another
part of Winthrop's game.
The unknown
male DNA was planted
on those bodies.
That woman
that I shot is
just another victim.
She was kidnapped,
she was used
by Winthrop,
she was drugged
and reduced to a paranoid state.
Just like Keri Torres.
Yeah, and like Keri,
he knew how she'd react
the minute we barged
into that room.
And he is probably
getting off right now
on the idea that I killed
an innocent woman.
We cannot trust the
evidence anymore, D.B.
You know how crazy that sounds?
Do you disagree?
It doesn't matter
whether I agree or not.
If we can't trust
the evidence,
then how are we gonna
stop this guy?
Well, we still have Keri.
She was in that
room being held.
And if we are right,
she will put Winthrop
in there with her.
Maybe.
Morgan says she can
barely remember anything.
She was a cop.
And a good one.
She's gonna remember.
It's just gonna
take a little time.
I'm gonna reach out
to a friend of ours.
Why don't you go back to the
hospital and check in with Keri?
See what you can do.
Hey, it looks like
you're getting some rest.
The doctor should be by
in a few minutes
to get some readings.
You should be
out of here soon.
(gasping)
Sir, you can't be here.
I'm just a friend.
I don't think now
is a good time.
Ms. Torres needs her rest.
That's okay. I can wait.
There's a lounge downstairs.
If you give me your name,
I can have you paged.
That's all right.
I'll-I'll check back.
(laughs): Oh.
D.B., good to see you.
Thanks for doing this.
I know you're a busy lady.
I'm never
too busy for you.
Glad I had that layover.
Did you get the e-mail
files I sent you?
Oh, interesting reading.
I'm always a sucker
for twin serial killers.
Well, given the games
they're playing,
I could really use an expert
in criminal psychology.
Cyber or otherwise.
Well, I can tell you
this much.
As far as killers go,
Winthrop is a profiler's dream.
How so?
His behavior suggests
that he is incapable
of working alone.
Seems he needs
a dominant-submissive
partnership
in order to kill.
Which is why he sought
out his brother.
Jared was easily
manipulated,
easily led.
All the way to prison.
Winthrop let his brother
take the fall.
But, in doing so,
he lost that loving feeling.
Which is why he wants
to spring him now.
He wants
his old partner back.
But in the meantime,
he's a serial killer.
He enjoys killing.
But he needs help.
And we think he found it.
Based on our
audio analysis of
the last crime scene,
we heard somebody
else in that room.
He has an accomplice.
With Jared in prison,
it's more like a temp.
And we both know
temps are never
fully committed to the job.
So, the partner's the key.
The little bit of profiling
I'm doing right now tells me
I'm not telling you anything
you don't already know.
You read the part of the file
where Jared Briscoe stalked
my daughter Maya?
And you put a security detail
outside her house.
Was that a mistake?
No. You have to protect her.
But she is also
your best chance
of catching a man
who is going to kill again.
The greater good.
D.B., if you're
not willing to put Maya
into play in some
kind of a way,
you need to take yourself
out of the equation.
You know what
you're asking me?
The same thing
you're asking yourself.
You've been a bad boy.
Get in.