(dog barks in distance,
bottle clattering)
(siren wails in distance)
(liquid sloshing)
(bottle clattering)
(man chuckling evilly)
(gasps)
Hey, old man.
What the hell
are you doing in my alley?
This... this isn't your alley.
What, you trying to tell
me that it's yours?
Why are you doing this?
THUG 2:
I'm just trying
to have some fun.
Ain't you having fun?
(others laughing)
(grunting)
Please, just let me be, please.
Is that the best you got?
(cries out)
(grunts, sobs)
(whimpers)
MAN:
Leave him alone!
Who's there?
Get that damn light
out of my eyes.
MAN:
You want to pick on someone?
Why don't
you pick on
someone who can
fight back?
I said, turn off
that damn light.
Forget it, man.
Who the hell are you?
I'm a guy who's sick of you
trashing this neighborhood.
THUG:
Well, if you're gonna
do something about it,
why don't you hurry up
and do it?
(crackling)
Let's go.
(whimpering)
(indistinct shouting)
(siren wails)
Thank you.
Morning.
MITCHELL: Morning.
STOKES:
What's going on, Mitch?
MITCHELL:
One of the owners
who backs on the alley
was taking out trash
this morning.
He made the find.
Oof.
Somebody worked him over
pretty good.
Judging by his knuckles,
I'd say he got a few shots in.
SIDLE:
Eh.
Ground is sticky over here,
probably thanks
to this Dumpster.
But it's given us
a lot of shoe impressions.
Looking at the number,
I'd say more
than one assailant.
Well, Mitch did say
there was a gang
terrorizing
the neighborhood lately.
Mostly vandalism
and burglaries,
but maybe they stepped up
their game to murder.
Nice get-up.
Is that a cape?
That's a costume of some sort.
And, of course,
no costume
would be complete
without a mask.
SIDLE:
Maybe he was one of those
sidewalk characters
over on the Strip.
They dress up like superheroes
and panhandle for money.
Yeah, and was walking home
and just got jumped?
Sara.
SIDLE:
Mmm?
One of my guys
found this in a doorway
up the street.
No ID.
Looks like it's
been rifled through.
Got some street
clothes...
and a sketch pad.
Uh...
Nick?
STOKES:
Yeah.
Take a look at these.
STOKES:
Comic drawings
of a superhero.
That's this superhero.
Battling a gang.
It's a little weirdly
prophetic, isn't it?
Like he knew
he was gonna
come up against
these guys.
Like he knew the future.
Too bad for him,
the hero only wins
in comic books.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
Hey, uh, quite a
collection of lifts.
SIDLE: Yeah, looks like
at least five or six
different individuals,
plus the victim.
And a bare foot?
What's with that?
I don't know,
but he was definitely
part of the mix somehow.
What do you got?
I think these are
the victim's superpowers.
One stun gun, spent,
no charge left,
and a pepper spray...
(rattling)
...also empty.
PHILLIPS: Hey, Nick.
Got a minute?
What's up, Super Dave?
Well, I'm gonna
say time of death
was between midnight
and 3:00 a.m.
Multiple bruises and contusions.
Several lacerations.
I can't hazard a guess
to say which ultimately
killed him, though.
Find any ID?
No. Nothing.
Leave it to a superhero
to keep his identity a mystery.
MAN:
Can I get my cart, please?
Can I get my cart?
OFFICER:
I said, be patient, okay?
Please.
Mmm. Mmm.
Mmm. Mmm, mmm, mmm.
How's your sandwich, Roger?
Oh...
Good, yes.
Thanks.
You said size 11.
They're not entirely new.
They're from our lost-and-found,
but they're something.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
They're, uh...
not entirely free,
though, either.
I need to know
what happened in
the alley last night.
You were there,
weren't you?
Some guy...
who looked like Batman...
...he saved me.
How did he save you, exactly?
I was,
uh, rummaging.
All of a sudden,
I'm surrounded by these, um...
villains.
And they start shoving
and hitting me.
What did these villains
look like?
Never saw them.
They-they covered their faces.
But they
wanted to hurt me.
Badly.
That's when the guy
in the mask appeared,
in a ball of light.
I see.
What happened next?
I don't... I don't know.
I left. I took off.
You didn't see their faces.
You didn't see what happened.
Did you see anything at all
that-that might help us?
Find the villains, I mean.
A truck.
A red pickup.
Um, parked in the alley.
RUSSELL:
How's it going?
Any luck?
Some.
I was able to identify
two of the boots
that made these
impressions.
Unfortunately,
they're all common work boots,
sold at dozens of retailers
and online.
But we may have some luck
in a different way.
Take a
close look.
RUSSELL: There are granules
stuck in the gel.
Almost like... coffee grounds.
Sara said that the ground
around the crime scene was...
was sticky.
Maybe the tackiness
pulled whatever this is
off of this guy's shoes.
Not just his.
Almost all of these have
the exact same trace on them.
I already pulled
a sample and gave it
to Hodges for analysis.
Hey, Russell,
you should, uh, see this.
It's, uh, security footage
from a pawnshop on Wallace.
Just a few blocks
from the murder.
Wow, they don't waste any time.
That's from
a little after 11:00.
Only an hour or so
before the murder.
Looks like this gang
had a busy night.
FINLAY: The owner already
started cleaning up inside.
So I told him
not to touch anything
until we're finished.
SANDERS:
Well, according to Akers,
this is the second time
these guys have hit this place.
They did the same thing
to a beauty supply store
a block down, a
couple nights ago.
So they're targeting
the same area.
Gotta be local.
Maybe a gang
of neighborhood kids
out wilding?
Wilding... now killing.
Got any shoe impressions?
SANDERS:
Working on it.
FINLAY:
What is that powder?
Oh, the, uh, display
has fluorescent lights.
And the inside of the tubes
is coated with
this phosphor powder.
When the tube breaks,
the powder gets everywhere.
FINLAY:
Any point in, uh...
dusting for prints?
Not sure.
Video was pretty grainy,
but it looked like
they were wearing gloves.
Besides, they took almost
everything they touched.
Maybe we don't need any prints.
I got blood.
"I wear a mask.
"And that mask,
it's not to hide who I am,
but to create what I am."
I give up.
Are-are you
quoting Sun Tzu?
Uh, no, no, no.
A different warrior.
Batman. Volume one.
Number 624.
What're you doing?
Oh, I'm just trying
to see your feet.
The last Batman fan I met
was shoeless
and lives in an alley.
You know,
I never
pegged you
for a comic book nerd.
My early teens,
every dime I had
went to comic books.
I guess I just don't
get it. You know?
My childhood, fantasy
was never my escape.
I lost myself
in science and numbers.
That's all I needed, I guess.
Well, you liked things
that were clear and proven.
Right or wrong.
Black or white.
Maybe.
This is the closest
that I've come
to the comic book world,
and it's ample enough.
HODGES:
Do you realize
how long walnuts have been
around as a food source?
Archeologists in
Southern France
found evidence of
roasted walnut shells
dating back
to the Neolithic period.
That's 8,000 years ago.
(shell cracks)
Wow.
I did not know that.
Thank you very much.
And you're telling us
this because...?
HODGES:
Well, because
the trace evidence
collected at the scene,
the granules on
the suspects' shoes...
it's ground walnut shell.
Now, it's not as exotic
as it sounds.
It's commonly used
as reptile bedding,
if you raise
reptiles.
They're also used as exfoliants
in soaps and scrubs.
So it's common stuff.
Not gonna help us
very much now, right?
Not necessarily.
Our samples are unique
in that they are
unusually charred.
They also
contain
a trace of calcium hypochlorite.
I'm still working
to determine why.
Good, good.
Go.
Work.
(clears her throat)
Hey.
(both grunting)
Oh, lord.
I need a revolving door
around here.
Results from the blood
Finlay found at the pawnshop.
Uh, DNA was male.
No direct match in CODIS.
But there was
a familial match to this guy.
Martin Preach.
Three-striker currently residing
at Ely State Prison.
I did some checking.
Mr. Preach has at least one kid.
A 19-year-old son named Trey.
A couple of
petty offenses of his own.
Could be the blood donor.
Was one of his petty
offenses his hair?
Wait a second.
Uh, look at the victim's
comic book drawings.
The gang that the
superhero is fighting.
One of them has
a purple mohawk.
Pow!
Like father, like son,
I guess. Right, Trey?
It's not much of a surprise.
Your dad wasn't exactly around
during your formative
years, was he?
I got a family I can count on.
That's all that matters.
Yeah, you got your boys, right?
Your-your gang?
It's one for all, you know?
Well, I hate to break up
the little party here, Trey,
but you guys are in it
pretty deep this time.
You left DNA on the window
at the pawnshop last night.
As we're sitting here,
our guy is outside matching it
to the sample
that you gave in the hall.
STOKES:
You ain't a juvie no more, man,
and this is far
from your first offense.
So... I suggest you smarten up.
SIDLE:
The D.A.'s gonna want
your whole crew.
All of them, all right?
You give us the names
and a serious statement,
and this murder does not
have to be all on you.
Hold on. What murder?
The guy you beat to death
in the alley
off Grant last night.
That murder.
I don't know nothing about that.
You don't know
nothing about this?
Wait a minute.
This dude?
He's the one that's dead?
I've seen this freak around.
He wears a mask
or something, right?
Uh-huh.
Yeah, I see him sometimes
when I cruise at night.
Sad damn freak.
But I didn't kill him though.
I didn't touch him.
Just heard from Nick.
Trey Preach
and his purple hair
deny any involvement
with the murder.
No shocker, I guess.
No, shocker would've been
if he didn't deny it.
Well...
no problem holding him.
The guy's a lock
for the smash and grab
at the pawnshop.
The problem is
that may be the only thing
that he's a lock for.
What do you mean?
So, the shoe prints
from the pawnshop
don't match the shoe
prints from the alley.
You sure about that?
Unless these guys went
home and changed shoes
in between crimes,
we're looking at
different gangs.
Two gangs working
the same neighborhood?
And what about
the comic book drawings?
No, no, no.
There-there can't be
that many guys out there
with purple mohawks.
Don't we know somebody that-that
saw the gang in the alley?
The homeless guy, Roger.
But he said he didn't
remember seeing any faces.
That's what he said,
but let-let's find him.
Show him a picture
of Trey and his purple hair.
Maybe he saw
more than he realized.
Maybe he decided it was
too high crime an area,
and picked up and moved out
You know what?
I'm gonna go back
to the other side,
have one more look.
Then we should check the
alley north of Grant.
Okay.
(thudding)
Roger?
We just want to talk to you.
Hey!
Hey, who's there?!
(movement nearby)
Hey! Hey!
What the hell?
Who are you?
Hey! Okay!
I'm with the LVPD Crime Lab.
I need you to step back.
Just stay back!
(gun clicks)
Unless you're faster
than a speeding bullet,
you better do what she said.
BRODY: Why were you
in the alley?
We got every right to be there.
We haven't done anything wrong.
SANDERS:
All right, for starters,
how about you take
off your masks?
Unless you have
something to hide.
We're not hiding anything.
We're just protecting ourselves.
Anonymity is vital to our work.
To what we do.
Which is what exactly?
We fight crime.
We patrol
the streets at night.
We do whatever we got to do
to make it tougher on the pimps
and the drug dealers
and whatever
other criminals we find.
BRODY:
Okay, we're
on the same side here.
The guy who was beaten
in this alley last night?
Judging from his costume,
I'm guessing he was
a friend of yours?
Dominion was beaten?
By who?
Where is he?
He's dead.
You didn't know?
How did it happen?
Well, we're working
to figure it out.
And it would help
if you could tell us
when was the last
time you saw him?
Dominion didn't show up
for patrol last night, so
when he didn't
show up again tonight,
we decided to go
looking for him and
that's when we saw
you two entering the alley.
What was Dominion's real name?
Your friend is lying
in a morgue.
An unclaimed John Doe
with a toe tag.
Tell us his name so we can
at least notify his family.
Brad Jeffries.
All Brad ever wanted to do
was help people.
I know it sounds trite, but...
ever since he was ten,
right after his father died,
he became obsessed with...
fairness.
He insisted that
everything had be fair.
That's when he got lost
in the comic book world
and this online role-playing.
How long had he
been doing this?
Dressing up and going
on, uh, patrol
with his friends?
The real-life
superhero movement?
That's what they call it.
Uh, they've been doing it
for probably ten months now.
Did he ever mention any problems
or run-ins they might've had?
Any enemies
they could've made?
He would've knew better
than to talk to us about it.
It would only worry me
that much more.
And it only aggravated Seth.
You weren't a fan
of what he was doing?
I was afraid of exactly this.
I mean, I war... I warned him
I don't know how many times
that they were playing
a dangerous game.
It's not comic book
land out there.
It's the real world.
People have guns and knives.
He said it was his calling.
That it gave meaning
to his life.
How can you argue with that?
No, I understand. Um...
his two partners--
Tina and Scott?
How-how well
do you know them?
Well.
They're here all the time.
They hang out
in the basement.
They were his best friends.
They would never
have anything to do
with his death if that's
what you're thinking.
So, Brad's mom
doesn't have a problem
with you guys setting up
in her basement?
TINA:
I mean, Brad was
the one who brought
the three of us together.
You know? Like, inspired us.
He got me believing I could
actually make a difference.
And change
the world, you know?
But why like this?
The masks, costumes?
Well, we have
our reasons.
For me?
I was a victim once.
Just a 17-year-old girl,
riding the bus late at night.
Yeah, I was never a victim.
But I was into some pretty
dark stuff in the past.
Hurt people.
What I do now,
it's my way to pay it back.
It's my redemption.
But you're not police officers.
You don't have police training.
You don't have the power
to even arrest anybody.
What you're doing is
borderline unlawful.
You know that, right?
So, what do we do?
We-we leave it up to the cops?
Is that it?
Well, there's an idea, yeah.
Cops go where the money is.
The casinos, the tourists.
We aren't exactly
a priority.
So, that's why we do what we do.
Come here and take
a look at this.
Tell me about the gang
this superhero's fighting.
SCOTT:
Yeah, we call them
The Disciples.
They've been running wild around
this area for about a month now.
They're sort of
our nemesis.
TINA:
The drawing was Brad's version
of what would happen
if he found them.
These are the rest
of Brad's drawings over here?
Yeah.
What's this one about?
SCOTT:
Just some guy
we ran into one night. Why?
Witnesses saw a red
pickup truck last night
around the time
Brad was murdered.
What can you tell me about it?
TINA:
Guy was arguing with a hooker.
Shoved her down.
So we intervened.
When he tried to bail,
Brad smashed the fender
of his truck.
Know anything about the driver?
Have you seen him
before or since then?
No. Just that night.
Okay. That's it?
Yeah, that's it.
Hey.
Hey!
You know, I had no idea
this was actually a thing--
this whole, real-life
superhero movement.
More than just our trio,
you mean?
Way more. I have found
hundreds of people
across the country,
who like to dress
in superhero costumes
and go out in their
neighborhoods, mostly
it seems
with altruistic motives.
I'm all
for making a difference,
but the whole
dress up part just seems so...
What's the word
I'm looking for?
HODGES:
Hello, ladies.
I bring news
on our walnut shells.
Now, you remember that I said
they were unique?
You said they
were charred, right?
And also that they'd been
exposed to calcium hypochlorite.
And all that
just might equal...
Sundip Pool Supply.
Might equal, how?
Turns out,
ground walnut shell
is also used by sandblasters
to clean pool tile.
They spray it
instead of sand
because the shells don't
scratch the tile.
And how does that get
us to this Sundip place?
The charring
and the chemical trace.
Sundip Pool Supply had a huge
fire about three weeks ago.
It's the only logical source
I can think of
that matches
our specific samples.
Thanks, Hodges,
I'll check it out.
Hey, Doc.
Long day for you.
Long and busy with some
very interesting findings,
particularly in the case
of your victim.
Really? What
have you got?
Well, as you can see
in his injuries here,
there's a lot of bruising
and swelling
as well as areas
of bleeding.
All of this is consistent
with a non-lethal beating.
Non-lethal?
And yet he's dead.
Thanks to a single blow
that landed just here
at the base of the skull.
The victim was struck once
with significant force,
effectively transecting
the brain stem
in the area
of the medulla oblongata.
Okay, so maybe
during the beating,
one of the suspects
gets carried away,
hits the victim in the
base of the skull,
and kills him.
But herein lies
the conundrum.
All this bruising and swelling
you see took time.
At least 60 minutes
for the body to respond
to injuries
of this degree.
The brain stem injury,
however, was instantly fatal.
Instantly?
Like switching off
a light.
So the blow
that killed him
was delivered 60 minutes
after the beating.
That means that
Brad Jeffries was beaten up
and left in the alley
for at least an hour.
According to Doc,
probably unconscious.
So somebody had
to come back,
maybe a gang member
or someone entirely different,
hit him in the back
of the head,
and killed him.
Does Doc have any thoughts
about the murder weapon?
Said it could be something
like a baseball bat or a club.
But here you can see
these bands on his neck.
Wait a second.
Nick just came back with
some more comic book drawings
from our superheroes.
Check out the weapon
in that hero's hands.
SANDERS:
It's a club with metal bands.
Right, so maybe our victim
was killed with his own weapon.
SANDERS: Well, there was
nothing like this recovered
at the crime scene, so
the killer must have taken it.
All right, so he either still
has it, or he ditched it.
There are a lot of Dumpsters
in those alleys.
Let's get LVPD to check
the area completely, okay?
Hey, looks like that
ground walnut shell trace
might have paid off.
Thanks to Hodges, I
went and checked out
this place called
Sundip Pool Supply.
Their place is all
fenced and boarded up,
but I got a security
guard to let me in.
There was charred walnut
shell, just like ours,
all over the place.
So our gang must've been there
at some point
before they went to the alley.
Guard said that the only
people working there right now
are the
demolition crew,
Company name is Agrerro
Demo and Hauling.
They are in
there every day,
and this is
the kicker,
the crew's foreman,
Tony Agrerro,
he drives a red
pickup truck.
STOKES:
Okay, boys.
This is the guy
we're looking for right here,
Tony Agrerro.
You're sure he's here?
Well, he better be,
that's his red pickup truck
right there.
Let's go.
Yeah.
There's the dent right there.
Hey, Nick.
Ground walnut shells.
Same as on the boots
from the alley.
(rhythmic beeping)
Do you hear that?
(rhythmic beeping continues)
It's still warm.
He's got to be
around here.
Keys are still
in the ignition.
Oh, Nick.
(beeping stops)
Lot of blood.
Whoa.
Mitchell, over here!
Well, we found him.
Looks like somebody
had an accident.
If this was an accident,
I'm Superman.
Hey, Nick.
STOKES:
Yeah?
There are tool marks
on one of these pulleys.
Looks like somebody
intentionally
jammed the
winch cable.
Yeah, they probably knew
the victim would crawl
into the gap
to fix it.
Yeah, and then once he was
in there, pulled the lever,
and squish.
Victim has a couple
nasty bruises on his face.
Yeah, yeah,
I saw those.
Looks like he got
into a fistfight.
How old do you think
those bruises are, David?
Recent.
I don't know-- 24,
48 hours maybe?
That times out perfectly
for the brawl in the alley,
so maybe our dead superhero
really did get some licks in
before they took
him down.
All right, so we've got
a red pickup truck,
walnut shells, we
have bruises now,
so Tony Agrerro here was
definitely a part of the gang
that beat up Brad Jeffries.
Yeah, I think so,
and then used his coworkers
as the rest
of the crew.
Well, that'll give us
the alley gang,
but it's not gonna tell us
who actually went back
to commit the murder.
Guys, there are some interesting
scratches on this truck.
(camera shutter clicking
Are they fresh?
They didn't have
time to rust.
Weren't the other two
superheroes...
were they wearing
spiked armbands?
Who, Scott and Tina?
Yeah.
Yeah, they were.
So, uh, maybe
they did this.
Case of revenge.
Time of death, David?
I'm gonna put T.O.D.
at around midnight last night,
more or less.
Midnight.
You know,
that's not too long
after I talked
to those two knuckleheads
about that red
pickup truck.
You lied, Tina.
You and Scott.
Huh? Wh-What are
you talking about?
Last night when
CSI Stokes was here,
he told you
about a red pickup
that had been spotted
near where Brad was killed.
Yeah. So what?
So when he asked you about
the driver, you said that
you didn't know anything,
but you did know. You knew
the driver was Tony Agrerro--
his name's right on the side
of the truck.
Okay, so maybe we didn't
tell CSI-- what, Stokes?--
everything,
but, you know,
obviously, you found
your way to Tony Agrerro.
Not before you got to him first.
Wait, got to him first?
What do you mean?
Tony Agrerro is dead,
Tina, and we
found evidence
that at least one of you
was there.
What?
W-Wait. No.
That's not what
we're about.
Okay? Th-The real-life
superhero movement is about...
asserting a positive influence.
It's about...
improving the neighborhood.
You want to improve
your neighborhood?
Go help in a shelter.
Get involved
with at-risk kids.
The game that you are playing
is dangerous, and now
two people are dead
because of it.
Where were you last night
around midnight?
I was here, with Brad's mom.
We stayed up all night talking.
I mean, Brad meant
everything to her.
All right, she's devastated.
I couldn't just leave her.
What about Scott?
Was he with you?
No. Uh...
I have...
I have no idea
where Scott was.
You need to tell me
where to find Scott, Tina.
No games this time.
RUSSELL:
What am I looking at here?
Tony Agrerro's
trash-hauling crew.
And shoe impressions confirm
what we already figured:
they're also his gang
from the alley.
LVPD rounded them up.
Morgan and I offered a deal
to the first one to talk.
We got four takers.
Their stories line up?
All of them told
the same tale.
Agreed to beating up
Brad Jeffries in the alley.
(sighs):
Anybody say why?
Because their boss
told them to.
Right. Agrerro had
that score to settle
with the superheroes
over the hooker
and the damage to his truck.
Somehow they knew Jeffries
would be walking home from work.
They also knew that he
couldn't resist playing hero.
So the tussle
with the homeless guy
was just a lure
to get Jeffries
into the alley.
And Jeffries
took the bait.
But... they left him alive
after the beating.
They were all big
on pressing that point.
Right. Well, we knew that.
I mean, he was alive for
at least an hour later,
until one or maybe more of them
came back and killed him.
Question is,
who and why?
Well, here's a thought.
According to all of them,
Agrerro's mask came off
during the fight...
(grunting)
Come on!
How does it feel
to be a hero?
...and Jeffries recognized him.
Well, there's a motive for you.
After the beating,
everybody leaves,
Tony starts thinking,
Tony starts worrying.
Exactly.
He knows that
if the victim I.D.'s him,
he could face serious
prison time on the assault.
RUSSELL:
So an hour later,
everybody's gone.
Agrerro goes back to the alley
and kills Jeffries.
(grunts)
And then Agrerro
is killed by the...
the superhero
out of revenge.
MORGAN:
Only problem is...
(sighs)
Tony Agrerro never went
back to the alley.
You sure about that?
After beating up Jeffries, they
all went to nurse their wounds
at a local dive bar.
I talked
to the bartender.
Swears all five of them
stayed there until close.
Agrerro ran a tab
and he never left.
SANDERS:
Well, if that's true,
then none of them
could have killed Brad Jeffries.
STOKES:
Scott...
I've been
checking on you.
You have quite a rap sheet.
Congratulations.
Almost every
charge in here
involves you beating the
crap out of somebody.
That's before I had a cause.
You know?
Something to believe in.
This superhero thing?
Yeah.
You want to know what
I think about that?
I think the mask and the
cape are just an excuse
for you to go out
and pound heads.
You've always been a thug,
only now you do it in a cape.
And you tell
yourself it's okay
because your victims
are bad guys.
(softly):
No, man.
You got me all wrong,
I'm telling you.
Tony Agrerro
deserved to die,
am I right?
He killed your best friend,
so you did what any noble
superhero would do-- you avenged
your best friend's death.
Only this time,
Scott...
that's not being a hero
right there, man,
that's being a vigilante.
I... I don't know what
you're talking about, man.
I didn't have anything
to do with that.
You weren't there last night?
You weren't
at the yard?
No. Nowhere near it.
Then explain how scratches
ended up on a truck
that perfectly match
those bad-ass superhero
bracelets of yours.
And then maybe
you can explain to me
how Tony Agrerro's blood
ended up on your boot.
All right, I... I was there.
But he was dead
when I found him.
I didn't have anything
to do with this, I swear.
So you were lying before, but
you're telling me the truth now?
I went looking for him.
All right? The place was dark.
I heard a truck engine running.
I went to go
check it out.
When I got there,
he was laying there, dead.
I reached in to check his pulse.
That's probably how my arm band
scratched the truck.
Scott,
if you're gonna lie to me, at
least get your facts straight.
Okay? The keys
were in the truck,
the engine wasn't running.
You want to try again?
No.
What I want is a lawyer.
Now.
Hey. How's it
going in there?
It's not.
He lawyered up.
Wow, that was fast.
Nick got him to admit
to being at the scene
at the time
of the murder.
It seemed like he was
on the brink of confessing
and then he just got smart.
You know, the stupid thing is,
if this was about avenging
the death of his friend,
he killed the wrong guy.
What do you mean?
Tony Agrerro and his crew
alibied out for the murder
in the alley.
Morgan put them
in a neighborhood bar
at the time.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Then who killed
our dead superhero?
That is still the question.
Hey. One of our officers
just brought this in.
Matches the description of the
weapon you're looking for.
Where'd he
find it?
The guy was
threatening some tourist
with it, outside the Palermo.
I guess they wouldn't
acknowledge him as
the one, true Batman.
Hi, Roger.
(door closes)
Do you remember me?
You gave me my shoes.
I need you to tell me
about that club
that you were carrying.
The club is the source.
The club gives me power.
I am invincible with the club!
Where did you
get the club?
I... found it.
You found it where?
In the alley?
The one that we were
in the other night?
No.
A different place.
Uh, in a Dumpster.
Roger,
that club belonged to someone.
The man that
saved you.
You said he
looked like Batman.
You remember?
I think that you were there,
in the alley,
after the fight,
after the man with the cape
and the mask was hurt.
That's where you found
the club, isn't it?
No. I told you.
The club is mine.
What happened, Roger?
Did he wake up?
Did he startle you, scare you?
Is that why
you hit him?
Roger, I need to know
exactly what happened.
The truth.
The club's not his.
The club is mine!
I found it.
In a Dumpster.
I don't know which one.
There are so many.
Give me something then.
So I can check
your story.
A golden star.
What do you mean, a golden star?
That's it.
A golden star.
Russell.
Yeah.
I think we just went from
one unsolved murder back to two.
I just read
Doc Robbins'
autopsy report on Tony Agrerro.
Now, the cause of death,
that's not a surprise--
that dude was crushed.
It's the time of death
that's a little off.
What do you mean, a little off?
According to Dave,
it was around midnight,
but according to Doc,
it was much earlier.
Maybe as much
as 18 hours earlier.
Whoa.
Which
means our
other superhero, Scott Hunt,
he doesn't work as the killer.
He alibis out.
So he was telling the truth
when he said
he got to the yard
and Agrerro was already dead.
How could David
have been so far off
with his estimate?
I don't think it
was his fault.
It was that truck engine.
It really was running.
Killer must've left it
that way after the murder.
But that engine would've
kept that dead body warm though.
Throwing off
David's calculations
when he did the liver stick.
Okay, so new time
of death.
That would put Agrerro's murder
just a little bit
after Brad Jeffries was killed
in the alley,
right? Probably
first thing in the morning.
So what do you think?
Maybe we have two bodies
but just one killer.
And zero idea who it is.
I have
good news
on our murder weapon,
particularly if you're a
fan of Ethiopian cuisine.
There was butter on the club,
infused with a host
of exotic spices:
fenugreek, cumin,
coriander, turmeric, cardamom,
cinnamon and nutmeg.
A concoction more simply known
as tesmi,
common in Ethiopian cooking.
I did a quick check
and found an Ethiopian
restaurant just five blocks
from the alley
where the victim was found.
(siren wailing in distance)
Well, there's our golden star.
STOKES:
So maybe old Roger was telling
the truth about the club.
Yeah.
It's empty.
Well, if the killer
dumped the club in there,
he figured
he'd never see it again,
'cause it'd be hauled away
with the trash, along
with any piece of evidence that
might've been along with it.
Oh, Nick.
Look at that.
(Stokes laughs softly)
Say "cheese."
RUSSELL:
Clearly, this is you, Seth,
ditching the murder weapon only
minutes after Brad was killed.
We also have
your phone records,
yours
and Agrerro's.
Looks like you and he
spoke several times,
before and right after
Brad was beaten in the alley.
Seth, you need
to talk to us, man.
Y-You know
what the jury's gonna think
when they see this?
They're gonna think
you're a monster.
You're not a monster.
I was just trying
to teach him a lesson.
23 years old,
living at home,
dressing up in a costume.
I-I thought I could scare him,
make him stop.
By having Tony Agrerro
and his guys
beat him up?
Y-You
had warned him that...
it was dangerous out there, and
this was gonna make your point.
It wasn't even that planned.
Oh.
I-I met Agrerro by chance
at a neighborhood bar.
I was bitching to the
bartender about Brad
and his friends,
the-the whole superhero thing.
And Agrerro overheard me.
He came over, pissed off.
Because Brad
dented his truck.
And-and now he expected me
to pay the repairs.
Said I owed him 700 bucks.
I-I joked that
I'd give him
$1,000 if he and his guys
would...
rough Brad up.
So it was a joke.
I mean,
at first.
After a few drinks, it started
to sound like a good idea.
RUSSELL:
Let's talk
about how we got here, okay?
H-How did this night happen?
Tony called
and said that he had done
like we talked about,
that they-they beat him up.
And I waited for
Brad to come home,
e-expecting him
to call it quits.
But an hour passed,
he didn't show up.
So I went out looking for him.
I found him in that alley,
knocked out.
He was just coming to.
Brad.
Seth.
What are you doing here?
Your mom's worried.
I came looking for you.
This is exactly what I warned
you about. Come on, Brad.
Let's go home.
But to be honest,
I felt bad for him.
I mean, not my kid
but-but I still cared.
But I messed up. I gu...
I guess I said something
about him being jumped
by a gang.
How did you know that it was
a gang that beat me up?
I didn't...
I didn't
say anything about a gang.
Brad, come on.
You've been talking
about a gang for weeks now.
You've never come looking
for me.
And now you know exactly
where to find me?
You son of a bitch.
You did this,
didn't you?
You set me up.
Okay,
come on, Brad. Calm down...
No, don't touch me!
I will get home on my own.
And when I do, I'm
telling her what you did,
and your ass is gonna be out
of our house for good.
No, no. You can't do that.
Screw you, Seth.
She's better off without you.
No!
It was just an impulse,
a stupid mistake.
The club was in my hand...
Seth,
we get it.
You're not a killer.
No, I'm really not.
Yeah, but...
wh-why don't you
tell me about Tony.
Tell me how that happened, Seth.
I went to pay Tony
the next morning.
He must've heard
about Brad being dead.
He thought
that he could blackmail me.
So when he was
on a call, I...
jammed the winch cable
on his truck.
I knew he'd have to crawl
in there to fix it.
It was just a matter
of throwing a lever.
RUSSELL:
Okay.
So... the first killing
was an impulse.
The second killing
was about money.
Why don't you tell us again
how you're not a killer, Seth.
There you are.
Good work on this
one, by the way.
Thanks. It was, uh,
good work all around.
Got a little, uh... a little
something for you here.
What's this?
Take a look.
Oh. (chuckles)
Comic books.
Yep.
I went through my collection.
I put together a little
"greatest hits"
bag for you. I also
plain-wrapped it so I wouldn't
blow your cover around here.
My cover?
Yeah.
You know,
as the hard science
and numbers person
who has no time
for fantasy.
I actually don't have time
See,
that's wrong. Everybody needs
a little fantasy.
It's a lot of pressure,
you know?
What if I don't like them?
Don't tell me.
Hey, Russell.
Thank you.
Yeah. You're welcome.