Previously on CSI:
FINLAY: Jared Briscoe,
the Gig Harbor Killer.
Murdered seven women.
TURNER: A man's been
wrongfully imprisoned.
SHAW: Who knew that psychopath
Briscoe had a twin?
RUSSELL: Do you think the
brothers were working together?
My brother Jared
is going to have
a new day in court.
We're investigating
the disappearance
of my partner, Keri Torres.
RUSSELL: Maya.
When I was little,
you always made me feel so safe.
RYAN: D.B., if you're
not willing to put Maya
into play in
some kind of a way...
The greater good.
Keri's gonna make it.
NURSE:
Sir, you can't be here.
You've been a bad boy.
Get in.
(muffled breathing)
Hello, Maya.
It's been a long time--
remember me?
Please, don't.
Shh.
My brother once taught me--
a long time ago-- he said,
"If you love someone...
...set them free."
Aah!
I could never
hurt you.
I love you.
Aren't you gonna run, hmm?
(kissing)
(whimpering)
Come on. Yeah, like that.
Oh!
(cackling)
You're so beautiful like this.
I can do this all night.
Oh!
No, no, no, no, you
don't want to do that.
(screams)
(gasps)
MAYA: Look, Dad, I don't want
to argue with you about this.
I just want to go home.
Back to Seattle.
Hey, come on, we've
talked about this before, honey.
With everything
that's going on--
Gig Harbor all over again.
Look, you said yourself
you don't feel safe.
Well, it's easier for me
to keep you safe here.
I know what I said,
but that's because
I was alone and scared.
But Ryan's getting back
from London, and
Katie's coming home
from his folks' ranch.
Dad, I appreciate
everything you've done.
OFFICER:
Control, One-David-42,
all clear.
CONTROL:
Roger that, David-42.
I know you just
want to protect me, but...
I've got to get back to my life.
All right, I'm sorry,
you're right, you're right.
It's what fathers do:
We worry, right?
And I love you for it.
I booked a flight.
Tonight.
I have a taxi picking me up.
No, no, I'll drive you
there myself.
But you said you have
that meeting with the sheriff.
Dad, it's fine.
All right, okay,
but no-no... no taxis.
I'll, um... I'll have
Detective Crawford pick you up.
No arguments. You hear me?
I hear you.
I love you, Dad.
I love you, too.
MAYA:
I'll call you from Seattle.
RUSSELL:
No, no, no, hey--
you will call me
when you get
to the airport here,
and then you will call me
from Seattle.
MAYA:
Okay, now you need to stop
being a worrywart.
RUSSELL:
Not gonna happen.
MAYA:
Bye.
RUSSELL:
It's happening tonight.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
(knocking)
Thank you.
Yeah.
You look good, Jared.
Today's the big day.
I don't understand...
any of this.
The judge reviewed
the evidence.
Nothing ties you
forensically to the murders.
He's thrown out your confession.
You're gonna be a free man.
You're not
listening to me.
Why am I here?
Jared, you listen to me.
This was not the plan.
You said, if I make a
sacrifice, in return,
I would live forever.
Ah, yeah.
Plans change.
Why?
I need you.
You need me.
Don't you miss what we had?
Of course I do.
So I say we can have it again.
And this time, I promise you,
it'll be so much better.
And why should I trust you?
How can you say that?
Look at me. Look in my eyes.
My eyes are
your eyes.
My heart is your heart.
When is it happening?
If all goes according
to plan, you'll be
a free man in a few hours.
And we'll celebrate.
In Vegas.
I'll even have
a little gift for you.
Something you've been dreaming
about for a very long time.
I stand before you today
a man fulfilled.
A man whose prayers
have been answered.
Because today, after four
long years of incarceration,
my brother Jared Briscoe
is a free man.
But Jared will not truly be free
until those who have
wrongfully imprisoned him
are brought to account, and
I will not rest
until I've made them pay.
(reporters clamoring)
(TV clicks off)
I don't believe this.
I heard Winthrop's
gonna sue Seattle PD.
I'm waiting to be served
myself, any day.
D.B., we cannot
let this stand.
What are we gonna do?
We're dead in the water here.
Keri Torres may be
out of the hospital;
she can't remember a thing
about who kidnapped her.
Hodges is working on something.
That's news to me.
Well, you know how he is.
What does he have?
All he would tell me is
that the strings
from the crime scenes
are starting
to sing to him.
That's very helpful.
Russell.
Yeah?
We're all set.
I'll pick up Maya at 7:00,
take her to the airport.
Thank you.
Maya's leaving?
Yeah, she's, uh,
she's going back home.
Up to Seattle.
CRAWFORD: For what it's worth,
it was a good idea.
Yeah, I got to say
I'm surprised that Winthrop
didn't try to make
a move, though.
I thought that Maya
was down here visiting.
She was.
Wait a minute.
You took Avery Ryan's advice?
Does Maya know that she
was down here as bait?
CRAWFORD: In case
you wanted to know,
we had her under
surveillance 24-7.
I'd hardly call that bait.
Really?
And what would you call it?
The greater good.
(violin playing out of tune)
You cannot be serious.
Never had one lesson.
Shocking.
And this stuff
isn't too pleasant, either.
HODGES: And yet it makes
such beautiful music.
You're replicating the
process that the killer used
to make the strings
for the crime scene.
The process, yes.
The material, no.
Oh, well, so good to know you're
not using real human tissue.
Although I haven't seen
Henry around lately.
(laughs)
Very funny.
You are looking at catgut.
Interesting fact one: Catgut
is used not just to produce
strings for instruments,
but also strings for tennis
rackets as well as sutures.
Interesting fact two: Catgut
isn't cat gut.
It's usually sheep or goat...
Interesting fact three
is the part where
this has something
to do with anything.
String manufacture like this
is extremely hard to do.
At least at the level of
competence shown by our killer.
Meaning what?
Meaning either our
killer was an expert, which
doesn't fit Paul Winthrop's
résumé, or our killer
recruited an expert and forced
that person to do his stringing.
Evidence suggests the latter.
It suggests more than that.
Did the research.
There are half a dozen experts
in the art of string craft
west of the Mississippi.
One of them is in Vegas.
That face look familiar to you?
That's the woman
that the killer
held at The Mizu.
The one that Finlay shot.
Aah! Aah! Di...
She was never I.D.'d. No one
ever reported her missing.
Huh. And now, thanks to this,
we have her address.
Mm-hmm.
You want to go along?
Get a little fresh air?
For you? Yes.
The lock is busted.
Somebody
broke in.
Oh, oh, boy.
You promised me fresh air.
Is that, uh...
Yeah, it's exactly
what you think it is.
All right, wait
here, all right?
Whoa, whoa, hey,
d-don't you need backup?
Don't you
need a gun?
Seriously, just stay here
while I clear the place.
Copy that.
(creaking)
Whew.
The house is clear!
Got a body, though.
Woman.
She's been here
for a while.
(exhales)
Someone enjoys reading
about himself.
Looks like our killer
has been camping out
in Rebecca Lowell's house.
HODGES:
Bad deal for her.
Enslaved to make his strings,
then he squats in her digs.
Any idea
who the dead woman was?
No, but hopefully
we'll get an I.D.
You know, this place seems a
little down-rent for a guy like
Paul Winthrop to squat in.
HODGES:
We have assumed that he's been
working with a partner
since he's been in Vegas, right?
Yeah.
So...
maybe it's more
his style.
Ants.
I hate ants.
(hissing)
How do you feel
about body parts?
(sighs)
MAN:
All units. All units.
We have a 444. Shots fired.
Officer needs assistance.
Corner of Highland and Branch.
Code 3.
Control, this is One-David-42.
Currently two blocks
from that location.
We are responding
but will require backup
at 923 Altos Drive.
(siren wailing)
(knocks)
Hi there. You requested a ride
to the airport?
I-I thought Detective Crawford
was gonna take me.
Yeah, he got called away.
I'm Detective Shaw.
I promise I'm just
as safe a driver.
Don't I know you?
Yeah. I used to work in Seattle
with your dad.
He just thought
a familiar face might make you
feel a little more comfortable.
You're here a little early.
Yeah, I know.
I probably should have called,
but there's a pileup
on the I-15.
Oh. Well, okay.
Um, better safe than sorry.
Can I get your bag?
Mm-hmm.
Hey. Got your text.
You have something on the
bodies Morgan and Hodges found?
Not all of them.
This poor woman
remains unidentified.
But according to DNA,
these body parts
came from Emily Bartson
and Pamela Kramer.
Two missing girls
here in Vegas.
PHILLIPS:
After all these weeks,
we found 'em.
That's not all we found.
Finn, you're gonna want
to see this.
We recovered
partial prints
from Rebecca Lowell's house.
In the kitchen,
in the living room,
in the bedroom. Everywhere.
The prints came back
to Daniel Shaw.
He's been there.
Staying there.
Shaw is Winthrop's partner.
So, you worked with my dad
in Seattle?
That's right.
Then you must know
Julie Finlay, too.
Yeah, I do.
How long you been in Vegas?
Not long.
My dad drag you
down here, like Finn?
Yeah. Yeah, I guess
you might say that.
It's funny. My dad talks
about Finn all the time.
He's never mentioned you.
I guess we're just not as close.
I think, uh,
you missed the turn.
Airport's back
that way.
I'm going another way.
You're not taking me
to the airport, are you?
No.
I don't know, Conrad.
The situation's fluid right now.
Yeah. My house is a crime scene.
They're processing it right now.
And as for Maya,
I have every available unit on.
I know. I know. Thank you.
I hope so, too.
D.B., I heard about Maya.
What happened?
Surveillance team was pulled
off by a false 444 call.
Somebody slipped in before
Crawford could get there.
We found Shaw's fingerprints
at the house with the bodies.
Yeah, well, I'm
not surprised.
What do you mean?
Keep walking with
me for a minute.
MAN:
This is One-David-30.
Crossing Bartlet.
Proceeding northbound.
MAN 2:
One-David-One. Crossing Temple.
We still got a visual
on the suspect vehicle?
Copy that, One-David-Ten.
All units, be advised, suspect
vehicle is continuing north
on Everly Boulevard.
MAYA:
Where are you taking me?
SHAW:
It's probably best
if we don't talk.
MAYA:
We have to talk.
SHAW:
No, we don't.
I can't believe
you let this happen.
Like I said, we had
surveillance 24-7.
For the greater good?
Maya agreed to wear the wire.
She wants to put
these guys away.
For all of those women.
And for herself, too.
She wants to end the nightmares.
Well, you're playing
a very dangerous game.
It's not a game at all.
We know Winthrop's M.O.
Shaw is not going to hurt Maya.
Not at least until
he delivers her to Winthrop.
And we'll have eyes on
the whole time.
Winthrop shows up,
we take 'em out.
Who else knows about this?
Present company, Ecklie,
and Nick and Greg
are in the follow car.
CRAWFORD:
Along with eight support units.
Operation like this,
the fewer people
that know about it,
the better.
STOKES:
Charlie-04-Stokes.
We've got eyes on
and are hanging back.
CRAWFORD:
What are you guys seeing
out there, Nick?
STOKES:
Not much.
Looks like this
guy's just out
for a Sunday drive.
I don't think we've been made.
He hasn't tried to shake us.
Let me talk to you for a sec.
Look, you don't agree
with what I'm doing.
That goes without saying.
Something is
really bothering me.
Tell me. I want to know.
I know what the evidence says,
and I know what this looks like,
but something
is not adding up.
I need to see the evidence
in Rebecca Lowell's house
for myself.
(door opens)
Hey.
Hey, David.
You get an I.D.
on the woman I found in the bed?
No name. Not yet.
But DNA came back.
The dead woman
was Rebecca Lowell's sister.
What was her C.O.D.?
A broken hyoid bone.
Suggests asphyxiation
due to manual strangulation.
That's inconsistent
with our killer's M.O.
So far, in Gig Harbor
and Vegas,
the women were beaten
and stabbed.
Looks like you got
a whole larvae farm there.
I know. And it's weird.
I found two distinct sets
of first instar larvae.
The white are blowflies,
and the brown are beetles.
The beetle and the blowfly
are natural enemies.
And natural enemies
suggests
to me that the eggs weren't laid
at the same time.
Put that together with the fact
that neither insect developed
past first instar,
and I think we're looking
at a sequence of events here.
So you're thinking that
these bodies were moved.
Multiple times.
(buzzing)
Frozen and refrozen.
Blowflies laid their eggs,
the larvae froze to death,
and then in a different place
and time,
the beetles had their chance.
If I can identify these species,
isolate them
to a specific habitat,
it might give us a map
to the killer's movements.
SANDERS:
We just turned onto Corvell.
RUSSELL: Where the hell
is he going?
I don't know.
I don't get it.
All right, hold on.
He's turning down an alley.
The car's stopped.
It's just sitting there.
Why are we stopping here?
Don't run.
He's making a call.
I can't hear anything.
(sighs)
I'm scared, Dad.
I keep thinking...
what would you do?
I know that's what's
gonna get me through this.
(shuddering exhale)
Love you, Dad.
I love you, too.
That person on the other end
of the line,
is that why you're doing this?
What do you want from me?
I just want the truth.
If I'm gonna die,
I think I at least deserve
that much.
You think that's gonna make it
any easier?
(starts engine)
(dog barking in distance)
(floorboard creaks)
(gasps)
Hodges.
What are you doing here?
Well, Morgan told me to stay,
collect evidence.
In the dark?
You ever heard of work lights?
My mentor, Grissom,
taught me to see the scene
as the killer saw it.
That's great.
But I would prefer work lights.
Sorry.
It's not my fault that
these floors are old and creaky.
What are you doing here anyway?
You found Shaw's
prints here, right?
Everywhere.
Everywhere?
On the clippings,
the work table
and the freezer?
Well, no,
not there, exactly.
I just suspect that when
he wasn't lounging around,
he was in serial killer mode
and... wore gloves.
Um, far be it
from me to listen
to office gossip,
but I understand
that you and Shaw were close...
Hodges.
I-I'm sorry.
Boundaries. I get it.
Did you move this table?
Ah, well, my mentor...
The answer would be "no."
Somebody moved the table.
Want to give me a hand?
Sure.
(squeaking)
(creaking)
See what I mean
about the floors?
Look at that.
(camera shutter clicking)
And that is why you're a CSI.
(whirring)
(computer clicking softly)
(computer chirping)
Ran the partials
from the strongbox.
They came back
to our homeowner
and string maker,
Rebecca Lowell.
I don't think
she was just making money
from making strings.
Did you find something
on the flash drive?
Files from an escort service.
Lady Aquarius Escorts,
to be exact.
All of our victims
are involved
in the sex trade,
but we never knew
how they were connected,
or who was pimping them out.
They were all working
for Rebecca Lowell?
File says yes.
Those are the names
of all our victims.
And there's quite
a client list, too.
Lots of prominent men,
including Paul Winthrop.
Talk about a smoking gun.
For solicitation,
not for murder.
Hmm.
I was looking at the receipts.
We are talking a lot of money.
Well, it's not surprising
given the clientele.
What is the
difference between
a client and a friend?
Is it a price point?
I don't know.
I was just getting there.
Those are cops
and judges from Las Vegas
and from Seattle.
Money says bribes,
protection.
Mm-hmm.
Shaw's on the list.
I don't believe it.
Cop on the take.
This connects him to Winthrop.
I have a daughter--
Kaitlyn.
She comes home
from her grandparents' tomorrow.
Your dad taught you well.
How to humanize yourself
in the eyes of a killer.
Do you have kids?
What does it matter?
MAYA:
Do you?
It's not going to work.
Then just tell me this.
Why me?
I know enough
about those other girls
to know that I'm not like them.
You're nothing like them.
Then why?
Is it because of my dad?
It's not just that.
CRAWFORD:
Okay, he's making another turn.
It's like
he keeps going in a circle.
No, he's going back
to the airport.
Winthrop got
his brother released
sometime this afternoon, right?
What time did they fly out
of Seattle?
We have that
information, right?
Winthrop's private jet took off
from Seattle four hours ago.
That means
they've already landed.
Guys, I think this is happening.
The meet's going down
with Winthrop somewhere around
the Executive Terminal
at the airport.
He's going into a garage
under an industrial building.
1017 Parkman Way.
Pull up that location.
That's Winthrop's building.
There's only one way in
and one way out of this garage.
We go in, we're
gonna get made.
What do you want to do?
Let's stick with the plan.
We wait for Winthrop.
What is this place?
Is this where
it's gonna happen?
Quiet.
Just listen.
(classical music playing)
I went to a recital once.
Music like this. Strings.
There was a young girl
playing the violin.
It was beautiful.
She was beautiful.
I couldn't believe that
something so beautiful...
could be mine.
But at the same time,
I knew I didn't deserve her.
'Cause everything I touch,
I destroy.
Because men like me are weak.
Because of that weakness,
they commit crimes.
They commit sins.
Sins for which
there is no going back.
She doesn't say anything.
Why isn't she saying anything?
There-there's
something wrong. Damn it!
Guys, go in now!
All units, converge now!
SHAW:
I want you to understand,
I need you to understand,
I didn't want this.
I didn't ask for this.
I didn't choose this.
The choice was made for me.
Some things are just...
ordained.
I sinned.
I sinned, and now you and I
are both paying...
Son of a bitch played us.
STOKES:
Russell, she's gone.
Nick, what happened?
Shaw pulled Maya's wire
and left it in the car
along with a digital recording
of his voice.
Made it sound like they were
still in there talking.
Any idea how they
got out of there?
No, we're still working on that.
Hey, Nick? Over here.
STOKES:
Hey, I think we just found
Shaw's escape route.
We're checking it out right now.
Keep me posted.
They're long gone.
Well, look around here, man.
There's got to be something.
Hey, here you go, Greg.
Come over here
and take a look at this.
It's a wedding ring.
You think it's Maya's?
I do. She's a CSI's
daughter, man.
She's a smart girl.
Leaving evidence behind
like bread crumbs.
Next to what looks like
tire treads.
Somebody peeled out of here.
I think she's trying
to tell us they switched cars.
That might not be all
she's trying to tell us.
Flecks of red paint here.
Must have been
from the driver's door.
Shaw gives her the keys,
tells her to drive.
She drops her ring
by the rear tire
and scratches the door
getting in.
SANDERS:
Tire impressions and paint.
Could tell us what
they're driving.
How is he doing?
CRAWFORD:
Not good.
Beating himself up.
He's not the only one.
I get it. We all want
to get Winthrop and Briscoe.
And that son of
a bitch, Shaw.
Should have heard him.
Talking about
his exploits.
Some story about stalking
a girl at a recital.
Who knows how many women he
and those brothers have killed?
What exactly did he say
about the girl at the recital?
His exact words were,
"It's hard to believe something
so beautiful could be mine."
You scumbag.
That's it.
That's what?
I got to go.
Will you keep an eye on him?
I have only seen him
like this once before, and
it was not good.
You don't have to worry.
I'm not gonna run.
I'm not even gonna
scream when you do to me
whatever it is
you're gonna do.
I'm not gonna give you
the satisfaction.
You know,
when I was a cop in Seattle,
I didn't have much respect
for people.
But I always respected your dad.
You're strong...
like him.
You have no idea.
I am not going
to make it easy.
Light's green. Go.
Hey.
I'm so sorry.
You heard about Maya.
I did.
Well, you were there yourself.
And I had a dad
who held himself responsible
for a decision that was just
as much mine as it was his.
Doesn't make it any easier.
I know.
Look, we're gonna get her back.
We're gonna find her
just like you guys found me.
Yeah. Yes, we are.
Greg ran the, uh...
tread patterns and the,
uh... the paint chip
from where Shaw
switched cars,
and it came back to a
2014 red Chevy Impala,
which is like a needle in
a haystack around here.
There are hundreds
of them in Nevada.
What about you? You're-you're
running the-the bugs from
the bodies, right, to track
down the killer's movement?
Yeah.
We know
that the bodies were moved
at least a few times
from the crime scene
to The Mizu,
where they were harvested
to make the killer's strings.
And then Rebecca Lowell's
house where you found them.
But given the condition
of the larvae on the bodies,
it looks like they were frozen
and unfrozen more than that.
So there might be
some other place they were kept.
Exactly.
Unfortunately,
the species of blowfly
that I found on the bodies is
far too common to zero in
on any specific location,
but I'm hoping...
that these guys are different.
Scolytus ventralis,
the fir engraver beetle.
Yeah. Most common
in northern Nevada,
but I'm checking with the
Bureau of Land Management
to see if they've had
any infestations
closer to Vegas.
It could be where
Shaw's taking Maya.
Well, that's where the...
the hope part comes in.
(beep)
I got a response
from the Bureau.
"In the last six months,
there have been reports
"of fir engraver beetle
colonies threatening
trees along Bighorn Ridge."
That's right here.
That's a big area.
There are only a certain
amount of roads in there,
so they have to pass
by a traffic camera
at some point, right?
Right.
Good work. Thanks.
♪ ♪
D.B., I need to talk to you.
I know why Shaw's
doing what he's doing.
Tell you the truth,
I don't really care,
and I need to
get to PD.
I need you to hear this.
The violin. The story
about the girl at the recital.
That was not Shaw talking
about one of his victims.
He was talking
about his daughter.
I should've realized it
right away. The violin--
it-it wasn't full size,
it's a kid's
instrument, and-and...
All right, slow
down, slow down.
I ran the DNA on the violin.
It's female.
It's a familial match
to the dead woman that we found
in the bed,
Rebecca Lowell's sister,
and to Shaw.
D.B., he had a daughter.
You sure about this?
Yes, and it all makes sense now.
He was protecting the escort
ring run by Rebecca Lowell,
and in her records
it says that her sister
was one of the escorts.
So Shaw was involved with
the sister and had a kid.
Yeah, and I confirmed
the birth records.
Amy Lowell was born 2001.
And I don't think I'm the only
one who's figured this out.
Winthrop.
He is exploiting
Shaw's one weakness.
And based on the evidence
that I found in that house,
I think that Winthrop
murdered the mother
and abducted the daughter
and now he's holding her
for one reason
and one reason only.
To trade.
Maya for Amy.
My daughter for his.
Shut off the engine.
(engine stops)
Give me the key.
Get out.
Why are you doing this?
Because you don't
seem like the type.
A killer.
A man who preys on women.
Let's go.
Are they
waiting for me?
You'll find out soon enough.
WINTHROP:
Maya.
Welcome.
My brother was right.
You're even more
beautiful in person.
I told you so.
Four years in prison.
It was worth every day
just for this moment.
You were right,
brother.
Dreams really
do come true.
We had a deal.
Where's my daughter?
She's here.
And you'll have her.
Just as soon as you
slide that gun over here.
We wouldn't want
any surprises,
would we?
I'm sure
you can understand.
My brother and I don't
have a lot of trust in cops.
Even dirty ones.
Well, I don't
trust murderers.
I want to see Amy.
CRAWFORD:
Just got this from
the Northeast Division.
That's Shaw's car traveling
east on Sunrise Highway.
RUSSELL:
6:27 a.m.
That's 20 minutes ago.
Yeah, if Shaw's meeting with
Winthrop, Winthrop's M.O.
says the location will
be an industrial area
or a warehouse district.
Right. Someplace isolated,
away from prying eyes.
Pull up the map
of Bighorn Ridge.
They're flooding this area
with patrol units.
We've also scrambled
air support.
We got eyes in the sky.
That's still
a hell of lot of real estate.
Yes, it is.
But we're getting closer.
Control, this is Air-Seven.
Just identified
the suspect vehicle.
Red Chevy Impala, license number
Adam-Tom-David-Charlie 425.
What's your
location, Air-Seven?
1500 block of Sunrise Highway.
Looks like
some kind of warehouse.
Come on, let's go.
Yeah.
Amy.
Dad.
Ah, ah, ah,
not so fast.
There'll be plenty of time
for hugs and kisses later.
The gun.
You all right,
sweetheart?
I want to get out of here.
Where's my mom?
It's gonna be all right.
Are you
all right?
Yeah.
So sweet.
Nothing like family,
right, Jared?
When do I get
what's coming to me?
Patience, brother.
You know we can't
have any loose ends.
I should've figured
you'd do this.
You should've figured a dirty
cop would have a throwaway. Run.
(both grunting)
(gasping)
(crunch)
(gunshot)
You think you're
smarter than me?
You've taken from me
the only family I've ever had.
The only real family.
The only real love in my life.
(soft grunting)
I saw how you looked
at your little girl.
I know how much
she means to you.
She's not gonna get very far,
'cause I'm gonna find her.
And just so you know,
when I do, I'm gonna
do things to her
you can't even imagine.
(grunts)
(groaning)
Don't move.
I'll get help.
Maya,
you all right?
Yeah, I'm okay.
Where are they?
Inside.
Shaw's wounded.
And Winthrop and Briscoe
are dead, I think.
Let's roll, boys.
(indistinct police radio
chatter, helicopter blades whir)
Check the back.
Briscoe's dead.
I got a pulse, but it's faint.
Charlie-04-Stokes.
I need immediate medical
at my location.
Maya said that Winthrop's dead.
But where the hell is he?
(siren wails,
tires screeching)
Hey.
You must be Amy, yeah?
I'm Detective Crawford.
We're gonna get you
out of here, okay?
Dad.
Hey.
You were so brave.
Learned from the best.
I was afraid...
I know. I know. Me, too.
Hey.
Hi.
How are you doing?
I've... been better.
How's Amy doing?
She's safe.
She's with
Child Protective Services now.
They're not gonna let me
see her, are they?
Well, that's probably
just the same.
I was never a very good father
to her anyway.
Just... some guy who showed up
from time to time,
took her to the park,
got her some ice cream,
then I was gone again.
I just wish
you would've come to me
before all this happened.
Maybe I could've helped.
I should've.
Yeah.
There's something
you can do for me now.
Amy's got a grandmother,
lives in Texas.
She's a good woman.
I just can't bear to see her
get lost in the system.
I'll make sure she doesn't.
You should just focus
on getting better.
That's when
the trouble starts, right?
When I get out of here?
I talked to Greg.
He and Nick are still
processing the scene.
They found a blood trail
leading from the building
to a drainage tunnel,
which led to a wash.
But no Winthrop?
No.
RUSSELL:
All these women.
Maya was almost one of them.
But she wasn't.
You came close, D.B.
The greater good.
Briscoe's dead,
and Winthrop's on the run,
a fugitive.
You can plaster
his face everywhere,
freeze his accounts.
You're in the driver's seat.
Why doesn't it feel like that?
No.
No, this guy's a predator.
He's an animal.
You know what they say.
Animals are most dangerous
when they're cornered.