(coyotes howling)
(insects trilling)
(panting, grunting)
(grunting)
(panting)
(weakly):
Hey. Hey.
(panting)
Hey! Hey!
Help!
(panting)
Hey...
(tires screech)
(siren wails)
Hey, what's up, man?
Hey.
Died with his boots off, huh?
Yeah, must have been
quite an impact.
Yeah. What's the driver say?
She's still
pretty shook up.
Crawford's waiting
(sobbing)
to talk to her.
What's the victim say?
Let's ask.
Hey, Dave.
Hmm?
Got an I.D.?
No wallet, but...
did find this.
Looks like a
hotel key card.
No identifying
marks on it.
Well, I'll scan it
when we get back to the lab.
See if it has an I.D.
embedded in the, uh,
magnetic strip.
He took the full force
of the hit, didn't he, Dave?
There are signs of extreme
blunt-force trauma.
But I don't think this guy's
problems started with the car.
Why's that?
Take a look
at this sharp-force wound
on his neck.
SANDERS:
Could've come from
headlamp glass.
True, but the blood
is mostly clotted.
That means
the wound occurred earlier.
Hours earlier.
Check out the
guy's clothes.
I mean, he's completely
covered in dirt.
Something's not right, fellas.
Yeah, here we go, Greg.
Check this out.
Directional blood drops
suggest he was bleeding
before he was hit
by that car.
SANDERS:
Tail indicates
he came from the desert.
Oh. Here's another
one in the dirt.
And more blood up here.
This definitely wasn't caused
by the impact with that vehicle.
Well,
whoever he is, he
came from out there.
Let's go.
(hawk cries)
Hey.
(sighs)
Ooh.
That ain't good.
Someone thought our John Doe
was dead. Buried him.
STOKES:
But he was still alive and...
must have crawled
his way out.
Only to get hit by a car.
Talk about a bad night.
Poor guy.
Died twice.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
Ms. Haymond. I'm sorry. I'll get
you out of here as quickly
as possible. I just need
to ask you a few questions
about the accident,
all right?
Well, I was in L.A.
at a beauty convention.
And I was so hungry,
and I was thinking
about my new
styling chair,
and he came out of nowhere!
I-I don't...
Whoa. S-Slow down. Slow down.
It's okay.
Okay.
Just... just tell me
what you saw.
I didn't see anything.
♪ ♪
I was reaching for a bag
of potato chips,
and I... I mean,
I looked away for one second
and suddenly he's there.
(gasps, screams)
(tires screech)
I did everything I could
to try to save him.
I mean, my Aunt Suzie,
she taught me CPR
when she lifeguarded.
I never thought
I would have to use it.
It was so disgusting.
Yeah.
I know none of this
is easy on you.
I just need your information.
And as I said,
I'll process you out of here
as quickly as I can.
Anything you need.
Thank you.
I just opened my salon.
This isn't gonna go
on my record, is it?
Hey, man, I found
an access road
that runs parallel
with the highway.
I'm thinking the killer
brought him in on that.
Any tire impressions?
No, killer got lucky.
It's gravel.
Maybe his luck
just ran out.
Found some green fibers.
STOKES: Vic wasn't wearing
anything green.
Yeah, well, maybe
the killer wrapped
the victim in a green blanket.
You see this?
What you
got there?
Snakeskin?
Yeah, but that shouldn't
be here.
Red and black bands
are indicative
of the regal coral snake.
They're venomous
little bastards.
Where does it come from?
Coral snakes are
from South America, but the
regal is found in, like, Panama.
So how'd it end up in a
dead man's grave in Nevada?
Good question.
Our John Doe here suffered
massive blunt-force trauma.
Numerous broken bones
and lacerated organs.
Basilar
skull fracture.
All from the impact of the car.
That's what the C.O.D. said.
But David was right.
The sharp-force injury
to the neck
is tangential
to the skin surface,
suggesting stabbing
and tearing motion
caused by a person, not a car.
Did find a tiny, clear
glass shard in the neck wound.
RUSSELL: Maybe he was cut
with a broken bottle?
ROBBINS: Could be. There was
also an odd abrasion pattern
on the victim's cheek.
Indentations
with a distinct marking.
Maybe a logo of some kind?
I found traces
of a metal alloy in the wound.
I'm thinking brass knuckles
caused it.
Well, you don't hear about that
very often, do you?
So he was incapacitated
with brass knuckles,
stabbed in the neck
with a broken bottle,
and then buried alive.
And then his luck ran out
and he was hit by a car.
I hope he wasn't
playing the ponies.
Hey. Got an I.D.
on our John Doe.
His name is Jimmy Turelli.
He is a recently paroled inmate.
He, uh, was two years
at Ely for grand larceny
and robbery.
Long sheet.
Ran numbers for Sam Braun
back in the day.
When did Turelli get out?
Two weeks ago.
Brass knuckles.
Mob-style body drop
in the desert.
Maybe Turelli's past
caught up with him.
What does magnesium
and silicon say
to you?
Sounds like your basic talcum
that is used in baby powder.
I found traces of it in the
abrasion on Turelli's cheek.
I also found the alloy residue
in the wound is comprised
of copper and zinc-- brass.
So, what, a homicidal baby
hits Jimmy Turelli
with brass knuckles?
It's weird, right?
Yeah. As is the
green fabric
that Greg found in
Turelli's grave.
It's worsted wool.
From a sheep breed
in Teeswater, England.
The fabric is used
to make expensive suits.
In this case,
dyed green.
It is an odd color
for a nice suit.
(English accent):
It's bloody peculiar.
(chuckles)
Oh.
Just what I've been waiting for.
The results for the glass
on Turelli's neck wound.
The glass is made
of potassium oxide.
Potash salt. The same thing
that fine stemware is made of.
It's all adding up.
Our green-suited killer baby
is sipping champagne.
(chuckles)
Turelli has promised him
a new toy. When he
shows up empty-handed,
the baby
snaps and...
What?
Champagne.
Let me see that fiber again.
You're thinking...?
I'm thinking
this is gonna be fun.
♪ ♪
RUSSELL:
Nice shot.
You know, these pool tables
aren't that cheap to rent.
I hope you found something.
I think that the green fiber
we found in Turelli's grave
came from a
pool table.
English worsted wool.
It's in my report.
BRODY:
In the billiards
world, worsted cloth
is also known as speed cloth.
Billiard balls fly over it
way faster than they do
any other woolen cloth.
All right. So that places
our vic near a pool table.
That's not
the end
of the pool game. You know
what a bridge is, right?
Yes, young lady, I do.
You use it
when it's a tricky shot
and you can't get
to the cue ball.
Exactly. Now, this bridge
is made of brass.
Note the pattern.
RUSSELL:
Very similar to...
brass knuckles.
BRODY: Right.
Traces of talc
also point to billiards.
Pool players use it
to keep their hands dry.
All right. Tell me
about these champagne glasses.
BRODY:
That's what got me thinking.
Could explain the glass
in Turelli's neck wound.
I've seen trick-shot
artists make
the champagne shot before.
And when they nail it,
they like to take their stick
and smash it
through the champagne glasses
in victory.
Kind of like this.
Oh... No, no.
D-Don't you dare.
Whoa! Whoa, whoa.
(chuckles)
Too easy.
Okay.
So our trick-shot artist
ends his act with a flourish,
leaving broken champagne glass
on the felt.
I think our
trick-shot artist
started a fight with Turelli.
Across the face
with the bridge and grabbing
a broken champagne glass,
nailing him in the neck.
I still have one
question, though.
Since when did you become
a pool expert?
I played a little
in high school,
and I've managed
to stay dialed in.
In fact...
I happen to know there is
a major pool tournament
at the Palermo this weekend.
♪ ♪
Thank you so much
for your time, Ms. Massey.
Last night of the exhibition.
It's finally picking up.
SANDERS:
You had a low turnout?
MASSEY: Sadly, billiards'
popularity is waning.
The girls' tournament's
the only one
that the fans turn out for now.
MASSEY:
You had some questions?
We wanted to ask you
about Jimmy Turelli.
I know Jimmy.
Did he have something to
do with the tournament?
He paid an entrance fee
for one of the players.
SANDERS:
Really? Which one was that?
MASSEY:
The Hornet.
♪ ♪
Fan favorite.
Don't chalk up yet,
Pamela.
Sometimes even a hornet needs
a little help from her friends.
Look at the hornet bridge.
BRODY:
That hornet pattern is
pretty similar to the bruises
on Jimmy Turelli's face.
(crowd gasping, murmuring)
(cheering)
♪ ♪
This...
is for you.
(smacks lips)
Thank you for coming.
(laughs)
Ms. Barrow.
Hi!
Enjoy the match?
Oh... very impressive.
You want to play a game for fun?
BRODY:
Actually,
we're here from
the Vegas crime lab.
We're here
to talk to you
about Jimmy Turelli.
What about him?
Well, for one,
he's dead.
Dead? How is that possible?
We thought
maybe you could tell us.
I don't know anything about it.
Your hornet here
says otherwise.
Look... you are
way off base here.
I can't even believe
Jimmy's dead.
When was the last
time you saw him?
I saw him last night
at the Vegas Rails.
The Vegas Rails?
It's the pool hall
where he bartended.
He managed it
before he went to prison.
Pro tables,
pre-ban ivory cues.
The real deal.
It's not like
this plastic nightmare.
Okay. While you
were at the Rails,
did you happen to do your
champagne trick shot there?
Yeah. So?
Took 500 bucks
off a total loser.
Was that loser
Jimmy Turelli?
Because he was stabbed with
a broken champagne glass.
BRODY: After
he was clocked
with a bridge--
one that looks
just like yours.
I sell those bridges online.
I've sold hundreds
over the years.
Well, we'll need
to examine yours.
Examine away.
I had nothing to do
with Jimmy's death.
We believe that
Jimmy was killed
near a pool table.
If it wasn't you,
did you see him play
anybody else last night?
No.
But he was excited
about a game he'd set up.
It was supposed
to happen at midnight.
Against who?
He didn't say.
It was all very hush-hush.
Said it was
for the stakes of a lifetime.
Look...
Jimmy was the best one-pocket
player I've ever seen.
He may have found God
in prison, but...
nothing could make Jimmy
put down that cue.
Except maybe his killer.
♪ ♪
(door creaking)
So this is the Vegas Rails.
Seems more like
an after-hours dive.
Back-alley entrance.
Explains
the back-alley vibe.
(chuckles)
SIDLE: Any luck
tracking down the owners?
Uh, I tried to find out from
Natalie Barrow, but no go.
BRODY:
Pool hustlers Wall of Fame.
SIDLE:
Yeah, I can practically
smell the cheap cigars.
(laughs) Oh.
There's Jimmy Turelli.
This has got to be his place.
Whoa.
Somebody left in a hurry.
Yeah.
SIDLE:
Blood spatter on the table
says that this is almost
certainly the primary.
Spatter pattern is consistent
with arterial spray.
You mind grabbing a shot
of this down here?
Uh-huh.
(shutter clicking)
This bridge.
The hornet.
Says here that
it belongs to the Vegas Rails.
I guess Natalie was making
money on her design.
The blood here says
it was involved in the attack.
Huh.
(shutter clicks)
Same goes for this
broken champagne glass.
Left after
the Hornet's trick shot.
Confirms...
somebody used it
for a different kind of trick.
SIDLE:
This is weird.
Check out these marks
left in blood.
What's it
look like to you?
Looks like a ball
rolled through the blood,
landed in the corner pocket.
(distorted, echoing grunt)
Only one problem.
There's no ball in there.
Well, maybe the killer took it.
I'm guessing
it was the cue ball.
Only ball in the game
that the player touches.
Killer was worried
about leaving prints.
Some players bring
their own cue ball.
Hustlers will swap out
their cue ball
in the middle of a game
to gain advantage.
Maybe... this fight
was about cheating.
Mmm, what are you doing?
Looking for a dead rail.
The bumper here--
you can deaden your rail
in a few secret spots,
and it gives you a
home-court advantage.
That's another way in which
a hustler tries to cheat.
Remind me never
to play pool with you.
Ooh.
You ready for another "weird"?
It's what keeps me coming back.
Snakeskin.
That looks like
the same kind
of snake that Nick found
at Turelli's grave.
Forget about Snakes on a Plane.
We've got snakes
on a pool table.
So, I've been digging into
the Rails billiards club,
and it turns out
that it is owned
by a holding company
called DeRosa.
No names.
Headquartered
in Antigua.
Probably a shell company.
And knowing
Turelli's background,
maybe it's got ties to the Mob.
A mobster
with a snake collection?
Are we any closer
to figuring out the snakeskin?
Yes, we are.
But it's connected
to a different kind of snake.
Morgan and Sara
found this photo
at the Rails.
Check out the
pool stick.
See the grip?
Snakeskin.
Well, that's making sense.
Old grip.
Snakeskin flakes
fall onto the pool table.
Who is this guy?
His name is Calvin Tate.
He's, uh, kind of a
part-time pool hustler,
full-time con artist.
He was arrested a few times
for identity theft,
and kicked out of five
casinos for counting cards.
What's his connection
to Turelli?
Tate's a regular
at the Rails.
And we know that
he paid for drinks
the night that
Turelli died.
And the drinks started
flowing at around midnight.
Which is exactly the time
that Turelli was supposed
to play his big-money game.
So I'm guessing maybe it
was against the "snake."
Nice place.
The hustling doesn't
pay like it used to.
LVPD. Open up.
Officers.
Uh, can I help you?
We're looking for Cal Tate.
I'm sorry.
He's not home.
And you are...?
Zoe Tate, his wife.
Okay, then
we'll ask you.
Do you know where
Cal was last night?
I'm sorry,
what's this about?
It's about Jimmy Turelli.
He was murdered.
Jimmy's dead?
Oh, my God.
So, you knew him?
Oh, a long time ago.
I-I used to wait tables
where he bartended.
I thought he was in prison.
Yeah, he got out.
MAN (in distance):
Bubbles? Where are you?!
And you need to let us in.
Come on, Bubbles,
fetch me a beer.
Make it snappy this time.
Why don't you go
and fetch it yourself?
Who the hell are you?
LVPD.
We got some
questions for you.
Well, I'm busy.
Nah. Not anymore.
Were you with Jimmy Turelli
last night
at the Rails?
You got that right,
cool breeze.
Kicked his behind
in nine-ball.
Won myself a crisp G.
Yeah, that guy, he taught me
a lot in the day, but...
he's lost his touch.
Well, we're thinking
you're the one who lost...
and did this to him.
(Tate whistles)
That's a bad shave.
Did you give it to him?
It's not my style.
You sure?
Positive.
Okay, say we
believe you.
Was Turelli entertaining
any other company last night?
He was alone.
But I did hear him on the phone
with that Massey broad.
Was that Elise Massey, the woman
who runs the tournament?
(snaps fingers)
The same.
She took over
the management of the Rails
when Jimmy had his...
incarceration vacation.
What were they talking about?
I don't think
Jimmy liked what
she'd done to the place.
Jimmy always
thought that only
real pool players
should be allowed.
Massey let in
rich wannabes
from China, Russia, Dubai.
Took you bloody
long enough.
Can I get you gentlemen
anything?
TATE: These gentlemen
were just leaving,
Bubbles.
How'd you get
that bruise
on your arm, Mrs. Tate?
Oh, um... I fell.
She fell.
You like slapping women
and old men around, Calvin?
I like a lot of things.
Right now, what I would like
is for you to arrest me or...
fetch me a beer.
Now, what's it gonna be?
Neither one, hotshot.
Don't leave town.
(clink)
Got something
from the Rails?
Yeah, it's about the phone
call that Cal Tate heard.
I don't think that Massey
and Turelli were fighting
over pool players
at the Rails.
Look at these
credit card receipts.
Notice anything odd?
Five grand for a game of pool?
Something else came
with the game.
Check out the
Rails' Web site.
So, when Morgan and Sara
were processing the place,
they found a notebook
with a security code and
a secret password
for the Web site.
Membership comes
with its privileges.
♪ ♪
MASSEY:
Welcome.
I can tell
you're a real player.
My girls are ready
for your best shot.
Whatever you desire.
(beep)
Elise Massey.
Looks like she
was doing more
than spicing up the
world of pro billiards.
Looks like she turned the Rails
into a brothel.
I'm thinking
that Turelli left prison
wanting to go straight,
and this was one game
he didn't want to play.
MASSEY:
My girls are ready
for your best shot,
whatever you desire.
Prostitution in Vegas? Shocking.
Oh, Vegas or not,
it's still against the law.
This isn't Nye County.
Arrest me, then.
With my friends at
the mayor's office
and my overpaid
solicitor,
I'll be out in five minutes.
I'm more concerned
with the homicide than hooking.
You see,
we know about your argument
with Jimmy Turelli.
Few hours later, he's dead.
I didn't kill Jimmy.
We had our differences,
but he always had
my back when...
when I used to work a little
closer with our clients.
Are you saying he was your pimp?
He was my friend.
I'll admit his...
moralizing was tiring,
but I'd never hurt him.
Somebody did--
in the club that you ran.
Can you account
for your whereabouts last night?
I was hosting an all-female
trick-shot competition
at the Tangiers.
Really? Well,
I'll check that out.
Do. I was there
all night.
Astonishing
what those girls can do
with a few sticks and balls.
Never seen this
version of pool.
I invented it myself.
Trying to replicate
the blood trail?
Mm-hmm.
I still think
a pool player
killed Turelli.
Maybe Cal Tate.
If I can prove
that his cue ball rolled
through the blood,
and find prints on it,
we put him away.
Pool shark
in the corner prison cell.
Chalk another one up.
Nice shot.
Thanks.
All right,
let's check it out.
See, I can't seem
to replicate the blood pattern,
no matter how many attempts
I make.
Looks like there
may be, like,
some kind of crazy
spin on the ball.
English?
I-I don't know.
You're the pool expert.
I'm no expert, Hodges.
But you used to
play a lot, right?
Come on.
What's the story?
There was a-a dive pool hall
in Venice.
Real old-school place.
Instead of surfing,
I would play nine-ball pool,
as my after-school sport.
It was so real,
you know, the...
the crazy characters,
the wild games, the hustles.
Pool is a lot
like chess, actually.
A silent game of war.
You really have to know how
to read a person to win.
You ever do a little bit
of hustling yourself?
Girl's got to make
her beer money somehow, right?
Beer money?
Is that all?
Well, that's all you're getting.
(laughs)
I'll tell you one thing.
I saw a lot
of really great games
when I was playing,
and the real hustlers know
how to clear a guy out
without the mark even knowing.
Who's winning?
Uh, working.
Can I help you?
Well, maybe I can help you.
Got a hit off of
the hotel key card
that we found on Turelli's body.
Not from a hotel.
It's a condo security card.
Turelli's condo?
Yeah, so I processed the place,
and I found a few long
female hairs in Turelli's bed.
Henry got a hit.
You got to be kidding me.
I wasn't having sex
with Jimmy Turelli.
I was sleeping at his place.
It was an escape.
From?
Cal.
Our fights
were getting really bad.
Why didn't you just leave?
It's complicated.
Well, it's time to
uncomplicate things, Zoe.
Jimmy Turelli was
brutally murdered.
You pretended not to
have seen him in years.
Why would you lie about that?
Hey,
you need to come clean here.
When I first met Cal,
I knew that he had
a real wild side.
I liked it.
I was the straight-A student
that wanted a thrill.
And I thought
I could tame him,
but I became just like him.
What's that mean exactly?
A year ago, Cal and I began
working on a scam together.
An old-fashioned Chicago sting
called the "Honor Hustle."
The Honor Hustle?
Cal would find the richest guy
in the bar.
I'd flirt with the mark,
mention to him how
I was unhappy
in my marriage to Cal.
Cal would end up
playing the mark.
Nah!
He'd lose intentionally.
Then he'd go in for the kill.
Listen, man,
give me one more shot.
All right,
for a grand.
No, no, man.
Straight up.
Give me my money.
Actually, you know,
how about this?
If I lose, you can have Zoe
for one night.
I'll make her do it.
You're on.
You got it.
Oh, wait a minute.
I remember how
to play this game.
Oh!
Did I just win?
You bet I did.
Yes!
It was a real rush.
CRAWFORD:
Yeah, I bet.
Ripping off people
is a dangerous game.
Jimmy thought
we were taking it too far.
He was worried about me.
I'm like the daughter
he never had.
And it all came
to a head that night.
Jimmy and Cal weren't playing
for money.
"Stakes of a lifetime."
I get that now.
That's what Jimmy
told Natalie Barrow.
Jimmy was playing for you.
But Jimmy ran the table
that night,
and Cal left in a hurry.
I have never seen him so upset.
You think he was
upset enough to kill?
I...
I don't know.
So, you left the
Rails with Jimmy?
Uh, we went back
to his place.
I fell asleep in Jimmy's bed
about 2:00 a.m.
Woke up at 3:00 a.m., I heard
Jimmy going out.
I guess he was going
back to the Rails.
I wish I'd stopped him.
And Where's Cal now?
Do you know?
I haven't seen him
since the cops came.
LVPD. Calvin Tate,
you in there?
Looks like a hurricane
hit this place.
Star-shaped wound.
Single GSW.
Forget the beer.
Somebody fetched him
a bullet.
(siren whooping)
Here we go.
Looks like a nine-mil.
Decent rifling impressions.
How we doing on T.O.D.?
Liver stick puts that
between 11:00 and 1:00.
That's just a few hours ago.
Yeah.
All right, thanks, David.
All right, so far,
no luck with, uh,
any of the witnesses.
Well, it's kind of
convenient
that Zoe Tate pinned Turelli's
murder on a dead guy.
Well, I just
checked in with Russell.
Zoe Tate's been in custody
since 9:00 a.m. this morning.
There's no way
she could have done this.
Yeah, maybe she
put out a hit.
I don't know. I mean,
mattress in the bedroom
looks like it's been
through a paper-shredder.
All right, that says our killer
was looking for something.
Something Cal Tate hid well.
CRAWFORD:
And all the damage says
they came up empty-handed.
SANDERS:
Maybe whatever the killer was
looking for is still
here somewhere.
You know, Tate was a hustler.
Always on the move.
Guys like him like
to keep their valuables close.
Yeah, so if you wanted
to hide something,
where would you put it to make
it close, but not too close?
Inside the lamp?
No.
Inside the hat.
How's that for close?
Let's see what Cal Tate's
killer was looking for.
That's Zoe Tate.
Cal's wife.
Yeah, looks
like she's
with some Honor
Hustle marks.
Wait a minute,
I thought the whole point
was for her not
to have sex with them.
The style of shots indicate
a hidden camera--
that says extortion.
Married man would pay a lot to
stop his wife from seeing those.
Cal had the photos,
so he had to be in on it.
Not according to his
bank account. Guy was broke.
But hidden camera,
lots of angles--
someone had to have
taken those shots.
Maybe she had a different
partner for the extortion.
Cal came across the photos,
wanted a piece of the action.
Zoe's partner
wasn't interested
and made that clear
with a nine-mil.
So who's the partner?
RUSSELL:
Zoe Tate lawyered up,
so if she's part
of an extortion scheme,
she's not gonna be diming out
her partner anytime soon.
Well, what if we don't
need Zoe Tate at all?
I've been trying
to replicate this
blood pattern.
At first, I thought
it was made
by a billiard ball.
But it looks like I was
chasing the wrong trick shot.
Now, you see
how the ball
rolled over the felt,
leaving blood prints
every couple
of inches?
Right, 'cause only
part of the ball
went through
the blood.
A cue ball has a 7.07-inch
circumference,
so the blood should have left
a cue mark every 7.07 inches.
Should?
The distance
between the cue marks reduced
by a hundredth of an
inch every revolution.
How's that possible?
(chuckles)
You're telling me that
the billiard ball was shrinking?
Exactly. I can explain.
Now, I also found traces
of bourbon mixed with
the blood on the felt.
And I found
this photo
on the Vegas Rails Web site.
Take a look at what's
inside the guy's glass.
RUSSELL:
Looks like a round piece of ice.
About the size
of a billiard ball.
The blood trail was not
made by a billiard ball.
It was made...
by an ice ball.
I made an exemplar, tested
it-- worked every time.
I'm thinking the ball
accidentally rolled
onto the table while
Turelli was being attacked.
Under the hot lights,
the ball melted
as it rolled down the table.
When we arrived at the scene,
the ball was completely melted.
Trick shot of all time.
But that's not all.
Turelli was sober.
He got sober in prison.
Doc confirmed it-- said he had
no alcohol in his system.
So, the killer was
the only one drinking.
You know what I'm thinking?
Yeah.
Leather pocket absorbed
not only the melted ice
but our killer's saliva.
DNA, corner pocket.
Did you get
anything?
(exhales)
Results from the, uh...
the ice ball DNA.
Elise Massey, right?
Had a feeling. I could
see pure evil in her eyes.
This is an evil
that we did not see.
Mary Haymond?
Who the hell is that?
It's the woman who hit
Turelli with her car.
She gave Turelli
CPR on the scene.
Greg had to get some DNA from
her for exclusionary reasons.
It was her
one mistake.
The best kind of hustlers
know how to take you
when you don't even know it.
Will this take long?
I've only got one girl
covering at the salon,
and she couldn't highlight a
football game, I swear. (laughs)
Are you done?
I'm just saying I'm
kind of busy. I...
Give it a rest, Ms. Haymond.
Let's start
with DeRosa Holdings.
We recovered bank statements
from your home computer.
Turns out that you are
president of DeRosa Holdings.
CRAWFORD:
DeRosa Holdings
owns the Vegas Rails,
two Laundromats and three
beauty salons.
I'm a businesswoman.
Since when is that a crime?
Well, since they're
all fronts to launder money
from extortion and prostitution.
Mary, we found your black book.
We know that Elise Massey
worked for you
and that she was just
the tip of the iceberg.
I found this photo
on your camera.
RUSSELL:
You recruited
Zoe Tate to extort
all the old rich guys
that she and Cal
had been extorting.
Honor Hustle?
Small-time.
You're big-time.
We already questioned Zoe--
she told us everything.
Uh, the photos
just confirm it.
I'm no different than
every casino in this town.
I take money from
fools who smile
while they're losing it.
And the biggest fools are men.
A lonely man
is like a blank check.
I figured that out when I was
dancing at the French Palace.
One day, I got tired of giving
half my take to management,
so I became management.
You want to waste
your time blowing up
everything I worked for?
Fine.
But I'm not a killer.
There's no money in it.
Sure, there is.
I mean,
that's why you did it.
To protect your scams.
You think we just believe
you were out
on a midnight drive,
just happened to be near
Jimmy Turelli's shallow grave?
RUSSELL:
Mary, we found
your DNA at the Rails
mixed in with Turelli's blood.
Try this one on.
The bullet that killed
Calvin Tate came from your gun.
Recovered from your office
at the salon.
I know a lot of people
in this building.
This could get very
uncomfortable.
Wow.
You just don't get it, do you?
The hustle is over, Mary.
I get why you
killed Calvin.
He wanted a piece
of your action.
You didn't want to give up any.
But, uh, why Turelli?
Ah. Everybody in your world
is a sucker.
A fool.
Guy makes a change,
he wants to try to do
the right thing and, what,
you just... you just
wouldn't stand for it?
Honestly, it
made me sick.
After his game with Cal,
Turelli found the drive with
the photos in Zoe's purse.
He assumed she was
in on it with Cal.
Guys always call
the shots, right?
So he confronted Cal.
Cal plays dumb,
but it was no act.
He had no idea Zoe was
running a scam with me.
RUSSELL:
Zoe realizes
she's lost the photos.
She knows that
Turelli's seen them.
She gets in touch
with you.
Then what?
What happened then?
I set up a meet with
Turelli back at the Rails.
I figured I'd cut him
in on the action.
Old-timer deserves a taste.
But suddenly,
he's the one fool in this town
who won't be bought.
Take the money.
Don't be stupid.
Zoe's a good kid.
(scoffs)
She deserves
a second chance,
just like I had.
No, I'm calling the cops.
It's the only way to save her.
Now, get out of my club.
Get out of my club!
It's not your club
anymore, Jimmy.
Don't you get it?
You're a ghost.
Just like those
hustlers on the wall.
(grunting)
(groaning, gurgling)
HAYMOND:
Later, I put Jimmy to bed.
Took me 20 minutes
to get back to the main road.
Guess Jimmy
wasn't finished dying.
Son of a bitch.
(tires screech)
When it's your time,
it's your time.
I couldn't have
said that better myself.
You know, it's funny,
but I thought
Zoe Tate lawyered up.
Yeah, she did.
So she never said a word about
her and Mary working together?
No. No, not a word.
You're telling me that you
lied to a suspect
in interrogation?
Best kind of hustle.
(door opens)
Hey, Hodges.
Come on, let's get a game in
before they take this thing.
Uh, I would prefer
to hang on
to what little
dignity I have left.
Come on.
We'll make it interesting.
I'll play left-handed and...
loser has to clean
the GCMS for a month.
Okay, now you're just
hustling me.
Okay.
Whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa,
wait a minute,
wait a minute.
Left-handed?
Yeah. And I'll even
let you break.
Okay.
If it'll make
you happy.
Let's do it.
Well, that was lucky.
Yeah. Lucky.