Previously on CSI...
FINLAY: Jared Briscoe,
the Gig Harbor Killer.
SHAW: Who knew that psychopath
Briscoe had a twin?
Plans change. I'll even have
a little gift for you.
Maya.
BRODY: The prints came back
to Daniel Shaw.
Shaw is
Winthrop's partner.
FINLAY:
All of our victims are involved
in the sex trade. We never knew
who was pimping them out.
Why are you doing this?
SHAW: We had a deal.
Where's my daughter?
Amy.
Dad.
Run!
(gunshot)
(shouts)
(grunting)
SIDLE:
Briscoe's dead
and Winthrop's on the run,
a fugitive.
RUSSELL:
No.
Animals are most dangerous
when they're cornered.
♪ ♪
(buzzing)
I don't understand...
any of this.
Why am I here?
This was not the plan.
You said if I make a sacrifice,
in return,
I would live forever.
Look at me.
Look in my eyes.
My eyes are your eyes.
My heart is your heart.
Hey, D.B. I heard you...
Whoa. How long's it
been? Like, a week?
Yeah. My wife's not too crazy
about it.
She'd like to see me
all cleaned up
like you.
Yeah, well,
there's something to be said
for a close
shave, yeah.
I spoke with Ecklie.
He and I
both heard from the lab director
down in San Diego.
I didn't know he was
actually gonna call you guys.
He did more than that. He put
you on the top of the list
of candidates to succeed him.
No, he shouldn't have done that.
Why not?
It sounds
like a good opportunity.
You trying
to kick me out of here now?
Last thing I want
is you leaving.
But I would support
you making the move.
FINLAY:
Sorry to interrupt.
I sent the samples
over to Hodges,
and I'm heading out.
All right. See you later.
Mom, what did you get me
this time?
Castor and Pollux.
The twins.
(gasps)
(phone ringing)
WINTHROP:
Did you get my present?
If you wanted my attention,
you've got it.
Oh, I want more
than your attention.
Because this is just
the beginning.
Or should I say...
the beginning of the end.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
That son of a bitch put my
mother's name on the package,
so I had to get the Philly cops
to put protection on her house.
Yeah, as soon as I got
your call, I did the same
with Maya
and with Barbara.
So what do you think
it all means?
Mythology says
that when Castor was killed,
Pollux went to Zeus
and asked him to let him share
his own immortality
with his twin.
To keep them together.
Zeus agreed,
and so they were cast
into heaven.
The constellation Gemini.
So cutting off his finger
is part of the message
that he and his brother
are now one?
RUSSELL:
He's saying we may
have taken his brother,
but he's more powerful
than ever.
All very interesting, you guys,
but here on planet Earth,
I thought Winthrop had a partner
while his brother
was in custody.
Didn't you hear
another set of footsteps
on the recording
of Pamela Kramer's
murder?
We did.
And you don't think
it's Daniel Shaw? I mean,
come on, this whole thing
with the estranged daughter
could still have been a setup.
It was not a setup.
You sure about that?
I am.
Then why
is Shaw's lawyer
saying his client
has information on Winthrop
that he's willing to trade
for a deal?
It's the first I'm hearing this.
Yeah, me, too.
Guess I need to go talk to Shaw.
I checked with World-Send.
The tracking number
and the bar code were bogus.
I'm guessing
that Winthrop faked them.
You got something?
Yeah, we've seen
this before.
The strings are made of human
tissue. Take a look there.
SIDLE: Yeah, thinner gauge
than the trajectory strings
but same idea.
We'll have Henry confirm,
see if DNA can
tell us who it is.
Sounds good.
Hey, let me ask
you something.
Is this about San Diego?
Because Finn mentioned
something.
Yeah, Nolan is stepping down
as the lab director there.
And, um, he seems to think
I'll make a good replacement.
Wow. You would.
Yeah.
So what's the problem?
(chuckling):
It's just like I said,
I have a lot
of friends here, and...
it's a big responsibility.
Yeah, but there's a beach.
And it's a
four-and-a-half-hour drive.
You'd see me all the time.
You know, Sara,
after all these years,
I realize
what's important to me.
It's not a promotion.
Well...
you know what Grissom would say.
You gotta go
where you can do the most good.
SHAW:
This is what
you got, huh?
How many times I got to
tell you I am not doing this?
I'm not playing the game.
I don't want a deal.
I want to cooperate.
If you can't get that
through your thick head,
there's the door.
Fine.
Need a new lawyer?
Yeah.
Looks like I'll be representing
myself from here on in.
Yeah, I don't think
that's the best plan.
Why break a losing streak?
So I've heard
that you have information
that you'd like
to trade for a deal.
Yeah, that wasn't my
idea. That was
my lawyer's.
Besides,
I'd rather talk to you.
I'm listening.
Look, I know
your boss, the sheriff, he
thinks that I'm Winthrop's
partner.
That's just not true.
I know that.
But given everything
that happened,
it's pretty hard
to make that case.
Not if you and I can find
the real coconspirator.
Before Winthrop abducted
my daughter,
I was working on a lead.
I figured his-his partner
was helping him get the girls,
the victims.
Through the escort service.
Exactly.
I thought Rebecca Lowell
ran Lady Aquarius.
She did.
But she had a connection here
in Las Vegas.
The important thing is
this same guy
was getting a lot of money
from Winthrop's company.
Who is it?
He's not gonna talk to you.
But he will
speak to me.
Are you asking me
what I think you're asking me?
You get me a 48-hour pass,
you and I can nail this guy.
Sheriff already
doesn't trust you.
You do. Just a little bit.
I'm gonna need a name.
Well,
it's someone you've had a run-in
with before.
A certain preacher-pimp.
Goes by the name
of Brother Larson.
WOMAN:
I can't go back up there.
I can't even look at that man.
Calm down.
Brother Larson is here,
and Brother Larson is listening.
Now, you tell me,
did he hurt you?
No. He didn't touch me.
And that's just it,
I don't want him
to touch me.
All right, then let's talk
about that.
You don't want him
to touch you how?
I came to you.
I came to your church
because I wanted to
get out of the game.
I don't want to do this anymore.
I hear you, baby. I feel you.
But here's the thing.
Here's the Word.
Our Creator...
He's bestowed upon
us gifts. You...
have a gift.
The only shame
there is in life
is squandering our gifts.
You feel me?
I guess.
Here's what we're gonna do.
You're gonna go home,
get some sleep.
You're gonna forget
about tonight.
I will see you in the morning.
I'll bring you
some breakfast.
One more thing.
Did that man give you
an envelope?
Bless you, baby doll.
(engine starts)
Get out of here.
Damn, you're good, Larson.
And you're taking liberties
with my car.
Been a while, Daniel.
I been reading
the papers.
You been in
the lions' den.
Surprised to see you.
Police think
I'm Winthrop's partner.
They think I'm a killer.
But you know me.
You know that's not true.
And how would I know that?
Because I know
about the money.
I used to help you
and your business in the past.
Now it's your turn to help me.
Unless you want me to give
this information to the police.
I always liked you, Daniel.
Always trusted you.
Until now.
Tell me something.
Do they shave you down there
before they tape
that little wire
onto you?
I'm not wearing a wire.
Then I'm guessing...
we're not alone.
You guessed right.
CSI Finlay,
as I recall.
Was all this really necessary?
I've always been a friend
of the police.
I've helped you before.
All you had to do is ask.
All right,
then I'll ask.
Are you Winthrop's partner
in all of these murders?
Direct. I like that.
The answer's no.
The cops are
onto the money trail.
They know you provided
the girls.
Help us
find Winthrop,
and maybe you won't get
the death penalty.
Being misjudged has been
my constant cross to bear.
Yes, I provided escorts.
It's what I do.
And I received a finder's fee.
Also what I do.
What I don't do is harm women.
Or anyone.
All right?
All right.
I guess
I'll just have to arrest you.
H-Hold on a minute. I said
I was gonna help, I'll help.
The money I got,
it didn't come from the son.
It came from the father.
Collin Winthrop.
In fact, when the first girls
went missing,
I suspected
him, but, uh,
given events, I see now how this
could be a family business.
You're saying
the father's the partner?
That'd be my suspicion.
Sometimes
the apple
doesn't fall
from the tree at all.
So say we believe you. Where can
we find Paul Winthrop's father?
I stopped dealing with
Collin a long time ago.
I do still receive contributions
to preserve his good name.
It's called extortion.
That is such an ugly word.
Look, if you guys want
to arrest me, go ahead,
but know that my lawyer
will have me out and about
in a Las Vegas minute.
You good? You good?
Me, too.
Got your text.
Please tell me
you have answers.
Well, let's start with
the finger in the jar.
Now, it turns
out the
finger was not suspended
in saline and blood--
as I expected--
but saline and something else.
I sent it off to
Hodges for analysis.
And you're sure
that it's
Paul Winthrop's finger.
It is.
And the story would end there.
Except I found blood
on the statuette.
Well,
Paul Winthrop's blood, right?
That's what
I thought.
And because we're
dealing with twins,
in order to
distinguish them,
I ran an
antibodies profile.
Not only was it not Winthrop,
but the sample was female.
Two females,
to be exact.
Identical twins.
How much blood did you find?
Well, there were only
a couple of usable traces
for testing, but take a look.
He wasn't just
sending us a message.
Winthrop sent us
a murder weapon.
You got to be kidding.
(chuckles)
I know.
It's not really me, is it?
Yeah, I picked up these sleeves
at the costume shop
down the block.
Just wanted to see what
it would feel like
to be a serial killer.
So I pulled
the booking photo
of Jared Briscoe's tats.
Now, this liquid
that Winthrop sent us his
severed finger in is a mixture
of saline solution
and Cryers #2 Vermillion Ink.
Let me guess.
Used in tattoos.
Well, not just any tattoos.
These tattoos.
I've discovered
in my research that
certain tattoo artists
are quite particular
about which inks they use.
And Cryers #2 Vermillion
is very rare.
So rare,
in fact,
that I was able to
identify Briscoe's artist.
Okay,
but what does that
have to do with
the jar of ink that
Winthrop sent us?
Briscoe's artist
lives in Seattle.
He has an ex-wife
who moved to Vegas last year
to live with her twin sister.
Henry found blood on the
Castor and Pollux statuette
consistent with
identical twins.
Unknown females.
Not unknown now.
I've got names
and an address.
Building manager
confirmed
the loft's rented
to Amelia Vance.
What about the sister?
Name's Margo. She signed
onto the lease a year ago.
Manager said he stopped by
yesterday 'cause they complained
the AC wasn't working.
No one answered.
Amelia Vance,
LVPD.
SIDLE:
Another processed crime scene.
Strings and blood
suggest two events.
Two victims.
Again, he took
the bodies.
Russell's theory
was right.
Winthrop and his brother
have become one.
Dead ringers.
Just like old times.
Everything's been dusted,
everything's already processed.
Something is different
this time.
What do you mean?
Well, not everything's
been dusted,
and these green strings--
Gemini?
He didn't even try to hide them
among the other strings.
Different murder weapon, too.
No gaff. This time,
he bludgeoned them to death
with a marble sculpture.
And this rope he used?
Never seen anything like it.
Looks hand-braided.
Unusual fiber.
Some kind of powdery trace
on it. It's yellow.
It looks organic in nature.
Suggests secondary transfer.
How's it going
with your new toy?
Oh, camera's
acquired the image.
Just loading it now.
So this thing is gonna
give us T.O.D.
on our victims?
Well,
it's worth a try.
We've had this
hyperspectral imaging prototype
in the lab for over a month.
I've been waiting
to field-test it.
How's it work, exactly?
Well,
it's all about the hemoglobin
in the blood.
As a bloodstain ages,
the blood reacts with oxygen
and breaks down.
Right, which is why
blood changes color
from red to brown.
Well, this
camera records those changes.
And then maps them on a visible
reflectance spectrum.
So here is
the crime scene blood drop.
I'm comparing it
to a preset baseline
of a fresh blood drop.
Software
does the rest.
Calculating the difference
between the two spectra, thereby
computing the age of the blood.
Wow.
Oh. And...
we got our answer.
The murders took place...
12 hours ago.
So something is different.
Yeah, I mean,
the other murders
took place weeks before
we discovered
the crime scenes.
And he took days
to stage them. Winthrop
has accelerated his time frame.
But why?
If anything holds
from the past,
I'm sure he's
eager to tell us.
DISTORTED VOICE:
Clearly, our killer's
behavior has altered.
Two victims this time.
Female. Not college age.
Selected for other purposes.
One being a tattoo artist.
Elementary profiling would say
the killer's
psychosexual fixation
has given way
to a transformative agenda.
WINTHROP:
Is that what you'd say,
Mr. Russell?
Games are over, right?
We can finally
be honest with each other.
I'm sure you've
realized your mistake.
It's one others have made.
From the very beginning,
this world
tried to separate Jared and me.
So many have paid
for that injustice.
But those truly responsible
have escaped our wrath.
Until now.
So I ran audio analysis.
There's no evidence
of anyone else on the recording.
He has to have
somebody else helping him.
And it's not
his brother's ghost.
Right,
I mean, the guy was wounded.
So he had to lay low.
Somebody's been hiding him.
Mm-hmm.
He also doesn't
have any access
to his bank accounts, so...
somebody has to be
supporting him.
Larson says that it's
Winthrop's father, Collin.
Do you believe him?
All right,
I'm going to follow up
on both of them.
You were right about the rope
from the crime scene.
It's unusual. Definitely
not your standard bondage gear.
If anything,
it tends more
towards a fetish
of gardening.
Gardening?
You are looking here
at a handwoven plant fiber.
Specifically
Apocynum cannabinium.
Otherwise known as dogbane.
It's an invasive species.
Grows like a weed
almost anywhere.
So, not particularly helpful.
No. But...
the trace that you
pulled from the rope--
that's a different story.
You were also right--
it's organic.
These are pollen spores
from a cactus
called the Artemis bloom.
Artemis.
Goddess of the hunt.
Artemis was also the daughter
of Zeus, twin sister
to Apollo.
So I'm thinking
that perhaps it's
another message.
Probably.
Is there anything more
you can tell me about the plant?
Uh, the Artemis
bloom is very rare,
very delicate and
also very expensive.
It's the ultimate
hothouse flower.
Prized only by
serious enthusiasts
with deep pockets.
Now you're talking.
And you're thinking
that if Winthrop isn't
our flower enthusiast,
perhaps he's spending
time with someone who is.
Maybe his partner.
FINLAY:
Collin Winthrop.
Wealthy recluse, plant hobbyist.
Who spawned a bad seed.
Looks like our weekend
botanist had some practice.
Yeah, not just cultivating
the sick impulses
of his son, but seems
to have some of his own.
2006. Legal secretary
accused him of sexual assault.
Case never
went to trial.
Rumors of more women
and more allegations.
Well, Larson's
theory
about Winthrop Sr.
is getting better and better.
Mm. There's just
one problem.
Says here that he
reportedly fled to Mexico.
Which means that he could
still help his son from afar,
but couldn't participate
in the murders.
Unless Dad never
left the country.
These are my files, right?
The ones from my hotel room
after I was arrested?
Yeah, why?
What have you got?
Well, like I said,
I was following the money.
I was looking into the Winthrop
company financials.
I remember a series
of transactions,
donations to a
nature conservancy. I thought
it was a front, but...
Here it is.
Tax records show there
actually was a charity
devoted to the preservation
of exotic plant species.
How much you want
to bet that money
went straight into
Papa Winthrop's pockets?
Place is in
Briar Creek,
California.
San Diego County's
a little out of your
jurisdiction.
You know, I think I know a guy
who knows a guy.
(sighs)
Hey, Finlay, what's your 20?
Shaw and I are about
five minutes out.
All right, I'm gonna
get the lay of the land
out here and I'll
call you back.
Copy that.
You Ellis?
Yes, sir.
Good to meet you,
CSI Stokes.
(chuckles)
Call me Nick, please.
I got it.
Lab Director Nolan said
to extend you every courtesy.
Did he?
And from what I hear,
I may be working for you
full-time soon.
Oh, we'll see about that.
What's the situation out here?
We've got
the place surrounded.
Warrants in hand.
There's no activity
in the main house.
But we have eyes
on Collin Winthrop.
He's working in
the greenhouse.
What about Paul?
No sign of him.
But my money's on
the guesthouse. Shades are
drawn, place is secluded,
and has easy access
to the back gate.
Okay, why don't you and I
take the guesthouse.
We'll have your team
search the property.
When my guys get here,
they'll take Daddy Winthrop.
Collin Winthrop.
I'm CSI Finlay, LVPD.
I have a warrant
to search your property.
No warrant
for my arrest?
SHAW: Depends on
what we find.
What do you expect to find?
Your son.
Uh-huh.
SHAW: Maybe some evidence
linking the two of you
to the five women
who were murdered in Las Vegas.
My son and I
are innocent.
We are the
victims here.
Oh, yeah.
How do you figure that?
Well, Paul and I share
a natural appetite for...
certain pleasures.
Society may not approve,
and the law may attempt
to prohibit, but when
they are both impotent
to stop us,
we are accused
of brutalities.
Is that why you
fled to Mexico?
It's not a crime for a man
to want to abandon his life
for a time
and wander in the desert
in search of beauty.
Like you see here.
Mr. Winthrop, where is your son?
You know...
if you're not going
to arrest me,
I would like you two to leave.
♪ ♪
STOKES:
Oh, yeah, look at this.
Winthrop was licking his wounds.
STOKES:
Yeah, Winthrop was
definitely here.
ELLIS:
And he's gone now.
Freezer chest.
What do you think?
That's never good.
(creaking)
(over radio):
Finn, it's Nick-- I've got
two bodies here
in the guesthouse.
Twins.
Copy that.
You're under arrest.
SHAW:
Well, there's half the battle.
FINLAY:
It's not gonna help us
find his son.
So we'll find him.
(phone ringing)
"We"?
You mean I'm never
gonna get rid of you?
WINTHROP:
I see you met dear old Dad.
I know what you're thinking:
"chip off the old block."
But that's where you're wrong.
Get down, everybody!
(gunshot)
(frantic chatter)
Get down!
(gunshot)
(grunts)
Daniel!
(Shaw groaning in pain,
Finlay gasping)
Oh, God!
This is CSI Finlay.
I need medical
at my location, code three.
Get down.
The ambulance is gonna
be here any minute.
Come on,
hold on.
Breathe.
Breathe!
Found the sniper's nest
on a ridge
above the property
500 yards away.
He had a clear shot.
Did you scramble
the search team?
Got every
available unit on it.
The problem is,
Winthrop probably knows
this area better
than any of us.
Yep.
Gives him
the upper hand.
You gonna process
the rifle?
I thought you'd want
to do it yourself.
RUSSELL (over phone):
You sure you're okay?
Yeah, I'm okay.
D.B., Shaw took
the bullet for me.
I'm sorry, Jules.
Were you able to confirm that...
that Winthrop was the shooter?
Uh, Nick, uh,
just processed the gun.
His prints are on it.
Units are searching, but...
still no sign
of him.
Son of a bitch is long gone.
I'm gonna stay here
and collect the evidence.
Nick's coordinating
with the San Diego crime lab
to, uh, transport it all
back to Vegas.
No, no. You need
to get back here now, Jules.
I told you, I'm okay.
No, you're lucky--
Winthrop's beyond targeting
college girls now.
He shot his father,
and he tried to kill you.
This is getting personal.
I agree with Conrad.
All right, I will transport
Shaw's body and the others
back to Doc.
All right,
but afterwards,
you go straight home.
No arguments.
I confirmed C.O.D.'s
on our female victims.
Blunt force trauma
to the head.
Women had so
many fractures
to the body and skull,
I almost lost count.
ROBBINS:
It's not just
the blunt force trauma--
Winthrop's M.O.'s seemed
to have changed as well.
With his earlier victims,
there's no sign
of sexual activity.
You found semen?
Yeah. On both victims.
ROBBINS:
Latent bruising
plus the ligature marks
suggest, at the very least,
rough sex.
All right,
let's get the DNA
to Henry.
Hello?
Hi, Mrs. Devlin.
My name is Julie Finlay.
I work with the Las Vegas
Police Department.
Uh, I need to speak
with your granddaughter, Amy.
It's about her dad.
What'd you get?
So, Collin Winthrop had
extensive HD surveillance
at his house,
all over the property.
I mean, it's no surprise that
cameras caught Paul Winthrop
in his guesthouse, but...
this is what
I wanted you to see.
RUSSELL:
That's Collin Winthrop, right?
Who's he arguing with?
BRODY:
Our friend, Brother Larson.
RUSSELL:
That son of a bitch.
He told us that he had
stopped having dealings
with Winthrop Sr.
BRODY:
Could be we've been wrong.
Paul Winthrop had more
than one coconspirator.
It would help
if we knew what they
were talking about,
but obviously,
that's impossible.
This is gonna sound crazy...
but maybe the plants
can help us.
Thanks to the wealth
of digital recordings
that Winthrop has
been leaving for us,
Sara and I requisitioned
every audio analysis
program on the planet.
Including one
that listens to plants?
This one tracks minute
vibrations of all sorts
of different objects
in a space,
and analyzes the sounds
that created them.
Okay, I-I get that the sound of
a voice can vibrate the leaves,
but if you can't even see it,
then how do you measure it?
Well, this is where the
impossible becomes possible.
This software is able
to detect motion less than
one 100th of a pixel.
By combining and filtering
all that minute motion
over the image, it can actually
recover the sound
of their voices.
I'm impressed.
I am tired of the blackmail.
I'm tired of the lies.
I am not lying.
I'm telling you, I don't know.
Oh, you know.
You've always known.
Now, where is she?
LARSON:
That's not the reason
I came here.
No, you came here
for money, as usual,
and you're not gonna
get another cent
until you tell me
where my daughter is!
I-I know, you think
I'm gonna hurt her.
LARSON:
Like you did before.
Oh, that's all in the past.
I'm talking about now.
I'm talking about Paul.
He's figured it out.
He knows who May really is.
And I need to protect her,
'cause if he finds her,
he's gonna kill her.
He'll never find her,
and neither will--
LARSON:
And you got all that
from a plant?
Yeah, don't worry about it.
You know, I agree
with Winthrop.
I'm tired of all the lies.
Based on that conversation,
I did a little digging
around the Winthrop family tree.
And it turns out that
Collin Winthrop had a daughter.
May.
May went missing
around age 15.
Police at the time determined
that she was not kidnapped.
She just ran away.
And, Brother Larson,
I think you know
where she ran to.
Hmm. I do not.
Look,
I gave you a "get out
of jail free" card last time
because you helped me.
If you do not
come clean here, I promise you,
it's gonna go the other way.
I guess confession is
good for the soul.
(clears his throat)
I'm gonna tell you
a little story.
Not a pretty one.
About a young girl, 15.
Innocent... or so it seemed.
Pregnant,
she ran off to a convent.
There she gave birth
to twin boys, Paul and Jared.
But she didn't want them.
More than that, though,
she didn't want her father
to lay claim to them,
because... they were his blood.
You're-you're saying
that Paul and Jared
were the product of incest?
Yes.
Now, May hid behind a name,
Nancy Harper,
just like she hid the boys.
She found a home for Jared,
but Paul was sickly.
She tried to buy time
by pretending he died, but
Collin found Paul.
Raised him.
But he never found Jared...
or May.
She vanished.
You're pathetic, you know that?
We ran your DNA.
It's a familial match
to Paul Winthrop.
So, you can forget
your Chinatown story.
You are the father
of Paul and Jared.
You want the truth?
A lie can be a powerful thing.
It can be used to deceive.
It can be used to protect.
I admit I deceived you,
but I only did it
to protect May.
I had nothing
to do with these murders.
Come on, Mr. Russell.
You know what
this is all about?
Paul Winthrop has been killing
his mother over and over,
getting ready
for his End of Days.
And with Jared gone,
that time has come.
Paul will find May.
He will render judgment.
Unless you protect her.
As, apparently, I no longer can.
Okay.
If I'm gonna protect May,
I need to know where she is.
You already do.
The convent
she ran off to,
she never left it.
Your CSI Finlay--
she's met May.
Or should I say...
Sister Alice.
Every time I talk to that guy,
I feel like I need a shower.
I don't even know why I bother
to believe him anymore.
I keep thinking about
what Winthrop said to you
on the digital recorder--
that so many have paid
for the injustice
done to him and Jared.
"And yet, those
who are truly responsible
have escaped his wrath
until now."
Think about it.
He killed Collin Winthrop,
he tried to kill Finn.
At some point, he's probably
gonna come after you.
Yeah, but top of his list
has to be his mother
who abandoned him
and his brother, right?
Not only abandoned them.
Separated them,
cast them adrift.
Yeah, you know what?
She's the way
we're gonna catch this guy.
Okay, okay, so, Finn and I will
go up to Seattle.
We'll put this Sister Alice
into protective custody.
Use her as bait.
Right.
Do me a favor.
Call Seattle PD.
Let's get eyes
on the convent.
I'll pick up Finn
on the way to the airport.
Jules, it's me.
Hey, Jules, come on, open up.
(door creaks open)
(screaming)
WINTHROP:
Hello, Mr. Russell.
Jared and I have been
waiting for you.
What have you done?
Isn't it obvious?
She's dead.
Easy! Easy, now.
Let's not rush this.
Yeah, copy that, Nick.
As soon as you
wrap things up in San Diego,
I need you back here.
Russell and Finn are
on their way to Seattle.
All right. Yeah, call me
when you're on the road.
Hey. Seattle PD called back.
They went to the convent.
No sign of Sister Alice.
Nuns have no idea where she is.
Did you tell Russell?
I tried calling him
and Finn. I can't
get a hold of either of them.
Do you know where they are?
They're supposed to be
on their way up north,
but I got a bad feeling.
Listen, find Greg, then
meet me at Finn's condo.
Okay.
(groaning)
Aah! You sick bastard!
How does it feel...
to lose someone you love,
to have your heart
ripped away from you?
Oh, I know what you're thinking.
Was it quick? Did she suffer?
Did she scream?
You're the expert.
What does the crime scene
tell you?
Look at it.
I want you to know
she suffered.
She begged
for me to end it.
I don't believe you.
You wanted me
to take a look
at your crime scene?
The blood gives you away.
That's hardly a lethal loss
of blood, wouldn't you say?
And where's
the spatter?
Come on, where's the spatter?
You haven't even
put up all your strings.
You weren't
waiting for me.
I interrupted you
before you were finished.
Where's Finlay?
Where is she?
What do you got?
Russell and Finlay's
vehicles are here.
They're still
not answering.
I'll have my men
secure the building.
Then we'll move
in tactically.
Let's do it.
WINTHROP:
Finlay is dead.
I told you. She's already buried
in the desert
where you will never find her.
You're gonna tell me
where she is.
I don't really think you're
in a position to negotiate here.
You've been looking
for your mom, haven't you?
I know
who she is, Paul,
and I know where she is.
You're lying.
Even my father didn't know that.
That's 'cause your father's
not Collin Winthrop.
Your father was a pimp
who got a 15-year-old girl
pregnant with bastard twins.
You and your brother.
I should kill you now.
You do that,
and you'll never know.
Where is she?
Where's my mother?!
You tell me where Finlay is.
I'll tell you
where your mother is.
What's it gonna
be, Paul?
No!
(Winthrop gasps)
He knows where Finlay is.
Where is she?
Where is Finlay?
You'll never find her in time.
She's still alive.
She's got to be close.
He said he was gonna
take her to the desert.
He has to get her there somehow.
Greg, Morgan, where are you?
We just rolled up.
In the garage.
SIDLE:
We need to find
Winthrop's vehicle.
We believe it's on the premises.
Start canvassing.
Start running plates.
SANDERS:
Copy that.
Where is she?
Can you hear me? Where is she?!
MAN:
All right, that vehicle's
a negative. Next one.
BRODY:
Vehicle is a black
Lincoln Continental,
Nevada plates.
Plate number HRGK-698.
That car was reported stolen
from the California-Nevada
state line.
Greg, take a look at this.
This car was stolen this morning
from the California state line.
Oh, my God.
It's Finn.
Come on, Finn.
Come on.
I can't find a pulse,
but she's still warm.
Call medevac.
Yeah.
This is CSI Morgan
Brody, requesting
medevac assistance
at my location.
♪ ♪
(sighs)
D.B.
Hey.
How you doing?
One day at time.
Isn't that what they say?
So, I was just up
at the hospital,
and the nurse there told me
you've been going
up there every weekend.
Yeah, she's just not responsive.
I mean, her body's healing,
but they just
can't say
when she's gonna
regain consciousness.
Or if she will.
Well, one thing we do know is
that Winthrop is gonna recover,
and when he does, he's gonna pay
for what he's done.
Right?
Yeah.
Did Lab Director Nolan call you
about that job?
Oh. I'm so sorry.
Yeah, he did. He did, yeah.
Congratulations.
I hear you're gonna take it.
I was. I think
I'm gonna call him back,
tell him to hold off on that
for a little bit.
No, no, no, no.
Come on, sit-sit down.
Just give me...
give me one second.
Now... why would
you do that?
It's just not the right time.
Not right now, not with
what's going on with Julie.
(sighs)
Whatever happens with Jules--
there's nothing
you and I can do about that.
But if she was sitting
in that chair right now,
she would tell you
to get your ass
on that plane to San Diego,
and you know it.
You need to do this, bud.
You're not trying to sneak
out of here, are you?
(laughs)
No, I wouldn't do something
like that to you.
SANDERS:
Wow.
This is really happening.
I respect and love you both.
I'll miss you.
You better stay safe out there.
I will.
We're really happy for you.
Lab Director Nick Stokes.
SIDLE:
Has a nice ring,
doesn't it?
SANDERS:
Yeah.
We're still on for drinks
at McCarthy's, right?
Yeah. First round's on me.
(Sanders laughs)
The raise I hear you're getting,
I think
they should all be on you.
Oh, yeah, that's fair enough,
fair enough.
Yeah, well, see you then, hmm?
See you later.
♪ ♪