♪♪ ♪♪
(indistinct chatter)
Ready?
Quite the party.
SIDLE:
All I want to do...
is relax.
BRODY:
Just wait for our
poolside spa treatments.
FINLAY:
All right, we have
very big plans
tonight.
What you got?
Well, first of all,
we are going
to dinner at Marcienne's.
Steakhouse. Awesome.
I called ahead.
The chef is going
to prepare you
your own special
vegetarian dish.
Then we're going dancing at Tao,
where I got us a VIP table.
Ooh... fun.
Maybe we'll run
into Kim and Kanye.
Yes.
Oh, waiter.
Excuse me.
Could we have a very nice
bottle of champagne?
Finn, it's, like, barely 9:00
in the morning.
Uh, with
orange juice.
Mimosas sound so good.
You guys, we
have a few hours
before this
conference starts.
We have to make
the most of it.
Excellent.
I wonder what the guys
are up to at the lab.
RUSSELL: Ah, the smell of decomp
in the morning.
Heard we got
a goopy one.
Yep.
Think we, uh,
drew the short straw
this weekend,
huh, Dave?
Oh, come on, you guys.
Can't afford to send everybody
to the conference.
Anyway, they're all boring.
Where'd you find the body?
Abandoned construction site.
Real estate agent took
one look inside this drum
and called the cops.
Killer must have used something
to dissolve
the body.
I'll get this to Hodges.
Somebody didn't want this victim
to be identified.
Well, the La Tijera gang
has been known
to dissolve the bodies
of their victims.
Okay. Let's dump it
and see what we've got.
Girls are gonna be real sorry
they missed this one.
Man, I needed this.
♪♪ ♪♪
♪♪ Who... are you? ♪♪
♪♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪♪
♪♪ I really wanna know ♪♪
♪♪ Who... are you? ♪♪
♪♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪♪
♪♪ Who... ♪♪
♪♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪♪
♪♪ Are you! ♪♪
(indistinct chatter)
FINLAY: Wow, it's
a really good turnout.
Yeah, way better
than Boise last year.
I think, like, only three people
showed up to my presentation.
Oh, Jane Snyder's here.
Hey, hey. You guys want
to get something to eat?
I'm buying.
Oh, my gosh.
Sara?
Yoo-hoo, Sara?
Sarah, it is so good
to see you.
How are you doing?
Great.
How are you?
Oh, fantastic. I just signed
a deal to host
a new show
on WNE, Crime Time in Primetime.
That's very clever.
Uh, these are my colleagues.
This is Julie Finlay
and Morgan Brody.
Dr. Jane Snyder, but most people
just call me Dr. Jane.
You probably know that.
I've read your book.
Oh, lucky you.
So if you have a copy,
I'm happy to autograph it.
Oh, no. Sorry, I forgot.
Well, I hope you're all coming
to my presentation
this afternoon,
"Defending Your Evidence:
How to Avoid Getting
Skewered on the Stand."
That is a great title.
(laughing):
I know it is.
You know, testifying
is an art form.
Not all criminalists
are good at it.
But I don't have
to tell youthat, do I, Sara?
MAN:
Dr. Jane!
Hey, Travis!
Well, I'll see you guys later.
Bring the book.
I'll sign it
for all of you.
All right, what is
the story with you two?
We were criminalists together
back in San Francisco,
and then she switched sides.
She became an expert
witness for the defense.
Did she, uh, "skewer" you
on the stand?
No, no, no.
Not me,
but a trainee of mine.
It was his first time
on the stand, and
he was nervous,
and she made him seem
completely incompetent.
She questioned
his protocol, his ethics.
BRODY: Guess that's why
those defense attorneys
pay her the big bucks.
SIDLE: Yeah, well, in exchange
for a fat paycheck,
she helped put a rapist
back on the street, so...
That is quite a display
you have there.
Thank you.
It's the latest in digital
downloading software.
How does it work?
Uh, let's say you
witnessed a crime,
captured part of it
on your phone.
This software allows
law enforcement to download
your most recent
photos and videos
right on the spot.
No access to
e-mails and texts.
No need to give up your phone.
Fascinating.
I wouldn't mind a demonstration.
SIDLE:
I think Morgan and I
are gonna go check out
the new tape lifts.
Yeah. I... that's...
Bye.
Looking good, Finn.
Oh, thank you.
I was hoping you'd be here.
Getting off
in a couple of hours.
Buy you a drink?
Absolutely.
Based on the narrow sciatic
notch of the pelvic bone,
I can tell you
our victim is male.
What about race? Or age?
The, uh, frontal suture
in the skull is closed,
telling me that
he's older than 18,
but beyond that, I can't say.
As for race,
if you'll take a look
at the maxillary bones,
you can see
they have a parabolic shape,
indicating
European descent.
So, adult white male, shot
with a medium-caliber pistol.
We found this bullet when we
poured him through the sifter.
Looks like he was shot
execution style.
Doc, you gonna be
able to extract DNA
from his dental pulp?
No, there's a risk
of bacterial contamination.
Our best chance
for DNA
is extracting marrow
from the femur.
If we can get a profile,
we'll run it through CODIS.
Maybe somebody's missing
our goop man here.
I can't believe you signed us up
for Snyder's presentation.
That was, like, two weeks ago.
How was I supposed
to know you had
some kind of history
with Dr. Jane?
I think it'll be fun.
I went on YouTube,
watched some of her videos.
I think she's gonna
be pretty entertaining.
Looking for someone?
A certain vendor, perhaps?
Yes, his name is Mark, and he is
meeting me here for a drink.
Well, please be careful.
Last time you picked up a guy...
No, no, no, no.
I have known him
for a very, very long time.
Really?
Yeah.
How do you know
each other?
Well, I met him five years ago
at a conference.
We spent some quality time
together,
and it's been
an annual tradition ever since.
So, you only see him
once a year?
Well, he lives
in Boston.
And the rest of the time,
you just talk and text?
It's not really
that kind of relationship.
It's, um...
We're just having a good time.
That's what I
wish I could do.
When a guy asks
me out, I...
it's like I have to make a pro
and con list before I say yes.
That's all right. It sounds like
you're looking for Mr. Right.
There's nothing wrong
with that.
Yeah, and I just think
that relationships
are really hard, and it's just
easier sometimes to...
keep it fun.
Less of a chance
of getting hurt.
Yeah, not so many
disappointments.
SIDLE:
Well, that's true.
But then you never get to make
a real connection with someone.
I mean, to be with somebody
who really gets you,
who loves you for who you are--
I don't know.
I think it's worth the risk.
Especially when he's
as hot as that.
FINLAY:
Bye, girls.
We're not gonna see her
for the rest of this...
The whole time--
she's gone, she's gone.
Reduced to a jar of goop.
Not how I'd want to end up.
Pretty sure our victim didn't
want to end up that way, either.
No, I plan on being
meticulously embalmed.
My chiseled features perfectly
preserved for all of eternity,
before being entombed alongside
my mother in a marble mausoleum.
You've given this a lot
of thought, haven't you?
Haven't you?
Oh, I don't know.
You know, cremate me.
Sprinkle me over a farm
so I can be of use.
Have you figured out
how this guy
got turned into goop?
Muriatic acid.
Killer probably assumed that it
would dissolve the entire body,
but didn't count on the fact
that the decomp process itself
gradually weakens the acid.
Unfortunately,
you can find this stuff
in any home improvement store
in the country,
so it doesn't really help us
I.D. the killer.
DNA paid off.
Got an I.D.
on our vic.
Paul Carson.
Security guard
from Henderson.
His wife
reported him missing.
Said he left for
work three days ago,
never came back.
There's a BOLO out on his van.
Do we know where he worked?
The Mediterranean.
Isn't that
where the conference is?
Yeah, and get this--
according to the hotel manager,
Carson's key card was used
just a few hours ago.
So, his killer could be
at the hotel right now.
Come on.
Hey, Morgan.
Is anyone sitting here?
It's all yours.
Thanks.
(audience murmurs excitedly)
♪♪ ♪♪
Strobe lights?
Really?
I told you, she puts
on a good show.
I am Dr. Jane Snyder.
(audience applauds)
SNYDER:
Thank you!
I am so excited to be here
to teach you how to defend
your evidence.
First and foremost,
the courtroom is a stage.
And it is your job
to perform!
♪♪ ♪♪
(women shrieking happily)
Oh. My. God.
(gasps)
(gunshots, screaming)
(people screaming)
Vicki!
(sounds muffled)
SIDLE:
It's all right.
It's over.
It's clear!
It's clear.
I'll go get
some help.
(indistinct murmuring, sobbing)
(sobs)
Vicki! Hey.
Just hang on, okay?
SIDLE:
This is CSI Sidle.
There's been a mass shooting
at the Mediterranean Hotel
forensic conference.
Roll paramedics and PD.
Code 3!
(Brody sobs)
Come on! Come on!
Morgan...
Come on. Come on.
SIDLE:
Morgan..
BRODY:
Please, come on.
SIDLE:
She's gone.
You're good.
Morgan.
Morgan...
Come on.
Morgan, she's gone.
She's gone.
Morgan! Look at me!
You okay?
Are you hurt?
No.
(sobs)
What the hell just happened?
How many shooters were there?
Just one.
An assault rifle.
It looked like an AR-15.
So you saw him?
He went out
the back door.
I'm gonna call Finn.
Admit it, Russell Wilson
is no Tom Brady.
You're just saying that
because he's married
to a supermodel.
No, I'm saying that
because he has three
Super Bowl rings.
And he's married
to a supermodel.
Yeah, well, at least
my team doesn't cheat.
Ouch.
You really know
how to hurt a guy.
Aw, poor baby.
(phone buzzing)
No?
No.
(giggles)
(phone continues buzzing)
(bell dings)
No!
(panting)
Are you...
Yeah, I'm okay.
That doesn't look good.
(groaning)
Hold this really tight.
FINLAY:
Oh, no!
Hey, Russell.
Have you heard
from the girls?
Yeah, they're okay.
Police are
on the scene.
Five dead.
More injured.
Is the shooter still in there?
We're still getting
reports of gunfire
in other parts
of the hotel.
We should get
down there.
I tried.
Hotel's on lockdown.
They're not letting
anybody in.
I'm gonna go meet
Ecklie at PD.
All right, well,
what can I do?
Uh... keep-keep working
the Carson case.
I mean, one thing we know
is that whoever killed him
used his key card
today at the hotel.
Yeah, so you think that
his killer is the shooter.
Get an I.D.
Maybe we can
stop this guy.
(sirens wailing)
Move. Move!
SWAT Two, up.
We got two down.
Dead.
Dead. One.
All right, let's move.
(indistinct conversations,
radio chatter)
PARAMEDIC:
Let's go ahead
and set her up.
(indistinct chatter continues)
(phone ringing)
Hi.
SWAT leader just called me
and told me that
you refused to evacuate.
I told you to get
out of there.
Shooter came in
through a side door.
I'm hoping he left a print.
I grabbed supplies
from the vendors...
Sara, the shooter
is still in the building.
Look, you survived once today.
Please don't push your luck.
SWAT has cleared the room.
There's deputies posted.
There's no way he's
getting back in here.
I can help, Russell.
Please, I need to do something.
All right, all right, all right.
Just... be careful
and get out of there
as soon as you can.
I will.
Listen, I talked to Finn.
Her friend's in bad shape.
I know that. I know, I know.
Engineering is on standby.
They'll get them out
as soon as it's safe.
Okay.
Hey.
Thank you for getting
Morgan out of there.
Yeah. She didn't want to leave.
Yeah, I'm sure.
I told her I needed her
back in the lab.
Look, she's using
this new software
she got from one of the vendors,
where she can download footage
from other people's cell phones.
Hopefully somebody caught
an image of the gunman,
'cause hotel
surveillance
went down right
before the shooting.
You're kidding.
No.
A security guard from
that hotel was murdered
three days ago.
His-his key card
was taken.
That's probably how the shooter
gained access to
the control room.
So he really planned this out.
Oh, yeah.
Most spree killers
fantasize for years
before they even pick up a gun.
Couldn't be a coincidence the
guy hit a forensics conference.
I mean, maybe he's got a beef
with law enforcement.
Yeah. What is that?
It's SWAT.
We're patched
into their live feed.
Clearing floor
by floor.
WOMAN (over phone):
I'm sorry, ma'am, there's
a gunman in the building.
FINLAY:
I know there's a gunman.
He just shot my friend!
Okay? You need to get us out
of the elevator now.
We have to secure the area
first. Stay with him.
I'm doing the best that I can,
but if I do not get him
to the hospital soon,
he is going to bleed to death.
They can't get in there
until it's clear, ma'am.
I understand!
Will you just hurry?!
They said they can't
fix the elevator until
they get the gunman.
Which I'm sure
is gonna be really soon.
Kind of romantic.
Here with you.
Dim lighting.
This whole bleeding
from the stomach thing
is kind of killing
the mood, isn't it?
You're losing way
too much blood.
A tampon?
Believe it or not,
these things were really used
in the 19th century
to plug bullet holes.
Ooh.
Ooh...
I'm sorry.
So...
you know sports and history.
Just basic first aid.
You're doing great.
Really wish that I had
gone through with my...
choice to go to med school
right about now.
(groans)
I wish you did, too.
Why didn't you?
I took a lecture
with this guy
Alec Jeffreys
on DNA fingerprinting,
and that was it.
I wanted to be a criminalist.
I slept through
a lot of lectures.
Had a lot of fun, though.
Wish I knew you back then.
Oh, come on,
I'm still fun.
Just wait till
I get out of here.
I'll hold you to that.
It's gonna be okay.
Let's go, let's go.
Go!
Hands!
Show me your hands!
Don't shoot.
Get on
the ground!
Okay.
On the ground now!
He needs help!
Now! On the ground!
On the ground now!
Okay!
Now!
He needs help. Don't shoot.
Okay, okay, okay.
He shot Perry.
I thought he was going
to shoot me, too.
Frame up on his face.
ECKLIE:
He's got dark hair.
According to Sara,
our gunman had
long blond hair.
Well, you gotta go with Sara.
She's a trained observer.
(sighs)
ECKLIE:
That's not our guy.
Let him go.
Cut him loose,
that's not our guy.
Let's go!
Move, let's go, let's go!
RUSSELL:
The gunman could've shot
that guy, but he didn't.
Why not?
His lucky day.
Who knows?
Oh, it's gotta
be more than that.
It's gotta be
something else.
Where... come
here, look-it.
The shooting began
in Conference Room A, right?
Yeah.
According
to Sara,
at 4:17 the
shooter comes in
through the
side door here,
shoots here,
here and here,
but never fires
into this area.
Then he goes down
the hallway here,
past B and C,
all the way to
Conference Room D.
And then he shoots the place up.
Why?
Why'd he skip
those two rooms?
Maybe nobody was in them.
No. No, no, I checked.
All four rooms,
at the time of the
shooting, were filled.
I mean, that's what
a spree killer wants, right,
is a high body count?
So why not
shoot up the casino,
for God's sake?
Or at least
the pool area?
You're right.
He's upstairs,
where the rooms are.
Doors are locked.
No crowds.
And no way out.
No, no. No.
This guy
is targeting
these areas.
Right there.
You're saying he's looking
for specific people.
This is not
a random killing spree.
Our gunman has a hit list.
♪♪ ♪♪
She was a mom.
I noticed a C-section scar
when I did my initial exam.
That's Morgan's friend.
The one she tried to save.
Gave her CPR.
Size of a .223.
Consistent with an AR-15.
America's favorite
assault rifle.
Capable of firing
700 rounds a minute.
That kind of firepower
belongs in a war zone,
not on our streets.
Our killer wanted to make
sure that he hit his targets.
He didn't care
who else he shot.
I wasn't aware that he was going
after specific people.
Some of these victims were
most likely collateral,
but the rest were
on his hit list.
I just need to figure out
what they had in common
so maybe we can figure out
who he's going after next.
♪♪ ♪♪
Heard you found
Paul Carson's van.
Yeah, abandoned in an alley
behind a strip joint
off of Fremont Street.
Yeah, that part of town,
nobody's quick to call the cops.
Well, the killer's smart.
Just like he thought
he'd conceal Carson's I.D.
by turning his body into goop.
Yeah, he didn't want
anything to get in the way
of his shooting up
the hotel today.
His wife reported him
missing three days ago.
We know that Carson
went to work.
So I pulled hotel surveillance,
and you can clearly see his van
parked in his usual spot.
But then I noticed something.
Check out this guy
in the hoodie.
You can't see his face,
and it looks like
he's walking past the van,
yet he never exits frame.
So he broke
into the back of the van,
and then waited for Carson
to get off work.
Drive!
And forced him to drive to the
abandoned construction site.
Shot him, dumped his body
into the barrel.
Poured muriatic acid on him
to dissolve the body.
Then got rid of the van.
And the only image we
have of this guy...
we can't make out the face?
No, but we might have his DNA.
I found this used tissue
underneath the backseat.
According to Carson's wife,
Carson was the only one
who used the van.
I suppose that could've come
from the shooter's pocket.
Have Henry run
that, all right?
Tell him to put it in
the front of the line.
HODGES:
This eyewitness software
is incredible.
No more scanning through
endless hours of footage.
Yeah. Finn's friend
Mark was selling it.
You just punch in the
time frame, and that's
the only footage
it downloads.
Hopefully one of the cameras
caught the shooter.
Have you heard
from Finn yet?
She's still stuck
in the elevator.
Well, I'm sure
they'll get them out soon.
Yeah.
That's the door
that the shooter came in.
Damn. He's blocked
behind a pillar.
All right, let me try
another clip.
That must've been terrifying.
Yeah. It was.
You know, you don't have
to be here for this.
I can take care of it.
I want to be here.
You know, when I heard
about what happened,
I was really worried.
I just...
I'm-I'm just glad you're okay.
Thank you.
Can we, um, scroll forward
frame by frame? I think
we might get something.
That's him.
Okay, let me zoom in.
I'll isolate his face,
run it through
facial recognition.
(indistinct radio transmission)
Morgan got an I.D.--
Jeff Lasky.
26-year-old out of Phoenix.
I have a warrant
for the guy's cell phone.
See if we can triangulate that.
RUSSELL:
That's just gonna tell us
he's still in the hotel, right?
If we tap into his Wi-Fi,
we can track him down
to within a few feet.
Suspect's name is Jeff Lasky.
He's on the ninth floor,
heading east.
MAN:
Copy that.
Ready? Go!
There he is!
Drop the gun!
Drop the gun now!
It's over, Lasky. Drop the gun!
Now!
Drop the gun now!
Shots fired! Shots fired!
Suspect is down.
MAN:
All right, move in. Check him.
MAN: We got him. All right,
continue sweep. Let's go!
All right,
get the bomb dogs in there
and sweep the hotel.
Make sure this guy
did not leave us any surprises.
Let's get Finn
out of the elevator.
ECKLIE:
And give engineering
an all clear.
(phone dings)
They got him.
They're gonna get
us out of here.
Mark, can you hear me?
They're coming
to get you right now.
Celine.
What?
Dion.
Show later.
Oh. Yeah.
I guess I'm more
of a U2 kind of girl.
You know, uh,
I saw them in Ireland.
Haven't been.
What? To a U2 concert?
To Ireland.
It was amazing.
I, uh, was there
on a Eurail pass,
and I was hanging out
at a bar in Dublin,
and all of a sudden U2 walked
right in and they...
started...
No!
Oh, God! Mark?
Come on, come on.
You can do it.
Breathe, breathe.
Mark, breathe.
(grunting)
Mark?
(doors open)
(groans)
He just crashed!
I didn't get a pulse.
All right,
we'll take it from here.
You got him?
Yeah.
Get a line in here!
Breathe, Mark.
Phoenix PD did a search
of Lasky's house.
Apparently he was obsessed
with the man
who murdered his wife
and daughter three months ago.
Uh, Luke Reaser.
Luke Reaser?
I heard about that case.
He raped them
before he killed them, right?
That was Lasky's family?
Yeah, that's enough to put
anybody over the edge.
Yeah, but Reaser was caught.
He's awaiting trial.
Why would Lasky go
on a rampage today?
Because Reaser
should've been put
behind bars a long time ago.
He raped and murdered
a teenage girl
back in 2012 in Texas.
Set the place on fire
in order to cover his tracks.
The evidence wasn't
strong enough to convict.
So, then he moves to Phoenix,
where he murders Lasky's family.
You know, Morgan, three of the
CSIs that were killed today,
they were from the crime lab
in Dallas.
Lasky must've blamed them
for putting Reaser
back on the street.
They're not the only ones
he was gunning for.
Guess who testified
for the defense.
Of course I'll talk
to the press.
We need to give
WNE the exclusive, though.
Now?
I can take care of that.
He was after you.
I'll call you back.
The gunman, Jeff Lasky.
Ring a bell?
What about Luke Reaser?
You helped put
that son of a bitch
back on the street,
and he went on
to murder Lasky's family.
If I remember correctly,
the prosecution didn't have
that much evidence
against Reaser.
And what they did
have was mishandled.
No, no, no, no.
I talked to the lab in Dallas.
A DNA analyst transposed
two numbers on a piece of paper.
It was a simple mistake, Jane.
And someone in the lab
should have caught it.
A guilty man went free
because of a typo.
It was sloppy work.
Who knows what other
mistakes that lab made?
You used to care
about the truth.
Come on, Sara.
We're not on
the same side anymore.
It's my job to poke the holes
in the science.
And put on
a show for the jury, right?
Luke Reaser raped
and killed Jeff Lasky's
wife and five-year-old daughter.
Slit their throats
and then dumped their
bodies in the trash.
That's why Lasky
went on this rampage.
11 people are dead
because of you.
I didn't put the gun
in Lasky's hand.
No, you kind of did.
Lasky sent you e-mails.
He sent you threats
over a month ago.
You didn't report it.
I get threats
all the time.
News flash, Sara,
I'm a woman with
strong opinions.
Some people
just don't like me.
Uh-uh.
None of this would've happened
if you had just gone
to the police, Jane.
Why don't you put that
in your press conference?
Keep me posted, then.
Take a look at this.
SWAT found
this man's body in the doorway
of his room on the 15th floor.
Looks like he was shot
when he opened the door.
Hotel security said
it happened at 4:17.
That's when the shooting started
in Conference Room A.
Lasky couldn't have been
two places at once.
I think there had to be
a second shooter.
You may be right.
Got DNA off of that
used tissue I found in
the security guard's van.
Jeff Lasky didn't kill him.
But DNA did
come back
with a match to this guy.
Cliff Ballard.
I've seen him before.
Yeah, this is the guy
that SWAT found
standing over a body
in the hallway.
He was unarmed
and acting scared,
like he was just
another hotel guest.
SANDERS:
Well, that's why Sara
only saw one shooter.
'Cause Lasky was shooting up
the conference rooms
while Ballard was shooting
people upstairs.
Yeah, well,
SWAT let this guy go.
He's still in the hotel.
SWAT's still
searching the hotel.
No sign of Ballard.
Please tell me
you found something.
Actually, Ballard was a CSI.
And he just got
out of prison.
Served nine years
for felony fraud.
Falsifying evidence.
Yeah, didn't he work out of
the crime lab in Baltimore?
Yeah.
Well, I remember
when he was arrested.
It was this huge scandal.
Every case he worked on
was called into question.
Well, maybe
he blames his coworkers
for turning him in.
No, no,
'cause then he would've shot up
the lab in Baltimore.
No.
All of Ballard's work
would have been audited
by a team of
forensic experts, right?
Criminalists from
all over the country,
selected to evaluate his cases.
They're the ones
who put him in prison.
Could be his targets.
Let me see if I can find out
who was on
that team.
I've been through all of
Jeff Lasky's e-mails,
his phone records,
his texts,
his Web history.
I can't find
any evidence that he's
working with Ballard.
All right, so what do we know
about our two shooters?
Lasky...
the grieving father, husband
that wanted to get even with
the murder of his family.
Ballard's the ex-con
who, presumably,
is going after the people
who put him in prison.
Two different shooters...
two different agendas.
But with one
big thing in common:
They both hate
law enforcement.
Now, we've been assuming
that the shooters
were working together, right?
What if they weren't?
So they both go on a rampage
same time, same place?
We've been
looking
for a connection
between these guys
and we haven't found one,
so maybe their connection
is the conference itself.
I mean, think about this.
Once a year, CSIs and cops
from all over the country
get together
at this conference.
Now, if you had a beef
with law enforcement,
what better place
to come than right here?
I found that list of people
who served on
Ballard's audit.
That guy, right there.
That's the guy that Ballard was
standing over in the hallway.
He must've killed him
right before SWAT arrived.
SANDERS:
Sara.
Oh, God.
She was on that team.
Notify SWAT.
I'll call Sara.
I'm on the 18th floor.
I got a text.
Cliff Ballard?
He's in prison.
BALLARD:
I got out in August.
Give me the phone.
All right.
Now the gun.
(gun clatters on floor)
The text telling me
to come up here...
it was from you, wasn't it?
I wanted to get you alone.
This woman, Linda Gage?
She was part of the review team.
You killed her, didn't you?
She helped send me to prison.
Just like you.
It was not personal.
We were just asked to take
a look at your work.
I was a good criminalist.
I know you were, Cliff.
You did a lot of good work
over the years.
I put rapists and murderers
behind bars.
They were all guilty.
They deserved what they got.
I'm sure they did, but...
you tampered with the evidence
to get the results you wanted.
I didn't have a choice.
The detectives
come to you.
They want a slam dunk.
Evidence isn't always like that.
It's a lot of pressure.
I've been there many times.
Convictions hinge on
conclusive evidence,
and if you don't
have enough,
you feel like a failure.
I had to do something.
I understand.
It's natural to want
to help the case
along, to...
You don't understand!
If you did, you wouldn't
have helped send me away!
Cliff, wait.
You treated me like a criminal.
(cocks gun)
Destroyed my life!
(gunshot)
Move!
You okay?
You good?
Thank you. Yeah.
SWAT OFFICER:
Shots fired, shots fired.
Suspect down.
(beeping steadily)
(indistinct conversations)
Hey.
Nurse said you
were out of surgery
and that you needed a visitor.
Yep. I got to the Pearly Gates.
They sent me back.
I'm glad they did.
You saved my life.
Well, buy me dinner.
We'll call it even.
Deal.
So the doctor said
that you're gonna need
some time to recover.
And that you cannot
fly back to Boston for
at least two weeks, so...
I was hoping that
maybe we could...
hang out.
You know, when you get
back up on your feet.
You mean date?
Yeah.
Like, uh, dinner and a movie
and a good-night kiss.
Well, as you know,
dating sometimes
can turn into a...
(sighs)
...real relationship.
I'm willing to risk it.
Me, too.
Hydrogen peroxide.
To clean off the blood.
Thank you.
We always wear gloves
when we go to the crime scene.
You know?
We're never there...
there when it...
when it actually happens.
I know.
Are you okay?
I'm okay.
Ballard wanted
you dead, and...
if SWAT hadn't been there...
But they were.
Finn called.
She said
they still have that
VIP table at Tao.
(laughs)
What do you think?
Dancing... tequila...
Yeah.
Tequila sounds
pretty good, yeah.