(indistinct chatter)
♪ ♪
PHILLIPS:
There's a lot of
damage to the neck.
I'm counting three
sharp-force injuries,
and I saw five more in the back.
Got arterial
spray over here.
So he was standing right
there when he was stabbed.
You know, if that's the case,
you'd expect to see
more blood
on his torso.
He must have been
dressed, right?
Clothing shielded him
from the blood, and...
the killer stripped him?
RUSSELL: Possibly.
Got a lipstick case here.
It's got bloodstains on it.
A woman was here?
Could be another victim.
Maybe an attempted rape
that took a turn.
Guy picks on the wrong woman,
she pulls out a blade
and stabs him.
Yeah, then why wouldn't
she just run away?
Stripping a victim usually
suggests a sexual component.
Maybe our mystery woman
was the predator.
Could be a vigilante.
I think we're getting a little
ahead of ourselves, actually.
You may be right.
Hey, guys?
What is it?
Uh, I'm not sure.
But it kind of looks like a face
stamped in blood.
PHILLIPS:
Might be the dead guy's face.
RUSSELL:
Yeah, but our victim barely has
any blood on his face.
I'm not so sure
he could leave a mark like that.
There could've been
a struggle during the stabbing.
Assailant gets blood on his
or her face,
gets taken down,
face-planted onto the concrete,
leaving the impression.
Could be our first impression
of the killer.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
(camera shutter clicking)
So, how is the Blood Whisperer
doing with the blood portrait?
Not so bloody well.
Image filters are giving me
no additional detail,
and I tried
facial recognition
software
with no luck.
A face no forensic
method could love.
You know, the weird thing is,
if you or I had
our lovely faces
smeared in blood
and mushed into concrete,
the resulting stamp
would be bolder in some areas
but not in others.
Right. Because our faces
aren't flat.
Yeah, but this face is.
BRODY:
Well, we think it could be
the face of our killer.
So any chance it's a
physical deformity of some sort?
Maybe.
BRODY:
Well, DNA says
that all the blood at the scene
belongs to the victim,
and prints
gave us an I.D.
His name is Nelson Kern.
He's a local with a few priors
for burglary.
Officers are headed
to check out his apartment now,
and Nick just pinged his cell.
(phone ringing)
Yeah, flip it open.
Let's see what
we got in there.
There's a bloody purse
right there.
Suggests
female killer.
You know, there was
a dropped lipstick.
Nick.
Purse might be hers.
Oh...
It's rubber. Like some kind
of life-size doll.
Or a costume.
Yeah, maybe.
It's hollow.
So we got...
fake body, real blood.
Yeah, looks
like it.
And if Nelson Kern's cell
phone ended up in here,
I'm betting that's his blood
smeared all over it.
♪ ♪
RUSSELL:
Hey, buddy.
Hey.
Homicide find
anything
in Nelson Kern's apartment?
No, nothing useful.
Apparently
the guy was a loner.
No job, no family in the area.
So how's it going
with her?
We're doing pretty good.
Doc's still...
working on the body, but
he did send these over.
The stab wounds in the suit
line up perfectly with the
stab wounds in Kern's back.
RUSSELL:
So clearly he was wearing this
when he was attacked.
Do we know
why he was wearing it?
Yeah, I found some
similar suits online
and a site
dedicated to those
who wear them. They call
themselves Rubber Dolls.
Men who wear these suits
and masks
transform into females.
It's a form of full-body
cross-dressing.
Like living Barbies.
Or, in this case, not so living.
ROBBINS:
Slight bruising
on the edges
of the lacerations suggests
the weapon wasn't
particularly sharp.
Maybe a dull knife.
I'm not so sure
it was a knife.
Based on the square
edges of the wounds.
Severed his
carotid artery.
C.O.D. was
exsanguination.
Looks like
a human bite mark.
Yeah, it's one of several
incidental injuries I noted,
including abrasions on his
wrists and bruising on his arms.
Could be he was bound.
He was also
under the influence.
Tox screen showed alcohol
and ecstasy in his system.
Did you hear
about the rubber suit?
Yeah. Dressed up and messed up.
Bad combo.
I pulled a lot of trace
from the suit's skin.
Uh, granted, a lot of it may be
transfer from the Dumpster,
but so far we've got
two perfumes,
baby oil, carpet fibers
and residue
from champagne, vodka
and mint liqueur.
Ooh, mint. Sounds
like a wild party.
Mmm.
With a brutal end.
(grunting)
The blood smeared on the mask,
that would explain
how the face
was stamped
on the concrete.
We may not know much
about Nelson Kern,
but maybe
the suit's maker does.
Superglue fuming didn't provide
any viable prints,
but there was one embedded
in the silicone.
Check it out.
RUSSELL:
Looks like someone
touched the skin
before it was set.
We know who?
Print came back to a local
named Belinda Goff.
(grunting)
(woman chuckles)
I told you
it'll stretch,
but there is no packing
Babe Ruth into Beyoncé.
Uh, excuse me.
Ms. Goff?
Uh, your height's
gonna cost you.
Pardon me?
It's $1,500 for the standard
doll, but you're, what, six-two?
(chuckles)
Big and tall ain't cheap
or easy.
No. No, I'm not
interested in purchasing.
I'm, um...
I got a few questions for you.
Okay. Um...
(clears throat)
why don't you go
get comfortable
in your skin.
Okay, let me guess.
College professor doing
a sociological survey,
uh, "Inside the Bizarre World
of Rubber Dolls."
Actually,
my interest is not academic.
It's criminal. I'm D.B. Russell
with the crime lab.
Can you take
a look at these for me
and tell me
if you recognize them?
He was killed
while wearing her.
Yeah, she's my work.
Right. Okay. And...
what about Mr. Kern there?
What can you tell me about him?
Nothing.
The men who come here,
they're not big on names.
They-they pay with cash.
And-and when my creations
walk out this door,
they take on a life
of their own.
Doing what, exactly?
Look...
once transformed,
the dolls might go out together,
flaunt their curves.
Depending
on whatever
intimate anatomy
they've paid me to install,
they can...
No, I see. I see.
Kind of.
(sighs)
Look, Rubber Dolling
is just a way
for men to inhabit the bodies
of beautiful women.
For whatever the reason,
from gender dysphoria to...
pure curiosity.
Um, you said that the-the dolls
hang out together.
Do you know where?
(sighs)
A man was murdered.
Maybe one of his fellow dolls
might be able to...
Can you hold?
Oh. Oh.
Go here.
Just don't say I sent you.
If you get bounced,
I mean.
♪ ♪
Well... welcome
to the dollhouse.
You're staring.
Yeah. Well, so are you.
At least we're not
the only ones underdressed.
The dolls have their admirers.
So, we're, like, what,
a couple of blocks
from the crime
scene, right?
That odds are pretty good that
Nelson Kern was here last night.
Killer could have
stalked him from here.
Somebody must have seen
something last night, right?
Shall we...
shall we mingle?
Sure.
Call me.
♪ ♪
Hey!
Stop!
(grunts)
Hey. Take it easy.
Now, why are
you running off?
LVPD.
RUSSELL:
Ladies, ladies.
Come on, now.
Hey, girls, come on.
Let's everybody
just take a breath now.
We don't want
to mess up
our suits, do we?
Do I have to tell you my name?
Or you can start
with telling me why you ran.
I'm a high school counselor.
The last thing I need is my
extracurriculars going public.
I just... I figured
that you and the other
cop were raiding the place.
What made you think I was a cop?
Please.
It's 31 flavors
of freak in here.
In walks Mr. Vanilla.
Scanning the place like
some Nordic Terminator.
How'd you know I was...?
Never mind.
Actually, we're CSIs.
We're here investigating
the murder of this man.
You know him?
No.
What about her?
Charlene.
Charlene's dead?
I'm afraid so.
What can you tell me
about her?
(sighs)
Charlene was a newcomer.
Started showing up
maybe six weeks ago,
but quickly became
the belle of the ball.
Were all of the other dolls
as charmed by her?
Well, I'm sure some of the more
Raggedy Anns around here
were jealous.
Roomful of divas,
there will be rivalries.
And these suits don't breathe,
so it can get heated.
Excuse me.
Do you mind if we chat?
Will you excuse us
just for a second?
Thank you.
Um...
face-to-face?
Would that be
all right?
I couldn't
help but notice
you've got a nasty scratch
on your knee there.
I tripped.
(chuckles)
These, uh, four-inch heels.
Murder, I bet.
Worth the pain.
Where'd you take your tumble?
I'm-I'm only
asking because
that-that shade of blue--
there's a wall painted
that color in an alley
not too far from here,
and one of the dolls
was-was killed last night.
I believe her name
was Charlene.
If there's something
you can tell us,
we'd appreciate it.
Anything.
I didn't fall.
Okay. All right.
What-what happened?
I don't wear this for attention.
It's just, it's something
to see in the mirror
to make this world suck
a little bit less.
I understand.
Someone else didn't.
I was attacked.
Last weekend
after leaving here.
Yo, I bet it
makes you sweat.
That costume.
It makes you stink.
You know what it
makes me? Sick.
You perverts
disgust me.
(grunts)
Did you report it to the police?
I had enough humiliation.
Okay.
But...
if this same animal
killed Charlene...
I did catch his license plate.
(engine revving)
What kind of perv
goes out like that?
What do you mean by that?
Wearing that costume,
hiding his face.
Guy's obviously embarrassed
of himself.
So, you want
to look him in the eye?
Huh? Is that it?
You want to see his face?
No, man.
We're cool.
What'd be the point?
Yeah, what's the point?
Take a look at the face
of one of his friends.
Someone didn't like
the outfit he had on,
so they cut him out of it
with a knife.
No, you don't think
I did that.
No, I didn't do that.
When was this?
When was he killed?
Last night.
I was clocked in all night,
pulling grave.
Boss will tell you.
Just ring him up.
Look, look, all right, yeah,
I roughed up the other one.
If I'm getting charges for that,
all good,
but I ain't a murderer.
No charges.
The victim doesn't want
to press any.
Doesn't want
to show his face in court.
Somehow,
he's the one who's ashamed.
What the...?
Henry.
Your befuddlement is showing
down the hallway.
This is all so weird.
What do you have?
A DNA result, and a...
ghost story.
I'm listening.
I was swabbing
the Charlene suit,
still hoping to find a sample
of touch DNA
from the assailant.
I noticed the doll's earrings,
figured their sharp edges
could have caught a chunk
of the killer.
Sure enough, there were skin
cells embedded in one of them.
I ran DNA on the skin cells
and got a hit in CODIS.
A match to a woman...
who died two years ago.
Charlene Brock.
Charlene? Like the suit?
They don't just share a name.
They share a face.
HODGES:
I've seen that woman before.
I mean, the real her.
Charlene Brock
had a short career
as a model in the early '80s,
including...
one poster that
sold millions.
Oh. That dress.
Just like the one
on Rubber Charlene.
Let me get this straight.
So, pinup goddess dies,
is reborn in rubber,
only to get murdered?
With DNA from the real
dead woman on the rubber body.
Insane.
Charlene Brock's family still
lives in town.
Might be worth a call.
I'll text Russell.
MAN:
What the hell?!
This guy was dressed up
as Mom, wearing her earrings?
It's completely sick.
Mr. Brock, it's my understanding
that Charlene passed away...
what was it, two years ago?
Mmm.
Mom had an aneurysm
out of nowhere.
Well, I'm sorry.
Now, this man
that was killed, um,
Nelson Kern?
Recognize him? No?
Connected to your mother maybe?
Char still had some fans.
You know, fellas
who'd grown up worshipping
that poster, you know?
Dad had an estate sale
right after her death, and sold
all of her stuff.
Well, then,
it's possible that Mr. Kern
purchased those earrings
from that sale, right?
Maybe to make his
doll more authentic.
This isn't right.
Somebody steals her image and
walks around dressed up as her?
Get over it, Jonah.
No need to sue for
copyright infringement.
You don't think it's creepy?
Just a lonely guy who wanted
to be close to her.
That's all.
That was me a few decades ago.
(sighs)
I remember in '79,
Charlene was a waitress,
and I was just starting out
my modeling agency.
I convinced her to pose.
That pinup made a nice buck,
let me tell you.
And she married me.
Gave me two wonderful children,
and she turned out to be
one hell of a partner
at the agency.
Sounds like quite a woman.
Yeah.
And whoever
stabbed that
doll's lucky
they didn't try it
on the real Charlene Brock.
She wouldn't have let him
walk away.
If you ever thought
those reality show housewives
were catty, they got nothing
on these vulcanized vixens.
Web forum
for Vegas Rubber Dolls.
Nick's hate crime suspect
alibi'd out, so now I'm focusing
on doll-on-doll drama.
The gossip, the grudges.
And this forum
is where they like to
sling a lot of dirt.
Find anything helpful?
Maybe.
Charlene, it turns out,
has a rival doll.
The mysterious
and alluring Lexy.
Hmm.
It's not one of the dolls
that Russell and Greg
met at the club.
Story I've been able to put
together from the forum
is that Lexy was
the queen of the club
until Charlene showed up
last month,
became the new hot hot thing.
And Lexy wasn't
happy about it.
Social snub could become motive.
Do we, uh, know
Lexy's real identity?
Nobody breaks character
on these sites.
I messaged Lexy,
but no response.
But I noticed
she wasn't in any
of the posted club photos
from the night of the murder.
Well, maybe
because she was
outside in the alley
(phone dings)
waiting to
attack Charlene.
Unis just found
Charlene's-- well,
Nelson Kern's--
car a couple blocks
from the club.
You want to check it out?
Absolutely.
Let's do it.
Unis cleared it,
but they didn't search it?
Whoa. Sara.
We know Charlene was
Kern's rubber ride
the night of his death,
but take a look at this.
This looks familiar.
That's Lexy.
Rubber Charlene's rival doll.
I don't get it.
Nelson Kern was wearing
the Charlene suit when he died.
What's he doing with Lexy
in the trunk?
(sighs)
As far as I understand,
every guy only has one
Rubber Doll persona.
Doesn't make sense that
Kern would be both
Lexy and Charlene.
Okay.
I got a crowbar
and bolt cutters.
Break-in gear.
Kern had a few
priors for burglary.
Taking a flier
on this one, maybe,
but let's just say
that Nelson Kern usually
stepped out at
night as Lexy,
the belle
of the rubber ball.
Until Charlene shows up,
making Lexy and Kern
old news.
That would make Kern
jealous, right?
Jealous enough, maybe,
with his history of B-and-Es,
to break in and steal
Charlene from her owner.
And then don Charlene
for the night.
I buy it.
But if we're
right, then who's
Charlene's owner?
And where did Kern
steal her from?
Maybe these will help
answer that question.
There's some trace
in the blades.
Looks like concrete powder.
This morning I noticed
you were doing
some concrete work
back here.
Yeah, just, uh, just trying
to keep the place looking nice.
My wife loved
this house.
You appear to have had
a break-in back here.
Mr. Brock, I'm gonna need
to take a look inside.
♪ ♪
My wife was my world.
That Charlene suit
was yours, wasn't it?
Nelson Kern
broke in and stole it.
Stole her. From me.
I loved her.
I lived for her.
Did you kill for her?
Stan, you lied to me.
Told me you didn't know
anything about the suit.
My children were
sitting right there.
They wouldn't
have understood
how I-I clung
to everything
that was left
of their mother.
Is that why you went
to this, um,
Belinda Goff-- had her make you
one of those suits?
I stumbled across
her work online.
And I sent her
some pictures of Charlene.
And I brought my love
back to life.
It wasn't just dress-up.
I could feel Charlene's
spirit all around me.
Others could feel it, too.
The presence
of a special being.
RUSSELL:
But one of the other dolls
didn't appreciate
that you stole the spotlight.
Lexy.
Right. We found the Lexy suit.
We know that it belonged to a
Nelson Kern.
His DNA is all over it.
Mr. Kern took a look
at you and Charlene,
and he figured
that if he couldn't outshine
the new girl,
he'd find some way
to become her.
Broke into your place,
he stole the suit
and he took your wife out
for a spin.
And it cost him
his life, didn't it?
Mr. Russell, much
as I may cherish
the memory of my
wife, her beauty,
and wanted to possess it,
I would never hurt someone else
for trying to possess it, too.
FINLAY:
I was doing some digging, and I
checked police
activity in the alley
the night of
the murders.
There was a parking ticket
issued to an Escalade, and...
the carpet fiber trace that
we found on the Charlene suit
is consistent with
the interior of an Escalade.
And the vehicle
is registered
to this guy.
I met him at the club.
He's one of their admirers.
Let's bring him in.
Hi, Adrian. I'm CSI Finlay.
I, uh, would like to talk
to you about Charlene.
We know she was
in your vehicle.
We found carpet fibers
that are consistent
with the interior
of an Escalade
on her doll suit.
You know what it is I love
about the dolls at that club?
How little they speak.
They're as close
to the ideal woman
as I've ever met.
Wow.
I can't imagine
how you could have
struck out
with real women.
(chuckles)
Well, real women
are just as fake...
...but lie about it.
Well, if I were
to tell you
that my eyelashes
are not this great...
...would you be honest with me?
Fair enough.
Charlene did join
me in my vehicle.
We'd been flirting with
each other for the past
few weeks at the club.
So tell me what happened
in the car.
Oh, we, uh, played around.
Then she left.
With abrasions on her arms
and a bite mark on her shoulder.
Which I bet is
going to be a match to those
fake veneers you got in there.
(laughs)
What can I say?
I like rough sex.
She had thick skin.
I did my research on you,
and I did find
that you have a history
of sexual assault.
Allegations. All dropped.
Uh-huh.
Well, you know
what I think happened?
I think that Charlene
was so messed up
that she decided
to get into your car.
And then when you started
to hurt her, she bailed.
So you followed her--
'cause you didn't like getting
rejected by a blow-up doll--
and then you stabbed her.
Stripped off her suit,
because everybody
at the club
knows who
Charlene is, but, uh,
Nelson Kern, he's a nobody.
(short chuckle)
Well, truth is...
I showed her too
good of a time.
She couldn't
contain herself.
And that voice that groaned out?
Deep-sixed the mood.
I kicked her out and drove off.
Am I free to go?
Got any evidence
from the suspect's SUV yet?
Finn is still working
the carpets and the
upholstery, but so far
we haven't found any blood.
Even though Kern was stabbed
outside, in the alley...
Yeah, you would have
expected
that Graham would have
tracked some of the blood
back into the vehicle.
You sure would.
What is all this lovely stuff?
Well, this is Adrian Graham's
mobile sex pantry. Lotions,
lubes and other sinful sundries
that he kept in his SUV.
We found them
neatly organized.
I was hoping in his cleanup that
he left a smear of blood behind,
but, uh, no
such luck.
Excuse me a sec, here.
Baby oil.
Nick found trace amounts
of baby oil
on the Charlene suit.
Now, it's possible that...
that some of this got
transferred from the suit
onto the assailant.
I'm not sure what that gets us.
Graham already admitted
that he was with her.
He just denies being
there for the murder.
Right, but whoever
the killer is,
we have no indication of his
movements in that alley
in the moments
right after the death.
No shoe prints,
no blood trail.
Oil trail could
be very helpful.
Baby oil fluoresces at a lower
frequency than biologicals,
so I've set the ALSs
at 525 nanometers.
There's a lot of oil here,
where the body was.
Uh-huh.
Oh, there you go.
Trail of oil going off
in this direction.
Oily part of the suit
must have been dragged along.
Huh. Brushed the wall here.
(short laugh)
It's the murder weapon.
It's a nail file.
Consistent with the wounds
that Doc Robbins found.
Sharp-pointed
but square-edged.
See this logo right there?
Uh-huh.
That's the Brock family
modeling agency.
Murder with a corporate sponsor.
We pulled a fingerprint
off of the weapon, Jonah.
And it's yours.
The weapon is one of 20 I gifted
friends of our agency
at the memorial
after my mom died.
It was a gesture in her honor.
Really?
A nail file as a tribute?
It was kind of her thing.
Those dealing with
Charlene Brock
knew that if she started
working on her cuticles...
she wasn't happy,
and you better make her happy.
Don't come into my office
with excuses,
you cowardly piece of...
I gave the file
out as a memento.
My prints might be
on every one of 'em.
You know, I might buy that...
had I not learned
about another file.
Your recent
motion to remove
your father as head
of the modeling agency.
Uh...
the company started slipping
after my mom died.
She was the guts,
the-the cutthroat, the whip
that my dad needed.
And after she died,
I noticed
that he started slipping.
Professionally and otherwise.
You knew about his
Rubber Dolling. I think you...
talk about it
in your statement.
Hey. Yeah,
I knew about all that.
I saw a few of his selfies when
I borrowed his laptop one day.
Hey, whatever the old man needs
to get his kicks.
But...
if a rival photo agency
pops a picture of him in his...
costume...
...everything that he and my mom
built goes away.
Instead of going to you.
The board
shut you down,
which left you
only one other way
to take your dad
out of the picture.
You just didn't know
that the wrong man
was in the suit.
(chuckles)
Ms. Finlay,
I didn't stab anyone,
and I'll prove it to you.
I spent the night of
the crime producing
a photo shoot, and I spent
the rest of the evening
in the company
of one of the models.
I have video.
(inhales deeply)
You feeling good?
Mm-hmm.
(chuckles)
I guess talking isn't her thing.
We don't have
to talk, beautiful.
Whoa.
Checking out Jonah Brock's
alibi, are you?
Yeah, the time stamp
on the video puts him at home
between 11:00 p.m. and 2:00 a.m.
Well, the murder
was around midnight.
So, unless Jonah messed
with the metadata...
Look at him.
Does he strike you
as the type of guy
who spends a lot of time
playing around with a computer?
I don't know. I mean,
first impressions
aren't always right.
Right. The way
you were spotted for 5-O
in .5 seconds
at the club there, Columbo.
Russell told me about that.
Whatever. So obviously
Jonah Brock's alibi checks out.
He's not our killer.
No.
Did we get anything else
off the nail file?
There were
minute bits
of fingernail lodged in
with the crosshatches.
DNA came back unknown female.
Oh, and there was some
unusual trace mixed in.
Particles of gold.
Gold?
Hang on a second.
Check that out.
Ms. Irina Turri.
You remember her, right?
She's back in
Helsinki right now.
We couldn't
bring her in,
but we talked to her
on the phone,
and she said that her nails
were filed by the assistant
at the photo shoot.
That would be you, right, April?
That same file found its way
into Nelson Kern's neck.
I already told you
I didn't know that man.
Why would I stab him?
Well, because you weren't
really stabbing him,
were you?
You were stabbing your mother.
And your father.
I love my father.
I was the one who defended him
when my brother tried
to destroy him.
Right.
The business
deposition, right?
You painted your
dad as having...
suffered under your
mother's tyranny.
It's quite the eulogy
for your... for your mom.
It was the truth.
Dad and I always stood up
for each other, ever since
I was a kid, every time
my mom would...
Would...
would what?
If you didn't live up
to my mother's expectations,
she would crush you.
And I guess the perfect daughter
that she wanted
wasn't me, so... it's hard
enough to see that
in your mom's eyes.
It's harder when she...
starts taking it out on you.
I can see that.
So when your...
when your mother passed away,
you must have felt
like you were...
free of her cruelty.
Your dad was free, too.
We'd survived.
We were done with her.
Only, your father
didn't want to be.
He still loved her.
He loved your mother.
He loved
her so much
he wanted
to bring her back to life.
See, I think that was a
betrayal that you just...
you couldn't live with.
Could you?
I would have ignored it.
Pretended like I didn't know
about the locked room,
the suit.
What I saw when I followed him
that night...
♪ ♪
As ghastly as it was,
I could have forgiven him.
But then he made his choice.
What choice?
Four days ago, I-I turned 30.
The only person in the world
I wanted to celebrate with
was Dad, and then he called
and said he didn't feel well
and he needed to cancel.
And I could hear the club music
in the background.
He chose your
mother over you.
Again.
Then what happened?
You go out,
follow her
into the alley,
you wait for her to be alone?
(grunting)
(panting)
RUSSELL:
Then you realized your mistake.
Why did you rip off the suit?
I had to throw her away.
(panting)
April?
Why couldn't you
just let her die, Dad?
She was a monster.
Oh, April.
Go to hell.
(sighs)
I never saw this before.
But you...
you remind me so much of her.
RUSSELL: Go on.
Get her out of here.
♪ ♪
Shift's over, Greg.
It's not work.
A guy could tell
I was law enforcement
across a dark club.
By just looking at me.
So?
You are.
But...
it's not who I am.
It doesn't define me.
And so I've just been looking
at old photos
of all the different...
stuff I used to do.
Parties, traveling.
6:00 a.m.
Kind of early
for a... identity crisis.
I guess.
Listen,
Greg...
people are never
just one thing.
Like, look at
your friends.
This guy, Mr. Sweet Dad.
You really think
that's all he is?
I once watched
that guy eat a beer can.
(laughs)
True story.
People are complicated.
It's never
that simple.
Everybody has layers.
People read "cop,"
maybe I'll at least get
a free cup of coffee.
(chuckles)
If they give you free donuts,
that means they're making fun
of you.
Well, how about if I update
my status to say,
"Taking a friend out
for a beer."
Me? Yes. I would love that.
All right, hold on.
Ooh. Yeah, I love that place.