(lock buzzes, latch clicks)
GUARD:
Let's go! On the line!
(indistinct announcement
over P.A.)
GUARD:
Okay, settle down! Keep moving!
(gasping anxiously)
INMATE:
I-I don't...
(muttering, gasping)
(inmate mutters)
Hey... I can't do this, man.
I-I hate needles.
Shut up.
I hate needles.
Please, please...
Please, please, please
don't make me, I can't...
I can't do this...
Just relax.
INMATE:
Nobody listens to me.
No...
I hate needles.
Relax...
I hate needles!
I hate...
Nobody's listening to me!
No... Nobody's
listening to me!
(alarm blaring,
inmates clamoring)
GUARD: Backup needed in the
inmate reception-- now!
(men shouting)
GUARD:
O'Malley-- we need backup!
(alarm bell rings)
(all clamoring)
Shut up! Shut up!
Yo, man...
Shut up!
(yelling)
Shut up! Shut up!
(gasping)
GUARD: On your knees now!
Hands above your head!
(yelling)
GUARD: Inmate,
drop to the floor now!
(screaming)
Crime lab.
Thanks.
DETECTIVE:
You must be Russell
and Stokes with the crime lab.
Detective Carl Brenner.
How do you do?
Heard you guys are
the best. Follow me.
I'm kind of the, uh,
new guy in Homicide.
Youngest detective ever promoted
into the bureau.
Been there just over two years.
Love the job.
Oh. Well,
congratulations.
BRENNER:
Well, you know what they say--
you can't solve murders
sitting behind a desk.
A motto I live by.
So... I work 24/7.
You need me, you call me.
Home number's
on the back.
Right up here, guys.
(indistinct conversations)
Quite a ruckus, huh?
Sure was.
STOKES:
What happened to him?
BRENNER: Took a punch
in the commotion.
He's fine. Door!
(lock buzzes)
(muffled screaming)
(louder, muffled screams)
What's his story?
BRENNER: Well, that's the cause
of the circus right there.
Denny Morrison--
he's got some mental issues.
Freaked out
getting a flu shot.
When he ran in here, the, uh,
extraction team got him.
Watch your step
through here.
Good thing it wasn't
a busy laundry day, right?
Anyway, in the process,
they found this guy.
Name's Bruce Grady.
There's a long rap sheet.
He's, uh,
awaiting trial on armed robbery.
Did he work in here?
No, he's assigned to the med mod
up on the third floor.
What's a hard-core felon doing
assigned to a low-risk
medical module?
Well, he had cirrhosis of the
liver-- on a bunch of meds.
Had one foot in the grave.
STOKES: Someone must have
gotten impatient.
He's been stabbed pretty good.
Look at that.
So we have an inmate
from the medical module
found three floors below,
stabbed to death.
Any particular enemies?
This is County--
everyone in here has enemies.
That narrows it down.
RUSSELL:
We have one victim...
and 2,000 caged suspects.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
I hate laundry.
I could never work
in a place like this.
I don't know, it beats
sitting in your cell
with some
sketchy roommate.
I don't know,
I think an inmate would
have been preferable
to my first
college roommate.
Hmm. Nutjob, huh?
Oh, yeah.
Liver temp
is 94 degrees.
He's been dead
around three hours.
So, 7:00 p.m.
That's about right.
Did you find any other
stab wounds, Dave?
Just the one you already saw.
And a defensive wound
on his hand.
It looks like
there's some residue
on his hands as well.
Blood drops on his clothing
are gravitational and elongated.
And...
there is blood
on the bottom of his shoes,
so he was
walking around bleeding.
So where is
all the blood?
There's some over here
near the sink.
Hot water handle.
Killer could have injured
himself during a struggle.
Needed to wash up.
Hey, I've got a bloody towel
over here, as well.
And somebody did
a lousy mop job.
Okay, I'm gonna grab the guys,
we'll pick up the body,
and I'll text you
when Doc schedules the post.
Thanks, Dave.
Nick, look at this.
Same residue as
on the victim's hands.
"M.M."
Medical Module, maybe?
Wasn't the victim housed there?
Well, that would explain
how he got down here.
He was hiding in
the laundry cart.
Yeah, but there's
no blood inside.
Okay, so he was uninjured
when he got in,
and attacked when
he got down here.
(yells in pain)
Question is, did he
come down here voluntarily,
or did somebody force him
to take the ride?
Yeah. Well, either way,
we're gonna have to find out
who was pushing that cart.
SANDERS:
Strep.
Pink eye.
Impetigo?
I mean, you can practically feel
the germs jumping on you.
(laughs) You're
being paranoid.
You do remember
that I was just quarantined.
Yes, and you survived
the Ibare virus,
which means you can probably
handle a little bit of pink eye.
If you say so.
Here we are.
Our victim's cell.
(sighs)
You know, this is
all new to me.
We never worked jail cases
back at LAPD.
Yeah, well,
welcome to Clark County.
Ladies first.
(sighs heavily)
Well... Grady's cell
is pretty clean.
Doesn't look like there was
any struggle of any sort.
Photo of his daughter Rachel.
It's got to be tough
missing your kid grow up.
Yeah.
This artwork here
explains the residue
on Grady's hands.
He had some talent--
these are good drawings.
SANDERS:
Lake views, forests, birds.
All showing
the beauty of nature.
Hard to believe
he'd want to be reminded of that
while he's in here.
SANDERS:
Well, maybe in here is where
you need to be reminded
the most.
Ugh. That's some nasty
medicine he was taking.
BRODY:
Got a file folder here
full of legal paperwork.
Well, that makes sense--
inmates are allowed
to keep their case files
with them in their cell.
Hey, look at this.
Oh. That's a jail kite.
It's how inmates communicate
from cell to cell.
A message is written on paper,
which is folded
into a triangular kite.
The string is there, in case
they need to pull it back,
if it ends up somewhere
they didn't want it to go.
"Liars don't last
long in here.
Watch your back."
That's a pretty
serious warning.
Sounds more like
a threat to me--
one our killer wasn't afraid
to follow up on.
(lock buzzes, clicks)
So, Officer Woo,
you were the guard
in charge of
the laundry room today?
Laundry's
my regular assignment.
I work days on a four/ten,
Sunday to Wednesday.
Okay. And you
work alone?
Yeah. It's
a solo gig now.
You know,
budget cuts.
Did you know the
victim, Bruce Grady?
Seen him around,
like any other inmate.
Well, did you know that
he was transported in a cart
to the laundry room
during your shift?
No. Didn't.
Where were you
around 7:00 p.m.?
Supply trucks got delayed
by a pileup on the 15.
Arrived three hours late.
Took my laundry trustees
down to the dock to unload it.
That was around... 6:45.
How long
did that take?
15, 20 minutes.
So you left the laundry
unsupervised?
Nobody should have
been in there.
I had six trustees with me,
and the rest were upstairs
doing linen swap.
How was the trustee
in charge of swapping the linens
out of the medical module?
Third floor.
That'd be Wilbur Tandy.
Laundry trustee--
that's a pretty good
gig, huh, Wilbur?
I like the routine--
it gets me out of my cell.
Got Bruce Grady
out of his cell, too.
Did you take him down
to the laundry room?
Just following orders.
Orders from who?
Now, I wouldn't last
very long in here
if I questioned who's
giving the orders.
You saying
you don't want to tell me, or
are you saying you don't know?
I'm saying I don't want
to end up like Grady.
Another option is, we can charge
you with accessory to murder.
And I ask for a lawyer
and you get nothing.
STOKES: All right,
all right, Wilbur...
I'm working for
the dead man here.
Now who gave you that order?
Got a kite.
Said bring Grady to the laundry
during the linen swap,
so I did.
Grady got a kite, too.
Pretty threatening one.
So, we're supposed
to expect he, uh,
voluntarily got into your cart,
knowing it could be
his last ride?
You don't get it.
Nothing sent by a
kite is a request.
Grady knew that.
He had to go.
Did he say anything?
Nah.
He was out of it.
He was drugged up on something.
Could barely get
in the cart.
Okay, so, you took him
downstairs, then what?
Left the cart,
got another one.
I told you,
I got my routine.
You see who he was meeting with?
Nope.
Dropped him off and left.
STOKES:
You can help us
eliminate you as a suspect
by giving your DNA sample.
I gave my DNA at intake.
Use that.
Well, you've got your
routine, I've got mine.
I take a DNA sample from
everybody I've talked to.
No exceptions.
What do I get
if I give it to you?
Well, you get to keep
being laundry trustee.
RUSSELL:
So, where are we
with Bruce
Grady's enemies?
There's no record
of any incidents
since he's been in jail,
but I did pull his rap sheet
to look at his history,
and I found
a very interesting trend.
Every time he's arrested,
the charges got reduced.
Yeah.
Suspiciously reduced, I'd say,
and there's only one way
that could happen.
Grady was making deals
with the DA.
So, the guy
was an informant.
Yeah. So,
I cross-matched cases where
he appeared as a witness
to inmates who are currently
assigned to the jail,
and I found out
something very big.
Grady was the star witness
in the murder case
of Lincoln Mayfield.
Mayfield--
the Snakeback assassin.
Yeah, but he was convicted,
so he wouldn't be in jail.
He's got to be
upstate in prison, right?
Well, he was, but the case was
overturned on a technicality.
The retrial is this week.
And Mayfield was brought back
to County for the trial.
He arrived two days ago.
(lock buzzes, clicks)
GUARD:
Mayfield!
On your feet!
Turn around,
hands behind your back.
Hey, Mayfield,
lookie here.
You want to explain this?
I ain't sayin'
nothin' to no cop.
You got a problem with that,
talk to my lawyer.
RUSSELL: Well, Mayfield
lawyered up, so,
he won't be talking.
No surprise.
D.A. handling the retrial gave
me a copy of the case file.
Care to take a look?
(grunts) Please tell me there's
a Reader's Digest version.
All right, as the so-called
"Snakeback Assassin,"
Mayfield was suspected
of over a dozen
gangland murders.
Yeah.
I remember this one.
Young, pregnant woman
caught in the crossfire.
They thought it was
a Mayfield hit, right?
Yeah.
Witnesses were, of course,
afraid to come forward.
Consequently, the D.A. never
had enough to charge him.
So, let me guess.
They decided to go
with a jail informant.
You got it. They put Bruce Grady
in a cell next to Mayfield.
And after a while,
Grady got him to talk.
Mayfield confessed?
No, but he provided details
that only the killer would know.
It was enough in court,
and bottom line is,
Grady's testimony
put Mayfield away.
Well, there's Mayfield's motive.
Payback for Grady's testimony.
(phone ringing)
Boy, I didn't see this coming.
Nick says
Mayfield wants to talk.
My lawyer here ain't happy, but
I got to tell you about Grady.
You're compelled to
tell me about Grady,
'cause he testified
against you.
That's just it.
That was all lies.
Dude stood up there and said
I told him stuff
while we was locked up together?
I never told him nothin'.
And that pissed you off.
Hmm.
Hmm. Were you mad
enough to kill him?
I didn't kill homeboy.
You sent a kite to Wilbur,
ordering him to take Grady
to the laundry room.
To talk,
straighten him out.
Why'd you bring a weapon?
Never know
who gonna make a move.
Look, all I wanted for him
was to do right by me
and take back those lies.
Okay, so you guys talk,
and then what?
Things just go sideways?
Dude showed up wasted,
makin' no sense.
Hey, Grady?
You're gonna tell 'em
you lied, hear me?
You're gonna make things right.
Just be cool.
I can hook you up in here.
Look here, old man...
Hey!
(Grady shouts, groans)
So you shank him?
To get his attention....
Lincoln.
Look, I shanked
a few dudes in my day.
Poke I gave him
wouldn't kill nobody.
You got his attention.
Now what?
I... strongly suggested
that he come clean.
(grunting)
Tell 'em you lied,
I'm gonna kill you.
Okay, okay.
And if you tell the D.A.
about our little talk,
I'm gonna kill you ugly.
I swear, I won't tell anyone.
I swear.
Not a word.
You stabbed him, but you weren't
trying to kill him?
I couldn't afford
to kill him.
I needed him alive
to tell the DA that he lied.
That's why I'm talking to you.
I'm telling you,
him being murdered
is bad for me.
Real bad.
(sniffing)
Ooh.
That odor is
disgustingly familiar.
It's the smell of success.
I'd hate to find out
what failure smells like.
Hey, did you
ever figure out
what that medicine
was in Grady's trash?
Wasn't medicine.
It was hooch. Pruno.
Jail alcohol.
I'm making a batch right now,
using only items available
to the inmates.
It's a simple recipe, really.
Fermentation is the conversion
of sugars to alcohol,
using yeast.
You combine fruit,
juice, sugar and bread.
Mix and wait.
The yeast from the bread
does all the work.
You just have to vent it
occasionally
to release the accumulated CO2,
and you're good.
Witness said
that Grady was out of it.
Maybe he was just
drunk on pruno.
Maybe he just needed
a little liquid courage.
If I had to face someone
who wanted to kill me,
I'd drink, too.
Mm. That looks like something
out of a zombie movie.
No, it's Bruce
Grady's liver.
Cirrhosis causes cells
and scar tissue
to create nodules,
rendering it ineffective
as the body's main
filtration system.
Makes you not want to have
that second glass
of wine at dinner.
Speak for yourself.
So, what about
the stab wound?
Well, it's a single laceration
penetrating the external
abdominal oblique muscle.
It's an inch wide, and about
one and a half inches in depth.
That's not very deep.
I'm surprised
that it killed him.
Well, it didn't.
Take a look here.
Petechiae.
So he died
from asphyxiation.
ROBBINS:
Manually strangled.
(gasping)
You can see finger-shaped
contusions beginning to form.
I swabbed the neck for
epithelial DNA from our killer.
Already sent it to Henry.
So, he was stabbed,
and then he was strangled.
That makes no sense.
That shank could have
done major damage.
So, why would you
strangle someone
if you had a perfectly
good weapon?
You wouldn't.
Maybe Mayfield was
telling the truth.
SANDERS:
Inmates can get pretty creative
concealing their contraband,
so let's just be sure to check
every hem, edge, seam...
So it's a tactile examination.
Pretty much.
But never forget.
The most popular hiding place
is the jail wallet.
What?
The keister stash.
Ah, well, I am double gloved,
so, I'm good.
I heard about this
inmate whose family
smuggled him drugs
by melting them
and using the mixture
to paint a picture
in a coloring book.
"To Daddy. Love Lindsay."
It's kind of hard
to explain a guy licking
a picture of a princess.
Maybe in the
outside world,
but in jail, not so much.
(sighs)
Greg...
take a look at this.
It's a tiny recording device.
I've never seen
one that small.
It's state-of-the-art.
I saw one of these at the
forensic conference last month.
It's not even available to law
enforcement until next year.
Well, then, how did
Bruce Grady get one?
Well, the vendor did say that
one law enforcement agency would
be chosen to test the prototype.
I wonder which agency
that would be.
Agent Parker,
thank you for seeing me.
Your call said it was urgent.
We found this
in the cell of an inmate
at County.
You recognize it?
I might.
Yeah.
We found that
after the inmate was murdered.
(wry chuckle)
All right, look,
Bruce Grady was a CI
for the DA's Office--
I already knew that-- but he was
also an informant for the FBI,
I'm not going to divulge details
on an ongoing investigation.
I can appreciate that,
but after the guy was murdered,
you might have picked up
the phone and told us.
Saved us a lot
of trouble.
Our investigation
is confidential.
Your investigation
is very likely the reason
why we're in this mess.
Look, we think
that Grady
was killed by that same inmate
that you're investigating.
So come on.
Let's work
together here.
Well, that's assuming the focus
of our investigation
is an inmate.
You're investigating a guard.
(sighs)
So Grady was not
just informing on crooks.
He was informing on cops.
ECKLIE: Agent Parker,
you blindsided me on this.
There's such a thing
as professional courtesy.
The FBI is under no obligation
to share information with you.
Oh, please. Drop the
federal policy-speak.
We're on the
same side here.
If one of my guards is dirty,
I want to know about it.
Now, who are you looking at?
We're empanelling a grand jury.
We expect an indictment any day.
I'm not going to risk a leak.
A leak?
RUSSELL:
We're investigating the murder
of yourCI,
and you won't share with us?
Sorry.
Best we can do is work
our cases in parallel.
If your investigation
collides with ours,
maybe then we can talk.
Have a nice day.
Perfect. A federal
corruption investigation.
We'll work the case
as fast as we can, Conrad.
If Grady's killer turns out
to be a-a jail guard...
Yeah, please let me be
the first to know.
Hey.
What do you
got for me?
All the blood
Finn and Nick collected
in the laundry room came back
to the victim, Bruce Grady,
including the blood on the sink.
Okay, what about the shank?
Mm. No surprises there.
Blood on the blade was Grady's.
DNA on the handle
came back
to Lincoln Mayfield.
A perfect equation,
except that the shank
isn't the murder weapon
'cause Grady was strangled.
I found epithelials
on the victim's neck swab.
DNA doesn't match Mayfield.
DNA has to be the killer's.
Did you run it through CODIS?
No hits.
Given that all inmates
are entered into the system...
Means we're not looking
for an inmate.
Just like we feared,
looks like Grady's
killer is a guard.
So, Grady
was reportedly intoxicated
at the time of his murder,
and yet
his tox report
says that his blood alcohol
level was 0.03%.
0.03?
That wouldn't make anyone
stagger,
let alone an alcoholic
like Grady.
No.
They also found
a half-dozen prescription drugs
in his system,
all on his medical record,
except for one,
a drug named terbinafine.
What's that taken for?
Skin infections.
And this
is the interesting part:
they do not dispense terbinafine
in the jail infirmary.
Okay, so where'd he get it from?
I don't know,
but somebody with access to the
outside must've given it to him.
Huh. All right.
Let me see here.
Terbinafine.
Here we go.
"Terbinafine
should never be taken
"by people with liver problems.
Can cause
confusion and an unsteady gait."
That would explain
why he seemed intoxicated.
And get this,
"cases of death have been
reported in individuals
with cirrhosis of the liver."
So somebody
was poisoning him
before he went down
to the laundry.
Yeah, and they must have gotten
tired of waiting for that poison
to take effect, went hands-on
and strangled him.
You know, Henry's DNA evidence
does back up the fact
that we might be looking
at a guard.
Well, the laundry was guarded
by Officer Woo,
who just so happened to be gone
when the murder went down.
Wow, that is awfully convenient.
FINLAY: So you said
that, on Sunday night,
at about 7:00 p.m.,
you were not
in the laundry room.
Right.
I was on the
loading dock.
And you were on the loading dock
for approximately 20 minutes?
Give or take.
You're on direct deposit
for your LVPD paychecks,
is that correct?
And your wife,
she doesn't work, does she?
So?
So I see
that there are several
cash deposits
to your account each month,
last month, totaling
more than $4,000.
Is there a rich uncle
that I don't know about?
It's funny, if you want
to know what the guards
are actually doing
when they're on the job,
you just have
to ask the inmates.
You want to know about Woo?
I'll tell you about Woo.
He takes money
to look the other way.
It's common knowledge you can
get anything in the laundry.
Drugs, weapons, sex.
Woo won't say a word
for the right price.
Laundry's a three-ring circus.
Woo lets inmates do
whatever they want.
Look...
my wife has a shopping problem.
Our credit
cards are maxed.
I can't even cover
the minimum payments.
So I get it: You need to make
some extra money on the side.
It started small.
I snuck in some pot brownies
for an inmate with migraines.
He told two friends.
They told two friends...
Pretty soon, I got inmates
threatening to rat me out
if I don't help 'em out, too.
I'd lose my job.
I'd lose everything.
Let's talk about Sunday night.
Mayfield paid me to stay away
while he met with Grady.
Had two grand
delivered to my house.
Said they were
just gonna talk.
How much did you know
about Grady?
I knew he was a snitch.
Yeah. For the FBI.
He was helping them
with a corruption case
involving a jail guard.
I think
that you found out
that Grady was snitching you out
to the Feds,
so you let Mayfield have
a little alone time with him,
hoping that Mayfield would do
your dirty work.
Only when you got back
to the laundry room,
Grady was still alive
so you had to kill him.
No. No way.
I didn't kill Grady.
It's a nice setup.
Mayfield's a known killer.
He's a perfect patsy.
I didn't do it.
I swear.
Cops don't have their DNA
in CODIS,
so if you want to prove it
to me, you're gonna
have to give me a sample.
Hey. You find anything
on the recording device
from Grady's cell?
No, it's blank.
(sighs)
We must've found it
before Grady had a
chance to use it.
Yeah, but here's
where it gets weird.
So, I got the specs
from the vendor.
Something isn't adding up here.
According to these,
the dynamic range of the device
is 80 decibels, with
a noise floor of 30 decibels.
Dynamic range? Noise floor?
All right. Well,
let-let me just show you.
So, the human speaking
voice averages
60 to 70 decibels
at three feet. That's...
the green wave here.
Now let's add
some interference.
(white noise hissing)
So as long
as the interference
from any kind
of background noise stays
within this range,
then the recording device
can still pick up our voices.
See how the green
and red waves
remain distinct?
But in
the jail's laundry,
with all the machines
running and the cement walls,
the noise interference level
would have to be a lot higher.
I went back and measured.
It was 86 decibels.
(hissing, crackling increases)
See?
Now look at the sound waves.
The laundry room's
way too loud
to record human conversation
with that.
(hissing, crackling fades)
So if the FBI was trying
to record Officer Woo
during his shift
in the jail laundry,
then this was the wrong device.
So, Morgan and Greg
don't think
Officer Woo is the target
of the FBI investigation.
I think they're right.
Woo's DNA did not
match the DNA
on the neck swab.
So Woo's not the one
who strangled Grady.
Mm-mm.
Where's that put us now?
Well, I have been looking back
over Grady's CI files,
and instead of links
to inmates, I've been looking
at links to officers,
and there's quite a list.
Grady has been making deals
for years.
Well, being an informant
can be good money.
Well, he's not doing it
for the money.
He's doing it to get his
charges reduced, so...
sexual assault is dealt down
to malicious mischief
and robbery down to burglary.
And the list
just goes on and on.
Is there a connection
to any officers that we know?
Carl Brenner.
Brenner?
The gung-ho detective?
He never mentioned anything
about knowing Grady
at the crime scene.
Hey, wait a minute,
was Detective Brenner a part
of the Lincoln Mayfield case?
FINLAY:
He was.
And Brenner would have been
in charge
of putting Grady into the cell
next to Mayfield.
When I talked to Mayfield,
he claims
that he never talked to Grady
about anything
when they were housed next
to each other.
So what if
Brenner fed his informant
the information on Mayfield?
There was a lot
of public pressure
at the time for a conviction.
Right? Perfect opportunity
for the new guy in Homicide
to make a name for himself.
What are you doing?
Looking up Detective Brenner's
personnel file.
You know, when officers
take a random drug test,
they have to list
all the medications
they've been taking.
Yeah, yeah.
That's routine.
Right. Here's his medical
disclosure form
from last month.
He lists a multivitamin,
ibuprofen...
...and terbinafine.
Same medication
we found in Grady's blood.
Wow.
So Brenner was poisoning Grady.
Yeah.
How much you want to bet he's
the one who strangled him, too?
Okay, here's what we got:
Detective Brenner
was using Grady
by feeding him case information
and then putting him
next to suspects
that he wanted to frame.
Making Brenner look like a hero.
Right.
Explains his
meteoric rise
in the department
over the last two years.
Mayfield
was the most recent.
Also the highest profile.
And that may be what got
the attention of the Feds.
Brenner's a smart guy.
Probably saw it coming.
Started to poison Grady.
Was Brenner at County
at the time Grady was strangled?
Conducting a lineup
down the hall from the laundry.
I'm gonna interrogate
this son of a bitch myself.
I thought we
agreed to talk
before pulling
the trigger on this.
Mitch.
Take Detective Brenner
to Interrogation Room B.
Be my pleasure, sir.
Let's go.
Special Agent Parker,
what we agreed was
to work our cases separately,
at yourrequest, as I recall.
Arresting Brenner
could affect
our grand jury hearing,
damage our case going forward.
Not my problem.
We have our own case to solve.
We could work together.
The LVPD is under
no obligation
to share investigative
information with you.
You want a shot at Brenner,
you can wait till I'm done.
Excuse me.
Sheriff...
Sir, look...
I don't know what
you've heard, all right?
But-but I am
a good cop, okay?
I can't believe
you march me in here
like-like some... criminal.
I put criminals away.
Yeah, you do.
You got a hell of
a conviction rate, one of
the best in the department.
And now every single one
of those convictions
is gonna be called
into question.
Aw, come on.
Every dirtbag I put away
was guilty, no question.
You falsified evidence
by coaching your informant
to lie in court.
So I nudged my cases
a little bit-- so what?
You framed them.
Going down that road,
you become worse
than the criminals
you're chasing.
No. No.
I could never be like them.
You already are.
You killed Bruce Grady.
The hell I did.
He had poisonous medicine
in his system.
Your medicine.
(chuckles):
Okay, yeah.
(sniffs)
Yeah, I gave him the medicine.
But to make him sick,
not-not to... to kill him.
Look, Grady was getting
cold feet
about Mayfield's retrial.
I figure if he's too sick
to testify, the DA's forced
to use his previous testimony.
No, you killed him because
you knew he was two-timing you.
What-what are you talking about?
With the FBI investigation.
Grady was ratting you out
to the Feds, and you found out.
That's why
you killed him.
Okay, I-I, um...
I need my-my union rep.
(chuckles):
Your union rep.
You've committed
multiple felonies while on duty.
Your union is gonna run
in the opposite direction.
Well, then I want a lawyer.
(sniffs)
You're gonna need one.
RUSSELL:
Hey.
How'd it go?
Admitted to the poisoning,
denied the murder,
then lawyered up.
Funny thing, though,
from the look on his face,
I don't think he knew
about the FBI probe.
Did you get a DNA sample?
No, and there's not a chance
he's gonna give one now.
Actually, wait a minute.
I think he may have
given it to me already.
You need me, you call me.
Home number's
right on the back.
♪ ♪
Henry, you look excited.
Were you able
to extract any DNA?
Oh, I got a beautiful profile,
but we're not gonna need it.
Well, yeah, we are.
Brenner only admitted
to poisoning Grady--
we need to prove
that he also strangled him.
Uh, except he didn't.
(sighs)
Okay. What am I missing?
I found a match to the neck swab
from the victim.
The killer's an inmate
named Peter McCrone.
This is the guy
that got punched
during that pepper spray melee.
Hey, what the hell?
He's an inmate, so how come
his DNA didn't show up in CODIS?
Oh, only DNA from felons gets
entered into CODIS.
Peter McCrone is in county
on a misdemeanor.
We just got his DNA when
Finlay interviewed him.
It was at the bottom
of a big pile of...
Hey, come on in.
FINLAY:
Hey.
Henry just found a match
to an inmate you talked to.
Yeah, Peter McCrone.
Henry texted me.
So, I went back to try
to find a connection
between McCrone and Grady.
Right. And?
Grady's earliest arrest was
for sexual assault.
Dealt down
to malicious mischief.
Right, I remember seeing that.
McCrone was his victim.
Grady molested him 20 years ago.
Well, there's
a hell of a motive.
You spend your whole life trying
to put things behind you.
To forget.
But some things,
they just never go away.
STOKES:
I know it's difficult.
So, tell me what happened.
Bruce Grady was a janitor
at my elementary school.
He was always nice.
Seemed like someone
you could trust.
But he broke that trust.
One afternoon,
I forgot my backpack.
Nobody here
except you and me, man.
There it is!
Thanks, Mr. Grady.
Hey, kid, want to see
a cool picture of a T. rex?
Sure.
He molested me.
I was nine years old.
I never should have
gone near him.
You know, I-I knew
something wasn't right.
I knew.
He took advantage of a child.
That's not your fault.
He threatened to hurt
my family... if I told.
I wasn't going to,
but when I got home,
my mom knew something was wrong.
So, I had to tell her.
You know, that's
a brave thing to do.
Lot of kids, they wouldn't
even say anything.
He was arrested the next day.
And I was ready
to testify against him,
so he couldn't hurt other kids.
It was all I could think about.
But Grady took a plea bargain.
He got three years.
Three years, that's it.
I couldn't believe it.
How'd you run
into Grady in county?
I was dropping supplies off
in the laundry.
And I heard arguing.
If you tell the DA
about our little talk,
I'm gonna kill
you ugly...
I swear, I won't tell anyone.
I swear.
Not a word.
That voice.
I recognized it immediately.
Don't say a word.
Not to anybody.
Not one word.
The bastard who raped me
was right there.
So I waited for
the other guy to leave.
You're Bruce Grady,
aren't you?
Who's asking?
Pete McCrone.
We met 20 years ago.
When I was a kid.
Not ringing a bell.
When you raped me.
Figures you'd wind up in here.
Squeezed his neck
as hard as I could.
It surprised me.
I didn't think I could do
something like that.
Hmm, well, then what happened?
I panicked.
I stuffed him into the closet,
I wiped up the blood,
and I got hell out of there.
What were you even
doing in County?
I mean, the only charge
I see here is a misdemeanor.
What the hell happened?
It's stupid--
child endangerment.
What do you mean?
I left my two-year-old
at home in the crib,
and I went and tried to pull
my wife out of the bar.
While I was gone,
the neighbors called the cops.
And that was a month ago.
You haven't had
your arraignment yet?
Public defender told me
he was handling things.
That I'd be out
in 24 hours.
And then never heard anything.
Hey, uh...
maybe you could talk to someone.
Get things straightened out,
get me out of here.
Pete, man, I just...
I don't think
that's gonna happen.
You know, not-not now.
After-after all this.
Heard you got a confession
out of McCrone.
Yeah.
Yeah, he copped
to everything.
He recognized Grady
20 years later?
It was Grady's voice.
That's what got him.
Pete never forgot
that voice.
Course, it was
a million-to-one shot
that McCrone'd even run into
Grady there in the first place.
Yeah, why was he in jail again?
Child endangerment?
Yeah, those charges
were dropped.
It was paperwork that kept him
in there for that month.
How you doing? You okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
Hey, seriously.
Sometimes these cases
hit a nerve, you know?
And... this one just hit a nerve
that was a little too close
to home for me, that's all.
You want to talk about it?
No, I want to forget about it.
Okay.
Well...
this is a hell
of a job, Nick.
We work a horrific crime,
turn around and
work another one.
They're bound to collide
with our personal lives,
sooner or later.
Just never know when.
Pete did the exact same thing
I would have done
in that situation.
Think you would have
gone that far?
Guy goes to jail
for a misdemeanor,
ends up in prison for murder.
Momentary decision...
ruined his life forever.
His life was ruined
a long time ago.