CSI Finlay,
I'm Sergeant Warner.
Don't worry,
we're gonna get you out of here.
We're pretty
good at this.
I'm gonna stick
this through,
and I want you to grab it,
and aim it under your seat
towards the bottom, okay?
WARNER:
You're doing great. Perfect.
Looks like C-4.
WARNER:
Yeah, the detonator
is wired to the vehicle's
security system.
We can't break the windows;
we can't open the doors.
But if we stop the clock,
we stop the bomb.
Okay, we have 13 minutes.
Let's do this.
Hard drive's on its way.
WARNER (over radio):
Copy that. I got it.
FINLAY:
Let me guess, the...
clock's connected
to the car's computer.
We give it a new brain...
maybe I get to keep mine.
That's the plan.
Do me a favor, pop the hood.
(phone ringing)
Russell.
DIGITALLY ALTERED VOICE:
Hello, Mr. Russell.
I hope you understand
you only have yourself to blame
for what's happening right now.
Hold on a sec. Who is this?
I would think
in the last three days
I've made myself clear.
In fact, if you answer
this simple question,
you can save CSI Finlay's life.
Who am I?
I'm not playing this game.
Wrong answer.
(line beeps)
(rapid beeping)
The clock's changed!
It's down to one minute!
Control, we
got a problem.
You need to extract. Now.
Extract?
But, sir...
That's an order.
Go!
You did everything
that you could. Go!
RUSSELL: No, no, no, no.
Why are you pulling back?
What the hell are you doing? You
can't just leave her out there.
There's no time.
Do something else, man!
She's gonna die!
She's already dead.
(phone ringing)
It's me. Yes?
Are you ready to be reasonable?
One last chance.
CSI Finlay's life
is in your hands.
Answer the question.
(rapid beeping continues)
Who am I?
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
(sirens wailing)
♪ ♪
(sighs)
I feel like I'm back
in high school.
You know, when we were
working together in Seattle,
I didn't think
you were that into me.
I wasn't.
(both laugh)
Detective Daniel Shaw is now...
Daniel Shaw, P.I.
How'd that happen?
Well, you left the job.
I was fired, remember?
Yeah, by your buddy Russell.
And now you're here in Las Vegas
working with him, together.
There's got to be
a story there.
You first.
What do you mean?
Well, we just happen
to run into each other in LVPD?
What brings you to Vegas?
Would you believe me
if I said it was you?
No. You're not that good a liar.
(phone chimes)
Man needs you. Always has.
You're gonna need to get
another ride back to the hotel.
(camera clicking)
Hey, I don't think
I was, uh...
running late.
You didn't have to process
the whole crime scene yourself.
I would've helped.
Where's the body?
Well, that's a good question.
(zipper closing)
The body's been removed.
Yeah, problem is,
I didn't process this.
Killer did.
I've seen this before.
We've seen this before.
In Seattle.
What are you guys
talking about?
Jared Briscoe,
the Gig Harbor Killer.
He murdered seven women,
all of them college students.
Last three victims,
he took the bodies,
left processed crime scenes
for us to find.
His way of mocking us.
He was mocking me.
I was the one
he wanted to laugh at.
But you got the
last laugh, right?
I mean, you caught him.
Yeah.
He's on death row.
Just lost his last appeal.
Scheduled to be
executed next week.
STOKES:
So, what?
You think someone's
decided to pick up
where your boy left off?
Yeah. Yeah, I do.
MAN: You got yourselves
the wrong man. I mean,
that's what you want me to say,
right, so that you can
beat a confession out of me?
It's not gonna happen.
Because...
...I am your man.
You got me.
Just like the newspapers say,
I am the Gig Harbor Killer.
DETECTIVE: You sound proud
of yourself, Jared.
JARED:
Proud? Nah.
I just did what I do--
some things
are just in your nature.
Does that include
playingat being a CSI?
Processing
your own crime scenes?
That was me just having a little
fun with my friend, Mr. Russell.
DETECTIVE: Right down
to stalking his daughter?
How is Maya?
DETECTIVE: Those last
three girls you killed,
where are their bodies?
JARED: 'Cause the families
want closure, right?
But... this ain't the movies.
And, trust me, they do not
want to see them now.
But maybe someone else does.
(whispers):
Is that what you want?
Reliving the past?
Unfortunately.
Well, unfortunately,
I just got a call
from the Washington State
Department of Corrections.
Apparently, you're
still loved up there,
enough to pull strings
to get Jared Briscoe
transferred down here
for an interview?
I didn't mean
to go around you, Conrad.
No, you didn't.
You just ran right over me.
You're pissed. I'm sorry.
No, it's more than
that-- I'm worried.
You're supposed to be the
cool head around here.
That's why I hired you.
Conrad, I need to talk
to Briscoe face-to-face
so I can understand
what's going on here in Vegas.
You mean a copycat.
Yeah, I do.
All right, D.B.,
look, I know what
happened in Seattle.
I know Briscoe started to follow
his exploits in the news,
started to focus on you,
the lead investigator,
even to the point
where he stalked Maya.
Yeah, and that was a mistake.
Well, don't make
one of your own
by opening up old wounds.
I already lost one friend
to ghosts of the past;
I don't need to lose another.
How is Jim?
Ellie Brass is facing a fight.
I don't think
either of them can win, but...
he says he's not
gonna leave her.
Even if that means leaving us.
I need to do this.
(camera clicking)
Wow.
Certainly lives
up to billing.
Uh-huh.
I saw Finn outside; she said
you could use a hand here.
I haven't had a chance to work
any of the blood pools yet.
Oh, well, I'm on it.
You know, this guy really
did our jobs for us.
He marked
all the evidence.
Including the murder weapon,
a fisherman's gaff.
You don't see that much.
Yeah, especially not
in the desert.
Even dusted it for fingerprints.
Killer leave us one?
(chuckles)
No, ma'am.
You know,
Finn's right-- based
on the volume of blood
and this arterial spray,
our missing victim
definitely died here.
Sara.
Yeah?
Digital recorder?
Yeah, just like the ones we use.
Dusted it for prints, as well.
Hit "play."
DIGITALLY ALTERED VOICE:
I'm standing facing south.
Spatter indicates castoff
consistent
with blunt force trauma.
Murder weapon:
a 28-inch fisherman's gaff.
(woman sobbing)
(screaming)
Turning back toward
the center of the room, I follow
the gravitational drops
to the primary blood pool.
First blush, I'd say our killer
played cat and mouse
with his prey, until he finally
gave her the hook,
finishing her.
First blush, of course.
Whoever this is, they knew
what they were doing.
I mean, if I didn't
know any better,
I would say it was one of us.
Or a cop. Or a CSI.
But even we
make mistakes, right?
I can start getting this stuff
back to the lab.
One thing left to do first.
♪ ♪
My hearing may be compromised
by twin ear infections,
but I know you're there.
So, do you have an answer?
(sighs)
Forgive me, but...
some results are
sufficiently disturbing
to merit a second look.
Including running peptide
mass fingerprinting.
Meaning you found proteins?
In concentrations
that corroborate your rather
unsettling suspicions.
So the strings and markers were
definitely made
from human tissue.
Ick. And yes.
Has Henry run the DNA?
Not yet. Your
samples are on deck.
Sara is having him
expedite the analysis of
the blood from the scene.
Did he get an I.D.
on our victim?
DNA got a hit in CODIS
to a Seattle college student,
Emily Bartson, 19.
Reported missing five weeks ago.
FINLAY: Is this what
you're waiting for?
What's this?
That is Emily Bartson's
homicide report.
Missing college student.
Seattle P.D. says that
her parents hired a P.I.
to help find her.
Ring a bell?
I didn't know
Emily Bartson was dead.
Truth is, I didn't
even think she was in Vegas.
Then why are you here?
My partner.
Keri Torres.
Oh, I know Keri.
She worked Homicide.
Yeah, we left Seattle P.D.
together, started up an agency.
Emily's parents
hired us.
Keri came down here
to check out a lead.
I've been having a hard time
getting ahold of her.
She's not answering her phone,
so I got worried.
So you're here looking for Keri?
Look, I'm not sitting here
waiting for homicide reports
for girls I didn't even know
were dead.
Then what are you waiting for?
CCTV footage off-Strip.
Last place
I know where Keri was.
I already slipped a C-note
to one of your dispatchers.
I was thinking
maybe you could help.
(scoffs)
You want me to help you?
After you lied to me?
You weren't even that great
in the car.
There's something in it
for both of us.
We're obviously working
on the same case now, right?
Are you sure
that's even Keri?
SHAW:
It's got to be.
I trapped her credit card;
her last charge was
at this coffee shop.
Can you get us
a better look?
FINLAY:
Can't make out the faces.
And the guy she's meeting with
has his back to us, so...
You have no idea
who he might be?
Keri interviewed Emily
Bartson's roommate.
She said she had a weekend
lined up with a client in Vegas.
Keri was trying
to track the guy down.
A client?
Emily dabbled in
the sex trade.
She worked occasionally
as an escort.
Maybe this is the client,
but whoever he is,
this video isn't
giving us anything.
Wait a second.
Look at that.
Look how he's nervously
running his hands
along the edge of the table,
gripping the underside.
Doesn't show his face,
but maybe he left something
of himself behind.
Waiters like to wipe down
the top of a table, but...
not the underside.
It's a long shot.
But this is Vegas.
♪ ♪
Hey. How's it going?
Well, I won't be
visiting Nell's
Street Coffee House
anytime soon.
That bad, huh?
But it looks like you were able
to pull some prints off of this.
(beeping)
Yeah, and a hit on AFIS, too.
Jared Briscoe?
That's the Gig Harbor Killer.
That's impossible.
Briscoe's been in prison
for the last five years.
And I've heard
of copycat killers,
but never carbon copycat.
Check out which
digit is a match.
He's giving us the finger.
♪ ♪
Maya.
(door creaks)
RUSSELL:
This is Russell.
I need backup
and a forensics support team.
West Puget Drive. Slip 37.
I just...
(creaking)
I just found
the Gig Harbor Killer.
Congratulations.
I'm not sure who's been dreaming
of this moment more.
Me or... you.
Show me your hands.
This is a surprise.
In the newspaper,
the reporter said
you traded your gun
for a microscope.
I'm not gonna ask you again.
Show me your hands!
Okay.
(gunshot)
(gunshots)
What are you waiting for?
Really?
All this trouble
just to say good-bye?
Mmm.
Crime scene.
Need a little help on a case?
You know, I'm pretty good
at forensics.
Yeah, apparently
so is someone else.
Someone who seems
inspired by your work.
You know anything
about that, Jared?
Can't say that I do.
Victim's name is
Emily Bartson.
College student.
(inhales sharply)
Sexy.
(chuckles)
She sell herself on the side?
Her body's missing, Jared.
Just like
the private investigator
who went looking
for her.
And she was last seen
outside a coffeehouse where
we found your fingerprint.
From your middle finger.
That's rude.
But...
so's this.
Lost it last year.
Prison fight.
Guy bit it off.
I think he swallowed it,
'cause all I know is...
I didn't get it back.
But then...
(chuckles) I'm not really
gonna need it, am I?
You've had
four appeals.
Lost every one of them, right?
You think we're gonna
offer you a deal?
You help us catch the copycat,
we're gonna let you go?
I have nothing to do with this.
The last thing I would do
is share my legacy.
I'm the Gig Harbor Killer.
You know, I have a lot of fans.
Books about me,
documentaries.
My point is...
maybe that guy didn't
swallow my finger.
Maybe he sold it
to a very sick person.
All work and no play
makes Nick a dull boy.
(chuckles)
It's a gaff,
not an axe, Kubrick.
Good point.
Good movie.
Looks like Ecklie's
purchase of a 3D mapping system
is paying off.
Yes, it is. So much, in fact,
that it's pointed out
something that's just
not adding up for me.
What's that?
Well, I reconstructed
the killer's movements based
on the blood at the scene.
Everything's consistent,
except for...
castoff patterns on the ceiling
and on the floor
to the south there.
They just don't match up
with the murder at all.
You think
that blood was planted?
Yes, I do.
And the fact
that he strung it
tells me it must mean something.
How so?
Well, Russell mentioned
that the Gig Harbor Killer
used to get off
on-on taunting them.
Yeah, I heard
at the last scene, he scrawled
Russell's daughter's name
on the walls and ceiling.
I didn't know that.
After Russell left the, uh,
"processed" crime scene,
he called Seattle P.D. and
requested a protective detail
for Maya and her family.
(exhales)
Well, if we're looking
at a copycat killer here,
then he may be leaving
some messages
of his own.
Hey.
Any word on Keri?
No. No, not yet.
See you got your visitor's badge
validated for another day.
Does that go with
the hundred dollars
you gave Dispatch?
Along with coffee privileges.
Oh, help yourself.
You know, I didn't think
that we got off
on the wrong foot.
Sex does not
buy you a free pass.
You lied to me.
Sin of omission.
Besides, you lied to me, too.
Prison visitor logs,
Washington State.
You didn't tell me
that the guy Keri met
at that coffee house
might be a killer.
More than that--
Gig Harbor copycat.
Sin of omission.
Look, we all worked
the Gig Harbor case.
You, Russell, me.
Even Keri.
If you let me in, I can help.
Keri's my partner.
I need to help.
So can we...
get back on the right foot?
We can try.
Uh, P.D.
found Keri Torres's car.
Sara's processing it now.
Talk about clean.
Yeah.
Um, I'm sorry,
have you two met?
Oh, yeah, we have.
Yeah, P.I. Shaw
is the one who's been
drinking all our coffee,
and "clean" is an
understatement.
The car was washed
and detailed.
No prints, no trace.
There's not a speck of dust.
Wow.
Even the inside?
Yeah, I fumed--
not a single print.
But you do need
to see this.
Whoa.
What the hell?
FINLAY: Looks like
high velocity spatter.
SIDLE: Yeah, that's what
I thought at first, too.
But there's no other blood
event in the car, and...
the pattern doesn't
make any sense.
It's like someone placed the
blood drops deliberately.
So why go
to all that trouble?
I don't know the
answer to that yet,
but I do think
it had something to do
with the Gig Harbor Killer.
Why do you think that?
Because Keri Torres
thought it before me.
Whoever wanted us
to find the blood
wanted us to find
these, too.
This is Keri's notebook.
And case files.
They were all
in the trunk.
You know, we were all thinking
that Keri was here investigating
the death of
Emily Bartson,
but most of these
files are related
to the Gig
Harbor Killer.
Well, like you said,
she did work that case.
According to this,
she's finding
similarities between
the Gig Harbor victims
and Emily Bartson.
She does fit the profile--
blonde, college student,
part-time escort.
Seems like
Keri was already onto the idea
of a Gig Harbor copycat.
And we know she was
on the trail of a client
here in Vegas
who hired Emily for the weekend.
A client who
may be the murderer,
not only of Emily Bartson,
but also Keri.
Did you find something?
Keri scribbled in
an appointment.
"Monday, 2:30 p.m.,
Nell's Street Coffee House."
FINLAY:
Last time she was seen alive.
Meeting our mystery man
on that video.
Who now has a name.
FINLAY:
Mark Turner.
You know who he is?
Yeah, thanks to
Washington State prison logs.
He's a local
guy who just
happened to have visited
Jared Briscoe
five or six times
in the past year.
I'm sorry, you can't
just walk in here.
This badge says
that I can.
TURNER: This offer
has to go out tonight.
No one goes home
until this is done.
You lost?
Mark Turner?
That's right.
LVPD.
We need to ask you
some questions.
Leave us.
What's this about?
It's about Emily Bartson.
Never heard of her.
What about Keri Torres?
Who?
You met her at Nell's Street
Coffee House on Monday.
That isn't me.
I was in D.C. on Monday.
Can you prove that?
Certainly can.
As general counsel for
Winthrop International,
my travels are
carefully documented.
Same as your visits
to the Washington State prison.
Unless you're gonna tell us
that you don't know
who Jared Briscoe is, either.
I am acquainted
with Mr. Briscoe.
However, my dealings with him
are privileged information.
Privileged how?
If you must know, I have
been enlisted to defend
a man who has been
wrongfully imprisoned.
Wrongfully imprisoned?
Says who?
MAN:
Says me.
I know how you feel.
The same way I felt
when I first discovered
my brother on the news.
A serial killer, a sadist,
sentenced to death,
they said.
I didn't know him,
yet the face I saw was mine.
So you and
Jared Briscoe...
We were adopted at birth.
And raised in different worlds.
We never knew
of each other.
Never met.
We still haven't.
The support I've been
lending Jared
is anonymous,
carried out through
my emissary, Mr. Turner.
I don't believe this.
Mr. Winthrop,
why don't you let me...
Give us the room, please.
I apologize for
my rudeness.
We haven't met either.
I'm Paul Winthrop.
And you are?
We're investigating
the murder of a college
student, Emily Bartson.
And the disappearance of an
investigator sent to find her,
my partner, Keri Torres.
And you think
my general counsel, Mr. Turner,
is somehow involved?
The evidence suggests he was the
last person to see her alive.
Whatever your evidence is,
I can vouch for
Mr. Turner's character.
He wouldn't harm anyone.
What about you?
Maybe that's you
in the photograph.
It's happening
again, isn't it?
Dead co-eds, missing
women, the police
searching
in the wrong places,
accusing the innocent.
Jared Briscoe is not innocent.
Jared is a victim.
First of fate.
Two boys abandoned--
one finds a loving home,
the other is consigned
to hell in foster care.
But Jared is not the depraved
killer you say he is.
Your brother confessed
to the murder of seven women.
And it is that confession alone
that keeps him on death row.
As Jared's twin, I was
prepared to submit my DNA.
But then I was told that my
DNA wouldn't help because,
to my surprise, Jared
was not convicted on DNA.
In fact, I
was told that
the killer's DNA
was never found.
We didn't need it.
There was plenty of evidence
on Jared's boat.
Circumstantial evidence.
Of my brother's
weak-minded obsession
with the exploits
of a serial killer.
FINLAY: Not to
mention the serial
stalking of the lead
investigator's daughter.
Maya Russell, yes, I know.
I saw her photo in the
newspaper-- beautiful.
Whatever you believe,
Mr. Winthrop,
your brother was
convicted by a jury.
Four appeals have failed
to change that.
Mere proof that the
system protects itself.
Because you
wouldn't be here
if the real killer
weren't still out there.
Well, maybe you're right.
Or half right.
Or maybe it's you, Ms. Finlay,
who needs to be right.
We both know why.
(gunshot)
(men grunting)
What are you waiting for?
I got your back.
(sirens wailing in distance)
FINLAY: In five years, I have
never doubted for one minute
that you and I made the
right call in Seattle, okay?
Except for letting
that bastard live.
I hope you're not planning
to share that sentiment
with anyone.
But being in that room
with Winthrop-- D.B.,
we missed something.
Briscoe had a partner.
You think the brothers
were working together.
I think they still are.
Okay, look, guys,
I'll admit the situation
is highly unusual.
But Paul Winthrop has
an unblemished record.
Man was a pillar of the
community in San Diego,
where he built
a real estate empire.
Same's true in Vegas since
he moved here last year.
Take advantage
of the soft real estate. Yes.
I read that
article, Conrad.
I just have a different
point of view.
Okay? I say that
Winthrop moved here
because you
and I are here.
And he's got a plan
to spring his brother,
so that they can go on
another spree, to mock us.
I already warned one person
in this room
about making this personal.
And given history,
I'm giving you
the same warning.
For all we know,
Winthrop is on the level.
And the murder of Emily Bartson,
here in Las Vegas,
with the same M.O.?
ECKLIE: Could be a copycat,
or maybe you didn't
get the right guy
and Jared Briscoe
is just what his brother
says he is:
a deluded patsy who took the
fall for the real killer.
You're being awfully quiet.
I'm thinking.
I have to say,
being in the room with Briscoe,
this time was different.
You know, maybe it was me.
Maybe...
five years has given me
some perspective.
Obviously, he believes
that he's the Gig Harbor Killer,
and it's the only thing
that gives his unremarkable life
any meaning
at this point, but...
So you're telling me that
you think he's innocent?
No, I'm not saying that.
I'm saying that maybe--
just maybe--
he wasn't the mastermind.
We're saying...
(knocking)
Sorry, I don't want
to interrupt,
but Henry ran DNA on
the evidence markers
and the trajectory strings
that the killer
fashioned out of human tissue.
Results are back.
DNA is a match to
Belinda Forster,
Nicole Davis and
Grace Duncamp.
Those are
the Gig Harbor Killer's
last three victims in Seattle.
The three women we never found.
♪ ♪
Hey.
So you probably
already heard by now,
The Shining has nothing
on our current case
when it comes to twins.
Yeah, I did hear that.
Well, in light
of recent events,
I think I may have
found something.
That is,
unless I'm crazy.
So, Sara found
this blood pattern
in the headliner of
Keri Torres's car.
What, do you think
it's a message?
Well, I kept
looking at it
and thinking that
I've seen this before.
Huh?
That pattern is
a constellation.
Gemini.
The twins.
You think I'm crazy?
No crazier than I am,
because I think I tripped
over the same thing.
Well, you remember
those castoff patterns
I said didn't make any sense?
Yeah, but were still
strung by the killer.
Right. Watch the monitor.
Keep your eye
on the green strings, okay?
Gemini.
Well, I may have found
something even
more than that.
The, uh, warehouse
where our killer left us
the processed crime scene
used to house a building
and supply company called
Castor Novelties, Inc.
Castor?
As in Castor and Pollux?
Yeah.
And the same company used
to own a chemical plant,
Pollux Petroleum,
off Highway 178.
I found the address
in Keri Torres's notebook.
It looked like she was
planning a visit there.
All right, I'll get over there
and look into it.
Son of a bitch.
I know. Just when you think this
guy couldn't outdo his last one,
he goes and does
something like this.
Full-on mass
grave excavation
complete with
strings and markers.
Crazy fool even set up
a field morgue this time.
I need to see the bodies.
STOKES: He laid them all out
just like a doctor would.
Female and mummified,
so we're definitely not looking
at Emily Bartson
or Keri Torres here.
No.
They've been buried
too long for that.
And not even
in this ground.
I mean, you can eyeball it
and see that soil trace
is nothing like
desert caliche.
Yeah, the whole excavation
has been staged,
just like everything else.
Yes, sir.
"Rainier Valley College."
Class ring.
Nicole Davis went there.
Okay, well,
Super Dave and the doc
are en route as we speak.
We'll collect
some DNA...
I don't need DNA
to tell me who they are.
I know these girls.
(camera clicking)
Find anything, Doc?
Well, based on
preliminary observation,
all the victims exhibit
blunt force trauma to the head
and multiple sharp force
injuries to the torso.
Beaten and stabbed,
just like all the others.
Well, the type
of weapon
is consistent
with a fisherman's gaff.
He also performed
his own Y-incision.
Seems to have
removed the organs.
That's what he used
to make the trajectory strings
and the markers.
Five years, we found nothing.
Families had to go
without answers.
So now he just gives them back
just like that.
So what do you
think it means?
Maybe he's telling us
he's closing the book on Seattle
and opening it on Vegas.
So, I collected DNA
to confirm I.D.,
but I think I may have
found something else.
One of the victim's nails
suggests
that she may have fought
her attacker.
Did she get
a piece of him?
Oh, yeah.
Big piece.
She bit him, too.
I found skin and hair
between her teeth.
ROBBINS:
Five years,
so he probably assumed
the evidence wouldn't survive.
Well, let's hope he's wrong.
David, why don't you
get that over to Nick.
He can run the sample
through RapidHit.
Yeah.
Hey.
I heard they
found bodies.
Yeah, not Keri,
not Emily Bartson.
Bodies were
the last three victims
of the Gig Harbor Killer.
You got to be
kidding me.
I know.
Who knew that psychopath
Briscoe had a twin.
Yeah. Who may be even more
of a psychopath.
Trick will be proving it.
I think we bring in Winthrop
and we lean on him.
Yeah, that's where
I'm going right now.
Not without me.
Sorry. Can't come with me
on this one.
You're out
of your jurisdiction.
Finn, come on.
When have you ever known me
not to be able
to take care of myself?
(car alarm chirps)
(rapid beeping)
(beeping)
Hi.
Confirmed I.D. on the victims.
Yeah, what about
David's samples?
Yeah, running it right now.
You know, Briscoe's brother was
so willing
to give up his DNA.
I wonder how eager
he's gonna be after this result.
Forget reasonable doubt.
Yeah, I say we get two for one.
(computer beeping)
What?
What do you got?
Ah, damn it.
All right, all right.
(phone ringing)
Take those samples
back to the lab.
Have Henry rerun
them, will you?
Yeah. Russell.
When?
(tires screech)
(sirens wailing)
How long?
15 minutes. My guys are on it.
(phone ringing)
Russell.
DIGITALLY ALTERED VOICE:
Hello, Mr. Russell.
I hope you understand,
you only have yourself to blame
for what's happening right now.
Hold on a second. Who is this?
I would think
in the last three days,
I've made myself clear.
In fact, if you answer
this simple question,
you can save CSI Finlay's life.
Who am I?
No, I'm not playing this game.
Wrong answer.
(line beeps)
(rapid beeping)
Clock's changed!
It's down to one minute!
Control, we got a problem.
HURST:
You need to extract. Now.
Extract? Sir...
That's an order!
Whoa, whoa.
What the hell are you doing?!
You can't just
leave her out there.
HURST: There's no time.
Do something else, man.
She's gonna die.
She's already dead.
(phone ringing)
It's me. Yes.
DIGITALLY ALTERED VOICE:
Are you ready to be reasonable?
One last chance.
CSI Finlay's life
is in your hands.
Answer the question.
Who am I?
All right, all right,
I'll give you what you want.
Yes, I know who you are.
You're the Gig Harbor Killer.
(rapid beeping)
That wasn't so hard,
now, was it?
(rapid beeping)
(gasps)
We're clear!
Go get her!
Now! Now! Go!
(officers shouting)
It's all right. Come on.
You're gonna be all right.
ECKLIE: You do know what this is
going to do to your career?
Yeah, what choice
did I have, Conrad?
You want me to let Finlay
just die?
That's not what
I'm talking about.
Jared Briscoe's defense
has already filed a writ
of habeas corpus.
They're going to haul you
into court...
I know that. I know.
They're gonna rehash
everything that happened
in Seattle.
They're gonna say
that I went after Briscoe
'cause he went
after my daughter.
That I built the entire case
on circumstantial evidence.
I know all that.
That's right.
They're gonna question
your motives there.
They'll question
your motives here.
Yeah, just like you did.
Not to mention
this new DNA evidence.
Yeah, which didn't come back
to Briscoe or his twin,
but to an unknown male,
who probably is the real killer.
Maybe. Maybe not.
You still think
the twins are behind this?
Yes, I do.
So, what--
the DNA was planted,
another part of the game?
Catch me if you can?
Yeah, that's right.
And if they're not?
If the DNA is right,
and you put the wrong man--
an innocent man--
on death row?
Then I will find
the right man, Conrad,
and I will just have to live
with the rest of it.
You're not the only one who'll
have to live with it, D.B.
This lab will.
You want me to resign?
No.
I don't want you to resign.
I want you to fix this.
If Briscoe and
his brother
really are the ones
behind these murders...
...catch 'em.
♪ ♪
(whispering): Do you know
whose crime scene this is?
It's yours.
(screaming)
♪ ♪