(siren wailing,
men arguing indistinctly)
Thought we were going
back to your place.
MAN: Babe, just
relax, it's cool.
I just got to pick
up a little package.
(cell phone dings)
That's it.
It's her again.
I'm so screwed.
Okay, just tell her
you're with me.
Yeah, right.
Abby, she's not even
your real mother.
You know what, just
give me the phone.
I have a few things that
I want to say to her.
Cash and phones.
Hand them over.
Okay, screw
you, buddy.
I said,
hand them over.
Oh, my God.
Okay, man, look, just
chill, just relax.
Now!
Slade!
Stop!
(gun fires)
(gasps)
Abby, come on!
Miss?
Can you hear me?
Are you okay?
Can you tell me
what happened?
Sara Sidle.
I need to talk to Sara Sidle.
What happened?
I don't know,
she's not talking.
You want me to
call her folks?
She's in foster care.
How do you know her?
Old case.
When Abby was five, her father
shot the whole family,
then turned
the gun on himself.
She was the
only survivor.
God, that's horrible.
Hey.
Are you all right?
Yeah.
You're okay?
Mm-hmm.
So, what's
going on here?
You're hanging
around the alphabets,
standing over the body
of a dead guy.
He pulled a gun on us.
"Us"? Slade?!
You were down here
with Slade?!
Abby, I told you
that kid is bad news.
Sara, please, I...
Did he shoot this guy?
Listen to me.
I finally remember something.
From ten years ago.
My father didn't do it.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
SIDLE: She's fine,
we'll see you soon.
Uh-huh.
Okay, bye.
Joanna's on her way.
As soon as you give
your statement,
you can go home.
But we need to talk
about my father.
I told you--
I think he's innocent.
Abby, you always told me that
you didn't remember anything
about what happened
that night.
I didn't.
But after Slade shot that guy,
I smelled something.
Uh, a chemical,
kind of like kerosene but not.
I smelled the exact same thing
the night my family was killed.
You mean, inside the tent?
When I smelled it,
it's like I was
right back there.
I'd just been shot.
My head was bleeding.
He picked me up.
That's when I smelled it.
When he was putting me
into my sleeping bag.
SIDLE: Your father?
ABBY: No.
This man had a beard.
It wasn't my father.
I am telling you--
someone else was there
that night.
He killed my family.
Tried to kill me.
My father didn't do it.
Okay, all right,
listen, I...
I know you
want to believe
that your father
is innocent,
but the evidence...
I know what I saw.
Abby, you were
five years old.
You'd been shot,
you saw your mother
and your sister killed.
That kind
of trauma ...
can play tricks
on your mind.
I'm not making
this up.
Abby, I...
I thought you of all people
would believe me.
Joanna.
Oh.
Cream and sugar.
Thank you.
Abby's just, uh,
giving her statement.
Uh, I'm really glad
she reached out to you.
She's 15.
You're her mom.
It's a complicated
relationship.
I don't think she really
thinks of me as her mother.
Ever since we started
the adoption process,
she's been acting out.
Breaking curfew,
skipping school...
She loves you
and Brian.
She's been through
so much, huh?
Sometimes I'm amazed that
she's done as well as she has.
Well, I-I think
that's because of you.
You two have
a very special bond.
I'm so glad you're
part of her life.
Thank you.
I am, too.
I'll be right back.
Hey, Slade!
What the hell is
wrong with you,
taking Abby
to that part of town?
Yo, you see that?
I didn't see anything.
She is not
your girlfriend anymore.
You come near her again,
and my face is gonna be
the last thing
you will ever see.
Let's go.
Hey.
That the guy
from the alley?
Uh-huh.
(sniffs)
Greg?
Yeah.
What are you doing?
Tell me what you smell.
(sniffs)
Urine.
Booze.
And years without a shower.
Why?
I smell smoke.
Like he's been
around a fire.
Yeah, well, he was probably
trying to stay warm.
Why are you so interested
in how he smells?
It's not me, it's Sara.
Uh, this guy was killed
mugging a young girl.
She smelled something
on him that reminded her
of a crime scene
from ten years ago.
Was the case unsolved?
Ruled
a murder-suicide.
Youngest daughter
survived.
Now she thinks her father
might have been innocent.
He's pretty ripe.
It's gonna be hard to isolate
one particular smell.
Sounds like a job
for the Cyranose 320.
♪ ♪
♪♪
Abby, I'm gonna take
a sample of your DNA.
Doesn't hurt.
I'm just gonna
put this swab
against your cheek,
like this.
Here we go.
Good job.
They're dead,
aren't they?
I'm sorry.
Abby, did you see
what happened?
Who hurt you
and your family?
I don't remember.
That's okay.
What's the last thing
that you do remember?
Mommy and Daddy.
They were fighting.
Then what happened?
I don't remember.
That's okay.
I want my mommy.
I know.
Of course you do.
It's okay.
SANDERS:
Sara?
Hey, Sara.
Got the, uh, results
on your Cyranose 320.
Your mugger was
a smelly guy.
Over 20 different
scents on him.
Most of them were
pretty common.
Alcohol, smoke, urine.
Abby said it was something that
she hadn't smelled in ten years.
Like kerosene,
or something.
Could've been
gun cleaner.
We found traces
of that on him.
Huh.
I didn't smell any of that
at the scene ten years ago.
Not on the gun,
not on the father.
Was there evidence
of another gun used?
No.
Firearms confirmed that every
shot came from the father's gun.
Well, someone could've
brought the smell
with him into the tent.
Stinky stuff.
I mean, it gets on your hands,
your clothes...
So it's possible
that someone
who smelled like gun cleaner
went into the tent,
used the
father's gun
and wiped out the whole family.
Abby... could be right.
Maybe her father didn't do it.
I know that you're pretty tight
with this girl.
I know you've stayed in touch
through all
these years.
She needed somebody
to look after her.
We've worked a lot of cases
where kids lost their parents.
Yeah...
but one parent killing another,
getting shipped off
to foster care...
That's something
I know a little bit about.
In all the years
we've been friends,
we've never really talked about
what happened
with your dad.
And I don't mean to pry, but...
You know what
happened.
They had
a volatile relationship.
And...
(phone buzzes)
It's Russell.
According to my case sheet,
you have
12 open cases.
Is that right?
More or less.
So then why are you
ordering evidence
from long-term storage
for a case that was closed
ten years ago?
Uh, new evidence
was brought to my attention
and, uh, I wanted to give
the case another look.
Well, then, you should've
come to me first.
I-I just wanted to see
if what I was told
had any merit.
All right.
Where are you getting
your new information?
Abby Fisher.
The girl that survived?
She smelled gun cleaner
and it brought back a memory
of the night that
her family was murdered.
She thinks that there was
someone else there.
Eyewitness accounts,
especially years after the fact,
are unreliable,
and you know that.
There's more.
Uh, I looked at
her dad's tox report
and there was a substantial
amount of alcohol
found in
his system,
but there were other peaks
on the GC
that were never analyzed.
Doc ruled this a suicide.
So you know what you're asking?
By reopening
this case,
you're asking Doc
to change the manner of death
and I just don't
see him doing that,
not with what you've given me.
Russell, Abby has believed
that her father was a murderer
her entire
life.
If there's a chance
that he wasn't,
we owe it to her
to find that out.
This girl lost
her whole family.
She has no one to fight for her.
Please,
let me just take a look at it.
All right, fine.
Take a look at it.
But wait, hold on.
Look, this is going to ruffle
a lot of feathers.
Not just Doc;
Ecklie, too.
So for my sake,
you'd better be right.
I know.
Let me get this straight:
Sara is accusing me
of cutting corners on my
examination of Mr. Fisher?
No, Doc.
In light of new
information,
Sara just wants to take
a look at the case
in a different
context.
All right.
Mr. Fisher died from
a contact gunshot wound
to the right temple.
There was gunshot residue
on his right hand,
his gun was found
beside him,
and he had a blood tox level
of .23.
Tell me, please,
what is it about this
that doesn't indicate suicide?
In the tox report,
Sara found a peak
from the GC that
was never analyzed.
Got that tox report right here.
What peak are
we talking about?
RUSSELL:
That one.
ROBBINS:
That's minor.
It has the same retention time
as ibuprofen.
That's why it wasn't analyzed.
Could be,
but you can't be sure
unless you do a Mass Spec,
so please,
Doc,
just pull the blood for me.
Retest it.
Sure.
ROBBINS:
Sorry.
You and Sara are out of luck.
Those samples were destroyed
three years ago.
D.B., if you
feel this strongly about it,
the only choice is
to exhume the body.
You're digging up my father?
Well, we need to do some
additional testing.
Then what
happens to him?
He'll be
re-buried.
Like a second funeral?
Well, there won't be
a service or anything.
He'll just be returned
to his grave.
I didn't get to go
to his funeral.
Or Mom's.
Or Hannah's.
You were still
in the hospital.
Did you?
Go to your father's funeral?
No.
Why not?
I wasn't allowed.
Do you miss him?
Yeah.
I do.
Guy looks pretty
good for being
in the ground
for ten years.
Miracle of
embalming.
Mm-hmm.
So, are you gonna
do a full autopsy?
It's not necessary.
Barry Fisher died from
a gunshot wound to the head,
and nothing is going
to change that fact.
Well, something caused
the peak on the GC.
If he was under
the influence of
some type of drug,
then maybe his death
wasn't a suicide.
If that's the case,
I will change my ruling
to "undetermined."
Well, good thing
he was autopsied.
Kept the organs
in a plastic bag.
I'm just glad
the mortuary
kept them in the bag
after they embalmed him.
Organs weren't exposed
to formaldehyde.
Best bet for identifying
acute dose of a drug
is the liver or the kidney.
Barry Fisher
was drugged.
Tox found trichloroethanol
in his liver sample.
A metabolite of
chloral hydrate, right?
That's what
the peak was.
It wasn't ibuprofen.
It was a knockout drug.
Doc changed the manner of death
from "suicide"
to "undetermined."
You were right.
Okay.
Where are we?
Well...
chloral hydrate is not
a recreational drug.
Fisher wouldn't have
taken it voluntarily.
So somebody drugged him.
Doc didn't find any injection
marks on Fisher's body,
but there were remnants of
paper cups in the fire pit.
The drug could've been
put into his drink.
Why would somebody
incapacitate the husband
if they were already planning
on shooting him?
Maybe to get the gun?
I mean, if
the plan was
to murder the family
and frame the father,
the killer would have
had to use his gun.
Fisher would not have
handed it over willingly.
Boy, somebody sure
hated the Fishers.
Kill the whole family?
Those two little girls?
I'll see if they had
any enemies.
So...
do I have the okay to...
officially reopen the case?
You bet.
When Doc ruled it a suicide,
I boxed up all of the evidence
because there wasn't
going to be a trial.
So... almost
everything
that I collected
has never been processed.
All right.
Have the boxes
sent to the garage.
Finn and Morgan
will set up the tent
and work the evidence.
You have a close
personal relationship
with Abby Fisher.
I need you to take a backseat.
Fair enough.
FINLAY:
Hey, Morgan.
You all set up?
BRODY:
Yep.
I used Sara's original
crime scene photos
as a guide.
Ah, those poor kids.
Had no idea that
their fun camping trip
would end
like this.
Yeah.
I, uh, placed note cards
reflecting the DNA results.
"M" is for Mom,
"H" is for Hannah,
"A" is for Abby.
All right.
And according to Sara's sketch,
the two girls were inside
their sleeping bags over here...
Hannah, Abby...
and then over here,
the mom.
Yeah, the nine-year-old, Hannah,
had Mom's blood
on her feet,
so we know Mom
was killed first,
right over there.
This, here,
is Hannah's blood trail.
FINLAY:
Hannah's wound
was immediately
debilitating and fatal.
So she would not have been able
to walk back to her bed.
So somebody carried her
and then tucked her in.
Well, the killer thought
Abby was dead, too,
'cause he tucked her in.
Shows remorse.
Or he wanted to make it look
like it was the father.
Somebody who cared
about his kids.
BRODY:
Yeah. Either way,
looks like the killer
had to touch the sleeping bags,
so it could be
a good source of prints.
Just like the tent flap.
I'm going to swab
every blood drop in here.
Maybe we'll get lucky
and the killer left
some of himself behind.
♪ ♪
♪♪
I got prints.
Some on the tent flap.
Those were unidentified.
But I also found one
on Hannah's
sleeping bag.
That one paid off.
Garth Fogel.
He's a registered
sex offender.
Convicted of molesting
a little girl back in '95.
He was released
from prison in 2004,
one month before the
Fishers were murdered.
SIDLE:
He has a beard.
The man that Abby remembered
tucking her into her
sleeping bag had a beard.
And smelled of
gun cleaner.
When Fogel
was arrested,
police found over
15 guns in his place.
ANDREWS:
Hey.
I analyzed the blood samples
Finn collected from the tent.
Everything belonged
to Mom and the two girls.
Except for one that turned out
to be animal blood.
"Animal blood"?
I'm still testing
to figure out what kind
of animal it came from.
There was no other DNA
in the tent?
Sorry.
But when I tested
Garth Fogel's samples
against the DNA samples,
I got a big surprise.
He was the biological father
of the nine-year-old
daughter Hannah.
Wait, I-I knew that Barry Fisher
wasn't Hannah's birth father.
According to a family friend,
Kathy Fisher told everyone
that Hannah's father died
in a car accident
before she was even born.
If I were pregnant
with a sex offender's baby,
I'd probably lie about it, too.
Maybe that lie
caught up with her.
Got the family killed.
Garth Fogel?
I'm CSI Nick Stokes.
I asked for a coffee
20 minutes ago.
Answer some of my questions, and
I'll see what I can do for you.
I haven't done anything wrong.
You mean recently
or ten years ago?
Do you recognize
this family?
I'll take that as a no.
Um...
how about now?
Oh, these are good.
How about these?
The Fishers went
on a camping trip and someone
slaughtered them in their tent.
Wasn't me.
The girls were five and nine.
They're really cute,
really innocent.
That's just the way
you like them, isn't it?
That's sick, you son of a bitch!
She was my daughter!
Sit your ass down!
I don't think the fact
that she was your daughter
would even stop
a pervert like you.
You probably even thought
you had a right to her.
You were out of prison a month
and you got that itch again.
Didn't you?
I think you followed
the Fishers to their campsite.
Drugged the dad
to get him out of the way.
And took his gun.
Went into the tent
to grab Hannah.
But Kathy wasn't gonna
let you take her daughter
without a fight.
(grunts)
Mommy! Mommy!
What did you do?!
You certainly weren't
going back to prison.
So, you got rid
of the witnesses.
I'm sorry.
And there must be some shred
of humanity
left in you because
after you shot
both girls,
you felt bad about it.
Tucked them
into their sleeping bags.
Then you finished off the dad,
and made it look
like a murder/suicide.
Sound about right?
That's a load of crap.
I was nowhere near that family.
Then how do you explain
your fingerprint
on Hannah's sleeping bag?
You'd better start
talking to me, man.
All right.
I saw them at their house.
They were packing
to go camping.
What were you doing there?
I wanted to see my daughter.
Kathy never told me
that she was pregnant.
I found out in prison.
So I looked them up
as soon as I got out.
But Kathy wasn't
gonna let you
anywhere near Hannah.
So you followed them
to their campsite.
No.
I went to their house.
Kathy was packing the
car and I told her
that Hannah has every right to
know who her real father is.
And that is me!
Kathy told me to go to hell.
That piss you off?
Yes, it pissed me off!
I lost my temper, all right?
I grabbed the sleeping bag
and I ripped it out of
the car, and that is
how my fingerprints got on it.
Kathy threatened
to call the cops,
so I got the hell out of there.
I never saw them after that.
SANDERS:
Nick thinks
Fogel's lying.
Does he have an alibi?
Said he was with his mom.
Great. Let's talk to her.
She died five years ago.
What?!
Nick is getting a warrant
to pull his old cell
and credit card records.
See if we can at least place
him near Mount Charleston
around the time
of the murders.
Abby picked Fogel
out of that mug book.
Thought he looked familiar,
she couldn't say for sure
whether he's the guy
that killed her family or not.
There's so much she doesn't
remember from the night.
There might be a way we can help
her recover those memories.
(bird squawking in distance)
You okay?
Yeah.
Just weird... being back.
Abby, you do not
have to do this.
I want to.
So... how do we do this?
You gonna hypnotize
me or something?
(laughs)
No.
We're just hoping that being
back here might jog your memory.
You know--
the sights, the smells?
Let your mind drift back.
It's worth a shot.
You did a great job.
It looks exactly
like it did ten years ago.
SANDERS:
Thanks. I even
put gun cleaner inside the tent
to see if it helps.
And I brought this.
We might need to
document it for court.
SIDLE:
Good plan.
GIRL:
Daddy!
Hannah...
(girls giggling)
Mommy!
(girls chattering indistinctly)
BOTH:
Daddy!
(girl screams)
♪ ♪
Mommy!
No! No!
No!
(gasps)
Mom and Hannah.
I saw them.
They were dead.
I'm so sorry.
What else did you remember?
The man, he...
he had a patch.
On his jacket.
It had antlers.
Like a deer?
Did you see his face?
I couldn't make it out.
He just shot them!
It's okay.
It's all right.
You did great.
Yeah.
It's okay.
FINLAY:
Henry identified
the animal blood we found
in the Fishers' tent.
It's elk blood.
Oh, maybe that's what Abby
saw on the killer's jacket.
I mean, an elk kind
of looks like a deer,
just with bigger antlers.
Okay, so we have a killer
who smells like gun cleaner
and has traces
of elk blood on him.
He's a hunter.
And if he was wearing a
jacket with a patch on it,
maybe he belongs
to a hunting club.
There are a lot of
them in Nevada.
Any close to Mount Charleston?
Let's see.
This club's logo is a duck.
That one.
That looks like
an elk to me.
"Legend Creek Hunting Club."
(door closes)
Dead animals.
Awesome.
God, it looks like they're just
staring us right in the eye.
So lifelike.
Thank you.
Stuffed them myself.
Right back there.
That 12-point buck? Three shots
to take him down.
He wanted to live.
He's a beauty.
Randy Pruitt.
Club president.
What can I do for you ladies?
This is Sarah Sidle,
I'm Morgan Brody.
We are with the Las Vegas
crime lab.
Crime lab?
We need to take a look
at your membership records
from 2004.
Specifically the members
who had tags to hunt elk.
(laughs)
Elk pressing charges these days?
We're investigating
the murder of a family
shot to death
on Mount Charleston.
We hunt animals,
not human beings.
Yeah?
Well, some people
can't tell the difference.
These people...
are my friends.
I'm sorry.
We're still gonna have
to take a look those records.
Well, our members have
a right to privacy.
Yeah.
Not anymore.
2004.
Thank you.
Let's pull all the members
that have beards
and tags to hunt elk,
and show the pictures to Abby.
Let's hope she can
identify our killer.
Take your time, okay?
That's him.
Are you sure?
Positive.
Yeah, we got an I.D.
Donald Wraith.
Lives in Henderson.
Donald Wraith!
LVPD! Turn off
the engine!
Out of the truck!
Get out!
Said get out!
Looks like the hunter
became the hunted.
STOKES:
Hey, Super Dave.
Sorry to drag you
all the way out here, man.
You kidding me?
Trees, good clean air.
It's nice to be out in nature.
STOKES:
Nine millimeter casing.
The ammo's consistent
with the victim's gun.
Powder burns indicate
he was shot at close range.
Yeah, but he couldn't
have shot himself--
the gun would have
fallen out of his hand.
Killer tried to make it
look like a suicide.
Abby Fisher I.D.'s Donald Wraith
as the man who shot her family.
We come out here to pick him
up and find him murdered?
Maybe to keep
him quiet?
Maybe.
Sounds to me
like someone else was involved
in this massacre ten years ago.
I thought Abby Fisher
only remembers one man
in the tent
that night.
Doesn't mean that somebody
else wasn't there.
Garth Fogel.
The pedophile?
Yeah, we haven't cleared him
as a suspect.
And so far I haven't been able
to find a connection
between Donald Wraith
and the Fisher family.
So, you're thinking Wraith's
connection is with Fogel.
Maybe they were
friends.
Fogel wanted
his daughter.
The Fishers weren't gonna give
her back without a fight.
Maybe he brings Wraith
for backup.
Go prove it.
Hey.
Nick said he found trace
on Donald Wraith's gun.
Were you able
to identify it?
Yeah, it was a
type of resin.
Traditionally, a hydrocarbon
secretion from plants,
resins were a prized possession
in the ancient world.
I'm sure you're familiar
with frankincense and myrrh.
Gifts for baby Jesus.
You're a wise woman.
But in this
day and age,
humans have been able to
create synthetic resins
that are much stronger
and more versatile
than their natural
predecessors.
As in this case, we
have a unique blend
of methyl methacrylate,
thixotropic and a
polymerization catalyst.
Aren't synthetic resins used
a lot in construction?
Yes, but...
'Cause
Garth Fogel works
as a laborer
for a construction company.
If we can prove he had
access, then we...
You didn't let
me finish.
Sorry.
The chemical structure
of this particular resin
is only used
in one industry.
Taxidermy.
Does Garth Fogel have a penchant
for stuffing woodland creatures?
No.
But I know someone who does.
Thank you.
You lied to me,
Randy.
You said you didn't
hunt people.
But you murdered
Donald Wraith.
And you murdered
the Fisher family.
No. No, I didn't.
We found a clear cast resin
on Donald Wraith's gun.
It's the same resin that
you purchased two weeks ago
for your taxidermy.
I-Is that all
you've got?
No, I have motive.
You and Donald Wraith killed
the Fishers ten years ago.
Donald was about to be arrested,
so you killed him
so he wouldn't
implicate you.
But you had already
implicated yourself.
We pulled your fingerprints
off the file
that you gave us
at the hunting club.
And it was a match to prints
from inside the tent
that the family was
slaughtered in.
What happened, Randy?!
Did you get tired
of hunting elk?
Did you want your prey
to beg for mercy?
It wasn't like that.
We never planned
on killing anyone.
What was your plan?
Donald wanted to have
some fun with the wife.
Her and the husband came by
the shop, asked directions.
Sorry to bother you guys--
it feels like
we've been driving
in circles for hours.
I'm a terrible
navigator.
We wanted to set up camp
near Deer Stream trail head.
Can't seem to find it.
Well, that's...
...easy to miss.
What you do is you
hit Timber Canyon.
There's a fork,
stay to the right,
it'll take you
all the way in.
Thank you so much.
My pleasure, ma'am.
You followed them
back to the campsite?
You had to get the husband
out of the way.
How did you drug him,
exactly?
Saw him sitting
alone at the fire.
Pretended we were
camping nearby.
Brought over
some booze.
When he wasn't looking,
we slipped him a Mickey.
You know, most people don't
just walk around,
carrying chloral hydrate
on them,
unless they've done
this kind of thing before.
What happened
after Fisher passed out?
I stood guard while
Donald went in the tent.
With Barry
Fisher's gun.
He was only gonna threaten
her, keep her quiet.
But she fought back.
I heard a shot.
Then two more.
What did you do?
We didn't know
they had children.
Donald said the girls saw his
face, so he had to kill them.
I took them back into
their sleeping bags,
while he went out to
take care of the husband.
There is a problem
with your story, Randy.
The youngest daughter
survived.
And she identified
Donald Wraith as the person
that put her back
into the sleeping bag.
Not you.
He's the one
that felt bad.
And I am
willing to bet...
that you are the one that pulled
the trigger that night.
Either way,
your hunting days are over.
So... they didn't
even know us?
They were just
bad people.
And you and your family were
in the wrong place
at the wrong time.
That's messed up.
Your father was
innocent.
All these years,
I blamed him.
Hated him.
Thought he killed
Mom and Hannah.
Tried to kill me.
You can let
that all go now.
Your dad was
a good man.
And he loved you
very much.
Hey, ready to go home?
Yeah.
Thank you.
Any time.
Oh, One D's playing
at the Hard Rock
Saturday night.
You in?
One Direction?
Seriously?
No, I'm just kidding.
It's Lorde,
I'll pick you up at 7:00.
Cool.
SANDERS:
You look like your dad.
He used to read to me
when I was a kid.
Charlotte's Web
was my favorite.
Must've read it
a hundred times.
That's a nice memory.
I have a lot of nice
memories of him.
My mom, too.
They were toxic when they
were together, though.
Your mom said
your dad was abusive?
She killed him
in self-defense?
That's what she said.
You don't believe her?
Look, I know my dad
wasn't a saint,
but my mom was
an alcoholic
who suffered from
mental illness.
I'm just not sure that things
were as black and white
as she made
them out to be.
Well, you did say they had
a volatile relationship.
Fact is...
I'll never know what
happened that night.
This is gonna
sound horrible,
but I'm kind of
jealous of Abby.
She gets to rewrite her
whole family history.
Nothing will ever change
what my mother did.
Well, you can't
change the past,
but you always
have the future.
Your mom's
still alive.
Not too late for you
to start over.
I don't know if I could.