(whimpering)
(whimpering continues)
You like what you see?
That is genuine artwork
by the Blue Paint Killer,
Keith Greer, collected
shortly before his arrest
and suicide.
Here, it's for only
a thousand bucks.
Certificate of
authenticity included.
Huh?
Mm, I don't know.
Think on it,
browse around.
Plenty of deadly
cool stuff here.
♪ ♪
This letter is
personally autographed
by the Strip Strangler.
A truly fascinating
criminal.
Throw in the crime scene photos,
we got a deal.
MAN (over speakers):
Fellow collectors!
Fellow collectors, it's time
to unveil the item
you've all been awaiting.
Bidding will start at $50,000.
No serial killer
in the last 30 years
has haunted Las Vegas quite like
the notorious Lucas Reem.
This morning,
we offer you the chance
to own the car driven by Reem
in 1995, when he slaughtered
ten souls over the course
of one summer.
(crowd murmuring excitedly)
Fellow collectors,
this is the chariot
that carried Reem
through his rampage!
(people gasping)
Damon?
That's fake, right?
Call 911!
That's rad, man!
Guess it's real.
Even cooler.
Victim's name
is Damon Harlow.
He and his
business partner there
started this interesting
little swap meet attracting
"murderabilia" buffs
from across the region.
Murderabilia.
True crime collectibles.
Artwork, autographs,
mementos.
All from famous killers.
Where'd they get all this crap?
Some of it comes from
police property auctions,
others are gifts from
incarcerated killers.
As long as the convicts
aren't directly profiting,
it's legal to
sell this stuff.
Including the car
belonging to Lucas Reem.
With our fresh kill here,
Damon Harlow.
You know,
I remember that summer.
I was 12 years old,
my parents were still together,
we were living in Vegas.
That monster was killing
a new girl every few weeks.
I watched my mom triple-check
the locks every night.
Yeah, it was a...
it was a big deal up north, too.
Reem confessed
to all ten murders, right?
Yet he still lingered
on death row for how long?
20 years.
Finally got the needle
a few months ago.
And now these guys want to
memorialize him.
Keep his legacy alive.
Yeah, it's a little disturbing.
Roomful of people
fixated on murder.
Maybe one of them
more committed than the rest.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
Liver temp puts
time of death
about ten hours ago.
So, midnight.
We're looking at
approximately...
a dozen stab wounds.
Cast-off and spatter indicates
that he was killed in the car,
not posed here after.
Unusual blood pattern.
Looks like something
brushed through the spatter.
Special breed of lookie-loos
in this place.
Nah, they're just figuring out
how much the fresh carnage
increases the value of the car.
You think I'm dealing in blood
money selling this stuff.
I think the city of
Milwaukee got it right
when they took all of
Jeffrey Dahmer's possessions,
shoved them
into a landfill.
Nothing like this
has ever happened.
Damon and I put on these events
a few times a year.
So when was the last time
you had contact with Damon?
Yesterday.
He called to say he wanted
to get the car ready.
He didn't show up this morning,
didn't answer my calls.
And yet you went right
ahead with the auction.
Damon was troubled, okay?
Drinking, depression.
Either could take hold
of him for a few days.
This car is
a huge sale.
I had buyers here
from all over.
I understand.
Got to give them what
they came for, right?
Let me ask you
one more thing.
Did Damon have any
enemies you knew of?
He had a temper.
Got into it sometimes
with customers, other dealers,
but it never got violent.
Look, these collectors
are good people.
Well, you'll forgive me if
I don't take my readings
from your moral compass.
50 grand for a car?
You'd think they'd
at least wipe the dust off.
These collectors want it
exactly as Lucas Reem left it.
Although he didn't leave
those fresh fingerprints
there on the dashboard,
so I'm gonna run them.
Memory card's full.
I got to get
another camera.
Hurry up.
Hey, hey, hey!
Get out of here.
Give me your I.D.s.
Come on.
I'll run them.
The hell are you guys doing?
Wanted to
take a look.
Maybe get a selfie.
We've just never seen
a real vic before.
Yeah, well,
I've seen plenty,
and there's nothing fun
about it.
What's that cop doing
with our licenses exactly?
He's checking to see
if you're criminals.
Or just idiots.
I mean, Lucas Reem?
Nate Haskell?
How would you feel if it was
your loved ones they attacked?
No records,
but I'll cuff them.
Why don't we give them
a break, Mitch.
As long as you guys promise to
find more respectable hobbies.
Got to be something cooler
to do in...
"Dead Owl Creek"?
Get out of here.
BRODY:
Greg.
Come take
a look at this.
The prints from
the dashboard come back
to a casino worker
named Nora Waters.
Her sister was one of Lucas
Reem's victims back in '95.
SANDERS:
So what do we think?
Nora came here?
To the place where her sister's
killer is being celebrated?
Maybe to put an end
to this whole circus.
SIDLE: Your fingerprints say
that you were in that car.
Nora, we need to know what
you were doing in there.
All right, um...
Look, I know about your family's
history with Lucas Reem.
Our history?
You mean how Lucas Reem
butchered my sister?
Sorry to bring
you back there.
Seven years old, seeing that.
Home alone with your big sister
when that man slips in
through the window,
comes creeping down the hall.
(panting)
Rachel helped me hide
in the closet.
Nora, I need you to stay
in here, okay? Do not move.
Please don't leave me,
Rachel, please.
Sorry.
(screams)
(screaming)
Stop!
(sobbing, screaming)
Lucas Reem had no idea
I was there.
Inches away while he...
hurt her.
That's something that no one
should have to go through.
I can only imagine how
angry you must have felt
about Reem's car
being auctioned off.
You think that
I killed Damon?
Damon?
Wait, you knew
the victim?
Knew him?
I loved him.
I don't understand.
Damon and I were dating
for the past year.
I heard about him online,
what he did for a living.
"Murderabilia."
I sent him
this awful e-mail,
telling him he should be ashamed
of himself, if not locked up.
And then he took me to coffee.
And he told me everything
that he'd studied
about Lucas Reem
and other serials.
The history,
the psychology.
Damon was a student,
exploring the darkest parts
of humanity.
Selling off some artifacts
helped him support his studies.
When exactly were you in the
car at the convention site?
Yesterday morning.
Damon was getting
the car ready.
I sat in it with him,
feeling its strange energy.
And I felt safe.
Because Damon was with me.
I have to ask.
Where were you last
night at midnight?
In bed.
I couldn't sleep.
The same as it's been
for the last 20 years.
Please, I just want someone to
tell me what this is all about.
Her name is
Nora Waters.
And she was told
to come down here.
I want to know
what's happening.
Excuse me. Can I help you?
Yes, my daughter,
Nora, was told to come...
I understand.
Understand.
Um, your daughter's in,
talking to a colleague of mine.
I'm D.B. Russell.
Bruce Waters.
Can you tell me
what this is all about?
Your daughter's fingerprints
were found
at the scene of a homicide.
What?
The victim's name
was a Damon Harlow.
Did you know Mr. Harlow?
Yes, yes, I know who he is.
And I know my daughter
is friends with him.
Wait, you're not thinking
she did something?
I'm sorry.
There's not much more
I can tell you
about an ongoing
investigation.
Were you here back then,
20 years ago?
Lucas Reem?
Were you one of the ones
we dealt with?
No, sir, I was not.
But I'm aware of the case
and what your family
went through.
Well, then you know why...
Nora is... fragile.
Doesn't always make
the right choices in her life.
Dating a man
like Damon Harlow,
who profits
from others' suffering.
But my wife and I...
see, Nora is all we've got.
I-I will do
whatever I've got to do
to protect her.
I'd do the same for my daughter.
Nick, Nick, we're still
a work in progress here.
That's okay.
What do you got so far?
I've counted 11 sharp-force
injuries to the chest
and abdomen; one appears
to have penetrated the heart.
So C.O.D. is
exsanguination.
Those are some
wide stab wounds.
What is that, a chef's knife?
Or a similar instrument.
Blade width is
at least two inches.
Lucas Reem himself used
a chef's knife back in the '90s.
I saw his work firsthand.
This is curious.
What is it?
It's a bone fragment.
From that busted rib?
It's too discolored to be
from a fresh break.
I suppose it could've been
floating around
from an old injury.
What do you mean?
Well, X-rays revealed
this guy
has known his share of violence.
A number
of long-healed fractures
dating back
to his adolescence.
Well, a childhood like that,
maybe trading in murder
and mayhem only makes sense.
To be honest, I think we all
have a bit of morbid curiosity.
I once took the wife and kids
to see Bonnie and Clyde's car.
We made a day out of it.
Snapped photos,
clowned around.
Bonnie and Clyde
killed 13 people.
Yeah, not so fun
when you keep that in mind, huh?
Yeah.
Okay.
I'll have Hodges take a look.
I analyzed the bone fragment
pulled from
Damon Harlow's viscera.
That bone fragment
was hand-sharpened.
It appears
to be the broken tip
of a larger piece.
So what are we saying?
That the murder weapon was
a knife made out of bone?
It's a weird choice of weaponry.
I've seen knives
made out of bones before.
You know, it's a hunter's hobby,
but they were made of,
like, elk or deer.
Hmm.
Yeah, I've seen those, too,
but this one isn't animal bone.
It's human.
What do you mean?
DNA match
to one particular awful human.
The bone came from Lucas Reem?
Dead serial killer himself.
STOKES:
So someone turned
a mass murderer
into a murder weapon.
The bone of a dead
serial killer,
sharpened into a knife
and then used
to kill again.
Yeah.
It's a whole new level
of demented.
It's kind of like the old days
when they used
the bones of dead saints
to make souvenirs
and jewelry.
The belief being that
the bones still carried
some of the saint's essence.
Yeah, but these guys,
these conventions,
they worship serial killers.
Maybe one of them
took a fragment
from Lucas Reem,
committed a crime in a way
to honor his idol.
Right.
Yeah.
I agree.
And I think
that Damon Harlow
was killed
by his own merchandise.
I found this article
from a couple days ago.
The same arrangement
of the stuff
that he had on the table
from the convention today,
but with one additional item,
now missing.
STOKES:
Bone-bladed knife.
Killer must have swiped it
right off of Harlow's table.
I also spoke
to Harlow's
business associate,
Alex Friel;
he said he knew that Damon
had been dipping
into shadier collectibles,
like the bones
of serial killers,
but he just looked
the other way.
Shady business
brings shady people.
Maybe Harlow was doing
some after-hours deal
with somebody, and the sale
just went sideways.
And Harlow paid with his life.
So if the killer swiped
the knife
off the table,
maybe he left something behind.
That's a good idea.
Let's check the tablecloth
for touch DNA.
I was also thinking,
since Harlow was dealing
in illicit goods,
it might make sense
to learn about the product.
The knife. You know,
it might bring us closer
to some of
his shadier associates.
Because one of them
might be our killer.
Well, based on
the cortical bone width
of the fragment,
the bone used to make
the blade came from
Lucas Reem's tibia.
But now listen.
The prison doctor did say that
Reem wasn't missing any bones
at the time of his execution.
So the tibia had to be removed
from him after death
to make the knife.
Exactly.
Question is:
where was Lucas Reem's tibia
and the rest of him
after his execution?
RUSSELL: It's my understanding,
Mr. Narvick,
that several months ago,
the state sent the body
of Lucas Reem to your mortuary.
Is that correct?
After his execution?
That's correct.
Mr. Reem didn't have any family.
The body was to be cremated.
It wasn't, right?
I mean, 'cause part of it just
showed up at a murder scene.
Want to tell me
how that might have happened?
The body, Lucas Reem,
was stolen.
It was on my
prep table.
I had the door
open to let
the night air freshen
my work space.
I went to take a phone call.
When I returned, he was gone.
Did you report that
to the police?
No, I did not.
Oh.
I knew what
wretched things
that man Reem had done,
and I thought the families
deserved to believe
he'd been turned to ash,
after all they'd been through.
I bet you also didn't want
your-your business to suffer
from the reports
of your negligence.
I volunteered my services
free of charge,
and it should end up
costing me customers?
Okay, you didn't happen
to get a look
at whoever might have
taken the body?
Maybe their car,
something, anything?
I do have something.
I found a liquor bottle
outside the back door.
Maybe the shot of courage
the thief needed.
I kept it because I did intend
to call the police.
Do you still have that bottle?
♪ ♪
Got your message. What's up?
The print
on the bourbon bottle
is a match to a local
named Todd Spanna.
This is his Web site.
"The man who brought down
Lucas Reem."
Well, that line may work
at a last call hookup,
but I'm afraid the truth
is not quite so heroic.
You know this guy?
I do.
He's all over
the case files.
Todd Spanna had
an apartment
across from Lucas Reem.
One night, he sees
Reem hosing blood
off his hands, so he calls
the cops, turns him in,
ends Lucas Reem's run.
Well, it looks like he's turned
that into a little celebrity
for himself.
Did a couple of talk shows.
I think he even wrote a book?
Yes, he did.
He will sign it
for $49.95.
There you go.
Yeah, looks like Spanna
is really milking
his connection
to the Reem case.
He likes to show up at
Murderabilia conventions
and sells a lot
of Reem souvenirs.
Well, it was his bourbon
bottle at the scene
of the mortuary theft.
You think Spanna went after
the ultimate souvenir?
Lucas Reem himself.
Yeah, I figure you guys
are rapping
with everyone
who knew Damon Harlow, huh?
Yeah, I heard about the murder.
If you're looking
for some pro bono help,
I can...
Todd.
We have evidence connecting you
to the theft of a body.
(chuckles)
No.
Lucas Reem's body.
Went missing from the mortuary
a few months ago.
A piece of it turned up in the
knife that killed Damon Harlow.
Oh, h-hang on.
You think that I shivved
Damon Harlow?
I think stealing
a serial killer's corpse
warrants a few questions.
No, I didn't do that either.
Your liquor bottle
at the scene
of the body theft.
Anybody could've put that there.
Todd,
why would anyone go
to all that trouble
just to frame you?
Do you know who I am to the
people who worship Lucas Reem?
I am the antichrist, all right?
I'm the one that put him away.
I am the schmuck bunter
who ruined
their hero's no-hitter
in the bottom of the ninth.
And there are plenty
of bottles in my wake.
Anyone could've
snagged one to frame me.
People who worship Lucas Reem.
Do you know any of them?
A few.
But none crazy enough
to steal his body.
I mean, come on, I do
the legit conventions.
(chuckles)
Ganking a corpse,
man, that-that's
Blood Market stuff.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Blood Market?
Yeah.
Yeah, all the merch
at the convention, right?
Autographs, photos,
the car, that's legal.
But that's only half the stuff
that's out there.
You want the truly forbidden?
Want a snuff film?
Hmm? Hot evidence?
Serial killer's remains?
You shop the Blood Market.
And what sleazy strip mall
would I find all this in?
Well, strictly online.
Anonymous.
But... but I could get you in.
Give you my username
and password.
♪ ♪
How you doing with this
Blood Market Web site?
I could use a shower after
looking at some of this stuff.
So it turns out
that the murder weapon
is not the only knife made
from Lucas Reem's bones.
Rumored to be eight of them
out there.
Any idea who has them?
No, but there
is a user
who is trying
to track them down.
He goes by the name
of DesertSky60,
and he has spent the last month
asking about those knives.
I ran his username
through a search engine,
to see if it would pop up
on any other site,
and I found
this profile.
"DesertSky60"
is Bruce Waters.
Wow, Bruce Waters.
That guy is chasing the relics
of the man
who killed his daughter.
Yeah, maybe hunting them down
so that he can destroy them
once and for all?
Maybe.
This is even more
interesting.
During his
last exchange,
another user
was telling him,
"There's a middleman
named Damon.
He can hook you up
with whatever you want."
Damon Harlow.
Mm-hmm.
Then Waters replied,
"I know Damon.
"Family connection.
I'll see
what he can do."
That was one day
before Damon Harlow was killed.
Bruce Waters didn't mention
any of this when I met with him.
So maybe he wasn't just going
after the Lucas Reem knives,
but the people selling them.
He did say that
Damon Harlow was profiting
from the suffering of others.
DNA came back
on the tablecloth
that the knife
was snatched from.
There was only one
identifiable contributor.
A male familial match
to Nora Waters.
It was her father.
Bruce Waters picks up
the knife,
then he makes
Damon Harlow suffer.
STOKES: Bruce Waters' wife said
he drove off after lunch,
and she hadn't heard
from him since.
We've got a BOLO
out on his vehicle,
we've tracked
his credit cards,
but he could be three
states away by now.
No, I met the guy
this morning at PD.
Looked me right in the eye
and then shook my hand.
Less than 12 hours
after Damon Harlow was killed.
Well, that takes some
brass, doesn't it?
Walk into a
police station
with that fresh kill
all over your hands.
He was adamant
about protecting his daughter.
Maybe he was trying
to make sure
that she didn't take
the fall for his crime.
And as soon as he saw that
she was released, then he fled.
Let's bring
his daughter back in.
I told you,
I don't know where he is.
(sighs)
Nora, your father was
hunting Lucas Reem's remains.
That hunt led him to Damon,
and I think it made him snap,
knowing that his surviving
daughter was dating a man
who kept relics
of Lucas Reem.
We have evidence of him there
at the convention site.
We believe that he killed Damon.
That's not what happened.
Then tell me what happened.
My dad came to me
a few days ago.
He had tears in his eyes.
He told me what
he'd heard.
Pieces of Lucas Reem
out there for sale.
He asked if Damon could
help track them down.
Here's the deal-- I
told him I got a buyer.
It's 20 grand, cash.
Dad, you can't afford that.
I'll figure it out.
They're gonna bring
the items to the lot
behind the Palermo,
8:00 tomorrow night.
That's all I can do.
You're on your own.
Let's go.
Wait, are you saying that that
deal was gonna happen tonight?
A few hours ago, yeah.
Why didn't you tell me
all this before?
Because Dad was hell-bent
on getting those relics
and destroying them.
This might have been
his only chance.
I didn't want anyone
getting in Dad's way.
Deal was supposed to go down
somewhere in this lot.
Whatever Bruce Waters
might have done,
he's a desperate dad.
It's hard not to feel
sorry for him.
He probably thought
he was just
doing right by his family.
Nick, there's
some blood over here.
STOKES:
Oh, Bruce.
What'd you go
and get yourself into, man?
No, no, he's gone.
Charlie 0-4 Stokes.
We've got a 419.
Roll homicide and a coroner
to my location.
I got a Beretta.
Magazine doesn't have a single
scratch from loading.
I don't think there's ever been
a bullet in this gun.
Whoever brought this had
no intention of using it.
You know what I think? I think
he never had the 20 grand
to buy those bone-bladed knives,
and he brought that gun out here
to do some negotiating.
They called his bluff.
He underestimated
who he was bargaining with.
And it looks like...
he was stabbed
at least ten times.
And there's some
silver-colored trace here.
Nick, there's something
in his mouth.
What the hell is that?
SIDLE: The odd object
from the victim's mouth
was actually a strand
of black suede,
like from a fringed
suede jacket.
Bruce Waters must have
bit it off his assailant
while tangled up with him.
And Bruce Waters' assailant
was wearing
the exact jacket that Lucas
Reem is wearing in this photo.
Got all that from
one strand of suede?
Henry ran DNA on the strand,
found a contribution
from Lucas Reem himself.
You mean to tell me now
there's somebody out there
that's not only collecting
Lucas Reem's bones,
but now wearing his jacket?
Kind of feels like
someone's trying
to bring him back to life.
Yeah.
You know what,
there were...
Right here.
I remember, there were
odd blood patterns
at Damon Harlow's
crime scene.
Take a look at that.
Fringe from a jacket could have
caused that pattern.
It looks like
the same killer
that killed Damon Harlow
killed Bruce Waters.
Good bet.
All right, so how do we think
it all played out?
Well, Damon Harlow agreed to
help Bruce find the bone knives,
set him up
with a seller.
Hours later,
Harlow is killed.
The next night, Bruce Waters
goes to meet the seller,
and Bruce is killed.
Maybe the seller knew
he was being set up.
Knew that Bruce
Waters was the buyer
and that Bruce's
only reason
to want those relics
was to destroy them.
Seller wasn't happy
about being played,
so he kills Harlow
for the betrayal,
and he takes Bruce out
at the buy-site.
So who out there is wearing
that jacket and two murders?
Mmm.
That jacket would be
a primo item.
But I don't know who has it.
But you know who might know,
am I right?
Mm.
Oh, come on, Todd,
give me that much.
Maybe.
So how do I meet
some of these Blood Market
traders face-to-face?
No, these cats do
not talk to cops.
Well, I won't go as a cop.
I'll go as, uh, a collector.
(laughs)
You can laugh all you want,
but the title of your memoir
was Cracking the Case.
Don't let me down here, man.
Okay.
Some of the Blood Market guys
did come down to the convention.
And I might have
overheard them talking
about a place that
they'd be partying.
Good.
Showing off their
collections.
Where?
(laughs) Look,
they are never gonna
let a random like you in.
Well, what if...
I bring something
very special to their party?
Like what?
Something that will
blow their minds.
Who are you?
I'm a collector.
Up from Albuquerque.
Brought something
for the show-and-tell.
Whoa.
Piece like that?
You better make sure
and show Gunnar
before anyone
else gets a look.
Upstairs.
Back of the room.
♪ ♪
Here, man,
check this out.
It's original.
You must be Gunnar.
Guy at the front door said
you might like this.
It's from
the Miniature Killer.
You're familiar
with her, right?
What are you hunting?
Originally, I came in town
looking for Lucas Reem items.
I was gonna pick up
his car,
but obviously that sale's
been eighty-sixed.
If you know of anyone
dealing in Lucas Reem...
Heard about some
bone-bladed knives?
Jacob.
Might be some
business here.
Haven't seen you around.
I'm not from here, Jacob.
That is one
heck of a jacket, man.
I've been looking for one
just like that, Jacob.
Well, it's not for sale.
Oh, well, that's a pity.
You know,
you got that one vein,
in your neck,
just working overtime,
pumping away.
Kind of makes
me feel like
you're not on the level.
I think maybe you should
get that knife out of my face.
What are you gonna do about it?
LVPD!
Everybody against the wall! Now!
Everybody get down!
Don't move!
Sit down!
Now who's the one
who ain't on the level, huh?
(grunts)
♪ ♪
Jacob Warren.
You are really obsessed
with Lucas Reem, aren't you?
So tell me what you did.
You put on his jacket,
you adorned yourself
with all his relics,
and then you murdered two people
as tribute.
You have no idea what it's like.
All the bad mojo
in those objects,
rippling through your body.
So you admit it?
You killed Damon Harlow
and Bruce Waters.
That is the work of Lucas Reem.
Right.
His spirit, reincarnated
in you.
Kindred souls find each other.
(phone chimes)
So tell me, Jacob,
when you and
the spirit of Lucas Reem
went to that lot to
kill Bruce Waters,
where'd you park?
Why do you want to know that?
Because the lab just told me
that the jacket
you were wearing is a fake.
So that makes me think
that maybe you are, too.
You're just a wannabe
and you're here wasting my time.
All right, maybe I wasn't there
for the murder.
Just heard about it
while I was clocked in at work.
I mean,
it sounded like
a kill that Lucas Reem
himself would do.
So, uh...
sue me for having a little fun.
Well, you just earned yourself
an obstruction charge.
Be fun to see how
the other inmates like your act.
Cuff him.
Hey.
Hi.
Henry finished
processing the knives
that we got
from Jacob Warren.
No trace of blood
on them, and DNA says
that they were not made
from Lucas Reem's bones.
Well, that's not
surprising.
Warren's a
deluded wannabe.
So is that a dead end?
Well, not exactly.
One of those knives he had was
made out of real human bone--
the bone of a different
serial killer.
His name was
Gerald Palmer.
Executed in Ohio
15 years ago.
What's this have
to do with that?
Well, the article says that
a certain Cleveland mortician
handled Palmer's body
after execution.
Roy Narvick.
Moved his mortuary business
out here
a few years later.
Okay, so this guy lied to me
about Reem's body being stolen.
Kept it for himself, obviously.
It sounds like he's been
collecting for years.
Arranging to handle
killers' corpses.
Turning them into souvenirs.
Maybe... he's killing
to protect his collection.
"Every man has to have a hobby."
You know who said that?
Ed Gein--
the real-life Norman Bates.
Decorated his home
with human skin.
How'd I do?
You clearly share
my fascination.
You might justify it as
professional research,
but you enjoy it.
Studying those black
swans that occasionally
emerge from the
mundane masses.
You understand
the mystique of men
like Lucas Reem.
No, men like Lucas Reem
should be erased.
Not enshrined.
Not emulated.
My hobby,
the crafting of those relics,
sanding harvested bone
into blade,
is only a misdemeanor, you know.
"Dissection of
a Dead Body,"
as per Nevada
Revised Statute 451.
A hefty fine,
but worth the price.
We're not here
to talk about that.
We're here to talk
about two homicides:
Bruce Waters
and Damon Harlow.
Right now, my CSIs
are going through your residence
and your business.
And you may think
you have every detail tidied up,
but I promise you,
my guys are gonna
find something.
Mr. Russell, I've drawn a lot
of blood in my life,
but not from the living.
I keep careful account of
my time, and I can tell you
my exact whereabouts
at the grisly moments
in question.
However,
if someone out there
purchased one of the
relics that I sold
and used it
for nefarious purpose...
A proper hobbyist
will always be open to a trade.
Meaning what?
In exchange
for forgiveness
of my misdemeanors...
you get my customer list.
Well, the mortician's
alibis checked out.
Does the customer list
he gave us seem legit?
Just started going through it.
The descriptions, the prices,
the shipping addresses for
some of the items he sold.
This one stands out.
"Knife made from Lucas Reem bone
with a silver-painted handle."
Like the trace found
in Bruce Waters' wound.
That could be the weapon
that killed him.
Who bought it?
Same person who bought
all the Lucas Reem knives
on this list.
No-name P.O. box
in a podunk town.
"Dead Owl Creek."
Could be a-a rental mailbox.
I mean, it looks like
the buyer has gone
out of his way
to remain anonymous.
Except I already met him.
He's one of the guys
who ducked under the tape
at the crime scene.
Got to be something
cooler to do in
"Dead Owl Creek"?
SANDERS:
You think he'd approve?
Of everything you've done?
You were doing it
for him, right?
Protecting his legacy?
We searched your car, Kyle.
We found the bone knives.
The jacket.
You kept them
all together.
Wasn't that the point?
Collecting all those relics,
making sure
that the last traces
of Lucas Reem
were never lost,
never destroyed?
Lucas will live forever.
You see, that dealer
and that pathetic father,
they thought
they were smarter than me.
Thought that they could
take him away from me.
So you took
two lives
over a batch of decaying bones.
(grunting)
The thing
I want to know is:
why did you come back here,
to see Damon Harlow's body
in that car?
Felt like I had dreamt it.
Wanted to make sure
that I hadn't.
But it wasn't
just in my head.
You know? It was...
It was real.
What Lucas and I have,
that's real.
He will be with me forever.
Well, you're one needle away
from making that dream
come true.
(handcuffs clicking)
Nora...
I just wanted
you to know
that we caught the man
who killed your father.
And Damon.
He's being taken into
custody right now.
So he's going away for good.
He took both of them from me,
but he can't hurt anyone else.
That's right.
That's the same thing
my dad used to tell me
when I was a kid,
about Lucas Reem,
when I would cry out
in the middle of the night
from a nightmare--
"Don't worry.
That man's going away.
He can't hurt anyone else."
But...
(sniffles)
I guess he never
really believed that.
20 years later, Lucas Reem
was still hurting him,
still haunting him.
You know...
I think that
your father,
by chasing after
those relics,
in his own way was just trying
to end the nightmare.
But... instead,
he just gave it new life.
His own.
(cameras clicking)