MAN:
It will come to pass!
It's just a matter of time.
You can only lie
to yourselves for so long.
We pretend that
we're not afraid.
But when it happens
and that day comes...
nothing will stop the world
from bleeding.
Nothing!
(door opens)
I spoke with
responding officers.
Landlord came by here
to pick up the rent,
saw him and turned
right around.
Tenant's name
is Jack Smith.
He lived alone.
Sounds like a
throwaway name.
Let me guess:
paid all cash, no I.D. on file.
Lifestyles of the broke
and anonymous.
This place is
covered in blood.
There's blood
on the floor.
There's more
on the wall.
It's all over
the place.
Blood void.
Got a spent
shell over here.
Nine-mil casing.
SIDLE:
GSW to his neck.
Looks like he bled out
pretty quickly.
Yeah? Then how did blood
get all over the room?
Expirated blood
on the wall here.
Possible fight
before the kill shot?
Well, if we're lucky,
maybe some of this blood
belongs to his assailant.
This whole bookshelf is about
world-ending
plagues,
biological disasters...
The wall is just plastered
with paranoia.
Uh... Greg?
Yeah?
This man was sick.
What do you mean?
I mean, don't touch anything.
I'm, uh, uh...
I'm gonna call the CDC.
His eye.
Have you ever seen
anything like that before?
SANDERS:
Yeah, in biology textbooks.
Viral epidemics.
Exactly.
SANDERS:
The pathogen could be
in all this blood.
It could be airborne.
Try not to panic.
I'm just trying not to breathe.
SIDLE:
This is CSI Sara Sidle from
the Las Vegas Crime Lab.
I'm at a crime scene with
what appears to be a possible
hemorrhagic fever.
One decedent.
Two others may
have been exposed.
♪&amp; Who... are you? ♪&amp;
♪&amp; Who, who, who, who? ♪&amp;
♪&amp; I really wanna know ♪&amp;
♪&amp; Who... are you? ♪&amp;
♪&amp; Oh-oh-oh ♪&amp;
♪&amp; Who... ♪&amp;
♪&amp; Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪&amp;
♪&amp; Are you! ♪&amp;
♪&amp; ♪&amp;
Let's go!
Get the windows sealed!
Secure the perimeter!
No entry without
Level Four coverage.
Keep it moving!
Clock is ticking!
PHILLIPS:
Hey.
Russell.
I'm so sorry.
I should've been the
first one in there.
I-I got stuck at that
suicide over on...
Relax. You were just
doing your job.
Coroner's office?
Yeah.
He'll get
you suited up
for entry to remove
the infected decedent.
Of course.
Supervisor Russell?
Yes.
Dr. Emmett,
CDC Emergency
Response Specialist.
Any idea what
we're dealing with here?
Undetermined, but the symptoms
suggest a virus.
We're treating the house
as a hot zone.
Extracting the potentially
exposed subjects.
Those "subjects"
are my CSIs.
I just spoke to them
on the phone.
They're a little concerned
about what's happening next.
They'll be suited up
and transported
to hospital quarantine.
They mention having removed
anything from inside the house?
No. No, no, no.
All their gear, their
collected evidence,
is still inside.
Good. It'll stay there.
Once the subjects are out,
we'll nuke the place.
Wait, wait, I'm sorry.
What do you mean, "nuke"?
Blast it with UV light
and formaldehyde fog,
killing any living
organism in there.
There's our
artillery now.
RUSSELL:
Well... wait a sec.
The dead man in there
was-was killed by a gunshot.
I heard.
Not his day at the tables.
What I'm saying
is there was
at least one other
person-- the shooter--
inside that room.
And he might
be infected.
So frying all the
biologicals in there
might stop us from
tracking the guy down.
A valid point.
But no match for
the holy gospel of protocol.
I'll keep you updated.
(helicopter whirring,
indistinct radio chatter)
You okay in there?
We had to leave
the evidence behind.
SANDERS:
Scene's getting
completely stepped on in there.
We uploaded our photos
to the cloud.
It might be all
we can salvage.
I'm not concerned
about that right now.
EMMETT:
Folks,
we need to
keep moving!
♪&amp; ♪&amp;
RUSSELL:
If they've been infected,
we may not know for days.
Viral incubation period
could be up to two
weeks, you know,
so they'll be tested,
observed, and... I don't know,
we just wait, I guess.
This is rough, D.B.
State's sending resources.
Area hospitals are on alert.
I mean, soon the story's
gonna hit the news,
and then everything
gets cranked up.
I've got Morgan
and Nick
going over the
crime scene photos.
On top of all this, we have a...
a murder to solve.
Yeah, right.
Gunshot in the throat
almost feels quaint,
doesn't it?
Supervisor Russell?
Yes.
Dr. Heather Lanning,
from RyneLab Biomedical.
My counterpart at the CDC
informed you I'd be here?
Yeah. This is...
Sheriff Ecklie.
Hi.
I understand the
situation's overwhelming.
I'm here to help.
RyneLab is a private
research facility
right here in Nevada.
The only Biosafety Level
Four site in the region,
equipped to handle the
deadliest organisms.
CDC brought us in to
assist on this case.
So your lab's gonna tell us
what kind of bug we're
dealing with here, right?
Because two of my team
may have been infected.
I understand.
If I can start
with a look
at the damage
inflicted...
Okay, I got this.
Why don't you
check in with
your team?
Right.
Right this way, please.
Okay.
(saw buzzing)
Surgical scissors
would be safer.
You risk puncturing your suit
with that blade
and infecting
yourself.
(saw stops buzzing)
This is Dr. Lanning
from RyneLab.
Helping with the case.
I appreciate your concern,
but believe me,
I've never cut
more carefully in my life.
ECKLIE:
So what do we have, Doc?
Well, starting with
the gunshot wound,
it's a through-and-through.
There's no sooting or stippling.
The entry wound is irregular.
It suggests a ricochet
before impact.
(saw buzzing)
I found no I.D. or
possessions in his pockets,
and there was
no print match
through Mobile AFIS.
ECKLIE:
So we're still not
even sure of his name.
A true "Patient Zero."
No way to build a profile...
who or what he may have
had contact with.
(exhales)
ROBBINS:
The lungs are soft,
hemorrhagic,
and the spleen is mushy.
Consistent with
a filovirus infection.
Like Marburg
or Ebola.
No. No, I disagree, Jules.
I don't think
you should fly back.
I mean, if this thing
turns into a real outbreak,
I think you're better off
in Seattle.
Well, how long till we have
an update on Sara and Greg?
RUSSELL:
They're still being tested,
so they couldn't take any calls.
I wish there was something
I could do to help.
I know.
You could tell me
you've found something
on our Gig Harbor twins.
I am still trying
to put together
Winthrop and Briscoe's
backgrounds.
You know, both men have lived
without leaving much of a trail.
But I'm going through
hospital records right now,
and searching
for identical twins
born to unwed Seattle mothers.
Ages that would obviously
be right for them.
You know,
I just need a birth date.
It would really help me
with foster searches.
All right. Well, it's a start.
Enough to keep fishing,
don't you think?
Mm-hmm.
Will you call me
if you hear anything?
Of course I will.
BRODY:
Hey.
So I talked to
the CDC rep.
I told him that
we need to be
in that house
as soon as possible.
I know all that
DNA evidence
is gonna be destroyed.
All we have right now are
the photos that they uploaded.
Overalls, uh,
shots of blood spatter.
I don't know what we're going
to get from these.
Just like any other case,
we need to find out
who this victim is first.
Maybe some small detail will
tell us where he's been,
who he's been
hanging out with...
Who else might
have been infected.
Yeah, exactly.
So I'm just
scanning these,
looking for an
I.D. badge,
a piece of mail...
Yeah.
Wait. What about
that book?
Seconds to Apocalypse.
Yeah, it's got a library tag
on the spine.
That might
just work.
He might have
a-an account
at the library.
It could help us
with the I.D.
Yeah.
It's worth a shot.
(phone chiming)
Yeah, there's Russell.
He's in Layout.
He's got some news.
Let's go.
Yeah.
LANNING:
Sara.
Greg.
I'm here to tell you
that RyneLab
has identified
the pathogen.
EMMETT:
It's called the Ibare virus.
A blood-borne filovirus,
not unlike Ebola
in viral structure.
It replicates
at a staggering rate,
decimating the host's cells
and causing massive hemorrhage.
SIDLE:
Are there treatments?
Antivirals?
Nothing effective.
So you know everything
about the virus
except what to do about it.
How does this virus end up here?
CDC is baffled.
The only prior outbreaks
were in rural South
American villages.
Vegas is a global city.
People come here from places
all over the world.
Right.
And head back to those places,
if you want to play
a nightmare scenario.
All it takes is one
infected carrier.
Sneezes in line
at the airport.
Infecting half a dozen more.
By the time the wheels are up,
the pathogen's on planes
to four continents.
That's just getting started.
Ibare has a rapid incubation
period: within 48 hours.
If you experience a fever,
muscle soreness...
The fatality rate.
80 percent.
80 percent?
Yes.
Thank you, Doctor.
Appreciate that.
There's nothing we can do
about Greg or Sara right now
except just...
just wait.
So let's-let's
focus on the case.
Somebody else walked out
of that bloody room.
Yeah, the killer.
Who could be anywhere
in the city now
just spreading the infection.
STOKES: Quicker we
determine who that is
and where they are...
Better chance we have
at stopping this outbreak.
All right.
SIDLE:
Don't let your mind go there.
That did not happen.
We were careful.
We always are,
working with blood.
I know.
We had a scare
like this before.
Yeah, the dead jock with the
killer mold in his wall.
A quick shared shower
in the middle of the street,
and we were fine, right?
This might not be that easy.
We're going to be fine.
(computer beeping)
Hello, Nick?
Hey! How are my two
favorite people doing?
Happy for the distraction.
Yeah, I heard they hooked you
guys up with some computers.
Is that right?
Yeah. How's the
case going?
Well, we just caught
a break on the victim's I.D.
Got it off of a library book
from the photos
you guys uploaded.
Registered to a guy
named Jack Weaver.
And listen.
This is not this guy's
first encounter
with a microscopic killer,
if you know what I mean.
SIDLE:
"Hunting Viruses.
"Dr. Jack Weaver
travels the world
stalking the planet's
deadliest organisms."
Yeah, now, that article
is from about eight years ago.
That's right around the time
his trail starts to fade.
There's no employment records,
no Internet presence, nothing.
So, what happened to him?
I'm not sure about that,
but I do know somebody
that has the answer.
Should have told us already.
That is Heather Lanning.
Uh, she's an old coworker
of Weaver's.
They used to do some research
together over at RyneLab.
And listen, she was in autopsy,
she saw the body
and never mentioned once
that she knew the guy.
MAN:
As counsel for RyneLab,
I want to be clear
that Miss Lanning is here
in the spirit of cooperation
to aid in the investigation.
Where was that spirit when you
neglected to identify
Jack Weaver's body?
I didn't realize...
Ma'am, you worked
with him for years.
No, RyneLab employs
over 500 individuals
along with countless
affiliated...
That face is...
a ghost...
of the man I knew.
So you knew him.
Thank you.
Why don't you tell me about him.
Jack was brilliant.
He made breakthroughs
in viral research
that we're still wrapping
our heads around.
But the fieldwork...
RyneLab's global
outreach sends
researchers around the world
to sites of epidemics...
Weeks spent slogging, neck-deep,
in disease.
Watching mothers fight
for a last embrace
of their dying child.
Those trips took a toll on Jack.
Even when we were back
safe in the lab,
he wasn't the same.
Eventually, he had to be let go.
It was a tragedy...
which...
...apparently continued.
A virus hunter
becomes the virus-hunted,
years after the job
is left behind.
So how did his old prey
catch up with him?
Ibare has never been
discovered in the U.S.
Weaver's passport records
don't show any recent
international travel.
The only specimens
of the virus within
a thousand miles
were the ones in
RyneLab's freezers.
All of which have been
inventoried and accounted for.
None went missing.
Wait a minute.
You're saying that this company
keeps a stockpile of this virus
here in Nevada?
That's exactly what I'm saying.
With the Defense Department's
blessing, of course,
and generous funding.
Why?
Military can't use biological
weapons like that.
Exactly.
Which is why the program goes
under the heading "Bio-Defense."
See, this company cultivates
and studies these organisms
to prepare for the
awfulpossibility
that one day they may
wind up on U.S. soil.
BRODY:
Hey.
Police records popped
something on Jack Weaver.
Field investigation card
from last week.
Officer responded to a street
where Weaver was drunk
and prophesizing
about a plague.
Plague!
The world is bleeding!
(siren whoops)
Cop just told him to move on.
And a week later his prophecy
came true, at least for him.
Well, let's not forget,
now, he was shot.
I can't help but believe
that this shooting
and the infection are
related in some way.
What are you thinking?
Weaver was broke and bitter,
but he still knew a lot
about deadly pathogens.
May have even had access to
one of those connections.
Maybe making him the perfect
wingman for a bioterrorist.
Exactly.
Yeah, but the only terror so far
happened to Weaver himself.
So, something goes
awry with the plan.
Second thoughts.
Sloppy execution.
Weaver ends up infected.
Coconspirator shoots
him to silence him.
And that same person makes
off with the viral ammo.
I saw something in the photos.
I wasn't sure what it was.
I think I do now.
Here.
The void in the blood.
It's rectangular.
It's got round corners.
Could very easily
be a briefcase.
BRODY: The kind you might use
to transport a deadly pathogen.
Conrad, we need to get
in that house ASAP.
No.
CDC is saying
it's not safe yet.
Yeah, but it's safer
than leaving a killer
and a deadly virus
on the street.
Well, you put it that way...
(phone beeping)
I'll get you in there.
BRODY:
The UV light and formaldehyde
nuked all biologicals,
so there's no DNA.
And no virus.
STOKES:
Everything's just
how they left it.
Lead would still survive.
Gunshot was a
through-and-through, right?
Yeah. So there should
still be a bullet here.
Okay. Let's go to work.
Body was right here.
Robbins' report said that
the bullet was ricocheted
into the vic, right?
Right.
Well, there's a...
there's a bullet skip mark
here on the floor.
Impacted at a low angle.
For Weaver to get shot
in the neck means...
he must have been
laying down.
Yeah.
STOKES: Which means the bullet
would have to stay low.
Oh... Morgan.
I think I've
got something.
I just found the bullet.
BRODY: Greg marked the case
right here by the door.
Killer would have needed
some distance to account for
the low-angle bullet skip, so...
Shooter stands here...
Fires at Weaver, who's prone,
sick on the ground.
Takes off with the briefcase.
And whatever lurks inside of it.
That works.
Clock is ticking, Sara.
It's your move.
What if it is starting?
An epidemic.
What if yesterday
was the last normal day?
What happened to the optimist
who used to share this fishbowl?
I'm just thinking.
You know how quickly
everything could change.
You have a headache or a fever.
You think it's just
a day off of work.
Instead...
You're booking a
trip to Costa Rica.
'Cause when we're
cleared from here,
something good's
gonna happen.
Motivation for a vacation.
Is that really what it takes?
Something like this?
To do the things
you've been putting off.
I'll take reminders
where we can get them.
Hmm. Booking your own
tropical vacation?
Not exactly.
WOMAN:
Greg?
Hi, Grandma.
How have you been?
Good.
So nice of you
to check in on me.
How are you?
I, uh...
It's been an interesting day.
Looks sunny there.
It's been nice all morning.
The garden looks great.
Yeah? Well, that's actually
why I was calling.
Thinking about coming up there
to see you and
check it out.
Oh, Greg, I would love that.
Me, too.
RUSSELL:
Heard you found a match
on the bullet
that killed Weaver.
Yep. A recovered round
from a gas station holdup
six months ago.
Case wasn't solved, but we did
have a very strong suspect.
Northtown nuisance
Shawn Steubens.
Priors for weapons
violations,
robbery.
Doesn't look like
a bioterrorist.
Agreed.
Let's get him to prove us wrong.
Shawn Steubens.
LVPD.
Open up.
Shawn!
It's very important
that we talk to you!
(faint groaning from inside)
STOKES:
This guy's infected.
Tell me that's the cure.
It's for your pain.
And then what?
You want to tell me
what happened?
Shawn, what's
happening to you
may be happening
to other people.
It may be
happening to...
...two friends of mine
that I care about very much.
Shawn...
I'm begging you, man.
Help us out here.
Driving around
the other night, late...
...saw someone go
into that house,
wearing a big rubber suit
like the guys
who brought me here.
A Hazmat suit?
Going in Jack Weaver's house?
Yeah.
That suit,
that part of town, I...
figured they had
a meth cook going on inside.
Then what'd you do, Shawn?
Grabbed my nine-mil.
Went in to rip the place off.
Saw what was really inside.
Briefcase looked important.
So I grabbed it.
I figured maybe it
was stuffed with cash.
Then that suit
was coming at me.
I panicked.
Shooting that guy
was an accident. I swear.
You didn't get
a good look...
at who was in that
Hazmat suit, did you?
No face, no eyes.
And the briefcase,
what happened to that?
It's at my house.
Spent a little while
trying to bust it open.
Kind of lost interest
in the briefcase when, you know,
my eyes started bleeding.
Well, I'm...
I'm gonna leave you to it.
Amateur video from the
scene shows CDC vehicles
and personnel at the
North Las Vegas residence.
Officials have not released
details of what drew
this emergency response,
but sources report that...
The story's still under wraps.
At least nobody's panicking.
Additionally, it's reported
that two veteran Crime Scene
Investigators were...
Did she just call
us "veteran"?
'Cause now I might panic.
I can turn this off
if it's bugging you.
No. No, no,
it's fine.
...spokesperson isn't releasing
any information
on their condition at this time.
Desert Palm and other
local hospitals
declined to comment
when asked if they
had recently...
Sara? Are you...?
Sara! Sara!
We need a doctor!
Sara!
Somebody!
Somebody, please help!
Sara! Sara!
(muffled):
Sara!
SANDERS:
Hey, Russell.
RUSSELL:
Hi.
They said that you have a...
100.4... fever.
But her viral antibody tests
are still negative,
so it could just be a common bug
or the stress of all this or...
I'm so sorry.
They wouldn't let me
come any sooner.
We know.
Russell, I need you
to do something for me.
Yeah, of course.
Anything.
If we're gonna die,
we need to go out
fighting, okay?
So, put us to work.
Neither one of you have
my permission to die.
You got that?
All right. Uh...
Morgan recovered the
stolen briefcase.
The only thing in it was
Jack Weaver's computer.
She'll upload
his hard drive.
She'll get it to you guys.
Yeah, we'll start digging.
♪&amp; ♪&amp;
RUSSELL:
So, you found anything
interesting yet?
Well, Jack Weaver was
obsessed with the Ibare virus
long before he was
infected with it.
His Web histories,
cached articles,
all dwell on that
particular pathogen.
SIDLE:
Especially one
outbreak of it
in 2006.
The disease tore
through a village
in Bolivia
called Campiza.
We know why this
was Jack's focus?
He did witness
the carnage firsthand.
He and Heather Lanning
were sent to the village
to study the outbreak
and help with the infected.
Yeah, but Weaver did fieldwork
at a lot of those outbreaks
which is why he burned out,
according to Lanning.
Wha-What makes that
one different?
Yeah, we're not sure yet,
though, speaking of Lanning,
Weaver had been e-mailing
with her right up to a week ago.
She told me that she hadn't
spoken to him for years.
Weaver was sending
her ramblingmessages
saying that they had
to talk about Bolivia.
Lanning shut him down.
"Jack, you're a troubled man.
You need help.
You need to move on."
That was five days
before we found him dead.
RUSSELL:
Okay, now,
Lanning said
she didn't recognize
Weaver's body,
and I let that slide.
But obviously she's
hiding something.
MAN:
Mr. Russell?
Yeah.
My name is Rudy Adela.
We met earlier.
Yeah, you're the attorney
for RyneLab, right?
I was informed by our
research tech at RyneLab
of a missing agent.
A vial of the Ibare virus.
You got something there?
I, uh, asked
Dr. Lanning about it.
(click, beep)
LANNING:
Rudy, the loss cannot
be reported.
ADELA:
We can't just ignore it.
LANNING:
You don't say a word to anyone.
How much was in that vial?
It's ten cc's.
20 million
virion particles.
And each one
a potential death sentence.
Your company lost a potential
weapon of mass destruction,
and then you covered it up,
at the very least.
What are you
accusing me of?
I'm here without an attorney.
Doesn't that tell you
something about my...
Tells me something about your
attorney's conscience, actually.
Now, contrary
to what you told us,
you were in contact
with Jack Weaver.
These are the e-mails.
He wanted to talk
to you about Bolivia.
I told you he wasn't stable.
He needed help.
Ms. Lanning, we're
working with the CDC now,
under a federal order.
As we speak, we're tearing
apart your offices.
Every file,
every hard drive.
And we just got this in
from your building
surveillance.
That's you walking
Jack Weaver
into the facility,
after hours,
a week before he died.
I thought bringing
him there, talking,
might remind him of all
the good work he did.
No, that's not true.
Once again,
these are the e-mails.
He demanded
to meet you there.
And because you
went along with it,
I'm guessing he had
some sort of leverage.
He had my pity.
I was trying to help him.
Ms. Lanning, a man who's
obsessed with the Ibare virus
visits the lab.
A vial of that virus
goes missing.
And that same pathogen
kills him within days.
You think he...
No.
I didn't let him near anywhere
near the specimen storage.
So, he was never out of your
sight, even for a moment?
Maybe for... two minutes.
He went to use the
men's room, but...
Uh-huh, yeah.
That man had worked
in that building for years.
He knew how to
access the specimens.
He could have gotten in
and out of there in two minutes.
And you know it.
Here's what I think.
I believe that you
realized your mistake,
so you went to his home.
You wanted to keep
track of Jack
and the missing vial.
Kind of damage control.
No! That's not...
By the time
you got there,
Jack Weaver had already
infected himself.
And what?
I just let him die?
That's what I think, yeah.
I think you realized
that if your mistake came out
that your labs
would be shut down.
So you watched him
crash and bleed out.
And then you were gonna
dispose of his body,
but someone came along
and ruined your plan.
So you panicked...
and you left behind
the body and the blood
for my CSIs to walk into.
I'm done talking about it.
I want an attorney.
Good idea.
Russell spins
a hell of a theory,
but we still don't know
why Weaver took the vial
or how he ended
up infected.
I think infecting
himself with that virus
was the whole point.
Conrad, he knew the dangers.
This was no accident.
What do you mean?
I'm saying that Weaver knew
something about RyneLab,
something major.
What?
I don't know yet,
but he hints about it
in his e-mails.
I think exposing
himself to this virus
was his way of exposing
that whole company.
All right, so he
got our attention.
What did he want
us to know?
Morgan and I are going
over the files right now,
but my gut tells me
'06 Bolivian outbreak
seems to have been
his obsession.
Well, let's make it
our obsession-- and quickly.
RyneLab's got
a lot of juice in DC.
Our investigation could
get shut down any minute.
I'm on it.
STOKES:
Hey.
Reports all tell
the same tale.
Lanning and Weaver arrived
at the Bolivian village two days
after the first
infections were reported,
identified
the pathogen as Ibare.
Yeah, they treated and contained
the sick in a field hospital.
20 infected, 17 dead.
Then the virus just
ran its course.
Her field reports, her journals,
they're all consistent.
So, what are we missing?
What is it?
It was collected from
Lanning's desk at RyneLab.
What is that?
It's from Bolivia,
to Heather's home address here.
Postmarked...
around the end
of the outbreak.
It's a letter
from Heather to herself.
Why would somebody do
something like that?
Because she couldn't
tell anybody else.
Read it.
"Let the reports
and lab records tally
"the dead and the lucky.
"But for my own sanity,
I need to put down what I saw.
"To remember that it happened.
So that it never happens again."
It's not our call, Jack.
The directive
for RyneLab was clear.
Yeah. Lie to them.
Tell these people
their family members
aren't dying in there.
We don't have the manpower
to deal with a panic.
We need to maintain
the quarantine.
MAN:
What is happening in there?
(villagers speaking Spanish)
You tell us nothing.
It's a fever.
It's just a fever.
They're gonna be fine.
Fever?
(translating in Spanish)
Then we will care
for them at home.
No. You can't go in.
We need to treat
them here.
(speaking Spanish)
Stop!
Please... don't
touch them! Wait.
BRODY:
"The official reports
"will simply show
"a spike of 15 new infections,
"12 of them fatal.
"But Jack and I
know the truth
"about the numbers.
And we will have
to live with it."
Well, it sounds like
she figured out
how to live with it,
but he didn't.
Well, suicide
wasn't enough.
It's too easy.
No, he infected himself
because he wanted
to empathize with
these victims.
To feel the pain
his lie caused.
We have to prove it.
We have to prove
that he stole the virus
from RyneLab's facility.
Any luck?
One tiny partial print--
it won't be any help,
except to tell us that...
somebody opened this container
without wearing gloves.
Well, the swabs I took
didn't find any touch DNA.
No useable prints, no DNA.
There is something
else to try.
Morgan, what's unique
about this room?
Freezers full of
exotic death.
Aside from those
contained organisms,
there's no life in here, but
the room's kept spotless.
Every person who
enters, per protocol,
is wrapped in rubber.
Except for one person
who broke protocol.
You're thinking
microbial forensics.
You're familiar
with the process?
I-I've read a little bit
about it, but...
This is theperfect
chance to try it.
The only microbes
living on that surface
would have been contributed
by that single ungloved person.
Every person has a a unique mix
of organisms on their skin.
Some they're born with,
some they accumulate.
The combination is as singular
as a fingerprint or DNA.
Other scenes, there are
far too many microbes
on every single surface
to ever distinguish
between contributors,
but here...
There's only one contributor:
whoever stole the virus.
I'll call Russell...
see if we can commandeer
RyneLab's equipment,
do a microbial analysis.
♪&amp; ♪&amp;
So, I cultured
the microbial population
from the swab...
I spread it over various agars,
each formulated
to breed
particular organisms
if they're present.
Each positive I.D.
we get of a species
gets us one step closer
to a microbial profile.
And our suspect.
Yeah.
(phone chimes)
Hey, Nick. What's up?
I was going over the
Bolivia files with Russell,
you know, explaining everything.
Yeah?
We noticed something
in one of the photos
of the village.
What?
Prepare to have
your stomach drop.
Eight years ago...
half a world away...
(sighs)
...but...
that's you.
I haven't seen this photo.
But I remember everything.
Your family
were among those
who were infected
in the village, right?
Both of my parents...
my sister...
all killed.
I was, um...
theluckyone.
Can't be a coincidence
that you're working
for RyneLab now.
Same organization
that handled the outbreak
all those years ago.
The company looked out for us.
The kids left behind.
Oh, I heard that.
I heard that they...
they sent you to school
in La Paz, right?
They...
paid for your college?
I wanted to work for them.
Help study monsters
like Ibare.
Turns out I didn't have
a mind for science,
but a law degree
got me in the door.
Rudy...
we know you found out
what happened in your village.
I mean, the real story.
We took your fingerprints off
of Heather Lanning's letter,
which you found
hidden in her office.
I heard rumors back then
that RyneLab had caused
the deaths, so...
I used my access
to get answers.
And when you got your answers
and you found out that
Jack Weaver was responsible,
you wanted revenge.
I understand.
Okay. Rudy...
my CSIs have developed
a microbial profile
of the hand that... that opened
the refrigeration unit
and stole the vial
of Ibare.
A zoo of different organisms
all living in harmony
on a... on a fingertip.
And that same unique
combination of life
was found on this--
your recorder.
You stole the vial, Rudy.
And you infected Jack Weaver.
My entire family.
They didn't deserve it.
He did.
(gasps, grunts)
I stayed there.
I watched him suffer.
Then I watched the
company lie to you.
Distance themselves.
Cover up.
Just like they did
allthose years ago.
Which is why
you recorded Dr. Lanning.
You wanted to bring down
the whole company,
so they couldn't toy
with any more viruses,
breed any more monsters.
I...
would be the last.
Sara?
Are you...?
I'm fine.
Dr. Emmett said that
I could tell you the news.
No sign of infection,
and tests are showing
that the virus dies
within two hours
of exposure to air.
Weaver's house wouldn't have
been infectious when we entered.
No.
CDC's gonna keep
an area watch,
but there haven't been
any other infections.
We're clear.
(sighs)
We're free to go.
(gasps in disbelief)
(sighs)
What are we waiting for?
I'm starving.
Me, too.
Breakfast?
Coffee.
Yeah.
Hey, Dave.
I spoke with your doctor.
You're both okay.
Uh, we were about
to grab a bite to eat.
Want to join us?
I'd love to...
but I'm actually here for work.
Shawn Steubens,
the kid who got
infected...
He didn't make it.
PHILLIPS:
He wasn't so lucky.
It goes without saying...
but I'm just really glad
you're both okay.
Goes without saying.
Yeah.