(siren wails, stops)
(indistinct radio communication)
(car doors close)
Oh, man.
What do you got there,
Super Dave?
First blush?
Well, judging from the major
crushing injuries
to his chest
and torso,
I'd say a hit and run.
More like
hit and drag.
Guy left a trail.
Mmm, that's one hell of a roll,
I'll tell you that.
You see something?
No skid marks.
He skidded plenty,
but there's
no tire marks.
So whatever hit him
didn't slow down at all.
Plus, the angle's
all wrong.
Look at it.
Car would have to be headed
off the road
to send him flying
in that direction.
All right, how about body dump?
Tossed out, high speed.
Come here and check out
this glass.
Look at the thickness.
That's at least
five-eighths of an inch.
Definitely didn't come
from a car.
More like a window;
it's heavy duty.
PHILLIPS:
Guys.
Wherever that glass
came from,
we got plenty of it
on the victim.
STOKES: You guys don't think
we've got ourselves
a jumper here,
do you?
SANDERS:
Well, you do realize
the problem with that theory--
there's nowhere to jump
from on this block.
So where did he come from?
Did you get an I.D.?
Bradley Weaks,
an accountant.
Silver Spring Office Tower,
30th floor.
Silver Springs...?!
STOKES:
Well, you got to admit--
that's one hell of a jump.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Are you! ♪
(wind whistling)
Looks like a tornado went
through this place.
This looks like the same glass
we found with the victim.
Radial pattern, so...
came from
that direction.
SANDERS:
Two blown-out windows.
It's just like an entrance
and an exit wound.
Something blasted in
from that window,
cut the corner
of the room here,
and then goes out that one.
Yeah, but what the hell was it?
I mean, this glass is thick.
Normally, you could hit
these windows
with a baseball bat,
they wouldn't even blink.
Yeah, I think we're way
beyond a baseball bat here.
Look at that.
Scorch mark.
Do you think this thing
was rocket-powered?
Like a rocket-propelled
grenade, maybe?
Then why's the office
still in one piece?
Didn't detonate?
Maybe it was a dud.
Or on a timer.
Some of these are
triggered by a signal--
maybe the signal
was never sent.
Now, what if the guy
was standing here,
and this rocket-propelled
whatever hits him...
...carries him out the window,
sends him 30 floors down
and 100 yards up the street.
This guy was
an accountant.
Somebody decides
to take him out,
and they use a rocket-powered
something to do it.
That don't make
any sense to me.
Maybe we'll know more
when we find it.
What goes up has
to go down, right?
It's got to be
out there somewhere.
Okay, so that's
puzzle number one.
Puzzle number two is putting
this window back together.
Maybe we can figure out
what came through it.
Your pick.
Needle in a haystack,
or the impossible
jigsaw.
Why don't you take
the easy one.
Which one is that?
♪ ♪
What do you think?
Well, it's not 100%,
but it's enough
to see an impact zone.
Yeah.
Bigger than any RPG
I've ever seen.
Yeah.
It's, uh...
it's about 24
to 30 inches.
Something that big
and rocket-powered?
I mean, unless we're talking
about a damn cruise missile...
What do you think
it could have been?
Honestly,
I have no idea.
Hey, can I bounce
something off you?
Sure.
So, I've been looking
into the death of our CPA,
trying to figure out who
would want to take him out
in such a
spectacular fashion.
Did you come up
with something?
I don't know, I mean,
this guy is as average
as average gets.
He's a mid-level CPA
at a mid-tier firm.
But there is one
possible lead.
The firm where the
victim worked--
Baker, Smith, Capaldi.
They, along with about 20
other firms across the country,
have very tenuous ties
with the Colombian cartel.
You're thinking this is
a cartel hit?
I don't know what I'm thinking.
I'm trying to draw a line
between a... a Vegas accountant
and a possible RPG attack.
So far, the cartel angle
is the only connection
I've been able
to come up with.
(indistinct page over P.A.)
Hey.
You having any luck?
Actually, I am.
I've isolated some of the trace
from our mysterious UFO.
It's a UFO now?
I'm only using the term
in the strictest literal sense:
"Unidentified Flying Object."
Although, admittedly,
I do find the notion
that we are not alone in this
universe to be oddly comforting.
Uh-huh.
What did you find out about
whatever this rocket thing was?
For starters,
it wasn't a rocket.
Or at least not
rocket-powered.
I found fuel residue
in the scorch marks.
Jet-A aviation fuel.
So it was jet-powered?
Yes, the marks come
from close contact
with the exhaust nozzle from a
jet engine rather than a rocket.
Which implies an entirely
different type of flying object.
Mm-hmm.
More likely, it's something that
was piloted rather than fired.
And there was
something else telling
about these scorch marks.
You expose wood
to intense heat,
such as the case here,
and you get
a spontaneous breakdown
of the cellulose into charcoal.
But what is charcoal?
BOTH:
Carbon.
Obviously.
Carbon with some tarry residue
and a little bit of wood ash.
The hotter the burn,
the faster the process happens.
The faster it happens,
the less wood ash you're gonna
have left in the mix.
Yeah, so you measure
the amount of ash,
you get a rough idea
of how hot it was burning.
I can go one better.
By measuring the wood ash
over the length
of the burn,
we can determine whether
our jet was throttling up
or throttling down,
so to speak.
And?
Tip to tip, the intensity
of the burn drops 20%.
Wait, so it was slowing down?
Rapidly.
Based on the relative
fuel residue,
I'd say it was running
out of gas.
Which means it couldn't
have gone far.
STOKES: Depends on
your definition of far.
Even if this thing
was slowing down,
it still had
significant velocity.
Enough to crash
through two windows
and take a 175-pound man
with it.
Any way to calculate
where it landed?
I've been playing
with some numbers,
uh, based on the energy
necessary to break the glass,
the momentum transferred to
the victim, gravity, elevation,
but these are only
ballpark figures right now.
Ballpark's better
than nothing.
What are the numbers
telling you?
Well, the numbers tell me
it could have traveled
another quarter,
maybe half, mile...
in this general arc...
landed somewhere...
in that area.
Okay, I'll make the call.
Get the uniforms
out there.
All right, cool.
FINLAY: While unis were
canvassing the area,
they said they found this.
(Stokes whistles)
STOKES:
Kidding me?
It looks like a war zone.
FINLAY: Looks like we have
what's left of a body.
Ugh.
Cab driver must have been
sitting in here.
Sleeping, maybe.
That would be
a rude awakening.
Right?
Pulverized.
Hey! Hey! What the hell are
you doing to my cab?
Look at it, what am I
supposed to do now?
That's my livelihood.
All right, sir, we're
from the Vegas crime lab.
Was there a fare
in your taxi?
Somebody waiting,
anything like that?
No, what are
you talking about?
I've been off duty
for 12 hours, I just woke up.
Nobody was in my cab.
All right, all right.
I'll tell you what,
this officer's gonna
take your statement, okay?
This is not how I needed
to start my day.
Hey...
if that's the cab driver, then
who got blown to bits in here?
That's a good question.
STOKES: This might be part
of our missile.
Engine, maybe.
This might be
the nose cone.
Ugh, Nick.
It's part of a helmet.
Look at this...
(grunts)
Is that a boot?
Yeah.
Somebody's foot's still in it.
Whoever it was
wasn't sitting in here.
I think they flew in here.
Our missile was a man?
(man whoops)
Oh! Sheesh...
It's called a wingsuit.
Or-or a squirrel suit.
Same difference.
(man whooping)
RUSSELL: And this is what
our guy was doing?
That's a hell of a lot
of kinetic energy.
How fast we going there,
do you think?
Oh, around
220 miles an hour,
depending on good design
and proper fit.
It turns falling
into flying, basically.
But that wasn't good enough
for our guy.
He puts the suit on,
figures it's not
dangerous enough,
so he straps jet engines
to his feet?
He was begging for trouble.
Well, I don't think he'd argue
with that now.
So, anyway, Morgan's been
working with David,
trying to separate the
man from the machine.
Literally.
So I'm gonna go in there
and check on her.
She should be back by now.
Okay.
STOKES:
Hey.
How's it going in here?
It's going.
You know, one of my exes
was a skydiver.
He had a wingsuit.
I don't remember it
being this high-tech.
If anything, it struck me
as more of a clown suit.
Course, I could've said that
about everything he wore.
Well, that's probably why
he's your ex-boyfriend.
(wry chuckle)
Now, this suit--
it, uh, it looks different than
the one I was just watching.
It's more advanced.
Looks like some sort
of metal exoskeleton
across the wings.
I haven't seen that before.
And this...
is what's left of the
propulsion system.
BRODY: It's definitely not
something that was
hacked together
in somebody's garage.
This is sophisticated.
So where in the hell do you
think this thing came from?
I don't know.
But check this out.
It's got one more thing
my ex didn't have
when he was diving.
There's a little box
integrated into the
front of the rigging.
And it looks like
it has leads
connected to the suit,
as well.
Looks like a
mini version
of a black box,
like they have on airplanes.
That's exactly
what I was thinking.
It's weird, right?
ANDREWS:
Hey.
I got an I.D. on your,
uh, Rocket Man.
Ran his DNA.
When he didn't
pop in CODIS,
I expanded the search
to military databases.
Military?
In this case,
Air Force.
Your deceased
was a pilot:
Captain Robert Holland.
He was stationed
at Nellis.
So has Russell
notified the family yet?
The wife.
She lives on base.
The victim's C.O.
is bringing her in.
All right.
Mrs. Holland, I am
so sorry for your loss.
Thank you.
Major Mills,
on the phone last night,
you said that
Captain Holland was not
on duty last night.
Yes. That's correct.
And the wingsuit--
that's property
of the Air Force?
Uh, no-- technically,
it belongs to TRP Aeronautics,
a DoD contractor.
The Air Force is
exploring the possibility
of using them in
urban incursion.
And Captain Holland was
on loan to TRP
as a test pilot.
If he wasn't on duty
last night, then...
what was he doing in his suit,
flying in downtown Vegas?
(sighs)
That's a damn good question.
All I can tell you
is that test pilots--
like Captain Holland--
live to fly.
It wouldn't be the first time
one of them
stole a prototype
to log a few extra hours.
No.
Bobby wasn't like that.
He-he never took
unnecessary risks.
He wasn't that
kind of pilot.
Amanda, you have
to understand--
Bobby didn't want you to worry.
Now, I'm sure
he downplayed the risks
of whatever
he was involved in,
authorized or no.
And that's not
a criticism.
Taking risks is what made
Bobby a great pilot.
RUSSELL:
Mrs. Holland...
when was the last time
you saw your husband?
Truthfully,
it's been about three days.
Three days ago?
Ever since he started
working for TRP,
it's not uncommon for him
to be gone for days at a time.
MILLS:
Mr. Russell, I understand
that this accident resulted
in the death of a civilian.
Now, for the record,
the blame here
lies entirely
with TRP Aeronautics.
They never
should've allowed
the unauthorized removal
of that prototype
from their facility.
Major, you keep saying that
like Bobby did something wrong.
(sighs)
Mr. Russell, if you don't mind,
Captain Holland's parents
have yet to be notified.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I, um... I forgot my phone.
I'll bring
the car around.
Mr. Russell...
I don't care what anybody says.
I know my husband.
And he wasn't some
yeehaw test pilot.
He never would've flown
without authorization.
Think the Air Force
is covering something up?
I think they're
trying to blame Bobby.
That way, they can avoid
paying death benefits,
they can take away
his pension...
I mean, it's all about money.
They don't even care
that they dirty his name.
Well, if there's something
to find, Mrs. Holland,
I promise you, we'll find it.
Okay.
Thank you.
SANDERS:
I've been examining
the wingsuit,
and our flyer's rig
has two chutes.
A primary...
and a reserve.
Now, neither one
of them deployed.
Why?
I don't know,
but you gotta figure
the guy was either dead
or unconscious when he
hit that office tower.
Wouldn't have
pulled the ripcord.
But the reserve
has an AAD-- an automatic
activation device,
which should have
deployed on its own.
No matter what.
So was the AAD
damaged by the impact?
Well, no sign of
external damage.
Okay, the trigger's based
on air pressure, right?
Needs two things to pop.
You gotta to be really
close to the ground,
and you gotta be falling...
really fast.
Which would scare me
into popping.
Okay, so...
let's scare it.
See what happens.
Okay.
All we've got to do
is trick this bad boy
into thinking it's
taking a fall, yeah?
We suck the air out,
lower the air
pressure inside,
the chute thinks
it's at altitude.
Couple thousand feet ought
to do it, don't you think?
(air hissing)
All we need now
is the fall.
Geronimo!
(air hissing)
SANDERS: Altimeter's showing
a rapid descent...
(beeps)
...altitude's dropping,
all the way to zero.
It should've fired.
Excuse me.
Standard
barometric sensor.
Hold on-- Nick,
check this out.
STOKES: That's obviously
been tampered with.
Tool marks.
Two-pronged pattern.
The circuit's been cut.
Well, let's see what happens
if I bridge the circuit.
All right, you ready?
Yeah.
And that's what turns
an accident into murder.
I'm so sorry, Ms. Mason.
These officers want to
have a word with you.
It's all right, Ellen.
Obviously, they have news
about Captain Holland.
Is that right, officers?
What makes
you say that?
(clears throat)
Thank you.
Well, last night,
Captain Holland stole
a wingsuit prototype
from this facility,
a very expensive prototype,
and we have not seen him since.
So, either he caught
the largest thermal
in history,
or he's gotten
himself into trouble.
You're here, so,
I'm guessing it's the latter?
STOKES: Your guess
would be right.
The captain crashed the suit.
Killed a civilian
and himself.
That means you have questions.
Uh, okay. I expect
you'll want to start
with our Project Icarus lab.
Icarus?
Icarus. Greek myth.
Wax wings,
flew too close
to the sun.
That's a bit of an
inauspicious name
for a wingsuit
project,
given the way things turned
out for poor old Icarus,
don't you think?
MASON:
I'm sorry, I didn't
catch your name.
CSI Nick Stokes.
Well, CSI Nick Stokes...
follow me.
Okay...
(tools and machines
whirring and buzzing quietly)
(low, indistinct conversations)
MASON:
Captain, this is
CSI Nick Stokes. And...
Detective Crawford.
Captain Ferris.
Is this about Holland?
Lance... Holland is dead.
What?
God, what happened?
He had an accident.
Not in the suit.
Yeah, it was in the suit.
Where is it?
CRAWFORD:
It's evidence.
No, I-I don't...
I don't think you understand.
We're at a critical
stage in testing.
I need to see that suit
to determine what went wrong.
We're the ones
examining it now, okay?
You do have some interesting
tools here, Captain.
Like that one in your hand.
What is that
used for?
It's specially made,
used to adjust
the attack angle
on the wing.
Specially made?
By me.
My design.
Mind if I take it
back to the crime lab?
Why?
Well, we can talk
about that downtown.
Wait... am I under arrest?
Captain Ferris,
just go with the officers.
I mean, we have
nothing to hide, right?
CRAWFORD:
Please.
Thank you.
STOKES:
Here's the deal:
someone used a tool
just like yours
to sabotage the AAD
on Holland's
reserve parachute.
Bobby was like a brother to me.
CRAWFORD: Yeah, we imagine
there's a lot of camaraderie
between test pilots.
Lot of competition, too, right?
Yeah. Not so that I would
do something to him.
STOKES: Okay, come on,
man, we're just
trying to get
some answers, here.
Poor guy's widow deserves
that much, don't you think?
God.
Amanda...
Yeah, Amanda.
And right now,
she thinks the Air Force
is going to hold back
her husband's benefits
for stealing that suit.
Look...
Bobby didn't
steal the suit.
Well, your C.O.
sure seems to think he did.
As does Ms. Mason,
the CEO of TRP.
No, that... that's bull.
From the Air Force
perspective, maybe
the flight was
unauthorized,
but not TRP.
God...! (groans)
Can I get something
for my headache?
In a minute--
keep talking about TRP.
Are you saying
that they knew
Captain Holland was
testing the suit on his own?
It's Claudia, she's got us
pushing the limits.
Logging extra hours
in the simulator,
in the hypobaric chamber.
Was she encouraging
after-hours flights?
More than encourage,
she, uh, she
paid incentives.
Cash awards for
hitting milestones.
Last month, Bobby,
he made, um, 25 grand
for sustained level flight.
You all right there,
Captain Ferris?
Hey.
Captain.
Hey, man, do you know
where you are right now?
H-Hey.
Hey, guys.
Hey.
H-Hey, you guys
remember that girl?
Th-That one time?
Man, what was her name?
Hmm?
Captain?
Captain.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Call rescue.
We need paramedics in here!
Captain?
I got you, I got you.
What the hell is happening?
I don't know,
I don't know.
Captain?
Crawford, he's dead.
FINLAY: Heard you were working
on Captain Ferris.
What have you got, Doc?
Textbook.
I could've told you
cerebral edema
without even looking
at the body.
Brain tissue's like
any other part of the body,
it swells in response
to injury or illness.
Yeah, but unlike the
rest of the body,
the brain has
nowhere to go.
True, it swells
against the skull,
causing neurovascular
constriction.
Cutting off the brain's
oxygen supply.
So if that's C.O.D.,
what caused the edema?
The list of possibilities
is long.
The fact that Captain Ferris was
a pilot suggested to me
we could be dealing with HACE.
HACE?
It's an acronym--
High-Altitude Cerebral Edema.
It's a form of altitude
sickness caused
by repeated
rapid ascents.
It's not the first time
I've seen it, either.
What do you mean?
Well, as I'm sure
you remember,
there was not a lot of
Captain Holland left to examine,
but his brain tissue did
present vasogenic edema,
capillary leakage and spongiosis
of the white matter,
and those are all
consistent with HACE.
Do you think it's possible
that Holland could have
stroked out mid-flight,
the same way that Ferris
stroked out mid-sentence?
It's possible-- if he was
dropped off a plane
at altitude in a wingsuit,
that could certainly cause
the onset of HACE.
A hypobaric chamber
replicates the condition
of high altitude, right?
Right, the Air Force
uses them for training.
According to Nick,
TRP uses them, as well.
They want to make sure that
their pilots can function,
even with altitude sickness.
Training like
that's dangerous--
the margin of error
is incredibly small.
And if you get even
a little bit aggressive,
the effects could be lethal.
MASON: People, no,
this work is unacceptable.
We're not building
these suits
for some jackass buzzing
a half-time show, okay?
These are weapons of war.
You know what, stop.
Everybody!
Hey!
Eyes on me. Listen.
I know that
there have been
a lot of distractions
lately, okay?
But that is no excuse
for failure.
Is that clear?
Clear enough for me.
CSI Stokes.
Nice seeing you again.
I assume you heard
about Captain Ferris.
Two tragedies
in as many days.
It's almost more
than one can bear.
Almost.
Not sure what you mean.
Maybe this will
make it clear.
That's a search warrant.
That allows us to seize
medical records, program
schedules, flight data,
all materials related
to Project Icarus.
I-I don't,
I don't understand.
I've been absolutely
nothing but cooperative.
Two of your pilots
have died.
Both victims of HACE.
Unfortunate accidents.
Is that really what
you want to go with?
'Cause on top
of the HACE,
Captain Holland's parachute
was tampered with--
either by the competition
or by you.
So, quite frankly, I think
you're hiding something from me.
This warrant is worthless
without being cosigned
by a military judge.
I don't need JAG approval,
and you know it.
Okay, boys.
MAN: Yes, sir.
Move out.
You really want
to cooperate with me,
give me the decryption key
for the code from the black box
on Holland's wingsuit.
I don't have it.
Black boxes are
Air Force property,
and if you want access, you're
gonna have to talk to them.
You know what that is,
right, Major?
Yes, I do.
We need the encrypted data
from Captain Holland's flight
the night he died.
According to TRP,
as his C.O.,
you're the only person
who can give it to us.
That's correct.
And?
I'm sorry, but I can't give
you the decryption code.
It's classified and...
Two of your pilots
are dead.
They died working
for a contractor
who subjected them
to unnecessary risks.
Might have even killed
one of them to cover it up.
Those are serious
charges, Mr. Russell.
These are your guys we're
talking about here, Major.
TRP did something illegal,
and right now, they're just,
they're hiding
behind the Air Force,
they're hiding behind you.
My hands are tied.
Only if you let them be.
Look, this kid,
Captain Holland,
was under your command.
He woke up every morning,
and he put his life at risk
simply because you asked him to.
Help me find
some peace for his wife.
You need to do
the right thing here.
There's an alphanumeric pass
phrase keyed into each box.
I'll have my office send it
over to you within the hour.
Thank you, Major.
Like you said, it's
the right thing to do.
How goes the data retrieval
on the wingsuit man?
Honestly, I am crashing
and burning, just like him.
What do you mean?
The numbers don't
make sense.
I think maybe
the data's corrupted.
I mean, this thing was
involved in a serious crash.
Black boxes are designed
to withstand crashes.
That's the whole point.
Take a look for yourself.
At the biometric data.
We thought Captain Holland
stroked out mid-flight,
but look at his vitals.
Heart rate, BP,
respiratory rate--
all flatlined,
the whole way.
According to this, he was dead
before he even took flight.
That can't be possible.
You know that
Sherlock Holmes quote--
"Eliminate all other factors,
the one which remains
must be the truth."
"Must be the truth."
So we're saying what?
We're looking at an elaborate
body dump from a plane?
Not according to this.
Check out the altimeter reading
at the start of the flight.
2,920 feet.
Yeah.
Now, given that
Las Vegas is
roughly 2,200 feet
above sea level...
That would mean he would jump
from a height of 700 feet.
He didn't jump
from a plane.
This is more
like a BASE jump.
Okay, well,
the flight data would give us
all the GPS coordinates, right?
Right.
We know where he landed,
now we just got to figure out
where he came from.
I've reconstructed
Captain Holland's flight path
on the night he died,
zeroing in
on the point-of-origin
of what we now know was
a BASE jump.
Beginning here.
The Delmore Towers.
SANDERS: The top-floor
corporate condo, to be precise.
Owned by TRP Aeronautics.
Right, it says here:
TRP's CEO,
Claudia Mason,
used it as her in-town digs.
But she wasn't
the only one using it.
The data on the black box shows
a history of BASE jumps
at the same condo
over the last several months.
So Holland was using
the Delmore Towers to train.
Off base, off hours, off regs.
And, we have to assume,
with Claudia's approval.
You know, all these test pilots
vying for the bonuses
that TRP was offering,
maybe Claudia was just
trying to give Holland
a leg up on the competition.
Maybe that's not all
Claudia wanted to give him.
Ah.
Okay.
All right,
I like that.
So Holland goes up
to the tower with his wingsuit,
a little off-hour training.
But first he and Claudia decide
to have, uh, a pre-flight tryst.
Things get hot and heavy.
But Holland has HACE
just like Ferris.
And in the heat of passion,
he just strokes out.
Okay, so I'm Claudia.
What do I do?
Well, you have
two choices.
You either call 911...
Yeah, but if I do that,
I lose my contracts,
I lose my company...
So you go with
choice number two--
You put Holland
in his wingsuit,
you drag him out
onto the balcony,
you fire up the jet engines
to give him just enough
thrust to launch him,
and then all you need
is a little push.
But first you disable
the backup chute,
so that when he crashes
to the Earth,
nothing left of him
to trace back to you.
After all, he was just
another reckless flyboy.
Stole a suit,
went for a joyride.
Not a bad plan if
you're Claudia Mason,
and you're coming up
with it on the fly.
Yeah.
But like all things
on the fly...
I'm betting that there's
something that she missed.
You sure about
your theory?
I'm just saying, doesn't even
look like anybody's been here.
Well, Claudia Mason
must have cleaned up.
Let's just hope she's a better
CEO than she is a maid.
Balcony.
Where Holland
started his flight.
I got some blood.
Like Russell said--
Claudia must have
missed something.
Would you hit the lights?
BRODY:
Wow.
That is one serious blood pool.
Well, it doesn't
end there.
Got some blood drops.
And cast-off.
You thought the guy stroked out
from HACE, right?
Well, that's what I thought,
but... I mean,
these blood patterns
suggest something different.
More violent.
This is from a brutal beating.
It's a crime
of passion.
You know how they always say,
"The cover-up is worse
than the crime"?
Not this time.
So, what does our CEO
have to say for herself?
Not a whole hell
of a lot, really.
She denies knowing
anything about Holland
going up to the condo to do
his BASE-jumping, so...
So she denies
having an affair, too?
Oh, yeah.
(sighs)
Well, look, the first time,
she was hiding behind
the Air Force.
This time,
she's hiding behind
that $800-an-hour lawyer.
Well, if she won't talk,
her condo definitely will.
♪ ♪
Well, no crime of passion
starts without the passion.
There were no prints
on the murder weapon.
But once we run the blood,
the fiber, the hairs,
maybe we can prove Claudia
was here, killing him, too.
She may not have been
the one wanting to kill him.
Just got the security
camera footage from the lobby,
the night Holland died.
That's Holland's wife.
The show is just
getting started.
RUSSELL:
You lied to us, Amanda.
You told me you hadn't seen
your husband in days.
And that the night
he was killed,
you assumed he was on
a training mission for TRP.
This video says you knew
exactly where he was.
And he was on more
than just
a "training mission."
Look, I know what this
looks like, but you're wrong.
No, I'll tell you
what's wrong--
you coming to me
asking me to find out
what happened
to your husband,
when you knew all along.
No. It is not like that.
CRAWFORD:
Okay.
Tell us what it's like, then.
The past few months,
Bobby has been different.
At first, I thought
it was just this new job
at TRP, I mean...
But a woman knows
when her husband is...
Is what?
Straying?
He said he was going
to TRP that night,
and I followed him.
CRAWFORD:
Downtown.
To the condo.
Yes. And I
confronted him.
And I was going to
confront that woman, too,
whoever she was.
But on the way up
in the elevator,
Bobby swore to me
that he was innocent.
That he really was there
training that night.
He was doing a BASE jump
from a condo tower.
He showed me his wingsuit,
he showed me his gear,
and I...
I had to believe him.
I didn't want to lose him.
RUSSELL: So you didn't
go up to the condo,
you didn't continue the fight
and you didn't kill your husband
in a jealous rage.
Am I getting that right?
I didn't kill Bobby.
I'm sorry that I lied to you
about seeing him that night.
And Major Mills is right--
Bobby didn't
follow the rules.
He lived on the edge.
And jumping from a tower
in the middle of the city
was against regulations.
You lied to us
just so that you could keep
his death benefits.
Yeah.
And preserve his memory.
And I'm not lying to you now.
Then you won't mind giving us
a blood and DNA sample,
will you?
HODGES:
Nick, you need to see this.
What is it?
Expanded tox panel on
Air Force Captain Ferris.
I don't think
it's any accident
that he stroked out on
you in Interrogation.
Tested positive for furosemide.
Isn't that a diuretic?
A hard-core diuretic,
often abused by models
and bodybuilders
to get that "cut" look.
Ferris' medical
records make
no mention of any prescription.
Okay, so the guy was
on a diuretic.
I don't see how
that would kill him.
Flip the page.
You'll see that
the furosemide
caused a major
sodium imbalance.
For a guy logging that many
hours in a hypobaric chamber,
it makes for
a lethal combination.
Makes for murder.
♪ ♪
Hey, Henry.
Got your text.
You have results on
the DNA from the condo?
I do-- uh, blood is a match
to the victim, Captain Holland.
Okay, uh, what about the bed?
The murder weapon?
I found semen contribution
from Holland in the bed...
Just cut to the chase.
Which woman killed him?
The wife? Or the boss?
The boss was in
bed with him.
But not the one
you're thinking of.
Your DNA in the bed,
and your DNA on
the murder weapon.
Mrs. Holland knew her husband
was having an affair.
She just didn't know it was
with his commanding officer.
FINLAY:
Would you like to tell us what
happened that night, Major?
Help us understand.
You know, maybe it'll
help a jury understand.
He said he was
going to leave me.
Said he was afraid.
CRAWFORD:
Of what?
Afraid of getting caught?
It wasn't just an affair.
And there is no way that you
or anybody can understand that.
You could try us.
I loved him.
And I thought that
he loved me, too.
He said his wife was
asking questions,
and that she followed him
to the condo that night.
Can you believe it?
For a second,
I was actually relieved.
I thought maybe this meant
that we could...
stop living the lie.
But he didn't feel
that way, did he?
No.
It's over.
Don't you understand that?
I love my wife.
You love me.
How can you deny
who you are?
Who we are?
Deny? This coming from you?
Your whole life is denial.
I had to make
sacrifices for my career.
Yeah, and me, too.
And now I'm making
another sacrifice.
I'm sorry, but...
we're done.
Don't turn your
back on me.
(yelling fiercely)
I panicked.
I... I cleaned up the condo
as best I could.
CRAWFORD:
Yeah, you put him
in the wingsuit
and you sabotaged the
chute so it wouldn't open.
FINLAY:
Or, at the very least,
make Claudia and TRP
the fall guy.
Is that why Ferris
had to die, too?
Yeah, well,
we searched your place.
And, um, we found this.
It's furosemide.
What was your plan, Major?
I mean, you slip some
into his coffee,
you hope he strokes out
in the hypobaric chamber?
But it didn't work out
that way, right?
He was a strong
test pilot.
Took a few extra hours.
Bobby and Ferris
were best friends.
If anybody knew the truth
about us, it was him.
I...
had no choice.
Major...
You always have a choice.
And you chose wrong.
Twice.
Mrs. Holland?
You still waiting
for something?
Haven't they finished
with you yet?
No, they said I could go.
I just...
I mean, go where?
Home is empty.
It's always going
to be empty.
I'm so sorry.
For everything.
Your husband...
You were just doing your job.
I understand.
Do you keep secrets
from your wife?
I used to.
Not anymore?
No.
She's a lucky woman, then.
Excuse me.