( women laughing )
We are just warming up,
my girl.
Wait, wait, wait.
I don't think
this is the right way.
It's a shortcut.
A shortcut? To where?
( laughing )
( thumping )
Stop.
Stop the car.
It was just a pothole.
I think you hit someone.
( tires screeching )
The blonde behind the wheel.
Girlfriend in
the passenger seat
called it in.
Vehicular manslaughter.
Taillight?
Yeah.
Have you been drinking, Warrick?
No, I'm having
a block party.
I marked it
where I found it--
over on the sidewalk
over there.
Two distinct tire treads--
one wide...
one narrow.
Given the extensive
bruising from
the wide tread mark
the victim was killed by
a larger vehicle, not a compact.
Hey, O'Riley
I wouldn't book
those suspects just yet.
I think they ran over a corpse.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
Yo.
What's up?
We got a call
about ten minutes
ago-- a shooting
at Vegas Grounds Coffee
Shop, Eighth and Main.
Multiple fatalities.
We want this one.
You guys get over there.
Keep me
in the loop.
Keep the media
out of it.
Right.
Hey, remember about
three months ago
I applied to the American
Academy meeting in Chicago?
Well, the deadline
for your approval
is end of shift today.
It's not a problem.
There's important papers...
You don't have to explain--
consider it done.
Thank you.
Good luck.
Printed your hit-and-run.
AFIS found a match--
Brian Clemonds, 22
born in Vegas,
and he's deaf.
You can tell he's deaf
by his fingerprints?
Actually, yes--
he was printed as part
of a state aid program in '81.
To confirm,
I examined his ear canal.
Normally, the malleus
is shaped like a hammer--
a long, smooth handle connecting
to a blunt head--
but Brian's malleus is knotted,
both of them-- birth defect.
There's a college for
the deaf about a mile
from where we found him.
WARRICK:
So, Brian takes a walk
crosses the street, doesn't
hear the car, gets creamed.
SARA:
The vehicle--
probably a truck
or an SUV, based on the width
of the tire tread-- takes off.
Later, along comes
a compact--
thump-- runs over his dead body.
ROBBINS:
Maybe, maybe not.
See the dried blood
on his knuckles?
No associated wounding.
Blood's probably not his.
WARRICK:
You know what that means--
Smackdown--
the kid was in a fight.
That ended in murder.
Did you send a sample
of his blood to DNA?
When you find the suspect
you'll nail him
with his own body fluid.
Has his family been notified?
Not yet.
One person dead, it's a shame;
more than one's a party.
Get ready
to pull a double.
( rock music playing )
Papa Roach. Couldn't hear
a bomb go off over this.
Welcome to
the caffeine wars.
We got four dead,
one on the way to the hospital.
The kid who belonged
to those headphones.
I count two--
where are the others?
One behind the counter;
one in the back room.
Guy wasn't light
with the ammo.
This place is raining
shell casings.
Hey, I know this guy.
I bet you do.
Who doesn't know
Frankie Flynn?
Used to own the Orpheus.
Lost his gaming license
a couple of years ago.
Oh, yeah.
Too many dips in the chips.
Yeah, you got that right.
Who's the muscle?
This is, uh, Al Robson
Frankie Flynn's bodyguard.
Cash taken?
Till's full and
all the wallets
are accounted for.
I don't think anyone
was interested
in the, uh, cash...
or the coffee.
You're thinking hit?
Maybe. Frankie drives
a bullet-proof car.
What does that tell you?
( sighs )
She's probably
still in high school.
( groans )
Bless her heart.
Assuming Flynn was the
target and it was a hit
the shooter followed Flynn
in the front door...
shot the muscle first...
then Flynn...
and some poor kid
minding his own business.
The girls were last.
( gunshots )
Four dead.
One is still alive.
( beeping )
Make that five.
Guy died on the way
to the hospital.
( doorbell rings
and bell ringing )
Mrs. Clemonds?
Yes?
My name is Gil Grissom.
I'm with the Las
Vegas Crime Lab.
Crime Lab?
May I come in
for a minute?
Okay.
My son is deaf.
That bell is connected
to the doorbell.
The bell sets off vibrations
which reverberate
on the floorboards
so that he knows
someone's at the door.
Yes.
Mrs. Clemonds, I'm here
about your son Brian.
There's no easy way
to say this.
Oh, God, please, no.
Brian was killed tonight.
No, no... no...
( crying )
This is my fault.
No. No, it's not.
When I was pregnant,
I had the German measles
and the virus
took away his hearing.
It's my fault.
No, Mrs. Clemonds...
we think he might
have been murdered.
Murdered?
Would you like to talk to
a family services counselor?
( laughs weakly )
Talking is overrated,
Mr. Grissom.
Just find out
who did this to my boy.
Please.
It's been
a hell of a night.
First the deaf kid,
now a hit.
It's going to take a while
to process all the bodies.
What do you know
about Flynn?
I always start
with the celebrities.
Frankie Flynn, 38
gunshot wounds to the head
and the abdomen.
Any bullets recovered?
Only one, out of the head--
uh, nine-millimeter .357.
I deal with
the pin cushions.
Ballistics deals
with the pins.
Shooter could have
saved himself
a lot of trouble
if he'd waited a month or two.
Why?
Invasive colon cancer.
On his way out.
Guess he got off easy.
I.D.?
Erin McCarty, 20.
Wonder if she even knew
she was pregnant.
Just keeps getting better.
Someone notify the husband?
Cop said she's single--
she lives at home
with her mother.
How far along was she?
About six weeks.
She knew.
Another nine-millimeter,
just like our casings.
Nine bullets,
all the same caliber.
Looks like Robson
never got a shot off.
I wouldn't want him
as my bodyguard.
Need help with the measurements?
BRASS:
Sure.
Captain, I got the
manager outside.
Okay.
That's the guy
right there.
This one?
Yep, that's the one.
( Brass clears throat )
I'm Detective Brass.
Catherine Willows.
Nick Stokes
from the Crime Lab.
Brad Kendall.
I heard it on the news.
They're saying it was
some kind of a hit.
Where are Erin and Alice?
They didn't make it.
( sighs )
Wait... Did you call
their parents?
Once the coroner makes
a positive I.D.
their families will be notified.
CATHERINE:
Shooting occurred
around closing time.
Is it customary
for your employees to close up?
Erin locked up twice a week,
10:00 on the nose.
She was training Alice, moving
on at the end of the month.
I can't believe
they're gone.
Dr. Gilbert, we need your help.
Brian Clemonds was murdered.
Was he having any difficulties?
Anyone have a grudge
against him?
We understand
you don't want
a homicide investigation
upsetting your students.
I'm severely deaf,
and I can communicate fine.
I'd appreciate it
if you'd look at me
when you speak to me.
I wear a hearing aid
and I can read lips.
You could have asked
if I needed an interpreter.
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to offend you.
There are 152 students
at my school.
We live together;
we study together;
we eat together.
We're a family.
And Brian is dead.
Dr. Gilbert, we're just
following protocol.
We need to speak
with Brian's friends,
his roommates.
We'll also need access
to his records.
The crime didn't happen here--
it happened out there.
I'm not accusing anybody
of anything.
Neither am I, but there
are more of you, right?
Send someone else, someone
with more understanding
of this school
of my students.
But we're here now,
and evidence is time sensitive.
How can you solve a crime
without understanding
the victim?
Um, she's kicking us out.
Hey.
How'd it go
at the college?
They're not cooperating.
Yeah, we didn't have a warrant,
so she kicked us out.
What did you do?
What did we do?
We met with the president,
asked a few questions.
She was kind of hostile.
Like it's our fault
we can hear.
All right. Let's go.
Dr. Gilbert?
I'm Gil Grissom
with the Crime Lab.
You kicked my people
out of your office.
Well, I'm kicking
you out, too.
Look, your student is dead.
Don't you want to know
who's responsible? I do.
Your people can't
solve this crime.
Why? 'Cause they don't
understand the victim?
Help them understand.
When a deaf person
meets a hearing person
the hearing person so much as
says, "I'm normal, you're not."
Is that what you think
I'm saying?
A student is dead.
Maybe you feel responsible.
Maybe you're angry.
But don't be angry at us.
We want to help you.
If I agree to cooperate
you will include me
in your investigation?
Yes, I will.
I welcome your involvement.
Now...
may I see Brian Clemonds'
file? Please?
I did nothing wrong.
Brian filed six complaints
against his roommate
Paul Arrington.
Paul lost his hearing less
than a year ago-- a tumor.
He hasn't adjusted.
He's angry.
And he took it out
on Brian.
Assaulted him.
Brian requested a new roommate.
Request denied?
There were no other
available beds.
I want to speak to Paul.
He doesn't read
lips or sign.
You don't need to hear or speak
to communicate.
Or... commit murder.
So, you going
to tell us
how you
learned to sign?
No.
Well, the president
of the college
is a real wack job.
Sara, you see deafness
as a pathology.
For Dr. Gilbert,
her deafness is
not her handicap
it's her way of life.
You know, I think you
might be siding with her.
As long as you see this as
us versus them, you're going
to have problems
on this case.
This explains
what we're doing.
What was that all about?
Grissom signs.
Do you know
what Grissom drinks
when he goes out at night?
He goes out?
Exactly-- who knows
anything about that guy?
Hey, check that out.
Oh, I've read about
this machine.
Very Frankenstein.
Brain printing.
They call it a visual polygraph.
You've used one
of these before?
Yeah, back in '97
Grissom and I used one
to interview this rapist.
The guy was mute
but his brain waves
spoke loud and clear.
So, you show the suspect
slides of the crime scene
and if he's our guy...
the oscillator
will give him away.
Good, he recollects you.
He recollects the college.
He recollects Brian.
No recollection.
No recollection
of the crime scene
or of Brian
under these conditions.
May we go now?
If you want
to find the killer
look outside
the school.
( faintly ):
Grissom!
Sorry.
I was thinking.
About what it's
like to be deaf?
About what it's like to hear.
Sara told me that
you spoke in sign
and now you're putting
plugs in your ears.
I'm on a case.
Mm-hmm.
Is that why you forgot
about the conference?
The what?
You missed the deadline.
No Chicago for me.
Oh, Catherine...
This is the one meeting
I needed to attend.
I don't always
want to be
second banana.
I can probably do your job.
I know that I can do Ecklie's.
I forgot.
I'm so sorry.
Make sure to submit
the paperwork
by the end of the day.
I thought you said
that it was too late.
Well, I knew you'd forget
so I upped the deadline,
gave you a buffer.
Don't forget again.
Those the tire treads
from the crime scene?
I photoed the
victim's torso
and imaged the tread
mark-- scanned it
got it running through
a Tread Assistance CD ROM.
Any hits?
Not yet.
CD database-- 11,033 patterns.
Could take a while.
Yeah.
What are you doing?
Checking out
the dead guy's clothes.
Whoa.
What are these?
What?
They look like lice.
Lice?
Wasn't our dead guy clean?
Yeah, he was.
Lice adhere to
hair follicles-- I didn't
find any stray hairs on him.
Well, he was in a fight, right?
Maybe his attacker had lice
and they crawled off
on his sweater
and they got comfy
and the stray hair blew away.
Hey.
Any luck on the
tire treads?
Computer's still processing
but Warrick found something
pretty interesting.
You know anything
about lice?
Yeah, they make
your head itch.
And after head colds
the most common medical
problem affecting children.
Little problem
no one talks about, huh?
Hey, Grissom,
can I see you
for a sec? Stat.
Stay on the tire treads.
Warrick?
Yeah, right behind you.
A few more numbers and
this could have been cake.
Guess who used to sign
Brad Kendall's paychecks
six years ago?
Frankie Flynn.
Oh, yeah.
Hey, Brad, thanks
for coming in.
We've just got
a few more questions.
Sure.
You used to work for Flynn?
At the Orpheus-- I was a waiter.
He came in all the time.
Sit down.
Did you see him
outside the coffee shop?
Once in a while--
he owned the place.
He was everywhere.
Why don't you tell us
about your CCW permit.
I made cash deposits.
I carry a concealed weapon.
What kind?
Glock, nine millimeter.
We'll need to
see the weapon
and any spare ammo.
Yeah, of course,
I'll bring it in.
I am the man.
Why, what'd you do?
Let me guess.
You ran a DNA profile
on the blood
off his knuckles
and you got a match.
No.
You ran a DNA profile
and got something
distinctive?
Not quite.
You got out of bed
and dressed yourself?
No.
What is it, Greg?
Just put your nose
down the scope.
Dots of blue light
on a red sea.
Pyoverdin.
A pigment excreted
from pseudomonas aeruginosa
which is a bacteria
occasionally found
in the bloodstream.
So what does
that give us?
Your killer has
fluorescent blue
dots in his blood.
So the guy's a glow-stick.
How does that help us
track him down?
Haven't I done enough
for one day?
SARA:
We have a lead--
I found a partial
serial number
on the broken taillight.
I saw it.
It's missing six digits,
it's useless.
Maybe on its own
but the tire tread database
kicked out a match.
The tire belongs
to a Ford Explorer.
A P235-75,
manufactured
specifically for their SUVs.
Only one with the same
partial serial number
is registered in Vegas.
What do you call a guy
with blue dotted blood
lice and keys
to a Ford Explorer?
A suspect?
A killer.
You found the car
that ran over Brian?
Yes.
The SUV's registered
to Adam Walkey.
He's 18 years old;
no prior complaints.
We're processing it now.
I promised to keep
you informed.
You kept your word.
Lice?
Creepy critters
in the passenger seat.
So... that's why Grissom's late.
You just don't like other women
in his life.
I'm going to pretend
I didn't hear that.
Affirmative on the head lice.
Taillights match.
We have a suspect.
I'm advising Adam
to invoke his
Fifth Amendment rights.
O'RILEY:
No charges have been filed
and I haven't asked a question.
Go ahead and ask...
he won't answer.
Well, that's why I
suggested we meet here.
I don't need him to talk.
I just want his blood.
Well, for that,
you're going to need a warrant.
This warrant is for blood...
and a scalp search.
It's a Licemeister.
We're going to comb
your hair.
Talk to me.
Good news, bad news.
Same caliber,
different gun.
Bobby?
Striations
don't match.
The gun that killed those
five people at the coffee house
isn't your store manager's.
The good news is--
all of the nine
millimeter bullets
fired at the scene...
from the same gun.
You're looking
for only one guy.
Well, what about
the breach-face marks
on the casings?
Indeterminate.
Hmm.
Well, well... looks
like you got zip.
I got a ton of people out
interviewing
every two-bit stiff
that ever had a beef
against Flynn.
They're all doing
the smart thing--
keeping their mouth shut.
WILLOWS:
So have no statements
or physical evidence
indicating
it was a hit on Flynn.
What we have is
five dead bodies.
Yeah... why?
You know something
I don't know?
Not yet.
Nick?
Smoke and mirrors.
If it was a hit,
the guy came to the front door
took out Al and Frankie,
and got the witnesses.
Bullets will confirm it.
Shooter was standing here
when he shot Al...
Bam. Once in the chest.
This is Flynn.
One miss...
one hit...
one through and through.
Headphones.
Ricochet.
Through and through.
Each victim
gets a different color.
Blue beams are isolated.
The kid with the CD player
was alone.
Flynn was closest to the door.
Shooter was positioned between
Flynn and the front door.
Flynn eats it...
and I would have taken out
Big Al...
bodyguard first.
Me, too.
Ident found
both of the bodyguards' paws
on the counter.
What if the shooter was here
when he shot Big Al?
Big Al would already be dead.
It doesn't make any sense.
If the shooter
walked through
the front door.
What if he came
through the back?
Erin McCarty-- the employee
who was supposed to close up.
Yeah, shot twice
in the back
while heading for the rear exit.
If she was headed towards
the parking lot
how do you explain
this ricochet?
What?
STOKES:
Whoa...
Like this.
I love this job.
The ricochet went
out into the store.
There's no hole in the door.
There's no hole in the door
'cause the door
had to have been open.
Assuming Erin
was running for her life
the shooter follows her
in the back room
shoots her twice--
he would have
been shooting
toward the parking lot.
He shot toward
the parking lot first
then toward
the front of the store.
He'd only shoot
toward the front
if there's somebody there.
Someone was in the line of fire.
( sighs )
What if we have it backwards?
What if...
the shooting began back here...
with Erin?
Yeah, and somebody else saw.
Frankie Flynn
was an innocent bystander.
Wrong place, wrong time.
The target was Erin...
the pregnant girl
and the rest was damage control.
Adam Walkey
doesn't have lice?
Not even lice eggs.
Maybe he got rid of them
since the other night.
Delousing agents take
time to kick in.
There would have
been evidence of
the infestation.
Hey... got good news.
Walkey's blood sample...
Pseudomonas aeruginosa?
Fluorescent blue.
WARRICK:
Same as the blood
we found on
Brian's knuckle.
Greg, start a DNA comparison.
This gives us
enough to hold Walkey.
It's just like
Dr. Gilbert said...
the killer
came from out here.
Dr. Gilbert can afford
her personal bias.
We can't.
And we need a lot more
than Day-Glo bacteria
to get a conviction.
You really think
Erin knew she was pregnant?
I mean, six weeks?
20-year-old girl,
living at home?
She would have
taken a test
if she was five
seconds late--
panic city.
Yeah, Brass talked
to her parents.
There was no guy
in her life.
Well, it's not
immaculate conception.
If the guy was Mr. Right
she would have
told her folks.
Which means he
was Mr. Wrong.
Maybe Mr. Married.
Back for more?
You still have
the pregnant girl?
Mortuary will pick her up
later this afternoon.
Stall them. We want
a paternity test.
At six weeks?
Six weeks with half of
someone else's DNA
in her body.
Check this out.
This fabric matches
the victim's sweater.
That's the muffler.
Now, this is the
back of the car.
And the taillight
was smashed.
There's no way this car
was moving forward
when it ran over
Brian Clemonds's body.
Who drives backwards
on a downtown street?
First degree murder.
That's how we see it.
It's okay.
In that case,
my client is
now prepared
to make a statement.
Tell him, Adam.
I may have hit the guy.
That's some statement.
ADAM:
Okay. I remember
hitting something.
It was dark.
I-I just kept driving.
Didn't look back.
Adam...
We found lice in the driver's
seat of your vehicle
but your scalp was clean.
Was there anyone else there?
A witness
who might support your account?
( clears throat )
( sighs )
Yeah, someone
was with me.
Mark.
Mark Rucker.
He can confirm
everything I told you.
I want to see him.
That's the coward
who killed Brian.
JANE:
What happened?
He scared you?
Talked a little funny?
Made a lot of
noises? Screamed?
Or maybe he just looked
at you the wrong way?
Get away from me.
You make me sick.
You said you'd include me.
You offered to help to help
with my investigation
and now you're
compromising it.
You found the killer.
Who says it was a hit and run
not murder.
He has a witness.
Who will lie for him.
The witness can say
whatever he wants.
The important thing is that
Adam Walkey was not alone
when he killed Brian.
Until now, I did not
know who was with him.
And now you do.
His witness is
our other suspect.
911 page?
What's up?
Right gun.
Wrong barrel.
Son of a bitch swapped
the gun barrel out.
Check this out.
Could be an
incomplete
tool mark.
Maybe the guy
dropped his gun.
Either way, we still
don't have the barrel.
This is true.
But we've got
Kendall's ammo.
What about
bullet batching?
Match the bunter marks?
Every casing's got two
pieces of information on it:
manufacturer and caliber.
Etched in by an
electrodischarge machine.
Every casing from a given batch
of ammo has the same markings.
So if you compared the casings
we collected at the crime scene
with the casings from
Brad Kendall's gun...
On a microscopic level,
we should find similar
characteristics...
Which would link Brad's
ammo to the crime
even though we
can't link his gun.
Not as airtight
as matching the barrel.
But still enough
to build a case.
What about motive?
Well, Catherine's
working on a hunch.
Me? The father?
No way. I'm married.
I don't fool around.
BRASS:
Would you like us to
explain the mechanics
of sex in the workplace?
CATHERINE:
You're the manager.
Erin was the employee.
BRASS:
You had the power.
Happens all the time.
You got it all wrong.
Maybe we do; we all make
mistakes, but just to be sure
why don't you give us
a DNA sample
and you'll be
on your way.
I don't believe this.
Talk to anyone.
I'm not like that.
I've got a court order.
It was a one-time thing.
I didn't even know
she was pregnant.
O'RILEY:
I read him his rights.
Last chance
for a lawyer.
I didn't do anything.
Why would I need a lawyer?
Fire away.
I have just one question:
Does your head itch?
Do I have to answer that?
I'm going to just, uh...
rearrange your part
a little.
Hmm.
According to Adam Walkey
you were with him in his SUV
the other night
and your head lice...
confirmed his statement.
They also tell me
that you were driving.
Yeah, yeah, I was with him.
And like he told you,
we didn't know he hit the guy.
How do you know
what Adam told us?
( rubber gloves snapping )
Now, why don't you just tell us
what really happened.
Well, it was around midnight...
and we were listening
to the radio.
I changed the station.
Adam got pissed.
Dude, what are you doing?
That song is a classic.
It's not a classic.
It's crap.
It's always
been crap.
Now, this... this is tight.
( modern rock )
( loud thud )
Wh-what was that?
Probably a dog.
Let's get out of here.
We just kept driving.
Yeah, it's the truth.
The evidence says otherwise.
What are you talking about?
Well, there weren't just lice
in the SUV.
There were lice
on the victim's sweater.
So, who cares about lice?
Do you know what lice eat?
Blood.
I'm pretty sure
I can prove that the lice
on Brian Clemonds
came from your head.
We got out of the car.
We got to call the paramedics.
We tell anybody,
we are in trouble.
We can go to jail.
But I didn't want
to leave him like that.
Adam talked me into it.
He had a scholarship
to Duke next year, you know.
He couldn't risk it.
( sighs )
Let me tell you
what I think happened.
You and Adam saw Brian
walking out of a liquor store
carrying a six-pack.
You're underage.
Maybe you wanted him
to front you some beer.
Hey, man, can you
do us a favor?
GRISSOM:
Brian doesn't respond.
What's his problem?
Let's find out.
( brakes screeching )
Then you got out of the car.
Hey, moron, we just want
you to buy us some beer.
How about we just
grab yours, huh?
What do you want?
What do you say?
You going to give it up?
Brian still doesn't
say anything.
So you keep pushing.
Go away!
Give...
Bring him down!
GRISSOM:
The blood on the victim's
knuckles led us to Adam.
The average male
loses 80 hairs a day.
Stray hair left behind lice,
which brings us to you.
It would have ended there, but
as you were about to drive away
something caught
your attention.
Something
in the rearview mirror.
Please don't hit me!
Please don't!
( yelling )
( engine revving )
You backed the car up.
And you took off.
I want a lawyer.
Let me tell you something, son.
Gil, the interrogation is over.
He's requested counsel.
Fine.
No more questions.
Just this.
You want
to know why
Brian Clemonds ran away
from you?
It was dark;
you were shouting at him;
and he didn't understand
what you were saying.
Brian Clemonds was deaf.
He was afraid of you.
But you were more afraid
of him... weren't you?
What am I looking at?
STOKES:
Microscopic surface analysis.
This ought to make
things more clear.
A bunter tool
leaves a unique mark.
Casings from your gun
are on the right.
Casings collected
from the crime scene
are on the left.
They're identical.
You came here
that night...
to kill Erin.
You came in through the back.
Erin was in the office.
We got to talk.
I'm tired of
talking to you.
Listen to me!
I'm tired of
listening to you.
BRAD:
I will take
care of this.
All you take care
of is yourself.
Erin, think.
Use your head
for once.
I'm not going to let
you ruin my life!
I already have
thought about it.
I'm going to
have this baby
and you are going
to support it.
I'll let you know if
it's a boy or a girl.
( gasps )
CATHERINE:
But Alice saw.
You shot her.
( screams )
You thought that
Alice had locked up
but there was a kid
drinking coffee
and then things got out of hand.
And you just kept on shooting.
BRASS:
Brad Kendall,
you're under arrest
for the murders of Frankie Flynn
Al Robson, Roy Hinton,
Alice Neely and Erin McCarty.
STOKES:
Six weeks pregnant
with your child.
I didn't mean for it
to happen like that.
I just wanted
to talk.
Is that why you
brought your gun?
Some people
are just afraid.
And that's why
they killed Brian.
Because he was different.
You don't see us
as different.
You're not.
Who taught you to sign?
My mother.
Tell me about her.
And use your hands.
You're a little rusty.