Good afternoon, Mr. McGrath.
How’s the golf?
Hi.
You look lost.
Okay, the stairs are all
the way back to the left
and the real estate office
is at the end of the hall.
Okay? Bye.
Ooh, are those for me?
Hi, Dominic, sign here.
Okay.
I tell you, though
this is going to be worth
a lot of money someday.
I know, Elvis.
Okay.
See you.
Okay, bye-bye.
( groans )
Domino, it’s your turn
to pick up dinner.
Okay, Jake-o.
Listen, uh, this goes
to Cooley Real Estate.
That’s on two,
all right?
And the Fed Ex is running
a little bit late
on the pick-up.
I’ll be back in...
hmm, about ten minutes,
all right?
You got it.
All right,
buddy.
( ticking )
( ticking continues )
( yells )
Oh, these fire guys
really know how to
trash a crime scene.
That’s what they do.
Put wet stuff on
the red stuff.
We’re all clear to go in,
but here’s what we’ve got.
Couple of head wounds.
Elderly guy had his arm
torn off.
The only fatality so
far is Jake Richards,
a security guard.
Body’s still inside.
BRASS:
How big you think this bomb was?
WILLOWS:
It’s not the size of the bomb.
It’s the overpressure
in the air around it.
The Van Gogh effect.
In stereo.
Both ears gone.
A perfectly symmetrical
amputation.
Means he was looking directly
at the bomb when it went off.
So either it drew
his attention
or it was contained
in something
that seemed benign.
Smell the sulfur?
Uh-huh.
Got your lighter, Jim?
Sure.
Light this.
Gunpowder.
GRISSOM:
Well, we know the propellant.
So would you care to make
a preliminary call on this?
I’d love to.
Seat of the bomb is here.
Victim was thrown...
three meters.
His clothes are torn
but not burnt,
indicating
a low-velocity propellant.
6,000-7,000 feet per second.
Who? Why?
Will he do it again?
Time will tell.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
The dirty little secret of bombs
is how easy they are to make
and use.
Our murder weapon’s
here someplace
in a thousand pieces.
We have to find it
and put it back together again.
Where do we start?
If it’s not growing
pick it up.
We cart everything we find
back to the lab.
And then what?
Stay curious.
Can you fill in the blanks?
WILLOWS:
Bombs explode.
Weird thing is their components
survive the explosion.
If we can piece together
this bomb
we’re closer to finding
who did this.
So, Warrick, when
you’re photographing
this debris
can you, uh...?
Uh, I know,
looky-loos.
( indistinct chatter )
Come on, Nick, it’s my
last night in Sin City.
One more drink, man.
Oh, no, I just
pulled a double.
And I still have to file
my shift report.
Man, you’re
off the clock.
You’d have never passed up
a wild night back at A&amp;M.
Well, I guess I grew up.
Too bad, check that out.
Enjoy.
You must really love
your job, man.
Ladies...
Here you go. Thanks, man.
WOMAN:
Get your hands
off me!
MAN:
Kristy, you’re not
going anywhere.
You got that?
Come on.
Relax a little bit.
Settle down.
Kristy? Kristy!
You don’t
own me, Jack.
Nobody does.
Hey.
Back off.
Hey, just mind
your own business.
Nick.
I know him.
He’s a cop.
A crime scene investigator.
Nick, tell him
to leave me alone.
Nobody tells me
to do anything...
Hey, are we going
to have a problem?
No, officer, we’re not
going to have a problem.
I’ll see you
around, baby.
You okay?
Yeah.
Yeah, I’m fine.
That was good
timing. Thanks.
I suppose you need a ride.
Do you mind?
No.
Come on.
Thanks.
WOMAN:
Seems like every time
we run into each other
I’m getting into trouble.
Not that it’s any
of my business
but maybe you should think
about changing careers.
Not every john
is like that guy.
Besides, I’m
making a change.
I’m going back
to school.
Yeah?
I’ve always wanted to study
communications.
I’m good with people.
That’s good.
You think so?
Yeah, I do.
Well, I’m going
to go inside now.
Unless, of course, you’d like
to come in for a drink.
I don’t think
that’d be a good idea.
Come on.
Just ’cause you’re
a crime scene analyst
you don’t have
to analyze everything.
( laughs )
WILLOWS:
"FP."
MAN:
Mr. Grissom.
Oh, uh...
Hi, I’ve...
I’ve, um, I’ve seen you
on TV before.
I admire your work.
Well, thank you.
And your name is...?
Dominic.
Uh, "i-c" rather than with
the "i-c-k"... uh, Kretzker.
I’m the, uh, Hansen
Building Security Detail.
Did somebody from Homicide
talk to you yet?
Yeah, as a matter
of fact, they said
that I was going
to be talking to you.
Because, well, we are...
you know, we’re both
in law enforcement, and...
Right.
Did you know the victim--
the other security guard?
Oh, yeah, he was one
of my best buddies.
As a matter of fact, you know,
two minutes’ difference
it would’ve been my face
all over the news
instead of his, right?
Would you, uh, like
to be on the news?
Yeah.
I mean... only if I
could help people, yes.
No, no.
I know what you’re thinking.
Uh, you know,
my building blows up
I’m over at Arby’s sucking
down some extra sauce.
You know, how could I want
to help people, right?
Well, I mean, realistically,
what could you have done?
Well, I know a lot about bombs.
You know, pipe,
power, powder.
The three "Ps"
of mass destruction.
Huh.
Dominic...
with an "i-c,"
not "i-c-k"...
Yes sir?
Would you be interested
in helping me
in my investigation?
Are you serious?
Yeah, yes, sir.
I’ll be honored, sir.
Oh.
But we can’t tell anybody
on the day shift, though
because they’re going
to get real jealous.
That’s good thinking.
Would you excuse me
a minute?
Yes.
Keep an eye
on that guy.
Oh, yes!
Well, we got
a live one out there.
I got a cop babysitting him.
How are you doing?
Well, are his
initials "FP"?
No, Dominic
Kretzker, why?
I found this near
the point of origin.
Whoever did this
is playing with us.
Or he wants to get caught.
Hey, it’s me.
You in the shower?
What are you doing?
Anyway, if you check
your messages
I don’t have to work till later.
So I thought since
you’re between careers
you might want to grab a late...
breakfast.
Hey, Nick, what’s up?
Not a lot.
What’s... what’s going on?
It’s a 4-19.
Dead prostitute.
Who’s the decedent?
Kristine Marie Hopkins.
Day shift’s
got it covered.
You all right?
Yeah, I must’ve, uh...
I must’ve got my wires crossed.
I’ll see you.
All right, man.
All right, you cram this thing
here with gunpowder, all right?
Then you cap it here,
and you cap it here.
Now, the grains inside,
all right...
they’re going to ignite
and they’re gonna
cause smoke.
Lots and lots of smoke.
Now, the problem is
is all this smoke here, man,
it’s got nowhere to go.
Okay, it starts
cooking, and then...
Bob’s your uncle... Boom!
Grissom was right:
you do know a lot about bombs.
How’d you learn so much?
Oh, they don’t teach
this stuff at universities.
You know, this is all
trial and error.
So what, you just, uh,
blow up bombs and study them?
Yeah. Yeah...
( knocking )
Margaret Finn, Public Defender.
Cease and desist
any conversation
with my client.
I’ve been assigned to you.
Guess the PD was thinking
of all the lawsuits
Richard Jewell brought
when he was wrongfully accused.
Someone died in
that office building.
Ma’am, you seem like
a very nice person
but these people--they’ve been
very, very good to me.
I’m sure they have.
Dominic, I think
you should roll
with your attorney.
Thanks for your
help, though.
All right.
I’ll see you guys later.
Listen, do me a favor.
Will you tell Grissom
that if he needs me
just call me
at home, okay?
All right.
Let’s roll.
So all this stuff
is from a five-meter radius
of the point of origin?
Yep.
How could the victim possibly
have been in one piece?
Vacuum effect.
The air is being
pushed out so fast...
and the bomb detonates...
there’s a calm at the center...
Calm, huh?
Well, except for
when he lost his ears.
Did you figure out
what this "FP" stands for?
I ran it through
ATF’s bomb database.
No profile.
So our bomber’s a newbie.
Does he fit Grissom’s wack job
from the bomb site?
Dominic the security guard?
Ah, it’s too soon to tell.
I found something interesting.
What is it?
Looks like a balance
wheel from a clock.
Bomb was time-delayed.
This is a piece
of the timing device.
What about the orange stuff?
Heat of the explosion
must’ve melted whatever it is
all around the wheel.
So Sara?
So what’s orange
and melts?
I would have
to investigate that.
Thank you.
Hey, guys.
Can I steal you for a minute?
I thought this
was your day off.
We’re kind of busy here, Nick.
Yeah, I know, and I’m sorry,
but I don’t think this can wait.
Okay.
You told me
you weren’t dating her.
I wasn’t till last night
after I broke up her fight
with this guy, uh... Jack.
And Ecklie’s at her house now.
Yeah, and I can tell you
what he’s going to find.
My fingerprints, my DNA.
What were you thinking, Nicky?
I wasn’t.
We had a connection, you know?
Chemistry thing, I guess.
She was irresistible, man.
I took off around 4:00.
Ecklie’s going to be
all over this.
( knocking )
Hey, Nick...
I’m sorry to hear
about your friend.
Who told you?
Word travels.
It was the day shift coroner.
So people know
I was with Kristy last night?
Not yet.
Maybe I should
just go to Ecklie
and tell him I was there.
When you’re a suspect
and you’re innocent,
you keep your mouth shut.
I’ll talk to Ecklie.
Bad idea.
You and Ecklie...
oil and water.
Just let me
get into it.
I can’t just sit here.
Okay, go for a walk.
Maybe you’ll accidentally
bump into your guy, "Jack?"
Yeah.
I.D. him, but
don’t approach him.
Okay.
If Nick’s arrested
it’s not going to matter
that he’s cleared later.
No, it’s an automatic dismissal.
25-year-old female Caucasian.
Liver temp’s indicating
time of death at 0600.
Petichial hemorrhaging,
cyanotic tongue.
( door opens )
Can I help you, Catherine?
I just want
to see the body, David.
Unless I’m mistaken,
this is Ecklie’s case.
Eyes, no hands.
Look at those ligature marks.
Petichials...
blue tongue, the works.
Raccoon eyes
excoriation around the neck.
She didn’t give up easy.
Struggled and strangled.
Ecklie find the murder weapon?
I only deal with bodies.
Did you check for fingerprints
on the body?
Not yet.
Half-life
of fingerprints on flesh
they’re disappearing
as we speak.
Catherine, I like Nick, too.
I know you’re here for him.
But what if I lift
his prints from her?
Then that’s what you report.
Evidence, Doc... all we got.
( ticking )
( alarm ringing )
Hey.
Could you find that
and turn it off, please?
( alarm ringing )
( alarm stops )
Find the clock
our guy used?
Not yet.
This is a good choice.
According
to the Bomb Data Center
which has a record
of every component
used in any bomb--
from Ted Kaczynski
to teenage boys
playing with fireworks--
the most recent
timing device of choice
is made by TimeTell Snoozewell,
$10.99 at any
local drugstore.
You’ve spoiled
all my fun.
Gris, can I get clear
on something here?
Anything’s possible.
Catherine gave me
this "FP" which was part
of the Hansen bomb
and I’m supposed to figure out
what tool the bomber used
to engrave it.
You isolate the tool,
and then we trace it.
Yeah, but he could’ve used
any number of things
to initial it.
I mean, a screwdriver,
a drill bit, a box cutter.
It’s the same
as guns...
we eliminate them one at a time.
What are you guys doing?
We’re going to go
blow up some bombs.
Oh, I definitely got the wrong
end of this investigation.
Alas.
Poor Warrick.
( buzzing )
( knocking )
Oh, hey, uh
Conrad, Grissom’s in the field.
I need to speak
with him.
And I need to speak with you...
about Nick Stokes.
Well, let me guess...
about his involvement
with a dead hooker?
Come on.
The hooker was a person.
Her name was Kristy Hopkins.
I realize that. Thank you.
I just came from the lab.
His prints were all over
Kristy Hopkins’ house.
Let’s see, wine glass...
oh, bedside table.
How’s it going, Cath?
Nick, I don’t think that you
guys should be talking.
It’s no big deal.
What’s up, Ecklie?
I need a DNA sample
from you, Nick.
I assume
you’re trying
to prove Kristy Hopkins and I
were sexually active last night.
We found a condom, used.
And my DNA will match,
no warrant necessary.
And I have something
else for you.
I got this off a valet
surveillance tape.
A license plate number?
Vehicle belongs
to Jack Willman.
Had a fight with Kristy Hopkins
outside the Orpheus
last night around midnight.
Well, I’ll look into it
but come on,
your fingerprints, your DNA
that’s what’s
going into evidence.
You just love that, don’t you?
You think I want to believe
that a CSI could commit murder?
Hell, I don’t even want
to believe that a CSI
could sleep with a hooker.
You know what?
Nick’s private life...
Is no longer private.
Catherine, I’m sorry
if you guys don’t like
where the evidence
is pointing.
But show me otherwise,
tell me I’m wrong.
In the meantime,
my hands are tied.
I have protocol to follow.
I hate that guy.
Okay, look, I’m going
to get O’Riley
to track down this Jack
guy for questioning.
But I am out on a limb
for you here, Nick.
Just don’t make it harder
with Ecklie, okay?
Yeah.
GRISSOM:
We find the bomber
by understanding the bomb.
Fortunately, Catherine figured
out the exterior container.
Aluminum briefcase.
And we know
the timing device.
Snoozewell.
And the propellant.
Black gunpowder.
So the final piece of
the bomber’s signature?
Identify the pipe
containing the powder.
Three bombs,
scaled down five-to-one
three different metal pipes.
Different metals
fly different distances
when the same force is applied.
Number one is
a plumber’s ex-flow pipe.
Number two is
an inflow pipe
which is thinner.
Number three
is galvanized steel
which is the thinnest metal
of them all.
You ready?
Let’s do it, Dan.
Green.
That’s the ex-flow pipe.
Inflow pipe, blue.
Red, the galvanized steel.
Last piece of green: ten feet.
Blue: 16 feet.
Red: 20 feet.
Fragments from
the galvanized steel
traveled the farthest.
20 feet.
Extrapolating five to one
that would be 100 feet.
That’s the outer limit
of visible metal detritus
at the Hansen building.
So the bomb was housed
in a thin container
of galvanized steel.
Like a muffler or a tailpipe.
I’ve seen it before.
It’s a common container
for homemades.
Don’t you love the smell
of sulfur in the afternoon?
You might want to go
and take a tour
of Dominic Kretzker’s house.
I tracked down the sale
of Snoozewell clocks.
926 credit card purchases
in the last three months
in Clark County.
Seven to Dominic Kretzker
of Prairie Road.
( indistinct police radio
chatter )
Hey, hey.
That your scanner?
Yeah, that’s how I knew
you were coming.
Makes me feel like
I’m part of things.
Mr. Grissom.
What can I do for you guys?
Dominic... this is
the type of device
that was used to set off
the Hansen bomb.
We have proof that
you purchased the same
make of clock.
Yeah, yeah,
I recognize that.
That houses a nice
little detonator.
Want to show us
that clock of yours?
Oh, sure. Come on in.
The place is kind of a mess.
Sorry.
Here.
( straining ):
Here it is.
TimeTell Snoozewell.
$10.99.
Well, you can get it for half
price if you’ve got a coupon.
The timing device
is still intact.
Yeah, ’cause I haven’t
made the bomb yet.
But you have made bombs before,
using parts from this make?
Well, yeah.
Yeah, I blow them out in back
all the time.
I blasted a few of them
a couple months ago.
BRASS:
Hey, look what I found.
Sulfur.
You blow up any bombs recently?
Is this from the Hansen bomb?
Sure is.
You’re keeping a key piece
of evidence
that could nail you?
Hey, that’s sentimental.
Well, that’s cute.
No, I mean, it is.
That’s like, you know,
Waco and Trade Center.
I mean, that’s historical.
I didn’t have a war,
all right?
I’m too flatfooted for the P.D.
and that’s as close to history
as I’m going to get.
I collect souvenirs.
I mean, th-that’s my building,
you know.
I mean... that was my place
of employment, man.
You’re going to be sorry,
talking to my client.
BRASS:
We called you.
We left word.
Dominic, don’t speak.
If I had anything to hide,
I’d hide it.
I’m pretty proud of that
container piece, I’ll tell you.
BRASS:
Well, maybe so
but you’re under arrest.
Put him
in the car.
You-you kidding?
Oh.
( siren approaching )
Cuffs?
BRASS:
Those vultures
never sleep, huh?
Could you do me a favor?
Can you put the jacket
over them?
I don’t want to
be seen like this.
Not on TV.
This is not who I am.
Thanks, partner.
GRISSOM:
I can’t tell whether
he’s brilliant or... nuts.
Sound familiar?
Tell you one thing
if he’s guilty
he’s putting on one hell
of a show.
Polyethylene? Terephtalete?
( clears throat )
You contact her family?
No family to speak of.
Has anyone claimed her?
For burial?
Friend, old roommate?
There’s no one.
City’ll be footing the bill.
No, I’ll pay.
Sure that’s prudent
given the circumstances?
Doc, I’m giving this girl
a proper burial.
I don’t much care
about my career right now.
Someone wants to throw me
in jail for that
so be it.
( cell door closing )
How you doing?
Just kind of using
the current experience
to understand the other side
of law enforcement.
That’s resourceful.
You think I’m guilty, don’t you?
I think the evidence raises
some serious questions
about your involvement.
That is crazy.
I mean, come on.
I’m one of the good guys.
The cops went through my things.
They find anything?
Dominic, you have
an attorney now.
I can’t really talk to you
about the case.
I was here
on another matter
and I thought I’d come by.
You do what I do.
Excuse me?
You don’t just
like, stop by to see someone,
you... make up excuse like
"I’m in the area,
just stopping by."
Wow, you’re just like me.
Except better-looking.
I’ll come by
and see you later, okay?
Okay.
What?
Bad news.
Another Fourth of July.
Where?
Thrift-Right Car Rental
on Flamingo.
Ten minutes ago.
( indistinct police radio
chatter )
BRASS:
So, the manager
was working the lot
when he heard the blast.
Fatality was
on the check-in line
and died on the way
to the hospital.
Anybody report hearing
a noise? Ticking?
No, no one heard anything.
SIDLE:
Ah, it’s not
the firemen
it’s the rain.
This crime scene is trashed.
What do you have?
Form follows function.
They’ve never been able
to make a better one.
Mousetrap.
That orange stuff again.
Someone picks it up,
motion trips the trap,
sets off the timer.
SIDLE:
Which sets off the bomb.
( explosion )
Be right back.
We say nothing
to the media or anybody.
Our bomber’s signature
just got a little more
sophisticated.
Excuse me.
Hi, I’m with the Crime Lab.
I’m sorry, but I have
to take your jacket.
Um... okay.
If it’ll help.
Thanks.
What are you doing?
Polyethylene-terephtalete.
Polyester.
Orange stuff.
GRISSOM:
You’re free to go.
I wanted to tell you
in person.
You mean, you weren’t
just in the neighborhood?
That second bomb--
it wasn’t remote, was it?
Otherwise I’d
still be a suspect.
I can’t discuss it.
So I guess you’re not going to
be needing my expertise anymore.
I mean, investigation-wise.
I knew it was too good
to be true.
Well, proud to have worked
with you, sir.
Dominic... I’m not
a police officer.
I-I-I’m a crime
scene analyst.
Yeah, but we know who
really solves the crimes,
don’t we, sir?
Good luck.
Take care of yourself.
Thank you.
Hey, Dom?
Yeah?
Next time
try not to be quite so trusting.
You don’t need
to be a hero.
I ran priors.
The guy’s got
an ’88 conviction
for sexual assault.
Boy, if I ever get in trouble,
I know which CSI I’m going to.
Let’s watch the show.
How would you characterize
your relationship
with Kristy Hopkins?
Oh, sir, we can
just cut the crap.
I saw him kill Kristy.
I saw everything.
O’RILEY:
Go on.
Well, Kristy and I,
we had words.
I was swinging by her place
to tell her I was sorry
but, uh...
I didn’t expect to see her
with a guy.
They were fighting.
I couldn’t make out
what they were saying
but he was pushing her around
pretty hard.
( arguing )
Could you I.D. this guy?
Yeah.
It was like, Nick something.
Kristy and I bumped into him
at The Orpheus earlier.
O’RILEY:
And you saw him kill her?
Well, I saw him
get violent, but
then I took off.
And you didn’t try
to help the girl?
He’s one of you guys.
He carries a gun.
I’m no hero.
So can I go?
O’RILEY:
Yeah.
The witness
sounds believable.
It’s a load of crap
and you know it.
I was listening.
He seemed credible to me.
Sheriff, you
arrest Nick now
you end his career.
So what can you offer me?
Nothing, except my gut
and ten years of experience.
He didn’t do this.
Ignore the evidence
against Stokes
it looks like special favors
for CSI.
Well, I can’t have that.
Not and keep my post.
So give me 12 hours,
access to the crime scene
and evidence without
filing papers on Nick.
12 hours.
But then we arrest
Mr. Stokes
with all the attendant
documentation.
How you doing, Greg?
Same as you.
Yeah.
Worried about Nick.
I need to see his DNA
from the crime scene.
You have it, right?
A sample from the condom,
yeah.
Popsicled in the freezer.
But, uh, it’s not your case.
Much as I want to help,
no can do.
It’s my case
for the next 12 hours.
Ask the Sheriff.
You know, I would never doubt
your word.
Smart man.
Nick’s little soldiers.
It’s all you.
Thanks, Greg.
WILLOWS:
When did you say
this sample was frozen?
Um, 10:15 a.m.
Why?
These guys are all heads,
no tails.
That’s normal, given
the post-ejaculate time frame.
How is that going
to help Nick?
WILLOWS:
The sperm found
in the condom
was frozen at 10:15 a.m.
It’s all heads, no tails.
I’m not quite up
to speed on the
particulars of...
It takes about seven hours
for bacteria to eat away
at the tails
placing the time of ejaculation
at around 2:00 a.m.
but Kristy’s time of death
was 6:00 a.m.
Well, it suggests a lag
between ejaculation
and Kristy’s murder
but it doesn’t disprove
Nick’s presence
at the time of
the homicide.
You could be
a little more supportive.
I have a new favorite color.
Orange?
The orange
polyester from the bomb
is a match
to the Thrift-Right jacket.
Guess where their regional
headquarters is located.
The Hansen Building.
You bet.
I ran a Lexis search
looking for disgruntled
employees, irate customers
anyone with a grievance
against Thrift-Right.
You get any hits?
Norman Stirling.
Former manager.
How disgruntled?
Let go
last year.
Caused a commotion at H.Q.
Filed lawsuits
against the company.
Guy’s been out of work
ever since.
Sitting around
making bombs.
Norman Stirling?
Yes.
What’s going on?
FP.
What?
You don’t recognize
those initials?
What’s this about?
The bombing of the
Thrift-Right Car Rental.
Hansen Building.
A-A bomb? Are you kidding?
I’ve never even been near
a bomb my entire life.
Well, those orange jackets
over there appear to match
the materials
the bombs were wrapped in.
I used to wear those
to go to work.
BRASS:
You were let go
by Thrift-Right
last year, and lost
a court battle
to get your job back.
BRASS:
In fact, they filed
a TRO against you
for throwing furniture around
their headquarters last July.
I want to call my lawyer.
Good, you can call him
from the car.
He can meet us at the PD.
Take him in.
Come on, let’s go.
Call your mom.
WILLOWS:
Kristy Hopkins was strangled
with this sash.
It’s fingerprint-free,
but the force of the pull
would have scratched
off epithelials
from the killer’s
hands, right?
Abraded, yeah.
And can you
extract DNA from epithelials?
If they’re fresh enough.
GREG:
Okay, epithelials
are an affirmative.
And they’re good to go
for DNA profiling.
I’m just going to need something
to compare it to.
Jack Willman has a prior
for a sexual assault
so his DNA is on file.
Well?
I think that you and I should
head over to the police station.
DNA didn’t pan out, huh?
Never have I seen
such a clean match.
Jack Willman killed her.
( sighing )
Thank you.
Hey...
Hey, I’m just
doing my job.
Besides, if they’d
sent you to jail
I’d get stuck
with all your cases.
( laughs )
Dispatch said
you were looking for me?
Yeah.
I finally matched this "FP."
To this electric etcher.
Now, I made an exemplar.
Boom!
WARRICK:
Identical type of striations.
The manufacturer says
that this etcher is only used
for training purposes.
And it’s only sold in bulk.
It was not sold
to Norman Stirling.
So who bought it?
Las Vegas School District.
I called the district
and we traced it down
to one high school--
Summit High.
Stirling’s son goes there.
BRASS:
Tyler, were you aware
of your father’s lawsuits
against Thrift-Right
Car Rental?
Yeah. It was kind of hard
not to be.
I mean, it’s all him and my mom
talked about for a year.
Until she left.
Do you miss your mother?
I miss our old life.
( quietly ):
Is there something
that we should be talking about?
You know, in private?
You said that’s how corporations
do it--in private.
See, they treated him great
at work, in front of everyone.
And then they let him go
at the end of the day
when no one’s around.
Thirty years of service
and then...
you know, they realized
they could hire two young guys
at half the price.
BRASS:
What does "FP"
stand for?
It was etched into both bombs.
We think you engraved it
with an implement
from your high school
shop class.
"Fair Play."
I used to yell that
around the house
that I was owed fair play.
TYLER:
I mean, they threw him
out like trash.
And you sent them bombs?
You said you wanted
to kill them.
How did you even know
how to do this?
Off the Internet.
Dad, are you mad at me?
I did it for you.
Tyler, did you make
any more bombs?
Where are they?
Where are you keeping them?
Tyler...
if you did this for me...
please tell them where they are.
( man over dispatch )
Victor 9, Victor 9,
report to Summit High School.
Prairie road.
Repeat: Prairie road.
Reported bomb outside
Classroom 22B in Locker 897.
( radio static )
Bomb is trigger-activated
and motion-delayed.
Do not handle.
P.A. SYSTEM:
Students and faculty
and all school personnel
please exit the building
immediately.
Security Detail, let’s go!
I need Classroom 22B.
Second floor!
Where’s 22B?
Come on, people!
Come on, people, don’t run.
All students and faculty
please exit the facilities
immediately.
Get out of my way, people.
Come around me.
( sirens blaring )
Dominic, stop!
Stop right there.
Put it down!
No, it’s all right.
Everyone’s safe.
No, no, no, drop it.
It’s active!
Hi. Just the guy
I wanted to see.
O’Riley.
Tell me why you did it.
I got nothing to
say to you, cowboy.
She was going back to college,
turning her life around
getting out of the business,
and you killed her for it!
Why?
Is that what
she told you?
She was getting out
of the business?
She was going to college
to recruit more girls.
Do you think
I’m going to believe
the john that killed her?
Oh, and you think
I was her client?
I was her pimp.
She was leaving me
to start her own racket.
So wake up. This
isn’t Pretty Woman.
She’s not Julia Roberts.
You’re not Richard Gere.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I guess you’re right.
Because there’s no
happy ending for you.
Twenty-five to life.
WILLOWS:
Get him out of here.
Above the fold.