Previously on CSI:
Congratulations, Nicky, my boy.
You are now
a CSI Level Three.
Whoo!
Mommy?
I couldn’t drive here
fast enough
to tell you how much I love you.
I love you too.
Sara Sidle?
I know who I am.
I think
you’re a little confused.
I just off the phone
with the Sheriff.
He says he wants me
to run the unit.
You’re the boss.
They say I got
to let you go.
I know.
I don’t care
what the book says.
I lost one good person today.
I don’t want
to lose another. Here.
Oh...
( quivering wail )
( screaming )
( distorted male voice ):
Bring $2 million in hundreds
to Charleston and Third
in three hours,
or your wife dies.
Stop me from taking the money--
she still dies.
This guy thinks
it’s some kind of joke
using a voice like that.
He’s altering
his voice, sir,
electronically.
We don’t consider it
a joke at all.
Bring $2 million in hundreds...
You guys have listened
to that tape like, 20 times.
Will somebody please go out
and find my wife?
Mr. Garris, please, sometimes
if you listen closely,
you can hear a lot.
( rewinds tape )
( low frequency buzz )
I don’t hear anything.
Right.
Where do you hear nothing
in Las Vegas?
The desert.
And judging by
what sounds like
a low frequency buzz
in the background,
possibly near power lines.
How’d you hear all that?
I listen.
Brass:
Right, okay,
all right, got it.
I just spoke with the FBI.
They’ll back us up
if we need it,
but we have the handle.
Garris:
Uh, Detective,
wait.
What are my chances here...
...of-of Laura...
f-for Laura?
It’s a three-hour window.
Will somebody
just tell me the truth?
A ransom message
with a short fuse
means that
the victim’s situation
will cause her to expire by
or before
the deadline,
regardless of
what we do.
In a car trunk--
that kind of thing.
It’s a form of passive murder,
if you want to be, uh...
honest
about it.
Then you guys
have got to move.
Grissom:
Mr. Garris,
it’s my experience
that in situations like this,
if you want to go fast,
go slow.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
Get a picture
of the security pad.
Someone touches it
before it’s dusted,
I break their fingers.
Shoot the mirror--
point of disturbance.
The lamp--point
of disturbance...
You’re standing
in my crime scene.
No, you’re in mine.
You’re doing audio?
I wanted that.
I outrank you.
Technicality--
who’d Grissom
hand-pick
to work here?
( chuckles )
Keep telling yourself that.
Get the lights, will you?
Got it.
Shady friends?
No. Laura
surrounds herself
with quality people,
people of real substance.
Has her behavior
changed recently--
drug use, alcohol,
things like that?
No, no, no, nothing like that.
She’s a health nut--
we both are.
Uh-huh.
Look, I’m a rich man.
How do we let this guy know
I’ll pay?
We don’t want
to go there yet.
( sighing )
Nick, tell lab
to do a reverse algorithm
on that tape
and then get it
into enhancement.
Yeah, I know what to tell
the audio guy.
You’ve been a Level Three
for what, two weeks?
I got it
under control.
Swear.
Later.
Cursory call--
looks like a
professional job.
Our guy bypasses
the security system,
surprises the wife
in the back hall,
drags her in here.
She grabs onto
the doorway--
sign of struggle.
No sign of sexual assault.
He’s in, they’re out.
Probably...egress
through those doors.
Excuse me, is my evaluation
interrupting you?
No, no, no.
I barely heard you.
Glad I have a healthy ego.
You find
something interesting there?
Dirt.
You’re so technical,
I can hardly keep up, but...
Oh, sorry, but, uh...
out of context,
it’s...just dirt.
( siren in background )
( sniffing )
Did you just slap on
bad cologne?
I never wear it.
It interferes with the job.
It’s almost sweet.
Hmm.
( sniffing )
Can’t be chloroform.
Halothane, maybe.
We’ll confirm it
in GC mass spec.
"Looks like a professional job,"
I think you said.
Care to amend
your evaluation?
I mean, if the guy
forgets the rag he used
to knock her out,
he can’t be much of a pro.
I keep trying
to be your star pupil.
Sara, that was a seminar.
This is real.
Pebbles, tile--
the front is all concrete.
No dirt.
Context--there is dirt
on the carpeting inside.
In an otherwise
spotless house.
You’re saying kidnapper
tracked the dirt in.
Possible.
As of now,
that’s about all we have, so...
I guess we follow the dirt.
( bag being zipped )
( siren blaring )
Catherine:
How many hit-and-runs
we had this year?
Warrick:
Too many.
One thing I can’t stand
is a punk coward.
My daughter wants
one of these scooters.
Says she’s the only kid
in the world
who doesn’t have one.
You want me
to take this case alone?
You feeling all right, Warrick?
Oh, I’m fine.
I’m...I’m looking
after you.
It’s that thing
with Holly Gribbs.
It’s made me think
of who I am to my partners,
you know?
So this is what, your new leaf?
You keep on busting on me,
you won’t see any kind of leaf.
Hey, relax, I’ll play nice.
Thank you for the offer.
I’m okay.
I can handle this one.
It’d be nice
if this paint transfer
had just one special property.
You want to call it?
Vehicle’s humming
down Rochester.
The vic was on her scooter,
heading eastbound.
Car brakes here,
impact here,
the vic was thrown--
what, 20 meters?
And all we’ve got is some paint
that’s gonna match up
to about 20 million
other vehicles.
Yeah.
Bastard.
Are you ordering me
not to pay the ransom?
It’s a very strong suggestion,
yes.
After you told me she could
already be dead?
I don’t believe you guys.
This is my wife.
I’m paying the ransom.
Look, if you
give up the cash,
the kidnapper has no reason
to communicate with us.
Does anyone on your team
know where Laura is right now?
We have an entire forensics lab
working on this.
Yeah? Something tells me
I’ll see her before you do.
Well, your job
just got harder.
Yeah.
I’ll stay close
to the money.
Grissom:
This dirt has
interesting properties.
The gold flecks--
that’s easy, it’s gold.
The little gray
squiggles?
Cyanide.
Cyanide?
He poisoned her.
No.
Did you know
that Nevada produces 80%
of the country’s gold?
Miners drop cyanide powder
into the dirt
and it draws the gold
to the surface.
And how does
a bug specialist
know so much about dirt?
I had a case five years ago.
We found a skeleton
in an abandoned gold mine.
I thought it was a murder.
Turned out the guy
passed out drunk
and the cyanide leached
into his system.
Gruesome, Grissom.
You know, it’s funny,
but every case
teaches me something
about the next.
So when you said,
"follow the dirt"...?
Gold mine--it’s possible
that’s where he’s got her.
Great, there’s got to be
100 gold mines in Nevada.
True, but how many
are near power lines
within range of the drop zone?
Three.
One, two,
three.
This is your
hit-and-run victim.
Bad thing about this job is,
you stop asking yourself why.
Here’s the bruise
I was telling you about.
You see it?
( girl screams )
Oh, my God.
Plate numbers.
From the license plate
when it impacted her skin.
Looks like a "four"
and a "J."
Yeah.
Not like he left us
any evidence.
Call DMV.
I’ll get them
to cross-check
this partial
within a five-mile radius,
see how many ideas
they come up with.
You’ll have those
pictures for me?
Yep.
I’ll meet you out front.
All right.
Freaky.
Is that what I think it is?
It’s a pack of coyotes.
The sensor picks up
any form of body heat,
two-legged or four-legged.
Captain Brass. Hey.
Geez, you scared me.
Sorry. Sorry.
Grissom told me
to hook up with you.
He says the drop place
will be a crime scene.
We hope.
Come on, give us
something two-legged.
Last mine,
we’ve circled it twice.
Yeah, well, we’ll
circle it again.
Why don’t they
move in on the guy?
Why? ’Cause he’s probably
just walking his dog.
Nick:
Well, he’s been there
five minutes.
Dogs take their time.
What, do you want
to be rushed?
Man on Radio:
Male in a ball cap, 10:00.
Here, kitty, kitty...
Nobody moves, you got that?
Rock solid till my order.
Man: Copy.
What was that?
Go back.
Where?
Grissom:
There. Swing around!
My God, she’s below
the surface.
Okay, let’s land!
Take her down! Down!
Ground team is
right behind us.
I’ll guide them in.
She’s got to be right up here.
Mrs. Garris!
Can you hear us?
We’re with the Las Vegas
Police Department!
( muffled screaming )
Here!
She’s here!
Got something here.
( sirens approaching )
Come on!
Get that end!
Yeah, come over!
Got to get her air!
Give me a pick,
an ax.
Pull it!
Oh, my God.
Somebody get up
behind her.
Okay, we’re gonna
pull her up.
Sara, get me something
to cut this tape.
Are you okay?
You’re gonna
be okay now.
Get this off.
Okay.
You okay?
Never ceases
to amaze me
what people
do to each other.
Transport the box
to the lab for latents.
Hair fibers, get soil...
Victor-18.
Brass, do you hear me?
Brass: Copy.
We got the package
and she’s still alive.
Brass, are you reading me? Over.
Victor-9, affirmative.
Way to go.
Major player
is in our sight.
Will update. Out.
You think that’s him?
You think that’s
our guy right there?
Move on ball cap!
Move, move, move!
( siren blasts )
Police officers, freeze!
Hey, no, I wasn’t stealing
the bag, all right?
Hands on your head.
Down on your knees!
Hold still.
Suspect:
Hey, look at the bag.
It’s not even leather.
Why would I want it?
I can think of about
two million reasons, Tiger.
( distant siren wailing )
( doorbell rings )
Hello.
Can I help you folks?
Mr. Charles Moore?
We’re with the
Las Vegas Crime Lab.
We’d like to talk
to you about your car.
We believe it may
have been involved
in a traffic collision
earlier this evening.
I told the police when they
called, my car was stolen.
That’s why we have
a search warrant, sir...
So that we can look
in your garage.
It--it was an accident.
I saw the girl
and I tried to break,
but I accelerated
by mistake.
I get confused.
I--I shouldn’t have left.
I was wrong.
Is she okay?
She died at the scene.
Oh, my God.
Warrick:
You’re going
to be charged
with manslaughter,
Mr. Moore.
A felony hit-and-run.
Do you have a lawyer?
Catherine, I just
got off the phone
with the traffic guys.
They’ve impounded
Moore’s car.
Should be here
any minute.
Catherine:
Is it me,
or did he give
it up too easy?
Old guy was scared.
Grissom:
You have to see
the birthday present
I got for your daughter.
What’s the rule?
How long do I have to be here
before I start kicking in
for gifts?
When the spirit moves you, Sara.
So, in your case,
I guess, never.
I got one of these
chem labs when I was six.
I almost blew up
the whole house.
I hope you can return it,
’cause, uh, Lindsey
doesn’t want a party.
Yeah, what kid
doesn’t want a party?
My kid.
Nick:
Hey, Catherine
what time’s your
little girl coming by?
She isn’t.
Yeah, but I got her a chem set.
You keep that;
might learn something.
Stop flirting with me.
Cath, really, when’s the party?
What do I have to do--put it
on the bulletin board?
There is no party.
My daughter doesn’t
want a party.
Is everybody clear on that?
( several pagers beeping )
Our car’s here.
The burial box
is in.
The victim’s ready
at Desert Palm.
We’ll play with
these later.
( chuckles insincerely )
Thanks, guys.
No problem.
"Garris Winery."
And you never
saw the person, huh?
He...grabbed me from behind.
There was something
clamped over my mouth.
That’s the last thing
that I remember.
You know how
you got the bruising
around your eye?
I have no idea.
I’m sorry.
I was knocked out.
( shuddering breath )
I just don’t think
I can help you.
She’s been through enough;
can we cut this short?
Sure.
I’d like to get a blood sample
from you, though, if I could.
What for?
You’ve got scratches
on your arm.
If we can find traces
of your blood in Rundle’s truck,
we can match the DNA,
make our case against him
that much stronger.
Come on, Grissom,
you have the guy.
Isn’t that enough?
Yeah, well, we didn’t get
any prints off the duct tape.
Our audio guys are
working on stuff.
Right now, we need
something more concrete
if we want to prove
that he did it.
I want to help, Jack.
Okay, all right.
Whatever it takes
to put this guy behind bars,
I’ll do.
So you want to talk to us,
no lawyer?
Why would I need a lawyer?
Look, I told you,
I didn’t know there was
any money in that bag.
Hit balls at that park
twice a week.
Ask around.
And the fact that you’re
Jack Garris’s trainer?
How does that mean
I kidnapped his wife?
I know the dude.
Yeah.
And the layout
of the guy’s house.
He pays extra for me
to come to him.
You want to explain why
we found your fingerprints
all over the crate
Laura Garris was
buried in?
I... look, unless it was
from Jack’s vineyard,
I don’t know.
Helped him move
some crates
a couple weeks ago
up to his garage.
I can’t believe...
Y-y-you got nothing
to hold me on.
Going once, going twice...
sold...to the man walking
out the front door.
Don’t go too far, pal.
My lawyer’s number.
In case you’d like
to communicate
with me again.
Hey, didn’t I see you
on the news tonight?
The chopper, you were
digging up Jack’s wife?
It’s amazing.
Hope you catch the guy.
Me too.
So?
Ah, kid didn’t give up
a thing...
except the tape that’ll
break the case open.
Did you let him know
you were recording him?
Yeah, the guy has no idea
what you science types
can do with
a little audio tape.
Thank you.
How tall you do you
think Mr. Moore is?
( sighs )
Six feet, I’d say.
Well, old people must love
hugging that steering wheel
’cause this seat is pushed
all the way forward.
Oh!
Oh...
Well, I’m six feet,
and this mirror isn’t
helping me at all.
Start the car.
Why?
Just do it.
( engine starts )
( loud rap music plays )
Mr. Moore was not the last
person to drive this car.
( music continues )
Uh, turn the music off.
This?
Yeah.
It’s good stuff.
Nobody over 19 was
the last person
to drive this car.
( sighs )
Yeah.
Hey, just in time.
We’re giving it
a final run.
Man ( garbled, over computer ):
Bring $2 million in hundreds
to Charleston and Third
in three hours
or your wife dies.
Stop me from taking the money--
she still dies.
This is the end of the same tape
after a reverse algorithmic.
Man ( clearly, over computer ):
Stop me from taking the money--
she still dies.
Sounds like our guy to me.
It is.
Now, ransom tape
against your exemplar.
You got it
loaded up, THD?
Right here.
Rundle:
Look, unless it was from
Jack’s vineyard, I don’t know.
Helped him move some crates
couple weeks ago
up to his garage.
Survey says...
perfect match
to the naked ear.
Now, where’s my spectrograph,
so the defense attorneys
can’t claim that our
alterations were altered?
Right here.
Uh, yellow lines
with the ransom message--
blue’s the interview.
( beeping )
Nick:
There’s something wrong.
There’s just a green line.
That’s ’cause the blue line
is directly on top
of the yellow line,
which makes it green.
It’s a perfect match.
We got our kidnapper.
What do you
do now, Nick?
I’ll call Brass,
tell him to go
pick the guy up.
But you tell Brass
to drag his heels,
’cause you still
got work to do.
Grissom, can you look
at something out back?
Could be big.
Yeah.
Come see me
after you raise Brass.
What’d I do wrong?
I’m not gonna spoil
Grissom’s fun.
This is how he teaches
all you guys.
Does anybody else
drive your car,
Mr. Moore?
I was driving yesterday.
Sir, that doesn’t answer
our question.
Boy:
Pops...
Hey, you okay?
What’s he doing here?
Your grandson is
an approved driver
on your insurance.
We had him pulled out of school.
So, James, you like Mos Def?
Did you hit that girl
with your grandfather’s car?
Pops, let me explain to them.
No.
They should hear what happened.
They’re going to...
from me.
I asked James to drive with me.
I don’t do so good,
night driving.
When I hit that girl,
I got knocked woozy,
and James switched seats
and took over
the wheel...
got me home.
He was worried about me,
not the girl.
One more moving violation,
and they take away my keys.
I’m not saying
good judgment was used,
but that’s what happened.
James, you want to add
anything to that?
No.
That’s how it was.
( sighs )
Will you please
escort Mr. Moore
back to his cell?
Sir.
I’ll come see you
with a lawyer.
Just not
during school hours.
I won’t.
James.
You have family,
someone you can call?
It’s just the two of us.
We can give you
a lift home.
Thanks--no.
I’ll take the bus.
You know that James
was riding solo that night.
Like I know my
middle name.
Well, let’s go
back to the car
and find the proof.
What?
It’s just that we’ve got
so much power in this job,
which we use to get
the bad guys.
Once in a while, I’d like
to use it to help the good guys,
like Mr. Moore and his grandson.
And what, forget about
little Renda Harris?
No...
What I’m saying is that...
putting James away isn’t
gonna bring her back.
Mr. Moore is willing
to do the time.
And the victim’s family
gets closure.
Hey, you don’t think
I’m feeling this?
But we got to follow
the evidence,
even if we don’t like
where it takes us.
It’s the job.
Yeah.
I know it.
Hey, we start making
deals with the Devil
and you don’t get
to walk away.
You understand
what I’m saying?
Yeah.
Momentary lapse.
Grissom:
I want you to find something
new on that tape.
Like what?
We already matched
the guy’s voice.
You know what the defense
attorneys will do with that?
That’s who you’re
up against in the end.
You think I don’t
know that?
Ah, you been second-
guessing me ever since
I got on this case.
People leave us clues, Nick.
They speak to us in
thousands of different ways.
It’s our job to make sure
that we’ve heard
everything they’ve said.
Anything less is
reasonable doubt.
I’ll go back
to the tape.
You any better?
What are you talking about?
Your little
major-minor blow-up
about Lindsey not wanting
a party.
Oh, that.
Yeah.
( sighs )
I’m just afraid that I’m
making her weird, you know?
No.
I work 24/7.
I have no time
for my friends.
My daughter rarely
sees me having any fun,
and all of a sudden,
she doesn’t want a party.
And that’s because of you?
Yes, I’m her mother.
She mimics me.
Well, then
she’ll be fine.
I mean, look at you.
You’re just saying that
to make me feel better.
Yeah.
Hey, Grissom...
could you come tape me up?
I love my work.
It shows.
( tape rips )
So you found Laura’s
hairs here...
passenger side,
front seat?
Right, not in the back.
Which made me ask,
what kind of a kidnapper
puts a woman bound
and unconscious
in the front seat?
The back of my arm isn’t
touching the sheepskin, see?
Yeah, so?
But there is sheepskin fiber
on the back of Laura’s sleeve.
That tells us Laura sat back
like a normal person would.
Cut me, Mick.
Like this.
So she wasn’t bound at all?
Correct.
But would a kidnapper risk
putting an unconscious woman
in the front seat
of his car, even unbound?
Answer is usually
in the question--
you taught me that.
So was she unconscious?
We found halothane on the patio.
Halothane knocks you out,
if you take it.
So you’re saying she never
inhaled the halothane?
Proof would be in her blood.
Halothane stays in the system
up to 48 hours.
How pleased am I that I got
a sample of
her blood?
So you can go check at the lab,
see how it turned out.
Damn it, I wanted to carry
the ball over the line.
I know.
We just picked up
our kidnapper, Chip.
What’s up?
His lawyer was at his house
and wants to make a deal.
No deals.
We know what Chip has to offer.
Oh, yeah, Kreskin, what’s that?
Laura Garris.
The victim.
The accomplice.
Hey!
You got something
that can’t wait, Nick?
Yeah, the ransom tape
enhanced--
mega enhanced.
Good. I’ll listen
to it right now.
All right.
Hey, I just...
I didn’t know there was more
to look for, you know?
You did it.
It doesn’t matter
how we got here.
Just remember this.
( horn honks )
( sighs )
When you want evidence,
you can’t find it,
and when you don’t want it,
it’s as big as Dallas.
What you got?
Can you tell
what that is?
My Aunt Bertha could tell,
and she’s legally blind.
You want to look at my teeth?
What kind of investigation
is this?
A forensic investigation, sir.
Fine.
You look at my teeth.
Give them back when you’re done.
( clears throat )
James...
We found a tooth chip
embedded in the
steering wheel
of your
grandfather’s car.
It doesn’t appear to be, uh,
from your grandfather’s teeth.
Warrick:
James...
You have a chipped tooth?
Must be an incisor,
or we would have noticed.
Pops, I’m sorry,
but I got to.
He’s a good boy.
It was an accident.
I make him call...
let me know where he is,
especially when he’s out
after dark.
( rap music playing )
Hey, Pops, it’s me.
Tips were good.
Hey, I thought
I’d go check out
a movie over at the Plex.
Okay.
See you later.
( brakes screeching )
( screams )
He drove straight home
and wanted me to go
to the police station with him.
I didn’t know that
little girl was dead.
I swear.
I didn’t know what to do.
I knew Pops would know.
I wouldn’t let him
turn himself in.
That was my decision.
Boy’s going places,
college...
He’s got a real future.
I’m very sorry, Mr. Moore.
James, I’m afraid
you’re gonna have to be
taken into custody.
Miss, please, now, I’m willing
to serve his time.
I know you are,
Mr. Moore.
We can’t let
you do that.
I made him cover it up.
That was my decision.
He can explain all that
to court.
I’ll be a witness.
We both will.
Hey...why don’t you
run on home?
I’ll handle this.
Is this more of
your new leaf?
Your daughter
gets out of school
in a half hour, right?
On her birthday.
Why do you want to pick
a fight with me now?
I owe you.
Don’t think I won’t collect.
Grateful Dead CD?
Who’s dead?
No halothane in
Laura Garris’ blood,
which proves she
was never knocked out.
She went willingly.
She and Chip
faked her kidnapping,
which, of course,
makes no sense at all.
Because she ended up
under ground in a box.
With a black eye.
Any theories?
Greed.
That’s ridiculous.
I didn’t even
know Chip Rundle
except that he’s
Jack’s trainer.
But you became
pretty good friends, didn’t you?
No.
Jack...no.
I believe my wife.
Thing is, Jack,
I tend not to believe people.
People lie.
The evidence doesn’t lie.
Sidle:
You and Chip
made a plan
to run away together
with your
hard-earned millions, Jack.
Divorce--just
too long and messy.
Anyway, the plan
was surprisingly
well thought out.
Don’t move.
Ooh...
( both chuckling )
Go on, say it.
No, no!
Say it!
Chet:
What?
Say the words.
I love you.
Put this on.
A lot of it.
You were in, you were out.
Oh, and you dropped
that halothane rag
to make sure we’d find it
and know you were unconscious--
a real victim.
Jack, all due respect,
she’s anything but.
Oh, really?
Then how did I end up
buried alive, scared to death?
We’re getting
to that.
You and Chip drove
out of town,
she sat in the front seat,
unbound, fully conscious.
They stopped
at a roadside phone.
Chipper called in
the ransom message
and I think you were still
in the truck then, right, Laura?
Whatever. This
is your thing.
Pay attention.
It’s about to become yours.
Grissom:
Then you both drove east
towards Sandfill Mine.
He probably told you
about some little line shack
or something
where you could stay
while he picked up
the ransom money.
But then, all of a sudden,
he pulled over,
probably made some excuse.
Chip...what are we doing?
Switching cars,
covering our tracks.
I got a Jeep up
over this hill.
Where?
I bet right away in your gut
you knew something was up,
and then,
just a few minutes later,
you knew for sure.
( grunts )
That’s when I believe
you got your black eye.
I, uh...
I don’t remember.
And then, finally,
you were unconscious.
He duct-taped your hands
and he buried you.
Guess he figured
why split $2 million
when he can dump you
and have it all.
Laura?
Jack, it’s not true.
I had no part in it.
Audio downloaded everything.
Dubs are queued up.
Grissom:
Let’s listen
to Chip’s message, okay?
Remember, Jack,
when I told you
you could hear a lot
if you listened?
Yeah.
Chip:
Bring $2 million in hundreds
to Charleston and Third
in three hours
\or your wife dies.
Stop me
from taking the money,
she still dies.
I’m sure you all recognize
Chip’s voice unaltered.
Now, one more time
with a slight variation.
Grissom:
It’s amazing what we can do
with the new forensic
audio programs.
Enhance sounds,
isolate them.
Nick:
Heck, we can lift
entire speeches
just to see what’s underneath.
( whooshing )
Grissom:
A car went by
when Chip was on
the phone to you, Jack.
Scared you, didn’t it, Laura?
Thought it might be the police?
Chip:
Bring $2 million
in hundreds to Charleston
and Third in three hours
or your wife dies.
( muffled audio )
Let’s hear it once more
without that annoying car.
Laura:
Chip, hurry up.
( gasps )
You’re my whole life.
Please, Jack.
Your work is your life.
How else do you
think I started
sleeping with Chip
right under your nose?
All right, let’s go, Laura.
Officer has a car
waiting out front.
Just wait, just wait a second.
Grissom, I can help you.
I can get you Chip
not just on this.
He was into
a lot of things--
steroids--he was
into credit cards.
We already have you both
for about 25 years, minimum.
There’s one thing
you didn’t explain in there.
As soon as you dug Laura up,
why didn’t
she turn Chip in?
Self-preservation.
She rats on him,
she rats on herself.
( car door shuts )
( ignition starts )
So did you have
a good day at school?
Yeah.
Three friends
made be birthday cards.
They did?
Well, you have got
some great friends.
So, Lindsey...
how come you didn’t want
to have a party with them?
I see my friends
everyday at school.
I never get to be
alone with you.
Oh... wow...
Well, I’m really glad
to be alone with you too.
I like this more than
you will ever know.
Boy:
Come on, man.
Girl:
I’m coming!
Are you going to
get me one of those
for my birthday?
Uh, maybe when
you’re older.
Like, 40.
Mommy!
Whatee?
That’s not fair.
I know it’s not fair.
Life isn’t fair.
Don’t worry, Pops.
I’ll be okay.
( sighs )
My grandson going to jail
is never okay.
You stay alive in there.
You hear me?
You too.
Don’t be going downhill.
( metal door thuds )
Hold on.
James...
The first couple days
are going to be the toughest.
Here.
Here’s my cell number.
If you run into
any problems,
you call me.
I’ll be right there.
All right?
Keep your head up.
You didn’t have
to do that--
give James your number.
I’ve seen other law enforcement
people in my day...
"My day."
Reminds me of
my grandmother.
Yeah, I gave her a lot
of rough nights too.
She used to call me
her "work in progress."
Yeah. Well...
she did something right.
Maybe.