Woman ( screaming ):
Help me!
Help me! Somebody, please!
Please...
Oh, God! Somebody help me!
( sobbing )
Please!
Help me!
( indistinct radio
transmissions )
Hey.
Heads up. The press
is gonna be
all over this one.
Did the count change
since you called me?
Four dead: mother, father,
two teenage boys.
The sisters were luckier.
Teen girl heard a noise,
hid in the closet.
Alerted the neighbors
after all the shouting
was done.
Younger sister's
over there.
They couldn't have killed
their father tag team--
soaking wet.
What's the matter
with your guys?
They've been inside.
( sighs )
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
Put your equipment down, son.
Put these on.
I'm going to do
a preliminary
walk-through.
You're going
to take my notes.
Don't touch that!
I want everything exactly
the way it was.
The air smells like copper.
Lots of blood.
Breathe through your mouth.
Yes, sir.
Male Caucasian
approximately 40 years old
lying in a pool of blood.
No drag marks.
Body does not appear
to have been moved.
Multiple stab wounds
to the back and neck.
Looks like a single-edged blade.
Force to such a degree
that the left and right
internal jugular veins
have been transected.
Head faces west.
Feet pointing east
Approximately two feet
from the north wall
one foot from the south.
C-Could you take your own notes?
I think that I'm
going to be sick.
I've got it.
Go get some fresh air.
I heard on the scanner.
Quadruple.
Figured you might need a hand.
You don't sleep, do you?
Mm.
Blood swirl
on the wall.
Are you thinking cult?
Manson?
Somebody left a message.
I need to see the rest of it.
Female Caucasian.
Appears to be
one stab wound to the throat.
Transection of left and right
carotid arteries
with exsanguinating hemorrhage.
No defense marks.
Cursory opinion:
She was killed in her sleep.
( dripping )
Do you feel this?
Her soul's still in the room.
There's something else.
You want a barf bag?
I want the paramedics
that were in this house
back here immediately.
Police escort.
Get them on this
front lawn now.
You'd think I work for you
instead the other
way around.
Call dispatch.
You tell my entire
graveyard shift
that I want them
here A.S.A.P.
All of them,
no exceptions.
Sara, those photos--
blown up times ten.
Tell the lab that we need
every forensics tool
available to us here
right away.
This is the only crime scene
in Las Vegas tonight.
Yes, sir.
The fear in this neighborhood
just south
of Las Vegas Boulevard
is almost palpable.
Scott Collins, his wife and
two sons were brutally murdered
in their beds.
Authorities thus far have
offered no comment
fueling the fears
of the neighbors
that a killer is on the lose.
It's okay.
We'll give you clothes.
The lab guys just want
to see yours.
Sergeant, may I?
( sobbing )
Tina...
I'm very sorry about
what happened to you tonight.
But everything we take
from your house
can help us find out
what happened to your family.
When can I be
with my sister?
She's so scared.
Soon.
Detective.
Hi.
Is your name Brenda?
I'm trying to find out
who hurt your family.
Do you think you could help me?
Did anyone come into your room
tonight?
Through the door?
Through the window maybe?
Okay.
( softly ):
The buffalo.
The buffalo?
Who's the buffalo?
Brenda?
First rule for
this crime scene:
do not do
any interviews.
Second rule: don't talk
to the sheriff either.
Media have it right?
Four dead?
The killer was here
not two hours ago.
He left part
of himself behind.
Catherine, I need
you inside, mapping
and blood samples.
You got it.
Nick, Warrick-- the perimeter.
I want to know how he got here
how he got in, how he got out,
and how he left.
I'll take the back.
You got the front?
You got it.
Hey, O'Riley,
Grissom wants
to see you.
They said you were
looking for me.
Hey, stop! Evidence!
We're going to
hug the wall?
This is the only room
with no blood in it.
There's nothing
to disturb.
You guys will never get it,
will you?
Grissom:
Knife drawer.
One missing.
It's the only drawer open.
The killer knew
where they were going.
I think the suspect's
been in this house before.
And this is the first place
they stopped tonight.
Good. Linoleum.
The best surface.
Best surface for what?
O'Riley:
You guys got some toys...
It's not a toy, O'Riley.
It's an Electrostatic
Dust Print Lifter.
Okay...
Like a supercharged
lint remover.
Only it lifts footprints.
Possibly our killer's.
We did everything
by the book, sir.
Relax. I just want
to know where you
walked in the house
and who you
touched in there.
Well, we did use the main entry,
and up the stairs.
But once we saw the husband,
we grabbed the walls.
I felt the pulses in each room.
Once I found they were dead,
we booked.
Show me the bottom
of your shoe.
Now yours.
You fellows were both
in the kitchen.
We didn't see bodies
in there
so I didn't think twice
about walking on the surface.
All right. Yours
are the only clean
prints I found.
Thanks.
You can go back to work.
News bim's waiting for you.
Thinks you have
an "interesting look."
Newswoman:
Any truth to the rumor
that a cult may have
committed these crimes?
I don't know that.
But you wouldn't rule it out?
I don't rule anything out.
Sheriff:
Grissom.
Sheriff?
The Mayor has
already called.
So what have you got?
Nothing.
I'm not asking you
to lay out your whole case.
Just give me something
I can run with.
I have got to feed the press
and defuse the panic.
As soon as I have something,
you'll have something.
Here's a thought.
Why don't you try
being more like Ecklie?
Maybe we need him
and his day shift crew
on this case with you.
I could speak volumes
about Conrad Ecklie
but I have a crime scene
to process
so... you'll have to excuse me.
Sheriff, can you tell me
what went on inside?
Let me assure everyone
that the situation
is well under control.
You want me inside?
I need you
to transport
the little girl
to the police department.
Brass is waiting for you.
You're kidding me?
Right?
I'm a taxi service
on the biggest case of the year?
Sara...
I need one of us
with that little girl.
I want to see all of
their personal property.
Clothes, jewelry,
whatever they have on.
If there's something
under all this blood
you'll be the first to know.
This kid should be out
playing Pop Warner.
Catherine:
I got the blood samples
on the way to the lab.
Good.
You buy this cult thing?
You mean the blood swirls
next to the father's body
in the boys' room?
I studied pictures
of the Manson murders.
This isn't butter.
It's imitation.
What's your take?
Whoever did it
killed the mother first.
In her sleep, quick.
Explains why the
blood is confined
to the bed and
the floor under it.
Husband woke up.
Ran to protect his kids.
The killer nicked him here.
and then finished him off
down the hall.
Gave his life for
the little girl.
There should be
more blood.
Yeah.
It's a hole.
We need to fill it.
If we start from the inside
and fan out
whoever's left at the scene...
The first suspect.
The teen daughter?
She'd need help.
Maybe a boyfriend?
I wonder if they
call him Buffalo.
Sara:
Catherine's the one
with the kid, not me.
And O'Riley was
primary on this
till it passed over
to me, big deal.
What about Family Services?
Can't they take her?
They sent their
case worker
over to the hospital
so meet her there
with the kid.
I am not good with kids.
Look, I'm not asking
you to adopt her
just take her over
to Sunrise for a
psych eval, will you?
That's very pretty.
Or not.
Want to go for another ride?
I'll take that as a "yes."
Tina, do you know what time
you heard those noises?
No, but they sounded
like footsteps
coming from the kitchen.
And that's when you
hid in the closet?
Yes.
Does your family normally
keep the doors locked at night?
I don't know.
My dad checks the house
at night.
It's always been
a safe neighborhood.
Tina...
Do you...
go out with anyone special?
I hook up with different guys.
No one special.
Are any of them...
called Buffalo?
Buffalo?
No.
How about this, Tina?
You live in a house
with six people, right?
You must be used to hearing
footsteps in the kitchen
late at night.
Why so scared last night?
I know my brothers' footsteps.
And my dad's.
These were different.
Nick:
How do you know it's fresh?
I checked the
sprinkler system.
It goes off every night
at 0200.
And paramedics
pronounced at 0240.
So somebody came
out of the house
and got on what looks
to be a step down
from a motorcycle
and drove it
across the lawn.
And I bet he dropped
the bidi I found
in the back on the way out.
Bidi?
Hand-rolled cigarettes?
Probably a teenager.
They're always taking shortcuts.
How's that hand?
Hmm?
I saw you beating
up the door
a little while ago.
You all right?
Yeah. It's cool.
I'll see you back at the lab.
Sara:
Hey, Brenda.
One of you
with Family Services?
I am. Connie Bellvue.
Doctor:
Brenda's fine
but I'd like her
to have a consult.
I've paged
the psychiatric resident.
He should be here
within the hour.
Thanks. I'll take
it from here.
What's the head exam for?
I said...
we'll take it
from here.
Look, if there's
any forensic evidence
found during this exam,
I need to be there.
It's already going
to be tense.
Go back to
your crime lab.
I'll keep you posted.
It's okay, Brenda.
I'm not leaving you.
( thud )
Damn. That you, Warrick?
You need to tell somebody
when you're cutting the lights.
What, are you working
for OSHA now?
Grissom, you remember
those tire treads
I found on the
front lawn?
Well, I ran them
through the FBI register
and they belong to
a '93 Honda scooter.
That's good.
I DMV'd it.
A kid four blocks
away from the scene
owns the same make.
That's very good.
I might've
just blown open the case
and all you give me
is a "that's very good"?
If your whole family
was murdered
wouldn't you run to them
to see if they were still alive?
Yeah.
This is a Lady Macbeth.
Lady Macbeth?
"Out, out, damn spot."
There's not a trace
of blood
on the teen daughter's clothing.
Not a spot.
Linds?
Lindsey?
Lindsey...
Lindsey,
hi, honey!
Mommy, hi!
Oh, am I glad
to see you.
Daddy came to ballet tonight.
I know. I was
just there.
Your teacher told me
Daddy came to pick you up.
Oh, you feel so good.
Ed... I'm working
this quadruple.
Time got away from me.
I apologize.
I figured
that's probably what it was.
When they couldn't reach you,
they called me.
Yeah, thank you,
I really, really...
Cath, Cath, Cath...
She's my kid too, okay?
All right?
Yeah.
Oh...
So, the case is bad?
I saw it on the news.
Hey...
are you hungry?
I made pancakes.
You made pancakes?
Mm-hmm.
For dinner?
Yeah.
( beeper sounding )
That would be Grissom.
How is your boyfriend?
Ed.
( phone ringing )
Yeah.
Grissom, it's me.
I need you back here right away.
The Collins case is busting out.
Okay, I'll be
right there.
Just let me throw on
some clean clothes.
Please do.
Eddie...
She's going to ask
where you are.
She always does.
Hey, Ecklie.
I just got off the phone
with the Sheriff.
He wants results, Gil.
He should go to
a sports book.
I hear the Stardust is good.
He should go to his first team--
my team.
Teams? I didn't know this
was a competition.
Well, it is,
and my crew usually wins.
Really?
Didn't graveyard beat day shift
in softball last summer?
You know,
you can joke all you want.
It's your ass
on the line.
I think it was 14-3.
Like I said,
it's all about results
and if you don't get them
I will.
The tire treads from the scooter
place you at the scene
of the murders.
Look, I was in Hoover
visiting
my father.
I don't know
about Tina's parents
getting killed.
Tina's parents?
So you know Tina Collins?
Yeah, I know her.
A lot of guys know her.
She's a freak.
You mean sexually?
Yeah.
Where's your scooter now?
I told him I don't know.
It disappeared?
Look, it costs money, right?
And my dad's been slacking
on support
so I bought it with
three other guys.
We share it.
Here's a pen.
Start writing.
Hey, heard you have a suspect.
We got about four
just on the tire prints alone.
Homicide's grabbing them up.
Let's talk about
what else we have.
Tina Collins' pajama top
from the murder scene
without a drop of blood on it.
Hello.
How does she
explain that?
We're about to go ask her.
Nick, what did you find out
about that stuff
you collected
at the back
of the house?
The bidi?
DNA's still processing,
but Tina said
nobody in the family smoked.
So a non-family member
was out there.
Bidi? Bidi?
I thought you found
a cigarette and a match
behind the house.
Well, it's just like
a cigarette.
Kids smoke them.
They think there's less
carbon monoxide.
What did you find out
about the psych exam
on the little girl?
The shrink says the kid
is in a catatonic state
from a trauma.
I could've
told you that.
But she did respond
to the name "Buffalo."
Respond how?
She freaked out.
And... what are you
doing about it now?
Going back to the girl.
I left her in the car.
The windows are cracked.
Give me a little credit.
She's at the hospital.
I don't know why I didn't get
blood on my pajamas.
I just didn't.
But your statement says
that you bent down
and hugged your mother
who was bleeding profusely.
Then you ran out,
tripping over
your father's body
in the upstairs hallway.
But there was no blood on you.
I saw my family dead.
I was scared.
I ran to the neighbors.
That is the truth.
The evidence
is telling a different story.
I did the nasty with her, yeah,
but I didn't kill her family.
Besides
my dad grounded me last week.
I share the scooter
with Oliver
but I was camping last night.
Ask my mom. She made me go.
Church group.
We had sex. So what?
I want a lawyer.
You want a lawyer?
Okay, we'll get you a lawyer.
Investigator Stokes
will stay with you
just in case you remember
where you left
that scooter.
There's no smoking
in here.
Sharon Stone--
Basic Instinct, dude.
Yeah, and I'm not your dude.
This ain't a movie
and Sharon Stone's fine, so...
Matches?
The kid's name is Jesse Overton.
He time-shares
the scooter.
He admits to having sex
with your girl
and he's asking for a lawyer.
I want to get a warrant
and search his house.
I'll keep you posted.
I want to see my sister.
It's not going to happen, Tina.
It's a little too
late to start
coaching her now.
You don't understand.
I need
to speak with her.
She won't speak.
The doctor says
it's from trauma.
What happened, Tina?
Did you catch your boyfriend
killing your family?
Stokes:
Ha-ha-ha.
Houston, we have lift-off.
Let me take a look.
You see how each half
of the match lines up?
I see.
Ah... who broke
the case?
Well, if you believe
what you hear in the halls--
Ecklie.
Ecklie?
Day shift.
Sophisticated criminal, huh?
Hmm?
This is the
getaway vehicle.
Tossing it in his own trash?
What else is new?
Whoa.
Is this
a pair of jeans
under all that blood?
"Yet who would have thought
the old man to have
so much blood in him?"
What was that?
That's Shakespeare.
The lawyer's
pleading him guilty.
Had to, once I put
the murder weapon in his mug.
Man:
Remember--
yes or no.
Got it.
Did Tina Collins
approach you at school
and ask you
to kill her family?
Yes.
Would you lie
about that
to escape the
death penalty?
No.
Did you kill
her family?
Yes.
Did Tina let you
in the front door
the night
of the killings?
2:00. I waited
till it was straight up.
Man:
Yes or no?
Sorry.
Yes.
Man:
Did she already have a knife
for you?
Overton:
No, she let me choose.
Man:
Did you use that knife
to kill Barbara Collins?
Yes.
And Mr. Collins?
And both sons?
Yes.
Was Tina mad
at her parents
for not letting you
see each other?
Yes.
Did Tina Collins tell you
she wanted them dead
so you could see each other?
Yes.
Well, the sick bastard
is on the up and up.
Except your
last question.
Why?
That they killed the family
so they could be together?
Operator says
his respiratory reactions
were inconsistent.
He's lying.
Stokes:
We got them both.
I don't much care
why they did it.
I'm with you there.
I care.
I don't like holes.
What are they hiding?
Did you collect the property
from the Collins family?
Right after the autopsies;
sealed them myself. Why?
I told one of your assistants
to make sure that I got them.
Well, I gave
them to Ecklie.
He said he'd
deliver them to you.
He was down here
on another case.
Ecklie!
I want everything right now.
I've been going over it.
The Collins case
is my shift.
You are completely off base.
What, you're afraid
I'll find something
that might show you up?
Oh, I'm sure if you could
you would have by now.
Where is it?
I don't care
that you got
some pimply-faced
kid to confess.
You kept
the Sheriff
out of the loop.
That's a career-killer, Gil.
That's what so sad, Conrad.
You think of this as a career.
The buffalo.
Yeah?
Sara.
When they examined
the little Collins girl
did they check for sexual abuse?
Sara:
There were no overt signs. Why?
Grissom:
Have some ultraviolet
photographs taken.
This... is a very
special camera.
It can see deep
into your skin.
It can see things
nobody can see.
How about I take a picture
of me first, okay?
See?
It's okay.
Are you ready?
Okay.
Notes on mapping: Collins family
murder, case #00-398.
Intruder killed mother.
Father went to protect
the little girl.
Got nicked by knife.
Killer subdued him
as dad was entering
the little girl's room to...
...save her.
( knocking )
Catherine Willows?
Who's asking?
Ted Goggle.
I'm with Family Services.
Were you working
the Collins case?
You know, your department can't
seem to get things straight.
If you're looking
for the little girl
she's already got a case worker.
I'm inquiring
about your little girl.
My Lindsay? Why?
What are you talking about?
Your husband, Eddie
filed a report
says you neglected
to pick her up
after dance class
last night
that you routinely
neglect her
for your job.
Is this Eddie's idea of a joke?
What, are you in
one of his bands?
I already made a field visit
to your house. Here's the form.
Lindsay seems okay
but there is going to be
an investigation
as to whether there
was parental neglect.
You're on notice.
( phone rings )
Grissom.
It's me.
Something's off on the map.
Off? How?
Uh, I'm looking at dad's blood
in the hall.
I found an interesting drop.
The droplet tells me
that he wasn't running
to the little girl's room.
He was coming out of it?
Yeah.
I filled one of your holes,
Grissom.
He killed the father,
then killed the mother.
The dad's blood
we found in the hallway
must've dripped off
the killer's knife.
Damn it.
Look at all those bruises.
Grissom:
Somebody was all over this kid.
We have forensic evidence
that your father
sexually abused your sister.
We also know...
that he was in
her room the night
of the murders.
How can you tell?
Blood drops.
They fall a
certain way
depending on the motion
of the victim.
Something horrible happened
in that house, didn't it, Tina?
Long before the night
of the murders.
That was the last night
he was going to touch her.
But why your mother
and why your brothers?
Because they should've
protected me.
You?
My father...
I was young.
I learned to deal
but when he went
for my daughter...
Brenda is...?
And who is...
The father?
I was 13...
and nobody noticed
that my clothes
were getting bigger.
Nice, huh?
Brenda may hate me
for what I did...
but I protected her.
I did that much.
Night, guys.
See you, Cath. Good work.
It'll be back to normal
in 24 hours.
Normal'd be nice.