Pilot:
McCarren approach
Las Vegas Nine-Zero-Nine,
30,000.
Request emergency personnel.
Over.
Las Vegas Nine-Zero-Nine,
McCarren Tower.
Specify request. Over.
Negative, McCarren.
Advise on runway.
Las Vegas Nine-Zero-Nine
cleared
for V-O-R Runway
One-Five approach.
Over.
V-O-R Runway One-Five approach.
Roger.
Request Las Vegas Police.
Understand-- "police"?
Roger.
Mommy!
( groaning )
Brass:
Luggage stays in the plane.
We're going to treat this
like a crime scene
until we're told otherwise.
Tim, Sam, talk
to the coach passengers.
See what you can't learn.
All right, look
I'm going to talk
to the first class passengers
that are in the lounge.
Let's meet back there
in a half an hour, all right?
So... dead guy
in first class?
Las Vegas Air.
Always heard it
was a good time.
( clears throat )
Coroner pronounce?
About 30 minutes ago.
Eyewitnesses?
Everyone in the
first class--
Nine passengers,
one flight attendant.
Where are they now?
Sequestered
in the lounge.
According to the flight crew,
the deceased had some sort
of panic attack
and died before
they landed.
Point of disturbance:
cockpit door.
Bloody handprint.
Looks like foot impression.
Ballpark shoe size...
ten to 11.
Deceased found lying
between rows one and two.
What is that, blood?
I want this whole
plane taped off...
nose to tail
and wing to wing.
Oh, it's going to
take a lot of tape.
I've got a dead body,
a crime scene with wings.
Something very wrong
happened in this plane.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
Sheriff?
We've got a whale of an
opportunity here, Gil.
Dead body on an airplane--
F.A.A. has jurisdiction.
But the feds won't be
here till sunrise.
That gives us about 12
hours to be heroes.
I don't follow you.
Well, we either
hand over
the guy who did it
when the feds get here
or we give them
all the glory
while we watch
from the sidelines.
I don't even know if
we have a homicide yet.
First reports indicate...
he had some kind
of an episode.
Give me a little credit.
Even you wouldn't tape off
one of these wide-bodies
unless you knew
you had something.
Arrest would be
good for you.
It would be good for me too,
good for Las Vegas.
You running for mayor?
What about the passengers
in coach?
Did they see anything?
Brass said the curtain was shut.
Flight attendant kept them
separated. They disembarked
through the rear.
What do we know
about the dead guy?
Tony Candlewell, age 30.
Communications company manager
from Atlanta, married...
no record.
So?
What do you think?
Catherine:
I don't know...
but this sure must have looked
scary at 30,000 feet.
Warrick:
All this done by one guy?
Had to be on drugs.
Too much damage for one guy.
So, more than one guy?
What do you think, Gris?
I think we've got ten witnesses
all singing the same song.
The deceased
went berserk.
Unless we find
something else
in the evidence,
that's what happened.
Catherine.
I'll start
the interviews.
Thank you.
Warrick, go with.
Brass has them all assembled
in the lounge.
Assume evidence
on everyone.
Nick, go with the coroner.
Sara and I will work the plane.
This is a mobile crime scene.
It might not be here tomorrow.
Miss, my daughter has
to go to the bathroom.
Okay. I'll see
what I can do.
Thank you.
How are you holding up?
I'm still shaking.
Could I have your attention?
I'm Jim Brass from Homicide.
This is Catherine Willows
and Warrick Brown
from Las Vegas
Criminalistics.
They're here to
gather evidence.
You know you can't keep us here.
Sir, we realize
this is an imposition,
and we apologize for it.
Nobody wants to see you on
your way more than we do.
We'll make this as
quick and painless
as we possibly can.
Man:
Okay.
Nice snow job.
More flies with honey.
Driver's license...
library card...
organ donor card.
Stand-up guy.
He had a family.
Can you imagine getting
that phone call?
What a shame.
David...
It's always a shame.
Man:
I saw him board.
He seemed like
an okay guy.
Here, let me help
you with that.
Oh, thank you.
Thank you very much.
Sure, no problem.
When did you become aware
that there was a problem
in the cabin?
1630 hours, about
35 minutes out.
Shannon asked one
of us to come out
and address an issue
with a passenger.
What's the problem,
Shannon?
Hello.
Do me a favor: Go back to coach.
Make sure no one comes forward.
Thanks.
Come on, it's
been ten minutes!
Sir...
is there some way
we can assist you?
You can help me
open this door.
There are two other
restrooms towards
the rear of the plane.
I paid $1,200 to pee
here, not in coach.
Sir? You need to
take your seat.
How much time did you spend
with him?
Two minutes.
In that time
did you notice anything
that would explain
his behavior?
Was he drunk maybe, or on drugs?
Not as far as I could tell.
A little agitated.
It's not like I haven't seen
this kind of behavior before.
Flying just makes people react
in funny ways.
Is that a meat thermometer?
Digital readout.
Bigger numbers.
98.1.
Guy should be
colder than that.
Body temperature
drops two degrees
in the first hour
after death
then one and a half degrees
for each successive hour.
Well, he's been dead
for two hours.
That would make his temperature
at the time of death...
101.6.
This guy had a fever.
Let's see what
else we've got.
Petecchial hemorrhaging
behind the eyes...
suggesting suffocation
of some sort.
Horseshoe-shaped contusion
on the left side of the neck.
Looks like the heel of a boot.
Oh, I'll buy that-- for now.
Multiple contusions
front and back.
Broken hand.
Well, this guy's a study
in contradictions.
He's got defensive wounds
on his palms
but the scrapes on his knuckles
and the broken hand
indicate aggression.
Grissom:
Dr. Kiera Behrle, 3E.
Emily Behrle, 3F.
Nate Metz, 2C.
Nate Metz.
Put your seat back and tray
table in their upright position.
I don't think so.
Let me guess who
was sitting in 3C.
Tony Candlewell.
The dead guy.
Look, the guy was a real ass.
In what way?
Look, you know why
I fly first class?
Other than the fact
that my company pays for it?
Because I can work.
I have to work.
And he wouldn't let you?
No, he, he, he kept kicking
the back of my seat
with his foot.
You know, like in
a movie theater
when somebody's
kicking your seat?
Imagine that all the way
from Atlanta to Las Vegas.
Catherine:
Are you telling me
this guy was
kicking the back
of your seat
the entire flight?
Maybe not the entire flight.
You know, like, like Dallas
to, to Las Vegas.
Hey, Pele, could you please stop
kicking the back of my seat?
I wasn't doing anything.
You know exactly
what you're doing. Stop it.
What did you do?
I ju... I ignored him.
You know, I punched the seat
a couple times in anger
and that's it.
Look, the guy set me off.
It was either the seat or him.
May I see your hands?
Your knuckles are
pretty banged up.
Blood drops...
away from the
main event.
Maybe that's where
the action started.
Could just be a bloody nose.
Who was sitting in 4B?
Lou Everett.
Lou Everett?
Yeah.
How'd you get
that slice around the chops?
The guy swung at me with a C.D.
Put his finger
in the hole and slashed me.
What guy?
That crazy guy, the psycho.
He was out of his mind.
What the hell is
wrong with you?
You know, you owe me
another laptop, pal.
( mumbles )
Hey!
Everett:
Hey, hey.
We're in mid-
flight now, guys.
That's enough.
So what do you think?
Bodily injury...
can I sue a dead man?
I think you need some coffee.
What do you mean?
A few cocktails
on the plane, Lou?
Look, I get nervous when I fly,
so what?
Well, alcohol does
different things
to different people...
at different altitudes.
Hey, I was fine.
He went bananas.
Why don't you just ask...
ask the flight attendant?
So, we were about
35 minutes out...
when he started pressing his
call button over and over.
He was complaining
of a headache.
And did you
give him anything?
Yeah, I gave him
a packet of aspirin
and he popped it
dry, no water.
Catherine:
And, as far
as you know...
did he complain
of a headache
when he boarded?
No.
So what made the worm turn?
Look, I've been flying
for ten years.
You know, I have seen it all.
I've seen ferrets in suitcases,
uh, fellatio in first class...
passengers stir-frying
on their tray tables.
I mean...
Who knows why anyone
does anything?
Right.
Well, thanks for your time.
Thank you.
Thanks.
So, any bites?
Nada. You?
If nothing criminal happened
on that flight...
why isn't anybody talking to us?
I'm going to go
out on a limb here...
and say... they're
hiding something?
Then we get to play
hide-and-seek.
I just got off the phone
with Nick.
The coroner did some carving
on our dead guy.
He found intercranial bleeding,
thoracic hemorrhaging
a ruptured spleen.
And for what it's worth
the guy also had a fever.
Did you find anything
interesting?
Well, the guy in 4B was
knocking them back pretty good.
Could be dried blood.
Victim had
defensive wounds on his hand.
Marlene Valdez
was sitting in 2E.
Look at me.
my blouse is ruined.
Just hope it washes out.
We'll get you
a new one.
Marlene:
After I saved
your life, you better.
Brass:
Mr. Valdez
was your life in danger?
Well, you know...
Of course his life
was in danger.
That maniac was
pacing up and down the aisles.
All sweating.
His eyes were glazed.
I was sure he was going
to hijack that plane.
Everyone needs to return
to their seats.
( cups rattling )
Do something.
No, we should just
mind our own business.
Well, if you don't
do something, I will.
Uh... Ex-excuse me, sir.
Uh... why don't you just
take a seat?
( crashing )
Grissom:
The other half
of the wine bottle... from 2E.
So... Marlene in 2E
slashes the victim.
He's bleeding...
where does he go?
The lavatory.
No evidence.
No.
No "patent" evidence.
But if there's blood present
there maybe latent evidence.
One step ahead of you,
every so often.
Thank you.
Well.
Would you hand me
the Christopher Columbus
from my field kit?
Thank you.
( clicks )
I take it that's not blood.
No... but there's protein in it.
Oh, the mile-high club.
That means
the two passengers
may have had no idea what was
going on inside that cabin.
You know, high altitude enhances
the entire sexual experience.
It increases
the euphoria.
Well... it's good.
I don't know if it's that good.
Cite your source.
Hand me a swab, please.
You're avoiding
the question.
"Enhances
sexual experience.
Increases euphoria."
Cite your source.
A magazine.
What magazine?
Applied Psychodynamics
in Forensic Science.
Never heard of it.
I'll get you
a subscription.
Now, cite your source.
Oh... now you want
to go down that route?
Yeah.
Nah. Never mind.
You started it.
Delta Airlines, Flight 1109,
Boston to Miami
March '93, Ken Fuller.
Hazel eyes
organic chem lab TABMOC...
overrated... in...
every aspect.
Could... we...
get back to work, please?
Yeah.
I think your, uh...
firsthand knowledge
and experience
in airplane bathrooms
you should do the swab.
Fine.
Catherine:
And where were you when this was
all going on, Mrs. Finn?
Uh, Mercer, Vicky Mercer.
Um, I was in the bathroom.
In the bathroom?
For how long?
For a while.
I... I really
don't fly very well.
And where was your husband?
Carl:
We're not married.
We just work together.
Right.
Where were you?
I was in my seat.
So, then
you saw what happened?
I had my headphones on.
I was listening
to the air traffic control
channel.
Puts me right out.
Catherine:
So, you... slept
through everything
and you woke up next
to a... dead body.
Basically, yeah.
Handprints.
A stallion.
All right, we're going
to have to change tact here
because what I said
about getting more flies
with honey--
I was wrong.
This is incredible.
Ten people
and no one's talking.
My theory:
the killer is in the group
and the rest of them are afraid.
That guy was wearing
khakis, right?
Yeah.
Fibers drawn from
his pants maybe?
We get anything else
off the clothes?
Nick's working on it.
What have you got?
Well... what you've got here
is a nice Bordeaux
and a Starbuck's blend.
No blood. No saliva.
What about prints?
Uh, well, suede leather's
a tough gig.
It's too porous.
Hey.
Are you losing
your touch there,
Einstein?
Coroner's photos
of the dead guy's back.
Multiple horseshoe-shaped
bruises.
Those are
definitely shoeprints.
Yeah, looks like somebody
stomped on your dead guy.
Hmm.
Bring me the jacket.
If I do heel impressions
I'll need something
to compare it to.
See you in 20.
I need their shoes.
Why you telling me?
Because you're the people
person, right?
Well, why don't you
tell them that?
They're not giving me bupkes.
( crunching )
Please?
Okay, people.
Listen up.
Shoes.
Off.
Now.
( crackling )
It all comes down to shoeprints.
Hey.
Catherine:
Hi.
Looks like a shoe sale.
Uh, Nick sent these
photo comparisons over
from the lab.
Oh.
Excellent.
Max.
That a fit?
Yeah...
( sighs ):
Well, that's it then.
( drops magnifying glass )
Okay, folks.
I've got some good news...
and I've got some bad news.
The good news?
Well, the good news
would be
that seven of you may be...
getting out of here very soon.
What's the bad news?
The bad news is that
three of you may be staying
in Vegas a lot longer
than you planned.
And that would be... Mr. Lou
Everett
Mr. Max Valdez
and Dr. Kiera Behrle.
Would you...
please come with me.
Stevie, keep
these guys on ice.
I'm sorry, ma'am.
This is as far as
your daughter can go
but we'll have an
officer stay with her.
Come on.
It's been a rough night.
Dr. Behrle, we're
going to be asking you
some very sensitive
questions--
questions that I know
that I wouldn't want
my daughter to hear.
Hi.
My name is Jim.
What's your name?
Emily.
Emily. Oh, that's
a great name.
Emily, I'm going
to make you
a deal, okay?
We're going
to borrow your mom
for a little while.
I'll be right back,
sweetie, okay?
Okay.
Okay? And here's
the good part.
You get to borrow
anything you see on me.
Can I borrow your gun?
Well, you know,
my gun...
it's kind of...
it's old, and
it's heavy and...
and it's stuck there.
Anything else?
How about your badge?
You got a deal,
and you know what?
This is the best thing.
You know why?
Because anyone gives
you any trouble
all you got to do is...
flash this.
There you go.
So, were you scared?
Did you see what happened?
Okay. Okay.
It's okay.
Sweet kid-- Emily.
Uh, so, Dr. Behrle...
how long have you been
a physician?
I prefer surgeon.
Mm, okay.
I've been practicing
for 11 years.
And what was the nature
of your visit to, uh...
to Las Vegas?
Emily. She wanted to see
the white tigers.
How did you get that black eye?
I caught it during the ruckus.
The price you pay
for being a Good Samaritan.
Okay.
I'm, uh...
just a little confused.
Your heel impressions
were found on the back
of the victim's suede jacket.
That's a little aggressive
for a Good Samaritan.
Man:
No! No!
Hey, stop it!
Oh...
Get out of the way.
Get out of the way!
Give him some air. Sir?
One, two
three...
One, two...
If he had been in my ER
I might have been able
to save him
but at 30,000 feet,
there's only so much you can do.
Look...
I did what I could.
And you're satisfied
with that?
Why?
Because I'm a doctor
I'm responsible
for what happened on that plane?
What did happen?
I protected my daughter
and I tried to save
a guy's life.
And yes, I'm satisfied
with that.
Well, you've seen Cops
the TV show,
so you know our game.
The first one to talk
gets to make a deal.
I don't need a deal.
No?
Well, maybe your daughter Emily
needs you to take one.
Grissom:
Mm-hmm.
Right.
Makes sense.
Okay.
Thanks, Catherine.
We have a ping-pong ball.
We just need
to find the paddles.
Where are they?
Probably
in the first compartment.
The doctor in 3E
told Catherine
that she performed CPR
on the victim.
Check the inside of the paddles.
See if there's any bio gel
on them.
These look like
they weren't even used.
There was more lubricant
in the bathroom.
It's pretty negligent
for a doctor.
She's got to know
every commercial airline
carries
defib paddles.
Yeah, and if she didn't know,
the flight attendant sure did.
By the time I thought
to grab the defibrillator
he was already dead.
But you are trained
to use the paddles
in the event
of an emergency
and this was an
emergency situation.
Yes, but I'm trained to use them
when a man is having
cardiac arrest in his seat
not flopping around
in the aisle.
So, whatever it was
he was going through
it didn't look a heart attack.
Look, I'm going to be honest
with you.
I was scared.
I mean...
I thought this guy
was going to take us all down.
All right, everyone
needs to return
to their seats.
I've got to get off!
( yelling )
I have to land this plane!
All right, so let me
get this straight.
2F is on the floor.
His wife is in the aisle
brandishing a broken
wine bottle.
What about 1A?
He was closest to the action.
That would be Mr. Cash.
Um, he was in his seat.
Mr. Cash.
I was wondering
when you guys
were going to get
around to asking
me some questions.
So, what did you see?
Not much.
Sir, it's been a long night,
and we don't have much time
before our crime scene
flies away.
I was in my seat.
You were sitting in 1A.
You were sitting ringside.
How do you not see
what happened?
The blind leading the blind.
I'm not
totally blind.
I'm legally blind.
My central visual acuity
is 20/200.
( grunting )
The plane has to land!
We've got to get off
this plane!
Woman:
Get him off the door!
No, no, no!
Brown:
Can you identify
the voices?
( sighs )
First voice.
4B.
Businessman. I could tell
by the way he ordered drinks.
How do you mean?
JW Black, triple
not double.
Second voice, guy in 2F,
kind of far away.
Max.
Third voice?
Third voice, row behind me,
two seats over.
Mr. Dot-com.
Guy must've typed
60 words a minute.
Mr. Cash, you've got to help me.
I've got eight eyewitnesses
with various stories.
I put them all in a mixing bowl,
add eggs, milk
stick it in the oven,
and all I got
is a limp souffle.
We need you to tell us
everything you heard.
From the time the deceased
banged on the cockpit door
to the time he died.
Then listen up.
We need to get off
this plane!
I have to get off
Get him off the door.
Get out of the way.
No!
( grunting, blows landing )
I never heard such silence.
( beeping )
I got two hours till I lose
my crime scene to the feds.
Tell me you have something.
I know what set
this guy off.
That's more than I got.
We know our victim suffered
from intercranial bleeding.
I had that pegged as
possible cause of death
so I crack his skull open,
and what do I find?
A cantaloupe
in a soup can.
Tight fit.
And not from one
or two blows to the head.
He was also running
a high fever
so I tested his spinal fluid.
A normal protein level
is between 15 and 45 milligrams.
Candlewell's was 60.
Did anybody mention
this guy had a headache?
Flight attendant gave him
two aspirin. Why?
He was suffering from
undiagnosed encephalitis.
Swelling of the brain.
It can manifest like
a heart attack: slurred speech
delirium, loss
of consciousness.
You throw in
the altitude
and the air pressure changes
in the cabin
and our guy was probably
out of his mind.
Is that what killed him--
encephalitis?
It wasn't the one thing
that killed him.
Ruptured spleen,
intercranial bleeding
petecchial
hemorrhaging.
And the guy's heart
just stopped beating.
A, B, C, D or all of the above.
Standoff with
the police--
guy gets shot in the chest
runs back into his burning house
inhaling smoke as he goes.
The roof collapses
the air conditioning unit
falls on his head, he dies.
What killed him?
Okay, Vicki Mercer and Carl Finn
I believe
are in the bathroom.
Mile-High Club.
If you ask me,
it's their spouses
that are the dummies.
Emily Behrle is in 3F.
Preston Cash, 1A.
Tony Candlewell, dead guy.
Right there, 3C.
And for now, he's alive
until he's dead.
So, you want to tell us
what we're doing here?
The physical evidence
that Sarah, Nick,
and I collected
is contradicting the
anecdotal statements
that you, Catherine,
and Warrick got
and my money's on
the physical evidence.
So is mine.
These passengers are lying.
I mean, if this was
an arson case, we'd
burn down an empty house
to prove our
theory, right?
Well, in this case
we're going to
recreate the flight
from... 1630 hours on.
You are in 4B.
Lou.
Lou, the angry
businessman.
How about that?
I want to be Shannon.
Good.
The stewardess.
Excuse me,
it's flight attendant.
Catherine-- the doctor, 3E.
Single mom.
What an imagination you have.
Max and Marlene, 2E and F.
You two are married.
Who wants to wear the pants?
CSI-3 seniority, sweetie.
Yeah, whatever.
You're henpecked anyway.
Let me guess--
you're the computer geek.
In the interest of clarity, yes.
Nate in 2C.
Okay, look, it's going to
be sunrise in ten minutes.
We're going to have
to do a Run, Lola, Run
and play this
in literal time.
Up until the point
that Captain Murdle
escorted the dead guy
back to his seat
the events are substantiated
by the flight log
and the eyewitness statements
unless anybody
knows something different.
What time was that?
1632 hours--
exactly 33 minutes
before they landed
in Vegas.
One minute later,
the plane hit turbulence.
And according to
the flight attendant
that's when our stiff lost it
and started hammering
his call button.
So, I walk over
try to calm the guy down,
but he won't quit.
Grissom:
Well, we know he's suffering
from encephalitis.
He's probably sweating and
fighting back a migraine.
I know what my guy's doing
in my seat-- Lou.
He's getting ticked off.
Yeah, but Candlewell is ticking
off Nate in 2C even worse.
I mean, this guy
is perseverating.
That's when he winds up
and breaks your seat.
So, I get up,
spin around
confront the guy.
Now, Lou in 4B said
he was the peacemaker.
Brass:
Peacemaker, my ass.
He's got three empties
in the pouch.
Seat reeks of whiskey.
The guy
probably spilled Lou's drink.
Very good.
I was boss at CSI once.
For a reason.
Anyway, Lou gets up.
He's angry.
He takes a swipe at the guy.
After knocking a few back
at 33,000 feet
you know,
probably misses.
And what does he get
for his trouble?
A CD swipe
across the chops.
So, he falls back,
and maybe spilled
his own drink.
This time Candlewell's
got to be out of
his seat, right?
Stokes:
If I'm Max,
I want no part of this.
Plus I don't have
an aisle seat.
Yeah, but your wife
is going to make sure
that you get
in the playing field.
Yeah, go ahead, honey.
Save my life.
Stokes:
Right. Max gets up
slides across Marlene.
Excuse me, Buttercup.
Candlewell's moving
up and down the aisle by now.
I come over
confront the dead guy.
Then what?
Who talked to 2F?
I did.
Max told the dead guy
to sit down.
He turned, he shoved Max
into the food cart
Max landed on the ground.
Warrick--
I mean, Marlene-- that's when
you got up
and grabbed
the broken wine neck.
Saved Nick's butt as usual.
Brass:
Bottle of wine
on the floor.
You slash at Candlewell
then he swipes him
across the hand--
hence the
defensive wound.
Now, our guy's bleeding.
He turns
and heads for the cockpit.
Bang-- he wants in the cockpit
but the door is locked.
Captain Murdle
gets on the horn
calls First Class twice.
No answer. Why?
Shannon's vapor-locked.
He can't get in the cockpit.
What's next?
He heads for the exit door.
Blood underneath
the latch handle
shows that Candlewell
tried to open it.
Candlewell gets the door open,
they all die.
Now it's a whole new ball game.
It's every man for himself.
Oh, yeah.
This is where
they all get scared.
Brown:
And according to Preston,
Max, and Lou
they got to Candlewell first.
The struggle ensued.
Max and Lou slammed
into Preston
and at some point
Candlewell goes down.
Now it's a
free-for-all.
'Cause my shoes
end up on his back.
Mine too.
Ditto.
Warrick:
He's messing with me;
I get my licks in.
Grissom:
Nate's knuckles were bruised...
he's in on it.
We're in close quarters
so there's elbows
flying everywhere.
That's probably how the
doctor got her black eye.
Right.
Hey, guys!
If you jump a guy
at the exit
he dies at the exit.
Yeah.
And our guy...
was found five feet away...
with his head towards coach.
Nick:
He tried to get away.
Warrick:
But they didn't let him.
Willows:
And at this point
we aren't individuals anymore;
we're a mob.
Emily:
Mommy!
You can't perform CPR
on a man's back.
Dr. Burley had to
have rolled him over.
Probably just
to cover for ourselves.
That makes us
all murderers.
I want five of those passengers
arrested for murder.
That's four more
than I anticipated.
We looked at the evidence,
and the evidence says five.
Let me get this straight.
Five strangers
get on a plane
and then together,
they kill a man.
On the surface,
self-defense.
They thought Candlewell
was bringing the plane down.
And he would've.
But he didn't.
They stopped him,
and then they killed him
not as individuals,
but as a mob.
Let's cut to the chase, Gil.
Can you prove your case?
Not yet. I
need more time.
Yeah, well, time's up.
I'm going to give these people
their walking papers.
If the Feds want to pursue it,
let them.
Oh, come on.
Don't do that.
No jury's going
to ever convict them.
You don't know that, Brian.
Look, if you or I
were on that plane
we would do whatever it takes
to save our lives.
That's what a jury would say.
That's not what
the evidence says.
Exactly my point.
( vehicle starts )
Woman:
Las Vegas Air has issued
no formal comment
other than to stand by
the actions taken
by the flight crew.
Meanwhile, the first-class
passengers from the flight
have been released
and no charges will be filed.
The airline provided a bus
to their Las Vegas destinations.
Our request for interviews
were denied, leaving the events
surrounding the death
of Tony Candlewell a mystery.
Hey.
Whoa.
Let it go, guys.
Those people
should be going to jail
not some hotel
on the Strip.
It's out of our hands.
Our field ruling was overturned
by the good old Sheriff
and the Feds.
Stokes:
And you're okay with that?
We processed evidence
for 12 hours
laid out the whole case
and now
those passengers
are going
to suck martinis
and eat shrimp cocktails?
Where's the justice?
Oh, you think
this is about justice?
Yeah, what else?
It's about
human nature
how people react
when their lives are threatened.
I know you're not condoning
what they did.
I'm not
discounting it.
I mean, think about it--
is there any place
more vulnerable
than being at 30,000 feet
in a tin can?
Feeling vulnerable
is not a defense
and where they were
is irrelevant.
They took a life.
Because their lives
were threatened.
Their lives were threatened
when Candlewell
was at the emergency exit
trying to open it,
but the five feet
between the exit and the aisles
is what made the difference
between self-defense and murder.
Human nature again.
I mean, adrenaline doesn't come
with an off switch.
I don't care
what you say.
I could never take a life.
If it was between him or me,
I could.
Nick?
I don't know.
Well... it's wicked serious
in here.
Yeah, well, we were
just talking about murder
and whether we would commit it.
I couldn't, Warrick could
and Nick's on the fence.
We're taking an exit poll.
Stokes:
Catherine,
you're a mother.
You have Lindsey, you're on that
plane. How far do you go?
All the way.
That's right.
!
You didn't even hesitate.
If it involves
the protection of my child
I fight to the death.
Warrick:
See? We have four people here,
all with different opinions.
Think of how the passengers
must have felt.
What do you think, Grissom?
I can't answer that question.
That's a cop-out.
It's a simple question.
What would you have
done if you had been
one of those passengers?
It's not about that.
You all have different opinions
but you've taken
the same point of view.
You put yourself
in the shoes of
the passengers
but nobody's put themselves
in the shoes of the victim.
I'm sorry. What are you saying?
Nobody stopped
to ask Candlewell
if he was all right.
They just assumed
because he was kicking
the back of Nate's seat
that he was a jerk
because he was pushing
his call button
that he was bothering
the flight attendant
because he was trying
to get into the lavatory
he was making a scene,
because he was going
back and forth
up and down the aisles,
he was posing a threat.
He was a threat.
No. He turned into a threat.
It didn't have to be that way.
People make assumptions.
That's the problem.
You just did.
And I think these
passengers made
the wrong assumption
and now this guy's dead.
Well, if that's your stance
how could it
have been prevented?
If just one person
had stopped and taken the time
to look at the guy
to listen to him, to figure out
what was wrong with him
it might not have happened.
It took five people to kill him.
It would've only taken
one person
to save his life.