Ah, these green worms
ain't worth a damn.
( thumping )
What the hell was that?
I don't know, probably
one of those eight-foot carp.
( thumping )
Let's get out of here.
( engine sputters and dies )
Something probably
caught on the blades.
Check the prop.
I'm not sticking my hand
in that water.
Move.
Move out of the way.
Okay.
( grunting )
Yeah, I got something.
Dude, throw it back.
What the hell is it?
Femur.
Strongest bone
in the human body--
it's sliced clean through.
Like a Ginsu
through a banana.
So, what do you think, drowning?
Yeah, probably,
but under what circumstances?
You don't wear flippers
at a five-star
restaurant.
Why would you wear
three-inch heels at a lake?
So, Watson?
The game is afoot.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
What do you think, bro?
Breakfast on me?
I got a court date...
straight off
of graveyard.
It sucks.
Ouch.
Well, time-and-a-half.
A cup of java,
and you're set.
Woman:
Fine suit.
And well, just fine.
That's harassment.
Hey, we have
one locker room
and it's my job
to be observant.
Well, evidence vault
opens in five.
See you guys later.
Later, bro.
Easy.
So, you and me,
419 Western Avenue.
I know, a dead body
at a fraternity.
7:00 A.M.-- Looks
like we're pulling
another double.
I know, we don't
have all day...
Are, are you going
to wear... that?
Yeah.
It's that hideous...
Hideous.
Thank you.
( clears throat )
Large propeller.
Blade cut clean through.
No epidermal bruising.
The leg was severed
post-mortem.
Well, that's good news.
How do you figure?
Well, do you want
to be alive
when your leg's
being cut off?
( door slams )
I believe this goes with that.
Divers recovered the body
about a half a mile
east of Calville Marina.
Female Caucasian,
mid-30s.
Left thighbone
connected to nothing.
I believe this
is our victim.
Well, she's wearing
a wedding ring.
Will you collect
a rape kit?
Always do.
How's it look for prints?
Her skin's shriveled
like a Shar-Pei.
No pressure, no prints.
No.
No way, use your own hand.
Come on, Catherine,
my hand's too big.
No!
It's the only way
we can print her.
Her skin on
your hand
should fit like
a leather glove.
Uh...
( exhales )
May I take your hand?
( slaps )
On behalf
of the decedent
I thank you.
Umm...
I think we're going
to know who she is
by lunchtime.
Ugh!
I can't believe I used to
live in a place like this.
It seems like
a hundred years ago.
And here I had
all this respect for you.
Guys, Nick Stokes.
This is Sara Sidel.
We're with the crime lab.
How you doing?
I'm Matt Daniels.
James is upstairs
if you guys want
to follow me.
Okay.
Hey.
( sighs )
Good God!
You see a suicide note?
We didn't find one.
Don't release anyone
downstairs.
We want to talk to them.
All of them.
Coroner pronounce?
Twenty minutes ago.
Just get him down.
( camera shutter clicks )
She's a floater, Wendy Barger.
34, local, Green Valley.
We should contact
her family.
Already did.
Talked to the husband.
Never reported her
missing.
The coroner said
she'd been in the
water for two days.
Where's the husband now?
At the coroner's,
IDing the body.
Hey.
Results are back
on the rape kit.
Positive for semen,
vaginal penetration.
You confirming rape?
Well, there are
signs of a struggle.
The victim's right
shoulder is dislocated.
Her skull is fractured.
( inhales )
Give me a little more
time with the body.
Sure.
Thanks, Jenna.
Mr. Barger, my name
is Gil Grissom.
Hello.
This is
Catherine Willows.
We're forensic investigators.
Sit down.
We need to ask you
a few questions.
All right.
Is there anyone that you know of
that might have wanted
to harm
your wife?
No.
Everybody loved Wendy.
When was the last time
you saw her?
Tuesday morning.
She needed some
time away...
to get perspective.
She did that
sometimes.
Uh, we have a, a cabin
up by Calville Bay.
And when was the last time
you had intercourse
with your wife?
Oh, that-that's personal.
It's part
of our investigation, sir.
Uh, well, the average
is only once a week.
Saturdays.
Mr. Barger...
Probably three
or four months ago.
Would you be willing
to give us
a DNA sample, sir?
What's going on?
I thought Wendy drowned.
We're still trying
to piece it all together.
A sample would be helpful.
By law,
we need a warrant
unless you are willing
to volunteer it.
Was James depressed?
You could say that.
Could you say that?
I mean, the kid's
18 years old
he's got his whole life
life in front of him
and why would he want
to hang himself?
I don't know.
He didn't get in?
Get in...?
The fraternity.
Pledging. I mean,
it's not easy.
Apparently not.
So, you guys
let James know
he wasn't getting in, right?
I told him last night.
I'm the one in charge
of dinging pledges.
Big job?
How'd he take it?
I think you know.
Hey, Judge.
What's going on?
I'm due in your court.
Called for a continuance.
Well, nobody told me.
Nobody was supposed
to tell you.
You're going
to do something for me.
Judge, I thought
we were even.
How much longer am
I under your thumb?
You do what I ask,
slate's clean.
Henderson rape case.
State's evidence.
Damn.
I knew you were in tight.
Judges aren't appointed
on a whim.
I owed the family.
I need you to compromise
the chain of custody.
Just like that?
We got a slam dunk
on a three-time rapist
and he's just going to walk?
I have to have this case kicked.
I'm already
on probation.
Give them an excuse.
You're good at that.
You worked the graveyard.
You pulled a double
and you're tired.
It could happen
to anybody.
Don't worry. I've got your back.
Yeah, I feel you back there,
believe me.
( techno music plays )
Hey, Maestro, what's the deal
on our floater?
Excuse me.
Professor.
What's up with our floater?
Come hither.
Willows:
DNA doesn't match.
Thirteen markers,
and not one of them
matches the husband's types.
It's funny.
I like the husband for this.
Well, you were wrong.
My client's been
through enough distress.
Winston, come on.
When you find out
what happened to my wife
I want to know everything.
I promise.
( exhales )
Let me ask you something.
Would you want
to know everything?
You're asking
the wrong guy.
Barger as much as told us
that he and his wife
are having problems.
She was staying at the lake.
It wasn't the first time.
And what do you think
the chances are she was
seeing somebody else?
You were married.
You tell me.
Very good to excellent.
I need to see
the Henderson rape case 4217.
Sure, in here.
Uh, sign here.
Thanks, Mike.
( sighs )
( footsteps approach )
Grissom:
Hey.
How's court?
Uh, damn case
was continued.
Clerk never called.
Look, go home.
Take a day.
You're been working
your ass off.
Nature of the beast.
I'm grateful, Warrick.
I'm glad you're back.
And I owe you a party.
Party?
Yeah, I made you
a CSI Three.
( chuckles )
You'll see it
in your next paycheck.
More money, more problems.
Mm...
Thanks.
Yeah.
I appreciate it.
If Wendy Barger
was sleeping around
none of her friends
knew about it.
Anybody seen her
since Tuesday?
Nope.
And as far as I can tell,
the husband's on the level.
He was happier in the
marriage than she was.
She had something
on the side.
I can tell you firsthand
when you don't cheat,
you don't suspect.
Oh, man.
I wish I had been
married to you.
Not a chance.
Oh... mm...
Coroner just called.
They're waiting for us.
Okay.
Brass, you coming?
I still got half a burger.
Besides, I prefer live bodies.
Hey, Grissom.
You got a second?
Uh, I'm in purgatory.
Need some guidance.
Meet you at the car.
Okay, here's your frat boy.
We have
a petechial hemorrhaging
which is synonymous
with asphyxia.
Stokes:
So he was asphyxiated
by hanging?
Are you ruling suicide?
No, not yet.
When a victim is found hung
we usually find
some teeth marks
on the tongue.
No teeth marks.
But we found him
swinging from the ceiling.
So, the question is,
how did he get there?
Speaking of
how did it
get there...
How did this
get on his penis?
Huh.
Is that a tattoo?
No, no,
it looks like ink.
Nick?
You want
to take a look?
Oh, no, I...
don't have to look.
I have a good idea
what this is about.
Okay.
Knock yourself out.
Does your fraternity
practice hazing?
No.
Yeah, I mean,
it took a long time
for Phi Alpha
to get its charter.
We have a strict
no-tolerance policy
and as president,
I enforce that
to the letter.
Come on, man, I was a Greek
and we had all kinds
of policies, too.
Guys still hazed.
We found ink on James' penis.
Are you trying
to tell us
he was just
practicing
his penmanship?
State passed a law-- no hazing.
It's six months in
jail plus expulsion.
We do not haze.
But there is an initiation.
Pledges, turn and face
your active chapter.
( heckling )
For the past ten weeks
you guys
have accumulated points.
Some of you
are way ahead.
are way...
behind.
It's time to get signed!
( cheering )
I could tell right off the bat
James was nervous, you know?
He was kind of this shy guy.
I mean, he...
He wanted to pledge.
He wanted to belong.
Yeah, he wanted to belong
but you know what,
I questioned his chops.
I think we all did.
So, yeah, we gave
the pledges
an assignment.
They were to go to sorority row
and, uh, get...
different parts
of their bodies signed.
I mean, the menu was
pretty straightforward.
Arms and legs:
five points
ten points for your chest,
25 points
for your butt cheeks
and 100 points for your Johnson.
Your Johnson?
Yeah, your, uh...
I know what it is.
Don't stop now.
And Johnson...
...your sorry ass
is so far behind
in points
that you better
get your...
"Johnson"...
signed a couple
hundred times
or you're... history.
( cheering )
Kyle caught him cheating
in the bathroom.
He was signing himself.
Oh, man!
No!
What a fake!
You humiliate him in front
of all the other actives.
Poor kid
was so scared
he had
to sign himself.
You give him a beer shower?
And you don't
call that hazing?
Answer the question, guys.
I had no choice.
I had to ding him.
I mean, come on,
you're only as strong
as your weakest link.
We didn't pledge him.
He pledged us.
He knew
what to expect
if he didn't measure up.
Humiliation, initiation...
appreciation.
That's what it's all about,
right, right?
We're sorry,
but we didn't kill him.
I don't buy it.
Judge... Warrick.
Listen, uh,
I got a little problem.
No, I can't talk about it
over the phone.
We got to meet in person.
There's something
in the evidence
I think you should see.
Good.
I'll start
at the top.
Head contusion,
right temple.
Imbedded with wood splinters,
lime green paint.
Willows:
What does that give us?
Nothing yet, but when
you find the murder weapon
it might give you something
to compare it against.
Moving down, three words.
Write them down.
Minimal
pulmonary
aspiration.
There was no water in her lungs?
If she died by drowning,
her lungs would be flooded.
But her lungs
weren't flooded.
So we think
she was raped
killed, then dumped in the lake.
After a very nice dinner.
Which brings me
to her stomach.
Fried calamari
and based on the extent
of the digestion
she died
about three hours
after she ate.
( chattering )
Willows:
Now tell me,
why are we here?
'Cause it's the only
place within ten miles
of Calville Bay
that serves calamari.
And you know this
because...?
I come here
for calamari.
Oh. Alone?
No. Sometimes I
have a beer with it.
Willows:
Do you recognize
this woman?
She might have eaten here
Tuesday night
right around this time.
Ordered the calamari.
Miss, everyone
orders calamari.
Well, I don't care
about everyone.
I care about her.
Uh... yeah.
Yeah, I remember her.
Um, she came in
with a guy.
Regulars.
Good tipper.
Would you happen to know
this good tipper's name?
Willows:
Mr. Swelco,
are you all right?
I can't believe she's dead.
Could you tell us
about your affair with Wendy?
Nobody knew we had one.
What about
your wife?
We were separated.
We filed for divorce last week.
I thought Wendy
was going to do
the same thing.
And... when she didn't,
you got angry?
No. No.
That's not
what I meant.
I loved Wendy.
She said the marriage
was over.
It's just that... just...
she was scared.
Scared?
Why?
She didn't want
to hurt Winston.
She thought if she left, he'd...
break.
( sniffling )
Tuesday night you and Wendy
had dinner at the Grille?
Where'd you go after that?
We went back to the marina
in her car
and then we took the outboard
back here.
Why'd you take the boat?
Wendy didn't want anybody
to s-see her car in my driveway
so we always met at the marina
and then we'd take
the outboard over here.
What happened once you got here?
We made love.
Then she left.
Took the boat back.
Where is... the boat?
At the marina.
Do you believe him?
I believe he
had an affair.
That the husband?
Mr. Barger,
what are you doing here?
You didn't call, so
I was following you.
Uh, this is...
Phil Swelco's house, isn't it?
Do you know Mr. Swelco?
Informally.
Does he have something to do
with Wendy's death?
We're interviewing
a lot of people.
Most of it's follow-up.
Grissom:
Mr. Barger,
this is a time
when you ought to let us
do our job.
You've been through
a terrible ordeal.
You've asked us
to keep you posted
and I promise
we will keep you posted.
I just
wanted to see
if you guys have anything new.
As soon as we know,
you'll know.
All right.
Drive safely.
( engine starts )
You know, eventually
we're going to have
to tell this guy
that his wife
was having an affair
with somebody he knows.
No, we don't,
Catherine.
We have to tell him
how his wife died.
Just the facts,
without all the other stuff.
When Eddie was cheating on me
I sure wish somebody
would have said something.
You mean me.
Who else?
( knocking )
New pet?
The African red baboon
tarantula--
the most feared
of all arachnids.
But basically harmless.
Yeah, well
just keep the
lid on it, okay?
I think you scared him.
All his hairs
are standing up.
If you're through
amusing yourself
I have some news
on the boat.
Was it at the marina?
What do you think?
My spider sense says it wasn't.
Right. We need to find the boat.
The coroner's prelim
on the frat hanging.
Bust it out.
( sniffing )
What's that smell?
I'm nuking a burrito.
Mmm, junk food and
radiation-- good combo.
A strip of raw calf's liver
was found lodged
inside the cleft
of victim's
throat.
Cause of death: choking.
Mm-hmm. That's interesting.
Microscopic threads of fabric
were found
embedded in the liver.
Microscopic fabric?
I have no idea
what you're talking about.
You just lost me.
Kyle, I'm getting
that hazing feeling.
Did you stuff him?
Suffocate him?
Shove towels
down his throat?
No. Look, lady, I have no idea
where you're going with all this
but you're way off.
Tell me about the liver.
What about the liver?
Kyle...
11 years ago
I was you, man.
Smoking cigars in closets,
playing tanks.
I wore a trout
in my jean pocket
for seven days
till my leg
went half numb.
I've been there.
So, don't...
don't tell me "What about it?"
Okay.
James begged us
for one more shot
so, we came up with a challenge.
Swallowing raw liver.
Oh, man.
Oh, man, he's choking.
Give him the Heimlich.
Give him the Heimlich!
( gagging )
He's turning blue!
How does a kid choke to death
and end up
hanging from a rafter?
Okay.
We freaked.
I mean,
we had a lot to lose here.
We could lose
our charter
or get kicked
out of school
or even go to jail.
So, me and Matt,
we strung him up, and...
made it look
like he'd committed suicide.
You do realize you just
admitted to killing him?
We didn't kill him.
It was an accident.
It was an accident
but now it's beginning
to look like Christmas.
Look, my dad's
a top defense attorney
so, if charges are filed...
Don't worry.
They will be.
It'll be manslaughter,
not murder.
And me and Matt
wind up
with community service.
We can hold him
for manslaughter.
Manslaughter--
are you kidding?
Are you willing
to settle for that?
Come on, Nick, you
know as well as I do
there is more to this.
You're going 80 miles an hour
in second gear.
Let's just slow down,
all right?
Okay.
They said they performed
the Heimlich, right?
Yeah. I don't
believe them.
Well, if they performed
the Heimlich
there'd be evidence
of trauma.
Yes, there would.
Well, now, you're right.
If they gave this frat kid
the Heimlich
chances are
we'd find a broken rib.
Not even a fracture.
What about abdominal
or thoracic bruising?
Nope. Photos
are all negative.
They lied.
When this kid was choking,
no one tried to help him.
Take a look
at this.
Now, we magnified
Mr. Johnson's privates.
The ink is
from a felt tip.
It's a Paper Max Thin Tip
to be exact.
"Jill W."
Two triangles.
No, it's two deltas.
Greek letters.
She's a Delt.
( groaning softly )
Freaks.
Stokes:
Jill, we need
to ask you a question.
Is this your signature?
( laughing ):
Oh, my God.
Oh, where did
you get that?
Where do you think?
You don't think
that has something to do
with what happened?
Stokes:
We don't know yet.
That's what we're trying
to find out.
How well did you know James?
Uh, he was pledging
my boyfriend's house.
We're Greek, I mean...
We sign them,
they sign us.
Of course you do.
Who's your boyfriend?
Kyle Travis.
( clearing throat )
So, looking
for fibers.
Yeah, fibers
liver-- anything
to implicate these guys.
What the heck
is that?
The murder weapon.
Dingle-dangle.
Let me guess.
Radiohead
or Rage Against the Machine.
Actually, it's
an audio book
on restriction
enzyme analysis
and DNA typing.
PCR fingerprinting.
Choice.
Right.
What's Grissom
doing in the garage?
Oh, he's working
that Wendy Barger case--
you know,
the floater?
Only clue he's got
is a missing boat
which sucks,
'cause... it's missing.
( chuckles ):
He thinks he's going to find it
in a bathtub?
It's a simulation tank.
He's re-creating the conditions
the night she died.
Body was dumped, like,
a half mile from Calville Bay.
They think the boat
must have drifted
with the currents.
And let me guess--
Catherine got bored.
Well, you know Grissom.
Shortest distance
between two points
is science.
And for Catherine,
it's pounding the pavement.
Hey, I thought Grissom
gave you the night off.
Yeah. Something came up.
See you.
( phone ringing )
Yeah? Grissom.
Catherine:
It's me.
I found it.
Just south
of Barring Point Bridge.
How?
I took a walk.
Just south
of Barring Point Bridge?
What color is the boat?
It's white with lime green trim.
Just like the splinters we found
in Wendy Barger's head wound.
Well done, Catherine.
Well done.
( stifled giggle )
Let's get the boat
back to the garage.
This better be good.
I need some assurances.
It's a two-way street, pal.
Did you do what I asked?
I checked out the evidence,
yeah.
But I'm not sure about the rest.
What's the big deal?
You break the seal
on the evidence box
it's over.
We put it to bed,
and I tell Henderson
"Mission accomplished."
Why don't you let me do that?
( siren blaring )
What's going on here?
Judge Cohen,
you're under arrest
for obstruction of justice
tampering with state's evidence
and violating seven articles
of scumbag.
I told you...
nobody owns me.
Move on.
Nice work, man.
( sighs )
Hey, Grissom.
I hear Catherine
beat you to the boat.
We work as a team.
We're not competing.
Okay.
But, uh, she found it first
right?
"Two roads diverged
in a yellow wood
"and, sorry
I could not travel both."
Robert Frost.
Very good, Greg.
Thanks.
But actually, in this case,
Mr. Frost does not apply.
When you have partner
you each take a road.
That's how you find
a missing boat.
Come on.
Level with me.
Who do you think killed her--
the husband or boyfriend?
And you've narrowed
it down to just two suspects?
Actually, you did.
You see, my second week
at CSI, you told me
that when a cheating spouse
is murdered
there's always two suspects
at the top of the list:
the lover and the betrayed.
I told you this?
Mm-hmm.
You see, I'm thinking
that the husband
caught Wendy
with the boyfriend
and when she left his house
he killed her in a jealous rage.
And this theory
is based on...?
Nothing.
I'm just trying to help.
I'm going to the garage
to meet Catherine.
You keep thinking, Butch.
That's what you're good at.
Hey. If this theory
checks out, uh
maybe we should
talk about a raise.
Yeah.
I think I may have found
some skin.
When Wendy hit her head.
Did you hear what I said?
Blood.
Blood?
You were at the autopsy.
The head trauma
wasn't a bleeder.
Well, maybe
she fought back.
Either way,
we got to call Brass.
Tell them to bring
the boyfriend in.
( camera shutter clicks )
Could you wait
right here, please?
Stay with Mr. Swelco.
How's it going?
Aah, you know, the usual
beep-bap-bop, you know?
The guy said he cut
his hand cleaning fish.
Got a tetanus shot.
That's his excuse for the blood
we found on the boat.
But I'll call the clinic
to confirm.
Damn, you're good.
Oh, shut up.
Stevie, hang with him.
Man:
Phil?
Phil Swelco?
Winston.
I heard about your wife.
I'm sorry.
What are you doing here?
Why are you questioning him?
Mr. Barger,
why don't, you, um
come over here
with me.
Just walk over...
why don't we go in here
sit down.
Have a seat.
I always knew
she was seeing someone.
I just didn't know who.
Oh, I'm sorry.
She was having an affair
with Phil Swelco?
And you think he killed her.
You just compromised
our investigation.
He deserved to know
the truth.
Knowing how
she died, yes.
Knowing that she had
an affair--
how does that
bring closure?
I guess you
just have to be
on the wrong end
of an affair
to understand.
You can't make this
about Eddie.
Look, you hurt our case
because your ex hurt you.
We bring ourselves
to our cases.
We can't help it.
I knew how Barger felt.
Would you relax?
I didn't give him
chapter and verse.
You can't give him anything,
Catherine.
We're scientists.
We're not psychiatrists
or victims' rights
advocates.
You right, you know.
I should be just like you.
Alone in my hermetically
sealed condo
watching Discovery
on the big screen
working genius-level
crossword puzzles,
but no relationships.
No chance any will
slop over into a case.
Right. I want to be
just like you.
Technically, it's a townhouse.
And the crosswords are
advanced, not genius.
But you're right.
I'm deficient in a lot of ways.
But I never screw up
one of my cases
with personal stuff.
Grissom...
what personal stuff?
Matt, I got to know.
How much did it tick Kyle off?
What are you
talking about?
Jill.
( laughs )
Man, Kyle must've been steamed.
His girlfriend signs
a pledge's privates?
Yeah, Kyle, can take a joke.
He didn't think it was funny
enough to share it with us.
You know, I never met a guy
who could just laugh that off.
Hey, Matt
you know why I joined
a fraternity?
'Cause I wanted
to belong
to something--
the brotherhood.
That's what it was
all about for me
you know what I mean?
So I'm going to cut to the chase
here, bud.
You come clean,
you might be able
to save your house
save the brotherhood,
but...
if you don't...
You and Kyle both get charged
with murder
and the house goes dark.
Everything you're trying
to protect
you'll destroy.
Martie
I found the string.
Now are you ready to tell us
what happened
after James got back
to that house?
Okay.
Hey, let's see
what Johnson
came up with.
Yeah?
Yeah, let's
see it, dude.
Show it!
Dude...
that's your girlfriend.
She signed it.
( guys hooting )
Did it hurt?
Meet me upstairs, pledge.
You're still behind in points.
So this is
what we're going to do.
I'm going to put this
down your throat
You're going to swallow it
and you're going to trust me
to pull it back out.
Okay.
( gagging )
Dude, where's Johnson?
Oh, oh, this is crazy.
All right, all right,
listen to me.
Anything goes down
my father will bail out
the Chapter.
Now you're just going
to follow my lead
and you're going to keep
your mouth shut.
( door sliding open )
Is my dad here yet?
No, but when he gets here
you can tell him
new charge:
first degree murder.
No way, come on.
That's ridiculous.
Your boy rolled
over on, Slick.
One thing about
the fraternity upstate
the brotherhood's
fantastic.
Oh, yeah.
They gonna love you.
( hollow clanging )
She ran out of gas.
Okay.
Get in the boat.
Pull the engine cord.
What?
Get in the boat.
Why?
Just indulge me, please?
There's no gas.
It's not gonna start.
That's not the point.
( sighing ):
As long as
there is one.
Pull it again.
( grunts )
Go on.
More.
Harder.
Go on.
That's it. What's your point?
How does your shoulder feel?
It's sore.
You already knew that.
I know what happened to Wendy.
She says good night
to Swelco
and gets in the boat.
Halfway home,
the boat runs out of gas.
Stranded in the middle
of the lake, she panics.
Starts pulling
on the engine chord.
She pulls so hard,
she dislocates her shoulder
and falls forward.
Wendy goes under,
where she remains
until Barger's propeller
severs her leg.
She died before
she ever hit the water.
It was just an accident.
Well, sometimes
it's about what didn'thappen.
Well, I guess
we better go talk
to the husband.
I mean, unless you think
I'm going to compromise
the integrity
of the case again.
Look...
Could we have a truce?
I would love to.
Good.
But let me do
all the talking
to the husband
and the boyfriend.
He had to say it.
Hey.
I'll meet you
outside, okay?
Okay.
Hey, Warrick.
Hey, Care.
Did it go okay?
Yeah. Fine.
Thanks for letting
Brass handle it.
The fewer people
who know about this
the better.
I'm proud of you.
No, Judge Cohen's got
a lot of soldiers.
Yeah. That's
what I'm afraid of.
You know, I can only
help you out so much.
After that, it's up to you.
Yeah, I know.
( knocking )
Hello?!
Mr. Swelco?!
( man sobbing )
He killed my wife.
We just came
from your house.
We wanted to tell you
that your wife's death
was an accident.
What?
He didn't kill her.