( rock music playing )
Hello, Rick.
♪ Living in a shack
in a one-horse town ♪
♪ Trying to get to heaven
'fore the sun going down... ♪
Welcome.
Congratulations, Patrick.
Well, thank you, Sheriff.
Your presence here
means a lot tonight.
Is that for me?
You talking
about the glass
or the bubbly?
I was talking about
the smile on your face.
( laughing ):
Well, if I'm smiling,
it's because we raised
$1.6 million for
Mrs. Richmond's
Burn Center tonight.
That sort of generosity
deserves a raise
of the glass, huh?
To Portia.
MRS. BURTON:
It's a shame she
couldn't be here tonight.
♪ Oh, she came on ♪
♪ with an alligator smile... ♪
We did it.
We sure did.
( woman screaming )
( sirens approaching )
Nice tux, Sheriff.
Do you know whose
house this is?
To know this town
is to know its celebrities
and their histories.
Portia Richmond was
a legendary showgirl
in her day.
That's not her.
Maybe 30 years ago
when she was the headliner
at the Lido de Paris.
Who found her?
Look around you.
( sighing )
This is going to take all night.
Come for the hors d'oeuvres--
stay for the interrogation.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
Yes, sir.
Well, I'll do my best.
All right, you guys,
like I said on the phone
it was a big party
and it's a huge house
so we're going to
divide and conquer.
Nick, tonight you do the
overall sketch, all right?
Catherine and Warrick,
you got the pool area.
I'll take the
shallow end.
Guess I'm going deep.
STOKES:
I wonder how much
it costs to feed
all these fish.
Marco?
Hold on.
You want to get
out of there, sir?
The pool closed at sundown.
Can I get you a towel, sir?
Yeah, please.
What'd you find?
Looks like a cufflink.
Initials "C.M."
Turquoise and silver.
Breaks down the regionality
to the southwest--
maybe Arizona,
New Mexico, Texas.
Good catch, pal.
You get the guest list.
Check for C.M.s.
I'll be wet all night.
( machine whirring )
I detect
a bitter alkaloid.
Don't tell anybody.
My weakness.
One macchiato, tall.
Coffee machine courtesy
of the city, I presume?
When the coroner asks
for something, they
don't question it.
Cheers.
Come on.
Have we I.D.'d her yet?
Working on it.
She's had a few upgrades.
Submalar augmentation.
Rhinoplasty.
Silicone breasts.
Run a serial number
on the implants. Instant I.D.
Our field's come a
long way, hasn't it?
Hmm.
Got a whole menu here.
Petechiael hemorrhaging,
bruising around the neck
broken hyoid bone.
She was strangled.
No water in the lungs
but she was dead before
she hit the water.
( slurping )
Strangulation's
a man's crime.
Preaching to
the converted.
Do me a favor, Doc.
Photograph her injuries.
Run a sex assault kit.
Include infrared
for subdural bruising.
This is our little secret.
Okay.
Hey.
Hi.
419 at The Sphere,
glass elevator.
You're on it.
This is a big case.
I'm in a groove here.
Well, groove on
down to the Strip.
What ever happened to
"You cross the tape,
you go the distance"?
I was probably saying that
to get you
to service my needs
at the time.
( ringing )
Great.
Hey, Sara.
You sleeping?
Oh...
Excuse me for a minute.
Hi.
Well, I got the horsepower
on everybody here.
99% of the people
know nothing, saw nothing.
Big surprise.
What about
Portia Richmond?
BRASS:
Well, according
to her friends
she's been romancing
some young stallion
for over a month.
She's in love.
She's cruising
the Mediterranean
on some yacht,
eating cheese cubes.
Got a couple
watching the house.
Apparently, she
often takes in strays.
Mr. and Mrs.
Haynes, this is
Gil Grissom
and Catherine Willows.
They're from
the crime lab.
Hi.
Do you mind if we ask you
a few more questions?
By all means.
How is it that you
know Portia Richmond?
Oh, we met her
at the Murado
at the top
of the Mediterranean.
You need an oil well
in your backyard
to belong to that place.
Private club,
50 grand a year
just to walk
through the door.
But worth every penny.
It was like we'd known
Portia all our lives.
Does that ever happen to you?
No.
PATRICK:
We were new in town.
Portia introduced us around,
and took us under her wing.
We were from back East,
and we had mutual acquaintances.
And you're house-sitting?
Or you're living in?
House-sitting while hunting
for our own place.
Portia refused to take
any money from us.
She wouldn't even let
us pay for a dinner.
PATRICK:
That's why when she
took off to Europe...
AMANDA:
We offered to host
this charity event.
It's the least we could do.
After all, we know how
to throw a party.
You can say that again.
Did you know the
deceased woman?
No.
And you, Miss?
Well, as far as I know
she wasn't even
on the guest list.
Something wrong?
Yes.
A woman's dead.
Lacey Duvall murdered.
She was here last night.
Unbelievable.
Could you put us in
touch with someone
who was close to her?
Sure. Rachel Carson.
They were best friends.
Like sisters.
She's in back.
Follow me.
Close your mouth.
She was seeing some
rich married guy.
Did he have a name?
Yeah, but she
wouldn't tell me.
You know, that's the
thing, it was so weird.
He refused to tell her
anything about himself.
Anything.
I told her it gave
me the creeps
but you couldn't
talk to her.
You know?
WILLOWS:
Turned on by the
mystery and the sex.
I've been there.
Hi.
Do you need
a hand with that?
Uh... no, thanks.
I'll be fine.
Are you a doctor?
Of sorts.
I'm just, um...
looking around.
See anything you like?
Yes.
I do.
( "Waltz of the Flowers" playing
)
Catherine?
Tchaikovsky's
"Waltz of the Flowers."
What's with the smile?
It's playing our song.
Detective Conroy.
What happened?
You get bumped
from first class?
No. I do my best work solo.
On the clock, that is.
What you got?
Walk-through.
Risky move.
The entire Strip can
see into that elevator.
All around the ten-ring,
once between the eyes.
Entry wound give you anything?
Small caliber?
You like to work solo.
Take a look for yourself.
Any thoughts?
Professional hit.
Hey, well, how did
the Knicks make out?
Better than you.
( shots firing )
Times have changed
since the canary days, huh?
"Canary days?"
Yeah. Brass told me
back in the day
when the mob
would make a hit
they'd leave a canary,
'cause the guy sang.
And the quarter stands for?
"Call someone who cares."
It's almost like
the guy wants
to get caught.
When you leave a gun,
you know it's clean.
The gun just traces
back to itself.
Killer cut you off at the knees.
What do you do now?
All I can do--
follow protocol.
You're going to print
the entire elevator?
It's like the Circle Bar
on a Friday night...
Three million people
on top of each other.
WILLOWS:
Let me guess:
You're wondering why
Lacey Duvall
had a music box engraved
to Portia Richmond.
You think?
Maybe it's
as simple as
they knew each other
and she gave it to her.
If they knew each other,
why wasn't she
on the guest list?
March 7, 1969
mean anything to you?
Meant something
to the Richmonds.
You know, when Eddie and I
were first married--
when things were
kind of good?
On the anniversary
of the day we met,
he always gave me a lace teddy.
Well, I mean, I know
it's not a music box, but...
Music box, lace teddy,
it's all the same thing.
It's tradition.
And the joy of tradition
is in the constant repetition.
Right.
( music playing )
What am I, working
food and beverage
at one of the hotels?
I haven't had a day off
in three weeks.
I mean, if they're going
to call me in, throw me a bone.
Give me the 419
on the elevator.
Someone's bitter.
I'm tired.
You? Tired?
I thought you never sleep.
( yawning )
( rap music blaring )
STOKES:
What up, G?
You're awake. I hate you.
A couple of glasses
of Merlot.
Rack of lamb
on my day off.
I slept like
a baby yesterday.
You look horrible.
Thanks, Greg.
Don't look at me.
I've got Sunshine
all night.
Check for DNA
in the sexual assault kit
and the fingernail,
please.
Everything has to be
in CODIS, A.S.A.P.
Oh, is that all?
I want to know who's going
to authorize my overtime.
Suck it up, Greg.
You're well rested.
You want a Valium for her?
I heard that.
March 7, 1973.
March 7, 1981.
March 7, 1956.
March 7, 1986.
I bet he gave her one
every anniversary
until he died.
She wouldn't give away
a gift this sentimental.
( "Fur Elise" playing )
It's not "Waltz of the Flowers."
( thumping )
The seal on the door
wasn't broken.
( thumping continues )
( groaning )
( knocking )
Las Vegas Police Department.
( moaning )
Caught in the act.
I think that
was the point.
Oh, yeah.
No, I can't drink
any more coffee.
My body clock is so screwed up.
I just want a steak and a shot.
Tut's Tomb.
Steak and eggs, $1.99.
Food?
Good idea. You're on.
It's what I live for.
You guys are never
going to believe this.
You ready?
So much for the steak.
I'll take the coffee.
Yeah.
Okay, sexual assault kit
on Lacey Duvall--
that showgirl--
came back positive for semen,
but that's nothing.
Ran it through CODIS.
Seminal DNA matches a cold case
from Texas.
Dead cheerleader!
Ten years ago!
Two for one.
Okay, I'm up.
Sir, I have four criminalists
working on this.
No...
As soon as we find
something tangible
I'll call you, I promise.
Sheriff?
Yeah, he calls me every hour.
I can't get anything done.
Every half for me.
I hope we didn't
embarrass you.
A little late for that.
Yeah, uh...
Hi.
I just have
a few more
questions
about the whereabouts
of Mrs. Richmond.
Fire away.
Drinks for anybody else?
No, thank you.
( clears throat )
So, let's, uh... let's
just take baby steps.
Where is she?
On a yacht somewhere
in the Greek Isles.
And if someone
wanted to reach her?
You have a compass?
Yeah.
She's incommunicado.
Big word.
Have we done something wrong?
What?
May I have your straw?
I... I collect them.
( laughs )
Thank you.
Oh... mind if I look
around a little?
Have at it.
The hostesses' bedroom.
Mm-hmm.
Too kinky.
Let me see if Portia took
her bathing suit with her.
Here we go.
WILLOWS:
Uh...
We've got a bathing suit,
lingerie, jewels
wallet, bags...
I'm not so sure
she's gone anywhere.
Shall we do
the room, too?
I think the tooth fairy
might have just left us
a piece of Portia Richmond.
What?
Take a look.
Ugh.
WILLOWS:
I guess now
we have two cases.
We've got a body
without a murderer
and a murder
without a body.
Oh, man, I got to get a raise
for this.
Greg...
why don't you start
the DNA profile on the tooth
so that we can tell
if it's Portia Richmond.
Okay, well, but getting
the DNA from the tooth
is going to be easy.
What am I supposed
to compare it to?
How about the toothbrush
and the hairbrush
that we took from her vanity?
Why don't you go talk to
the dead-end twins over there?
Hmm.
So, either she's extremely
hygienic, or...
Somebody did some serious
spring cleaning.
If you want to know
if it's Portia
you got to get the DNA
somewhere.
I can't believe
I've been in this
town 20 years
and I've never seen
the Liberace Museum.
That's funny, I was just here
a couple days ago.
I believe it.
We have all
of Liberace's costumes
on display here.
This one, for example,
worn by Mr. Liberace
in the 1984 World's Fair
in New Orleans.
Lovely.
Mmm.
Did you ever see
one of the old shows?
The Lido in the '50s?
Before my time.
You weren't even born then,
of course.
Every dancer
was from France
and the attention to detail
in the costumes
was unparalleled.
And the audience
dressed to the nines.
Oh, yeah.
The town was different then.
The other great cities--
New York, Chicago
London--
they restored.
But in this town, they destroy.
Hmm.
So you want to see what belonged
to Portia Richmond?
Yes, please.
Folies Bergiere
1959.
Yeah... um, looks heavy.
Imagine that on your head,
two shows a night.
She used over 15 combs
and various epoxies and glues.
They damn near had to drive
a spike in her head
to keep it
from falling off.
Ow.
She lost all her hair.
DNA heaven.
SHIBLEY:
Warrick...
personal artifacts from
your elevator victim.
Cool.
You got an I.D. for me?
The driver's
license is local.
Tyson Green, 35.
Can't drive without
corrective lenses.
Too bad he wasn't
driving that elevator.
Ooh, Chicago bankroll.
This guy's not
from out of town.
No, that's just a term.
Old school.
"Shrimp Cocktail Appetizer.
Surf &amp;amp; Turf Dinner.
Two Glasses of Wine."
All comped.
Free food. Nice.
It ain't free, believe me.
You okay?
Yeah. Yeah.
A long time
since I seen these.
( footsteps approaching )
Hey, Brown.
Just talked to Bobby Dawson
in ballistics.
He ran that .22
from the elevator.
Serial number came back--
Vincent Morgan.
Lives on the West side.
Cool.
Coming?
Yeah.
Will you log these
for me?
Yeah.
Mandy, you got any prints
off of that quarter
I found on the vic?
Still working
on it, Warrick.
I don't work
one case a day.
( ripping )
Bingo.
Well, that only took
45 minutes.
What do you got?
A hit off
Patrick Haynes's
social security number.
There's only one problem.
He's an eight-month-old infant
that died 10 years ago.
Same social? You're sure?
Bam!
Oh, yeah.
( scatting and humming )
♪ Match, boom, match, boom ♪
♪ Match, boom ♪
♪ Boom ♪
♪ Match. ♪
You want to take that thing off
your head, Greg?
It's evidence.
Cool your jets, Cath.
I already got all the
evidence out of it.
Now... it's all woman.
Did you ever wear
one of these
when you were dancing?
I wore nothing but skin.
Ooh.
( clears throat )
I, uh, compared the
DNA from the tooth
with hair follicles
found inside the
headdress.
I think we have a match, sir.
And I think we may
have a homicide.
Excuse me.
So, did I break the law
by not reporting it?
It's a good idea
that when your
house is robbed
you report that your
registered gun was stolen.
Guy's story checks out.
He was robbed.
My wife's not comfortable
about having the gun in the
house since we had our boy
and I told her
that I'd gotten rid of it
but I never did.
I mean, man, the last thing
I ever expected
was it'd be used
in a murder.
We're going to
keep your name
on ice for a while.
Thanks for your time.
Hey, thanks, right on.
Oh, hey, bring up car 309!
Nobody kills anybody
with their
registered gun anymore.
Isn't that the truth.
Jim...
Hey. We got the
whole place clocked.
Keeping an eye on
the Haynes couple.
Sheriff doesn't want
them skipping town.
And neither do we.
We have a strong suspicion
Portia Richmond is dead.
Did you see that?
They're on the grift.
Hi.
May we check your coats?
What are you, a
couple of kleptos?
I don't follow.
A $5,000 stole
your wife stole?
What, are you
guys in business?
Amanda didn't know
she had taken it
till Mr. Grissom
here told her.
Is that kind of like
the guy who, uh
walks out of
the auto mall
with a Nissan Sentra
in his pocket?
Why am I here? Why?
GRISSOM:
Jim...
may I?
Mr. Haynes, we ran
a sexual assault kit
on Lacey Duvall.
We found semen.
Can you
explain that?
Yeah.
Yeah, my wife's not here.
Time to convert lies
into the truth.
I had sex with Lacey
before the party.
Would you mind giving us
a DNA sample?
No.
My relationship with Lacey
was purely sexual.
It was good sex.
Well... great sex.
Whenever we could
steal a moment, uh, we did.
Just like an addiction.
Well, in addition to exchanging
bodily fluids
did you exchange gifts?
Whatever do you mean?
Just answer the question.
No.
No, I never gave her anything.
We found a music box
in Lacey Duvall's dressing area
that belonged
to Portia Richmond.
Did you give
it to her?
Honestly... no.
Those music boxes
belonged to Portia,
not to me.
But Lacey had been by the house
and she did admire them.
You saying that she lifted it?
Human nature.
We always covet
what we can't have.
What did you covet
from Portia Richmond?
( door opens )
Grissom?
Can I talk to you?
Are you looking for work?
I just...
The sign says,
"Do not enter," Nick.
You can't read anymore?
You're blind? What?
Grissom, this is important.
This is important.
Sometimes in
interrogations, Nick
you get one chance;
one answer.
And while I'm out here
screwing around with you
he's in there
thinking up an answer
that he didn't have
before you walked in.
We matched the DNA
taken from Lacey Duvall
to a cold case in
Texas ten years ago.
And?
The suspect's name
was Chad Matthews.
C.M.
Okay, I'm starting
to forgive you.
Sara ran Patrick
Haynes' social.
The real Haynes
is deceased.
So, Patrick Haynes
is Chad Matthews
and Chad Matthews
is on the run.
And he just ran into us.
Good morning.
Nice to have you back.
Do you have
any idea
what the hot topic
of conversation is going to be
when I walk
into that breakfast?
You're announcing your
candidacy for mayor?
That's cute.
Patrick Haynes
is in custody.
Does he have
anything to do
with Portia Richmond's
vanishing act?
Haynes is in lockup
awaiting extradition to Texas
on an unrelated matter.
So in the meanwhile
we're questioning him
in connection
with Portia Richmond's
disappearance.
You know, I think
you're going to get
my vote for mayor.
What have we
got on Richmond?
A canine.
Her dog.
Her tooth.
What about
the rest of her?
Still looking.
Well, look harder,
'cause if someone
leaks it to the press
that she's dead
and then she gets off a Lear Jet
at McCarran with a tan
we're both going to have
egg on our face
and I'm going to hold
you responsible.
Portia Richmond
got me elected, Grissom.
I was at her party.
Do you see what this
does to me?
Evidence is like
fine wine, Brian.
You can't just open the
bottle and drink it.
You got to let it breathe.
Look, I'm going to lay this
on the line right here and now.
You find me
Portia Richmond
or you find me
a motive for her murder
'cause I'm in your kitchen
till it's solved.
Make yourself at home.
Where you been?
Proctologist.
Sheriff getting your ass, huh?
Well, I just hit megabucks.
Austin PD has five aliases
for Chad Matthews.
Tom Sheridan,
wanted in Beacham County.
Petty theft,
check fraud.
Warner Drysdale,
wanted in Sacramento.
Grand larceny, car theft.
Guy took a car
for a test drive...
never brought it back.
Jock Jasper-- I'm not
making these names up--
extorted money
from a rich widow in Denver.
Busy boy.
Yeah, and organized, too.
The Denver PD sent me
copies of his journal.
Guy kept lists
of rich women
all around the country.
Logged in all their vitals.
Height, weight, how much money
they have, you name it.
Guess who was on that list.
Does her name begin with a "P"?
Well, according
to her credit card statements
Portia Richmond
hasn't spent a dime
since she's been
in the Mediterranean.
She's dead.
Oh, not necessarily.
Maybe she's been...
swept off her feet.
Hmm. Yeah, some guys still
like to foot the bill.
Really? How would you know?
Hey, I only go Dutch
if girls ask
the wrong question.
And what question is that, Nick?
"What do you drive?"
It's an honest question.
No. No, it's not.
What it means is, "How
much money do you make
so you can take care of me."
Well, not this girl.
Boys and girls, we've
got ourselves a forgery.
Ooh. Either that
or a dimpled ballot.
Well, his name is Chad.
Hmm.
Let's connect the dots.
What does that mean?
Here, I'll show you.
Catherine, you wear
pierced earrings. May I?
All right, but...
I've had them on for a week.
Can't account for what's on it.
Sign your name, please.
Okay.
Now, nobody signs
their signature
exactly the same way twice.
Not even you,
chicken scratch.
If they do, then one
of them's a forgery.
Here's where connecting
the dots comes in.
We dot the lines...
and curves... of the signature.
WILLOWS:
Which leaves indentations
on the blank page
and then you connect the dots,
get rid of the evidence...
but, obviously
they didn't.
Well, that's scary.
All you need is one signature
to break somebody.
You look terrible.
I been spinning my wheels.
I'm never going
to solve this case.
It was over before it began.
That doesn't sound like you.
I got a dead man
in a glass elevator
with a bazillion prints
and a .22 caliber bullet.
It's virtually untraceable.
He left the gun at the scene.
You know what that means.
Hit man with a ghost.
But I got two
things left, right?
Make that one thing.
You got to be kidding me.
It gets worse.
Got a print off your quarter.
Ran it through AFIS.
Came back your dead man.
Pretty gruesome.
Want to share?
I was just thinking
what old man Binion
told Steve Wynn
when he hit town.
Always give a gambler
an excuse to gamble
and he'll thank you for it.
Was your guy a gambler?
A bunch of cash receipts
in his pocket.
Markers all over town.
Once you get to that place
there's no getting out.
Who picked this place?
Me. I thought it
would be nice.
Okay, you can pick up the tab.
Let's keep talking about motive.
Let's. I don't think
a forged signature
is a slam dunk for murder.
Hey, did anyone
tell Grissom
where we were
having lunch?
Yeah, Dispatch
left him a message.
Maybe he thought
it was the sheriff
and blew it off.
Right.
Hey! You might want to take
your face
away from that.
Really?
Why is that?
SIDLE:
This Chilean sea bass
is wonderful.
So is this.
Okay, you got
your missing widow.
Her bloody tooth
found in her own bedroom
which is currently occupied
by two moes.
"Moes." I'm rubbing
off on you.
No, you're not, and stay
out of my sea bass.
Oh, that is good.
One of our moes has
six names that we know of
including Chad Matthews.
Right, right, and
we've got a cuff link
with the initials C.M.
found in the bottom of the pool
along with
a floating showgirl.
Who was sleeping
with six men
rolled into one--
Patrick Haynes.
Hey.
Photos of your showgirl.
What did I miss?
It's not what you missed.
It's what seems
to be missing.
A fingernail?
STOKES:
Okay, Patrick Haynes.
Or whoever.
Whoever. He commits
a murder ten years ago.
Why give up
your DNA so easily?
Exactly. I mean, you know,
you can change your name.
You can't change
your blueprint.
Right on.
SIDLE:
Risk versus reward.
You sleep with someone,
you kill 'em, the heat's on.
You flee, or, you roll the dice
and maybe you get your cookie.
What's the cookie?
The cheese, brother.
Maybe that 1.6 mil
they raised
at the charity
event that night.
The Hayneses controlled
Portia Richmond's
bank account
including the Burn
Center account
but they had to stick around
for the checks to clear.
So why kill Lacey Duvall?
Excellent question.
I don't know, but if Lacey
Duvall hadn't been murdered
Patrick Haynes
reinvents himself
becomes another skippy in
another state, $1.6 mil richer.
Wait, wait. Time out, now.
I had half a Caesar
and a coffee.
How's my end 20 bucks?
You want to go dutch, Nick?
Excellent idea, Sara.
You're catching on.
I'd love to.
Uh, Brass, cough it up.
Cover Nick's, too.
He had that tiramisu.
I hate going out to lunch
with you CSIs.
You notice everything.
Hey.
Whatever happened
to the fingernail
that Catherine found
at the crime scene?
Got the results right here.
First things first.
Not a match to Patrick Haynes.
I never figured a man
for the fingernail, Greg.
Okay, but here's where you break
out the can of creep repellent.
The fingernail and the semen
share half
the DNA markers in common.
Possible first-degree relative?
Do me a favor.
Run this for me.
What is that, lip gloss?
You tell me.
BRASS:
On behalf...
of the state of Nevada
my apologies.
You've been cleared
of all charges.
It took three of you
to tell me that?
But...
on behalf of
the state of Texas
you're under arrest.
You're being
extradited
for the murder
of Lana Grimshaw.
I slept with her,
but I didn't kill her.
WILLOWS:
Huh.
Just like with Lacey Duvall.
Absolutely.
Mm-hmm.
Now I see it.
What?
See what?
The family resemblance.
Donnie and Marie.
Brother and sister
and I got the DNA
to prove it.
Let me tell you
what else I can prove.
Your sister...
killed Lacey Duvall.
He told me he loves me.
No more faking love.
No more acts.
Is that what he told you?
That's an act?
It's as real as it gets.
Patrick says you're small time.
You don't have the stones
to go big.
You don't know Patrick.
You mean Chad?
He gave me this.
You know
what's next.
It's my turn.
( snap )
You're surprised?
Look at your face.
You never made a mistake
until you met her.
You killed Lacey
because I told
her about us?
I had no choice.
We were partners.
You can't grift me, Chad.
Uh...
Who wants to tell us
about Portia Richmond?
She's in Europe.
On a yacht, in Greece.
Oh, right. She's incommunicado.
Old Testament.
The Book of Jonah.
"And now, the Lord arranged
for a great fish to
swallow up Jonah."
You know what's wrong
with the piranha, though?
They've got
high cholesterol.
Cholesterol is found
in humans, not fish.
So how does a fish acquire
human cholesterol?
You want to fill in the blanks?
Hey, Portia.
You're both under arrest for
the murder of Portia Richmond.
These belong
to Tyson Green.
Just came to let you know
he won't be paying up.
What's he, dead?
Yeah.
( women screaming )
It's machine 25 again.
Been spitting
silver all day.
It's a good day to gamble.
WOMAN:
Vegas, NFL football,
a guy like you.
Come on, you trying to tell me
that you didn't make
a little pit stop?
GRISSOM:
What you do on your time
is nobody's business.
What you do on my time,
is my business.
MAN:
Warrick Brown had one
of my guys sub for him in
court
but I have it on good authority
that he was gambling.
WOMAN:
Warrick has a problem.
Ignoring it isn't
going to make it go away.
BROWN:
I won't let you down again.