Oh...
Honey here, take this.
Not again.
We are buying
that alarm system.
No argument from me.
I'm serious.
They got the cash.
Why did they have
to make such a mess?
Oh, my God...
What? What's wrong?
Call 911.
Introductions?
Joseph Felton, 44
not an employee;
no reason to be here.
Mind if he and I
have a moment?
No.
Burn marks?
Unusual way
to penetrate a safe.
Hmm...
How much was taken?
Three hundred and something,
small bills.
GRISSOM:
Multiple contusions
to the back of the skull.
Might've been taken by surprise.
Robbery interruptus?
Yeah, I think our robbery
suspect is a homicide victim.
One way to beat the rap.
[Captioning sponsored by
CBS
and CBS PRODUCTIONS/
ALLIANCE ATLANTIS]
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
DR. ROBBINS:
This is an easy one.
Three hits to the head.
Trauma to the brain stem
was fatal.
Death was instantaneous.
Can you tell us
about the murder weapon?
Nothing definitive
but I swabbed the points
of impact.
Slide's under
the microscope.
STOKES:
Yellow looks like transfer
from the murder weapon
but what's with the glitter?
ROBBINS:
Unidentified mineral.
I sent a sample to Trace
for analysis.
Hey, Doc, you have a comb?
Your hair looks great, Cath.
Gee, thanks, Nick.
Guy's still dirty.
They don't get a bath
till evidence is collected.
That's what I'm doing
although I don't think
this is dirt.
He's covered in spores.
I think these are from a fern.
Well, the back entrance
was overgrown with them.
A fern plant deposits billions
of spores in its lifetime.
Most are just dust in the wind.
In our case
they're evidence.
As good as fingerprints
or fibers
in placing a suspect
at a crime scene.
Hey, you forget
about the coroner?
Melissa Marlowe.
Excuse me?
You lifted 38 prints
from the pottery store.
I scanned them
through AFIS.
One came back.
Melissa Marlowe.
Why do I know
that name?
Kidnapping
Arizona,
21 years ago...
the little girl.
Oh, that Melissa Marlowe.
Wasn't she presumed dead?
Well, not anymore.
On the left
is Melissa Marlowe's print,
age four--
preschool fingerprinting
initiative.
On the right is a print
that you lifted.
I don't see a match.
Neither did I
but since fingerprints
are set for life
during the fourth month
of fetal development
I looked beyond
the size differential.
Now, both prints
are ulnar loops.
Bifurcation, recurve
and ridge endings
are identical.
I've aligned the prints
along the delta.
WILLOWS:
You've got a
perfect match.
Wait... is she a suspect
in the homicide?
No, her print wasn't fresh.
There was dust on it.
Has to be
a few weeks old.
I think
we have two separate cases.
So I'm going to
take the new lead
in the old kidnapping case.
Nick and I will cover
the homicide.
SIDLE:
Nadine Winston falls
asleep in that chair
and incinerates.
We could make history.
Come on, now. Don't tell me
you believe in that BS.
No, of course not.
I'm a scientist. I just...
She has been reduced
to ashes.
Spontaneous human combustion
is science fiction.
I know.
There's no such thing
as a human torch.
What if it is real
and we've uncovered it?
Sara, this is a crime scene.
Stay with me here, okay?
Don't lose it.
I'm not.
I'm just open to all theories.
What's that?
Looks like cotton fiber...
possibly from a nightgown.
It's barely
scorched.
Weird.
It's like the body burned,
but...
the clothing
was fire retardant.
BROWN:
Wow.
Check that out.
Fire practically burned
a hole in the roof
but it's isolated
in one spot.
It's like the fire
created a chimney for itself.
The victim
she live alone?
Husband's already
at the station.
Look, I am telling you,
I have no idea what
happened to my wife.
Were you having
marital problems?
No.
We were like newlyweds.
INVESTIGATOR:
If I understand
you correctly
you went to bed.
Nadine fell asleep
in the easy chair.
Ten hours later you woke up,
walked into the living room
and she was a pile of ash.
A human torch.
Yeah, right.
You say you were like newlyweds?
Yeah.
But the two of you weren't
sleeping in the same bed.
Good question.
She snored.
It was a problem.
A small one.
Mr. Winston...
do you know how to use
a blowtorch?
Another good question.
Look, I came down to
this station on my own.
If I can be helpful,
let me know!
( door slamming )
So you still think
it's spontaneous combustion?
Theories give way to conclusions
once all the evidence is in.
I am merely thinking about
the next piece of evidence.
Yeah.
Hey, Nicky,
you paged me?
Yeah. Yeah, Jim, hi.
I took these photos
at the crime scene.
Safe was cracked
with a plasma lance.
Okay, I'll bite.
It's a high-powered
electric blaster.
It could cut through
that hard plate
with extreme
precision.
It's not common, but effective.
Crime scene photo from
a robbery case in '99.
Joseph Felton
our dead guy,
was arrested
but granted immunity in exchange
for his testimony against his
partner, Darin Hanson
who used
a plasma lance
to crack that safe.
Darin Hanson was released
from prison last month.
Last known address, Vegas
I see
where you're going.
So Hanson gets out of jail,
hooks up with our dead guy.
Yeah, they hook it up...
break through
the rear entrance
of the pottery store
Hanson lances the safe...
Once the safe is cracked,
Hanson steps back
allowing Felton
to collect the cash.
With Felton's attention
diverted
Hanson seizes the moment...
And kills him.
Revenge for testifying against
him and putting him in prison.
That's not bad.
Any chance you
found the murder weapon?
No, no... but I think we know
who to ask.
I haven't seen Joseph Felton
since the trial two years ago.
So it's a coincidence
he was killed
shortly after you were released
from prison.
Yeah. Guy put me in jail.
I had no reason
to see him again.
He put you in the "Gray Bar"?
Sounds like motive to me.
BRASS:
Darin
you and Felton,
you go back, huh?
Mm-hmm.
Knew the guy 15 years.
My folks lived across the street
from him.
We'd barbecue
with his wife and daughter.
Then it must've really pissed
you off when he turned on you.
STOKES:
The transcript
from your trial
says that you used
a plasma lance
in that '99 burglary,
and there it is again, Darin.
Joe was the lance guy.
He taught me how
to break into safes.
That's why the MO's the same.
BRASS:
Where were you
this morning
early a.m.?
I was in Barstow all week.
Just got back
this afternoon.
Okay...
here you go...
receipts from the trip.
Go ahead.
WILLOWS:
Looks authentic.
Cactus Pine Cafe,
Barstow, noon today.
We can't hold him.
WOMAN:
21 years ago, the chief of
police sat in our living room
and told us
our daughter was dead.
After all this time,
She's in Vegas?
That's a hundred miles
from our home.
Well, we still don't know
where she is.
Her prints in the pottery store
tell us that she was here
possibly a few weeks ago,
but Vegas is a tourist town.
But you know she's alive.
I'm still not sure
we can find her.
She's our only child.
We never gave up hope.
We're not giving up now.
MILLER:
Excuse me.
Teri...
come in.
Hi.
Teri Miller, Mr.
and Mrs. Marlowe.
Hello.
Hi.
GRISSOM:
Teri is a forensic artist.
I called her
to help us.
Did you bring
the photographs of Melissa?
Yes, but I don't see
how they can help.
In some of those,
she's just an infant.
It doesn't matter.
Do you remember her eyes?
I could never forget.
As we age,
our eyes don't change.
That's where we'll start.
Using computer software
Teri can age Melissa's picture
so that we can determine
what she looks
like today at age 25.
Then we send it off
to every law enforcement
agency in the state.
It's been so long.
Tell us the truth.
What are
our chances?
Well, 21 years ago, they told
you that your daughter was dead.
Now we're moving
in the right direction.
Where did you find him?
At a pottery store
on Stansberry Street.
Tammy, we've already
ID'd your father.
If you don't
want to see him,
I'd understand.
No, I want
to say good-bye.
Well, don't be surprised
by some swelling
and discoloration.
You have any
other family?
No.
I can put you
in touch with a counselor
if you need to talk.
No, thank you.
If there's anything you need...
Tammy...
were you at
the pottery store
with your father?
What are you
talking about?
WILLOWS:
There's some plant spores
on your sweater.
We found them
on your father, too
and matched them to some ferns
behind the pottery store.
I don't understand.
What are you doing?
I'm taking these spores
into evidence.
They place you
at the crime scene.
Is there anything you want
to tell me?
Okay, I was there.
Dad!
Dad, don't do this.
I'll get a job.
We don't need the money.
Tammy, go home.
And I don't know what happened
after that.
Why didn't you
just tell me that?
I wanted to preserve
the good memories
not remember my dad
as a thief.
I didn't kill him; I loved him.
I need a release
from your office...
so I can bury my father.
Tell me everything you can
about this foot.
Where's the rest
of the body?
Incinerated.
Lab results from the ashes
came back.
Negative for accelerant.
Nothing flammable
but sebaceous glutamate.
Human fat.
Well...
I can tell you
that the malleolus--
the ankle bone--
is completely hollowed out.
Bone marrow was reduced to ash.
Which means that the
foot was burned off
the body, not severed.
That's consistent
with your theory of
spontaneous combustion.
How do you know
about Sara's theory?
Word gets around.
You're siding with Sara
'cause you got a crush on her.
No, that's why I wore
a clean coat.
I'm just reporting
my observations.
If the foot had been
severed, the marrow
would still be intact.
So your official "observation"
is spontaneous combustion?
Not yet.
I want to send
a scraping down to toxicology.
Excuse me.
I want to check
for any flammable
compounds in the blood
but don't expect much.
The quality of the sample
may have been compromised
by the heat.
I'm going to go talk
to Grissom
see what he thinks.
No, no, we're a team.
The only place we're going
is back down
to that crime scene.
Okay, software's loaded.
It's preprogrammed with
developmental averages?
Exactly.
Aging is about predictable
craniofacial growth.
Faces grow down and out.
So the first step
is to stretch
the bottom half
of the face.
You try.
Go ahead.
Well!
Maybe you should drive.
Good idea.
Here we go.
So at age four, the bridge
of the nose is taking shape
and the interorbital distance
is established
and baby teeth
are visible.
I have a question.
Okay.
Since I screwed up
our last date
will we ever
have dinner again?
Oh, we'll have dinner...
just not together.
So the ears
are low and large
in proportion to the head.
You know, I
did apologize.
And you're forgiven.
So over the next ten years,
the face elongates
the skin thickens,
the hair pattern is set
and the small deciduous teeth
are replaced
by the secondary dentition.
Once the face is aged
I look to the mother
to fill in the blanks.
Is that Mrs. Marlowe?
Uh-huh.
Most daughters at age 25
age quite similar
to their mothers.
A network of grids
allows me to fine-tune
the tiniest facial
characteristics one
section at a time.
I'm just softening a few edges,
growing the hair...
and we're done.
Well...
hello, Melissa.
Am I interrupting?
Not at all.
You're just in time.
GRISSOM:
Catherine, say hello
to Melissa Marlowe.
Oh, my God.
What?
That's Tammy Felton
and we've already met.
Tammy Felton's
our murder suspect?
She was kidnapped
21 year ago
and may have killed the man
who raised her--
possibly the same man
who kidnapped her.
Whoa, wait. I
thought her prints
from the crime scene--
they weren't fresh.
Yeah, well, she could've
cased the place weeks ago
and then remembered to wear
gloves on the big night.
So what's the word
on the murder weapon?
Well, the swab from the
head wound's at Trace.
And?
I'm on it.
You and I have an appointment
with our shrink.
Here-- you twirl, I'll talk.
My son has Little League
in an hour.
He's scared of the ball.
You think this new bat's
going to do the trick?
( chuckling )
Why don't you just
talk with him?
Dr. Kane, this girl
was kidnapped at age four.
Would she have any recollection
of her prior life?
The theory of infantile amnesia
suggests that we have
no cognitive memory
before the age of three
but since Tammy--
or Melissa--
was taken from her biological
parents at age four
she may remember something
of her former life.
But these memories
would be... tenuous?
A sound or a smell might awaken
some latent image or feeling
but she'd have difficulty
contextualizing
these sensations.
That's got to be frustrating.
And it's precisely
that frustration
which dominates this woman's
present state of mind.
Kidnapped children
at that age tend
to exhibit
some degree of sociopathy
as adults.
Such as?
Inability to feel guilt,
compassion or love, right?
Correct, but the most
defining characteristic
is their instinct for survival.
There's nothing
that they won't do.
Tammy Felton needs help.
She may be a suspect,
but she's also a victim.
Cath, meet with her again.
Ask open questions.
Thanks for your insights,
Philip.
I'll let you know
how this unfolds.
Gil... be careful.
Sociopaths
are dangerous
because they don't function
by the same... moral code
as the rest of us.
Welcome to my world.
I checked
with Homicide again.
They found no evidence
of foul play.
What about the husband--
is he still a suspect?
No motive.
O'Riley spoke with
friends and relatives.
They were a loving couple.
What about, uh...
life insurance policies?
No, and you're reaching.
I'm not the one
who's reaching here.
We're scientists, right?
We want answers,
the satisfaction of certainty.
I'm not ignoring
scientific method.
I'm just keeping an open mind.
If we eliminate
all the alternatives
we're left with
spontaneous combustion.
That's exciting!
That would be cool, but you've
been jumping to that conclusion
from minute one.
She's a pile of ash.
Well, I brought
the ion detector.
This will pick up
even the smallest traces
of hydrocarbon fumes.
I don't care what the lab says.
This puppy will reveal exactly
what accelerant was used
to start the fire.
( clicking )
( clicking continues )
Well?
( clicking stops )
Nothing.
You know I love you.
Yes... no, I love you more.
No, I love you more.
( clears throat )
Bye, baby.
Do you have the results
on the swab yet?
Uh...
Uh... from the dead guy
at the pottery store?
The coroner sent over
a sample.
You were supposed to analyze
the mineral content.
Oh, yeah, I'm sorry.
Grissom has just been running me
around like a lapdog.
I haven't had a chance.
Grissom's on a missing persons--
he hasn't sent you anything.
Did I say Grissom?
No, I meant Catherine.
Oh, yeah.
Catherine's working with me.
Oh.
Well, what do you say we check
out that swab then, huh?
Great.
( laughing )
Don't you ever
goof off, huh?
Do you ever get a
little lost in life?
No.
Well, you should.
STOKES:
Do you see the sparkling bits?
Fluorescent minerals.
Interesting.
Here, do me a favor, will you?
Put your nose
down the scope.
When you see
the sparkling bits glow
give a shout.
Okay, ready?
Yeah, ready.
Lead.
Zinc.
Lithium.
Anything?
Nothing yet.
Manganese.
Petroleum.
Whoa, whoa, whoa...
Stop.
It's uranium.
Are you serious?
Simple quantum
mechanics.
When the molecule is bombarded
with energy at a specific level
the electrons excite,
causing the mineral to glow
and at this wavelength,
it's definitely uranium.
Which is radioactive.
Do we need to evacuate
the building or anything?
The amount is trace.
We should be fine.
Are you sure?
No.
But I can tell you
one thing for sure--
there is definitely uranium
on your murder weapon.
I hear that, uh
Greg found uranium on the swab
from Felton's skull.
Yeah. He says I'm okay,
but you know Greg.
Tell me, am I radiating
a green glow?
You'll be fine, Silkwood.
What's uranium doing
on a murder weapon, anyway?
Well, before Peter Parker was
bit by that radioactive spider
and became Spider-Man
back in the '50s
oxidized uranium flecks
were used as color enhancers.
Color enhancers?
Like paint?
Paints, dyes, glazes...
Since our guy
was killed
in a pottery store...
Say no more.
( clicking )
You got to be kidding me.
You found Melissa?
Yes.
When can we see her?
It's not quite that simple.
What do you mean?
Well, I don't want
to be evasive.
It's just that, uh...
we suspect
she might've committed a crime.
What kind of crime?
A homicide.
This can't be happening.
Mr. Grissom, we want to
see our daughter-- now.
Tell me about
your mother.
What's she got to do with this?
Tammy, if you've got
nothing to hide
and you want me to find out
who killed your father
why don't you just
answer my questions?
Mara, my mother...
died a few years ago.
I can let you see her,
but I can't allow you
to talk to her
not right now
and not under
these circumstances.
WILLOWS:
Do you have
any siblings?
Only child.
How was your
childhood?
Were you a
happy child?
Did you have
any friends?
Look, I don't see how these
questions are going to help you.
May I go?
Sure.
( door slams )
Melissa!
Melissa...
Excuse me?
It's mom...
Baby...
Lady...
I'm not your daughter.
Who is she?
Her name? Who is she now?
Tammy-- Tammy Felton.
Oh, my God.
What?
Mara Felton was our baby-sitter.
The police questioned Mara
when Melissa disappeared.
Tammy referred to her mother
as Mara, now deceased.
I am her mother.
Of course. I didn't mean...
We need a lawyer.
Why would you need a lawyer?
Not for us; for our daughter.
What were you thinking?
I don't know.
I wanted to observe them,
I guess.
That woman hasn't seen
her daughter in 21 years.
You actually thought a glass
wall would keep them apart?
I never thought about that.
I know.
You're not good with people.
Yeah.
Interesting voice mail
you left me.
What's that?
"Meet me behind CSI
and bring a cotton nightgown."
I'd wear it for you
but, uh, I prefer pajamas.
Really? It was actually
for my girlfriend here--
Miss Piggy.
We're experimenting
on a pig again?
Yeah.
You know,
I-I-I haven't eaten meat
since Grissom used one
to estimate
postmortem insect growth.
Well, I tried for human
volunteers, but no takers.
What are you going to do,
exactly?
What are we going to do?
We're disproving the existence
of spontaneous
human combustion.
You do not give up.
Well, we're recreating the death
of Nadine Winston, right?
She was wearing
a cotton nightgown-- thank you--
and she had a half a
pack of smokes on her
end table which means
she was probably smoking.
If she burned herself
with a cigarette
she would've woken up,
not burned up.
Best part:
toxicology sample came back.
Nadine had a high concentration
of Seconal
in her blood.
Sleeping pills.
Enough to knock out a horse.
All right.
Care for a light?
Now what?
We wait.
WILLOWS:
Hi, Tammy.
We just, uh, want
to look around.
We have a warrant.
A warrant for what?
Any evidence linking
you to the murder
of your father.
Tammy, could you
step outside?
This officer will
keep you company.
( clears throat )
What?
I should get a finder's fee.
Here. One for each of you.
Yellow paint.
Shall we test for uranium?
I need a darkroom.
Now, if uranium is present
the photons should react
with the film.
Well, that's affirmative
for uranium.
Nicely done, Nick.
Thanks.
Miss, have you ever worn
these gloves?
No. They belonged
to my mother.
Really? Well, we'll see.
Tammy, I need your
right index finger.
It's a perfect match.
Joe lanced the safe.
Once the safe was cracked
you seized the moment
and bashed his head in--
three blows.
Nick, call Brass.
Tell him it's time
to make an arrest.
Done.
You're making a mistake.
I didn't kill my father.
We weren't alone.
I'm sorry, but there's
no evidence to indicate
that there was a third person
present at the crime scene.
Who else was there?
I tried to stop her, I swear.
Tammy...
Who was with you?
Melissa Marlowe.
But that bitch wouldn't listen.
So we're looking at
a split personality?
Quite possible.
Two personalities in one.
Is there any
scientific evidence
that supports
this disorder?
Brain scans have
documented changes
in the hippocampus
of individuals
shifting from one personality
to another.
But would these
two personalities
be aware of each other?
Well, usually the dominant
personality is aware
of everything.
The subjugated personality
is only aware of itself.
Tammy's the dominant
personality.
WILLOWS:
But Melissa killed
Joseph Felton--
Tammy's father.
Who was
also Melissa's kidnapper.
BRASS:
But revenge
for a kidnapping
21 years after the fact?
Well, it is possible.
It may have taken that long
for the subjugated personality
to break free.
BRASS:
Maybe, uh, Miss Mirror
Has Two Faces
is playing us for fools.
We corner her with the evidence,
she goes nuts
sets the groundwork
for an insanity plea.
Forensic Psychology
is a science.
We have to stay open
to all the possibilities.
( knocking )
Captain?
Yeah?
The girl's parents are here
with her attorney.
Well, this ought
to be interesting.
Melissa...
Lady, I'm sorry,
but I don't know who you are.
I'm not Melissa;
I'm Tammy-- Tammy Felton.
Tammy, my name is Randy Painter.
I'm a defense attorney.
The Marlowes have hired me
to defend you.
I didn't kill my father.
Melissa, I don't know
what you've been told
but you're our daughter.
You were taken from us.
We've spent the last 21 years
looking for you.
My father was Joseph,
my mother was Mara
and they're both dead.
Bail's been set at
half a million dollars.
Are you looking at my necklace?
Your father bought this for me
when you were born
and you used to play with it.
And we're not going
to let you go to jai.
Right, Hank?
Raising even ten percent
won't be easy.
( sobbing )
Hank, she's not spending
another night away from us.
Whatever it takes.
When are we due in court?
The prelim's tomorrow
morning, 9:00 a.m.
Then I'd better hurry
with bail.
I just got back to the lab,
saw the smoke. What's up?
We're just working the case.
Yeah, we're disproving
spontaneous
human combustion.
We dressed a pig up
in a cotton dress
and torched it with a cigarette.
And what happened?
The pig's been reduced to ash.
The fat acted like
candle wax; burned hot,
slow and intense.
Nothing spontaneous about it.
You both knew
there would be a scientific
explanation for the human torch,
though, right?
Of course.
Did you find the wick?
The wick?
The what?
A piece of fabric
that's scorched
but not completely
burned...
like possibly
from the nightgown.
We found the same thing
at the crime scene.
It's called
the wick effect.
It's like an inside-out candle.
The fabric acts like a wick,
and the body burns inward
explaining the high
temperatures
which destroy the bone.
The fabric ends up scorched,
but not completely burned.
You knew about the ashes?
Why didn't you say something
when you gave us the case?
Well, in science
we learn through
experimentation, right?
Sometimes we need
to see it to believe it.
You guys did
a nice job.
Now you have to clean it up.
Well, I would've looked
like an idiot.
Thanks for covering.
Well, you can show
your appreciation
by, uh, cleaning up.
Done.
Thank you.
I got a call
that Melissa wanted to see me.
Thanks for coming.
Am I speaking to Melissa...
or Tammy?
Melissa.
I know who I am now...
after spending time
with my real parents.
I'm not an attorney.
There are no privileges here.
Whatever you say...
What are my chances... in court?
The evidence is damaging.
If I plead insanity...?
You have a lawyer.
Why are you asking me?
You wanted to help me.
When I ID'd Joe, you were kind.
I need you to testify
that I was not sane
at the time that I killed Joe.
My lawyer says
that would go a really long way
with a jury.
I'm not an expert.
But it doesn't matter.
You spent time with me.
You could answer questions
the right way.
I can't explain what happened
in that room today
but it's like...
the only memories I have
are of being a little kid.
The last 21 years
are a blank--
like they never happened.
Then you shouldn't have
any memories of me...
Tammy.
There is no Melissa, is there?
Get the hell out of here.
I'm gone.
( little girl voice ):
Don't go!
Don't leave me here with her.
( normal voice ):
Just practicing for court.
Not bad, huh?
Guard.
Hey, come on, we're going
to be late for the prelim.
Tammy Felton's prelim's been
postponed indefinitely.
What? Why?
She left town. Skipped bail.
How much did the parents lose?
Their house
and their life savings.
It's over.
Case closed.
We move on.
Right.
Brass, it's Catherine.
I need a credit card purchase
report on the Marlowes.
The last 24 hours.
Based on what?
Based on the fact
that the Marlowes are blind
when it comes to their daughter
and would do anything for her.
We have no idea
where she is.
Look, you're here, she's not
and we know that
you helped her flee
the jurisdiction.
What?
22 bus tickets bought
with your credit card
to 22 different states?
You made sure that
we couldn't track her.
Now, that's aiding and abetting
the flight of a suspected felon.
Wherever you think she is--
wherever you're planning
on meeting her--
she's not there.
She played you.
Now, if you'll just tell us
where she is,
we won't file charges, right?
Well, if she's
apprehended, yes.
Otherwise it's a felony.
You're going to jail.
Arrest us.
Think about what
you're doing.
We know exactly
what we're doing.
Melissa's free.
That's all that matters.
Frankie?
BRASS:
You have the right
to remain silent.
Anything you say can and will be
used against you
in a court of law...
Am I late?
Oh, you're worth waiting for.
You owe me one, Darin.
Owe you?
I'm the one that told you
the truth about your father.
And you knew exactly
what I'd do about it.
Where to?
Does it matter?