MAN: Isn't great to get back to nature.
You want to set camp here?
We can camp on the moon,
just give me the shovel.
Chill, chill.
You got paper?
I have what I need.
( insects buzzing )
Oh, my God!
Angie?
( buzzing continues )
Angie!
They're...
they're everywhere.
What the...?
That's a person.
( coughing )
DETECTIVE:
Hey.
Hikers found her.
Looks like a gunshot
to the head.
Did you find a weapon?
No.
I hate bees.
Just paper wasps
and they're having
too much fun to
worry about us.
I never get used to this part,
you know
when the bugs get going.
Just doing what
God intended...
...recycling us back
to the earth.
Hey, officer
can I borrow some
of your hot coffee, please?
Preservation.
John...
Paul...
George...
and Ringo.
Beetles.
No alkali fluids
in the dirt
so she wasn't killed here.
Whoever dumped her
must have been
in a hurry.
Didn't take the time
to bury her.
What do you think?
You got any of that beef jerky
you're always gnawing on?
You can eat?
I want to keep
these little fellas alive.
They're our first witnesses
to the crime.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
BROWN:
You guys want some coffee?
Please, cream with some
of that fake stuff.
There's nothing good
to eat around here.
Hi, sorry I'm late.
Hey, how's the body
with the bugs?
How do you know
about that already?
Hey, don't look at me.
We, uh, played a hunch;
checked with Homicide.
You were late.
What do you have for us?
A Paul Sorenson...
...missing since last night.
Last seen at home
of Richard Zeigler
in-- ooh-- Summerlin.
Summerlin... rich folks.
Warrick, you can work
this with Catherine.
Don't you have a
court date coming up?
Yeah, the DA asked me
to testify on chain of custody.
I could do that in my sleep.
Listen, juries need
to have confidence
in the evidentiary process.
Work with Catherine.
Break off
when you have to appear.
Yeah.
Bye.
Good luck.
Need help with your homicide?
No, Sara's going
to work with me.
You get a missing person.
Sheryl Applegate.
Her husband notified
the police that
she took the car
and headed to L.A.,
but she never showed up.
A few hours ago, PD found
her car at the bus station.
They requested a CSI.
She took the bus instead.
Case solved.
( laughing )
Hopefully you're right
but until
she's located
treat her car
like a crime scene.
Is everything okay?
You've been quiet
all night.
Yeah... I got a call
the other day
from Child Services
asking about
you and Lindsey.
I don't believe this.
They told me
they'd notified you--
some investigation--
that Eddie had made
a charge or something.
Yes, he's pissed off
because I won't let him
back into my life
so he sics
Child Services on me.
I never expected they were going
to talk to my friends.
Well, what
did they ask?
What did you say?
Well, I...
( door opens )
Hello?
Hi.
Sir, we're with
the Las Vegas Crime Lab.
We're here
about a Paul Sorenson.
I'm Richard Zeigler.
The cops told me
you were coming.
Here, please, come in.
Thank you.
Thanks.
Well, this, uh
where the Sorenson
was displayed.
Sorenson is a painting.
Paul Sorenson was an artist.
Early 1900s.
How dumb are we?
What's he know
about the
forensic analysis
of a friction ridge?
Right on.
I think
I may have surprised the guy
while he was stealing it.
I came downstairs to read.
By the time I got to the room,
he was gone
but the door was open.
Why don't we dust for prints?
What about
the security alarm?
Somebody disengaged it.
BROWN:
You thinking
what I'm thinking?
Oh, yeah, inside job.
So... was it a disaster
with Child Services?
Disaster?
What do you mean?
Well, my job
does take me away
from my daughter.
Nobody knows that
better than you.
Yeah, but you think
I'd say that?
Well, not
intentionally.
They just, you know,
know how to ask questions.
Are you finding anything?
We're working on it, sir.
Your young woman
from the mountains.
Do we know
who she is yet?
I gave her prints
to Homicide for ID.
There's the blanket
she was wrapped in.
Whoever she is, last day
on earth was not pleasant.
.38 caliber gun,
flush to the scalp.
Shot clean through,
right to left.
Bullet out
the other side.
Stellate pattern
and beveled wound
confirms the proximity
of barrel to scalp.
No question this was
an intimate killing.
GRISSOM:
Full of sound and fury
signifying what, Doc?
I took these.
Fracture to the nasal bone,
orbital bone, mandibular...
All facial fractures.
Typical for battered women.
These aren't fresh, are they?
The old fracture lines indicate
this woman was in a long-term
abusive relationship.
Any idea
how long she's been dead?
The elements
really got to her.
Grissom and his insects
are going to have
to figure that one out.
Have we lost you,
Grissom?
"The worms go in
"the worms go out
"the worms
play pinochle
on your snout."
Shakespeare again?
An old nursery rhyme.
ROBBINS:
A very special insect,
Dr. Seuss?
A muscid fly--
typical only in urban areas.
But you found her
in the mountains.
Hmm...
How many people have access
to your home--
keys and security code?
Just my wife and my two sons
and, uh...
my secretary.
WILLOWS:
Can you get them all here?
They might be able to help us
with evidence.
Hey, Catherine
check this out.
Helix, antihelix, helix rim,
tragus, antitragus.
I think the thief
must have pressed his head
against the wall
to check
if the painting was wired.
Come on, an earprint?
Hey, a jury
convicted
a first-degree murderer
based on a print
just like this
two years ago in Washington.
Yeah, I know, I know.
I'd like to see that one
on appeal.
Well, photograph and lift.
We'll have someone
to compare it to soon enough.
Okay, bear with me.
I mean, you're
one of ten guys
in the country
that understands
this stuff.
I think there's at least 15,
but go on.
What don't you get?
Insects arrive
at a corpse
in a specific order, right?
Like summer follows the spring.
And you can pinpoint
time of death
based on the type and age
of insects present
on the body?
I watch the insects mature
from eggs to larvae
to adults
and then count backwards.
Linear regression.
How old are those
creepy crawlers?
They're not done maturing yet.
Oh.
But when they are, I'll be able
to tell you how old they were
when I found the body.
Which will tell us
when the woman died.
I ID'd her body through AFIS,
and located her husband.
Let me guess, downtown,
the Fremont district?
You know,
I'm not even going to ask.
Synthesiomyia Nudiseta
is the Latin name.
SIDEL:
It's a muscid fly.
Only breeds in urban areas
but Grissom found
one on our girl
which means
she was probably killed downtown
and then carried
into the mountains.
Well, the neighbors heard
a gunshot
at their apartment
five days ago.
The "grieving"
husband...
His name is Scott Shelton.
What was her name?
Kaye screamed at me a lot,
that's for sure
but I didn't kill her.
In fact, I was
out of town last week
at a convention.
Yeah, in New Orleans soaking up
the gumbo. You told us.
When was the last time
you saw your wife?
Five days ago.
When I came back from my trip
she was gone.
You didn't think
to notify the police?
I keep
my personal business private.
If Kaye had
left me again,
I wasn't going
to broadcast it.
BRASS:
So this neighbor lady
who told me
that she heard a gunshot
and a woman scream
inside your apartment...
What, she just
imagined that?
It was probably our TV.
BRASS:
Uh-huh.
Mr. Shelton...
did your wife drive race cars?
You're kidding me?
No.
The two most common causes
of facial trauma
in adult women:
motor vehicle accidents
and domestic violence.
These are your wife's X rays.
Every face and neck fracture
your wife has sustained
over the last six years
is highlighted.
Kaye can get wild.
If I came home late with friends
I've wrestled her off me.
I admit that.
Three complaints against Scott
for spousal abuse
in the last two years.
Kaye was excitable.
Like I said
I've wrestled her
off me
but I never, ever laid
a hand on her.
How about a gun?
You have your hands full
with her.
So do you.
We're going
to investigate
your apartment.
Do we need a warrant
or are you going to play nice?
Come on over.
I've got nothing to hide.
We'll be the judge of that.
Detective Secula.
Mr. Stokes.
What's up?
You got stuck
on this one, too?
Yeah, well, missing person,
could be interesting.
Husband reports wife missing.
Car's at a bus terminal?
Come on.
Lady took a trip.
Didn't want him
to know where to.
Not much of a mystery.
Auto unit
been by yet?
No, they just
slim-jimmed.
We checked for a body,
didn't find one.
Big surprise.
Yeah.
No, I didn't touch a thing.
Something wrong?
We had dinner last week.
I thought it went great.
You never called.
That doesn't mean
I wasn't going to.
Is our missing person a redhead?
Yeah.
Call in a tow
to the CSI garage.
This case is now
officially interesting.
CATHERINE:
It's just like a fingerprint...
for your ears.
RICHARD:
Now, wait a minute.
Are you thinking
one of us did this?
Well, there's no
forced entry.
Someone shut off
your alarm.
That tells us
that we eliminate
the family first
before we widen
our investigation.
I'll tell you what, I'm not
putting that crap on my ear.
Well, we can
get a warrant.
RICHARD:
Oh, no, nobody's
getting a warrant
against this family.
We'll humor them,
and get this over with.
CATHERINE:
Thank you, sir.
See?
Mm-hmm, we got a match.
CATHERINE:
Let me see...
WARRICK:
Jason?
What?
Earprint talking.
Why would you steal from me?
Sir, are you going to
want to press charges?
No, no, no, no.
God, no, no, I just...
We'll get help for Jason.
I don't want court records.
CATHERINE:
Jason, do you
still have the painting?
What if I told you I sold it?
Well, that would be
selling stolen property
and you would be
arrested, no matter
what your dad says.
Okay.
Painting's in the trunk
of my car.
Can I get you guys
something to drink?
Soda, ale?
SIDEL:
No, thanks.
Not a lot of room for Kaye.
She's shy.
Does it get cold in
here in the winter?
Sometimes.
Why?
That's why you'd need a
blanket on the couch, huh?
A green one, I bet.
Looks like your gun's
just been cleaned.
Yeah, I, uh, cleaned it
before I left town.
Took out the garbage, too.
Does that make me
guilty of something?
No bullets missing here.
Bullets are missing here,
though.
I fired them at the
shooting range last month.
I go there with a
couple guys from work.
We're going to need
to borrow
your bullets.
This back door
lead to your car?
To a car.
I drive a different
demo every day.
Perk of the dealership.
You smell that, Grissom?
Did you do laundry
back here today?
I got news for you, Scott.
Bleach doesn't make
blood disappear.
You just can't see it
with the naked eye.
I have no idea
how that got there.
It "got there" when you shot
your wife in the head before
you wrapped her
in a blanket
and you dumped her
in the mountains!
Get your finger
out of my face, bitch!
Touch me again,
draw back a stump!
Look at her.
Sara!
Can't you control her?
Get him out
of here, Jim.
BRASS:
Come on.
You don't know a handful!
What is the matter with you?
I am a woman,
and I have a gun.
And look how
he treated me.
I can only imagine
how he treated his wife.
Thank you.
Hey.
Nicky, how's it going?
Good, good.
Are you putting one of Lindsey's
drawings into evidence?
If only her artwork brought
in this kind of dough
I wouldn't need to worry
about her college tuition.
Yeah, I heard your missing
person was a painting.
At least we solved
our case.
Oh...!
Keep walking.
Give me an evidence tag
for this painting.
Okay, now I know that
these are rich people
and it's just a painting
and nobody died, but...
this just doesn't
feel finished.
I know every time you say that,
I'm looking at more overtime.
I know.
( pager beeping )
You know what?
I've got to be somewhere.
Court.
Yeah, right.
Can you handle this from here?
Yeah.
Cool. I'll see you later.
Hey, Warrick.
Are you going to tell me?
What?
About Child Services?
Oh, I told them as far
as mothers are concerned,
you're the bomb.
Really?
Yeah, and I also told them
your ex is pretty screwed up.
No worries.
What do we need to
nail him at trial?
The neighbor puts him in
the apartment five days ago.
You tell me she's
been dead five days
and a jury is
going to jump
all over that
coincidence.
The post-mortem insects will
tell me when she was killed.
No, all I'm saying is five days
is what I need.
Jim, please don't try
and compromise my end
of the investigation.
Good luck.
The bullets from Scott's gun
are unusual.
Since we didn't find
the spent bullet
I sent one from the box
over to Trace.
Everything else stacks up.
He killed her.
What'd you get?
( sighs )
She's been dead three days.
Are you positive?
Not five?
Three.
My client was in New Orleans
three days
before his wife's body
was discovered on that mountain.
He couldn't possibly
have killed her.
Unless I misunderstand
what you've explained
to us, Mr. Grissom
your "linear regression."
You understand.
Okay, forget
time of death.
How does your client explain
Kaye's blood all over
his apartment wall?
Quite simply.
Scott has three prior complaints
for abuse.
What's to say the blood
didn't get there
during one of those
altercations?
"Altercations"...
upgraded from "wrestling?"
BRASS:
This is good.
Admitting to prior abuse
to cover up actual murder.
My client and I are leaving.
And Mr. Grissom, thank you.
Hey, tough luck about
the, uh, wife abuser
getting released.
There's no secrets around you,
are there, Conrad?
You think I wanted you
to whiff out on that?
Your reputation
as an entomologist
elevates this
entire crime lab
which elevates
my stature
by association.
Well, then, you must feel
very small today...
by association.
You're dropping the ball
in other areas though.
Administratively?
Did I miss
one of your status meetings?
Warrick Brown had one of my guys
sub for him in court.
So? I'm sure something came up.
Hey, he told my guy
it was an emergency
but I have it
on good authority
that he was gambling.
At the Monaco.
What?
That's right.
On CSI time.
I don't like him
using one of my guys
as a cover.
I figure if he brings anybody
down with him
it should be from your shift.
Don't you think?
( kettle whistling )
Sara?
Are you okay?
Fine. Yeah.
Did you sleep here?
I was working till 4:00 a.m.
I combed
every demo Scott's driven.
Zilch.
What's up?
I need you to do some background
for me on Warrick
without letting him know why.
Oh. Warrick-- your favorite CSI.
That's why I want you
to handle it
so that Ecklie
can't accuse me
of favoritism
if it turns out
that Warrick's clean.
What do you want to know?
This painting's a forgery?
Where does it say that?
I was reading up on Sorenson,
and I found a site that says
that 15% of all museum art
is fake.
It's not our job
to authenticate art.
Case is closed.
You're so right,
but if this is a forgery
we've got a new crime.
This ElectroThermal atomizer
is set at the excitation
wavelength for titanium
which was not used
in oil paint
before the 1950s.
So, an authentic Sorenson
would be titanium-free.
If it's present,
the canvas will fluoresce
and we've got a forgery.
Flip the lights.
CATHERINE:
Mm-hmm.
No doubt about it,
it's a fake.
Okay, so if the owner
purchased this painting
from a reputable
auction house
they would have run
a similar test to this?
Absolutely.
So, the kid stole the original
painting from his pop
and gave us back a forgery.
This kid's in
college, right?
Let's check
his dorm room.
There's no more hair.
Not even a trace.
No signs of foul play.
And the carpet's clean.
Yeah.
Yeah, too clean...
...which begs the question...
What lies beneath?
Hand me the phenothaline,
please.
You're checking
for blood?
Well...
I am checking...
to see why someone scrubbed
this carpet so clean.
If there is blood present...
...we'll know why.
It looks like our missing person
might be a homicide.
Right.
( knocking )
Hey.
Did you find out anything
about Warrick?
Um... I'm-I'm here
about something else.
You... you know how you say,
"We're the victim's last voice"?
Mm-hmm.
I thought it was our job
to speak for Kaye Shelton.
You don't crunch evidence
to fit a theory.
What if you hear
the victim's screams?
In the car, at the store.
You have empathy
for her, Sara.
You want someone to pay
for what was done to her.
That's normal.
You want to sleep with me?
Did you just say
what I think you said?
That way, when I wake up
in a cold sweat
under the blanket,
hearing Kaye's screams...
you can tell me it's nothing.
It's just empathy.
So, you planning a
little late-night luau?
Roast pig?
It's an experiment.
Maybe Kaye was dead
five days.
I thought your bugs
never made mistakes.
They don't. People do.
The victim was wrapped
in a blanket.
Normally a blanket or clothing
doesn't impact
insect maturation.
The insects usually
fight their way in anyway.
But I examined
the folds
in Kaye's blanket.
She was wrapped tight--
maybe tighter
than I realized
which would have decreased the
corpse's exposure to insects.
So, it took longer
for the insects to get in there?
And deposit their eggs.
Maybe two whole days.
I've wrapped Porky here
pretty tight.
Well, let me
ask you this.
You killed a pig
just for this?
This poor ham was already
on its way
to someone's
Christmas dinner table.
I mean, wouldn't a rabbit
be easier?
Got to be a pig.
Interestingly,
they're the most like humans.
Yeah, I've been saying that
since I was a rookie.
You're on your own, pal.
Thanks.
How's the case going?
Hey.
Dead end.
How about you?
Just got a hit
on one of our missing lady's
credit cards.
A motel.
Her abductor
sold her card
or is using it
himself.
What motel?
Four Aces.
That's right
around the corner
from where we found
her car.
I've got some uniforms
meeting us there.
Good job.
Are you Sheryl Applegate?
( door opens )
Man:
Oh, whoa, man!
Ow! Oh,
what's going on here?
Michael, shut up!
Las Vegas Police.
Your husband reported you
missing.
Can she put that gun away?
You, uh, you haven't
been abducted
have you, Mrs. Applegate?
Not really.
We found evidence of blood
in your car.
I saw an injured dog last week
and drove it to the vet.
( clears throat )
Uh, Nick,
let's get out of here.
( clears throat )
Wait!
What are you going to tell
my husband?
That you're okay.
You're going to have
to fill in the blanks.
( muffled laughter )
So the pig's insects matured
at a rate
consistent
with a five-day-old corpse?
Once I took the blanket
into account.
Your initial
computations
were wrong.
You went back,
adjusted conditions
and proved
actual time of death?
Five days, not three.
Which places the victim
with her husband
who's already guilty as sin.
Captain Brass
do you understand
Grissom's
insect evidence?
To a degree.
You know...
in a general way.
Do you think a jury
will understand your
"adjustments"?
Or do you think
they'll realize
your "conditions"
can make the evidence
say anything you want it
to say?
I can make a case to any jury
against Scott Shelton
for the murder of his wife.
Your arresting officer
can barely understand it.
I read the file.
Other than bugs
is there anything else?
Get something a jury
can understand, or move on.
Hello.
Hello, Mr. Zeigler...
Oh, oh, good,
you brought it.
WILLOWS:
Yes.
Come in.
Thank you.
That's a nice campus
you got there, Jason.
What?
We went by your dorm earlier
with the police here.
We'd like to ask a favor of you
Mr. Zeigler.
A private viewing
of the painting.
My God, my-my...
my Sorenson's a forgery?
Wait, I have
ten million dollars'
worth of forgeries?
BROWN:
No, sir.
The police recovered
your originals
in Jason's
dorm room today.
What?
I don't even know you.
BROWN:
What, did you have
an art major
do your fakes for you, Jason?
WILLOW:
Robbery checked
with your school.
They actually teach classes
in how to copy the masters.
My friends helped me out.
They didn't know what I was
doing with the copies.
And what exactly
were you doing?
Your son stole
all your originals
replacing them with forgeries.
But the other night,
his little scam was interrupted.
If the hook hadn't dislodged
from your Sorenson
you would have spent the rest
of your life
admiring a fake.
And you never even knew
the difference, did you, Dad?
You're right.
You don't know me.
Where are your pictures of me?
You're too busy staring
at your masterpieces,
and they're not even real!
I'm right here, Dad.
You don't even see me.
The police are going to want
to know
if you're pressing charges
this time.
I am.
You want my attention,
Jason?
You got it.
I heard you were going
into an autopsy.
How can you just move on
to another case?
They're laughing at us.
You know that, right?
They think we're
a couple of science nerds.
They threw out
our findings.
That body should be up
in a few minutes,
Mr. Grissom.
Thank you, David.
You know, there was
a murder recently
in a village
on the other side
of the world.
Every man in the
village denied
having any part of it.
The victim's throat
had been slashed
with a shovel.
So this one guy--
I guess you could call
him a science nerd--
asked all the men
in the village
to bring their shovels
to the center of town
and hold them
spade-side up.
And he waited.
Eventually, flies
started showing up
on one specific shovel
looking for microscopic bits
of blood and flesh.
"First witness to a crime."
The investigator got
his murderer, and...
...and forensic science
was born.
Sung T'su, 1235 A.D.
You call 800 years ago
recent?
To an astronomer, it is.
But then people forgot
about forensic science,
didn't they?
And they had to be
reminded again
by Francesco Redi
in the 1600s.
And again by Bergeret d'Arbois
in the 1800s.
Every civilization learns
what it needs to know
and the next one
forgets it.
The sheriff...
Well... it's not personal.
We're part of a cycle.
Yeah, they laughed
at fingerprints
70 years ago,
and now it's law.
Except somebody had to push
for prints.
And you're standing there saying
"All things in their own time."
You're confused, right?
Yes.
That's the best place
for a scientist to be.
( doors opening )
My body's here.
Kaye Shelton...
Shall we?
SIDEL:
You gave her
a bath, huh?
Routine cleaning.
We had to do it sometime.
Doc, what's this
blue mark here?
Why didn't we see this
at the autopsy?
It was under a gallon of blood.
But the blue's embedded;
it won't wash away.
Didn't you say the suspect's
ammunition was in Trace?
Yeah.
"Lead, copper, zinc...
Teflon."
Teflon?
And? So?
Strand of hair from our lady
in the mountains.
The blue dust
from around her entrance wound--
that's from
the bullet's impact.
It's made of Teflon.
Now look at the next specimen.
The bullet is
from Scott's personal
ammo supply
which I test-fired.
See, the Teflon disintegrated
into blue powder
at the moment of impact.
You're gonna leave me,
is that what you think?!
No, Scott, no!
And the guys are gonna see
a woman walk out on me?
No! Scott, no!
You just try...
( gunshot )
You did very good.
But this is just more
circumstantial evidence.
We're a long way
from a conviction.
But we can bury him
under evidence.
You're the one
who's always saying
it's better to have
one piece
of forensic evidence
than ten eyewitnesses.
What, do you tape everything
I say?
You still have
to educate the jury.
On bullets.
It's got to be
easier than bugs.
Less Latin.
( handcuffs clicking )
BRASS:
You know, I've been waiting
three days to do this.
No, make that five days.
Let's go.
( door opens )
Hi.
I checked out Warrick.
His story about missing
court was, uh... lame.
I got this
surveillance tape
from the Monaco.
He was in the casino.
I'm sorry.
Thanks.