My name is Royce Harmon.
I reside at 7642 Carpenter
Street, Las Vegas, Nevada.
I am 41 years of age...
...and I'm going
to kill myself.
I'd like to say
"I love you" to my mother
Paige
and my sister Gina.
I'm so sorry.
I never wanted
to put you through this.
I just can't do it anymore.
I love you, Mom...
( gunshot )
( helicopter flying overhead)
( siren flipping on and off )
Here comes the nerd squad.
I hate the legwork.
I'm telling you, that Deputy
Chief job better come in soon.
I don't know how much longer
I can put up
with these damn
public appearances.
Gentlemen...
Hey, guys, take
a break, huh?
Suicide.
You think so, huh?
You got the sleeping
bag for easy cleanup
the bathtub to
catch the bullet
open window so the stench
alerts the neighbors...
God bless him.
( coughs )
Oh, geez...
( clears throat )
Pupa, stage three.
English. I'm not
an entomologist.
It's the third stage
of larva metamorphosis.
This guy's been dead seven days.
That's a maggot,
and he stinks.
Oh, good, it's almost 11:00.
Maybe if I'm lucky
I can break out of here
in time for a shot
at the first rack
of the Krispy Kreme.
I think we may have
our suicide note.
Harmon:
I never wanted
to put you through this.
I just can't do it anymore.
I've lost hope.
I love you, Mom...
( gunshot )
( both gasp )
Oh, my God!
Go upstairs, Gina.
This can't be happening.
We're so sorry about this,
Ms. Harmon.
I can only imagine how difficult
this must be for you.
No, you don't understand.
This is his picture...
but that's not my son's voice.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
Hello?
Ooh...
My God.
Hi.
( gasps )
Sorry.
Welcome to Forensics.
Gil Grissom. I'm your supervisor
on graveyard.
Holly Gribbs.
Nice office.
Thanks. Would you mind
taking off your jacket
and rolling up your sleeve?
For what?
I need a pint
of your blood.
It's customary
for all new hires.
Why?
So many reasons.
I-I haven't even
clocked in yet.
( people laughing
in background )
Attention, Command
One more, baby, one more.
Hey.
There he is.
What's up?
99. You and me,
dead heat.
Next crime solved gets
promoted to CSI III, man.
Yeah, yeah, choice of shift,
$8,000 raise
extra week vacation-- oh-ho,
it's all about Cabo, bro.
Twenty bucks, by the end
of shift, I'm the man.
Is there anything
you won't bet on?
Nah.
It's college
football season, man.
I won eight of ten
this weekend.
Kilt 'em. Outside
the Huskers and them
punk-ass Irish
I'm up about four G's.
Hmm, what's the line on us?
On us?
I'm like Tiger, man--
I'm heavily favored.
Come on, give me a winner
for tomorrow.
Ah... Green Bay, minus seven
and a half over Niners.
Always go with the
better quarterback.
Uh-huh.
Cool.
Hey, good luck tonight, man.
Thanks. You, too, Nick.
I hope you get that
"trick roll" noise.
You'll never crack that
in a shift, never.
Yeah, well, we'll see, and I
hope the Pack wins by seven.
We scrutinize the crime scene,
collect the evidence
recreate what happened
without ever having been there.
Pretty cool, actually.
I just got out of the Academy--
I already know this.
Of course you do.
Then if you'll just sign these
waivers for personal injury
or death while in the line of
duty, we can begin our shift.
Mmm...
What's the matter?
Um... I'm kind of light-headed.
Sit down, sit down.
You're probably low
on blood sugar.
I've got just the thing.
Here, try one of these.
No offense, but I
don't think I want
to eat anything
that's been in
this office.
Is there a grasshopper
in here?
( crunching )
When we get some free time, try
and catch up on your reports.
I'm getting a lot of heat
from the Sheriff's Office.
There I said it.
Administration,
not my favorite thing.
All right,
here we go.
Nick Stokes, 414, trick roll.
Victim found drugged and robbed
at the scene.
Warrick Brown, 407,
home invasion, forced entry.
Person reporting crime fired
multiple rounds at the suspect.
Suspect's condition is unknown.
Anyone seen Catherine Willows?
Okay, give me a kiss.
Mommy's got to go catch
some bad guys.
I'll pick her up in the morning.
Bye, sis.
Bye.
I love you!
Brass:
So your mother is
Lieutenant Jane Gribbs
from Traffic, is that right?
Yes, sir.
Well, congratulations,
Gribbs.
You're the...
You're the fifth person
I've been forced to hire.
We're the number
two crime lab
in the country.
We solve crimes
most labs render unsolvable.
Now what makes you think
you belong here?
Sir, with all due respect
I thought the key to being
a lucid crime scene investigator
was to reserve judgment
until the evidence vindicates
or eliminates
assumption.
You're prejudging me.
I graduated with honors
in criminal justice at UNLV.
Yeah, so?
That's not fair.
Fair? Well, you think putting
a juiced-in
lieutenant's daughter
on this shift is fair?
You know, I've been
in the field 22 years.
I've seen it all.
I've seen people like you
come and go, and you know what?
They're nothing
but headaches and bad press.
Dismissed.
Fine.
Think you got through to her?
You're scheduled to appear
at an autopsy at 12:30 a.m.
They're cutting up that bozo
put a hole in his chest.
Take her with.
I think every new hire
should experience
an autopsy
on their first night.
( siren wailing )
( child crying )
Woman:
It's okay, shh.
Willows:
Ma'am...
are you all right?
She's fine.
She's just a little
shook up is all.
Somebody want to tell us
what happened here tonight?
My wife invited
her drunk friend
to stay here
so he could get
back on his feet.
Two weeks tops,
she says.
That was
six months ago.
( child screaming )
Jimmy, Jimmy!
Please take your sweaty feet
off the head pillow.
They stink.
( glass breaking )
Here's a 20-- twice as much
as you came with. Hit the road.
( yelling )
Open up!
( wife screaming )
Call 911.
( child crying )
That was it.
I feared for my wife
and my baby.
Let's put the
baby to bed.
What do you think?
Oh, he's lying.
That's why I took this job.
I can always tell
when whitey's talking
out his ass.
It's a gift.
It's also your 100th.
Yeah, that, too.
So tonight you might say
I'm extra suspicious.
Why don't you print that tread
and see how good you are?
Why are you doing that?
It's just procedure, sir.
We just want to make sure
the shoe on the suspect
is the same shoe
that kicked down your door.
Wait... Wait a minute.
What's the matter?
Sir, after you shot
the deceased, did you move
re-dress, or alter
the body in any way?
No, why?
Talk to me.
The left shoe's
tied differently.
Sir, in the six months
that the victim lived with you
did you ever wear his shoes?
No, why would I do that?
You willing to sign
a statement to that effect?
Sure.
Sir, what happened
to your pinkie toe?
I tripped over a rattle.
You got to breathe
through your ears, Gribbs.
First dead body, ma'am?
Yes, sir, but I'll be okay.
To tell you the truth,
he looks fake.
I hate to put a damper
on your night, Grissom
but it looks like we got
ourselves a homicide after all.
You see, if the victim had
extended his arms like...
Here, I'll show you.
Give me your hands.
And pushed the trigger
with his thumbs, like so...
( echoing gunshot )
The wound would look like this.
He's right, honey.
This wound's too big.
This person was shot
from six to seven feet away.
It's like somebody
stood over him and, bam!
( echoing gunshot )
Criminal homicide.
Let's see what God
would have to say.
Are you okay?
I'm sorry, sir.
I can't take the smell.
Oh, God, restroom?
Right down the hall
to your right.
She is cute.
How soon does
the Captain want
that one out?
Eight hours.
Whoo!
( gasping )
Help! Help me!
( pounding on door )
There were bodies.
I could feel
them breathing.
Oh, God!
It's okay, Holly,
it's all right.
You assholes!!
There.
Okay?
What's up, fellas?
We got a call
about a trick roll.
Right there.
Room 1413.
Hey.
Mr. Laferty?
Well, what's left
of him, anyway.
I'm Nick Stokes,
with Criminalistics.
You mind if I ask you
a few questions?
She got everything--
my wallet, my ID...
Hell, she even got
my wedding ring.
Did you two
have a nightcap?
You think she
could've slipped
you something?
Nah, I can't drink.
I got this bum ticker.
Look, Officer, I...
Nick.
You can call me Nick.
Nick, I...
I love my wife.
We've been married
31 years now.
I've never cheated
on her before.
I come into town
for this convention
and I'm setting
in the lounge
minding my own business,
when this...
sweet-smelling brunette
came up to me and...
Next thing I know, she's
nibbling on my earlobe and...
( laughing )
Well, my goodness.
Look at you.
For a second there,
I thought I was your age again.
We've been seeing more and more
of these the past 48 hours.
Let's take a look.
Open your eyes
wide for me.
Sunny side up.
Now say "ah."
Ah.
Was she hot?
( chuckling moan )
Attaboy.
Mr. Laferty, your
eyes look okay
but I notice
some discoloration
around the inside
of your lips.
Have you always
had that?
No. What the hell is that?
I'll swab your gums
see if we can find out
what made you pass out.
Grissom:
You know, my first robbery
solved was a store like this.
When we caught the guy,
the owner was so happy
that he gave me a
dozen farm fresh eggs
out of his cooler.
You're trying
to cheer me up,
aren't you?
Yes, I am.
How am I doing?
Pretty good.
Good.
Okay, look, this was
a routine robbery.
Dust for prints,
check the videotape
take lots of fun photos.
I'll be back in
about an hour
to pick you up.
Okay.
If you get done early
use channel seven
on your walkie.
What's up?
Hey, rookie.
Hair fibers
from the home invasion.
Take a look.
Tell me what you see.
I see a lot of things.
Look at the end
of the follicles.
Oh, yeah, you know,
I see, like
little tiny seeds
or sacs or something.
That's pulp
when the human hair
is yanked out
like this.
Ow! Damn, man.
Look, you see
the seeds?
Hair only comes
out in that form
when it's yanked
or pulled
signifying a struggle.
You know what?
I got to go.
Tell Grissom,
when he gets back
I went to Homicide
to do a follow-up
on the husband.
Peace.
Yeah.
Now, how long
is this gonna take?
I'm losing business
because of you.
Ma'am, I told you,
if you let them in
it will contaminate
the scene.
Oh, contaminate, my ass!
What the hell
difference does it make?
You ain't
gonna catch 'em.
You never do.
Sir, I'm on your side.
I just want
to clear you.
Then clear me.
I already told
you everything.
I understand that.
The evidence tells us
something different.
So I'm going
to ask you again,
just one more time--
before you shot
the deceased
did a struggle ensue?
( woman shrieks )
I've got a gun.
Woman:
What are you doing?
( shrieking )
( gunshots )
Call 911.
( child crying )
I must've tied
the laces wrong.
I'm sorry, I...
I know I should've
told you earlier but...
I was nervous.
I mean...
I took a man's life here.
You don't believe me,
do you?
This is Holly Gribbs
requesting backup
at Junk's on West Owens,
over.
This is Catherine Willows.
Are you in danger?
Uh, we're getting there.
This is my popsicle stand--
I'll defend it
to the hilt
if I have to!
So, this is it, huh?
The $8,000 Q-Tip.
Well, you're the chemist.
I just need to know what
knocked the old man out.
In 20 seconds, this'll give us
a complete chemical breakdown
right down
to the atom.
But I'm going to
warn you, though
These mouth swabs
don't always read.
Vaginal swabs,
no problem.
Anal swabs-- money.
Anal swabs?
Anal swabs.
Ouch.
( beeps )
( machine whirs quietly )
Dude, you get NFL-2K
for Dreamcast?
Yeah. Bought it
the day it came out.
Those graphics are killer,
aren't they?
My team's
the Falcons.
Who do you use?
Randy Moss.
( whirs and beeps )
( whirring slows )
It didn't take,
did it?
A hint of saliva;
some denture adhesive...
That's it.
Sorry, man.
All right, put the gun down.
What?
We're getting robbed again now?
Everything okay here?
Yes, ma'am.
Control, Junk's
is a Code Four.
Officer:
Copy that.
You the new girl?
Yeah. Hi, I'm
Holly Gribbs.
Thanks.
I'm Catherine Willows.
And I'm Lesley Stahl.
Look, let's forget
the formalities.
Which one of you people's
gonna clean my counter here?
Let me tell you
something, lady--
if you don't care
about catching the suspect
neither do we.
We're out of here.
You can pick your
gun up tomorrow.
You can do that?
No.
Ow!
Damn!
Blunt force
trauma case.
Bermuda Hills Country Club.
Pregnant wife
caught her husband
in bed with
another girl.
What do you think?
Malicious intent?
Little bit, yeah.
( camera clicks )
How's it coming?
It's coming.
Whose blood
is that?
The new girl's.
Would you like to donate?
Hell, no.
How'd the follow-up
go with the husband?
Boe tells me
you were onto something.
The story's
changed a bit.
Now he says
there was a struggle.
Said he stepped on his shoe
while they were fighting.
You believe him?
At first, no
but now...
Hell, I don't know
what to think.
You ever see the movie
The Exorcist?
Yeah.
The old priest
and Father Karras
are about to exorcise
the demon.
Father Karras explains
that he's recorded
the little girl's voice
and he's broken
down the spirit
into three distinct
personalities.
But the old priest
quickly corrects him--
"There is only one."
Forget about the
husband, Warrick.
Forget about
the assumptions.
your promotion.
These things will
only confuse you.
Concentrate on what cannot lie--
the evidence.
Follow...
the reason we're having
this conversation.
Follow the shoe.
( sighs )
Well, I'll be damned.
Tripped over
a rattle, my ass.
Remember this
from your suicide case?
Minute I pulled it,
I knew something
wasn't right.
The impression's
perfect--
maybe too perfect.
Take a gander.
What are those red particles?
Latex flakes.
From what?
Protective
gloves, maybe
but the way I figure it,
this son of a bitch is smart--
probably planted
the damn prints.
So on a hunch,
I chemically tested the flakes.
Guess what it
was laced with?
Lecithin.
That chemical's found
in cooking spray
isn't it?
If latex rubber
and cooking spray
went on a blind date,
how would the night end?
A lot better than ours did.
I know,
Pink Floyd's not your thing.
I have on cowboy boots.
I work in a lab.
What makes you think
Dark Side of the Moon
synched to The Wizard of Oz
is going to warm my damn barn?
I just thought
it'd be something different.
You want to
be different?
Pin me up against a wall;
lay one on me like you mean it.
You're slacking, pal.
How long till
we get a hit?
It could be four minutes,
could be four days
but you can bet your ass
she'll give you something.
She always does.
Pin you against a wall?
Look, um, I got
to be honest.
This isn't me.
I was pushed into it by my mom.
She's a lieutenant in Traffic.
She's never going
to get out of Traffic. so, um--
I'm fulfilling
her dreams, not mine.
I can sit here
and I can baby you
and I can tell you to quit
but I'm not going to do that,
because I really love my job.
We're just
a bunch of kids
that are getting paid
to work on puzzles.
Sometimes there's a piece
that's missing.
Sometimes we solve it
in one night.
So you think I should stick
with it?
Stick with it?
The cops?
Forget it.
They wouldn't know fingerprints
from paw prints
and the detectives...
chase the lie.
We solve. We restore
peace of mind
and when you're a victim,
that's everything.
Stick with it.
At least
until you solve your first
and if after that you don't feel
like King Kong on cocaine...
then you can quit
but if you stay with it
my hand to God,
you will never regret it.
Dispatcher:
Catherine Willows,
cut your lunch short.
You got a 428.
Copy.
Brass:
If you want me to call
Judge Cohen at 4:00 in the morning
you'd better bring me something
more than a damn toenail.
Captain, you've got
to make that call.
If you don't, he'll walk.
And what do you got?
Hair fibers. Big deal.
So there was a struggle.
I mean, who gives a corn cob?
The guy was protecting
his wife and kid.
I've got the toenail.
If I can get a warrant
and match the husband's shaving
to his toe
I can prove
that the suspect's foot
was inside the victim's shoe.
That alone will establish it was murder.
The guy lived there, Warrick.
Maybe he put on
the victim's sneaker and fetched
the paper one morning.
I have a sworn statement stating
he never wore the victim's shoe.
You don't even know
the toenail was the vic's.
It can't be.
He was wearing socks.
Not good enough.
Not good enough?
Look, I said no, Brown,
damn it!
( phone rings )
Hey, we're not
done, Warrick.
You stay right there.
Criminalistics, Brass.
Grissom:
We've got a name on the
suicide case, sir. He's local.
He's local, good.
I'll phone the judge
for a warrant.
Hey, Warrick,
I guess we're all done now.
Hey, do you mind closing
the door behind you?
I got to make
an important call.
We'll talk about your
little foot fetish later.
Judge Cohen, please.
Officer:
A white female,
mid-20s.
Said she passed out
behind the wheel.
Thought you might want
to check it out.
All right. Thanks, brother.
Hi.
Nick Stokes,
Criminalistics.
Mind if I take a look?
I don't know what happened.
I remember this song
that was playing
on the radio.
I just don't remember
passing out.
Say "ahhh..."
What?
You know, ahhh...
Ahhh...
No discoloration.
I don't see
anything criminal here.
Take her to
the hospital
have her checked out.
Well, might as well roll the
dice; take that ass-whooping.
( siren whooping )
Police!
Put your hands
on top of your head
and walk backwards
towards me.
I'm ID. Check the badge.
I'm from Criminalistics.
Keep your mouth shut
and follow
my instructions.
Now get down
on your knees.
I won't get down on my knees
for anybody. You can shoot me.
I said get down on your knees!
Hey!
What the hell
are you doing?
That's Warrick Brown from ID.
Put those guns away.
Sorry, Judge,
we got a call
from a neighbor
about a black man
outside your house.
We responded.
All right,
you caught him.
Congratulations.
Clear out of here
before you wake the neighbors.
Yes, sir.
Dispatch, please be advised
Judge Cohen's residence,
a Code 4: false alarm.
Brown, what the hell
are you doing?
I'm sorry, Judge.
Captain Brass wouldn't call you
for a search warrant.
I got a whopper on the line
with a 100-pound test.
You got a winner for me?
I'll make it worth your while,
you give me a name.
Favre.
Oh, I knew it. Listen, kid,
I'll make a deal with you.
You put $5,000 down
on the Pack for me
I'll give you a blank warrant.
All I ask
is that you have
the ticket in my chambers
before kickoff.
You do that, I'll square it
with your Captain.
No problem, Judge.
A staged suicide.
You're kidding, right?
I swear on my kids
I've never seen that
man before in my life.
Then how the hell
did your fingerprints
wind up at the scene?
We talked to the family.
The deceased
didn't even know
any Paul Millanders.
Oh, I...
Hi, Sergeant.
Would you mind if I, uh...?
Oh, you want
a whack at him, Grissom
be my guest.
Hi, Mr. Millander,
my name's Gil Grissom.
I work in Criminalistics.
May I ask you a few questions?
Sure.
Do you have any hobbies?
Make model airplanes,
make toys
wind chimes for the backyard,
that sort of thing?
No, why?
Well, we found some particles
of latex on your thumbprint.
Would you have any reason
to have access
to that particular
substance?
Well, yeah.
Yeah, sure. At-at my job.
Wow, you made all these?
Yes, sir,
everything
from scratch.
We mold, carve, shape,
paint and authenticate.
Excellent work.
These seem very real.
Thanks.
You ever make any rubber hands?
Sure we do, uh...
This is our best seller
right here.
Sold 10,000 of those units
last Halloween.
Even used my own
hand for the mold.
These are your prints.
Yeah, why? What does that mean?
It means you're free to go.
He's not the guy.
Grissom, are you sure?
This explains the latex
and the lecithin.
You need oil to make a print.
Anyone who purchased
one of these hands could be the killer
and what's worse,
he's proficient in forensics.
Hey, Dr. Leever!
Hey, what's up, man?
I got your page.
Have you had any
trick rolls lately?
A ton of 'em. Why?
I've had six pros
come through the ER in the past two nights
all with two distinct
similarities.
Every girl has
been mysteriously
knocked unconscious
and we found some
skin discoloration.
Skin discoloration?
Where? Their lips?
No, their nipples.
We meet again...
May I see your
discoloration?
You wanna give me
20 bucks?
You wanna do time?
You know, I just came
from a trick roll downtown.
The victim's mouth
had similar blotching.
Chances are, whatever
he ingested orally
you absorbed through
your nipples
knocking you both out.
So I'll give you a choice.
You give back the old man
his belongings
you tell me what
you girls are using
and I won't have
you charged
with attempted murder.
Which is it?
Eyedrops?
No, it's scopolamine.
It's a chemical used
for motion sickness.
This eyedrop bottle's a front.
One drop of this stuff
and she's out cold.
We're ruling out
suicide.
The evidence leads us
to believe that it was
in fact a homicide.
Then he was murdered?
I believe so.
You know...
this may sound funny
but I feel better knowing
that he didn't take
his own life.
To me that would
never sit right.
He was such a good man...
We'll find him,
Ms. Harmon.
I promise you.
There is always a clue.
I'll find him.
( phone ringing )
Nurse, excuse me.
I'm Catherine Willows
from Criminalistics
and I'm here for the 428.
Hi, Laura.
I'm Catherine.
How you doin', kiddo?
What's that?
Well, that is a camera.
I'm gonna take
a few photographs.
Before I do that, though,
could you do me a favor?
Could you take a look
at this drawing
and point out to me...
where he touched you?
( whispers ):
Can you just show me?
Can you hold
my dolly for me?
I'd love to.
Not just hold her.
Take her away to your house.
To my house? Why?
Because I don't want the same
thing that happened to me
to happen to dolly.
It's okay.
It's gonna be okay, sweetheart.
You're off the case.
What? Why?
Why? you deliberately went
over my head, Brown.
The phone call from the judge
saved your job,
but not your ass!
I want you
shadowing Gribbs.
A robbery just came in.
You can't do that.
Me and Nick are tied!
Tough!
Grissom! Have Warrick shadow
Gribbs for the next three weeks
or until Nickie makes his
hundredth, whatever comes first.
I hate your ass, you know that?
People walk every day
because of you-- every day!
That's enough, Warrick.
Let's go!
Damn it, Gris.
I had his ass too!
Yes, you had him
and the minute you started
thinking about yourself
instead of the case,
you lost him.
There is no room
for subjectivity
in this department,
Warrick.
You know that we handle
each case objectively
without presupposition
regardless of race, color,
creed, or bubble gum flavor.
Okay?
Let's go.
( Indistinct police
radio transmission )
Sorry you gotta baby-sit.
Yeah, I'm sorry too.
Control, P-4442 arrive.
Okay, go inside.
Dust for prints.
Make sure you take
plenty of photographs...
Photographs. Be thorough.
Don't worry.
I got the same speech
from Mr. Grissom.
Good. Look, I gotta
run an errand.
You'll be okay
on your own?
You kidding?
I'm fired up, ready to go.
Besides, there's
an officer here.
( knocking )
Morning.
Gil Grissom, Forensics.
I'm taking over the case
for Warrick Brown.
Mind if I come in?
How can I help you?
I need to give you a pedicure.
Come again?
I have a warrant
for your toenails.
A warrant?
What? Am I a suspect?
I already gave you
a sworn statement.
A statement's just
a public record of your version.
We still need proof.
Well, I'd love to help you,
but I already cut them.
May I see where you discarded
the clippings?
I flushed them down the toilet.
May I see your toilet?
I'll be right back.
Excuse me.
Control, this is P-3901.
I'm going to be on break
for about 15 minutes.
Mommy?
Shh. We don't want
to wake up Jeremy.
Mommy, what's wrong?
Mommy just kind
had a rough night.
I couldn't drive here
fast enough
to tell you
how much I love you.
I know, Mommy.
I love you, too.
Nope, loser.
Give me the next item
up for bid.
It's nasty.
No, striation.
Whenever two objects are broken
there occurs
what we call striae--
two unique connecting points.
If I can match the nail
in the sneaker
to the suspect's clippings...
Alcatraz!
The brother was right,
wasn't he?!
Uh-huh!
Yeah!
Careful, Boe,
you'll hurt your back.
What's up, man?
Gimme Packers.
One second...
Man ( over radio ):
Warrick, come in.
This is Warrick. Go ahead.
It's Grissom. We got him.
Whoo-hoo-hoo-hoo, yeah!
I'll be right there.
Who do you want now?
Gimmie Niners for five dimes.
( man yelling outside ):
Open up!
Open the door...
What are you gonna do?
Don't ask questions.
Just open the door.
You son of a bitch!
( three gunshots )
( baby crying in background )
Call 911.
( echoing ):
Do it!
Hey, weren't you supposed
to be shadowing Holly?
Oh, she's cool.
She's doing prints
on that 407.
There's an officer there.
I'm out.
Excuse me, ma'am.
Hi. Uh... can I help you?
I'm the neighbor
from across the way
and I just saw
a cop car leave.
Is everything okay?
Yeah, we had a robbery,
but everything's fine.
Oh, okay.
( knocking )
Room service.
You're kidding me.
My stuff!
You found my stuff!
Yeah, yeah, your wallet,
your cash, credit cards...
wedding ring...
Oh, thank God.
Okay, next time
you wanna take a shot
go to the dice table.
At least if you crap out,
you can go home broke
instead of busted,
you know what I mean?
I sure do.
Thank you.
Congratulations, Nickie my boy.
You are now a C.S.I.
Level III.
Whoo!
( clapping )
Good job, Nick.
Thanks.
Uh, hey, Warrick, listen
I heard about the whole thing
with the shoe and...
Forget it, man.
It's all you.
Thanks.
Let's get some breakfast.
It's on me!
Sorry to break up your party
but I need grave
to pull a double.
Holly Gribbs has been shot.
She's in surgery now.
Apparently the suspect
returned to the scene.
They don't think
she's gonna make it.
Brown, I'm putting you
on administrative leave
pending a full report
of your whereabouts.
So wash your faces;
change your socks.
You have a long day
ahead of you.