( clock quietly ticking )
( creaking )
( gasping )
( screaming ):
NO!
( sirens blaring )
( indistinct radio transmission)
Excuse me.
My name's Gil Grissom.
I'm with
the Las Vegas Crime Lab.
Please help us.
I'll certainly try.
Is that the ransom note?
Yeah. They don't even say
how much money they want.
They just say that
they'll call us
in six hours.
Have you let anyone else
touch this note?
Police, a relative, anyone?
N-no, just us. Why?
Well,
because the person
who touched it before you
has your son...
and he's just left us
the first piece of the puzzle.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
Jim, Dispatch said
this is a kidnapping?
Divorce situation?
No papers filed.College sweethearts.
Neighbors say they're
the salt of the earth.
So this could have been
legitimate?
They have a
security system.
Never put it on.
They say how come?
They feel safe
in the neighborhood.
Check the premises?
Attic, wine cellar,
crawl space.
No four-month-old baby.
Nice digs.
Yeah, guy got rich
off some dot-com outfit.
Moved here from Oregon
two years ago.
Bet they wished
they hadn't today.
Are you sure he won't hear
a click or something?
He won't.
And if he asks,
you and your wife are alone.
Question him about your son.
Ask to hear him breathing.
Anything
to keep the guy talking.
Understood?
I don't know.
Yeah, yeah.
Okay.
Built my own business.
I can handle any
kind of pressure.
GRISSOM:
Was this yours?
Yeah.
May I ask
when you opened it?
I don't know.
Um, sometime
after we called 9-1-1.
You mind if I, uh...?
No, no, go ahead.
You have any more of these?
In the fridge.
Thanks.
WOMAN:
Do my boys have to be here?
I think this is
hard enough for them
without having
to hear the facts.
BRASS:
I understand,
but it's best
for our investigation if we keep
the whole family together.
It's okay, Mom.
You were saying,
Mrs. Anderson?
Um...
I got up at 4:30,
like I usually do
to feed Zack.
I'm still breast-feeding.
And I went down
to Zacky's room.
I looked in his crib
and he was gone.
He wasn't there.
And I felt around for him
and that's when
I found the letter
saying that he
had been taken
and I...I don't know.
I-I think
I screamed...
You screamed, Mom.
I jumped
out of bed
and I went to her,
and that's when we called 9-1-1
from the upstairs hallway.
9-1-1-1-1-1.
Give me the phone,
Robbie.
We're going to need
a piece of the baby's clothing.
Something from
his hamper,
if possible.
We're going to use scent dogs
throughout the neighborhood.
I'll go see what I can find.
No, I know what he wears.
I'll go with you.
GRISSOM:
I'd also like
to get blood samples
from each family member.
Why?
Well, the sooner
we can eliminate
the expected hairs and fibers
from within the household
we can begin
looking for outsiders.
Is it going to hurt?
I hope not.
Sara?
Yeah?
Take this ransom
note to Q.D.
Typewritten ransom note?
Kidnapper was organized.
I think it's ink-jet
not typewriter.
I'll get it
to Questioned Documents
check for origination prints,
the works.
Take every computer
and printer
from the Anderson
house with you.
You think the suspect
printed the ransom note
from inside the house
while they were sleeping?
I'm not thinking
anything yet.
Nick?
Yo.
No, thanks,
I'm an iced tea man.
It's not a
refreshment.
It's an experiment.
Now take this
to the lab
in a controlled space,
72 degrees Fahrenheit
and open it.
Keep this in the same
room-temp space.
Okay, then what?
Process, Nick, process.
Baby's bedroom
window is open
and the ladder's
still out there.
So canvass the whole
grounds from outside to in.
I'm all over it
like a cheap suit.
You see this spiderweb?
Damn, Warrick!
I'm sorry.
Your ticker okay?
What spiderweb?
Right here.
Kind of hard to get a baby
out of a window
climb onto a ladder
without messing up this web,
don't you think?
Well, it could
have happened
after the abduction.
Spiders can build
one of these things
in a few hours.
Warrick?
What are you doing?
Go around.
Ooh, you're right
on the golf course.
That must be nice.
Steve likes it.
I never cared for the game.
( sighs )
That one's my favorite
but Zacky, he, uh...
he liked another one.
Here it is.
( chuckles )
There's a little spit-up on it.
He liked the way
the fabric felt on his skin.
Oh, God...
It's okay. It used to happen
to me with my daughter
if I didn't get to
her right on time.
I can't believe that
this is happening to us.
I'll get this to our guys.
What you got?
Two hair,
separate and distinctive.
Ah, the plot thickens.
You smell something?
I smell these dirty
diapers over here.
It's like a household cleanser.
There's a pine smell.
Probably used to clean
that diaper pail.
No, it's stronger than that.
And it's emanating
from this specific spot.
Whew.
Baby was killed
before it even left the house.
Guy tried to cover
his tracks.
SIDLE:
What do you mean
you haven't checked for prints?
It's a ransom letter.
MAN:
Everything
in the proper order.You know that.
I got five other tests
I got to run on this paper
before I try
to isolate prints.
You got anything for me?
Yeah. The paper's expensive.
High rag count.
I could have
told you that.
Can you explain
these three small vertical dots?
What? Where?
It tells me that
the printer that
emitted this letter
has a spot on the drum.
A drum goes around three
times to print one page.
So if the Andersons'
printer was used...
There'd be
three small dots
on any paper
that comes out.
No vertical dots.
And different paper
than the ransom letter
F.Y.I.
Yeah, this mold I made
of that shoe print
matches the gardener's
boot that I found
in the shed over there.
Yeah, well, we need to look
for what's out of place.
And a gardener's boot
in a garden is not
out of place.
Well, the Andersons did say
the guy's been out of town
on vacation for
the last three days.
( cell phone rings )
Grissom.
Ransom note's
not from the Anderson's printer
or paper supply.
You're breaking up.
The Andersons are clear.
Whoever wrote the letter
did it from a different location
and brought it with them.
Are you standing
next to the copy machine
outside ballistics?
You want me to check ballistics?
No, I want you to move away
from that machine.
Look, check all the printers
at Steve Anderson's company.
( dogs barking )
Get Q.D. to help you
with a warrant.
Target all
immediate co-workers
and disgruntled
employees first.
Are those our dogs?
Grissom?
Grissom!
( dogs barking frenetically )
Get those dogs back.
Get them back!
Stand back.
Well, we got to
have pictures.
The coroner will be
all over us.
I'll get the pictures!
I'm going to take him.
MRS. ANDERSON:
Oh, God, my baby!
Oh, my God,
my baby! No!
( no audio )
( screaming ):
My baby!
Oh, my God!
( wailing )
ANCHORWOMAN:
The Andersons, who own
a profitable Internet company
in Las Vegas, are said
to be devastated
by the death of little Zachary.
As for leads,
the police will only say
they have widened
the investigation
to include employees
of Steve Anderson's company.
Immediate coworkers are being
asked to give DNA samples.
By all accounts, the employees
are complying voluntarily.
One of them is quoted as saying
"Anything to help
Mr. and Mrs. Anderson
in their time of grief."
ROBBINS:
I can't give you
exact time of death,
but I do know
cause of death
was asphyxiation.
He was smothered.
The retinal hemorrhages
are the result
of intercranial pressure
from an edema.
The edema was caused by
an acute lack of oxygen.
Smothered how?
Did you find hand marks
trauma around
the mouth or nose?
No.
He was in a blanket
when I found him...
wrapped pretty tight.
Positional asphyxiation?
Maybe.
Abductor might have tried
to protect him from the cold.
Suffocated him
by mistake.
I'm going
to run tests
on a microscopic fiber
I found in his throat.
But I don't think
his death was benign, Gil.
Or accidental.
Sternum was cracked.
X-rays say the
fracture is fresh.
Manhandled
and suffocated.
This little guy
didn't have a chance.
Are those
from Anderson's company?
Yeah. There's like 200
of them in that place.
I'm going to test them
against the ransom note,
one by one.
You got Homicide's list
of disgruntled employees?
They're still
working on it.
You call Homicide back
and tell them
to get us that list now.
Hey.
Hey.Where are we
on those DNA samples?
I got the
hair samples
from the baby's crib
ready for comparison.
Yeah? So answer my question.
Well, DNA's jammed.
Sanders says he'll
get to the blood
comparisons as soon as...
I hear you're backlogged.
20 "Unknowns" from
some drug shoot-out.
FBI special request.
Sheriff told me to clear it
off my counter
before I do
anything else.
These?
Yeah. You can almost smell
Quantico, huh?
There.
Now they're
off your counter.
Zachary Anderson,
date of birth 01-23-01.
Date of death,
three hours ago.
Until we find out
how and why...
this is the only case
you work on.
Yes, sir.
Never seen him
like this before.
Grissom?
What?
You told me a few weeks ago
that nothing is personal.
No victim should
be special.
Everyone follows
your lead.
Everyone didn't find
that baby.
I did.
And that little boy
is dead
because someone lost
their temper
or screwed up,
or God knows what.
So, excuse me,
but this victim is special.
Mr. and Mrs. Anderson
are calling.
They want to know
why you refuse
to release the body
for burial.
They said that you gave
the coroner strict instructions.
( sighs )
You better drive.
Sure.
GRISSOM:
I'm very sorry, but we have
to preserve the evidence
in a case like this.
And as difficult as this sounds,
Zachary is evidence.
We need to refer to him
as the case unfolds.
Well, do you have
any leads?
Any idea
who did this?
Your child
was found
500 yards from your back door,
in clean clothes
wrapped in a white blanket,
laid carefully under a statuary.
WILLOWS:
A stranger wouldn't
treat a victim
like that.
You think we had something
to do with this?
GRISSOM:
The FBI tells us
that you never received
a call from the abductor.
What kind of a kidnapper forgets
to call the family?
The wealthy family.
STEVE:
My lawyer warned me
that you were going
to try this.
You don't have a suspect
so now you're going
to come after us.
But you have nothing to hide.
You're damn right
we don't.
( knocking )
I thought I'd deliver this
in person.
DNA came back
on the entire family.
GRISSOM:
The blood we found
in the baby's room...belongs to your son Tyler.
I was playing ball
in the backyard
and I cracked
Zacky's window.
Dad had told me not to hit
the ball towards the house.
So I went up
and replaced the window
before anyone got home
and I cut my finger
on the glass.
And you wiped up the blood
with some type of pine cleanser.
I thought
I got it all.
GRISSOM:
Let's go back
a second, Tyler.
You said that you baby-sat
for Robbie and Zack last night
right?
I told the police that
this morning.
We had a Homeowner's
Association Vote meeting.
It was just five doors
up from our house.
I had, uh...I had made dinner
and then Steve and I
walked up to the clubhouse.
We were gone maybe 30 minutes,
until 9:00.
We contacted the Association.
The story checks out.
I also did a
background search.
Tyler has quite a temper on him,
don't you, Ty?
What?
You were expelled
from school twice last year
for physical altercation.
That was school yard stuff.
CATHERINE:
Beat up a
12-year-old
in the school stairwell.
He made fun of my mother.
I wasn't going to let him
get away with that.
BRASS:
Your brother Zack
say something
you weren't going to let him
get away with, either?
Don't talk about my brother
thatway, you bastard.
STEVE:
Sit down. Now.
GWEN:
He's, uh...he's upset.
He is not usually like this.
People are calling us killers.
And I miss my little brother.
That still doesn't mean
you didn't kill him.
So what are we looking for?
I don't know.
Well, let's start up
and work our way down.
Here's the father's
bottle of cola.
Here's the Unknown.
I duplicated conditions
and monitored the pressure
that escaped
from the father's bottle
which he'd told
you had been
open two hours
against one I know
was open two hours.
Kept this log.
Pressure released
every quarter hour.
Good, Nick.
Did you find any ethanol
on the lip of that bottle?
Well, I've got Trace
running tests
now, but I did
an unscientific
whiff test.
Picked up a hint of
some kind of booze.
Call me when you get
the results.
See if they can
find out
what this green substance is
on these nylons I found
in Mr. Anderson's closet.
I'll take a swatch,
get it back to you ASAP.
GRISSOM:
The mother's prints...
the father's prints...
and a set of Unknowns.
They're
not unknown.
I ran them against
the employees
of Steve Anderson's
computer company
disgruntled and otherwise.
They belong to
a Needra Fenway.
And who is Needra Fenway?
Steve Anderson's
secretary.
So, of course,
I checked out
her printer.
As I'm sure you know,
all printers have their own
unique signature.
These three...
tiny vertical dots
from Needra's printer
match the ransom note
perfectly.
Thank you.
Thank you for coming in.
Anything I can do to help.
You know, it's, it's just
terrible what happened.
BRASS:
Maybe you can explain
why your printer
was used to create the ransom
note found in the Anderson home.
What?
We have evidence
that this came
from your printer.
There are 500 people
who work in that office.
Anyone could have used
my printer.
We also found a strand of hair.
Our lab has matched it
to you.
From the Anderson home.
I'm Steven's secretary.I go there.
Do you go upstairs?
'Cause that's
where we found
this particular hair.
WILLOWS:
You two were
having an affair.
We ended it.
Because his wife got pregnant?
I'm not going down this road.
What? A new baby
screw up the office romance?
It was more than
just an office romance, okay?
Much more.
WILLOWS:
Well, a lot of women
would understand
if you went over there
and... got rid of that baby.
Sure. Quickest way
to end a guy's marriage.
Okay, I need a lawyer.Is that it?
Is that what you're saying here?
( sighing )
Are these your nylons?
I found these hidden in the back
of Mr. Anderson's closet.
So, did you come to him
after you disposed of the baby
and ask him to hide them
for you?
Talk to Steve.
Steve asked her to get out
of an obligation of a newborn?
Geez, haven't these people
ever heard of divorce?
Needra didn't kill Zack
any more than I did.
How do you explain her hair
in the baby's crib?
We broke up the day
that I learned that Gwen
was pregnant with Zack.
I loved Needra
but I love my family more.
Needra asked if she could
see Zack, after he was born
to help her kind of
accept the reality.
So, I had her in
last Saturday
to watch him sleep.
Gwen had the kids
at skating.
Needra was out
of the house
in 15 minutes.
You don't believe me.
You've lied to me before.
About what?
You told me that you
opened that cola bottle
the morning
you reported Zack missing.
We had a test done.
You opened that bottle
six hours
before you said you did--
the night before--
somewhere around 11:00 P.M.
The lab is still testing it.
I also believe that you
cut it with alcohol.
Rum and cola--
what does that prove?
Was Needra Fenway
in your house that night?
Did you catch her
suffocating your son?
( baby crying )
What are you doing?
What have you done?
That's not how it happened.
Well, why don't you tell me
how it happened.
( glass shattering)
( gasp )
GWEN:
Robbie, what did you do?
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
All right, I heard you.
Do we have to have this
conversation right now?
Mr. Anderson?
What? Yeah.
I'm from the Las Vegas Post.
Comments about these
pictures your secretary
sold to the Midnight
Informer this afternoon?
Where did you get these?
The tabloid's web site.
Needra sold them to pay
for her legal fees.
REPORTER:
Mr. Anderson?
My only comment is
that I love my wife very much.
REPORTER:
Excuse me.
I'm from the Las Vegas Post.
May I ask you
a few questions?
GWEN:
No.
A wife kills her baby
to get back at her husband
over his affair.
Come on.
Any woman would go after
the husband, not the baby.
True. But in some instances
women have been known
to kill their children
as a way to pay back a spouse.
Particularly
if it's over an affair
and particularly
if the child was a male child.
Well I don't buy it.I just don't buy it, Doctor.
She really loved that baby.
Well, Catherine
that's why
she's in this much pain now.
A guy cheats,
but the wife commits murder.
How come moms always end up
the bad guy
with you Freud types?
That's because this mother
is the bad guy.
CNN just dug up
a 13-year-old charge
against Gwen Anderson.I heard it on the car radio.
What kind of charge?
It's called shaken
baby syndrome.
The oldest boy, Tyler?
When he was a newborn
she shook him so hard
they had to go to the hospital.
She shook the kid unconscious.
Is this authentic?
Yeah, they were on the phone
with the arresting officer
from Oregon.
He faxed me this report.
Our grieving mother...her record for child abuse.
( crowd clamoring
and camera shutters clicking)
MAN:
Baby killer.
You should die.You call yourself a mother?
You're the worst.
MAN:
Baby killer. Someone should take
those other kids from you.
REPORTER:
Did you kill Zachary
over your husband's affair?
Did you act alone
or did Tyler help?
WOMAN:
Baby killer. Bitch.
You deserve to die.Gil Grissom.
You found the baby.
How hard is it for you
to look at Gwen Anderson?
Let me tell you something.
People are presumed innocent...
innocent until a court of law
can examine all the evidence
and prove otherwise.
Until then
everything else is...
gossip.
WOMAN:
She deserves to
be put in jail.Gil Grissom. Gil Grissom!
Ice.
I don't need this.
Just do it.
That was quite a speech
you made out there
but between you
me and the water fountain...
you think that
Gwen Anderson's innocent?
What? Are you
changing teams now?
You've been her
biggest supporter.
I still am.
I'm just... taking
your temperature.
BRASS:
Hey?
We're up.
You didn't answer my question.
You're right. I didn't.
( throws ice bag in trash can)
I never meant to hurt Tyler,
you have to understand.
You shook him unconscious.
He was choking.
All on his own?
ATTORNEY:
Change your tone
or I'll end this right now.
Well, it's
a legitimate question.
But I have to work on my tone.You're right.
Try again.
All on his own?
Go ahead, Mrs. Anderson.
He had gotten food
in his windpipe.
His face was... turning red.
Steve was at work.
So, I, I patted him
on his back
and-and on...and on his stomach
and finally,
I turned him upside down
and I started shaking him
to get the food out...
to... to dislodge it,
and I did.
But I realized that I had hurt
him, so I called 9-1-1.
She was a new mother
23 years old.
If she'd meant to harm her son
why would she call 9-1-1?
Did the E.R. find proof
that there was food lodged
in Tyler's throat?
No, that's why
the police were
called in.
And by the time
my client went home
and found the chewed food
on the kitchen floor
it was all too late.
She was branded.
It was a French fry
he had grabbed from my plate.
LEWIS:
As for the death
of little Zachary
my client
categorically denies
any involvement.
She's a victim
of an intruder
who entered her home
and abducted and killed
her child.
Thank you all
for your continued efforts
to find the real killer.
Did you know that your
golf course paints its grass?
Excuse me?
It's actually a vegetable dye.
Biodegradable.
They've been using
green dye on television
tournaments for several years.
What's your point?
I found a pair of nylons
in the back of your
husband's closet.
BRASS:
We, uh
we have a receipt
that links them to your client.
GRISSOM:
The exact same dye
from the golf course
where Zachary was laid to rest
is on your nylons.
She belongs to the club.
Grass stains.
WILLOWS:
But she doesn't play golf.
Remember our conversation,
Mrs. Anderson?
It's not your game?
If you arrest her now...you have 48 hours
to charge her.
You really want to show
your hand at the arraignment?
We'll be in touch.
Look.
Mommy, I want my Mommy.Hey.
Can we just go, please?
What's going on?
Did you see that?
A mother repelled
by her young.
She didn't seem
like that type to me.
All right, okay.Here, go to your brother.
I'll catch you later.
I want to hear
that 9-1-1 tape.
Hi.Hey.
Grissom?
The Coroner's been
trying to reach you.
Did he nail time of death?
9:00 P.M., but, uh,
there's something else.
He isolated the fiber found
in Zachary Anderson's throat.
It's a flame-retardant
material--
generic name's Metaramid.
From the baby's clothes?
Fire-retardant
infant's clothes are made
out of vinyon.
The fiber found
in Zack's throat
is a stronger
chemical treatment.
It's found in things
that are made to be
near fire and flames.
Hey?
Hey, can I go with you?
Same color as the fiber
in Zack's throat.
Okay, this is
the 9-1-1 call
from the Anderson house
at 4:30 A.M.
STEVE:
Our baby has been kidnapped.
493 Fairmark.
Please hurry.
Mrs. Anderson wasn't there?
You wouldn't think so
but I went ahead
and separated out
any underlying voices.
GWEN:
What are we going to do?!
She was standing, like,
two meters from the phone.
Yeah, well,
it's a legitimate comment.
Doesn't make her guilty
of anything.
I know, so I checked
to see if she was, like,
faking her concern.
This program measures
the stress level
of the speakers.
GWEN:
Oh, God,
what are we going to do?!
The stress is real.
Are you familiar
with the JonBenet case?
A little.
Well, the police went back,
and they found an earlier call
that was placed
from the home to 9-1-1
and the audio tests
separated out the son's voice.
Now, I'm not saying
that Tyler's our guy, but...
we need to check
into every avenue.
Well, I did backtrack
and there were no
other calls that night
from the Anderson house--
from the land line,
or from the cell phone.
In the parents' name,
but did you look under Tyler's?
I mean, a rich kid like that's
probably got a cell phone.
Yeah. All right,
I'll get into it.
( phone ringing )
Hello.
MAN:
Anderson attorney, 7:00 A.M.
7:00 A.M.?
I'll be there.
All the evidence.
Yeah. I'll bring it all.
Thanks.
LEWIS:
My colleagues,
Messrs. Landry and Frank
are representing Steve
and Tyler Anderson respectively.
Although we're not co-counsel
in the strictest sense
we've agreed
the authorities should have
no more than three questions
to put to our clients each.
After that, we'll
accept written
submissions only.
Nice... what money can buy.
My family is done being
railroaded by you people
so just ask your questions,
and let's go.
I don't have any questions.
We know what happened
in your house
the night Zachary died.
We've interpreted the evidence.
WILLOWS:
All right, let's
work backwards
starting with
the cover-up.
Sometime around 11:00 P.M.the night of the kidnapping
you and Mr. Anderson
had a drink--
rum and cola...
and decided what to do
with the body of Zachary.
We have yet to determine
whether or not his death
was accidental or intentional.
The Question
Documents lab thinks
that a parent
wrote the ransom note
because there's
no money amount.
Too hard to put a price
on your own son?
Mrs. Anderson,
while your husband
was writing the ransom note,
you wrapped
Zachary's body
in a blanket
that you got from the
upstairs linen closet.
You then laid his body to rest
near a statue
on the golf course.
( sobbing softly )
( crying )
That's how
you got the grass stains
on your nylons.
You put down
a plastic bag
from the pantry
so that he'd remain dry.
Evidence of
genuine care
and concern.
And Mr. Anderson
you put up a ladder
outside the window.
The only shoe prints
we found were yours
and the gardener's
and the gardener
has been out of town.
You then drove over
to your office
and cranked off
a ransom note
on the first
available printer
possibly thinking that
if you used a printer
from outside your house
we wouldn't be able
to trace it.
But these three dots...
have given you away.
This may prove cover-up.
None of it proves
they killed Zachary.
You're right,
Counselor.
Zachary's life was taken
much earlier in the evening.
The coroner estimated
time of death at 9:00 P.M.
LEWIS:
Estimated.
It could be 8:30.
Yes.
While Robbie and Zachary
were in Tyler's care.
You said we could ask
three questions each.
Am I right?
Stop.
Ty didn't do this.
LEWIS:
Don't give them
anything.
We're already ruined.
They're just...
They're just trying
to protect me.
Please.
And I can't go on.
Mrs. Anderson.
I killed him.
I came home.
Tyler h-h-hadn't put Zachary
to bed because he
he was crying,
and I wanted to hush him up
and, and I just, I went too far.
For the record
my client made this statement
against legal counsel.
Would you tell us...how you killed him.
I smothered him
with a pot holder.
And that's when Steve and I
came up with the kidnap story.
It was the longest night
of our lives.
You had to wait till the morning
to report him missing.
So that it wouldn't
look suspicious.
And you may not believe me,
but I loved him.
I loved him very, very much.
We're going to have
to have them both arrested.
I'm just coming
to meet you guys.
I thought
you were at the Andersons.
She copped.
Guilty people
do that
when you corner them
with evidence.
Guys, the mother didn't do it.
What?
Listen.
TYLER:
What did you do, Robbie?!
What did you do?!
I was watching the boys.
I had my eye on them;
I did.
( baby cooing )
Yeah. But then you
called your girlfriend.
And we got to talking.
And I was kind of ignoring
Zack and Robbie.
They were
being quiet.
They were behaving.
I turned around,
and I saw how still he was.
I ran to him, and he was dead.
And that's
when you called 9-1-1.
( beeping )
( audio indistinct )
But you must have
dropped the phone
to tend to Zack.
TYLER:
What did you do, Robbie?!
What did you do?!
Then I guess somehow
in the chaos
you got
disconnected.
Soon after that,
your parents arrived.
GWEN:
Oh, my God.
What happened?
One of you worked on him so hard
that you cracked his sternum.
He was already blue.
I pushed.
I tried to breathe air into him,
but he was gone.
We did everything
that we could.
Why didn't you
just tell the truth?
We wanted to protect Robbie.
We didn't want him
to grow up with
the stigma of...
"the boy
who killed his brother."
He's three.
He's clinically
unaware of his actions.
No court would hold him
accountable for that.
But everybody else would know.
It would follow him
the rest of his life.
And my wife...would rather go to prison
than to have anybody know
what Robbie did.
Mr. Anderson,
we won't let that happen.
Now I know why you didn't
want to hold Robbie
when your older son
handed him to you
outside the
police department.
I'm very sorry.
( sniffling )
I always, uh...
I always tell them,
"Gentle, gentle."
He didn't mean it.
I know he didn't mean it.
Of course he didn't.
You must think
that we're awful people--
all the stuff that's come out.
You're an average family
burdened with a tragedy
that put you under a microscope.
That close,
nobody can look good.
Your family's waiting for you.
You ready?