Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
( man grunts )
This came for you,
Mr. Grissom.
What's this?
An anonymous package
from county lockup?
Yeah, well, hey,
just a second.
Wait a minute. Give an innocent
bystander a chance to clear out.
What are you worried about?
One minute
I'm eating tomato salad.
The next--
I'm gazpacho.
With any luck
it'll be the next episode
of G-String Divas.
My name is Frank Damon...
and I'm awaiting trial
for the murder of...
my wife and son.
That's an arson case
a few months ago.
The D.A. is asking
for the death penalty.
I didn't kill my family...
but my lawyer says
the evidence is against me.
I was a good father.
I loved him.
I would have given my life
for Toby and Jeannie.
They were my world.
Mr. Grissom,
you are my last hope.
Please...
help me.
An innocent man.
Jail's full of them.
It only takes one.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
Am I disturbing you?
Yeah.
Good.
Oh. Great. Sorry.
Uh, I was supposed
to pass out
some supervisor
evaluation forms.
Where are they?
Here they are.
Mm. Get to rate
the boss. I dig this.
Give him
a perfect ten
or your ass
is out of here.
No, it's not.
All right.
Assignment:
parking lot of the sportsbook
at The Monaco.
Caucasian male found dead
in the front seat of his car.
Two days before the Super Bowl.
I'll take a piece of that.
No. Uh, Nick and Catherine.
What else you got?
GRISSOM:
You and Warrick
are working with me.
WILLOWS:
Prisoner plea.
Brass told me about the video.
If we take the case,
we have very little time.
The trial starts
in three days.
How did he find you?
1-800-GRISSOM...?
WILLOWS:
Wait a minute.
Ecklie was the CSI
on that arson.
I see a bad moon rising.
Can a CSI take over
another CSI's case?
Only if they're
of equal rank
and looking for trouble.
No trouble.
We're both colleagues
searching for the truth.
Okay, that's it.
Look onward.
You have to start
by looking at this.
Hey, what happened to that,
uh, meeting the other day?
Meeting?
Yeah, the department
heads were voting
on an extra vacation day
or something?
Yeah.
Hmm. "Organization"...
minus one.
Yo, cousin.
I'm going to save you
some gas here.
I did some checking
on your pal, Damon.
I don't remember asking you to.
Eyewitness saw him running
from his burning house.
Inside was his wife and kid.
Now, wife's
a big spender.
Maxed out
on the credit cards.
They just bought the place
and already he's late
on the payments.
Couple's always arguing
about money. No surprise.
Well, how does
killing his family
solve his money problems?
Maybe
he didn't mean to.
Maybe he needed
the insurance dough
and things got out of hand.
Too many maybes.
I think we should go
with the evidence.
Well, I got something
for you on that, too.
Gasoline found
in the master bedroom closet.
Yeah. Hydrocarbon.
I read Ecklie's brief.
Did you
skip the page
that had Damon's
credit card receipts?
'Cause he bought
a gallon of gas
a week before the fire.
Do I seem like the kind of guy
who skips stuff?
Read my lips.
There is no compelling evidence
to suggest
Damon was wrongfully charged.
Well, then, it'll be
a short interview, won't it?
( car starts )
STOKES:
Whew! Two days
before the Super Bowl
and they're already
killing each other.
Hey, O'Riley, anyone put
their meat hooks
on this vehicle?
How long have
we worked together?
Still got to ask.
Sergeant.
What's up?
Oh...
Gunshot wound to the head,
point-blank range.
Just a baby.
Tap city.
Empty.
WILLOWS:
Killer was probably
in the back seat
waiting for him.
Kid never stood a chance.
Check this out.
Hearing aid?
Maybe he was deaf.
Possibly.
Got some condensation
on the window.
You should get
a shot of this.
( chuckles )
You hungry, Nick?
Got a burger.
Extra lettuce.
A rule of thumb:
$2,500 an inch.
There's got to be...
$15,000 there?
"Rams
negative nine."
Oh, "Rams minus nine."
It's a Super Bowl ticket.
Straight bet-- $30,000.
What does a kid doing
walking around
with a wad like that
betting 30 grand
on a football game?
Who wrote
the ticket?
Teller 12.
Yeah, I wrote the ticket.
So what?
So, it was found
with the kid killed
in your parking lot.
Yeah. 30 dimes.
It was 517's.
517?
What's that?
That's his number.
He was a runner.
A runner?
Yeah, a go-fer--
runs from book to book
places bets
with other people's money.
Kid wasn't a day over 16.
Isn't that illegal?
Lady, he's not buying
a pack of cigarettes.
He's betting $30,000.
Vig for the house
is three grand.
We look the other way.
Well, I'd be
willing to bet
there's a mother out there
that wishes you hadn't.
Hey, what do I care?
I'm out of this job
by the end of the week.
Tired of looking at scumbags.
Well, does 517 have a name?
I only know them
by their numbers.
Well, you've been very helpful.
Thank you.
Thanks.
MAN:
Yo, Grissom!
Yo, man, this guy's
the reason I'm in here.
Shoe print.
Yo, man, next time
I'll go barefoot!
Even better.
Footprints.
So, you're the Grissom
they wrote about
in the newspaper?
I thought
you'd be older.
Why did you contact me,
Mr. Damon?
Arson specialist
gave me your name.
Well, six of them, actually.
They all turned my case down.
Will you help me?
Fires are
very complicated.
It wasn't too complicated
for the guy who put me in here.
You think if you
stare at me long enough,
you can tell if I'm innocent?
I don't mean to stare...
but yes,
I can learn some things.
For instance
the back of your
hands are smooth.
You read a lot.
You have indentation marks
on your nose
from reading glasses.
Your speech tells me
that you're well-educated.
Your occupation's not
listed in the file
but I think
that you had
a white-collar job.
Paper-pusher
for the phone company.
I don't know yet
whether you're left-
or right-handed,
though.
Now, you want
to tell me
what happened?
It was about midnight.
Okay, baby.
My wife, Jeannie--
she was hungry.
She had a food craving.
She sent me out to the store
to get her
some ice cream.
My son, Toby, he was
in the bed with us.
He couldn't sleep.
I was going
to take him camping
the next day.
Toby was eight.
Why don't you tell me
about the fire.
I got back from the store
in under 20 minutes.
I saw smoke coming out
the back of the house.
I could hear the alarm.
Jeannie!
The house was filled
with smoke.
Jeannie!
I checked the door for heat.
I knew not to open it.
Why?
Flashover.
Flashover?
That's right.
When the fire reaches
about 932 degrees Fahrenheit
you add oxygen
and the smoke
will burst into flame.
I know how fire behaves,
Mr. Grissom
because I'm a volunteer fireman.
I was hoping to make
the department this spring.
So I couldn't open the door.
I ran outside to my car
to call a rig.
Well, if you're
a volunteer fireman
then you must be familiar
with the use of accelerants.
Yes.
According
to the report
there were traces of gasoline
found on the floor
of your bedroom closet.
That's right, and I don't know
how it got there.
I didn't keep anything
like that in the house.
Our homicide department
has a credit card receipt
for gasoline-- your receipt
and there's no
other suspects.
I didn't burn down my house,
Mr. Grissom.
I bought the gasoline
for the lawnmower
and kept it in the garage.
Now, if there was gasoline
in our closet
someone else put it there.
Find them.
I don't chase criminals,
Mr. Damon.
I just evaluate evidence.
I need someone
to believe me--
to figure this out.
How'd you burn your hand,
Mr. Damon?
I don't remember.
People with third-degree burns
don't forget how they got them.
You're not going to help me?
I'll take your case.
I don't know whether
I'll help you or not.
Nothing harder to investigate
than arson.
If the fire hasn't ruined
your crime scene...
Sara:
The firemen have?
Mmm.
Funny place
for a mattress.
Overhaul.
Post-blaze, firemen removed
charred items
to neutralize the hot spots.
It prevents flare-ups.
( camera shutter clicking )
Looks like the kid
was going camping.
( unlocking latches )
Waterproof matches.
Bag those.
What do you think?
The kid might have started it?
We don't rule anything out.
GRISSOM:
Yeah.
Master bedroom.
The fire was contained
inside this room...
but the outside doorframe
is severely charred.
Well, fires take the path
of least resistance.
I mean, they feed off
of oxygen and combustibles.
GRISSOM:
We're going to take
a piece of this back
to the lab.
It's a weird place for such
a thorough burn
especially since the door
isn't scorched.
Huh.
Look at this.
Rubber?
Firemen wear rubber gloves.
According to Ecklie's report,
which was filed in record time
the point of origin
for the fire
was the closet.
Of course, there's
nothing left here.
More than you think.
"V" pattern
on the outside wall.
Fires like to go
up and out.
That's why you can always
count on seeing a pattern.
This one's narrow.
This was very intense,
rapidly moving fire.
Well, that confirms
Ecklie's findings
about the use of an accelerant.
The apex of the "V"
usually indicates
the point of origin.
You want to call it?
Damon doused the closet floor
with gasoline, lit it
and got the hell
out of Dodge.
Shards of glass.
Bag a sample.
I'll put it
through the lab.
Can't.
It's melted into the concrete.
So, that's why
the concrete's discolored?
From the heat?
It's called "spalling."
It confirms the presence
of an accelerant.
Why would there be glass
in the middle of the hot spot?
Good question.
WARRICK:
Who cares?
The guy torched
his wife and kid.
Really?
Where's the trailing?
An arsonist would spread
the gasoline around
to maximize the burn area.
He still did the job.
Listen, you guys.
You're like Dodger fans.
The ball game's only
in the seventh inning
you're already out
of your seats.
Mrs. Hillman?
Is this your son?
( inhales )
( sobbing )
( whimpering )
( sighing )
Mrs. Hillman?
Was your son
hearing-impaired?
Joey was wearing
a hearing aid.
No.
No, Joey's hearing was fine.
Why would he have that?
( softly ):
I don't know.
Wait a minute.
( sighing )
Danny... swore to me
he'd keep Joey
out of that racket.
Danny?
My older son.
He's a runner, too.
They wear
remote earpieces.
That's how they talk
to the guy they worked for.
We've had full-scale wars
about him doing that
carrying around
that kind of money
but does he stop?
No.
He gets Joey involved.
Well, the police will want
to talk to your son, Danny.
I haven't seen him in a week.
And he hasn't
returned my calls.
Do you think something's
happened to him, too?
( Grissom sighs )
Grissom.
I'll see you guys
in the evidence lab.
Night shift so slow you've
got to pick over my cases?
I'm just making sure that we've
answered all the questions.
Was it arson? Yes.
No doubt about it.
What accelerant was used?
Let's see, hydrocarbon residue,
and a credit card receipt.
Got to be gasoline.
Yeah.
Why was there no trailing?
And why no evidence
of an incendiary device
anywhere in the bedroom?
He's a volunteer
fireman, Gil.
He knows how to start a fire
and hide the evidence.
Don't you think if this guy
was remotely innocent
his attorney would be involved
in your little investigation?
What are you
so afraid of, Conrad?
We're just a couple
of science geeks.
Why can't we work together?
No, we are public servants.
We investigate cases
as efficiently as we can
and then we move on.
We're not a clearinghouse
for defendants
on the eve of trial
who don't like
what we've turned up.
Yes, we are
if it's our mistake
that put them there.
Fine, spin your wheels.
Hey, Eck?
What is the new policy
on vacation days?
WARRICK:
Runners, huh?
I know a little something
about that world.
Yeah, we thought you might.
So?
It breaks down like this.
There's about a half a dozen
runners in town.
They're mostly kids
and they make
about two "G's" a week.
And they all work
for the same guy.
Well, that's more than
a little something.
I used to be a runner
in college.
It paid the bills.
I had Route Five.
Worked Boulder, Sunset,
Vacation, and The Bay--
all of that.
So, who was
your boss then?
The Voice.
He didn't have a name?
Runners go from bet to bet,
they jot down their orders
and they call them
into "The Voice."
Guy runs the entire operation
underground.
I mean, he takes orders
from back East
and lays them
off in Vegas.
Pockets his vig,
his commission.
He's like the trader
on the stock exchange.
( pager beeping )
I knew it. That's Grissom.
I've got to bail.
So... how do we find
this, uh... "Voice"?
You don't.
He's not who
you're looking for anyway.
If you want to know
who capped this kid
then you should talk
to another runner.
I mean, they'll kill each other
for a good route.
Uh... you might want to
take three giant steps
backward.
WARRICK:
What's going on?
Danger, Will Robinson.
Three drops of gasoline,
limited oxygen supply
heat to ignition temperature
of 932 degrees Fahrenheit.
Same conditions in Damon's
bedroom the night of the fire.
Smoke to fire.
Flashover.
So, that confirms the first part
of Damon's story.
Tell me you're here
to confirm part two.
As a matter of fact,
here is your doorframe.
I had Collins analyze
the burn depth.
You see these
rolling blisters?
It's called
alligatoring.
See the way
the wood's cracked?
It looks like the skin
of an alligator.
Based on the depth
of the allir... allo...
Alligatoring.
This wood burned very hot
and very fast.
Use of accelerant?
Negative.
But that piece was a doorframe
outside of the bedroom--
which was a contained site.
So, the only way this
could've happened was...
O2.
Damon opened the door.
He lied.
So, what happens now?
We chase the lie...
till it leads to the truth.
All right.
You take care.
And don't-don't worry.
Everything's
going to be fine.
That's my sister.
She's the only one
who stood by me
in all of this.
Anything else
you want to tell me?
What, about my sister?
About the fire.
I...
I told you everything.
Your bedroom doorframe
disagrees.
If no one opened the door...
the outside frame
would not have burned.
As a firefighter
you know that.
May I see your hand,
please?
Palm up.
This is the same type
of doorknob that you have
on your bedroom door.
Mr. Damon...
Please...
I don't want anyone to know.
Why?
This places you outside
of the fire.
You're facing
the death penalty.
Why are you lying?
I'm a firefighter.
And when my wife and my son
needed me...
I forgot everything.
I didn't check for heat.
Jeannie!
I didn't look for smoke.
All I could think about
was getting them out.
So I opened the door...
and I let the monster out.
I could just about make them
out through the flame.
Jeannie! Jeannie!
But I... I couldn't
get to them!
( howling ):
Oh!
What else?
I had to close the door.
The whole house
would've gone up
and the firemen would
have never reached them.
I killed my family.
Carbon monoxide killed them
long before the fire
got to them.
You know about
CO2 poisoning.
It doesn't matter what I know.
My family died because
I wasn't there to protect them.
You tried to save your family
but that doesn't mean
that you didn't start the fire.
Are you lying
about that, too?
You tell me.
I will.
TONY:
Hey, you didn't hear this
from me, all right? But, um...
you see the guy
over there--
blue sweatshirt
with the orange hood?
702.
He's a runner.
He used to hang
with 517-- the kid
who was killed.
He's not talking
to himself, is he?
Talking to his boss on a wire.
It's illegal to use two-way
communication in the sportsbook.
As long as you don't get caught.
I've got to get
back to work.
Lakers are minus 11.
The total is 189.
Yeah. Bulls pick.
Kings are down
to nine from eleven.
Done.
Lakers.
$50,000.
Give me as much
at 11 as you can.
You like the
Lakers today?
So do I.
Yeah, Joey Hillman, 517.
Yeah, he was
a good kid.
It's too bad about him
getting shot.
Yeah, I guess
all the runners heard
about it by now, huh?
I guess.
So, who got Joey's route?
I don't know.
The only thing
I know is my own route.
What was Joey's route, exactly?
You guys are asking
a lot questions here
for not being cops, huh?
Are you interested
in helping us
better understand
Joey's crime scene, or...
...not?
I only know
what I see on the news.
Later.
( sighs )
You got me.
Sorry.
What are you doing here?
Sifting through this debris.
You mind?
No.
Give me a hand
with this mattress.
Space heater.
Janko Electric, Model...
...220.
WARRICK:
Or it was.
I figure it must have
burned up in the bedroom
and the firemen
threw it out here
with the rest of this overhaul.
GRISSOM:
This is heavy-duty,
high voltage.
This thing could heat
our whole lab.
Or overload a house.
Breaker box.
WARRICK:
Circuit overload.
The master bedroom.
You know what
to do next?
Yeah.
( drilling )
The condensation
inside Joey's
back seat window
is nasal mucus.
From a sneeze.
Most likely.
You're thinking...
the shooter was
in the back seat?
Mm-hmm, with the sniffles.
Mm-hmm.
So what is the DNA like
in mucus these days?
It's pretty good.
I'll start a DNA profile.
Thanks.
Catherine?
Oh, hi, David.
What's up?
There's someone waiting
for you in reception.
Detective?
She came in with her son.
Thought you'd like
a conversation
before we sat
down with him.
Yeah, thanks.
Did you call Nick?
Yeah.
Uh... come on.
This is my son, Danny.
He heard about Joey
and came home.
So, I took some
of my runner money
and I hit the
blackjack tables.
I lost...
so I doubled up.
I ended up losing 30 grand
in eight minutes.
Well, I can see
why you ran.
I was scared.
You know, it wasn't my money.
NICK:
Did you think
to get back to your boss?
Try to make amends?
You guys don't even know
who your boss is, do you?
NICK:
Did you tell Joey
to get out of town, that someone
might try to harm him?
On behalf of your boss?
I should have.
But, no...
DANNY:
I only worried
about my butt.
They killed Joey
to send a message to me.
Mom, I'm sorry. I didn't know.
CATHERINE:
Danny...
...do you have any idea
who shot your brother?
One of the runners.
Probably a guy...
No!
No. No names.
DANNY:
One of them
killed Joey.
You know, they'll do
anything for money.
It's like a-a disease.
And if you talk,
they'll come after you.
No.
No, I'm not losing
another child.
Joey died because of me.
Either they find his shooter,
or I do.
NICK:
Whoa, whoa!
Hold on, now.
Nobody's going after anybody.
Okay, he doesn't have to give us
a name, Ms. Hillman, all right?
Danny, you wear an earpiece,
right?
Just give us the frequency
your runners operate on.
What the hell are you doing?
Something you probably
should have done.
You're checking
for faulty wiring?
Waste of time, Gil.
The fire started on
the floor in the closet
not in the wires
in the wall.
Yeah, that was your report.
This is an electrical socket
from the closet
where a space heater
was plugged in.
A heater?
There was no
heater there.
I found it in the living room,
melted.
And I suppose
you happen to know
which outlet
it was plugged into?
It was a cold night.
The outlet in the closet
was closest to her bed.
That's a little far-fetched,
don't you think?
Look...
if this wire burned
from the inside out
then the fire started
in the wall
not on the closet floor.
GRISSOM:
Discoloration throughout
the conductor.
It burned from the inside out.
The cause of this fire was an
electrical overload in the wall.
All right, you say wall,
I say floor.
We differ on points of origin.
The jury's only going
to hear one word:
gasoline.
Speaking of which...
where's your accelerant
analysis work?
I personally swabbed
the closet floor
found traces
of hydrocarbon chains
confirming gasoline.
Leave it alone, Gil.
The D.A. agrees
with me on this.
Too many
unanswered questions, Conrad.
This case should not
be going to trial yet.
No, there's only one
unanswered question.
Why was there accelerant
in the closet?
Only one person knows.
And that's why he's looking
at the death penalty.
DAMON:
Look, I told you...
I don't know why it was there.
You've got to do better
than that.
I can't!
It doesn't prove
you didn't start it.
Until we can explain
why there was gasoline
in the bedroom closet
the charges stand.
Then I guess I'm a dead man.
Hey, this is bull.
I thought I was showing up
to win a trip.
CATHERINE:
Oh...
one of you's going
to win a trip, all right.
Everybody clear,
this is voluntary?
Yeah, sure, then she
just calls the cops
to come and arrest us.
So everyone is clear.
Yeah.
Okay...
here's what we're going to do.
Open your nostrils.
You know, look,
I got a hundred bucks
that says none of us
are the shooter.
Well, if you're that confident
it's not one of your guys
you must know who it is.
Even if I did,
you think I would tell you?
NICK:
You're on
Cool Breeze.
A hundred bucks.
Okay.
Head back.
( sighs )
Okay. You're all free to go.
NICK:
This way, gents.
You owe me a C-note, baby.
I don't have it on me.
I'll have to bring it to you.
Okay, I'll be
holding my breath.
Mm-hmm.
Ugh!
SARA:
Counting matches?
Yeah.
From the kid's room.
I counted them yesterday.
And I counted them
this morning.
Twenty.
They're all there.
I really don't know
what I'm doing anymore.
I got a theory.
You want to hear it?
Sure.
You know the melted shards
of glass
we found on the closet floor?
They prove that
the fire burned
at over 1,000
degrees, right?
But that temp,
combined with the water
used to douse the flames
would have destroyed
most of the accelerant.
That's what happens.
So, Ecklie's conclusion
of gasoline
wasn't based
on any physical evidence.
It was based
on Damon's credit card receipts.
I can't fault him for that.
The burn pattern is consistent
with a gasoline accelerant.
But...
hydrocarbons are found
in all kinds of things: oils...
kerosene,
polyethylene-
based compounds
like laxatives, even the foam
used in push-up bras.
Yeah, under the right conditions
any hydro-carb
can be an accelerant.
Thank you.
Warrick, you're driving.
You ever worry about
professional suicide?
Not while I'm committing it, no.
Crime scene cleanup.
Let's go.
You son of a bitch.
You swept my crime scene.
You sent cleanup!
I didn't send anyone.
It's been on the books
for months.
You knew, and did
nothing about it
even with a man's
life on the line?
If you'd checked the docket
like everybody else
you would've known
what was happening.
Coffee?
( glass breaking )
Guess you don't want cream
with that.
Thanks, Ecklie.
Hi.
Excuse me.
My name's Gil Grissom.
I know. You're helping
Frank. Thank you.
May I ask you a question?
Sure. Anything
to help Frank.
You're his family.
What was his relationship like
with his wife and son?
Frank was a
wonderful father.
Toby adored him.
Uh, I'm sorry.
I, um... I have to
get back to work.
But thank you.
I broke a coffee pot today.
Lost my temper.
Anything like that
ever happen to you?
We found shards of
melted glass on the
floor of your closet.
You want to tell
me about it?
Okay, you can
explain it in court.
It's all part of
the report now.
I didn't leave that night
to buy ice cream.
I was leaving Jeannie.
I warned you.
It's just a few things.
It is half the damn state!
I told you this was
the last time.
Going to leave us now?
I'm leaving.
You can be broke by yourself!
You want to leave?
Fine, okay?
Get out!
What the hell
are you doing?
So I just got the hell
out of there.
Drove for about 20 minutes
and then thought,
how could I end ten years
of our life like that?
I mean, we had a son,
so I turned around.
Wait a minute. Go back.
What did she throw at you?
Be specific.
Man, I just ducked and covered.
I don't remember.
Think.
Uh... a-a phone.
A-A bag.
Uh, a vase maybe.
What kind of a vase?
A flower vase?
I don't remember any flowers.
Was it even a vase?
Look, I don't know.
I can't remember.
Was it glass?
Could it have
been glass?
Yes.
It was glass.
It was a glass lamp,
because it had a wick.
Get out!
What the hell are you doing?
DAMON:
I'm leaving!
Just get out!
Like a kerosene lamp?
Yeah, she bought a lamp
like that.
I found kerosene on the
floor of your closet.
I think the space heater
overloaded the circuit
causing a spark to ignite
the kerosene.
Can you prove it?
In court?
The evidence can.
Hey, how you doing?
Hey.
Who do you want?
The runner... um, 702.
I owe him a little cash.
Uh, this isn't the
only place he hangs out
but if you want me
to give it to him...
Um...
you have an envelope
I could use?
Yeah.
( sniffles )
Nice watch.
Thanks.
Thought you were getting out
of this business.
Yeah, uh...
it's my last day.
Got a new job.
Later.
Yeah.
( sneezes )
You're out of
business, Joey.
( sneezes )
New job, huh?
Joey's old route?
Did you get so scared
when you shot him
that you forgot the money?
I want a lawyer.
Well, you better get one
that knows forensics...
'cause we got you.
Dispatch, Victor 19.
Code 462
on the 4-20 suspect Monaco.
Thought you might
need a ride.
No. Thanks.
DAMON:
I'm okay.
Your sister.
Who is she?
Would you have helped me
if I told you
that my wife and I
fought that night
that I was leaving her
for another woman?
For Rachel?
I don't judge people.
It's funny-- when I got out,
I thought I'd feel...
free.
And?
I feel...
Responsible?
( Damon chuckling )
Come here.