( growling )
( growling continues )
( screaming )
Ah, Jeez.
All right, guy?
I guess he won't be eating
dinner tonight.
I think Running Man
was attacked up there
and then dragged or slid
down here.
Look at those wounds.
STOKES:
He picked the wrong time
of day to be running alone.
Dusk is when the animals
come out.
BROWN:
Yeah, from what I hear
they carved out a piece
of this valley
when they made the park.
Some mountain lion probably
didn't like
getting relocated.
Mountain lions are brutal.
And smart.
This one evidently knows
how to use a scalpel.
[Captioning sponsored by
CBS
and CBS PRODUCTIONS/
ALLIANCE ATLANTIS]
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
Catherine.
What are you doing?
The carnival case.
I'm taking it.
The carnival case?
A six-year-old girl
died on a ride
at the carnival
over on Washington.
The paperwork's
on your desk.
Did you straighten up
my office while
you were in there?
You think
I overstepped?
These people
come to town
they commit crimes
and they leave.
I just want
to get there
before the carnival
moves on.
Okay. Take Sara with you.
She's meeting me there.
BROWN:
So, Doc
how big of a cat
are we actually
dealing with here?
We're not.
We're not?
You ever owned
a kitten?
When you play with them, they
don't just bite, they scratch.
Doesn't matter whether
they're tabbies or tigers.
And there's no signs
of claw wounds on the victim.
So what are
we dealing with?
Forget Whiskers.
Think Spot.
Teeth marks look canine.
I was wrong
about the species.
I'll make a mold
of the bite.
If we're lucky
we can narrow it down
to breed.
What?
Most people don't admit
when they're wrong.
I'm wrong all the time.
That's how I eventually
get to right.
ROBBINS:
You weren't wrong
about the scalpel.
Whoever removed this guys organs
knew how to handle one.
STOKES:
So a dog killed him
then someone came along
and cut him up.
GRISSOM:
Someone with two legs
and a medical degree.
Stop.
What are you doing?
That bag's been used 100 times.
Get her a new one.
They get washed every time,
right?
Yeah, with disinfectant.
What if it was your kid?
She gets this one.
Yes, ma'am.
She looks scared.
No six-year-old
should have to go through that.
You okay?
Why don't you go find the mother
and talk to her.
I'll take the crime scene.
Okay.
I don't know
what happened.
One minute
Sandy was laughing,
holding my hand,
and the next...
The next, sh...
Oh, my God.
Mommy!
Sandy!
Sandy, where are you?
I...
I got out of the car...
but I couldn't find her.
By the time I got the operator
to stop the ride...
she was dead.
MAN:
How can this happen?
At a carnival.
"Go back to the crime scene.
Collect the dog's scat."
I didn't realize how many dogs
take their walks up here
when I said that.
BROWN:
Yeah, but I bet Grissom did.
This sucks.
But it's evidence,
right?
No, hair and fiber
is evidence, Warrick.
This is combat duty.
Yeah, it's somebody's doody.
STOKES:
Don't even waste
your time.
That's cougar.
How do you figure that?
See the rabbit hair
in the feces?
Don't you remember
the seminar?
Seminar?
Julie.
Julie, oh...
A CSI should not be that fine.
( chuckles )
What is that?
STOKES:
Looks like
dirty ice.
Yeah, well, I'm taking it
into evidence.
It's evidence of a picnic,
Warrick.
Yeah, well...
we'll see.
We've never had a problem
with this ride.
This is the safest ride we got.
Not anymore.
So you didn't know
that anything was wrong
until this car came out
of the tunnel, right?
As soon as the Mom
started screaming
I stopped the ride.
Seat belt's loose.
I check those every morning.
Did you check this one?
Yeah.
So do you strap
the riders in,
or do they do it themselves?
Lady, it's the Tunnel of Love,
not Colossus.
People like to get up close
and personal on this ride.
So you keep the belts loose
on purpose.
Loose enough for adults
to get close
or six-year-old kids
to slide through?
Officer, give us a minute.
You tampered
with the evidence.
Ma'am, I don't know
what you're talking about.
Oh, spare me
the Hee Haw routine.
You run this nightmare
on wheels.
I found this in there.
You send one
of your employees
into that tunnel
to fix the track
where that little girl
was killed to cover your ass?
Glad you found that,
'cause Puppy's been missing
since I rolled
into Vegas.
Look, I, uh...
I'm sorry as the next jim-jim
about what happened,
ma'am
but... I ain't got nothing
to do with it.
Field test for drugs.
I'm sure you've done
this before.
You can't make me
take a drug test.
Oh, before you came
to Nevada
you should've looked up
the law.
Mandatory drug testing
wherever there's been
an accident.
Pee now,
and don't tell me you're shy.
Stay on him.
Mandatory drug testing?
There should be.
And I don't have to wait
for results
to know that guy's coked
out of his brain.
Cocaine bugs?
Oh...
Crawling all under his skin.
GRISSOM:
Like David Crosby said,
big fella:
"If I'd known I was
going to live this long
I'd have taken better care
of my teeth."
Right you are,
Mister Crime Scene
Investigator.
You know, most dogs
have 42 teeth
but, as you've discovered,
your Cujo
only has 41.
Woof-woof.
Did you ever hear
a dog say woof-woof,
Greg?
I mean, what is
the origin of that?
And what do we sound like
to them, I wonder?
I don't know.
Probably blah, blah, blah.
Did you come here
with some particular
blah, blah, blah for me?
Yes.
Two words. Paw prints.
Your dentally-challenged
killer left them
all over
the vic's clothes.
Greg, you know that paw prints
are not the same
as fingerprints.
True, and even if they were,
we don't have the database.
But they can tell you
the size of the dog.
And?
And according
to my sagacious
calculations, this is a big dog.
At least 100 pounds.
Now if we can just figure out
where he went to medical school
we'll be home free.
Huh?
The, uh
big dog is
a Great Dane-Mastiff mix.
So my paw prints
didn't even help.
No, odontology did.
Dr. Robbins' dental mold.
But, uh
it's always nice to have
a visit with you, Greg.
Thank you.
So now you think
you're going to find this dog?
The array of the bite
the squarish impression
of the jaw
are unique to a Dane
or Dane mix.
And there are only 40 registered
in the greater Las Vegas area.
So if one of them
is owed a visit
by the Tooth Fairy...
yes... I think I can.
Corn.
Hamburger.
Rawhide.
But no human cellular tissue
in this sample.
Only 30 more jars to go.
This is rough, man.
We should be pulling
better cases by now.
Millionaire murders,
casino heists.
It's interesting how
we categorize evidence
in terms of what
it means to us
as opposed to what
it might mean
to the case.
Uh, we're supposed
to like scat patrol?
Sometimes we deal
with bugs, worms,
waste or worse.
But as scientists
we look beyond
the possibly
offensive qualities
of these things
to what they might
tell us
about the puzzle
we're trying to solve.
Yeah.
Man, do you turn it on
like this at your seminars?
People actually pay to go
to my seminars, Nick.
We've I.D.'d the dog.
Well, if he's got bits
of jogger hanging out
of his mouth, cuff him.
I pulled those rap sheets.
Called around.
And?
The one with the missing tooth
is no angel.
He attacked a gas man
checking a meter.
Took a chunk of thigh
and severed a testicle.
( doorbell chimes )
( dog barks )
Can I help you?
Are you Susan Hillridge?
Yes, Dr. Hillridge.
Is this your dog
Doctor?
Yes, Simba.
Well, you have a problem.
Oh, no. Not again.
What makes you think
Simba was involved?
There have been complaints
about your dog in the past.
Your meter reader's
singing soprano.
Oh, I get it now.
You're talking about
my old dog, Dickie.
He was aggressive.
That's why
I put him down.
Simba just gets out
of the yard a lot.
The dog we're
looking for
is missing a tooth.
I noticed that Simba is
also missing a tooth.
Okay, he is missing a tooth.
But he just gets out
and wrestles with
neighbors' garbage cans.
He's not a violent dog.
That may be.
We still have to take him into
custody until we can determine
whether or not he had any
involvement in this homicide.
Officers, go ahead.
He's all yours.
You're making a mistake.
GRISSOM:
You said that
you were a doctor.
May I ask your specialty?
Nutrition.
My patients are mostly
professional athletes.
Do you ever consult
with amateur athletes?
Like marathoners?
You mean like that jogger?
What was his name?
Terry Manning.
Doesn't ring a bell.
And I'm very good with names,
Mr. Grissom.
You'll let me know when
I can pick up Simba.
You're assuming a lot.
So are you.
So you did the tox screen
on my carnie?
Roger that.
You know, I have seen
guys drink, like, five
gallons of water
to try and dilute
their urine.
It's the old straight flush.
But all Bad Boy Sanders
has to do
is just test the specific
gravity and blammo.
I can still catch
their toxic butts.
Mm-hmm.
So?
So your guy didn't do that.
Great.
What'd he do?
Try and mask it?
No.
Oh, come on, that
creep tested clean?
Yeah.
For someone who's on the pill.
What?
He's got synthetic estrogen
in his urine sample.
Should modulate
his mood swings.
Oldest trick in the book.
Somebody else's urine.
Probably keeps a stash
in his trailer.
And that Uniform was
too green to look for it.
Isn't that in
the Constitution somewhere?
A man's inalienable right
to pee in private?
Hey, I just got off
the phone with OSHA.
Our carnival has violations
in eight states.
What a surprise.
But that's
not all.
More than half
these guys
have records.
And Pickens, the boss?
His real name is Roger Peet.
He's a convicted
sex offender on parole.
Let's go.
How was I supposed to know
she's 16 and a half?
From the neck down
she was all grown up.
You know what I mean?
I have a teenage daughter.
So, no, I don't
know what you mean.
Jerry Lee Lewis, man.
Same thing happened to him.
What's all this got to do with
the little dead girl, anyway?
You tell us.
I was walking down the midway
and I seen this woman come
whishing out of the tunnel
screaming for her daughter.
My baby! My baby!
My baby!
Me and Joey,
he's the Operator
we hit the kill switch,
stop the ride
ran in the tunnel
and look for the kid.
And I seen
her laying
facedown in the pool of water.
What did you do?
I didn't do nothing.
She was dead.
I didn't come within
two feet of her.
I'm sorry
about what happened.
But that's all that I know.
If you so much
as breathed on this child
the evidence will tell me.
You can dope your urine
change your name
compare yourself
to Elvis himself
but if you harmed Sandy Dantini,
I'm going to get you.
You worried you tipped
your hand in there?
No.
Look, don't bite
my head off,
but any chance
you're going after this guy
because you're a mother?
Pickens is a drug addict
and sex offender operating
a two-ton kid magnet.
Did you take a look
around that carnival?
Yeah.
Did you notice anything
about those other rides?
Maybe.
Ferris wheel--
single cars in the open.
Zipper-- single cars
in the open.
Himalaya-- group cars
How come Pickens was hanging
around the only ride
that takes kids
into the dark?
What if he pulled
that little girl
out of the car?
You have anything
to support that?
Hey.
We aren't going
to lunch are we?
Simba's mold's still damp,
but you can see
it's a perfect match
to the bite mark
on the jogger.
Does this mean Simba's going
to the big dog pound in the sky?
No, we need to build
some more evidence.
Find some jogger
in Simba's stool.
Well, I can
tell you
we found a unique sample
at the crime scene.
Great Dane-sized scat containing
bits of premium
pet store kibble.
How premium?
Sirloin, rice, nothing
artificial.
We need to find out what
Dr. Hillridge feeds her dog.
Just coming to see you.
You remember that ice we found
at the crime scene?
There's nothing in here.
It didn't melt.
It evaporated.
Dry ice.
Frozen CO2 sublimates
into invisible gas, not water.
The jogger was missing
some organs.
Surgical teams use dry ice
to pack organs
shipped for transplant.
It just so happens the dog's
owner is a doctor.
Surgeon?
Nutritionist.
But all medical residents
have surgical rotations.
Fellas, we have
a doctor's appointment.
Would you mind
if I looked in your freezer?
I have a patient coming
in exactly 20 minutes
so if you want to rifle
around until then, fine
but I will not leave
my place of business.
No one's asked you to.
You're very organized,
Dr. Hillridge.
I imagine
you're upset
about your dog--
having to put him down.
I don't hold onto things.
I accept the evolution
of change.
We live, we die,
we replenish the earth.
Man's best friend...
but not yours, huh?
None of us gets out alive.
I would think in your job
you'd know that.
But if we treat our
bodies like a temple
we can cheat time.
Your eyes...
What?
The lower rims are pale.
You're deficient in folic acid.
You're not eating
your beets.
Two beets have 541/////2%
percent of the RDA.
May I ask you what medical
school you attended?
Will that help
with your investigation?
I just thought the way you
handled that knife...
Oh, the knife. No.
I was in the CIA.
Culinary Institute of America.
( blender whirring )
Tell me, Mr. Grissom
how does a man choose death
as his profession?
It chose me, actually.
I guess one man's corpse
is another man's candy.
Care for a sip?
It's full of folacin.
No, thanks.
Griss, can I show you something?
Excuse me.
Surgery equipment.
"Emory Medical Supplies,
Boston, Mass, 1875."
Antiques.
Boy, these are
well maintained.
Exactly.
What I find interesting
is that she keeps them near
the door, not in the office.
In case she needs to break out
and go do some work.
Maybe she makes house calls.
May we help you?
Yes, is Dr. Hillridge around?
I'm here for a 4:00.
Edwin.
You look great today.
How'd the race go?
I finished in three hours
and ten minutes.
You can do better.
She gives me the willies.
We can't arrest
her for that.
Yeah, well, maybe
we can link these
to the crime.
Her dog may have eaten
that jogger
but he can't harvest
the organs.
No question about it, the cause
of death is drowning.
How tall
was the victim?
Three feet, give or
take an inch.
The water was
a foot and a half deep.
She could've easily climbed out,
unless she was unconscious.
Maybe she had a minor
concussion, or was stunned.
That could explain why she
couldn't get out.
I checked, believe me.
She didn't.
The only injury
I could find on
this little girl
was a fractured
forearm.
Spiral or straight?
X-rays just came back.
Let's see.
Spiral.
That's not from a fall.
Somebody twisted
that little girl's arm
hard enough to break it.
Perimortem?
Swelling takes
at least two to four minutes
of active circulation.
There's no swelling,
so it had to happen
moments before she died.
So someone did yank her out
of that car in the dark.
Mommy!
Sandy!
Wait.
Pickens yanks her out
just so he can drown her?
He's a sex offender.
He was going
to take her someplace.
Not without someone seeing him.
You read the OSHA report.
How many emergency doors
were operational?
None.
He was trapped like a rat.
He did the only thing he could--
he hid the evidence.
Drowned the little girl.
I'm going to go call Brass.
You're going
to enter this
as a homicide, right?
Technically, it's
somewhere between
accidental and undetermined.
It's a homicide.
I'm going to get your proof.
So write down that accidental
in pencil.
Can you help me?
I need to find out when my
daughter's going to be released.
I'm not a coroner.
What's your daughter's name?
Sandy Dantini.
Oh, Mrs. Dantini.
I'm Catherine Willows
from the Crime Lab.
You've spoken with
my colleague,
Sara Sidle.
I'm so sorry.
Um... did you find out what
happened at the carnival
to my baby?
Actually, I'd like to ask
you a few questions.
Is it possible
that someone reached
into your car
and pulled out your daughter?
I... thought it was an accident.
You read all the time
about how dangerous
amusement parks can be.
You think it can never
happen to you.
You think you can
protect your kids.
Well, when you went in
the water to try to save Sandy
did you hear anything?
Did you... sense that anyone
was there... in the dark?
I-I-I don't know.
I mean, well, you know,
it all happened so fast.
I was... focused on
finding Sandy.
Do you...
do you think someone else
was there?
I'm not ruling anything out.
Look, I didn't do
anything wrong.
I may have recycled
a few caskets
but you're
talking about
a whole different
ball game, here.
Mr. Gesek, I'm not
accusing you of anything.
I'm not even
here officially.
Think of yourself
as a consultant
to the Las Vegas Crime Lab.
Do I get paid?
What do you know
about organ theft?
Oh, if I was
in that business
I wouldn't worry
about getting paid.
You know there are
places overseas
that'll pay 50 grand
for one lung?
60 for a heart?
And you know
this because...?
Not firsthand.
Not even secondhand.
At the last funeral
directors' convention...
you'd be amazed
what you hear.
But, you know,
it takes a lot
to keep a
business afloat.
Tell me about
the local market for organs.
Well, we're talking about
life and death.
It's probably pretty good.
If someone was disemboweled
and their liver taken
what would that go for?
Menu, everything a la carte.
Corneas, $5,000.
Kidney, $20,000.
Liver, 40.
Bowel, 30.
Pancreas, 18.
It's amazing what you can learn
at a convention.
Warrick.
I got a match.
Cool.
Yeah.
You want to
hand me those
filter papers
right there?
The scat I found
at the crime scene
and the scat from
the doctor's house
were the same,
except for one difference.
The stuff from the backyard--
full of human
cellular tissue.
Jogger DNA.
So we got the right dog.
Well, let's see
if the owner cut the vic up.
Reactive agents.
One part
leuko-malachite.
hydrogen peroxide--
used by blondes
everywhere.
Blue.
Weird, isn't it?
What's that?
To prove
the presence of heme
the stuff
that makes blood red...
Turns the swab blue.
Yeah.
I own this attraction
and it's going with me
to the next town.
It's evidence.
It's not going anywhere.
Nothing is.
What, says you
two string beans?
It's going
to take a
lot more than
vegetable insults
to get us to move.
Lady, you don't know
who you're messing with.
Oh, I know exactly
who you are, Mr. Pickens.
And if you so much
as look at me
in the wrong way,
I will personally
lock you in a cell
with someone who's going
to do the same thing to you
that you've been doing
to those little girls.
BRASS:
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
What, you start
the party without me?
That could get dangerous.
Thomas Pickens?
Yeah.
I got a court order.
This ride stays in Vegas
and you're coming with me.
You pullin' my pud?
You know, the thought
never crossed my mind.
Come on.
What?
Nothing.
This is fun.
As compared to what?
As compared to a more
scientific approach.
I'm sorry, guys.
If she cut up that jogger
she didn't use that scalpel.
But we found evidence
of blood on it.
I had Sanders
run a degradation
on that same sample.
The blood is
50 to 200 years old.
Antique, like
the scalpel
ruling out
the possibility
it was used
in the murder of our jogger.
( phone ringing )
Yeah.
I'll be
right out.
I have a visitor.
Hi.
I have folic acid.
I was worried
about your eyes.
I assume my
surgical instruments
came back clean,
or relatively clean.
Are you here for
a nutritional
consultation
or to eavesdrop
on my investigation?
Actually, my house
felt a little crowded--
all those men you sent.
The, uh, police sent them.
But you dictated the
scope of the warrant.
They're taking everything
from my kitchen and office.
You have three prior complaints
in three separate states
for owning vicious dogs.
And?
What else do you
know about me?
Each complaint is
from a mountain state.
Is it a crime to
like the mountains?
No.
Only if we find other joggers
have turned up dead.
What's a liver go for
these days, Doc?
What?
Terry Manning was missing
several key organs--
healthy organs.
You disappoint me.
I thought you were
smarter than that.
Coenzyme Q-10 could
help with mental acuity.
"The last act is bloody
however fine
the rest of the play."
Pascal.
Very impressive.
I prefer Buddha,
though.
"Even death is not to be feared
by those who lived wisely."
One request.
Ask them not to leave
my house a mess.
You know how I like order.
What, are you guys
working in bulk now?
Hey, you're the one who said
that lady doc keeps
skipping town.
If the jogger's blood
is in any of this stuff,
we need to find it now.
This is only part of
the kitchen-- the rest is
in those bags and boxes.
I'm ready, Nick.
You want to
hit the lights?
She made a protein shake
in this yesterday
right in front of me.
Why would she do that?
Get this to DNA--
see if this is
the jogger's blood.
I'd place a bet on it.
Whoa, whoa.
So she's not
selling the organs
on the black market...
she's eating them?
Possibly drinking them.
I want four techs in there
placed four feet apart.
Let's try to pull
the girl out
from every
conceivable angle.
Okay, based on our theory
a loose seat belt
enabled Pickens
to yank the little girl
out of her seat.
Mom was on the left.
42 pounds?
Just like
little Sandy.
And, just like...
the loose seat belt.
The belt wasn't loose enough
to yank the girl out.
Forget Pickens.
The only person who
could've done it, then
is the person that was in
the car with her-- the mother.
Her eyes were pointing
in the wrong direction.
I'm sorry, what?
Carla Dantini was looking left
when she told me
about the accident.
When a person is remembering,
they look right
and when they're creating,
they look left.
And by creating,
you mean fabricating.
Neurolinguistics
programming
human behavioral science.
Call Brass and tell him
to meet us
at the mother's house.
Mr. Grissom.
You're looking grim.
I'm afraid I don't have
a supplement for that.
We found blood in
your kitchen blender.
The lab has matched it
to the dead jogger.
It had to happen eventually.
Why?
You're the scientist.
I should have thought
you'd figured that out.
I haven't.
Think of the bugs, Grissom.
Cycle of life?
Angels versus insects?
When we die
the fable we tell ourselves
is we go toward
a white light and angels.
But you and I both know
the hard reality
is that insects
arrive immediately
and begin turning us
back to earth.
Yes.
But the insects
haven't killed anyone.
No.
But they'd die if they didn't
have bodies to feed off of.
And so will I.
Porphyria.
The madness of King George.
Or the legend of the vampire.
Which makes it
a real hard disease to have.
But it's real for me.
It's genetic.
The only thing
my father ever gave me.
The first time it presented
was after a minor sunburn.
My lips receded,
so did my gums.
I increased my glucose intake
and I was fine...
for a while.
I began
a drug regimen.
But they only treated
the symptoms.
I had my spleen removed
because it absorbed my blood.
But nothing helped.
Lesions started forming
on my face.
That's when I bought
my first dog.
Bullets and poison
leave residue in the blood.
Dogs kill clean.
Imagine what I'd look like
by now without them.
You could've tried
intravenous hematin.
Human blood is
the richest source of heme.
And so you extracted
the organs with
the most blood--
the liver,
the spleen,
the heart.
If you lock me up, I'll go mad.
Unfortunately,
a symptom of your condition.
But you've been
killing people, Doctor.
I'll die in prison.
Yes, but the people
you'd be feeding off of
will still be alive.
Cycle of life.
Sergeant.
You're under arrest for
the murder of Terry Manning.
You have one more question.
How could
I consume
raw organs?
Not morally,
aesthetically.
I dried them
and ground them into powder.
Protein powder.
You want
an empirical experience?
There's a fresh shake
in my fridge.
Let's go.
Officer.
She is nuts, right?
She's a cold-blooded killer.
You got the
warrant, right?
Yeah, but it's
limited in scope.
The boyfriend's
an attorney
so we can't
toss the place.
Mrs. Dantini.
You have news
about Sandy?
We may have a lead.
We need to see the clothes
that you wore
the day that your
daughter died.
Why?
It's okay, honey.
I'm Hugh Young,
Mrs. Dantini's attorney.
Carla's grieving.
We both are.
Can't this wait
till after the funeral?
No, it can't.
Where's your bedroom?
WILLOWS:
So this is everything
that you wore
at the carnival
last night?
Yes.
Your watch is waterlogged.
Yes. I went into the water
after my daughter.
So, you jumped in the water.
Yes.
How come your shoes are dry?
Well... it
was yesterday.
Of course they're dry.
The lining's blue.
If they'd gotten wet
the indigo dye would have bled
onto your white socks.
You never went in the water.
WILLOWS:
If you didn't go
into the water
how did your watch get wet?
Like I told her
reaching for
my daughter.
You reached for her all right.
My baby!
And when she managed
to grab onto you
you broke her arm.
And you held her under
while you sat in that car
until you drowned her.
YOUNG:
Carla
is any of this true?
I want you to leave.
You took your daughter
to the carnival
'cause kids get hurt there
all the time.
You thought the blame
would leave town
with the ride.
Well, you should
have planned better.
What did you actually think?
That you and your boyfriend
would run off like newlyweds?
No kid, no cares?
I never thought
anything like that.
She did.
Didn't you?
I'm going to need a new lawyer.
Bag the evidence.
Arrest her, Jim.
Hey...
you all right?
Yeah.
Since we skipped lunch
you want to get
something to eat?
Walk it off?
I got to go home.
Thanks. Rain check?
Mm-hmm.
( sighs )
You got my call.
It couldn't have come
at a better time.