Previously on CSI:
May I see
your discoloration?
You want to give me
20 bucks?
You want to do time?
( beeping )
You know what?
I got to be somewhere.
Can you handle this from here?
Yeah.
Warrick Brown had
one of my guys
sub for him in court,
but I have it on
good authority
that he was gambling.
I need you to do some background
for me on Warrick.
Warrick? Your favorite CSI.
That’s why I want
you to handle it,
so that Ecklie can’t
accuse me of favoritism.
I got this
surveillance tape.
He was in a casino.
I’m sorry.
( cart rattling )
Woman over Loudspeaker:
Manager to register two, please.
Manager to register two.
( glass shattering )
( sirens chirping )
( garbled police radio
transmissions )
Well, if it isn’t
The Boss himself!
Where’s your
E-Street Band?
They had another gig.
How you doing, Jim?
How’s your "new" old job?
Ah, I can sling scum
all day long. You?
I curse more.
Oh, yeah?
Well, wait.
The shopping cart’s
over here.
The missing woman
is Margaret Shorey.
Lives with her sister.
Went out to get groceries;
never came home.
Car is still in
the parking lot.
And her purse
is still in the cart.
With no wallet.
Maybe she left the purse
as a marker.
Chicken soup, ice packs...
pain reliever...
Sister broke her wrist
in a car wreck.
Hot dogs, hot dog buns...
Junk-food junkie.
Oh, that’s sanitary.
Mustard.
Did you have any mop-ups
in this aisle today?
Yeah. Yeah, as a matter of fact,
we did.
Life holds no surprises.
$1.98 for the mustard...
plus my two cents.
( shatters )
What are you doing?
Now, where would you go?
Oh, man.
Hey, Brass, look at this.
What?
You see this?
See what?
This circumference?
Looks like somebody did
a Brillo job on it.
All I see is a clean door.
You know anything
about this?
Yeah, he’s right--
we cleaned it up today.
I had a complaint.
Kids are always writing crazy
stuff on bathroom doors.
So I had one
of my employees
scrub it off.
Could I borrow a hammer?
( camera shutter clicks )
"I’ve killed 5 women.
Catch me if you can?"
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
( soft talking in background )
Hi, kids.
Hi.
Sara Sidle. 419.
Dead body--bonus.
Oh, somebody likes her job.
Nick Stokes--416,
fight at the Bellagio.
She says she’s a
"friend" of yours.
Ex-girlfriend, Nick?
Well, that depends.
Was she the assaulter
or the assaultee?
You tell us--you like
leather or lace?
No, I’m not even
going there.
Lace.
Catherine,
you have a 418--
an obituary
on a stall door.
I’ll meet you
in the garage
but first, I’ve got
to take care of Warrick.
Oh, no. What are
you going to do?
I don’t know.
I filed my report.
I read it.
Hey.
I missed assignments;
I know.
I’m running late.
What did I pull?
How was court
the other day?
I handed it off to
Michovitch, from Daze.
Uh, I told Sara.
Yeah, because you had, uh,
"personal business."
Yeah.
What’s that?
You...
at the Monaco Casino.
What?
I don’t believe this.
Now you’re pulling
up film on me?
Casinos tape everyone
who walks through their door,
Warrick, you know that.
I thought we had a deal.
We do.
Look, what you do on your time
is nobody’s business.
What you do on my time
is my business.
( sighs )
I was at the casino.
But I wasn’t gambling.
Get me a picture
of the body...
the items on
the bedsheet...
the window,
the drafting table.
( camera shutter clicks )
Everything
on the floor.
Sara Sidle, Crime Scene
Investigation.
And you are...?
I’m... Kenny Berlin.
That’s my brother.
I’m the one
who found him.
Sorry for your loss.
You want to tell me
what happened here?
I don’t...
I don’t know.
I came...I came walking
in the door,
I saw my brother lying there...
stuff everywhere.
All I could think was that...
Hey!
( two gunshots )
Hey, Jeff.
I-I called 9-1-1
and then you guys
showed up, and...
Thank you.
There have been
several burglaries
in the neighborhood;
all benign.
Nothing benign about
two $20s screaming,
"take me" on the bar.
Maybe he missed it?
Yeah, well, it’s hard to miss
all that high-tech
computer equipment.
There’s got to be
five, ten grand there.
First thing I’d take.
He was interrupted.
Before or after
he used a bedsheet
to transport
the silverware?
Pillowcases are the norm,
you know that.
Something’s not right.
( camera shutter clicks )
( indistinct conversation )
Gentlemen, Nick Stokes.
I’m here for the 416; something
about a "special request."
Don’t ask me.
Go ask Catherine Zeta Jones
over there.
Over where?
Thanks.
Excuse me... ma’am?
Oh, Nick, hey...
You got to be kidding me.
Oh, you probably
don’t recognize me
with the shorter hair.
My nipples are
all better, you
want to see?
Yeah, yeah, Kristy Hopkins,
what are you doing here?
I’ll tell you what she’s
doing here--she’s cruising.
No, I’m in here,
minding my own business
shopping for a dress,
spending my hard-
earned money!
Okay, semi-hard-
earned money.
When Squiggy over here
starts harassing me
saying he doesn’t
want my type in here.
He grabs my arm,
cops a feel,
then he spit on me,
so I slugged him!
Whoa, whoa, whoa...
he spit on you?
Wait, you’re not
listening to this?
This is such a crock.
Oh, I’ll
show you...
All right, all right,
break it up, break it up!
Ease up! Ease up!
Ease up!
Hey, I’m pressing charges!
I don’t care
who you know!
Kristy!
What?
It’s all right--
I’ve got to take her in.
Just give me a minute,
will you?
Get over here!
I need your shirt.
Why is it every
time we meet
you’re wanting me to
take my clothes off?
Because every time
we meet,
you put yourself
in a position
where you have
to take them off.
SIDLE:
Using your arms--
how big’s a whale?
Now freeze, don’t move.
Up.
What are you doing?
Checking for blood spatter.
What blood?
Am I a suspect?
This is what I do.
This is how I eliminate you
as a suspect.
I’ll take that
for you.
Well, that’s good news;
no blood, bud.
I am gonna need you
to strip, though.
Right here?
Don’t be shy on my account.
But if you are,
this nice detective
will accompany you
to the bedroom.
Oh, and, uh, I’m going to need
to take your window
with me too.
It’s all in the warrant.
( camera shutter clicks )
The person who wrote this
is left-handed.
And we know that because...?
The "t-bar" in "catch,"
it’s left-tending.
And uneducated...
The contraction
in "Iv’e" is misplaced.
Then we have the large,
arched hood in the letter "Y"
and the arches
in the bottom of the "Ls."
This indicates
criminal tendency,
which is supported
by the heavy pastiosity,
which suggests
low impulse control.
Heavy pastiosity?
The pressure--
how firmly you put pen to paper.
Or marker to metal.
Do we know anything else?
Yes.
Overall, the handwriting
is cursive and round.
This tells me
it was written by a woman.
( machine rumbling )
Damn!
Taking the
whole window.
Grissom reinstated you.
And you have a
problem with that.
Let me guess.
Grissom gets you
to dime yourself off
and now you both feel better?
You’re supposed
to be in court.
Instead, you’re placing bets
for a cheap thrill
to satisfy nothing.
Hey! This has nothing
to do with you.
So are we going
to work together?
Or not?
I’m already working.
( machine rumbling )
You weren’t
in your office.
And good morning
to you too, Miss Sidle.
Warrick has a problem.
Ignoring it isn’t gonna
make it go away.
You asked me
for a report
and then you disregard
my recommendation.
I read your report.
So you feel comfortable
jeopardizing a unit
to placate an addict?
I see the whole puzzle, Sara.
You’re only seeing one piece.
Then at least take
him off my case.
No.
I trust him.
Do you trust me?
( door opening )
Grissom.
I’ve got something
you want to see.
( clears throat )
You know how you’re always
pushing that Holy Trinity stuff?
Father, Son,
Holy Ghost?
Victim, suspect,
crime scene.
That one--oh.
Right. Well,
we don’t have a victim.
We don’t have a suspect.
All we have is
a crime scene--
the restroom
at Marty’s Market
with the message,
"I killed five women."
So I figured there had
to be four others.
You found
the other four victims?
No, I found
the four other crime scenes.
Brass ran our case
through VICAP.
I made a few calls.
"Iv’e killed 1 woman."
Victorville.
Salt Lake City--
"Iv’e killed 2 women.
Catch me if you can?"
San Bernardino--
"Iv’e killed 3 women..."
"Iv’e killed 4 women.
Catch me!" Mesquite.
"...5 women... " Las Vegas.
Five stall doors
from five
supermarket restrooms.
Five missing women,
including Margaret Shorey.
What else do you know
about the crime scenes?
Just like
Marty’s Market--
there was no physical evidence
indicating
that the women
were killed there.
Which means
they were probably alive
when these messages
were written,
making these messages
of intention, not fact.
What if we shuffle these doors
like pai gow tiles?
San Bernardino, California.
Victorville, California.
Las Vegas, Nevada.
Mesquite, Nevada.
Salt Lake City, Utah.
Interstate 15.
God knows I’ve driven
it enough times.
So has our suspect.
Okay, dude, it’s ready.
So this paper should
have soaked up
any foreign material
on the shirt,
particularly amylase...
You know, I’ve done
this procedure
on jeans
and leather jackets,
but never on
something like this.
It’s very see-through.
Very Jennifer Lopez.
Down, boy.
What can you tell me?
Is there saliva on it?
It’s gonna be
a tough one to prove.
This is only step one.
You see,
when a person talks,
saliva naturally comes
out of their mouth.
Let’s say that we’re tossing
the hog back and forth, right?
What can you tell me
about the hottie
that goes
inside this blouse, huh?
Is it true she’s
a friend of yours?
What, is it on the Internet?
Might as well be.
Just remember that.
My saliva’s getting on you;
your saliva’s getting on me.
Gross.
What’s that stuff?
Starch and iodine.
If this is saliva,
we’re gonna get
the ol’ Dalmatian effect.
So, Nick, if I
wanted to meet
this friend
of yours...?
No.
Figured.
That’s a pretty big spot.
That’s more
than just a spray.
In fact, looks like
a distinct glob of spit.
Kristy was telling the truth.
But it doesn’t mean it was
the security guard’s spit.
Step three.
I’m going to need a sample.
Well, if the guy
knows he did it,
he’s not gonna
cough it up.
If you saw the girl
that went with this blouse...
you’d try.
You found what
on my pants?
Glass. Any idea
how it got there?
Well, it’s just a guess,
but someone broke
into my car last weekend
and smashed my window
and made off with my CD player.
So I must’ve been
wearing those pants.
Did you file
a police report?
No, but you can check
with my insurance company.
I already checked with my lab.
They do this test,
and guess what?
The glass--it floated.
You know what that means?
No.
It means the glass
on your pants
and the glass from
your living room window
have equal densities.
Sorry, I was never
very good at science.
The glass didn’t come
from any car window.
That’s science.
Anything else
you’d like to tell us?
Look, it’s like I told you.
I walked in the house...
( rattling )
...and I thought,
"They’re coming back
and they’re gonna kill me too."
I heard a noise
and I walked to the window.
That must be when I got
the glass on my pants.
Look, somebody really did
break into my car, okay?
And I just remembered
all that stuff just now.
So am I in trouble?
You’re free to go.
No, he’s not.
We’re not cops;
we can’t hold him.
Just one more question.
What do you do
for a living?
I’m a day trader.
You make a lot of
money doing that?
That’s two
questions.
Feel free to answer
it anyway.
Yeah, you can.
But you don’t, right?
You showed him
all your cards.
Sucker play.
I was playing him.
Cops ran Kenny’s financials.
He lost a pot
in the market.
Had a ton of
margin calls.
I’m surprised you didn’t tag him
as a fellow gambler.
Oh, you just don’t let up,
do you?
It’s a flaw.
I’ll flip you
to see who drives.
Where we going?
Moapa.
What’s in Moapa?
Besides the I-15?
So my guys tell me
that your guy Nick
is helping a working girl
at a five-star
and it was quite a commotion.
Really?
Yeah, and if I know, it means
a lot of other people know.
People bigger
than you and me.
A kid from a crime lab
doing favors for a hooker?
Can’t make the unit
look too good, huh, boss?
Yeah, well,
I’ll get into it.
You know, I bet that’s
just what Nicky said.
You two ladies
done talking?
It’s hot out here.
So, a kid over there
started to
take a leak.
Found the body.
Well, it’s
not Margaret.
This one’s a blonde.
And blue.
This is bizarre.
The body’s cold.
In this heat?
And she’s stiff--
like a two-minute burrito
that’s only been
nuked for a minute.
Meet Joan Sims
from San Bernardino, California.
We’ve been
getting acquainted.
Missing woman number one--
disappeared
from a supermarket restroom
last July.
Cause of death
was strangulation.
I found ligature marks
on the wrists and the ankles.
That was the easy part.
This one’s weird.
Like, I-may-use-her-
in-a-lecture weird.
Her decomp is
completely backwards.
It’s supposed
to begin on the inside,
but her organs are
in better shape than her skin.
Take a look at this.
I took tissue samples
from her heart.
GRISSOM:
Looks like the planet Krypton.
More like Kryptonite.
Those are actually
ice crystals, Superman.
You want to know
why she’s blue?
Cold to the touch
in the middle of the desert?
This lady was frozen,
kept on ice
until approximately
12 hours ago.
I-15?
Refrigerated?
That’s how she was transported
from San Bernardino
to Vegas--
in a refrigerated truck.
That’s our crime scene.
And it’s mobile.
Hey, Nick,
I’ve been looking for you.
This girl you’ve
been helping with
the 416...?
She got in a fight
with a security guard.
Is she a friend
of yours?
Are you asking me
what I think you’re asking me?
Are you doing anything that
could compromise the unit?
I don’t believe this.
You’ve always been
so cool.
I have to ask.
It’s part of the job.
Sanders ratted me out,
right?
No, Brass.
Do you want to
talk about this?
I don’t think so.
Excuse you.
What’s his problem?
Me, I guess.
Did you find out
anything?
Brass got us a listing of
all the refrigerated trucks
that made deliveries
to the market yesterday.
There’s a female
trucker on it.
SIDLE:
Not bad.
I’m impressed.
Yeah, I passed up
a chance to play
semi-pro ball.
Went to college
instead.
I meant the Haeckel marks.
They should tell us
what we need to know.
This is the glass
you line-drived.
That’s the glass
you "sawzalled."
SIDLE:
Right angles face
the same direction.
Take a look.
Oh, now I’m worthy?
Just take a damn look.
That’s crazy.
I loved my brother.
Maybe you did,
maybe you didn’t,
but we think
you murdered him.
Based on what?
The evidence.
What evidence?
You ever heard of Haeckel marks?
No.
When a window
is broken
from the outside,
which is what a burglar
would do,
Haeckel marks form right angles
to the inside of the window.
But when a window is broken
from the inside,
which is what a peckerwood
like you would do,
Haeckel marks form right angles
to the outside of a window.
What did you use
to break the window, Kenny?
I didn’t use anything.
I didn’t do it.
I want a lawyer.
Well, we know
he did it.
We can’t prove it,
but we’ve got a motive.
He needed the money.
Okay, let’s say
killing his brother
would get it for him.
We’re back to how
do we prove it.
He’s a day trader--
spends all day on his computer.
If we want to know
more about him,
that’s where we
should be looking.
And his computer is...?
Still at the house.
Still at the house?
Well, we got probable cause.
Why don’t we go get a...?
Why don’t you
go get a new warrant?
( fish singing ):
♪ ...I want to know ♪
♪ Can you help me... ♪
That’s my
"Big Mouth Billy Bass."
It’s better
than a watchdog.
I’ve got valuable stuff in here,
you know.
♪ ...Drop me in the water... ♪
Yeah, I bet
there are a lot of people
looking to steal
your two-headed scorpion.
Not to mention "Miss Piggy."
I was out of line earlier.
I’m not sleeping with her,
if it helps any.
It does.
And for the record,
she wasn’t working,
she was shopping.
And the security guard
was a jerk, man.
He pushed her around,
then he spit on her.
That’s why
she lost it.
That sounds
pretty straightforward.
Why don’t you put
a rookie on it?
No, I can’t.
There’s something about her.
Just looking at her--
she doesn’t have
anybody else.
I had Sanders
run a test on the shirt.
There’s saliva on it,
but the problem is,
I can’t get a match.
The security guard
refuses to give
me a sample.
"If Mohammed
won’t go to the mountain,
then the mountain
must go to Mohammed."
Think about it.
Black, no sugar.
Yeah, thanks.
Like I said
on the phone,
I don’t want to
seem biased here.
This girl’s nothing to me.
She’s a hooker.
Yeah, but you do know her.
Yeah, professionally.
My profession, not hers.
I cut her some slack
a while back.
She’s bad news,
but she’s a babe.
( chuckling ):
Tell me about it.
Yeah, between you and me,
I should have busted her,
but I thought I might get lucky.
Yeah.
Well, next time
she gets in a jam,
she throws my name out.
My boss--not pleased.
So...
( clearing throat )
Tell me what you think.
I want you to write
down your own statement,
seal it up in
this envelope,
and I’ll hand-deliver
it to the D.A.
It’ll be good
for both of us.
Yeah. Thanks, man.
No problem.
Us guys have got to stick
together, right?
That’s right. Yeah.
That’s right.
Of course
I graduated high school.
Hey, if this is gonna
take forever,
I could lay a urine sample
on you too, gratis.
A writing sample would be
sufficient, thank you.
What’s that gonna
tell you--
whether I was writing
under the influence?
Do yourself a favor.
Yes, ma’am.
Now, what is it
that you want me to write?
"I’ve got a kite.
"Can you see the women?
Kill the lights."
That’s what you want me
to write?
Three times.
Caucasian female with only
a high school education
and left-handed.
You can keep the pen
as a souvenir.
I’ll be right back.
Hey, come on!
You’re making me late.
Hey, hey, hey.
Two cheeks on the car.
There you go.
Okay, thanks.
She’s not the one.
So did I win
something?
The right to
keep on trucking.
( chuckles )
Here you go, bubba.
Hey, we’re outta here!
You know,
I’m starting to think
that maybe we should
be looking for a man.
Only 3% of multiple killers
are female.
And a woman
wouldn’t need a trophy.
BRASS:
And a body on ice
is definitely a trophy.
Well, Ms. Hard-ass travels
with her boyfriend.
I bet you a lot of guys
travel with their girlfriends.
What if it was a man
with a woman
who would do anything he asked?
Then I said,
"Hey, us guys have
to stick together."
He’s like, "Right.
You’re the man!"
So, I mean, I could’ve
used an STR-DNA
but it’s too state-of-the-art,
it’s overkill.
So I used
an HLA-DQ-A1 with a...
polymarker.
That’s--that’s very,
very interesting.
You don’t care about this
at all, do you?
No.
( chuckles )
But to be honest with you,
all I really care about
is whether the charges against
me are going to be dropped.
Are they?
The D.A. threw out the case.
Great.
So I can shoplift
at that boutique again?
I was kidding,
I was kidding.
Besides, they never have any
good sales there, anyway.
( chuckling )
I’d invite you out
for coffee, but...
it’s probably
a bad idea.
Uh, yeah.
Yeah.
But I can call you
sometime, you know,
just in case I ever
get into trouble
or something.
Maybe you should try
not getting into trouble.
You do owe me one.
I owe you two.
You know
where to find me.
Is that right?
Your boy Kenny
just lawyered up.
Well, we got a warrant,
so that should give us
the room for a minute.
There’s something
wrong with it.
Computers turn on.
When they don’t,
it’s for a reason.
Did you plug it in?
The power light’s on.
Really?
Let me check it out.
Well, he’s a sneaky S.O.B.,
I give him that.
SIDLE:
Oh, o one is gonna
believe this.
( snaps picture )
All right.
Let me see
that flashlight.
There’s scratches
all over it.
Nothing really
special about them.
And the hotshot
takes another strike.
Check it out.
Not enough to cause
even a small scratch
on your finger,
but more than enough
to use as a basis
for comparison.
SIDLE:
We match this to
the broken window, we got him.
One, two, three.
Left one is from
the broken window
the other one
is from the gun,
both dropping
at an identical rate.
Glass is from
the same source.
So Kenny broke the
window from the inside
using the butt
of the gun.
My theory...
The brother was the executor
of the parents’ estate.
He controlled
the family money.
Sounds like more
than a theory.
I called the county clerk.
With the brother out of the way,
Kenny is the sole beneficiary.
KENNY:
Do you have
any idea
how much money
I’ve lost?
Kenny, come on,
what are you doing?
I’m your brother, okay?
I already said
I’d loan you the money, okay?
Come on!
$20,000?
That doesn’t even begin
to solve my problems!
Slam that jail door.
Makes you reconsider,
doesn’t it?
I never said
you weren’t a good CSI.
WOMAN:
We’re state-of-the-art here--
number one in vehicle
satellite tracking.
I can locate
one or all
of our trucks
with just a click
of a mouse, 24-7.
Do you ever worry
that technology
is gonna make us obsolete?
No.
Can you, uh,
narrow your database?
Say, eliminate all trucks
that are not refrigerated?
Yeah, I think I can.
Can you eliminate all trucks
that were not
in Las Vegas yesterday?
Eliminate all trucks
that only travel in state.
Now eliminate the trucks
that don’t deliver
to supermarkets
along the I-15.
GRISSOM:
This is very cool.
Eliminate all trucks
that did not deliver
to Marty’s Market yesterday.
WILLOWS:
That’s our guy.
He delivered to all five towns
all five supermarkets.
Where is he now?
( squealing tires )
Police!
Get your hands up!
Step away from the truck
and put your hands
on the back
of your head!
Keep your hands in sight!
Get out of the truck!
Hands over
your head!
Step away from the truck.
Put your hands on
the back of your head.
I’m just making
my regular delivery...
Don’t make me ask you twice.
Move! Hands on
the back of your head!
Hands on the back
of your head!
Left hand on the wall,
right hand on the wall.
Check him for weapons.
Police Officer:
Spread your legs. Nice and easy.
Hey, get away from my truck!
It’s not your truck anymore.
It’s our crime scene.
Come with me.
Check the cab.
It’s all yours.
Police Officer:
All clear here, sir.
We got three.
Where is she?
Where is Margaret Shorey?
Screw you, man.
Look, pal,
I already know what happened.
I even know
your type--
Decent, trusting,
middle-aged women.
Please help me...
You got to help me!
I locked my baby in the car!
Did you call
the manager?
It is so hot,
she’s gonna die.
Please help me!
All... all right.
Where’s your car?
This way.
( muffled screaming )
Go on! Write it!
( muffled screaming continues )
Okay. All right, listen.
First one of you lowlifes
can name that tune
gets to make a deal.
Hmm?
The difference between the chair
or life in prison.
So...
He made me do it.
( screams )
Cuff him.
Man:
Let me go!
Hey, hey, hey...
Where is she?
( metallic rattling )
There’s a lock.
Are there any keys?
Try those.
Hello, Margaret.
My name is Gil.
This is Catherine.
We’re gonna
take you home.
You look lost.
Oh, yeah...
Do you know Warrick Brown?
Yeah, you want me
to tell him you’re here?
Oh, he’s probably working.
He works really hard.
If you see him,
could you just tell him
that, uh, Jason says thanks?
Okay. Will he know what for?
Uh...
Hey, Jas, how you doing?
Better.
Hey, thanks
for busting me loose.
My mom said she’ll pay you back.
No, you’ll pay me back, shorty.
Just don’t be pulling
any more fire alarms.
I won’t.
Gets you more attention
than you want.
I know.
You still working on those moves
I showed you?
Yeah, every day after school.
How about that?
How about that
right there?
Good.
Hey, I got to go.
My mom’s waiting for me.
Hey, come here.
Apologize to your mom,
all right?
Let her know
she can trust you.
Yeah.
All right?
Bye, Warrick, uh...
see you next week.
See you next week, Jaws.
So you went to the casino
to win bail money.
He needed my help.
I didn’t win
anything, Sara.
You’re a CSI.
You saw me enter
a casino.
Did you see me
place a bet?
You want to tell me you didn’t?
I don’t have
to tell you anything.
Look, I went there to collect
a debt that was owed to me.
We’re supposed
to be working together.
Next time,
just try talking to me
instead of going around
behind my back.