( thunder crashing )
( rapid tapping )
( thunder rumbling )
( thunder crashing )
( screaming )
Eileen Jane Snow.
Lady she
carpools with
couldn't get her
to answer the door.
Police broke in.
This is exactly the same
as the last two.
Audrey Hayes
was strangled
in her basement
and the other one
ended up in a park.
Different M.O.,
but it's the same signature.
M.O. is how he breaks in.
Signature's what he does
once inside.
Three or four
overpowering blows to the head
from a homemade weapon
fashioned
at the scene.
Forces her to drink a mixture
of sodium amytal
as a chemical
restraint.
Overligature of the victim
and an object rape.
Then he strangles her.
Ejaculates on the bedsheets.
And as a final
act of degradation
he poses her
like a pinup.
Damn it.
Sara.
Damn that guy.
Listen, no
emotions in here.
He's escalating,
Grissom.
That's the pattern;
it's a continuum.
Guess he wants
to get caught.
Signature killers never
want to get caught.
And they won't stop
until they do.
[Captioning sponsored by
CBS
and CBS PRODUCTIONS/
ALLIANCE ATLANTIS]
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
I have tape-lifted,
roll-lifted--
I'm not finding
one hair.
I wonder what that might mean.
He vacuumed this place
before he left.
We've established
that he utilizes
materials
from the victim's domicile.
Hey, guys.
He took the bag.
Well, look for prints.
Don't bother.
There aren't any.
Just like the last time.
The guy's Mr. Clean.
Here, knock yourself out.
He stalked
this woman.
He knew how much time
he had in this apartment
to kill her,
and to clean up after himself.
I'll tell Brass
to check for sex offenders
in a two-mile radius.
Yeah, have him check
peeping Toms, too
five years back.
That's how they
get started.
Peeping Toms to murderers?
It's about crossing boundaries.
It's like, uh,
with cake, you know?
You're just going to have
a little bit of the frosting
and you end up eating
the entire plate.
BROWN:
Nobody move.
Mr. Clean needs a maid.
I'm going to take this
back to the lab.
Gil.
I need a word
with you outside.
You're bringing
the FBI in? Why?
They offered their assistance,
and I'm inclined to take it.
Of course, uh,
I'd want to make sure
you're okay with that.
I-I don't believe
the investigation
should go
that way, Brian.
I mean, roadblocks
and special ops?
Oh, that's a pity,
'cause I do.
Maybe you'll
feel different
when you meet
Rick Culpepper.
Sheriff Mobley.
Rick.
Hi, Rick Culpepper.
Federal Bureau
of Investigation.
Gil Grissom,
Agent Culpepper.
Uh, Special Agent.
It's great
to meet you.
All our kids
back in Quantico
are always going on
about your bugs.
Well, listen,
the FBI is here
to help you
and your people at CSI.
Of course, uh, as SAC
the investigation
will run through me.
Sheriff probably
already told you that.
No, he didn't
mention that, either.
All rivers
run through Rome
so to speak.
( chuckling )
But, uh, you get an attaboy.
Three women dead
'cause you couldn't
get the job done.
There's not many guys
who would hand the case over
to us fibbies.
I'm not handing it over.
I'm willing to work
in conjunction with you.
Well, that's fine.
We'll work the Strip Strangler
case in conjunction.
The what?
He strangles them
near Las Vegas Boulevard
then removes their clothes.
Why, what
are you calling him?
Unknown Signature Homicide,
Metropolitan Las Vegas.
Oh. He's not kidding, is he?
O'RILEY:
Excuse me.
Guy over here's
got something
you might want to hear.
Syd Goggle.
He's a security guard.
Community patrol.
Says he saw a man
speeding away from
here last night.
Mr., uh, Goggle?
Gil Grissom.
I know who you are, sir.
I've seen you on TV.
Special Agent
Culpepper.
You have information for us
about a man fleeing the scene?
I didn't get his license.
I didn't think of it
till this morning.
He was really
burning rubber, though.
Would you please
give Detective O'Riley
a full statement?
If we have any more questions,
we'll get back to you.
Listen, if you need any help
in your investigation,
Mr. Grissom...
The last time a security
guard tried to help me
he ended up dead.
But thank you.
MAN:
This way.
I'm late for an autopsy.
He'll need a
little patience.
Wouldn't respect him
if he didn't.
What can you tell us?
Nothing you don't know.
Trauma to the head
with a blunt object.
Overwhelmed her.
He got a mixture
of sodium amytal in her.
A hypnotic.
Allowed him to control her
for up to six hours.
Torture her.
Look at the bruises.
Purple means
she was alive for all of it.
Percussive control.
He choked her
unconscious
and then brought her to
multiple times.
What about the rape?
Same as the others:
indeterminate object
caused severe
internal lacerations.
I did find
a small trace of something
creviced in the uterine wall.
Looks like an everyday polymer
to me.
Okay. I'll go back to the scene,
try to find something like it.
Be careful, Nicky.
The chilche's true.
Signatures
return
to their scenes.
Will do.
Are we done?
Something we didn't find
with the other two women.
Fibers.
One in the back
of her throat.
One stuck
between her lower molars.
This looks like cotton.
Maybe terry cloth.
Could be silencing
them with...
white bath towels?
Well,
it would explain
why no one hears
the victim's screams.
He brings it with him
and takes it away after.
So, somewhere, there's evidence
of this victim on a towel.
Kind of a forensic smoking gun.
Mmm. Now we just
have to find the guy
and hope that he hasn't
done his laundry.
The semen taken from
this morning's homicide
matches the semen taken
from the bedsheets
of the last two
female victims.
So, we're looking
at the same guy.
Yeah, but,
check this out.
The ejaculate sample.
What's the red stuff?
Mystery substance.
Not blood?
No.
So, what, this guy's
got some strange chemical
in his mutated DNA?
Freaky, huh?
Freakiest semen
I've seen in a while.
Call me.
Oh.
Catherine, you busy?
I was hoping we might be able
to talk about a few things.
Pertaining to the case?
As a jumping-off point.
Well, Sheriff,
I'd say let's
go to my office
but I don't have one.
Well, that's just
the sort of thing
I was hoping we would discuss.
Hey, Warrick
you got a second?
What's up?
I got this hair
that Catherine
found this morning
and I'm trying
to compare it to the one hair
we recovered
from the murder last week--
the Hayes girl?
And you got a match
microscopically
but it doesn't mean
a damn thing
'cause it still
doesn't lead us to the guy?
No. I can't even tell
if we have a DNA match.
There's no skin tag
on either one.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
A girl defending herself
against a guy
is going to pull that hair out
by the roots.
I mean, you get scalp skin
filled with DNA.
No scalp, no skin.
It's almost like
this hair was...
Shed?
( beeping )
Mine.
Hey, Gil, you want
to give me the skinny
on this meeting
of yours?
I'm on my way back
to the crime scene.
What meeting?
I'm going to Evidence.
I got paged
about the signature case.
Hey, Warrick and
I just got a break.
The guy's been
planting hairs.
Shedding. He's trying
to throw us off.
What he doesn't realize,
we got no DNA on the hairs
so we can't chase down
his other suspect.
Grissom...
are you hearing us?
You all got my page. Good.
I didn't.
We'll get you a new battery.
I thought we'd convo
about the strangler.
Hear what you've got
tell you what we think
our next move should be.
Would you guys go back
to my office, please?
I'll be in in a few minutes.
I'll be happy
to pass on
any pertinent information
you may have to my team.
Okay. Fine.
Got anything to report to us?
You first.
Okay. We have an operation
in place.
Your CSI, Sidle
has expressed
an interest to my agents
in availing herself.
I wanted to let you know
before we made
the official offer.
Really? What kind of operation?
All this talk about your great
capacity for observation.
Sara Sidle matches
the victim prototype to a "T."
She's a young woman,
brunette, tall for a female.
You're not serious.
And by all reports,
she's steady.
Has the right personality
for a decoy operation.
You're going to bait this guy
with a human being?
This is your big FBI plan?
Before he kills again, yes.
Got a better idea?
Understanding him
first, completely
so that we can get
out ahead of him.
And if
he kills again
while we're trying
to understand him?
Well, I'm sorry, but he's
not going to kill my CSI.
I'm going to do it, Grissom.
I want to.
You want to put
yourself in the path
of a psychotic killer?
I'm trained
in weaponless defense.
Too bad, because that's
what turns him on--
women fighting back.
Gives him a greater
sense of power
when he makes
his final kill.
Grissom...
Sit down, Sara.
Okay. If we're to follow
your line of thinking
are you out ahead of him?
Not yet.
He knows just enough
about forensics
to be dangerous.
He thinks
he's throwing us off track
by planting confederate hairs.
He probably shaves his head
maybe his entire body
as DNA protection.
He may gag
his victims
using a garden-
variety bath towel
which he then takes with him
as part of his murder kit.
He will go after
another tall brunette
and the torture will be worse.
But this time,
he won't ejaculate.
At least not
at the scene.
At home, later.
Learning control.
Think he knows his next victim?
Signature killers
always know their next victim.
But they don't know him
until he tortures,
rapes and kills them.
( faint creaking )
( screaming )
Freeze!
Hey.
Get out of there.
Get out of the closet.
Hmm.
What are you doing?
Um, I a reporter.
What?
We know the police
are withholding
information from us,
so I came down here because...
Are you out of your mind?
I could've killed you.
This a crime scene.
You don't belong here.
Unless you want me to get
the cop at the front door
you'll get out of here now.
And I'd better not
see any pictures
of this apartment
in your paper...
or I'll have the D.A.
on your front door.
I'm sorry that I scared you.
You didn't scare me.
Mm-mm.
Want to tell me what you found
over by the window?
No.
( softly ):
Okay.
Fast.
I'm impressed.
You got a hot dog?
This one of your jokes, Greg?
I got the ketchup.
I'm sure this is meaningful.
I went back
and looked at
the ejaculate from the last
two murders.
The same thing.
"Indeterminate red stuff."
It's C12, H22
and O11, NaCl, H2O
and tomato paste.
Sugar, water, salt
Ketchup?
Ketchup.
Well, does he
add it after or is it organic?
Don't ask me why, but, uh...
he adds it.
I was expecting something
a little more elemental.
When we zig, he zags.
Yeah, well, he's not
as smart as he thinks,
you know?
I mean, ketchup is not going
to mask the DNA in his semen.
All of which I'm sure
you'll share with the FBI.
I'm sure.
Hey...
is it so bad to avail our lab
to the resources
of the federal government?
You've been to talking
to our sheriff.
I've been listening
He says that you won't.
Yeah, yeah, I know.
And if I don't shape up
he going to have Ecklie
take over the case.
No, he prefers
someone from night shift
and it may be more
than just this case.
Ah.
Now that the trees are gone,
I can almost see the forest.
Gil...
learn to be more politic.
( knocking on door )
You guys got a sec?
He's wearing latex gloves.
The thick kind, too.
He must know
the thin ones
leave prints.
When we zig,
he zags.
BRASS:
What about Paul Millander?
Maybe he's our guy.
And, uh, he had
the latex hands.
And he's a serial.
Millander stages suicides
in bathtubs
with paternal figures.
This guy's signature
is overkill rage
against young women.
It's completely different.
Maybe our brethren at the FBI
have some sort
of special database.
When did you become friendly
with the feds?
I didn't think you had that
in you.
Never make an enemy when you can
just as easily make a friend.
FBI's okay.
I've kissed
worse ass.
But I've got to say
I don't like this decoy op
the feds are talking up.
I remember when
Holly Gribbs died.
I sent her out in the field
and she wasn't ready.
I told Culpepper
that he could not have Sara.
I know what you told him.
CULPEPPER:
Okay, listen up.
All personnel will be
tethered to our decoy
by this radio.
According to
Captain James Brass
two of our assailant's
victims patronized this
specialty grocery store
to which we are about
to embark forthwith
two days before they
turned up dead.
There's a very good chance
our assailant
will refrequent this store,
looking for his next victim.
This is a pretty flimsy excuse
to get your circus up
and running, don't you think?
Lives are at stake.
I'll take flimsy over nothing.
This is action
for action's sake
Culpepper.
You're risking my CSI's life.
SIDLE:
Look, this
is my idea.
I want to do something
before another girl
gets killed and...
Listen to me, Sara.
If we study his past,
we can predict his future.
You've been saying
that for weeks.
It's taking too long.
Someone else is going to die
and you're still going
to be figuring it out.
CULPEPPER:
Sidle
we're good to go.
Wish me luck.
( "Danke Schoen" playing
over intercom )
( sighs )
( carts clanking )
Oh... it's three hours expended.
( clears throat )
Maybe we should reposition
over at that Borders Book Store.
Gets a lot of foot traffic
in there
according to the field agents.
♪ I recall ♪
♪ Central Park in Fall ♪
♪ How you tore your dress. ♪
Whoa.
That guy's coming back.
Would you happen to
have a cigarette?
Uh... yeah, actually.
Culpepper...
Let her play.
I've been trying to quit.
Didn't want to buy a pack.
Me, too.
This is my last pack...
but, uh, I say that
every week, so...
Nonfiltered.
The women I know
smoke filtered-- you know
those long, skinny cigarettes?
Guess it depends on the woman.
Guess it does.
You got a light?
Sure. Yeah.
You live around here?
Maybe.
I don't usually give out
that kind of information.
It's probably smart.
I wouldn't tell me either.
You're cute.
Thanks.
All right, we're on the move.
Let's go.
( guns cocking )
Hey!
OFFICER:
Don't move!
I'll give it back. Here.
( cell phone ringing )
Yeah, Culpepper.
Time and coordinate?
Yeah, will do.
All right, gentlemen
nothing ventured,
nothing gained.
I do not believe
this is our man.
What was your first clue?
Murder at the Monaco Hotel.
Woman found bound in her room
stripped and strangled.
He met the profile.
Sometimes the harder thing
to do is to do nothing.
Starting to look like
deja vu all over again.
Hmm.
Not?
Occasionally I'm struck
by the absence of evidence.
It's there
or it isn't.
The lamp--
cord's still attached.
All the others,
he yanked the cords off.
Look at the table.
Books aren't even disturbed.
Staged?
First time in a hotel?
First time he didn't come
in through the window?
I don't think he made
a deposit... either.
That just means his
signature's evolving
isn't that
right, Grissom?
Who's that guy?
BRASS:
He's the husband.
His name's Brad Walden.
They're locals, come here
a couple times a year.
He was downstairs
playing poker.
She was up here reading
a romance novel.
He comes back
five grand richer.
He finds her like this.
Husband?
Let's bring him in.
I'll transport
the witness.
Witness?
Suspect.
What did you get?
I posted the lady from
the hotel, and I have to say
it's the same menu as the last
three-- chemical restraint
overligature,
death by strangulation.
What about the object-rape?
Indeterminate polymer?
No, this one's different.
Different how?
DR. ROBBINS:
Cross-hatched leather, with
tiny air holes for breathing.
I was thinking driving gloves,
or weightlifting gloves, or...
I'm not accusing you of
anything, but a man and his wife
get a hotel room
for a romantic weekend
then spend
that whole weekend apart--
makes me wonder if there's
trouble in the marriage.
I like... to gamble.
She liked to read.
It was, you know...
just the perfect
getaway.
You liked to play golf, too.
These are your golf clubs.
We found them
in your hotel room.
I prefer a titanium
driver, Mr. Walden.
I'd like to see what you use,
but your carrier is locked.
Yeah, I have a key on my
keychain... my car keys.
So you won't mind
opening it, though?
No...
Uh, uh, w-why?
Well, so I can see if the
leather on your club handles
matches the leather
from the object used
to violate your wife.
Well, I-I, you know,
if it does... I read
that this, uh...
this, uh, you know,
character
uses whatever is
at the scene of
the crime for, uh...
for killing his victims.
Well, if this character...
killed your wife?
How did he get your clubs out
of the case without the keys?
Or, for that matter
back into the case
after he killed your wife?
Read this man
his rights, please.
You're under arrest
for the murder
of Jennifer Walden...
and Eileen Snow,
and Tracy Berg, and...
Can I have a word with you
outside... please?
You can't charge him
for the other women.
What do you mean?
For the murder
of his wife, maybe
but I am certain that
he didn't do the others.
Every piece of the
signature is there.
He read the papers--
he piggybacked on
top of the killer.
For what possible reason?
Who knows? Convenient way
out of a lousy marriage?
He's not our guy.
You know, this is where I like
to reference the majesty
and the power of the Republic
of the United States of America.
Go ahead. Pull rank.
But that hotel crime
scene was staged
to look like
the Signature's.
And that golfer
just got lucky
that the victim type fits his
wife to a Texas T, is that it?
If you stop and think,
you'll see it.
Duly noted, Supervisor Grissom.
Duly noted.
Details of the arrest will be
forthcoming in this live report.
Federal Agent Culpepper is about
to start his news conference.
As we've been reporting,
a suspect has been arrested
in the Strip-Strangler case.
We believe that Bradley Mac
Walden not only killed his wife
but also took the lives of
Audrey Hayes and Eileen Snow
and Tracy Berg.
Our field agents have divulged
that Mr. Walden
lived within two miles
of the other victims
worked in the same office
building as Ms. Snow
and has no believable
explanation for his whereabouts
on the dates of their murders.
We believe that
Bradley Mac Walden
found and stalked these
victims, and...
I just talked
with Brass.
He said that Walden
was having an affair
with a dentist
in his office.
I'm telling you, this guy did
not kill those other women.
This statement is concluded.
Las Vegas, its locals
and visitors can rest
a little easier tonight.
A suspect is
in custody.
Thank you.
I'll take some questions.
Mr. Grissom-- Linda Darby,
Las Vegas Tribune.
As the lead CSI on this case
do you have anything to add
to the FBI statement?
Politics...
No.
So, Las Vegas can
breathe easier?
You do have the Strip
Strangler behind bars?
No, we don't.
SHERIFF:
The FBI did me
a favor being here
and they have a viable suspect.
He's not viable, Brian.
Then further investigation
will prove that out.
In the meantime
people will feel better
about their daily lives.
Now, why on Earth would you
want to counteract that?
For those who have to ask,
no answer could suffice.
Look, I see we've
come to an impasse.
If further investigation
determines
that Walden didn't kill
those other women
then you can rejoin
the investigation.
Oh, do I get the weekend off?
For starters...
and a two-week holiday...
anywhere but CSI.
You brought this
on yourself.
Now, the next time you want
to play with my career
maybe you'll think twice.
( slamming locker door )
You know, it's
not fair, Grissom.
You know more about
signatures than most
of them put together.
That may have been
the problem.
Is there's no one
you can appeal to?
No... I'm off.
Come on, this guy's on the loose
and there's nothing you can do?
It's all Catherine.
She's the boss.
Good luck.
( classical music playing )
( sighing )
Hey!
Your door was open.
You okay?
Migraine. It's been a while.
I get them about
once a year.
I'm not used to having
people in my house.
You just don't like it
when you can't solve a case
or command your troops.
( sighing )
Did you come here to tell me
about your new job?
I told the Sheriff I'd pass.
You don't want to be
a Supervisor?
Well, if I get a promotion,
I want it to be on merit...
not because you're
politically tone-deaf.
So, our guys are outside
in their Tahoes.
If you're a civilian, we are.
Except we are putting in
for overtime.
We should reexamine
each victim--
all the evidence
pertaining to each one
individually.
All right, well,
I got dibs on Eileen Snow.
And I have a strong feeling
I'm going to be the one
to break the case.
Tracy Berg.
I got Audrey Hayes,
but those fibers
we found in
the Snow lady's throat aren't
going to give us anything.
White cotton fibers
are like oxygen--
they're everywhere.
Well, then go back
to your crime scenes
and look for a persistence
of fibers.
"If you can't prove uniqueness,
prove abundance."
Something's better
than nothing.
SANDERS:
Hunter F. Baumgartner.
Our ketchup DNA guy.
This guy showed up
on the database.
CODIS updates its database
every couple weeks.
Yeah, well, don't act
like it's so simple.
This guy could have
gone another year
without being picked up.
What did they get him on?
Well, Indecent Exposure.
Caught in an alley
behind the Monaco.
Oh.
Suspended sentence,
released two days ago.
Call Grissom on his cell.
I thought he was off the case.
He is.
Dial. Tell
him to meet me
at this guy's
work address.
( rock music playing )
You think anything
illegal goes on in here?
( Grissom laughs )
Excuse me?
Hunter?
Yeah.
You two look like you made
a wrong turn somewhere.
We're with the
Crime Lab.
Heard you just
copped a plea
for indecent
exposure.
I'm sorry, I'm working.
Uh-uh.
You recognize any
of these women?
Yeah.
Strip Strangler girls.
They are all over TV.
Do you know them?
No.
WILLOWS:
How do you explain
your DNA on the bedsheets
they were murdered in?
I don't know.
Yeah, "I don't know"
doesn't get it, pal.
DNA's like fingerprints.
No two samples are alike.
You were
in these women's bedrooms.
Believe me, mister,
the last place
that you will find me
is in a woman's bedroom.
Unless we're discussing
window treatments.
Hey, and my indecent was
for tricking too close
to the Boulevard.
I don't know
anything about killing women.
That's straight boy stuff.
Any recent trick
offer you money
for something
a little weird?
Say a portable sample
of your DNA?
Only about ten times
this month.
This is Vegas.
Would you be able to recognize
any of these guys?
Well, I'd have to be looking
at them in the face
now, wouldn't I?
( Willows clears throat )
I guess we should
have known
if our guy was
planting hairs
he was planting semen.
Yeah. Probably in little
hollowed-out packets of ketchup.
I didn't really find
anything instructive
but Warrick hit pay dirt.
Well, I went back
to Audrey Hayes' apartment
and I paid particular attention
to the point of entry.
I found a small persistence
of white cotton fibers.
Could have been
the staging area.
Maybe he
wears his murder kit.
Well, I remember
what you said about
signature guys
and how they have
low self-esteem.
They're always going
to the gym to work out
so I'm thinking gym towels.
SIDLE:
The Frequented Locations
report said
none of the women
belong to a gym
where he could have
spotted them.
I went back to see
if any of them had tried
out introductory offers.
Which I do all the time.
It's a free workout,
and you don't have to sign up.
But you do have
to sign in.
All three women
went to Strong's Gym once
in the last three months.
So, I'm going back there,
grab some towels
bring them back to the lab
see if I can get
a match from the
crime scene fibers.
And, of course, get a list
of the club's male gym members.
Call Brass, tell him
to meet you guys there.
Let me know.
Will do.
( phone rings )
Grissom.
Yeah, I'm looking
at a photograph of the street
in front
of Eileen Snow's apartment.
This security guard said
he saw a guy burn rubber
out of there the night
of Eileen's murder.
I remember that guy.
Yeah, well,
there's no rubber here.
On the pavement or the curb.
A couple of oil spots,
that's about it.
And I called Brass.
Nobody took any photographs
of any tire marks.
Not the Las Vegas PD.
Not the feds.
Hmm.
Little lie, big lie?
Mm-hmm.
The only shift CSI
I can actually find.
You're tampering with evidence
of the United States government
there, Mr. Stokes.
I was just looking
for a quiet spot
to call my girlfriend.
Well, tell your girlfriend
she's going to have you
out of a job.
Best thing you could do
for your boss--
protect him from himself.
Grissom?
I got to run, Peanut.
Love you, too. Bye-bye.
Goggle.
If you need any help
in your investigation,
Mr. Grissom...
Syd Goggle.
( crickets chirping )
( door creaking )
( TV playing softly )
Mr. Goggle?
( blades whirring )
( machine motor whirring )
Gil Grissom.
Syd Goggle.
I thought you were too busy
with the FBI to talk to me.
These investigations
are always in flux.
Am I, uh, interrupting
your laundry?
I'm just doing
some gym towels.
You were so meticulous
about so many things.
Shaving.
The gloves.
Planted evidence.
That's why I don't understand
why you'd bring towels
that eventually could be traced.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Strong's Gym.
That's where the women told you
to you to get lost, right?
Stuffing club towels down
their throat make your point?
You know,
the thing with women...
is they work out
because they want us
to look at them.
And then they...
parade around.
And you just want to...
Say hello.
Everybody knows
white cotton fibers aren't
like fingerprints.
They can't be traced.
You don't get a... match
on a towel.
In theory.
But the truth is
every object is changed
by its owner.
By his habits.
His... washing machine,
for instance.
His detergent.
The totality of
microscopic elements.
It's Locard's Theory.
( washing machine banging )
Your towel is caught
in the agitator.
Now, see, that's going
to leave distinctive marks
on the fabric, Syd.
And that's just
the beginning.
I've had a look
at your garbage.
You were in my apartment.
No, nothing from there's
admissible in court.
Your garbage is
in a public area.
Plain sight.
It's enough for me
to get a warrant.
( gunfire )
You all right?
Yeah.
How did you know I was here?
Nick told me.
Everybody okay?
Special Agents,
we got a shooting.
Notify LVPD and
paramedics ASAP.
I just wanted to talk to him.
We can say unequivocally,
based on statements made
by a certain local
law enforcement employee
and corresponding evidence
that the deceased,
Syd Booth Goggle
is the Strip Strangler.
Furthermore, since Goggle
was killed
by a second member
of Las Vegas law enforcement
during his apprehension,
this case is now closed.
I would like to thank the FBI,
along with Special Agent
Rick Culpepper
for his invaluable leadership
in this pursuit.
In short, we couldn't
have done it without you.
I'd like to thank you, Sheriff,
Las Vegas Police.
I'd also like to thank
the citizens of Las Vegas
for their courage.
We at the Federal Bureau
of Investigation
are proud to have served you.
Thank you.
Oh, that's cool.
We don't need props.
At the end of the day,
we know what time it is.
Give me some of that.
SIDLE:
Do we have a
breakfast budget, Grissom?
I believe Catherine
was going to requisition one.
Good, cause our
plates are up,
and nobody has
any money.
Right behind you.
You, uh... you got me,
right, War?
Yeah. Picture that.
I never should have put you
in that position, Catherine.
I'm sorry.
What position?
Never doubt
and never look back.
That's how I live my life.
I admire that.
SIDLE:
Whole wheat and fruit?
Who ordered that?
Here.
STOKES:
How's this
for service?
Very good.
Re... fried beans. Mmm!
( laughter )