( whimpering )
( camera shutter clicks )
Maggots.
This kid's been here a while.
No gunshot wounds.
No stab marks.
No signs of strangulation.
It's a long way out
in the sticks just to drop dead.
Not if you're being chased.
Look at the foot patterns
leading up to the body.
See the strides?
This kid was running.
See the left
foot impression?
It's straight; that's normal.
But look at the right foot
impression.
It's turned outward.
Almost 90 degrees.
He was looking over his shoulder
when he was running.
Think there was
somebody else here?
Based on these prints,
it's hard to tell.
Can I get this
taped off here?
So you want
to call it?
How do you think he died?
Fear.
Someone chased this kid
to death.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
( phone rings )
Grissom.
No. No, I did it yesterday.
Yes, I did.
Thank you.
Hey, you want to give us
our assignments
or do you want us
to take... the night off?
Paperwork,
paper clips, paper-punchers--
all these people want me to do
is push paper; nobody wants me
to solve crimes.
Hey, you could've
turned the job down.
Yeah, the grass is always
greener, Catherine.
Well let's just
hurry this up.
( sighs )
Cool.
You really want to
see flash paper flash?
Walk in on a bookie.
That's what this was
about, bookies.
( phone rings )
Don't answer it.
We've got work to do...
Boss.
( ringing continues )
Warrick, you and I are
on the 419
our dead body in the desert.
Sara, dead body of your own.
Dumpsite out near Henderson.
Oh, I'll dress down.
Catherine, Verbum Dei Charter
School. 420 homicide.
The school dean was killed
in his office.
Suspect called it in;
could be self-defense.
Did some kid off him
with a silver spoon?
Suspect's not a kid.
It's the woman
who founded the school.
Take Nicky with you.
Where is he?
Here I am.
You're coming with me.
Glad you could make it.
I'm outta here.
Good luck tonight, you guys.
See you.
Can't make a ruling?
Look at the bruise marks
on John Doe here.
I call that suffocation.
Not necessarily.
It could be the result
of his face impacting the ground
at expiration.
I'm going to take a mouth swab.
Go ahead.
Grissom, I have something
to show you.
You know, when a kid
this young drops dead
smart money chases
anesthetics, alcohol
methanol, maybe even
a little Freon.
I've got to be honest.
I've had a lot of dead
bodies from the desert
and when they're out
there too long
the elements tend
to eat away the evidence.
My opinion is,
you are looking
at the picture
of health, internally.
Externally,
it's another matter.
Skin sample.
Grissom:
This kid was dry as a bone.
From exposure?
The skin's not consistent
with elemental damage.
Warrick told me
what you said
about the cause of death
being fear.
I never read about that
in any medical book.
Try the Forensic Medical
Journal.
Read the four canons on cause
of death:
Homicide, suicide, natural,
and unexplained.
Talks about fear
in the last part
of "unexplained."
I had to ask.
You want to know
what killed this kid?
Benihana the maggots.
What the maggots?
Tox the maggots we found
on the victim.
Whatever he ingested
has probably evaporated
from the sun.
But the maggots are
like little refrigerators.
They preserve what we digest
for longer periods of time.
Entomology is our friend.
Yes.
Sorry, little buddy.
Scalpel.
My name is Paul
and this is between y'all.
Talk about Pulp Fiction.
It's all yours, Doc.
Fire up that
gas chromatograph
mass spectrometer thing,
will you?
No problem, son.
15 seconds till pay dirt.
Cool.
Play any pigskin, man?
No, I'm off that.
It's prime time for you.
I haven't made a bet
in a month.
I can't say I don't have
that itch, though.
Hmm. Haven't seen
this stuff for a while.
What's that?
Jimsonweed.
Do you have a name?
She's not exactly carrying
a purse.
Oh...
( camera shutter clicking )
Okay, let's take her out.
Thanks.
Sure.
That's strange.
What's that?
Glazed like a doughnut.
Well, here's the reason
the skin was funny.
Formaldehyde, right?
Close. BioTone Arterial.
Promotes high diffusion
and fast drainage
in skin tissue.
So I was right.
This woman's
been embalmed.
Yeah. Yeah, I already
ran her prints
through work-hire;
got her I.D. right here.
I, uh, I just want
to say I-I...
Well, I really admire
the gusto
with which you approach
your job.
Are you hitting on me, David?
Uh...
( chuckles )
Let me give you
some friendly advice.
If you want to pull chicks,
you've got to get aggressive.
You've gotta drop
the glasses
lose the coat
grow some scruff.
You do get a "C" for cute,
though.
( typing )
"Stephanie Reyes was laid
to rest
at Desert Haven
Funeral Home."
Her funeral was last week.
Hi.
Hey.
What do you got?
Vernon Woods,
dean of the school.
39, single.
Multiple blunt-force
trauma wounds
to the head.
With that, probably.
Stokes:
I got it.
Man, check out
all that blood spatter.
Yeah, blows to the head,
up close and personal.
A lot of passion
around this one.
Any suspects?
Kate Armstrong.
Founded the school.
She called 911 herself.
She says he attacked her.
She's out in the hallway.
He wouldn't let go of me.
He kept pawing.
I can still smell
his aftershave.
( sobbing ):
I mean...
It's all a blur.
I grabbed the closest thing
I could and I hit him with it.
A rock?
I don't know
what it was.
I didn't care.
I just wanted
him off of me.
How many times did you hit him?
Once.
What's the matter?
Come on. No one's
going to hear.
Everyone's in class.
Where's the harm?
I said get off of me!
Miss Armstrong...
were you and the dean having
a personal relationship?
No.
No, Vernon's a pig.
Then why did you hire him?
You founded the school.
It's your integrity
on the line.
He's great at raising money.
His donor list is huge.
I didn't mean to kill him.
( sniffling )
I just wanted him
to leave me alone.
But you hit him
more than once.
Oh, who knows. I...
Well, you hit a man once,
there's no blood.
The first hit's free.
You hit him
more than that...
( clears throat )
The walls in his office
look like the dean
went a couple rounds
with Mike Tyson.
Then I hit him more than once.
Like I said, I just...
I wanted him off me.
Will you excuse me?
Officer. Thanks.
What'd you find out?
Heavy on B.S.;
zippo on truth.
You don't seem
too bummed about it.
Hell, no, I'm stoked.
( sotto voce ):
We drew the best
case, Nicky.
I can feel it.
Mm-hmm.
Then there's
only one thing left to do.
String it.
I've never filed a missing
person's report before.
But I'm getting
concerned about Eric.
Where was the last place
you saw your friend?
After work, we went out.
You two work together?
No, a few blocks apart.
I'm over at Voosh's,
you know?
Voosh's Fireworks
and he's at Element Sound,
the music store.
You guys go into the desert?
Yeah, a party out near Red Rock.
How'd you know?
You just told us.
( chuckles )
So spill it.
We, uh, drank a couple beers
hung out, and...
then I just lost track of him
around midnight
and I haven't
seen him since.
Did you guys drop
anything that night?
Ecstasy, crystal, G...?
No.
No way.
Look, do you, do you know
where Eric is or not?
Bobby, we found a body
that matches your description
of Eric.
Would you be willing
to identify him?
Is this your friend?
( crying )
Oh, God...
What happened to you, Eric?
( knocking )
Hey, boss.
I got something for you.
( sotto voce ):
I did this whole
tox-the-maggots thing
like you said.
Found jimsonweed
in their blood.
Which means?
Jimsonweed in Eric's blood.
Jimsonweed.
"Dry as a bone,
red as a beet
blind as a bat,
mad as a hatter."
Really?
Cite your sources.
Internet insomnia.
But Brass just said
they weren't doing any drugs.
Yeah.
Blood spatter on northwest wall.
Blood sprays northeast corner
above...
Wow.
Now, there's a look
I like to see-- confusion.
( chuckles )
No, I'm not confused.
X marks the spot.
A blow here...
here... and here.
Our dean received
the majority of blows
when he was on the ground.
Cast-off from the weapon
against the window.
Mm-hmm.
The back wall...
Void... against the back wall.
The floor under the body?
The blood spatter has a void
instead of one continuous line
of spray.
There's an interruption
a space where something
or someone comes between
the blood coming off
the body and the wall.
Which means our assailant
was here and...
There was somebody else
in this room.
Kate Armstrong is lying.
Fruit juice, half ice.
Thanks, Warrick.
The guy said it was natural,
that it wasn't a drug.
I mean, jimsonweed is a plant.
Most drugs derive from plants.
That doesn't make them safe.
Or legal, for that matter.
Yeah, but he said it was safe.
That's why we bought it.
Did you take the drug, too?
Yeah. We both did.
You drink it. It's a tea.
Who sold you this "tea"?
He didn't give a name.
He just...
He told us that j-weed
would be a cool high.
Mind-expanding.
I mean, that's the whole point
of a rave is to experiment.
Did you get a stamp
when you got in?
Yeah. But that was like
four days ago.
Well, mostly they use
water-resistant pads
so you don't sweat it off.
Could you hit the lights, Gris?
Where'd they stamp you?
Yeah, that's
DJMasterband's stamp.
He is the spinner
in Vegas right now.
Must've been playing
at the rave
these two were at.
Is there any way for us
to track this, uh, DJ person?
The free papers, yeah.
They have ads
for all sorts of raves.
Bobby?
Would you be able
to recognize the guy
who sold you the jimson?
Definitely.
No one in the mortuary business
likes to discuss the issue
but it does exist:
people rob graves.
Are you telling me
that someone dug up
Stephanie Reyes
and stole her body?
They do it for gold, trinkets,
or just kicks.
You should hear what
I hear at conventions.
( chuckles )
Did you report the robbery
of Mrs. Reyes' remains
to the police?
As I say, we try not
to discuss the issue
outside of the community.
Profits over people,
is that it?
I wouldn't put
it like that.
Eight feet.
How deep do you
bury these caskets?
Well...
There's nothing else
in there.
I thought you said
grave robbers
only stole bodies.
This might've been
an inlaid casket
something of value
that people would steal.
You sell caskets, right?
As part of your
mortuary service?
I want to see some.
I can arrange a viewing.
Bonus.
( knocking )
Gris, I got the prelims back
on that swab I took
off of our desert guy.
And?
Products found
in mouth and nose:
mentholated nose spray,
patchouli and aluminum.
Nose spray?
He had a cold.
Patchouli-- they burn it
at music stores.
Aluminum's the
odd man out.
Warrick:
Yeah. I got Trace
putting together
a list of products
made with the stuff.
Something tells me
it's not lemonade.
Jimson tea.
I like to see what
I'm dealing with.
Doesn't look
lethal, does it?
Doesn't look like tea, either.
You know what the
Japanese tea ceremony signifies?
What's that?
That every human encounter
is a singular occasion
which can never recur again
in exactly the same way.
Does that apply to our case?
Everything applies, Warrick.
That's the beauty part.
Cheers.
All right,
it's true.
Someone else
was there.
A name would be nice.
She's a friend on the faculty
but she had nothing
to do with this.
The blood evidence
is telling us otherwise.
Look, homicide will give us
her name if you won't.
There are detectives,
and your school's not that big.
Julia Eastman, but she
was doing me a favor.
She was just at
the wrong place
at the wrong time.
We kind of made a plan
so that the next time
Woods hit on her
she'd have a witness.
You know, because
of the harassment.
When you were playing witness,
where were you standing?
At the doorway.
You're sure?
Yeah.
I know you want it.
Give us a little...
( woman sighing and crying )
Why you...
( grunt )
Ah!
( grunts and sighs )
We're forensic scientists,
Julia.
Blood talks to us.
People exaggerate
or forget.
Blood's like my grandfather.
Never lies.
Nick reenacted the crime
using blood spatter.
No, I just strung it,
but thank you anyway.
No, the computer
gizmo does
all the geometry.
Computer:
You factor in the location
of the body in relation
to the blood on the wall
in order to create
an equation
that recreates the event.
Each hit that drew blood
gets its own unique color
as he fell.
Nick:
See?
Dean Woods was not
in a standing position.
When he was killed,
he was on the floor.
So how could
your friend Kate,
who's roughly half
his size, wrestle him to the
ground and keep him there
while she bludgeoned him
to death?
Without help?
I don't know.
Hmm.
Could we take a break?
I need a break.
Sure.
( rave music plays )
Three.
It's gonna be 20 each.
Teenage wasteland.
Who?
Yeah.
Hi!
Hi.
I love you.
( nervous chuckle )
Uh, thank you.
You're a total
stranger to me.
It's Ecstasy.
It makes everyone fall in love.
Don't take it personally, miss.
He's kind of married to his job.
I love you.
Come on. Let's go.
That's him, there, there!
Grissom:
Bobby, wait!
You killed my friend!
Break it up!
Bobby, stop it!
( shouting )
Ow...!
What do you guys think
you got on me?
Selling jimsonweed to kids.
Do you see any j-weed on me?
You sent, uh, Bobby over here
and his friend
on quite a trip the other night.
Which trip was that?
The one to San Diego
or the one to Mars?
To the impound,
where your car is going.
Probable cause.
You don't have to take my car
to the impound.
You can search it.
But, I got news for you.
Jimson's an unscheduled
controlled substance.
Mandatory suspended sentence
for the first go-round
for possession.
And you can't even prove
that much.
Guy knows a lot about
the Nevada state penal code.
Well, if you're gonna break
the law
you've gotta know the law.
Exactly.
Just don't scratch my puppy.
What do you say, Ethan?
These seeds look familiar?
( laughs )
You just fish those
out of your undies?
Look, man, if you want
to take me in...
take me in.
I'll be back
before the party's over.
'Cause you know the law,
don't you?
Mandatory suspended sentence
for the first possession.
Exactly.
Let me tell you something.
You're twice the age
of these kids
and most of them couldn't find
their ass with a map.
You prey on innocent children
concocting God-knows-what
from God-knows-where
selling Russian Roulette
in a bottle
and you think we came
all the way out here
to bust you for possession,
you dumb punk?
I'm gonna get you for murder.
Cool?
This Ethan was
selling jimsonweed tea
at the desert rave.
I believe Eric drank
the most toxic part--
the dregs,
the bottom
of the batch
the part that's full of seeds.
Williams:
If that's true,
then we might be able
to catch up
with some of those seeds
because they have a way
of hanging around
the lower intestinal tract.
The last ones to leave the party
would be right about here.
Jimson reduced
his gastric motility
which kept this in his system.
Now we just tie that
to the dealer.
Well, we see
if it ties to the dealer.
That's not what you were saying
out at that rave
all up in that guy's face.
There's three things
I've got a real
problem with:
Guys that hit their wives,
sexual assault on children
and the scum
that deal death to kids.
Warrick:
The chemical compositions
break down exactly the same.
Yeah, but that doesn't
necessarily prove that the seeds
from the dead kid's gut
came from the same place
as the seeds
in the dealer's car.
We'd need the pods
to do a DNA match
and we don't have them.
The truth is,
it wouldn't matter.
I ran the seeds Eric ingested.
The toxic levels are low
too low to
have killed him.
Square one.
There is no way
I'm going to end up
in a dumpster
wrapped in plastic.
I'm going to be cremated--
dust in the wind, you know.
I don't want any part
of these things.
I've already got mine
paid off.
Are you serious?
Yeah. It looks
just like this one.
How much did
it run you?
Ten thou.
$10,000...
For a box buried in the ground
that everyone's
only going to see you in once.
I like it.
It feels like a Caddie.
So when you buy one of these
for $10,000, it's yours, right?
Well, of course it is.
No one else
gets to use it.
It's built for one.
Then how did
all these people get in here?
Thought I'd
find you here.
It's why I live.
Evidence...
the double-edged sword.
Yeah, nobody wanted to put that
pusher in jail more than I did.
The evidence sets him free.
How do you feel about this?
It doesn't matter how I feel.
The evidence only knows
one thing: the truth.
It is what it is.
You don't really believe that,
do you?
I was flying to a seminar
in New Hampshire
a couple summers ago.
I was sitting
on the plane
next to this
philosophy professor
from Harvard.
He told me this story
about how every morning
he takes a leak right after
his three-hour philosophy class.
He'd flush the toilet
there'd be
this tiny, brown spider
fighting for its life
against the
swirling water.
Come back the next day, flush
same spider clawing its way back
from oblivion.
A week goes by, he decides
to liberate the spider.
Grabs a paper towel,
scoops him up
sets him on the floor
in the corner of the stall.
Comes back the next day
what do you think
happened to the spider?
Dead.
On his back,
eight legs in the air. Why?
Because one life
imposed itself on another.
Right then I realized
where we stand.
I understood
our role.
We don't impose our will
on a spider.
We don't impose our hopes
on the evidence.
Twenty, ten, five, boom!
Touchdown, baby.
What's my name?
( Ethan laughs )
You'll be back.
Oh, really?
What, have you got
a crystal ball
in your pocket or something?
You're a creature of habit.
I'll catch you later.
Okay, this is what
we've got so far
on our dead dean.
Blood spatter and
blood cast-off
on the walls.
Kate Armstrong's
confession,
her clothes.
Three void areas, and
that's pretty much it.
Anything else?
It's not enough,
it's not enough.
What's the one thing
we're missing?
That's it.
What's it?
The one thing
we're missing.
The blood.
On Julia's clothes.
We need the clothes
that you were wearing
the day that the dean
was killed.
I burned them.
Why?
The blood wouldn't come out.
They were ruined.
Blood's funny that way.
In fact, I bet
there's plenty of blood
on Dean Woods' shirt.
Look at that void.
What a beaut.
Oh, yeah.
You don't even have
to know every star
and you can draw
a constellation.
And fill in the rest.
Whoa, look at
that last finger there.
Talk about
your unique attributes.
What do you think,
a bandage?
We'll have to ask our ladies,
but I can tell you this--
somebody's playing
through the pain.
Grissom:
I, uh...
I just wanted you to know
that Eric didn't die
from jimson tea.
It didn't have
the chemical toxicity
to kill him.
The seeds weren't strong enough.
Is your arm all right?
Yeah, uh, spider bite.
I think it's infected.
May I take a look?
Sure. You're a doctor.
You might be able to give me
something for it.
I'm a Ph.D.,
not an M.D.
( chuckling )
Bobby... this bite
is not from an insect.
Hey.
Hi.
I found a bite mark
on Bobby's arm
and I think it might be human.
Do you feel like sharing?
Not really.
Just a little?
( sighing )
I don't know, Jenna.
This whole case is going
from bad to worse.
I mean, usually it's a body,
it's a specimen
but when it
involves kids,
I just can't...
Gruesome Grissom...
Tin man with a heart.
Who knew?
Hey, guys.
This came back for the test
on aluminum products
on our kid in the desert.
Fireworks.
That's where Bobby Taylor works.
Jenna, I need a mold
of Eric's teeth
and an impression
of Bobby's arm.
Julia, make a fist for me
with your right hand.
I mean, count it down like so,
starting with your thumb first.
Five, four, three, two, one.
Sprained it at tennis.
It heals a lot faster
when you wear one of these.
Dean Woods' shirt.
Now, remember we said
blood tells us
everything?
Well... so does
the absence of blood.
Oh, my God.
You held him down...
while she killed him.
All because the guy was handsy?
Seems a little severe.
We're going to be placing you
under arrest for murder.
Is there anything
you want to say?
No, no, this isn't over.
For all forensic purposes,
it is over.
They're going to eat bread
and bang a metal cup
against some bars.
That's it.
It's over for us.
We still don't know why.
It's not our job to know why.
It's our job to know how.
You heard Grissom.
The more the why,
the less the how
the less the how,
the more the why.
Hey, Nick.
Yeah?
Grissom's not
always right.
Do yourself a favor.
Think for yourself.
I mean that as
a friend, okay?
Okay, Detective, we've got
some more homework to do.
What are you playing,
time-share coffins?
Uh, there's no such thing
as a time-share coffin.
Sure there is.
Once the funeral is over,
you dump the body
and use the same casket
over and over.
You can't prove that.
Yes, I can.
This is a set of prints
on the inside
of the plastic sheeting
we found in the dumpster.
What are the odds
they belong to you?
All you had to do
was put the bodies
back in the grave
and no one would have been
the wiser.
You have no idea what
a cutthroat business this is.
The chains are moving in.
I have payments to make.
I see the world
from a completely
different perspective
than most people.
Yeah, I know.
You see dead people.
So do I.
And when they turn up
in dumpsters
I like to see they get back
to where they belong.
I'll repay the money.
Minimum.
Then you're going to pay
for Stephanie Reyes' family
to have
a real burial.
Okay.
At a respectable mortuary.
Then we're going to let the DA
run a table.
Did some homework
on Kate.
Mm-hmm.
Financial records
for the last year.
Great.
Personal checks
from Kate Armstrong
to Vernon Woods
over the last year.
$5,000.
Another for $5,000.
$3,000.
"Memo: loans."
I don't think so.
I think she was paying him off
for something.
Did Julia say anything?
Like what?
The real reason
you killed Woods?
This is where
Grissom and I differ.
Forensics is about
more than science.
Human behavior.
The inconsistencies
of human behavior.
Yes, "how" is crucially
important, but so is "why."
Okay.
I'm finished paying you.
We're going to live openly,
honestly.
It's a new century.
Parents are evolved.
Not where their children
are concerned.
I'll tell everybody
that I caught you two
having sex on school grounds.
That's a lie!
What?!
Of course it's a lie.
That didn't stop
the McMartin School
from closing down.
Yeah, I think
I'll make a call.
Julia and I would never
have survived a rumor like that.
We panicked.
The school is our whole life.
Mm, you got your "why."
Crime of passion.
Bigger "why":
why did it have
to come down to this?
I guess they didn't feel like
they had a choice.
Maybe they didn't.
A lose-lose situation.
I'm telling you,
I didn't kill Eric.
Can you remember
your last hours
with him Saturday?
Don't answer that.
I want to answer it.
I just... I can't
remember anything
after we took that stuff.
It's not about
memory now, Bobby.
It's about the evidence
and the evidence...
sucks.
Grissom:
You and Eric bought jimson tea
from Ethan that night.
Enjoy, fellas!
( laughing )
Cheers, man.
But you guys have never taken
j-weed before
so you weren't aware
of the side effects
of photophobia.
Ph-photo what?
Photophobia.
It's just a big word
for lights freaking you out.
You guys were
hallucinating
and whatever
Eric was seeing
was scaring him,
big-time.
The coroner states
that Eric's dose
shot his temperature
through the roof.
He was boiling
in his own skin.
So he stripped
which is why we
found him naked.
We just don't know
if it was an act of aggression
or self-defense.
I loved that guy.
Grissom:
That's why I
tend to believe
it was an act
of self-protection.
The lights were scaring him.
At the same time, we conjecture
that you were suffering
auditory hallucinations.
Both of these
symptoms are routine
with this drug.
( groaning )
Shut up! Shut up!
Shut up! Shut up!
Shut up! Shut... shut up!
( both grunting )
Shut up...
I just...
I-I can't remember, honest.
You can "believe"
and "conjecture" all you want.
None of this
is based on fact.
I'm afraid that it is.
The evidence tells us
that Bobby suffocated Eric.
We found traces
of aluminum
trapped in Eric's
nostrils that are
consistent
with what we found
in your client's
hands and arms
earlier today from his job
at the fireworks plant.
I don't think I would do that.
I know, Bobby, but you did.
This is a mold of the bite mark
that we took
from your arm today.
This is a mold of Eric's mouth,
postmortem.
Shut up! Shut up! Shut up!
Come on, you shut up!
Shut up! Shut up!
You shut up!
( Eric yells )
You overpowered him.
He suffocated...
and then finally
the noise stopped.
I can tell you right now
we're going to plead
diminished capacity.
Good.
I hope you win.
It doesn't matter.
It's the difference
between
prison and a hospital, Bobby.
It matters.
You don't understand.
I don't care what happens to me.
I killed my best friend.
( vehicle engine starts )
Where you going?
Away.