Woman:
What's taking
you so long?
I just wanted you
to fix the leak.
Look, lady,
to fix the leak
I need to find the leak.
( material ripping )
Hold on.
You find the leak?
( grunts )
Plumber:
I found something.
Okay, I'm ready up here.
Hang on a minute.
Okay, I'm there.
Stokes ( over radio ):
Can you confirm it's human?
Medicarpal, phalanges...
No question about it.
Hold on, Nick.
There's got to be
an easier way.
When a body decomposes
in concrete
it leaves an air pocket,
vacuum-sealed.
If we do this right, it'll open
like a jar of pickles.
Ten bucks says the owner
sells the house.
Grissom:
By law, you've got
to disclose everything--
three bedrooms,
two baths, and a skeleton.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
Okay, I'm late again.
Nick's going to work with me
on that unidentified body
at Summercliff.
I hear it's just bones?
What a rush.
O.I.S. at the Jockey Club.
Officer-involved shooting.
I'll take a piece of that.
Good, I want you to double up.
Listen, these deals
are never easy
so keep me informed,
please.
Will do.
I drive.
Picture that.
So what do you
have for me?
I could use a rush.
Well, this qualifies, 4-26.
But I can't give you
the case.
Because?
Conflict of interest.
The alleged rape victim's
an exotic dancer.
Because I used to be one,
I'll be biased?
No.
The suspect's your ex-husband.
He's asking for you,
but you can't take it.
Just let me do the prelim.
All right.
Do what you can.
But after the preliminary,
you pass it off, okay?
Thank God you're here.
Eddie.
I didn't rape
that girl.
According
to the police report
she's telling
a different story.
I wonder what the rape kit's
going to say.
We had sex, okay?
But she was there
with me 100%.
In the parking lot
behind the club.
Well, some women like
the outdoors.
Melanie know about this?
Mel and I split up a while ago.
You might want to call her
anyway.
She can loan you the money
for an attorney.
You're not going
to help me?
Cath, I am in a jam here!
A detective from Sex Crime's
been assigned.
I'm going to place another CSI.
What about Lindsey?
What about her?
You want her
spending Sunday afternoons
with me
at Nevada State Prison,
or the mall?
Based on the auricular surface
I'd say she died
when she was about 20.
She?
It's in the hips.
The pelvic bone is
definitely female.
You know, for a ladies' man
you don't know much
about bone structure.
I know all I need to know.
I figure
she was killed
before her cement bath.
Yeah, how?
She was stabbed
at least a dozen times
a screwdriver maybe
or a spike.
No, the gouges on her ribs
are unusual.
The instrument had to be...
slightly curved
with some kind
of serrated edge.
Like crocodile teeth.
Whatever killed this girl
it was not a traditional weapon.
Well, stabbings are personal.
She knew her attacker.
That's the rule.
Who are you?
Sara Sidle, Warrick Brown
Officer Joe Tyner.
Hi.
Officer Tyner.
How are you doing?
Tell us what happened
here tonight.
He responded
to shots fired
the suspect fled the scene.
Why don't you tell us
what happened here.
( tires squealing )
Unit Five. I'm in pursuit
of the fleeing 413
heading southbound on the Strip.
( tires squealing )
Get back
into the car!
Drop your keys
to the ground!
Put your hands
on the wheel!
I didn't do it!
Whatever
you think I did!
I'm looking at three strikes.
I'm not going back.
I'll show you my registration.
No, put your hands
on the wheel!
( fires gun )
Then he turned
the weapon on himself
and one shot,
right through the forehead.
Where's his gun?
I left it in the jeep.
I'm going to go bag it.
Officer, we're going to need
your weapon as well.
I never fired.
Drawn but not fired.
It's just standard procedure.
It's okay. It's all right.
Brown:
We're going to need
to seal off this lot.
Tyner told you
what happened here.
Whose side are you on?
The officer told me
a fleeing suspect
committed suicide.
I'm just verifying
his account.
You know how
this works, Brass.
Can we clear the jeep
so I can do my job?
Well, at least test the dead
guy's hands for gun residue.
At that proximity
G.S.R.'s invalid.
They'd both be covered,
no matter who fired.
Can we get back to work?
Yeah.
( light buzzing )
( door opens )
You brought
the foundation
of the house
to our lab.
It's a six-by-three-foot
section.
When the concrete dried
it preserved a partial
impression of our Jane Doe.
Did you find out anything
about the house?
I pulled the permits.
Summercliff was built five years
ago on nothing but desert.
That would explain
why the body was so desiccated.
House was sold
subsequent to completion
so the homeowner
isn't a suspect.
Homicide is running
a missing persons check.
( clears throat )
Well, if it wasn't
for a leaky pipe
she might have been down there
forever.
I think our killer was counting
on that.
Hey.
Why would a guy speed it
all the way down the Strip
just to pull over
and cap himself?
What are you
getting at, Warrick?
Officer's weapon,
Smith and Wesson 5906.
Standard issue.
One bullet missing.
Nothing standard about that.
Brass isn't going to like this.
I don't give a damn
what Brass likes.
Like I do?
If Tyner's dirty, he goes down.
I just know what happens
when you piss off the P.D.
Yeah, it's war.
Gil Grissom?
Or should I call you
Spider Man?
It's harmless.
Of course it is.
Orange-kneed tarantula.
Nice specimen.
The tarantula's touch
is very gentle.
It leaves no prints.
They move without a trace.
May I?
Maybe I should introduce myself.
Teri Miller does not need
an introduction.
I need you to make me a face.
I didn't kill him.
That's what I told IA.
It's what I told my superior.
It's what I'm telling you.
Officer Tyner, your gun--
there's a bullet's missing
from the magazine.
I don't top off.
I know it's against regulation,
but the 14th bullet
puts pressure on the spring
and the gun can jam.
Can anyone confirm your story?
It's not a story!
And no...
I don't tell people
how I carry. Do you?
Check the other magazines.
What the hell's
going on here?
We're just having a talk
with Officer Tyner here.
Next time, don't
start without me.
I'm the union rep
on this one.
Then you should know.
Tyner's magazine--
one bullet shy.
Is the expended round
still missing?
It's not in the body,
bullet's a round point
wound was a through-and-through.
I did not fire a single round.
And with a record
like yours
we're supposed
to just take your word?
Warrick:
Five civilian
complaints--
three for excessive force.
Two IA investigations.
I was cleared.
I'm sure you were.
What is that supposed to mean?
I don't have to take this crap!
Tyner... sit down,
sit down.
What you do need
is for these guys
to go out and find
the missing bullet.
So what are you waiting for?
I guess it's a good thing
I sealed off that crime scene.
It's like a human
Jell-O mold.
The impression's
only a partial.
It's not going
to be easy.
They told me you
were the top forensic
artist in the country.
And Canada. I didn't
say I couldn't do it.
Give me your hand.
You'll enjoy this.
It's as much science as art.
It doesn't really
look like anything.
Miller:
No light, no shadows.
No shadows,
no perspective.
Now look.
So teach me.
Okay.
First I'm finishing off
the plaster mold.
We can't give her life
with only half a face.
Although not
actually symmetrical
most faces
appear that way
and the thin layer
of slip
makes the plaster and clay
appear seamless.
Her cheekbones and nasal spine
indicate Nordic descent.
I've seen a few
Norwegian brunettes
but your girl's
probably a blonde.
Grissom:
Brown eyes?
I thought
you decided she was Nordic.
But in this country, brown
is a dominant eye color
and more importantly,
brown photographs better.
You want to get her face
out there, don't you?
Yeah.
I'm sure someone needs closure
and somebody else
needs to go to jail.
Miller:
There she is.
As we first reported yesterday
the remains of
an unidentified Caucasian female
were unearthed in Summercliff.
The 5'4" woman
was approximately 20 years old.
Here you go.
Authorities are asking
for the public's help
in identifying the victim.
If you have any information
please call
the Las Vegas P.D. hotline.
Hotlines... hit or miss.
I don't know. In my experience
people usually remember
a beautiful woman.
Uh, Nick,
weren't you going to go
and do the,
uh... at the...?
Stokes:
Yeah.
Yeah, okay, I'll do that.
So I saw Eddie.
He actually... seemed scared.
Did that make you happy?
Um, no.
I'm not really sure what I feel.
You're not still in love
with Eddie?
Catherine, you have
to hand off the case.
Warrick can just double up.
Uh, Grissom,
Dr. Robbins wants to see you.
Something about
your skeleton.
Okay.
You have to pass off the case.
If you compromise
the investigation
there's no going back.
You could hurt Eddie
just as much
as you could help him.
Hey. I've already seen
the marks on the ribs.
Uh-huh, but
did you see
the hairline fracture
on the posterior skull?
No.
Robbins:
Easy to miss, but it screams
blunt-force trauma.
Also, the middle ear
has three bones.
They're dusted
with sodium
and lodged against the malleus
I found a tiny ball of earwax
with grains of sand.
Salt and sand.
Killed at the beach?
Not ruling it out.
Stokes:
Grissom.
Hey, Doc.
Hotline's lit up.
Five callers all ID'd
the same woman
and her mother just confirmed.
I need to know what happened
to my daughter.
We're trying
to figure that
out for you.
She was quite an athlete, huh?
Mm-hmm, yeah.
Did she scuba dive?
She'd just been certified.
Did, uh, Fay
before she disappeared,
go on any vacation
go diving or spend
time at the beach?
No, not that I recall.
And she, uh
lived here with you
until she disappeared?
No, she had just moved
in with her boyfriend,
Jason Hendler.
He still lives
on Medley Place.
Grissom:
And the, uh
police interviewed him
after she disappeared?
A couple of times.
He had nothing to do with this.
Well, how do you know that?
He loved my daughter.
He was good to her.
Did they... ever fight?
The first few months
of a relationship
nobody fights.
She was crazy about him.
( sobbing )
I've given Eddie Willows
20 lap dances.
He never got rough
till last night.
In the parking lot.
Yeah, he asked me
to go for drinks
you know,
but out in the parking lot
he starts kissing on me
and I kind
of laughed it off, but...
then he grabbed me
and he slams me
against the wall
and... that pig.
Hi, Evans
I'm sorry I'm late.
I'm Catherine...
just Catherine.
I'm a forensic scientist.
Scientist, wow,
you look so normal.
Thanks.
Catherine,
you sure want...?
Yeah.
Are those bruises
from last night?
Yeah, a guy pinned me
against a wall.
Sexual assault nurse
collect a kit yet?
Evans:
She just finished.
Why don't you see
if you can catch her.
I'd like her to get a sample
from under her fingernails.
Uh... what kind of sample?
Anything that might, uh,
show up from a... a struggle.
You'd think what that nurse took
down below would be enough.
The weird thing is...
I liked the guy.
It's not here.
Bullets just
don't disappear.
Sidel:
Excuse me.
No one's allowed
inside the tape.
I saw what happened.
Have you talked
to the police?
Police make me nervous.
You guys aren't cops, are you?
We're crime scene
investigators.
We need to know
what you saw.
I was kind of taking a break,
hanging out in a PT Cruiser.
I was laid back in
the heated driver's seat
when I heard the siren.
( siren blaring )
Tyner:
Put your hands on the wheel!
Suspect:
I didn't do it!
Whatever you think I did!
Man, I'm looking
at three strikes.
I'm not going back.
Just let me show you
my registration.
No! Hands
on the wheel!
And just like that,
the officer fired?
Just like that.
Sidel:
Missing bullet,
eyewitness...
we better tell Grissom
we got a war.
I heard about
your eyewitness.
A valet who joyrides.
He sounds reliable.
So, uh, how's
the thing going
on Eddie Willows?
What thing?
The thing that
I told Catherine
to pass off to you.
Oh, good, um...
We just put some stuff
through the lab.
Get hold of the DMV?
I was just about to.
Warrick? Why would
you call the DMV
on a rape charge?
Okay, I didn't hand it off.
Really?
I'm sorry, Warrick.
If you want me to suave anyone,
I've got to know the shot.
I know.
I'm sorry.
I'm doing this for Lindsey.
You so much as breathe on the
evidence, it's contaminated
and I end up the bad guy.
Eyes, no hands.
What's the status?
Skin samples from under
the woman's fingernails
are consistent with Ed's.
I saw some bruises
but Eddie's style
has always been very...
involved...
vigorous.
Vigorous?
She's trying to tell you
Eddie likes it rough.
Thank you, Warrick.
Eddie said that
she was into it.
He said, she said?
It's about the evidence,
Catherine.
And you may not like
where it takes you.
So how many grains of sand
in the ocean, huh?
I don't care about the ocean,
just the sand in my skeleton.
Can you pinpoint a beach?
I don't know.
I might have to do
some field research.
Hey, you think Grissom
would send me to Hawaii?
Why don't you ask him yourself?
Ask me what?
Oh, nothing, I, uh...
I was just telling
Nick about your sand.
Well, it's not sand.
It's not natural anyway.
Here, check this out.
Now, if this were natural sand,
the surface would be smooth.
Now this looks more
like Fremont Street
on a Saturday night...
rough.
Could the particles be
sediment from the concrete
where we found her?
No, no way.
I analyzed the mineral content.
It's feldspar and quartz.
That's crushed
gray sandstone.
It's man-made,
in a rock crusher.
What does that mean?
It means she wasn't killed
in Hawaii.
Other than that...
he has no idea.
Is this payback, Warrick?
Is that what this is?
I was tough on you,
so Officer Tyner takes my heat?
That's how you
think I work?
Brass, this has nothing
to do with anything.
The D.A. has
filed charges
and on the testimony of
a bleary-eyed car jockey
who was 40 feet
from the jeep.
Eyewitness is a bonus:
Your cop's magazine
was one bullet shy.
That's you CSIs,
always counting bullets.
What's he doing here?
You show up with your
latex gloves and your
little fancy metal boxes
and your little powders...
You have no idea what it's like
to put your life on the line
every day!
Oh, you mean dealing
with punk-ass cops who hide
behind their
union reps?
Brass:
Hey!
You're just a psycho.
You don't
deserve a badge.
Cut it out!
Not in my lab, pal.
Scientists!
I bet you've never
even drawn your weapon.
Yeah, I hope I never have to.
Nick, walk this guy
out the door.
Now, let's go.
Sara.
Yeah, come on, Warrick.
Let's cool down.
This is your fault, Gil.
Your nose is so
far down a microscope
you have no idea
what your people are doing.
Yeah, I know one thing:
My guys will not bend
and they will not
be intimidated.
Yeah, I sat in your chair.
Your guys have one job:
to find the evidence.
So where the hell
is the missing bullet?
Huh?
Eddie?
Catherine.
I'll take a root beer.
What are you doing here?
I knew you'd be here.
You got a routine:
Turkey club, no bacon.
You could be a detective.
Thank you.
( sighs )
Well, you obviously made bail.
Did you get a lawyer?
I got you and the truth.
Who needs a lawyer?
I came to tell you
how great you are.
It always comes out wrong.
When I married you,
I married up.
I know that.
It wasn't all bad.
You think the bullet's
somewhere in the jeep.
It's not in the body.
It's not at the crime scene.
I like our odds.
Let's do it.
( wrench grinding )
( metal clanging )
We have searched every
single piece of metal.
I think
hide and seek is over.
( sighing )
Yeah.
We've searched every
piece of metal.
Spare tire.
Sara:
You've got to
be kidding me.
The tire sucked up
the bullet
and the treads
covered its tracks.
We match the bullet
to the cop's gun,
the case is airtight.
There's a match.
We got Tyner.
One bad cop going down.
Well, actually, Warrick,
the evidence round wasn't
from the cop's gun.
It was from the suspect's.
No way.
( hard rock music )
These guys never give up
anything on their girls.
Well, let me give it a try.
Excuse me, sir.
Can we see your permits?
Oh, hi, gorgeous.
How are you?
Okay, Ted.
How are you doing?
I'm okay.
Hi.
You should've seen
this lady dance.
Was she good!
You still working
with the cops?
Can't seem to get
off the night shift.
You dressed like that?
If you want to
call that dressed.
Yeah, Evans.
Hey, Ted, you heard
about this thing
with Eddie and April?
Yeah, the night guy
told me about it.
Boy, Eddie never
changes, huh?
Bring back memories?
You mind if I look around?
Help yourself.
Thanks, Ted.
( doorbell rings )
Can I help you?
Ma'am, my name is Gil Grissom.
This is Nick Stokes.
Honey, who's out there?
Mr. Hendler,
we're criminalists
from the Las Vegas
Police Department.
What's this about?
We're investigating
the disappearance
of Fay Green.
May we come in?
Yes.
Thank you.
Did you find her?
Yes, I'm afraid we did.
She'd been dead
for quite a while.
Hmm.
You always hope...
Mr. Hendler?
Would it be possible
for us to look around?
Fay only lived here
for about a month,
five years ago.
I've got nothing to hide.
Thank you.
Thanks.
A trigger and a lionfish.
Yeah, that's right.
Interesting choices.
Violent, carnivorous predators.
( floor squeaks )
It's just a warped
floorboard.
It's been like that forever.
Mr. Hendler, at any time,
was your fish tank over here?
Maybe, a while ago, why?
Did it ever
overflow?
Or break?
Not that I recall.
You said I could
look anywhere, right?
Yeah.
Got a pocket knife?
What are you doing?
Pops out, pops in.
What do you find
inside an hourglass?
Mr. Hendler, I think
the tank was over here.
I think it broke.
I think you got water
and artificial sand
all over the place.
I'd like you fellows
to leave now, please.
Fine, we'll go.
We'll be back...
with a warrant.
So what did the rape kit say?
Nonoxynol-9,
polyvinyl alcohol, and...
Glycerin?
Yeah.
It's a contraceptive film.
What are you drinking?
Chamomile.
May I?
Sure.
Thank you.
So you used to work at
the French Palace, huh?
That's right.
You know, my friends and I
used to go there.
Really?
Payday Fridays.
Uh-huh.
Maybe I saw you perform?
Oh, I doubt it.
Why?
You would've remembered.
So, this film
it's kind of hard
to detect
because it dissolves
with body heat.
And, as you know, Greg
sex can make a body pretty hot.
This stuff has to be
inserted
15 minutes to three hours
before sex.
Which means that
April inserted the film
while she was still at work.
But how could she have known
to put the birth control in
before she was raped?
Exactly.
Guess where Jason Hendler
was employed five years ago?
Summercliff
housing development.
A plumber, perhaps?
Close. A subcontractor.
How'd you know?
Why else
would you be so excited?
Hey!
You weren't
going to say
good-bye to me?
I'll meet you outside.
Thought I'd let you off easy.
But I did tack up
my number
on your big fish corkboard...
Under "cold cases."
The ones that got away.
Let's hope not.
So, check it out...
the laser is the path
of the bullet.
If you were
Officer Tyner
and you approached
the suspect
from the driver's side
of the vehicle...
Vic was shot
in the frontal lobe
through the windshield.
There's no way I
could shoot the guy
from here and mimic
that trajectory.
The laws of physics
trump the eyewitness.
There's only one way
this could've gone down.
...show you my registration.
No! Put your hands on the wheel!
( gunshot )
Officer Tyner
was telling the truth.
So I bet you think
I owe you one, huh?
We work. We get paid.
You don't owe me anything.
Fine with me.
He promised me
a million things.
I got tired
of him lying.
Like what, marriage, kids?
Music videos.
He kept telling me
he'd put me in one
but he never delivered.
And for that you
set him up for rape?
( sighs )
No, it wasn't supposed
to go this far, okay?
I got this friend
over at the Trop.
She got this high roller
on a rape charge.
He paid a ton
to make it go away.
Wait a minute. You think
that Eddie's got money?
He is in
the music business.
He reps some bands Off-Strip.
No, I met a producer
friend of his from L.A.
and he's always throwing
money around this place.
( laughs )
What?
What's so funny?
Nothing.
I see you've cleaned house.
I thought you might.
I vacuumed up the sand.
Big deal.
Will you at least tell me
what you're doing here?
I'm working, sir.
Officer, would you hit
the lights, please?
You're getting
my floor wet.
It's luminol, sir.
It dries quickly.
Surface is non-reactive.
I know what you're doing.
You're looking for blood.
My husband didn't
do anything.
Why are you
harassing him?
Let's try the ALS.
Why use the alternate
light source
if the luminol didn't
pick up anything?
Luminol works on the surface
ALS chases the protein
molecules in blood.
It actually
penetrates the wood.
These floorboards are
all made of maple.
High-end, but
they've been lacquered.
Who lacquers maple
unless they're trying
to hide something?
Turn it off, Nick.
Officer, hit the lights, please.
Mr. Hendler
let me tell you
what I think happened to Fay.
On the night
of her disappearance
the two of you
got in a heated argument.
Don't you walk away from me!
Suffering a concussion,
Fay falls to the floor.
In the heat
of the moment
you decide
to make it final.
But Fay surprises you:
she fights back.
She pushes you off.
She crawls a few feet away
and you move in
for the final attack.
One thing that
I don't know though
what did you use to kill her?
I didn't kill her.
Well, whatever the weapon
it wasn't a knife,
but it worked.
You drove her body
over to Summercliff
where you were employed
and you buried her
in wet concrete.
I worked
the Summercliff job
less than a week.
Ask Amy; she worked
for the same contractor.
That's right.
He got a better job
in Reno.
Jason wasn't even in Vegas
when Fay disappeared.
Yeah, you painted the floors,
covered your tracks
for what, aesthetic reasons?
Five years
is a long time
but eventually the past
catches up to everybody.
I didn't kill Fay!
I loved her.
I still love her.
Amy, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
You still love her?
Officer,
would you please
arrest Mr. Hendler?
Call my father.
He'll get a lawyer.
I'll ride along with the cops.
Bring Homicide
up to speed.
This is now
a fresh crime scene.
I'll get to work.
Grissom:
"...the instrument had
to be slightly curved
"with some kind
of serrated edge
like crocodile teeth..."
Mrs. Hendler, do you and your
husband do much rock climbing?
( gun cocks )
Yes.
That's what I killed her with.
I can prove I was in Reno
when Fay disappeared.
I've got records.
You don't want to talk, fine.
But I've got a question for you.
Why do you care so much
about the floors?
I mean, Amy paints them
every spring.
It's no big deal.
Jason was in Reno.
I came here to tell Fay
that we would be
together again one day.
Mrs. Hendler, put the gun down.
Do you know he was engaged to me
when he met her?
Where are you going?
Stop it!
There was blood everywhere.
No one else could see it.
But I knew it was there.
A dead body is so heavy.
Mrs. Hendler,
I'm a good listener.
You've got to give me the gun.
I can't!
I'm sorry.
No, wait.
But you arrested my husband.
Wait!
Mrs. Hendler.
Nick, don't move.
Please.
I don't want to fire my gun
any more than you do.
For five years
you've been washing
the blood off your hands.
Let's put down the guns.
You okay, Nick?
Yeah.
Come on.
Morning.
( bike bell rings )
Please don't tell me
that you're in trouble
again already.
You weren't home.
I figured you'd be here.
Lindsey loves this park.
So, I thought I'd take you
out to breakfast.
Say thank you.
You're welcome.
I don't think
that's such a good idea, though.
Cath, when are we going to talk
about what happened between us?
What's to talk about?
You cheated on me.
I caught you.
I've got a new life.
Cath...
Come on...
why do you fight
the one thing we're good at?
Daddy!
There's my little girl.