Eight years.
People said
we wouldn't last.
Happy Anniversary, baby.
Happy Anniversary.
( distant dog barking )
She's on the sidewalk,
a block from the curb
and he's in the middle
of the street.
What's missing here?
No car.
No mercy.
This guy's stabbed
at least five times.
Got some reddish hair.
Vic's hair is brown.
They had dinner
at Andre's.
Coroner's assistant
has his wallet with
the credit card receipt.
They didn't bother to valet.
Saved five bucks,
cost them their lives.
Carjacking gone bad.
Carjackers don't use knives.
Never?
They used to say,
"Never on Sunday."
Then Pearl Harbor happened.
I never say, "Never."
Oh, man...
We got three minutes
to process
this crime scene!
After that,
we lose it all to the gutters.
Sarah, take over-alls.
Warrick, put a cone down
on everything you bag.
Nick, we got to
get these bodies
into the van.
Bring me a body bag.
Can we get another gurney?
We need another gurney.
Go to the van.
We're losing everything.
Yeah...
our killer got lucky tonight.
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Who, who, who, who? ♪
♪ I really wanna know ♪
♪ Who... are you? ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Who... ♪
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
♪ Oh, you! ♪
Well, rain screwed up all our
chances of a good DNA profile.
Don't even bother
bagging it.
Do we have
any eyeballs at all?
It's a quiet street,
weeknight.
Neighbors heard
the commotion.
Kid over here, he
had the only view.
What's your
name, son?
Justin Green.
Well, Justin,
my name's Gil Grissom.
This is Sara Sidle.
We're with
the Crime Lab.
Is, uh, is that
your blood?
No, i-it's his,
the one you took away.
I tried to help him.
I thought
I was doing everything right.
I think I might have killed him.
Whoa. Slow down.
What did you do exactly?
JUSTIN:
I was crossing the street.
This SUV came out of nowhere--
almost clipped me.
I turned and there was
this body lying in the street.
Oh, my God.
Help! Help!
Somebody call 9-1-1!
I freaked.
I did everything wrong.
I didn't tilt his head back.
I-I didn't clear his airway.
If it makes you feel any better,
that's not what killed him.
SIDLE:
Justin...
we're going to need
to take your clothes.
Why?
Because there's blood
all over them.
( garbled radio transmission)
MAN:
Catherine?
Hey.
I like the hair.
Thanks.
What are you doing here?
I was assigned.
This is my case.
Case?
The building collapsed.
There's nothing
criminal here.
Right.
That's why you were assigned--
a homicide detective.
What happened?
Oh, part of the basement
caved in.
Brought the rest down with it.
Body count?
Three old women.
Sisters.
One minute you're watching
Wheel of Fortune--
next thing, game over.
And you're not calling
this a crime scene?
Catherine,
it's a building.
O'Riley...
it's a suspect.
Hey, Greg.
Shh.
I might be looking
at the mother of
my children here.
Somebody's been putting in
way too much overtime.
No, man, this is serious.
I had a date last night
and this girl has
the most impossible
green eyes.
Just... Bam.
Shoulder-length
blonde hair...
intelligent...
and she smells so good.
Cute toes?
Oh... ideal.
Mmm.
And none are longer
than the big toe.
Mmm.
Both feet.
But, you know, what I
need to know is
what's on the inside?
Oh, what's in her heart?
No...
her DNA...
and let me tell you--
this girl has got
some fine epithelials.
Dude, you're sick.
Man, you've officially
lost it.
No, no.
There is this guy
in Louisville.
He charges 300 clams
to test your spouse's
underwear for
foreign DNA.
Now, that guy is sick.
I'm just a romantic.
But whatever happened
to getting to know someone
over coffee...
letting the relationship
evolve?
Romantic is
sending flowers
not bogarting
her skin cells.
Ahh, that's boring.
What are you doing?
What have you got?
Um, pulled some hair
off a male stabbing vic.
Okay.
Baby.
Uh-huh.
What?
Nine lives.
Cat hair?
Meow.
Kevin Shepherd.
Six stab wounds
to the upper torso--
one to the back,
five to the front.
And his wife?
Amy Shepherd.
One slice across
the neck,
right to left.
Work of a lefty?
Well, the blade transected
the jugular vein
and both carotids.
Hard to scream
when your throat's been cut.
Defensive wounds.
This guy put up
one hell of a fight.
Attacked with two weapons.
Two?
Two types
of stab wounds.
First a long,
sharp double-edged blade.
The blade went in smooth...
left a little
collateral bruising
to the skin.
Weapon number two
was blunt.
caused extensive bruising
around the points of entry.
Two weapons... two attackers.
Hi.
District Engineer?
Ah.
Follow the tie.
Is that from the rain?
Depends on who's asking.
Are you hiding something,
or am I not worth your time?
Excuse me?
You are the District Engineer
of the city, right?
You're responsible
for the structural safety
of this building.
I'm sorry. I didn't
catch your name.
Catherine Willows,
Las Vegas Crime Lab.
Crime Lab?
Yeah.
The building fell down.
Three people
were crushed to death.
Why is the wood wet?
It's a flat-roofed
structure.
Leaks aren't uncommon.
Maybe that explains
the dry rot.
And what am I looking at?
That would be Sheetrock.
Drywall. But what about
this layer right here?
When they installed
the original drywall
they used half-inch
and then, when they came back
and repaired it
they used quarter-inch.
Was the quarter-inch
on sale that day?
Look, lady, I don't know
what it is...
Catherine.
Sorry.
Don't say, "Sorry"
just know who
you're talking to.
When they applied
the second layer
and then they spackled it
and they painted it
the difference
wasn't noticeable.
It's noticeable now.
Which District Engineer
conducted the last
inspection?
There's only one
District Engineer.
Then it looks
bad for you.
( laughing ):
Okay.
Look, uh, Catherine,
why don't I write a report
and then I'll
e-mail it to you.
How would that be?
Where's the point of origin
of the collapse?
Look, this is my crime scene.
I can find it
myself
but that might mean
lots of question
to lots of people.
Well, it's just my,
uh, expert opinion
but I'd say right below us--
in the basement...
the laundry room.
Then that's where
I want to be.
Hey, Griss.
Kevin Shepherd,
chiropractor.
Amy Shepherd,
dentist.
House in the Lakes.
Married eight years.
Perfect credit.
You know, I'm lost.
There's nothing jumping
off the page, here.
What about
the eyewitness?
Justin Green.
First witness,
first suspect
but he hung around,
waiting for us.
Covered in blood.
But his story jibes.
Several eyewitness saw him
performing CPR
on Kevin Shepherd.
But if-if-if it is a carjacking,
I don't get it.
Why fight
to the death?
It's four wheels
and a chassis.
In the heat
of the moment,
it's not a car,
it's a possession
and people will fight
without realizing
what they're risking.
So, you are thinking the
Shepherds lost their lives
for their SUV?
I'm speaking
in generalities.
Regarding the Shepherds...
I'm in the dark, too
just like you.
Hey, Warrick.
Is Grissom around?
You see him?
( chuckles )
You know,
between you and me
as long as I've been
on the job
I still don't like
touching dead bodies.
Well, that's why
you got the badge
and I got the syringe.
I'm casting the stab wounds.
From the molds, we can identify
the murder weapons.
You're getting more like Grissom
every day, man.
Did you want me to give Griss
a message?
Yeah.
A patrol car located
the Shepherds' SUV.
The car is registered
to our dead couple.
When you carjack a car,
you keep the car.
You don't dump it.
Unless you're joyriding.
Well, who kills
for a joyride?
Wouldn't be the first time.
Has anybody else
touched this vehicle?
No, sir,
and I'm the one who found it.
Just the rain.
The evidence on the outside
of the vehicle
will be compromised.
Well, maybe there'll
be some evidence
on the inside.
Whoa.
Well, I haven't felt that
in a while.
What's that?
The element of surprise.
( sighing )
What's she doing here?
Good question.
Better question,
who is she?
Hmm.
Uh. Put some gloves on.
Yeah, I know.
You know, I... I can't believe
you messed up the crime scene.
The body fell out
when I opened the door.
It happens. We move on.
Mmm. Going
to bother you all day.
"Jessica Hall.
"Date of birth--
8-5-73."
Cell phone, power's off.
Didn't call 9-1-1.
They would've instructed her
to leave it on.
Seat belt's unbuckled.
That's why she fell out.
Yeah, so?
Well, she's
in the driver's seat.
Was she driving?
Or could she
have been placed in here?
Maybe she's
like 28% of Americans--
she doesn't buckle up.
I think it's 29%, actually.
I'll go radio the 4-19.
Hope you're not
allergic there, Boss.
What?
Cat hair. Found similar hair
on Kevin Shepherd's clothing.
How about Amy Shepherd?
Nope. No hairs on the wife.
Shepherd's SUV.
Stab wound. Cat hair.
She's linked
to the first crime scene.
But how?
Victim number three.
Wrong place, wrong time.
Saw something she shouldn't.
Well, finally.
What?
Someone has a theory.
Look, I-I've got guys
that are trained to do this.
Why don't you
let me call them?
You're going to go in there,
you're going to get
that snappy little jumpsuit
dirty, and...
No offense,
but they work for you.
So what?
Well, so the victims' family
deserves answers.
Somebody's responsible.
Hey, I didn't do
anything wrong.
Well, maybe not intentionally,
but if a ship sinks
the last person
who checked for leaks
is negligent.
You're not married, are you?
Divorced.
Okay. All right.
What you see, I'll see
but I just want
to go on the record.
This is a bad idea.
Thanks for your input.
All right.
We got a hot feed.
I'm going in.
I'll be right here.
Catherine?
You sure you want
to do this?
Why is everybody asking
me if I want to do my job?
Because we care.
And?
The Mayor ran
on a platform of urban renewal.
Clean out the slumlords,
create habitable,
low-cost housing
maintained by the city.
If you find so much as a scratch
on an aspirin in there
you know who it's going
to come back to.
I know I have
a job to do.
Excuse me.
Hey, Doc.
What's with the
fluoroscope?
When we brought
the body into the lab
she set off the metal detector.
Did you check in her pockets?
Nothing in the pockets.
What about a pin or a plate--
something metallic
on the inside?
I had the same thought,
but that's not what we've found.
David, take her down.
Yes, sir.
Cause of death,
laceration of the liver.
Exsanguination.
Once you nick the liver
it's almost
impossible
to stop the bleeding without
immediate medical intervention.
Whoa, David.
Go back up to the
12th rib, please.
I was just getting to that.
Our killer leave us a souvenir?
What is that?
What do you leave your waiter?
A tip...
of a knife.
How soon can we get that
out of the body?
Am I almost at ground zero?
Almost. About ten more feet.
Uh, then you should be
in the laundry room.
You should have
more headroom, too.
I feel like I'm crawling
through a straw.
( grunting )
Sweet.
What? What is it?
Are you getting this?
What is that? A roach?
I'm not an entomologist,
but I know one.
He can tell us.
( rumbling )
I thought this building
was secure.
It is secure. Just hang on.
The daily sorties.
I think that was an F-16.
Nellis Air Force Base.
About a mile south of here.
Anything else I should, uh
be aware of?
You're in the clear.
Okay.
I'm in the laundry room...
what's left of it.
You want to talk me
through this?
Okay, look up.
You should be able
to see the beam now.
Got it.
All right, connected to the beam
running vertically
to the concrete foundation
are the support columns.
Now, in a perfect world,
they should be steel
but given the age
of the building
they might be wood.
Yeah, it's wood, all right.
And it looks like somebody
took a sledgehammer to it.
So you really pulled this
out of a corpse?
SIDLE:
Yeah...
but I cleaned
it for you.
We need to know
the make of that knife.
Well, it's not a knife.
The tip's double-edged.
Bevels on both sides,
downward slope.
This came from a dagger
which means it's
either carbon steel
or stainless steel.
I get asked this question
more than you think.
SIDLE:
Acid in the
lemon juice
should react to carbon steel,
but not stainless steel.
How's a cop know all this?
He's the cop.
I'm the scientist.
I got a cop question.
What are we looking for here?
Dark spots.
SIDLE:
Carbon steel.
What's next?
Length.
Daggers are
rarely more
than an inch
at the base.
We got the tip.
So, we can fill in the rest.
Basic geometry.
Five inches.
Top row-- five-inch daggers,
carbon steel.
This is the one you want.
$24.99. We don't
take credit cards.
WARRICK:
Forget Shepherd's wife.
I can't match
the slash marks.
It's all about
these stab wounds.
So I concentrated
on Kevin Shepherd.
This is a nice job, Warrick.
You know, casting is an art.
And while the artist
was at work,
Brass and I
identified Jessica Hall's
murder weapon
from the tip we found
lodged in her ribs.
It's a dagger.
Fugasi Model 502.
Cool.
So we've identified
the weapon used
on Jessica Hall.
Was it also used
on Kevin Shepherd?
Well, I measured all
the sharp points of entry
on Kevin's body.
They're all identical.
They're all made
from the same murder weapon.
So, if this dagger
matches your mold...
SIDLE:
Okay.
We just put
the sharp wounds to bed.
Identified
murder weapon number one.
Now we just need
that second murder weapon.
Points of impact on these
two are blunt, right?
WARRICK:
Yeah, who stabs someone
with a blunt instrument?
Sara, you still have
the dagger tip from the body?
Yeah?
And you have the cast
of the unidentified
murder weapon.
Yeah.
A dagger's not a diamond.
It doesn't last forever.
We don't have two weapons.
So he started with Kevin
and then he went
after Jessica
and then the tip broke off.
And then he went back
to Kevin to finish the job.
One weapon, one killer.
An Anobiid powder-post beetle.
Very nice specimen.
He likes you, too.
Now, tell me about him.
Your building collapsed.
You assigned me the case.
You already know that.
And this little guy
confirms it.
This species of beetle
eats softwood.
Tell me about the building.
The frame's made
of Douglas fir.
A delicacy.
I did find
more than a bug.
Dry rot, questionable repairs,
a jittery engineer.
And check this out.
GRISSOM:
Forget the beetle;
this damage was intentional.
You're looking
for a Homo sapiens.
I know. Gives new meaning
to "home wrecker."
Catherine, there's a reason
I assigned you this case.
You're good with people,
both the dead and the living.
Translation: we're opening
a political can of worms.
The mayor's involved,
an election's around the corner
and you could've clued me in
a little earlier.
Can I keep it?
Sorry. It's evidence.
Don't forget to feed him.
I know-- wood.
WARRICK:
Oh, yeah.
I got three prints
on this gearshift
and they are beauties.
Sweaty palms make
the best prints.
The coroner just
sent over a ten card
of Jessica Hall's fingerprints.
Evidently,
I'm the new delivery boy.
Are you doing
what I think you're doing?
If we find
what we're looking for
the answer is yes.
Can I see those prints?
The photos are printing.
Thanks.
No need for AFIS.
We got a visual match.
All three prints belong
to victim number three.
So Jessica Hall
was the last person
to drive the
Shepherds' SUV.
What does that give us?
She was stabbed
at the crime scene,
but then what?
Was she driving herself
to the hospital?
Was she under duress?
None of the above.
Hey, Grissom, you know
that theory I had?
Yeah.
I'd like to revise it.
It's a scientist's right
to reexamine his theory
with each new piece
of evidence, Nick.
My evidence is
in the layout room.
All the wounds sustained
by Kevin Shepherd
were to his torso.
Now, look at this.
Blood flow on the left instep
of Kevin Shepherd's shoe.
WARRICK:
Lucky for us
the rain missed that.
When death is not immediate
the victim will instinctively
curl up into a fetal position.
Which may have protected
this from the rain.
Preserving blood pattern.
You expect blood on a victim
but let's ask
the question:
could the normal action
and behavior of our victim
have put his blood there?
The victim was lying
on the ground
wounds above the waist.
It's not Kevin's blood.
Who else had a flowing wound?
Amy Shepherd was too far away
but Jessica Hall
was alive and bleeding.
Okay. How did her blood
get on his shoe?
Gravity.
Warrick, please,
on the floor
on your back.
Man, why are you always
trying to put me down?
Sara, you're Jessica.
Come on, now.
SARA:
Okay.
All right, I'm bleeding
from my abdomen.
Standing here, I'm not
going to get that much
blood on Warrick.
Get closer.
Well, I can't without...
stepping on him.
You can if you kneel down.
Why would she do that?
Possibly to help
or to hinder.
I say hinder.
( loud gasp )
She was in on it.
She held him down
while someone else stabbed him.
By the positioning
of the wound
I'd say it looked
like her stabbing
was an accident.
Stabbing's are
messy and inexact.
So victim number three
becomes suspect number two.
GRISSOM:
Nick, get a warrant for
Jessica Hall's apartment.
We'll see if suspect number two
leads us to suspect number one.
And bring a scorecard with you.
Can, uh, can I give
you a hand with that?
No.
How did you get in here?
Well, I flashed my city I.D.
and, uh, my smile.
What are we looking for?
A lot of factors contributed
to the collapse.
I'm focusing
on the human element.
Now... if a sledgehammer was
taken to this column recently
there'd be evidence
of discoloration.
The damaged part
would be lighter.
May I?
Hands off.
Oh, right. Sorry.
No. No discoloration.
Would you like to know why?
Yeah.
Five years ago, this building
was apartment Vietnam.
The facility
was substandard.
The city turned
its back on it.
The tenants revolted.
Blake Neferson,
apartment 204
took a sledgehammer
to that column.
It's public record--
he was arrested.
Public record?
And you failed to indicate
the damage
in your inspection report?
There wasn't enough damage
to cause concern.
Tell that to the women
who were crushed to death.
I heard the lab matched
the blood
on Kevin Shepherd's shoe
to Jessica.
My theory's getting
better and better.
BRASS:
Not so fast, Nicholas.
P.D. traced a call Shepherd made
to Jessica
from Andre's Restaurant.
What's he doing calling
the woman who helped kill him?
It's your theory, pal.
Our little Jessica
was a prolific note-taker.
"Be a good person today."
Yeah, right.
Try not to kill too many people.
"Cancel water cooler delivery."
"Plan girl's night out."
"Light bulbs for porch."
NICK:
I think I found a key
piece of evidence.
The redhead
we've been looking for.
Red hairs on Jessica.
She owns a tabby cat.
Red hairs on Shepherd.
Chances are Shepherd was here
without his wife.
BRASS:
Yeah. I'm going to run
Jessica's cell phone records
and Shepherd's.
If anything was going on
between those two
we'll find out.
Let's go.
NICK:
"To access Achex,
double-click icon.
User name: Jessica.
Password: money."
Try it.
Yeah.
Achex.
Personal on-line banking.
Deposits, checking,
money transfers
everything under the sun.
Okay, I'm in.
Direct deposit
from Beaumont's Department Store
$500 a week--
probably her weekly paycheck.
And then a $35,000 day?
What, she win the lottery?
How does a girl who
makes $2,000 a month
pull in $35,000...
only to give it away
on the same day?
Let's see who she gave it to.
It hasn't posted yet.
( sighs )
No luck.
Wait. Go back.
Well, we know who she
got it from-- Kevin Shepherd.
Wait a minute--
Shepherd paid Jessica
to murder him and his wife?
Maybe. Maybe not.
We can't speak
from the evidence, Nick
and everybody else is dead.
I took this from
our suspect's apartment.
Husband and wife carjacking.
I heard about the case.
My friend and I
eat at Andre's.
Creepy.
Don't cancel
your next reservation.
It wasn't
a carjacking.
Well, it's a fresh pad.
Only a couple
of pages missing.
Let's see what she wrote
on those missing pages.
"Quarters for laundry."
Not incriminating.
"Pay parking ticket."
"Andre's at 9:00 p.m."
Whoa.
"Andre's, 9:00 p.m.
"Green SUV.
"Corner of Sixth.
"Sunday, K's office, 8:00 a.m."
This is a blueprint
for murder.
Assuming "K" is Kevin
they were planning
to meet three days
after he was murdered.
He paid Jessica $35,000.
He called her as he was
leaving the restaurant.
He wasn't supposed to die.
No. Neither was Jessica.
Kevin Shepherd took
a hit out on his wife
and something went wrong.
And we may
have the proof.
Okay, we've got the blueprint
and Kevin Shepherd's credit
card receipt from Andre's.
Okay.
Now, normally, a signature
wouldn't give us much.
But look at the "K"
on the receipt.
Now, look at the "K"
in "K's office."
Okay?
Also, look at the "S"
in "SUV" and "Sunday."
Now, look at the "S"
in Shepherd.
Both letters are identical.
He wrote both these documents.
I think Shepherd planned
the murder of his wife.
I'm with you.
Why'd he end up dead?
Bad karma.
Jessica and
this Shepherd guy
had been phoning
each other
day and night
for the past two years.
What does that tell you?
They had a very healthy
relationship.
He was cheating
on his wife, Amy.
And there's more.
On the night of the murder,
after Jessica got off the phone
with Shepherd, she made a call.
To who?
( buzzer )
Grissom didn't say what
he was looking for, huh?
No.
He just said check
his clothes.
Drying Room.
Six years in the job and it
still freaks me out in here.
I think it's peaceful.
Yeah.
WARRICK:
Here we go. Here we go.
Justin Green.
Eyewitness.
He's a suspect?
When did that happen?
Here's another thing
the rain ruined--
the blood pattern
on Justin's jacket.
Not the T-shirt.
Warrick...
What does that
look like to you?
That looks like
a handprint.
Right hand.
Justin's?
Wrist doesn't
bend that way.
So, it's not Justin's.
We know where
Jessica's hands were.
Holding down Kevin's feet.
And Amy Shepherd
died instantly.
So, whose handprint is that?
Kevin Shepherd's.
This is a transparency
of Kevin Shepherd's
defense wounds.
They fit perfectly over the
handprint on Justin's shirt.
Justin's story was
that he performed CPR
on Kevin Shepherd.
Yeah, but Kevin grabbed
Justin's shirt
so that means he
was still breathing.
Which means he didn't need CPR.
We just put the dagger
in Justin Green's hand.
Damn it.
Justin sold me a lie
and I bought it.
( aircraft approaching )
What are you doing?
Proving that you're
not responsible
for what happened
to that building.
I'm growing on you.
Aren't I?
The damaged support
column buckled.
Why?
The weight of the building
wasn't evenly distributed
out to the load-bearing
walls by the joists.
Good.
We're on the same page.
Now, I put a section of the
floor assembly in the tank.
I added a dozen or so of my
daughter's Superballs
two sub-woofers...
You put the whole thing
on vibration isolators.
Exactly.
Because I suspect
that sound vibrations
may be the ultimate
cause of the collapse.
( Beethoven's Ninth
Symphony plays )
Are you saying Beethoven
brought down the building?
No, but, uh, maybe F-16s
and whatever else they're flying
out of Nellis Air Force Base.
Now, I ramped up
the decibels on the stereo
to maximize
the vibrations.
Now you've lost me.
Watch the bouncing balls.
The nails are rotating.
Like screws.
Righty, tighty.
Lefty, loosey.
Of course.
Loose nails,
bounce in the joists.
Multiply that
by 50 years of flybys.
( symphony continues )
So you're pointing the...
( music stops )
So you're pointing the
finger at the Air Force?
No.
You point one finger
there's always going to be
four pointing back at you.
Beetles, sabotage,
dry rot and time.
Am I off the hook?
Yes.
Anything you want
to say to me?
As a matter of fact, yes.
Could've saved yourself
a lot of trouble
by not making me a suspect
in the first place.
You're welcome.
Okay.
Jim got us a court order
for production of documents.
On the left, the phone records
of Kevin Shepherd, Amy Shepherd
Jessica Hall
and Justin Green.
On the right, their
on-line banking records.
Wednesday, 10:02.
Kevin transferred
$35,000 to Jessica.
Wednesday, 2:16 p.m.
Jessica transferred
the money out of her account.
To Justin Green?
SIDLE:
Yes.
Deposit for $35,000.
Well, if it was
a straight-on hit for hire
Jessica would've steered clear
of the crime scene.
STOKES:
Maybe not.
In 1997
Jessica and Justin
had a joint account.
And they shared
the same last name.
Whew. Curveball.
BRASS:
So she hired her ex-husband
to help her kill
her boyfriend's wife.
All in the family.
I can trump that.
Sorry, Nick.
Thursday, 11:09 a.m.
$70,000 was transferred
to Justin Green's account.
From?
Not Jessica.
Not Kevin.
Only one left is Amy.
WARRICK:
I can trump that.
Wednesday, 3:00 p.m.
Justin called Amy Shepherd.
Oh, I bet I can tell you
that conversation.
Do you really expect me
to believe that?
Yeah. Look, you've got
to know about the affair.
Check his bank account.
He paid out 35.
You want to counter?
Amy Shepherd does
the unthinkable.
She doubles it.
Why kill one when you
can take out both
and collect over 100 grand?
Makes financial sense.
And Justin secures his double
cross with an insurance policy.
He eliminates
the person that hired him.
Jessica wasn't stabbed
by accident.
She was a loose end.
It's over, man.
It's over.
Look, you better split.
Go call 9-1-1.
( Jessica gasps )
Stop! What are you doing?
Shut up you slut!
( screams )
She's always going to be my wife
you're never going to have her.
( engine revving )
( dog barking )
Call an ambulance!
Jessica took the car.
You hid in plain sight,
offering aid to the victim.
Normally, when they pay
to have someone killed
they do it so they're not
connected to the crime.
Why was Jessica even there?
Timmy.
The Shepherds--
to the world
they looked like
the perfect couple.
You know what they say
about looks.
They can be deceiving?
They can kill.